Gentlemen tardy,
but here nonetheless,
sort of,
it's like halfway through because the
uh,
the one on Ustream says 3:00
and this one says a and I said at 2:00
because I'm an Indian,
but it's supposed to be 3:00,
so we figured we'll start somewhere
around.
Now it's all about checking out the
twitter that I to find out when really
going on.
Well,
that's ridiculous Brian,
because some people have lives and they
can't just be on the fucking twitter all
the time looking for you.
Shit.
Have you met people that have their
twitter setup?
So when twit they
automatically get like a text message.
I don't know.
People get mad at me sometimes you may,
you're tweet too much,
man.
It's blowing up my phone to take you
off.
That's ridiculous.
Why would you have.
I think maybe in the beginning it was
almost like an instant message for
people,
you know,
but it really,
that's just text messaging.
That's someone who,
you know,
text messaging but text messaging to all
their friends.
Right?
And then it got crazy,
you know,
it's a strange way of communicating.
Now,
twitter is one of the weirdest fucking
interventions that the Internet has ever
spurland sparring.
Spring gives birth to shit out.
It's amazing.
It's just,
it's so simple.
Keep it to 140 characters so that,
uh,
you know,
you don't get to fucking verbose stupid.
You learn how to edit your shit,
you know,
you can't have these long run on.
You ever read someone's blogs?
And even my own blogs ramble so much,
too much sometimes.
But some people,
your blogs are for smart people that you
know,
like,
like readers,
like I have to be in a reader mode most
of the time I'm in more of a video to
bullshit.
I don't want to read anything like that.
I write,
but,
but uh,
it,
it's.
Sometimes I do,
I times I think when I have what I want
to write it,
I have to write it.
Whatever the,
if I'm writing something,
it's just because that's what I'm
thinking about and I've been fucking
with it and I've been rolling around in
my head,
you know,
and they might not be correct.
I have no idea.
Most of them,
most of my ideas are just pure
speculation,
but the only way to really be honest
about it,
so write in a blog.
You can't like tell people stuff like
that.
You start talking to people about your
theories and you suddenly got nut least
if you write it down for whatever
reason,
it looks more thought out.
Isn't that weird?
You know,
have you just tell people that you think
that technology,
some sort of a symbiotic life form
that's existing with us and eventually
it's going to overcome us and then
everybody's looking at it like we
control it always,
you know?
No,
no,
like those terminator movies,
those guys got it right.
Like,
that's like super possible.
It really is.
I mean,
no one wants to believe that,
but if you look at how fucking chaotic
human life is and not,
not really in America,
you know,
this is pretty bad ass country,
but if you watch like documentaries on
like that vice squad guide to Liberia,
is that what it was?
What is the,
the website?
Did we talk about that last week?
Uh,
W,
what was it about those vice tv guys,
those guys that go to Liberia and talk
about all the cannibalism and shit
that's going on?
It seems like you did.
We did talk about it.
If you haven't seen it.
Well,
I'm going to find the link and throw it
up anyway because it's so crazy.
There's that link also that you talked
about last week that somebody said that
you didn't.
Did you ever.
They were like,
this links not working.
A lot of people are saying a,
I forget what it was about maybe the
lions that you were talking about the
lions last last week that,
that,
uh,
the amped up.
Oh yeah.
Really that was the wrong.
Maybe it was that one.
There was a few,
there was.
I just remember because somebody said
that they saw it.
It was amazing.
Maybe they googled it or something.
Maybe.
Maybe they were smart.
They were like,
oh,
maybe we should use google talking about
something or I'll give you the wrong
way.
Just let me know.
I'm sorry that that is annoying when
you're trying to figure out what it is.
But most of the time Google works out
pretty well.
Don't you feel like a little genius when
you figure out where they fucked up
though,
you go back to the url and you go,
oh,
there's the bottom part of it.
You've got to copy and paste the whole
thing they put in your browser.
It's like,
solves a little bit,
a little puzzle.
That's awkward.
That's a Papaya.
Kombucha.
Shit's good for you.
Or is it mango?
Papaya.
Cuban.
A male.
Um,
well it's up to other people.
The flux Kragen how's life?
It's like that lion shit was crazy.
Yeah.
If you haven't seen what we're talking
about with the Lions Shit,
there was a,
these gigantic lions that lived in
Africa and they got cut off from the
rest of the continent and there was a,
there was stuck on an island and they
were like regular size lines at first
they presume and because they were on
the island with only water,
buffalo water buffalo,
hardest to kill.
So these lions got gigantic.
They grew fucking huge from taking down
water buffaloes.
It's really pretty fucking spooky stuff.
You know,
it's intense.
Like they looked like the hulk,
they didn't look real like,
yeah,
those mice that have that milestone and
thing that they like.
Those dogs was whippets.
When they do those experiments on them
and make them look like cartoons
you ever seen that?
That disease,
I guess it would be that makes you grow
fast.
Like they just showed this a woman that
was 12 years old,
but she looked like she was 62 and a
smoker.
It has to do with the fat and your skin.
It doesn't have to do with growing fast
and it has to do with the fat in your
skin.
When you get older,
one of the things that happens is the
fat leaves your skin and these people
who are like 13 and 12 and we're little
babies even they have this disease where
that's how their body like starts
treating it right away so their skin
starts to behave like an old person's
skin.
Oh yeah.
It was weird though.
I felt so bad for her because she was
really.
Her mother had it too.
It's terrible.
Super rare though,
so don't worry about.
It's.
Yeah,
but it's pretty free
when you find diseases like that,
you know,
but this Liberia Shit,
man,
if you haven't seen this,
I have to throw this link up because
it's one of the gnarliest fucking
documentaries I've ever seen ever.
And these guys,
I think this show's called vice guide TV
vice guide to Liberia.
I'm going to give you exactly
the last,
last night.
Yes I did without giving any spoilers.
What do you think?
No spoilers,
no spoilers.
I think uh,
I'm getting tired of it.
You are.
So you didn't find it exciting.
It was exciting,
but I like,
come on,
you're just jumping back in time and you
know,
people are dead but then they're not and
like come on really.
You know what I'm saying?
It's like,
really?
That's what's going on now.
Well,
when that one thing with the one thing
and he was like,
I'm sorry for being that thing.
It was crazy.
Yeah,
it was like a certain point in time.
I was like,
God damn,
this is like comical.
Yeah,
it was a caricature.
You know what I really hated also how
many commercials they're worried.
There were like every three minutes.
There was a commercial in the future.
Hopefully you could like go.
All right.
No,
I don't want commercials.
I want pop up ads on my tv,
you know,
pretty pretty nutty because that was
just like you were into it,
out of it,
into it,
out of it.
Yeah.
It is pretty naughty.
It's,
you've got to watch it on Dvr and even
then you've got to fast forward through
commercials are a very inefficient way
of reaching people because you're
annoying the shit out of him,
you know?
I mean it does have you stuff enough
shit down.
Our throats will eventually take it.
But putting it out in the middle of like
shows and stuff like that.
What if you could go to like a group
once a month for like 10 minutes and
they showed you a bunch of products and
then they're like,
all right,
no more advertising for you on the
internet or for the TV.
Just because you,
you know,
you went to like a group meeting just so
advertisers can sell their products to
you in person.
You know what I mean?
Like this is coke here.
Taste tasted.
Yeah.
Alright.
So we won't advertise on TV anymore.
Well I think there's maybe a better way
would be to do it the way they do it in
the movies where they show you the ads
first.
Yeah.
And then the movie.
But you have to watch it.
That's the thing now.
But still,
it's like once the show begins,
you shut the fuck up.
You know when you go to the movies,
the conceded,
the you're conceding is it?
You give them money so they're only
going to know you in the beginning and
then they're gonna stop annoying you.
They're going to let the thing play out
in its full form,
which is the most enjoyable way when you
appreciate any like a coca cola or any
one of those people just stepped in and
said,
listen,
we all know the TV shows are better when
you let them play from the beginning to
end.
You don't want to interrupt him with
commercial all the time.
How about we'll do this.
We'll advertise in the beginning.
Thank you very much.
I hope you enjoy our product.
Hope you enjoy this movie.
Bam.
Yeah.
That's how it's supposed to be.
They've got it nailed.
These movie guys.
Got It.
Nailed.
These TV guys are retarded.
It'd be putting shit on the middle of
the fucking show.
Stupid.
It was.
Yeah,
and it was so bad last night that I was
just like,
really?
This is getting an insane 15 minutes.
Come on.
It wasn't even 20 minutes.
Maybe.
Maybe every hour.
If you have a two hour show every hour.
Trolling a few commercials.
Fuck it.
It pretty much was one hour show,
one hour of commercials,
but they built it as a two hour event.
Yeah.
Well it's a lot of money,
man.
There's a lot of money.
I wasn't.
I really enjoyed the series up until
now,
but especially early on.
I'm a fellow is.
It's like a really creative series,
but I got to admit that last night just
seemed kind of like hokey.
It's like,
you know,
the Chinese guy who doesn't like to a,
I don't want to say anything right now.
Yeah,
you
gotta just go replace everything that
blah blah blah,
blah.
I'm not.
No,
no spoilers.
I don't want to give it away if you
haven't seen it.
So,
uh,
that's what I think it's a,
it's still a great show still,
even though it seems Hokey,
it's still fun,
but at a certain point in time,
the whole premise is hokey.
I mean,
come on.
It's silly.
It's ridiculous.
It's the suspension of disbelief show.
Yeah.
Now when you jumping back in time with
nuclear weapons,
like,
what the fuck are you doing?
You know what?
You can just hit that thing and you go
back.
Oh,
okay,
cool.
No,
it's just utter nonsense.
It's like I want to talk about it,
but there's something I want to talk
about it,
but I'm trying to censor it,
but I.
There's no way to do it.
Yeah.
You can't eat snacks.
Well,
how did you,
did you enjoy it?
Yeah,
I did.
I was so pissed off about the
commercials that kind of upset me very
upset.
I,
I like being in a rural road and imagine
watching Avatar and every five minutes
you got to take commercial.
No,
you're absolutely right.
It's ridiculous.
There's got to be a better way to sell
shit.
That's not the best way to sell shit.
That's stupid.
If they think that just by,
you know,
by conditioning people to be used to,
interrupting and over and over again
that that's the best way.
Make us watch it in the beginning
they're like,
well,
we're not gonna.
Watch it anyway.
Then you have a Webcam set up on top of
your TV that detects if you're sitting
there watching it.
You know,
people get excited for previews.
Man.
I get excited for the whole preview.
I don't know why,
but I get excited.
I'm more amped up to see the wolf man
this year.
Then I think like anything,
man,
that looks awesome.
Can you do it?
That's going to be like in a gang sign,
dude,
do the wolf man.
It looks sick.
It looks cool because it's like old
school.
The wolf man,
you know,
and Rick Baker did all the makeup.
He's that dude who did star wars and
he's done like everything.
He did an American Werewolf in London
and this is like real old school makeup,
you know,
it's not like Cgi,
like parts or CGI,
like the transformation that CGI when it
becomes the wolf man,
but then it's like a dude in an outfit,
you know,
and Rick Baker's the master.
That shit.
When I was a little kid I used to want
to be a makeup artist,
Hollywood guys that made the makeup of
the guy on the hog video up there.
But I used to want to do like werewolf
masks and Shit and like special effects
movie,
special effects,
mass stuff.
I thought that was the coolest shit
ever.
I wanted to do that for a while,
man.
I was a big fan of that guy.
Rick Baker.
He's the dude.
He's doing this movie too.
So that's what was going to be the shit.
It looks good.
Fucking del Toro's probably a part where
he sings like a wolf man song or
something like that.
This fucking ass off that dude.
You know,
he's one of those dudes white when when
he's playing like angry or crazy,
like he goes so far you would worry that
he's going to like,
you've worried he's going to do
something fucking crazy,
you know?
Then when he's in a role,
he,
he's one of those dudes.
It's like I always look forward to his
movies,
like whatever is he knows how to
do it.
Acting such a tricky thing,
isn't it?
Like some actors,
you look really look forward to seeing
them in movies,
you know?
Yeah,
definitely.
It's a weird thing now.
Sissy spacer.
Some dudes get like super obsessed with
it.
How about those guys guys?
We're like super obsessed with movies,
movie trivia and Shit.
You know what's really gay?
Is that gross is that there's a John
Travolta movie that's coming out where
it's a love story and it uses a cross
movie reference.
That's how bad it is.
He's like embarrassing goes.
I always like a royale with cheese and
I'm like,
oh no.
Oh my God.
It was like John Travolta seems to be
losing his mind.
I would love to talk to that.
How dare he ruined a character.
You didn't.
And you know what I mean.
He's ruined and then he's creating a new
one.
I don't think he's ruining it.
You can't ruin it.
What it is is a slice of time.
Now you go back and you could see it not
as gross as commercials to me.
Well,
he was good in that Pelham one,
two,
three movie.
If you didn't see that pal.
Who moving here was fucking good in it,
man.
He plays a good psycho
tape.
I didn't like.
Is the hurt locker?
Have you seen that?
I didn't see it.
Rent it on Amazon.
Already have it.
Oh,
you got it.
Everybody says it's the best movie ever.
It's so slow and boring.
It's like,
let's go to one mission anymore.
I don't know.
This is running.
Nothing.
Go to one mission to another mission.
Oh,
let's go to another mission.
That end.
It's like,
why am I watching this?
Like I felt like I was just
watching.
You know what?
I felt like that with no country for old
men.
Yeah.
I never saw that.
No country for old men.
I was like,
listen,
I know what you're trying to do.
I know you're trying to be crafty and I
ain't trying to be unconventional,
but here's the deal.
When I go to movies,
I want you to stick with the fucking
framework.
Okay?
Here's good guys and bad guys and maybe
monsters.
Okay?
And at the end.
Good guys,
win any questions?
Okay.
Make your shit okay.
I like watching good guys.
When you fucking Weirdo.
I don't watch.
I don't like watching people just drive
off.
The whole thing is fake.
All right.
Are you pretending that?
Well,
in the real world,
things don't turn out well.
This isn't the real world stupid.
This is a God damn fucking movie and I
want a good ending.
Right?
I want an interesting ending with a
fucking cunt
avatar.
Avatar.
I,
I've talked to so many people that have
been in the military that are pissed off
at that movie for killing what they say
represents US soldiers,
but yet nowhere in there did they say
they're like us or anything.
They're just like an army,
you know?
That's a good point really,
when you think about it,
like,
well,
they're saying who are whatever that
the,
the one guy was a marine,
but he was one of the blue guy.
I can see it,
but it's like,
all right dude,
calm down.
There's Smurfs,
you know?
Well that's this.
He's got a point,
man.
You could see it that way because you're
not a a military.
Right.
That's what I'm saying.
Especially a military person in the
middle of two wars that they mean not
support and there's a lot of people that
are,
that are in the military that don't
think we should be there anymore.
A lot of people.
Yeah,
but I think Avatar in general is just
like,
it was like Joe wasn't real us army
troops,
you know,
there's no reason to get mad that
they're just an army.
They're representing like a space army
or something.
It was so much in the future.
It was like a thousand year old man.
It was to human life.
If you want to be real to me,
don't get mad at Predator.
Could you imagine though,
for Real,
if if
was such a planet and there was such a
mineral and there were mercenaries who
were going to that planet if it wasn't
broadcast to us,
we don't know what the fuck is going on
in Afghanistan every day.
We don't know about these crazy drones
and they're firing missiles into
Pakistan.
I mean this is real stuff that's on the
news.
It seems like science fiction,
this is going on every day and other
parts of the world and how ain't that
much different men and ate that much
different.
It's people that don't know people and
people for their shit,
you know,
and that's what's going on right now and
that's what it was going on in the
movie.
It's not that unrealistic,
you know?
And in fact it might be,
it might be generous.
The idea that they would go so far as to
make artificial ones,
to try to be friends with them really,
but more like kill them more like kill
them.
I mean that's what people do mean.
That movie painted a much more,
a much brighter picture of humanity than
the real humanity.
The real humanity,
we're not making like Arab clones and
we're operating with remote control to
go in and infiltrate the Taliban and go,
hey guys,
what's wrong with being American?
We could,
maybe we can all be cool.
You know,
you know,
I mean if the United States government
had that kind of insight and innovation
into the human body,
could you imagine that kind of shit that
they would do?
They would just make billions and
billions of Republicans that would just
start cloning Republicans and making
them and operating them with a remote
control republican girls fucking all the
important guys getting all their deals
past just.
They'll do.
You're just shaking your robot girl.
That's,
that's an Avatar for the real life if
that.
If they.
We don't,
we're not that Nice,
okay,
we're not going to make fake Arabs were.
No,
that's not gonna happen or fake whoever
the fuck we're fighting.
We're going to figure out a reason to
convince everybody on this side that
those people are evil and that's what
we've always done.
Those people are evil and then we jack
them.
You know?
I mean,
it's,
it's fucking amazing that the same game
can go on for so long and in this age of
information it can still be passed off
as like,
you know,
as the important thing to do.
You know,
the important thing to do at a certain
point is to try to fucking help
everybody try to get all these countries
to chill the fuck out.
But that's never gonna happen man,
because they live in somewhere that
sucks.
And when you live somewhere that really
There's a lot of Goddamn conflict,
you know,
that's just a fact.
They got a fucking roll the dice and
they're living in a part of the world
that stuck hundreds and hundreds of
years ago.
They've got technology but they've got
chaos and you know,
it doesn't,
it's just a mess.
They've been fighting forever.
They've been fighting forever over
there,
man.
I mean that's what they do.
That's what these fucking people do in
the Middle East.
War has been going on in the Middle East
for so long.
Like you talked to Israelis,
like due to a live in Israel already
talks about all the time.
Those motherfuckers are hard,
you know,
those people are different,
those,
those people were experiencing war on a,
on a daily basis.
Man,
that's like a part of their culture
almost,
you know,
it's like this conflict has been going
on for so fucking long over there and
it's almost impossible to see a way
without evolving,
without evolving as a species.
It's almost impossible to see a way it's
going to end.
It just keeps going.
It doesn't show any sign of letting up.
You know,
if you looked at it as a,
you know,
as a wave,
and you see the wave bouncing back and
forth.
Like what?
It doesn't seem like it's gone away.
It seems like there's always some
bullshit going down.
There's always this motherfuckers mad at
that motherfucker and he's gonna launch
bombs and dented the.
It just,
it,
it seems like it takes a little time off
and then it bounces right back in.
Palestine wants their land back and
tipped it to an,
a settler as an oh shit.
Someone got run over by a tank to to,
to,
you know,
it's like,
it's always there this spring backing
forth.
Violent tension is always there and it's
like something's gotta be done at the
core of that shit.
Something's gotta be done.
Unless you're.
I mean,
unless that's what people really want.
Once people what they really want,
it's conflict lumens.
That's just human nature.
You know?
It's possible,
right?
So avatar is nicer than people
advertise,
nicer than people I think.
I don't think we would make fake people
to deal with our animals.
We would fucking kill him.
So for people that say that,
that's.
Oh,
you moved pitch people in bird load
mercenaries,
man.
That's,
that's crazy job.
Those kinds of space mercenaries.
Motherfucker,
don't you play doom,
right?
Those dudes are serious space
mercenaries.
That's an excellent character.
If you're playing quake three,
you know,
it'd be a space marine.
Fuck you bitch.
Tough characters.
So I have an eight year old pole that
was revisited recently.
It was about pooping poop.
Standing or sitting or wiping.
It's pretty funny though.
It's gained popularity.
Again,
wipe,
standing up or sitting down.
What do you know how a white
motherfucker,
we've talked about this.
I know we've talked on this.
W O W I stand up to get a good goddamn
white bed.
I'll tell you this,
I was using those flushable wipes,
you know,
to keep my button
nice and fresh and tidy.
You got 50,
58.
Those aren't good man.
Fifty slash 50.
No,
no,
no.
Even if 50 slash 50 that the problem
with those wipes is can't really flush
them.
They call them fly and bone,
but I've added to my house twice.
That's how stupid bitches.
The pack up in your pipes.
You can't flush them.
You know?
How many are you using?
Like 15 to Russia.
But you can do that.
So then the only other option is you
have to either have a bad day,
which I have never used.
Why don't you use it?
I would totally love one because I'm an
American.
I think it's great.
It's like,
Hey American,
I want to force it up my butt hole.
It doesn't even look remotely
comfortable or inviting fracture so
hard.
Whoever the fuck invented that,
that asked me to machine.
They're hard people,
man,
because that thing is just like
polished.
It's white and there's like steel and
chrome.
It doesn't look like anywhere.
You want to put your asshole really warm
and soft and inviting.
Police your asshole here.
We'll clean it off for you know,
it looks like metal and fucking.
It's 2010.
If you need a better way to clean my
asshole with a machine and this stupid
little monster looking thing.
It looks like a torture contraption.
It looks like a faucet and looks like
someone's going to shut that other stick
right up your asshole and you turn it on
and water goes inside your body or
something.
I mean that's what it looks like.
It's just make like a robot Asian face
head that just eats your ass.
I can pick her up.
He was like leaning against it and he's
like,
yeah,
clean it because it looks like Lucy Lu.
What about for you?
What about for girls though?
We need something for girls.
Wouldn't be a black guy with the same
one that cleans her husband's asshole.
I guarantee if there was an asshole
cleaning machine and it was a woman's
face like a really hot Asian woman,
will your wife would want her own
asshole cleaning machine right next to
magic Johnson or you send a picture,
a photo to the manufacturer over father
and they send back the father.
Imagine if you could do that.
I mean,
why can't you do that soon in the
future?
I guarantee you in the future there's
going to be toilet seat that looked like
celebrities.
They can eat your ass hole.
Julia Roberts.
Look,
somebody's twitter this down that this
is the future because we're going to
forget this.
Twitter me this please toilet seats.
They look like celebrities and they
clean your asshole that that is the
future.
Genetic like fake leg.
They're so close to like replicating
different parts of human beings.
You know they.
They created a woman's bladder,
took her bladder and they've used stem
cells and they created.
They took a piece of her bladder.
They created a big bladder for her,
were doing do incredible things.
Now that's going to be a.
that's going to be able to happen.
You're going to have to be able to have
puff Daddy,
right?
Your asshole.
It's gonna look like,
like those wax figures,
like that's famous.
It's gonna feel like flash and they're
going to have emotions and all he wants
to do is lick your asshole.
That's it.
But yeah,
but they have emotions.
Sometimes they would cry and be sad when
I think Julia Roberts face going.
No,
no,
no.
Who would you have if you had,
if you have the ability to buy any
celebrity.
Megan Fox,
Megan Fox News.
But as a gag gift I would get my friends
like,
Hey,
I got your uh,
Brad Pitt.
Be Brutal though.
If like,
what if your friends really liked.
It's not even a real person bro.
Fuck.
I want my asshole clean.
I liked,
I liked it.
What do you give a shit?
It's not even a real guy because it's
the guy's image because image,
images eat your ass.
Who would you do?
I don't know man.
I have to think about that.
I would go right from Megan Fox,
but I would also have like a,
like,
like a different one for special
occasion.
Maybe I'd go with like Traci Lords right
when she became legal chapman.
It's like Tracy Chapman,
Tracy Lawrence.
Because like the craziest porno story
ever.
You know that story.
I was thinking a divided lims player
from Mathis.
I met her.
Oh No.
Oh,
vh one thing.
One of those,
uh,
like uh,
they did a bunch of shows called the
list and I got to sit down with a rob
Halford from Judas priest.
He was one of the guests.
Meatloaf was one of the guests and I
hosted it and she was on a tour.
She was one of the guys.
She was very nice,
very.
She seems like an like a normal human,
but she was so super hot man when she
was young.
Who?
Not that she's not super on now.
It's pretty hard now,
but God damn,
when she was young it was just
ridiculous.
She got into porn at like 16.
Lied about her age.
They're all illegal.
Yeah.
I've never seen one on my computer ever.
Yeah,
I mean it should be illegal.
I totally understand.
I'm with you.
I know there's plenty of porn.
It's so funny.
Back then though,
the seventies looked like an old lady,
you know,
like,
like I,
you look back at 70 videos.
Those kids don't look like kids.
They look like older women like cougars.
Here's something that I really like.
Your hair and your makeup.
They did dress crazy,
but it's so fascinating,
man.
Those whole pawns are fascinating.
Know Donna,
you liked that one?
I like her.
She's,
she's always favorite too,
I think.
Yeah.
I just like her because she's like real.
It's like,
hey look,
here's a picture of my butthole.
Very real.
She'll shock you with her.
Yeah,
she's got great twitter's.
If you don't follow her,
it's not safe for work.
And you click on it and it's a gaping
butthole with.
Yeah.
Kind of like,
yeah,
that's kind of not safe for work.
Talk about,
you know,
the understatement of the year award.
Okay,
hold on.
If you don't want to see a gaping
butthole dog,
God dot.
It's funny because she was doing an
asshole movie and she was like
practicing all week.
He's like,
I got to practice more like a fist up or
God bless
her.
God bless you girl.
Keep going with it.
Enjoy.
So a three d porn coming soon.
It is coming soon,
man.
I was at the uh,
the Sony store,
the Sony store at the mall and they have
the three d tv and you put glasses on
and you turn them on with a button and
it's just like watching anime tie three
dates.
Fucking insane.
They had sports on.
I had soccer and the soccer balls
fucking flying by you.
I mean it's really wicked.
It just like so much more immersive.
It's really,
really cool.
And that's going to be on TV soon,
man.
It's coming out this summer in 2010.
They're going to have the first units
out and then it's going to just explode
so crazy.
They're going to be filming in three
days.
Everything.
Everything's going to be in three d.
yeah.
I got something to add to the old crop
dusting theory.
I was thinking of this the other day.
It was like the crop dusting pot on
people.
No,
no.
I mean Shit.
Kim Trail.
That's something I did the whole Kim
trails discussing.
I thought of you better night.
So if you're going to do like spray this
shit over cities,
we know where people are going to be
like,
what the fuck is that?
Why don't you do it at night?
Yes.
Hey,
should we do it when everyone can see it
in is awake or should we do at three in
the morning?
That's part of the eval or well-planned.
The evil plan is that they sprayed right
above them.
They willingly,
you know,
allowed these politicians to control
them with the spray in the sky.
You know,
who really,
really,
really believes that shit is prince
prince is like crazy.
But chem trails,
he was like,
you know,
so crazy.
We would all be in the ghetto and
everybody would be playing and having a
good time.
And then they'd start spraying that shit
over our heads and all of a sudden
everybody was fighting like,
why are we fighting?
What's it about?
Like what the fuck are you talking
about?
All right.
People always fight.
There's always violence.
Like what are you insane?
Any place where people are poor,
people are violent.
Shut the fuck up.
Like you really think that they're
spraying shit from the sky that's making
people in poor communities be violent.
Wowza people believe some nasty shit.
Can you imagine being stuck in an
elevator with prints that would be.
Love it for that.
He's a genius.
She to just be in that guy's presence
and just talk to him.
A fascinating dude,
but sometimes even dudes who are
geniuses at anything,
whether it's playing chess or you know,
being a martial artist,
there's sometimes there's something
wrong with them to get them there.
There's something about getting really
amazing at something.
People that are the very,
very best at something who almost all
crazy.
It's really hard not to be,
you know?
Could you imagine if you like the best
in the world?
Like a Lance Armstrong type dude?
How's that?
Do not fucking crazy.
It is.
Pancakes.
Pancakes was on about waking up in the
morning making a difference.
Kicks.
Oh,
that story.
Yeah.
I can't tell you a personal story.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I protect my friends.
Who was Joe Rogan?
Who are you,
man?
How Dan Jones home?
I was thinking deep thinking deep being
mean to me.
Yeah.
But if he has,
if he to be asked that same question to
John Malcovich,
you'd be like,
who is John Malcovich?
I'll tell you,
you know,
like,
you really look at that different
products.
We boot this up,
my shit is whack.
How awesome is that?
Uh,
Dana White's playing or the pride shit
on spite of so much.
Awesome man.
I've been addicted to it.
There is so much fun.
I showed Brian the,
uh,
the difference between the rules Brian
was alive,
talked about in my blog where when the
dude tried to stomp the dude,
he went,
he could do that.
You remember?
Yeah.
I was really stoned.
And next thing I know this guy is like
stopping this guy's brain.
And I'm like,
Whoa,
whoa.
Is he trying to kill the guy?
Fucked up.
It was pretty fucked up.
It's like when you watch those,
uh,
those pride fights,
like they were pretty fucked up.
You know,
it's like old school,
UFC.
ECI.
Yeah.
But you know,
there's something about the way they did
it.
Man.
I like it.
I love the fact that they did 10 minute
rounds.
The first round was cold.
That's great.
That's how it should be.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
and everybody says no bullshit because
it's too hard in the fighters.
I don't necessarily know if that's true.
You know,
there's a lot of times where a momentum
is being established and it's been
established and you would like to see
where it goes.
You don't want to see him like fuel up
and have some water in the corner.
I want to see where it goes from there.
From there,
have a dude works for like four minutes
and finally gets out of the ground.
Or if a guy gets taken out immediately
and a dude finally gets up and there's
only 20 seconds left and then the dude
starts bombing on him and then the guy
who took him down as tired,
I want to see what the fuck is
happening.
Keep going.
You know?
I mean,
that's what I think.
That's what the best guys would want.
The best guys would want to see that
they would want to see a big ass 10
minute round,
but he put it in the interest of the
safety of the fighters though they're
going to take less damage than a five
minute round.
That's why I accepted.
I accepted unified rules because if you
look at it like in terms of like what's
what's going to be the most palatable
for the American people for the American
public.
Yeah.
That's the most palatable five minute
rounds,
five rounds for championship fights.
I totally agree with all that stuff.
The only thing sometimes I think that I
would substitute knees on the ground for
elbows,
I think needs from that position when
you're holding onto a guy and you can
name and the face,
elbows on the ground,
cut that shit out to dudes and sometimes
they fuck up fights,
you know,
they,
they'll end a fight early.
That was like a really good fight and
it's because of a cut and they usually.
That doesn't happen,
but occasionally,
you know,
the UFC is so much better about that
than
boxing the.
Any,
any kind of a bad cut and they'll stop
the fight like right away,
UFC lit Stephan struve fight and he had
like a hatchet wound in his head.
I mean it was a giant cut.
It was a giant cut and then led the
fight,
go and eventually got the dude down and
choked him out.
And it was an incredible fight.
I mean he was busted wide open,
covered with blood.
It was insane.
And after it was over,
the guy was so dizzy,
he had lost so much blood,
he could barely talk to me and I was
talking to him after the fight.
It was incredible though.
They would never let that happen in a
boxing match.
I think it was kind of crazy that that
fight took place in Germany because the
Germans were kind of reluctant to have
the UFC there.
And then I was like thinking like,
wow,
this is one of the bloodiest fights ever
and you know,
this is where it's going to take place.
And that place where they were
apprehensive about it,
you know,
apparently a bunch of German dudes came
down to see the UFC.
And I'm in Vegas and you know,
they didn't like it.
They thought it was horrific and
violent.
What's kind of like pink spinning with
the water?
You see that on the grammy's that,
that girl is so talented.
That's pretty amazing though.
She's very talented and she something
about her,
her,
her performance charisma.
Like when she walks on stage it's like
you have to like step back,
you know,
she's got it.
Whatever it is,
she's got it,
she's hot.
She's,
she's like,
there's something about just the way
that she just walks on stage and sings
so confidently and so commonly like her
energy.
It's like that's a girl that's like born
to perform.
That bitch can perform her fucking ass
off.
And when and then when she goes up in
the air,
you're going to go,
oh well the other ones are going to do
the acrobatic.
She ain't gonna do shit.
She's just kinda like get lifted up.
No,
she gets all fucking crazy and she's
looking in this half naked outfit and
she dumped in one arm.
She's spinning around and then she turns
up,
she,
she spinning with her head down and
she's singing at the same time.
That's,
that's the baddest bitch and music
period.
Everybody else.
Shut the fuck up.
Shut the fuck up,
man.
Pink just owned all those bitches.
All of them.
Lady.
God got sit the fuck down.
But did you not see what happened?
Can you do that if you can't Shop Lady
Gaga?
It was pretty good too.
I didn't see it.
That fucking poker face song made me
want to punch holes through walls.
I like leading.
I like it all.
You Want Fella?
Busy man.
I love.
I love chick songs.
I love when chick saying people get in
my car and the thick.
It's a joke,
dude.
You got to get this us CD tieger APP.
Let me think.
Maybe I told you already.
Tig Rue twitter recently.
They've fucking jam man.
You know punk checks puncture?
Yeah,
I'll do it.
I'm all over that.
I love chicks with great voices.
Like people get in my car and like I
have sheryl crow on and they would think
it was a joke.
Like what are you joking like that?
I like the long.
That's good cd.
It is her voice,
her voice is like comforting.
You know,
her voice makes me want to like,
feel like you're going to cuddle up in
the corner of the fire ceremony locking.
She's given you a big hug with her
voice.
No,
it's French for breeders.
The breeders remember them.
There were lines that sing a big song in
nineties,
uh,
mean splashed
turner and every man in our banner
banner,
they were like big and then they just
went away.
Yeah,
I think it's really hard to keep a
musical band together.
You know,
I know Eddie has a hard time,
like keeping,
like he's,
he does a bunch of different projects
all at the same time,
so it doesn't ever has to rely on any
one person.
Right.
And he runs all of them.
It's got to be super hard to keep a
bunch of people who are like wanting to
be stars and you know,
wanting to just can't wait to get rich
and get nutty and fucking lose their
marbles and think that they're the
reason why this bands there in the first
place and how many arguments like that
happen in bands,
you know,
they're all nuts.
They're all wanting to want to be the
outfit.
So very rare that a band like can
really,
you know,
like foo fighters,
band or something like that could really
come together and just be that she's bad
ass band and keep it together and make
good music so hard.
You know,
it seems like bands,
bands are good for like,
they're good for like a couple of cds
and then it just gets rough for,
for most of all the rare few can just
keep jamming on,
you know,
the rare few,
like the rolling stones just keep it
together forever.
That's nuts.
No,
like they don't go out.
Like the crazy thing about the rolling
stones is they're calling out like a
young rock band.
Like they,
they,
they fucking,
you know,
Mick Jagger still bounced around on
stage and yelling and shit.
Like he's in incredible shape,
you know?
That's that,
that's the amazing thing about how the
stones are doing it.
It's not like he's just,
you know,
decided in his later years,
he just gonna stand there and sing the
song still fucking running around and he
still takes his shirt off and shit and
least it looks like a monster,
you know,
looks like a bunch of Nice.
He just glued a bunch of Nice Lotion in
the basket.
Guy made a hilarious,
but he's got like a six pack and shit.
The dude has to be in insane shape to do
that act that says that's incredible
men.
Mick Jagger still keeping it out there.
Yeah.
So his,
uh,
what's his name?
Springsteen and all those guys.
Yeah.
He's still out there doing crazy for our
concerts and shit.
You know what man?
Those guys have people that have them.
There's people,
there's people that have fans.
And then there's people like Bruce
springsteen that have people that
worship him and live for the fact that
Bruce springsteen is alive and their
whole day revolves around springsteen
and they probably post on a message
board some there somewhere and their
message board name.
It's probably like be springsteen or
something like that.
You know what I'm saying?
Or some obscure nicknamed that they know
that Bruce springsteen had when he was
younger that they dropped after awhile.
You know what I'm saying?
You know the fucking,
the Long Island Expressway,
whatever the fuck it would be.
You know,
whenever they were calling people get
nutty,
mad.
You know,
people get nerdy about people.
Especially Jersey guys.
He's from Jersey.
Bruce Springsteen,
he's from Jersey City,
New Jersey and Jersey.
They get fucking crazy.
People are so crazy.
They're savages.
They are savages.
That's why I was born by the way,
don't get angry.
I'm talking about me.
I just saw a kitchen nightmares that was
in Jersey and it's like the whole family
was just out of out of their mind.
There are some of the toughest guys that
fight in the UFC or from church.
Frankie Edgar,
Jim Miller,
Dan Miller,
those guys are all Jersey guys.
They're fucking savages there.
Are there different kinds of dudes?
They will fight you.
They will fucking punch you in the head.
It's like this.
It's a totally different type of human
being than like the average dude that
grows up.
Like in California.
People are so much more relaxed in
California,
so much friendlier,
so much nicer.
Jersey people will punch you in your
fucking head.
It's not all of them,
you know,
and they're not bad guys.
They're not.
They're not mean.
They're just.
There's a level of tension in certain
towns.
Philly's another one.
There's a level of tension and Philly,
you know,
that the dudes would come out of.
There are so many bad assets come out of
Philadelphia.
Boxers.
Joe Frazier came out of Philadelphia.
Bernard Hopkins came out of Philadelphia
and MMA got Eddie Alvarez comes out of
Philadelphia and Philadelphia is filled
with fucking and nimbles.
You know,
that's a crazy ass tough town.
It's weird how there's towns like that
is that there's certain towns that just
have like,
like,
you know,
no one thinks of like San Francisco is
being like aggressive.
You know what I'm saying?
Like it's like that's like kind of a
relaxed town.
You'd almost feel like if you got mugged
in San Francisco,
you're a pussy,
but no,
there's like regular people in San
Francisco.
There's violence there to but some
places is just way more violent.
Right.
Columbus,
you grew up in Columbus,
Ohio.
Was that don't get tense in the winter?
No,
not really,
but the worst is I like Cleveland,
Cleveland's getting bad,
but Michigan driving through Michigan
and go to the casinos.
That was scary.
Like cars on fire and houses.
They got bears walking through Detroit.
They're spotted bears in the city of
Detroit.
There's so many abandoned houses that
bears are starting to move back around.
That's nuts.
Yep.
Bears in Detroit.
Wow.
That's spooky shit,
man.
That's like one of my bits really is.
That's like the the bed I have about
the,
the dumb people out bringing smart
people,
smart people die off and everything
shuts down and then the dumb people are
stuck there,
but in this case it's poor,
unfortunate people that were actually
born in this one town.
It's happening.
So you know,
Detroit is falling apart like this
insane rate and it's not getting any
better.
It's like they say that it's over 50
percent joblessness in Detroit because
they report like 20 something percent,
but the rest of them are just people who
have stopped.
They stopped counting them after a year.
It's crazy,
man.
Scary.
You know,
we used to make the coolest fucking cars
ever.
If you compare just on a coolest factor,
like some of the cars that America is
making in like 1969 and then like Alpha
Male,
those gay looking pieces of shit,
those goofy looking clump boxes take a
19,
67 corvette over all those bitches.
You know,
America is making so radical fucking
cars,
man.
60 seven vet,
69 Camaro.
Pretty good.
Cars are starting to a jk just got news
today that she has two recalls on our
Toyota and she's like,
Holy Shit,
I have one of these cars,
and she's like,
what am I supposed to do?
And they're like,
oh,
well,
you know,
just drive careful.
And uh,
she's like,
whoa.
Have you heard that gets stuck on.
No,
they're not even saying that.
There's some people that are saying that
whatever programming is a Steve Wasniak
I said that he's figured out that it's a
software error.
Omar.
And so now we're thinking,
wait our cars to go crazy over software.
Now you got,
you got pc in your car,
now it's got a virus,
and now I can control your car and lock
the doors.
Oh my God,
I didn't even think about that.
Somebody can bluetooth your fucking and
it hack your car right next to you.
They can hack your car,
lock the doors like mission impossible
style on the breaks.
Yeah.
I wonder what the fuck they can do to
stop shit like that from happening.
That's craziness.
I didn't even think about that.
And did you hear that nine one,
one call of the people that were in one
of the cars that led to the recall,
there's a nine one,
one call that you can listen to where
the guy's like,
hi,
we're going to have three words.
We're going to be at 120.
Our brakes aren't working.
We can't turn off the car.
And we're.
And we're,
we're going towards the end of the
freeway and we're,
we're,
we're going through an intersection like
family of four,
something like that.
It's awful.
All because of this Toyota Bullshit.
I don't even want to hear about this
one.
Yeah,
that's scary as fuck man.
Check out google a nine slash 11.
Call Toyota.
Recall
Jesus.
Well,
I have Alexis.
Alexis has made by
right?
I think actually it wasn't lexis that
have you checked to see cars on a recall
list?
No.
You better do it right now.
Jessica just did it today to two recalls
on her car.
Get the fuck.
I swear to God.
Doing it with.
And Alexis was the one that was now
correct.
So yeah,
I'm pretty sure here.
Let's Google that.
Alexis,
nine one one call
toilet lexis.
It's a matte recall.
It's a mat.
They're not saying anything about a
software software
thing.
No.
Steve Wasniak the lake.
We're wozniaks said doubt about it.
It was on in gadget yesterday.
Let's,
um,
let's
post it up for people because this is
kind of important.
Otherwise we can get in trouble,
right?
Not really,
but he said that if he didn't know you
could say he says he likes to suck cock.
You know,
she just made something of them.
You can't be saying that.
I can make that up.
Brian,
when Steve was neck,
my dog.
Shit.
Dog.
You guys tight?
Yeah,
I didn't know bu my gosh,
they added a multitouch to the that new
google phone.
Yeah,
just like an iphone does the same thing.
It's about time now.
Nobody owns the right to do that.
Nobody owns it.
Supposedly apple had the US patent
night.
So.
So what are they selling it to?
All these people probably,
but I don't know if that's all
speculation.
Actually.
It's probably Gizmodo there.
You can't find that you mother was
google.
Is this Gizmo Gizmo Bitch fucking
Internet.
Shelly's,
well,
we've got to find out which cars were,
uh,
were recalled and whether or not Steve
was nag actually said it was a software
issue.
That's scary.
She's really pissed.
That's scary shit because that guy's a
super genius.
One of the guys who helped create apple,
you know,
and uh,
that's not something that Erica would
say lightly.
Okay.
Toyota,
to borrow Steve Wozniaks Prius for a
week.
No,
that's not it.
no.
That's software and duplicate either.
That's it.
Yup.
Toyota Prius has scary software program.
He could duplicate.
Told the crowd chromosomes.
Social situation problem in the Prius.
Oh,
it's not under a recall.
This is software.
It's not a bad accelerator pedal.
It's very scary.
Whoa.
Toyota has had.
Toyota has this accelerator problem
we've all heard about.
I have many models of Prius that got
recalled,
but I have a new model of didn't get
recalled.
This model has an accelerator that goes
wild,
but only under certain conditions have
cruise control.
And I can repeat it over and over again
safely.
Whoa.
That's fucking terrifying.
That's what's the greatest thing about
old cars.
Old Cars are fucking terrible to drive
like my old 1970 Barracuda.
Yeah.
But there's,
there's something about old cars where
there's no computer running.
Nothing was like a direct experience
between you and the engine.
You know what I'm saying?
Like those old,
the old sound of the engine,
everything about it connected to the
car.
It was all connected.
There ain't no fucking computer is going
to save you bitch.
It's just a car.
You better not get crazy but better.
I think you can,
you know,
take that turn to too quick and you
know,
the wheels will lock up on the outside
so you'll be all right.
No you're fuck man.
That's not gonna save you one of the
many reasons
not to buy a prius.
You know,
it's really interesting.
Um,
I think it was a prius that they did.
They did this because a priest is a
hybrid,
right?
Yes.
Yeah.
There was a prius.
Then they took a prius.
This is what they did.
This on top gear.
That fucking awesome car show on the BBC
if you haven't seen it.
So you can get it on BBC on like do you
get direct TV?
They have like BBC America and it's a,
it's an awesome car show and they did
this test with a.
took a prius and they ran around a track
as fast as it could go as fast as they
could get it to go around the track and
they followed it with a bmw m three,
which has a big Vat and they found out
that all the BMW,
all BMW had to do was to stay at the
same pace as the Prius.
Just keep up with it.
That's all it had to do.
Well when they measure the miles per
gallon,
the BMW got more miles per gallon in the
Prius.
It's like when you drive it fast,
it looks like it's a piece of shit.
It's like yeah,
that's your reasoning.
There's no reason to.
And the long run,
the price also costs so much more money
that you'll be spinning on the car that
it's not even worth the money you save
on their gross look into.
And it was.
I think they said it was like the
difference between like the Prius was
only getting like 14 miles to the
gallon.
The BMW got like 17 or 18.
Yeah.
By the way,
I posted a number of Steve Wiszniak
video has posted at my twitter,
which is backslash red band.
I'm going to retweet,
retweet,
fucking know how we do and what's
awesome.
We're talking about the IPAD now,
so a manufacturer a that's going to fix
I pads.
He has a company that fixes i-phones
fixes like a third party warranty guy.
Could you tweet that?
Yeah,
I just thought,
well you just gotta you just gotTa do it
now.
Oh,
that's it.
Just because you're using that.
I'll go to my twitter page to how you're
supposed to do it.
That's gross.
And your twitter page if you don't use
tweet deck,
man,
you live in.
So 2000.
I don't tweet that much.
Oh yeah.
Whatever lies.
I forgot what I was saying.
Yeah,
because you're stoned.
Oh,
so this ipad manufacturer that is going
to fix it pads,
he fixes iphones.
Just got a shipment.
Every placement bezels for the IPAD.
So if he ever has to replace that and it
has a spot for a camera in it and that
the software has caused to a camera and
all those other things.
So the IPAD,
they might not even be done with the
Ipad,
like it's going to come in with a camera
and all these other things.
Probably that's what it looks like.
So this is just the beginning.
So the first one is just this plane.
The first one was not finished as well.
A lot of people are thinking like it was
like a prototype because that's why it's
two months away and stuff.
They were still really.
This is all,
this sounds like some fucking
conspiracies type marketing shit to
probably think probably.
Why would you do that though?
Why would you release a crappy one or
you get a crappy ones?
You were going to be talking about it
every time there's a new rumor,
you know,
like,
oh now it has a.
well maybe they'll hold off for a few
months and then come up with a version
two.
Maybe they'll do that.
But if there are any doing anything like
the iphone,
it's probably once a year down man.
They got people that bitches.
Apple has more people that are bitches
and than any other company in the world.
Did you see the spice shot of the next
iphone?
Which is funny because I was just
thinking how I'm a little bit of an
apple bitch.
I'm going to be honest with you.
They got me a little while.
I get all fucking hyped up when I fly
out to have a new announcement.
I get fired up and I don't remember the
last time I ever got fired up for
anything that Microsoft makes a.
it's funny because these photos that get
released like this photo,
the next iphone is so awful.
It could be just like a box on the
ground and it's like people are freaking
out about this.
You know what's really funny?
People?
What does that.
That is what people are hilarious about.
That looks like an iphone man.
People retarded.
I know who gives a shit whether you use
windows or Mac,
everybody gets nutty.
That's what's really crazy about all
this shit is that people pick teams,
you know,
they're on team windows or Mac.
Like what the fuck do you care?
Like really?
You want to.
Why do,
why does everybody want to using the
same shit?
It's,
if you don't prefer it,
that's fine.
I don't give a fuck and taken pictures
and had a picture online,
you know,
have me on a laptop and you see the
little apple thing.
Oh Joe,
what the fuck do you know you use Mac so
gay.
Like what?
You're upset at the choice of computer.
I make weird what?
I'm on the wrong computer team.
Really?
We have computer teams.
We team up for everything.
We are fucking dumb.
God Damn.
People are dumb.
We argue over fucking operating systems.
People get mad if you choose the wrong
brand of car.
Like there's dudes would get mad at
their buddies for buying Chevy's the
fuck bro.
Ford for life,
for life bro.
We were Ford for live dumb assholes.
They have like the picture of the Calvin
and hobbes peeing on the Chevy logo.
You know,
and it's weird thing.
There's just certain things that are
like,
like coke and Pepsi,
Pepsi,
what the fuck?
What the fuck is wrong with?
Is there a definitive difference between
the two of them?
Who Fountain when you go to like a sub
shop and he ran the fountain.
That could be anything.
Diet coke,
diet coke.
It's like there's a certain amount of
sweetener,
a certain amount of color and just shut
the fuck up and drank it.
That's pig slop,
man.
That's some shit.
You only drink because you're starving
or you're drunk.
Motherfuckers.
People are so God damn dumb.
US included sometimes,
but not as much.
Not as much as last year.
Moving forward for the future.
Always trying to evolve.
Hey,
how you see that video of this?
Somebody filmed at the space shuttle
blowing up.
Yeah.
It's pretty trippy.
Those two old George,
weird,
dire trouble
growing up in the.
When it exploded
in this guy and started spinning around
separate pieces.
That's not trouble.
Brian.
The Usual Jimminy cricket.
I know I'm never going to get in
trouble.
You've got to go to school.
Come here and that trouble in this guy.
What a horrible,
tragic handkerchief
feed the woman.
Not to belittle the challenger,
exploding.
I remember I was watching that.
I was at this girl's house.
I was like,
it was 1986,
so I was.
It wasn't any sex like 19 years old.
Completely lost it.
No idea what I was doing my life.
I had a hard time getting laid.
Very difficult.
So this ex girlfriend who lived like an
hour and a half away and I was talking
on the phone and we're talking dirty and
she wanted me to drive up to visit her
and it was such a fucking long drive and
it was the winter.
It was snowing out and I'm an idiot and
I went out there and
completely forgot what I was talking
about.
How high am I work out and you're
watching challenger,
so what?
So we're sitting there and we're sitting
there in front of the television in the
morning and she goes to the bathroom and
I turned on the TV and right when I
turned the TV it fucking exploded.
It was that second.
Wow.
Right when I turned on the TV,
they were showing it and I don't know if
it was a replay,
I don't think it was.
It's hard to remember,
but I remember like very clearly at the
moment I turned on the TV,
the image of the thing exploding,
what's happening right there,
and you were seeing spiral and you're
like,
what the fuck is that?
It was like a weird,
like,
what is that?
What's going on over there?
And then people started talking about it
and then it took a while before they
just flat out admitted,
okay,
everybody's dead.
Like that shit just blew up.
Like I think for awhile they were like
wondering whether or not the people that
survived,
if the capsule it made it to the ground,
you know,
they're looking for parents,
shoots and shit.
It was all sorts of different kinds of
reports.
But I remember thinking,
Holy Shit,
those people just got shot through the
fucking air and exploded in the sky.
What a crazy way to go.
What a crazy thing to do.
No,
it's so weird.
When I saw it,
I saw it with a bunch of people and we
all had to watch tv because we were in
middle school and it happened and to
start crying and I just remember like,
oh,
what's going on?
And the teachers were all freaking
because you couldn't like just text your
mom like,
hey mom,
do you know what happened?
So you have to get like these birds and
tight messages to a man who swift to
foot knows the way home quickly run some
amazing how back in the day you just had
no communication with friends and family
and you call people and if you've got a
hold of them,
you got a hold of them.
Yeah.
Have you didn't mean it must've been so
easy to get away with everything back
then.
Oh,
everything.
I was thinking about having a second
where you were.
When I was a teenager,
I would have sex in public places
because I went.
I wasn't allowed to have sex at home,
so I'd go to like behind little Caesar's
and fuck behind beside the dumpster.
And one time this guy came out and was
like shocked.
Like he worked at these places,
he goes,
Oh,
I'm sorry you want some pizza?
Because he thought we were homeless,
but I'm thinking nowadays you on the
ground laying on her and it was just
like God,
but now ground on the dirt dude.
We used to do it in movie theaters,
theaters all the time.
Or I could just get her to like climb on
top and he goes to fern.
Golly,
you know,
because no one else was there during the
day watching fern gully.
But you're in the back half the fern
gully having sex.
But nowadays,
can you imagine I can't do that because
it will be filmed and on youtube done on
youporn because like everyone just
filming and I wonder if kids are having
a hard time finding places to have sex
without cameras are being back.
Yeah,
it's not,
it's not like nasty.
They know what's really fucked up is
this whole sexting thing with young
kids.
And what's happening if you don't know,
is that these young kids are sending,
you know,
you give a 13 year old cell phone.
They're going to take pictures of their
dicks to girls.
Girls are going to take pictures of the
posters.
The boys,
it's musical girl.
There's always going to be one freak
bitch in the class.
It's willing to take it to the next
level.
All right.
There's always one girl whose dad was
not around and she needs male attention
and she needs it extremely bad and she's
willing to fucking logout.
We are so lucky because my shit would
have been everywhere.
There'd be live video of me just having
sex on web cams if this gets pretty
crazy,
pretty crazy.
You know?
It's just really wrong that kids,
when you're that young,
you make all kinds of fucking mistakes.
People,
they do all kinds of stupid shit.
Your dumb.
The fact that kids today,
like anything you say and do.
Back then it was like,
that shit is like a record forever.
You know,
any,
any blog you write,
any space picks you post up like that
Shit's a record of you for the rest of
your life.
You know,
and for some kids,
fuck up and pictures of them suck.
A deck.
Then some dude who ordinarily would like
really loved this chick,
but can't get over the fact that there's
this picture that every one of his
friends has of her sucking her ex
boyfriends,
cock that's online.
I think he just freaks out.
He can't fucking deal with it and that
ruins the relationship because this dude
can't deal with the fact there's a
picture online that anybody could say
where I've his wife,
the mother of his children,
supposedly someday and some other guys
deck,
especially if it's a black guy,
right?
We go back to the Julia Roberts hurt,
hurt and that black eyes,
let's be honest,
you know,
for the most part,
except for obviously Brock Lesnar,
he says that brock Lesnar was like a
white guy with black guys.
Check this shit out.
This is a great email I got today from.
Listen man,
we're in a very tricky subject.
Just interrupt me when I'm talking about
genetics,
black people,
until I clarify that I'm not a racist.
How dare you.
It's very important because going to go
into another medical thing,
it's a funny thing that you would think
that people would think that,
uh,
like saying that a black guy having a
bigger deck.
I'm black,
I've been better sexually and you know,
more,
more troublesome to white dudes.
You why?
How would that be racist?
Wouldn't that be like positive for black
eyes?
Could you imagine what people are saying
that about you racist?
He's digging,
but there's a lot of people that if you
say that,
if you put it that way,
like there,
there's people that think that black
eyes
oversexed black lives
more well endowed.
Hold on.
Is that your page or making that noise?
What the fuck?
What the fuck got suckered
anyway,
ladies and gentlemen,
what we're talking about guys.
Dicks.
If you're not scared,
you're not paying attention.
Go Online.
There's some incredible fucking porn out
there where you can't believe that's
really.
That guy's dead.
How many black guy?
Because it's fake though.
Like there's a lot of them is fake and
there's a lot of them that are real
giant dicks.
There's a lot of them do.
There's some dudes like,
what's that guy's name?
Lexington steals dicks like 14 inches
long and it's like like an arm.
It's huge.
It's gigantic.
That's real snow.
White guys like that online,
you know,
because even like John Holmes,
you want to go old school.
John Holmes at a big duck,
but he was club you with it it and
stabbing me with it.
It was so big.
It never totally got hard.
It was like an elephant's trunk.
Never got hard.
It was disappointing.
He had like this super hot checks and
they were trying to suck his dick,
but he was on heroin doubt with this
giant rubber monster.
Dick has trying to snake it into their
mouths.
You know?
It was never like a,
like a black guy's giant Dick Black.
I was trying to dig.
That thing's going to do south.
Done some shit's going down.
Have you been to the playboy mansion
before?
Yeah,
I was there a couple times for the
strikeforce fights.
I went there for once.
I had to do a,
a fear factor broadcast.
It was early in the morning and for a
marijuana project where you going to
told me that like everything's like so
antique,
like the old way old.
Yeah.
There's something cool about it.
I mean there's something ridiculous
about that.
They have an upgraded it and change it
for the.
But there's something kind of cool but
a.
because it really stopped thinking
about.
I mean this is just a party house,
right?
Like isn't it kind of dope that this is
the same phone from 1970?
I mean it's a fucking,
it's like a rotary phone and shit man.
You know?
Or if it's a push button phone,
I can't remember.
It's a rotary or push buttons,
but if it's pushed by some old wack ass
look and Shit,
you know.
But that's kind of cool because it makes
you part of is like,
yeah,
that's,
you know,
they should upgraded,
that's not even cool anymore.
That's shit too tired.
But there's so much history to it that
it's almost like a living museum to like
Hollywood,
you know?
I mean think about how many people
partied in that place.
You know,
that's like where James Caan was always
hanging out.
Holly shore,
pauly shore,
and fucking first is always hanging out
there.
Have you seen the biodome thing that's
been abandoned by scientists?
Remember that thing that like the movie
the biodome is all about the indoor
don't those with pauly shore,
Steven.
That's a real.
Don't know.
That's a real biodapt really?
Yeah,
and now it's like abandoned and like
they showed it and has been.
This is where they were doing
experiments with seeing people could
live together in this one.
Right.
And they abandoned it.
What happened in those experiments?
Right.
I don't know.
I thought that was a funny mood at the
time.
I thought it was silly.
It was funny.
Andrew dice clay is all the movie
forward.
Farrell,
where he's jumping off the building.
He was like my hair,
my hair back when that came out last
year.
Dice Clay.
And not that I'm not anymore,
but I am.
I am still.
I think he's hilarious.
I've got to see him.
I've got to see dyfs,
the comedy store.
So many nights go up and who was just
crushing people in the audience.
He's a nut.
He's a fun dude.
You know,
I liked this whole thing.
I like his whole,
his whole attitude,
his demeanor.
I think he's Hilarious,
but when I was a kid,
he was gigantic.
There was no comedian.
The kids were more excited about when I
was a kid then dice clay when dice
client blew up and when he started doing
like Madison Square Garden and Shit,
that's all anybody talked about.
Dude.
There was kids all day in school.
Everybody below like,
you know what's in the bowl bitch,
you know,
people would sit everywhere.
Yeah.
Something.
Everybody was doing vice clay lines.
You do a good dice.
Clay.
I've been around him so many years,
you know,
at the comedy store.
That was one of the craziest things
about being a kid and being a fan of his
and then being,
you know,
then starting to be an amateur comedian
and then,
you know,
doing,
getting paid gigs after a couple of
years and then moving to California
years and years later because that I
would go on and I would have to
introduce dice,
you know,
like the comedy store,
the way it used to work and still does.
Um,
but the way it works is each comic
brings up the next comment.
So like I got brought on stage by Martin
Lawrence.
I was one of the first time somebody
famous ever did it and you know,
he brought me on stage and I was like,
Holy Shit.
Like Martin Lawrence just said my name
and brought me.
I was like,
to me that was like a crazy deal.
Like,
you know,
see that guy on TV and movies and all of
a sudden I'm shaking his hand and now
I've got to go on stage after him and
nobody knows who the fuck I am.
But dice clay was the coolest.
That was the craziest one ever that was
like,
you know,
getting the WHO's next?
Who?
Joe Rogan,
who the fuck is Joe Rogan and I don't
remember how it said it,
but what he brought me on this date,
I was like,
Holy Shit.
Dice fucking clegg has brought me on
stage.
Like that was a.
to me that was a fun moment.
That was a crazy moment comedy.
You know,
when I was a kid,
that guy was a the most hyped up comic
ever.
Mark Gaydon?
Yes you did.
You did open up for me in.
I'm an England mark.
Hayden is going to freak out.
He keeps insisting that this mark Gaydon
guy is not him,
but whoever this guy is,
I think he's representing Mark Hayden
very well,
so I'm going to keep pretending that he
is him.
Who is Joe Rogan?
You're doing standup and CEO before the
versus.
Oh,
who is Joe Rogan?
Hmm.
Is that like how these kids are talking
these days?
Who is Joe Rogan is a new way of talking
to people.
That doesn't make any sense.
That sounds cool.
That does kind of sound cool.
You know,
what is your name dude?
Carpet version.
Who is copper version?
You know,
if that's what you say when you see
people instead of like,
Hey,
what's up dude?
Say who is Joe Rogan?
I'm I doing stand up in Colorado.
Yeah,
I'll be doing it somewhere.
I don't know how many books,
but I will definitely be there the night
before.
Whatever the uh,
I think the UFC fights or on a Sunday
night I think.
I'm not sure,
but whatever,
whatever night there on the night before
that,
whether it's a Saturday or Friday,
I'll be doing standup and I'll put it on
twitter and I'll let you bitches now.
Have you heard of the cat that was
predicted over 50 deaths in a nursing
home?
You know what that's like?
That's like predicting alcoholics are
going to drink.
That's ridiculous.
That's a terrible fucking prediction.
Tell that fucking faggot cat to go
predict.
I know it is only curls up around people
when they get to die.
Yeah,
right.
When they're about to die,
they're dying the job,
but like flies thousand years old.
They're a bunch of old people living
with other old people that are dying.
It's not a fun environment.
It just goes back to that whole weird
thing about how animals might have
sensors that we don't even know about
them and then when that video of the dog
in here,
it might be or it might be these people
are hanging on by a thread so thin that
tat hops in that last bucket that night.
Yeah,
that's possible too,
man.
You gotTa admit it's possible.
Can you discuss vaporizers?
I would recommend vaporizers.
The volcano is a very good one.
It's sometimes kind of a pain in the
ass.
I mean at the end of the day,
you don't want to be that guy that's
sucking out of a plastic bag.
It just seems like a junkie move.
I'm not a fan.
Right.
It seems like junky behavior.
Do we suck it out of a plastic bag?
Something seems wrong,
but there's another vaporizer that I
enjoy.
It's like a glass pipe,
like a,
like a glass lip,
like sort of like a bond with a tube
attached to it and you stick it on this
thing and yeah.
That's cool.
That's cool one.
You know what I like about that one?
You don't need,
you don't need like five friends around
you to get high.
You know,
like when that bag fills up,
you don't know when to stop.
Right.
You keep sucking it in and then you're
too high and then you're like,
I can't even think that's not good.
This is the other vaporizer.
You can take one hit and Bam and you
know what's up?
I liked that one better,
but if you got a party,
you've got a bunch of people hanging
around and you're all medical patients.
Many bongs.
No.
Have you got a bunch of people around
them?
The volcanoes to shit,
then it's perfect because for all being
junkies together,
man,
I suck out of this plastic bag.
It's weird.
I'll keep it together.
Yeah.
There's some weird about sucking out of
a plastic bag.
Me,
I'm just like,
you know,
like a joint.
Just give me a joint.
That's cool.
I'm a fan of the joint too,
you know.
Well I joined because,
first of all,
because you don't have to keep lighting
it.
And I hated the taste of lighter fluid.
No,
that shit's nasty.
Like if you have a glass pipe and you
keep tasting that lighter fluid.
Yeah.
That shit ain't good for you.
Especially when it's like a Zippo.
You're like,
Oh really?
You got that shit.
Ain't good for you man.
I don't like it.
I liked
joints.
I'm converted joints,
man.
I liked that shit with a match,
you know,
if I can or if I'm doing it with a
lighter,
I'd get it real quick and I'll let it
sit for a minute.
And uh,
I think there's a residue man that gets
on,
on the weed with those lighters and I
think that Shit's bad for you.
It's probably worse for you than smoking
for some people.
Like for your lungs.
It's going to be very unhealthy man.
It's like a toxic fume you're inhaling,
you know,
that ain't good.
You know,
we don't.
There's no studies done.
And you know how many times you can
fucking suck off,
lighter fluid and breathed into your
lungs and not do permanent damage,
you know,
joint bitches matches and joint stop
fucking around or go with vaporizer if
you don't know what the vaporizer is.
The beautiful thing is,
is there's no fire,
there's no smoke.
It's like a mixed.
And what it is,
is you pack the product,
the memorable and put into,
into this little filtered area.
And then you connect that to this
machine and then it heats up and then
you inhale and it's literally like
missed.
And that missed is just the pure thc.
It's a very heady experience.
It's very,
um,
like you'll come up with some of your
craziest thoughts on vaporized.
We'd,
except the only thing crazier is eating
when you eat it.
That's the craziest.
I don't like that anymore.
Eating.
It gets scary.
We've talked about that overheard of
nutmeg.
Man.
Your Mama.
Oh one.
Oh eight,
nine.
Three.
Yeah.
I heard you can get high off nutmeg
somehow or another one of the guys are
message board hr.
I think he did it.
He tried it and documented it.
He said it was really tripping.
It lasted a long time and it's kind of
gross.
I think anything that's really good
people would be doing it left and right.
And I think there's plenty of shit to
get high on.
You know,
we don't.
But the one thing that I think is
interesting,
they came up with a new marijuana.
It's a synthetic marijuana and it gives
you like the same effects as regular
marijuana,
but you don't test positive.
Yeah.
And they're trying.
They're scrambling right now to make it
illegal and they call it two.
It's called k named after that mountain.
And it's a synthetic version of
marijuana.
So if you have,
if you're a cop,
if you have a government job and you
have to piss tests all the time,
you could smoke.
Does Shit.
I used to in Ohio had the piss tests all
the time.
I need to go to the store and buy the
shit.
And it was scary when we be keeping pots
for cops from smoking weed,
if anybody should be smoking weed,
it's cops.
If anybody what?
Cops should be smuggling weed.
Cops should be smoking weed.
Fuck yeah.
The people that I'm down,
everybody calm the fuck down.
These are like intense people on.
We'd like to be a cop.
You kind of have to get like a bully,
like stuff.
I know a lot of guys so became
cops and a lot of them became cops
because it's good money and they're
tough guys.
They do martial arts and they figure,
you know what?
I can handle most situations.
I'm pretty friendly.
I can handle this.
This is good money.
It's a good career.
I could set myself up,
have a nice pension.
You got to look at it.
Realistically people look at it as it's
an economic choice for a lot of people.
Know I have a lot of buddies that became
cops.
It's an economic choice.
They just.
There's a lot of people did a great job,
man.
If you can get into Boston police
department
is.
That's good.
Fucking money.
You can make a nice living.
You know,
you can get some,
some detail work on the side,
you know,
and weekends and shit like that.
You pick up big money,
no guardian places and shit like that,
and it's a good job,
man.
It's not all Douche bags,
but there's a lot of douchebags that
work for better cops that if they were
stone would be horrible,
man.
Maybe they'd be more sensitive.
We're not for everyone,
that's for sure.
It's not.
They don't have to do it,
but I think if they wanted to,
they wanted a male out of the weekend,
like Serpico memory when Serpico got
high back in the seventies,
so have a go.
Didn't have.
They didn't have a drug test for Shoboko
Albert,
you know,
and he was a cop who's just walk away
with
girl hanging out just like that movie
superfly.
That's remember.
Yeah.
I've never seen super fine.
You never seen
superfly ladies and gentlemen,
if you ever watched one blacksploitation
movie from the seventies,
it should be super fly.
It's one of the most God damn brilliant
film to have ever been created.
And when you're high it becomes a mother
fucking masterpiece because it's real.
I mean,
this is a real move where they're
playing off real cool cats and one,
one time this guy says,
you know everything he's thinking about
getting out of the game.
I got off the thing.
I ever
bonded my hall,
my vines,
a white woman like you,
my hall,
my vines of white with my hall,
my car,
my vines,
my clothes and white women like you.
Wow.
It's genius,
Dude.
It's hilarious.
It's such a bad movie.
It's so fucking good.
It's so bad.
And so you could take a parody like
airplane and they'll be funny but
they'll never be as funny as something
that's supposed to be good but isn't an.
It's funny on accident.
There's something about those that it's
like a different kind of funny.
You know what I mean?
Like a holy shit funny.
Like what the fuck were they thinking?
Funny,
you know,
and superfly is one of the best of that.
Like sort of like showgirls is
showgirls,
you see showgirls and it's like,
what the fuck are they doing?
Like this movie crazy.
You know,
it's one of them.
What other movies are like that?
I just can't believe some movies from
the eighties.
I just can't believe people actually
bought like the Howard,
the duck maybe.
I'm like,
are you serious?
Your cartoon or I'm a comic book goes
Marvel Comics.
I know.
I can't believe he was cool in the
seventies and the eighties to when I was
a kid.
I was a Howard.
The duck fan.
I would have by Howard.
The duck books.
Yeah,
it's weird.
I was a marvel comics fan and Howard the
duck was a big part of marvel comics who
had drifted in and out all sorts of
comic books.
They did a lot of cool shit with Howard
the duck.
I saw that movie theater and it was
great because I was a kid and he was
like.
I remember he pulled out condoms,
condoms to the Howard.
The duck was cool when I was a kid
because he was a duck,
but he was an adult.
He would.
He was like a creepy duck,
you know,
just trying to get laid.
I never read it.
That was the Douglas Dope.
I was a huge vitamix.
Spiderman mostly.
I love the x
men.
I love Spiderman.
The whole goes a big hug fan.
A big Conan the barbarian fan got
download,
loved in,
you know,
I wish someone would have done.
Someone will do a real cone and like
almost in the style of gladiator,
you know what I'm saying?
Like a real high end,
not a cheese ball one.
I think they're doing another one,
but it seems,
I don't know,
it's got the rock in it.
I hate to be prejudiced coney island now
and there's an image of him as cone and
I mean he certainly looks the part and
who knows,
but maybe he could pull it off,
but there's a certain amount of movies
when you do a certain amount of kids
movies,
you know,
after awhile I just felt like it's hard
for me to watch you and something where
you're crazy,
you know,
is making crazy money and still did
good.
Fake aggression.
Conan the barbarian.
If you ever read the book,
awesome.
That was a big fan of the books.
This Guy Robert e Dot Howard,
wrote him and he was just mad genius who
super depressed wrote all these books
and I think he was only like 36 when he
blew his fucking brains out.
Just couldn't take it anymore.
I just lived a terrible life,
lived at his mother,
was super depressed apparently,
and just wrote these incredible fantasy
books about,
you know,
far off lands and a fucking crew could
not be beat,
would destroyed cut men down,
fight monsters,
shit and all fucking all these chicks
and drinking wine.
And it just,
he was just a,
like a human but yet hyper human
character that represented all this
guy's frustrations.
Fucking genius shit man.
You know,
especially if you think about the fact
that God was writing in the fifties,
you know,
and then by the time they made it a
movie,
you know,
Arnold Schwarzenegger was like,
Damn,
dude,
why are you so much?
That's ridiculous.
You know what's,
what's the reason for that?
That's not cold in Canada there's a
tournament is more like a,
uh,
George St Pierre type build.
Did you like to.
That's how the gay more like,
um,
James Irvin's build that would be a good
corner,
like thick,
but it looks like an athlete,
you know,
like a Herschel Walker.
Herschel Walker.
How about that motherfucker?
Forty seven years old.
Dude has his first MMA fight beat to
shit ass.
I'm young boy.
Hershel Walker's 40 fucking seven dude.
And he looks like a Goliath.
He's still just swole as fucking
chiseled and just cut and dudes down.
That guy's a suit.
That's a super athlete.
They should be saving his DNA.
I don't know how many kids that guys
have.
How many kids do you have?
Kids have no idea.
If he doesn't have kids they need to get
the guy shoots him loads into some cops
for sure.
Right?
Don't you think?
Get Him.
You imagine if you got Herschel Walker
and one of the Williams sisters and,
and,
and they fell in love and I mean,
I don't know.
No disrespect to her.
So I believe he's married and I don't
know if the Williams sisters are
married.
So let's just hypothetically make that
and not in the real world is the fake
world.
Nobody got upset,
but I'm saying,
you know,
you get to super athletes like that and
put their genetics together.
It'd be incredible.
Incredible.
Like you ever know who Lucy a riker is
lucy a rikers,
a female boxer.
This chick could punch like harder than
men.
She was incredible.
She was so good.
All the other female boxers avoided the
fuck out of her.
This is back in the Tonya harding days.
This chip was like leaps and bounds
above other female boxers.
She was just a freak athlete,
right.
I don't remember what nationality she
was.
I feel like I want to say something,
something Latin American or so,
but she was from Holland,
but I don't remember what her
nationality.
I'm totally guessing she was a a dark
skinned chick,
but God damn it was just this fucking
freak athlete.
Just beat the fuck out of church.
She even fought dudes.
She got flatline though.
She fought a dude and the dude
connected.
Our John just.
She went in [inaudible] 99 and it was
weird to see him because she was at
attacking.
She was trying to cut this dude down and
they do just bang and she just flatline,
stiffened up and face planted.
But it looked like before the flat line,
like she was getting the best of the
dude.
The dude just hit too hard.
There's a thing about bone structure.
I think,
you know,
like if you.
One of the things,
if you meet someone,
meet a guy like this,
like a big puncher,
like I met Michael Moore once.
Michael Moore was the boxing heavyweight
champion of the world.
And uh,
he was uh,
the light heavyweight champion at one
time too,
for a long time.
It was bad ass as a light heavyweight.
I just couldn't keep cutting the way he
was too big,
but it was like one of the best light
heavyweights ever.
But he's got like a frame,
like,
you meet that dude.
He's like frame.
It's heavy,
you know,
his fists are heavy shoulders heavy.
That's the type of dude when he hits
you,
it's just,
there's so much.
There's so much to him,
you know what I'm saying?
And a check.
Even if a chicken is really talented,
ultimately they're not built the same
way,
you know,
so it just makes you think like a chick
like that,
like a Lucier,
weicker,
you know,
matching her up with like an Anderson
Silva,
some other freak athlete,
you know,
God damn,
I sound like some sort of a genetic
engineer.
I'm trying to make future warriors.
It's going to happen.
It is going to kind of be like,
well,
you know what's going to happen?
It's going to happen in a laboratory
before it's going to happen with two
people having sex.
Sex is not going to happen the old
fashioned way with the gladiator meets
the warrior princess.
It's not gonna happen like that.
The way it's going to happen now is you
know you're going to,
someone's going to take the attributes,
you're going to get some fat,
dumpy dude,
you know who's,
who's got a little Dick,
but he's got a lot of money because he's
crazy and he's invested all of his time
to learning the stock market and
swindling people and he's going to have
children that are like psychotic warrior
genius offspring because he's going to
like manipulate all his shitty genes and
it's gonna create some super offspring
and wanting to fucking his young wife
and killing him coming in.
Yeah.
Brock Lesnar is Kona.
That would be a real conan.
Yeah,
that's a real cool.
And that's exactly what I'm talking
about.
Like Brock Lesner is like somebody put
that up there.
Whoever put that up there,
we lost her money in Japan.
Yeah,
yeah.
Money.
Japan.
That's you're correct sir.
That's the perfect bill.
That's what you talking about.
Just a big giant motherfucker doesn't
look like a bodybuilder.
Looks like a dude.
He'll smash you.
You know,
like the best fighters.
I don't want to say all of them,
but most of them don't.
Look that ripped,
you know,
I think when you accept George St
Pierre,
he's fucking chiseled,
but like Bj,
when he is in as best shape,
he still has like a good layer of fat on
him.
And Bj I think also has thick skin too.
I think that's one of the reasons why Bj
doesn't cut that easy.
You know,
nobody,
nobody's got a tougher facing in Bj,
Bj and will fight like a fire round
fucking war and commander,
there were a couple of scratches,
like it's crazy,
you know,
I mean,
and they just,
that he's,
he's fucking awesome.
Which it is.
I mean,
he is,
but there's something about that dude's
genetics,
you know,
everybody's there.
Everybody's got different genetics.
So that's one of the most amazing things
about life is the variation amongst
human beings.
I mean,
we vary so much more than any other
animal.
If you look at like the only animal that
comes close is dogs and dogs supposedly
are like that because we engineered
them,
which makes you wonder what the fuck
made so many people so different because
we vary so much.
I mean,
the,
the fact that,
uh,
Chinese midget could have sex with
Shaquille o'neal and make another baby
and that baby would look a combination
of those two and there's that much
variation between pygmies and women from
Iceland,
you know,
in like a muscle tones,
ex wife Bridgette Nielsen,
that big giant Icelandic Nordic look and
check,
you know,
that,
that her and flavor flave they can have
babies,
you know,
and they can.
I mean,
they're so different.
There's so much diversity.
There's no other animal like that except
dogs,
you know,
rhinos that looked like rhinos.
You know what I'm saying?
Some fish look different and they,
you get a small mouth bass flux or a
large mouth bass.
They get crazy to get freaky with it,
you know,
and you get a hybrid that's possible.
Tigers and lions make loggers,
but for the most part,
man,
human beings are.
We're the most diverse world,
weird fucking species.
It's kind of incredible to,
when you think about the fact there's so
many of us,
we think there's so many humans.
You would think by now,
we'd all be a big fucking blurry mess.
It's crazy when you see like countries
like Asian countries where almost
everyone has a very similar appearance,
you know,
almost everyone has dark hair.
Almost everyone is,
you know,
within a certain height rates changing.
Now I get Japan and making big giant
dudes now.
Big giant athletic dudes.
A lot of them are changing their diet
too.
I think it has something to do with
that.
Have you,
you motherfucker.
What kind of showing running here,
man,
the phone rang and how dare you.
How dare you,
you do you do.
What does this kind of fish I fuck talk
ladies and gentlemen.
What does that mean?
Or I shouldn't encourage that guy's
pocket.
Not encouraging him.
Joe,
talk about Nibiru folks.
I'm going to tell you right now and the
bureau is not going to save you.
Okay?
It's not happening.
It's not.
It's a myth.
Not In the beer was a mess.
I don't know if the bureaus are true,
but there's some.
This is something that we have in our
head about someone coming down and
fixing everything.
And uh,
I don't think their shit's happening.
I think we're looking for daddy to come
down and throw down the rescue boat and
pull us out of this mess and I think
that's why people look at,
if you don't know what Nibiru this,
there's people that,
there's people that believe that there's
a planet that's in an elliptical orbit
and every 3000,
600 years it travels between Mars and
Jupiter travels like very close to earth
or between us and Mars rather.
And this gigantic huge planet is
responsible for many,
many catastrophic events in Earth's
history.
And it's also responsible for these
beings called the Annunaki to come from
this planet and go on earth and create
human beings with genetic engineering.
I mean,
it's some fascinating shit.
It's all from the Sumerian text in the
Sumerian texts is the oldest known
written language.
It's like,
it's called uniform and they write it
and he's like little weird strokes.
And they,
the,
they're one of the oldest civilizations
that we know of.
They had the first,
uh,
astronomy,
the first astrology,
including they had detailed depictions
of the solar system with planets in all
the right orbits.
They had like Mars and Pluto even had
pluto,
we didn't know about Pluto until 1970
and they had a drawing of Pluto that was
carved into stone or that was rolled
into a tablet 6,000
years ago,
5,000
years ago.
I mean,
it's really,
really crazy stuff.
And when this guy,
Zacharias [inaudible],
and this is where it gets controversial
because some guys who are scholars who
are a language scientists and guys who
are archaeologists breaking down ancient
languages and trying to figure out the
roots of the word,
they don't necessarily believe that
citizens.
Right.
And I think that maybe he's leaped leapt
to some conclusions and his depictions.
Oh,
it's,
I don't know.
I'm,
I have no knowledge when it comes to
foreign languages.
So I don't understand the argument.
No.
So I,
I see it back and forth and I.
It's fascinating to me.
It's interesting.
You can't prove it.
Who the fuck knows?
But what is interesting is that culture,
the Samarian culture is crazy.
They had the first,
everything,
the first mathematics,
they had the first use of the wheel.
What the fuck bro.
Shut you shit off man.
How dare you anyway.
Who the fuck knows what's more
fascinating than this idea of a planet?
Because there's not enough evidence that
there is another planet,
but there is enough evidence that these
people,
back then 6,000
years ago,
had some amazing view of the world.
They had some amazing technology they
had.
They knew about the DNA,
the double helix of the DNA that was
there.
Their signed for medicine.
They're signed for pharmacy.
They,
uh,
they drew a caduceus,
which they still use today as a sign of
medicine.
That's crazy shit,
man.
They,
they had all these depictions of a,
there was like large people with small
people in their labs and the small
people had tails.
And you know,
the,
the people that look at these goals,
look,
this is genetic engineering,
the giants they made in the monkey to
the,
the DNA of the alien.
They created this hybrid.
Maybe.
Maybe they're just drawn a fucking big
guy with a monkey on his lap and make
the monkey like curious George and
looked like a person.
You know,
what the fuck man,
how do you,
how can you tell me that?
That's exactly what that doesn't mean.
It could be like their cartoon.
There's their little character.
This is the crazy monkey.
Looks like a human once asked stupid
questions,
sit in my lap and that could be it.
Right?
I forgot what your.
I can't bitch.
You don't even pay attention to me
anymore.
He goes so deep into stuff that like
halfway through I'm like,
alright,
this is my brain is I can't even catch
up anymore.
To be honest with you.
Half the time I don't know what I
started talking about.
By the time I get to the end,
what I found is
that I'm a conduit,
ladies and gentlemen.
These thoughts come to me and I just
have let a girl that's sort of sounds
faggy.
That sounds completely factored,
but that really is the truth.
You know,
the better I get at comedy,
the more I feel like I'm not really
responsible for what I'm doing.
It's like I got to just do the work.
I got to write and I got to perform
enough,
but when I get it,
when I nail it,
whatever it is that when I tuned back
into the frequency,
whenever it is,
I just ride it.
It's like it's,
it's almost like the easiest thing in
the world.
It's like it's difficult to maintain.
It's you got to maintain your enthusiasm
and maintain your writing and maintain
your performing,
but when you're in that groove,
when you lock in and it's the fucking
show,
it's fun.
When that's going on,
that's just a ride.
You just ride the ride.
You're not,
you're not doing anything.
I don't feel like it's like if I dig a
hole in the dirt in the backyard,
I feel like I just did something.
You know?
I started at fucking hole.
It sucked every day,
but I got to the end.
I get this feeling of satisfaction when
I got off stage.
I never had like a feeling of
satisfaction.
I always have a feeling of Ooh,
that was crazy.
Was like our road something.
Like I just got off a crazy ride.
You know?
You don't know.
Like I'd be like,
wow,
that was fun,
or that was,
that was cool.
That was great audience.
But I never feel like I just did
anything.
I always feel like I just wrote a crazy
ride,
you know,
that's what it feels like.
Know,
it's like you have to do it enough so
that you're comfortable enough so that
when you get up it's all smooth,
you know,
and it's all fun.
You know,
what you're talking about,
you know,
what you want to say,
and you're working on what you want to
say all the time so that it's always
fresh,
so it's always relevant in your mind.
So then who's the asm is there and it
didn't do zasmine is there,
and then the audiences enthusiastic and
then you lock to those things together
and then you just ride it.
Once you get the laugh,
start going,
you just start writing it so much fun.
It's like you're skiing downhill.
I think you're going to get a segway on
your lap.
If you live in mountains,
you can be like,
oh,
I've be to jump off right quick.
I had a crazy Jaguar dream last night,
man.
I had a dream that jaguars big ones.
We're trying to break into my house.
I'm having very strange apocalyptic
dreams lately.
No,
not,
not serious ones because I survived the
apocalypse.
The retail apocalypse dream who's ever
the end had been having dreams pretty
much at all lately or ones once.
I remember for some reason.
Yeah.
I get every now and then I get these,
the system fails dreams,
you know,
every now and then like some mad max
type shit.
Maybe it's just because all these
assholes are screaming,
the sky is falling.
You know,
one of the things that's really
interesting,
I was listening to some recordings of
hunter s Thompson speaking at the
University of Colorado and it was like
1974 and he was talking about,
you know,
like the car,
which is like supposedly the group of
people that control the world,
you know,
the global bankers,
the Bilderberg group,
that type of shit.
And he was talking about,
uh,
you know,
like what's going on overseas and what
the United States is up to and how
corrupt the political system is and how
it's probably,
you know,
if it goes this way much longer,
the country is going to fall apart,
but then you look at it like 30 years
later,
it's still the same shit.
It's still the same shit.
It's like,
is it getting any worse?
Well,
there's more people,
so it seems to accelerate a little bit
because there's more activity,
there's more humans,
but it all seems to be going along the
same lines.
You know,
and this,
the sky is falling crazy shit like
really mean what takes something big
man.
And if it takes something big,
you're probably going to be dead anyway.
This guy is really gonna be following.
It takes like a meteor.
We need like a volcano,
like yellow stone,
which by the way,
ready for this.
This is January 17th.
There's been over 1,600
earthquakes in yellowstone.
What the fuck is common?
If you don't know yellowstone is a giant
volcano.
See,
nobody ever taught me this in school.
They ever teach you this in school.
Do you remember this?
Yeah.
Do you get the Caldera?
What would the.
The whole volcano thing with then it's
going to blow up.
I think it's weird when you live there
too.
It's like a lot of people can't live
with it because they're in constant fear
of it too.
I've heard.
How could you not?
I forget who it was.
I think it was a Adam Corolla or
somebody or was talking about when I was
in high school.
I know.
Well I'm older than you.
How old you?
A $30.
Shh.
Don't tell these people though.
They're cruel from seven.
I'm seven years older than you.
So you have to think about like if we
were in high school,
like I was in high school earlier than
you.
They probably didn't even know yet
because one of the things they found out
about with these,
um,
yellowstone is a,
they had satellite images and when they
took the satellite images,
that's when they realized that what they
were dealing with was a called era,
which was a volcano.
That was so explosive that the top
literally disappeared,
like be like Hawaii,
but Hawaii fucking explodes and it's
just flat.
I mean that's how big this volcano is.
It's 300 miles across.
That's insane.
And when it blows up,
you imagine 300 miles of explosion
straight up into the air.
Everything will be okay here or will be
fucked.
The whole continent would be fucked.
We'd be fucked.
But we would have like,
like a good,
like one hour slow lava or no,
it wouldn't be
lava.
You'd be fucked because the ash wood rat
and fuck everything up.
It would kill animals.
It would.
It would pollute the water supply.
So what way would fuck everything you
think about it?
How much it was?
It's like heavy,
heavy [inaudible] is like snow.
Okay.
Except it's much heavier.
So rooms would collapse.
So you would get like,
you know,
two,
three feet of certain that would come
down.
And even if you stayed inside your house
and relax,
your house would very likely get crushed
from this fucking sit because there's
certainly thousands and thousands of
pounds on your roof.
So it's going to cave your fucking house
and you can't breathe outside.
The sky is filled with cert you don't
understand everywhere and it's heavy,
thick shit.
Volcanic ash,
soot.
You're fucked.
And it covers the continent.
It comes over us.
Like I said,
the volcano.
How long does it.
Do you have any?
They don't have any idea.
Well,
they know that there's been smaller ones
where it's just killed a lot of things.
And then there's been these gigantic
earth shattering ones every six to
800,000
years.
And the last time there was one with
600,000
years ago.
What if it was something like,
it wouldn't hit you for like a week and
say you just get out and people will
segue there going,
fuck,
would you do.
You'd have to leave the continent yet.
Well,
I think you could be okay if you could
get off in North America to Europe.
Even if you knew that shit was going
down and you could get on a plane and
fly to England,
just take your family and a crazy movie.
A evacuating the whole United States.
Well,
you know,
there's a,
there's a rock shelf in Africa,
um,
that if it breaks off like it's,
they have these underwater,
uh,
these underwater landslides occur with
these big shelves of these mountains
fall off and it's happened thousands of
times throughout history.
Well,
if this one particular rock flat,
this,
this whole area which they predict one
day we'll break off and go into the,
the ocean is one particular side of a
mountain.
If it does that,
it's gonna repeat a gigantic tsunami
that engulfs the whole east coast of the
United States,
like miles in.
It's just going to just miles in water.
I mean,
just a gigantic chunk of raw pouring
into the ocean and these fucking waves
that are like a mile high.
So it's going to roll in wreck
everything.
It's going to be insane.
Or it's just gonna be mildly irritating
to be insane.
It's going to be insane and it's
probably gonna happen.
Yeah.
You know,
it might not happen in our lifetime,
but the,
but you can't say it was so against it.
So not though they probably are.
There's so many things,
but there's so many things.
Do there's so many different things.
The odds aren't against it.
If you look at all of them together,
the odds aren't against it because if
you look at like meteors,
man,
they don't know when the fuck those are
coming.
They have no idea how many asteroids are
out there,
how many big chunks of fucking rock and
metal and iron are flying through space
in any one of those Kojak us and they've
happened so many times over history.
It's been proven.
There's so many planets that are
scattered with craters.
There's no way we can predict it.
There's,
I mean they could monitor the sky and
hope they catch most of them,
but there's always ones that are
sneaking right bias that we miss and
it's happening left and right man.
Well,
when you black,
what the fuck?
That's the government man.
Can you guys still hear us well?
Let's start recording.
Hm?
Well,
refresh your browser.
Refresh that.
I don't even know what the fuck we're
talking about.
This is interrupted math.
Hello?
Ladies and gentlemen.
A long time scale.
Everything is inevitable.
Yeah,
that's,
that's really,
dude.
Just nailed it on the head.
That guy money,
Japan again,
money,
Japan for the wind and motherfuckers
raise money to have two good quotes.
He,
if he listened to that one is money,
money,
money.
And if you talked to Eddie about being
in Japan and how cool it was.
No,
he just got back last night.
I haven't seen him yet.
I would love to get to Japan and he,
um,
he's been to Japan,
but though he,
when he used to work for pride,
what am I in Japan.
So yeah,
a long time scale.
Everything is inevitable.
That's what people have to realize.
Like we know for sure that human beings
have a lifespan.
You're going to die as much as you plan
for the future.
It's where you're going to die.
We know that planets have a lifespan as
much as you plan for the future.
Flagging signs eventually run into
energy am I take billions of years,
but it's going to happen.
And what we have to worry about is not
just that,
not just earthquakes,
not just super volcanoes,
not just media.
We have to worry about gamma ray
explosions.
We have to worry about supernovas that
happen out in space that make these
giant gamma ray bursts and fucking flood
the earth.
Crushing all our communication systems,
crushing off satellites,
breaking everything.
No wireless Internet,
no oprah.
Everything shuts the fuck down.
I mean,
that Shit's all possible.
Giant,
crazy solar flares.
There's a lot of shit that could fuck
human beings up.
You know,
there's a lot of shit,
you know,
and they say that the polar ice caps
have shifted more than once in the past.
And they also say that 10,000
years ago,
during the last ice age,
the North American continent,
like half of it was under a mile of ice.
I mean,
North America was fucked up,
dude.
It was all ice,
you know?
I mean,
that's crazy shit.
That's only 10,000
years ago,
man.
Crazy things can happen if.
How would we stop North America from
turning all ice again?
If the earth got that cold again,
what the fuck would we do?
What we do?
Turn on the heat.
What the fuck would we do?
What would we do if all of a sudden
North America started turning into a
fucking mile high sheet wall of ice?
Odds are dinosaurs would come back
first.
Why?
Why do you say that?
I don't know why.
Listen,
Brian,
you can't give me.
That is what makes.
What makes these climate changes is very
mysterious.
Most likely have nothing to worry about.
Maybe.
Yes,
most likely,
but there's been some gigantic things
that happened to men at times.
I could.
I could freak out about that shit or I
could just be like,
hey,
let's talk about real things that are
freaking me out.
Shit.
I gotta pay my bill tomorrow and do this
tomorrow.
And I think people avoided though.
I think people.
It's not just the fact that people
choose not to think about it.
I think they typically avoid it so they
don't ever have to think about like the,
the,
the real,
the real big picture.
The real big picture is very frightening
to a lot of people.
And now there's the big picture.
Like what are you gonna do with your
life and you know you're going to get
married,
you're going to have kids going to get a
good job,
you're gonna.
Be Able to put your kids through
college.
That's the,
that's the real picture.
And then the big picture and the big
picture is what the fuck are we doing?
You know,
we're involved in two wars.
It's 2010.
This is the age of information we see
everywhere that were being fucked left
and right.
You know that your bailout money is
going to these corporations,
the corporation ceos are taking hundreds
of millions of dollars in payouts for
bonuses and all this insanity and you're
like,
what fucking bonus like that.
They used the United States tax payers
money to bail out the company and now
they get to get money.
They get bonuses,
big giant checks for what?
For fucking up.
Like what kind of a criminal
organization is this and we're accepting
it.
What the fuck is this country running
under?
That's part a of the big picture.
And then part b of that picture is what
the fuck we're in space.
That's,
that's the crazy one.
The Part B is we are,
we are on a planet and this planet is
one of an infinite amount of planets and
an infinite amount of solar systems and
an infinite amount of galaxies spread
throughout an infinite amount of space
and that space and the universe itself
may be some sort of a geometric pattern.
That model is get on this face thing.
Well,
that's the most amazing thing.
I do always get on the space now,
but it's because I get on those space
thing in life.
When I think about,
when I think about life,
when I think about anything or I think
about,
you know,
Obama talking about gays in the
military,
we must repeal,
don't ask,
don't tell.
Finally Gay people go to die too.
Like this is nuts.
Like who the fuck wants to be in the
military now at this point in time,
they're saying to them,
you know,
like,
oh look,
okay,
we need gay people.
Let's just be cool about this.
Gay people were running out of people
who want to join the military.
Let's get some gay people in it too,
right?
You know,
the military,
I think in our,
our grandparent's era,
you know,
I think they were,
they were at least less under the
illusion that they were getting fucked.
You know this,
I've talked to so many dudes that come
back and are so disillusioned.
You know,
that Pat Tillman Guy,
that's the best example ever.
There's a dude who's a NFL football star
who decides that he wants to go fight
for his country.
The nopal list of virtues.
You know,
for a man to want to represent his
country in a time of need to realize
that he has to step up.
That there are certain times in history
where men have to do things and fuck all
the glory for being an nfl player.
He's going to do the right thing and
fight for his country and he goes over
there and gets killed in friendly fire,
accidentally gets Kennedy quick,
make it work.
Crazy thing was how quickly he was
talking about how fucked up it is over
there and how disillusion he is and how
it's a mess and his brothers talking
about it and they completely incompetent
and he was talking about how just
completely unorganized it is over there
and,
and chaotic and how he didn't believe in
what he,
what he joined up for the army in the
first place.
It was,
he was being tracked and that's not what
it was.
And it was fascinating,
fascinating fucking story,
you know,
and that represents everything that's
best about America.
Like a guy who is willing to look at it
and say,
man,
I need to fucking do something.
Fuck all his football plan.
I'm going to go over there.
I want to make a difference.
And then when he gets there,
he's man enough to go,
oh shit,
this is a mess.
Like this is not what I wanted.
I'm not gonna.
I'm not going to be United States.
This bitch over there.
So this is craziness.
This is chaos.
And then
he's dead.
Which is what happens,
man.
You know,
you got to fucking war people died.
It's terrible,
but it's just at this point in time,
man,
you know,
there's gotta be better ways around
this.
There's gotta be better ways to and I
don't know what the fuck they are.
What are you doing with that shit back?
So we could see each other.
I want to read the fucking truck,
man.
They'll be going on TMZ,
you know,
but I'm looking at yours so I don't do
like that.
So we don't look at two totally
different things that are a couple of
weird geeks.
What about the ether?
Who's doing the either?
That was a good Nazan I'm getting into
Nas again lately.
Nice to move on,
man.
You should listen to a kid.
Cuddy?
No,
there's some good.
There's some good music.
I Hate Nizam.
I've overheard too much of his stuff
now.
Oh,
don't be a bitch.
She don't get sick of the same music or
I do,
but I liked.
I liked going back to it on occasion.
Yeah.
I tried to listen to Nas recently,
but it was like,
how dare you.
Kate cuddy though.
I recommend kid cuddie kid cutting.
What does kid cuddy do?
This kid cutting smooth little wrapper.
Okay.
This is the song.
Whenever I travel,
this is the move he eat a cookie like
right before you get to the airport.
So then any board,
you're not riding dirty.
You have to worry about anybody arrested
him.
He doesn't even kick in until like an
hour into the flight,
you know,
an hour into the flight,
Dan Daniel barbecued,
and then that's the best way to fly.
I mean suddenly you're operating heavy
machinery or you're going to think about
yourself.
You're going to think about life.
You can think about a lot of deep,
important shit when you're high on an
airplane.
That's the only way I travel.
This is the best way to do it,
but then when I land,
every time I land Atlanta this song,
think about yourself.
You've got to think a little deeper.
Let's.
Woops.
That's me.
There's a delay.
I don't want to listen to that.
This hip hop is dead song by now.
This is the best barbecue.
Contemplating your role,
overseeing all these different
characters.
Walking through the airport,
Dr Dre headphones on and I get it down
before I don't like this,
but I've heard it a million times.
Shit,
same shit over and over like new music.
This is the God damn
classic.
Look at this thing.
It's like Nirvana would be the.
Somebody tells me what the fuck is wrong
with ustream?
Ustream,
get it together.
People.
I know you're free.
This shit is wack.
Can I read this social stream?
Yes.
Ryan.
L Egg 10.
I can.
But uh,
here's the deal son.
We've got to keep this bitch flowing and
sometimes we're going to look at what
you have to say and sometimes we're not
know.
There's no rhyme or reason.
Don't get crazy.
Don't spam.
Let the universe that the University of
guide
just went down a notch in my book
jamming to that.
The other side I like to listen to in
all fairness,
is Jimi Hendrix.
Voodoo child.
That's another bad ass landing song.
I used to have.
That one is my main one.
I would land and listen to what the
other one is a little gay.
Tori Amos,
crucify.
I liked that song,
that song.
I like it landed in the Tori Amos House.
Heavy.
Her playing the piano.
Oh,
sexy on white sheets.
Like sheets.
She's white.
I get to see you in your car with your a
fanny pack and pack on blasting out the
Tori Amos.
Most of the time I don't drive in my
fanny pack on.
The only time I do is when I'm on the
way to the airport.
People like give the fanny pack a hard
time.
Matt Serra.
I saw you on your,
your video blog,
which is fucking hilarious.
Leading up to this week's UFC and I'm
very much looking for do you fight with
frank trigg?
But I saw you coming down with a fanny
pack,
my brother and you got to let it go.
Not Wrong with fanny pack.
Okay.
Y'All reason there is something wrong
with a fanny pack is because you know
you can't get laid if you wear a fanny
pack.
So who gives a fuck?
Anybody that want to fuck you because
you wear a fanny pack,
you don't want them.
That's what I have to say.
That's a functional piece of wardrobe.
It's excellent.
You fucking strap that bitch on right
there and you've got all your shit right
here.
It's nice.
It's right there.
You go to the airport and you take it
off.
Bam.
You walked through the metal detector.
Not saying you have to wear it every
day,
but if I were it,
fuck you man.
Fuck you.
I got a fanny pack on boy.
That shit on stage before people get all
angry.
I think it's a prop.
You sent a proud.
This is my fanny pack bench.
It seems like it would be a prop.
Yeah,
because it's very unstylish,
but guess what I'm.
The reality is I'm a 42 year old married
dude with a,
with a family trying to come at you
trying to cover.
You're not trying to fuck you.
I'm trying to walk into the airport
which is trying to cover your hog.
I'm Daniel.
We're gonna.
Have to pull that
fanny packs.
Haida bone or really well now my bone or
bitch.
Maybe your boner.
Maybe.
I guess maybe maybe it would hurt if you
had like a cell phone digging into your
deck as I like more of like a little
backpack slingbox.
It's very rare that I walk with boners
anymore though was when I was a younger
man.
Boners like,
you know,
walking through the airport for some
reason.
Just got this random boner cooking that
don't get those random boaters anymore.
I get morning loners but I'll get no
random daytime boners.
Especially if I do a lot of Jujitsu and
that's mixed Jujitsu.
Sound very gay because it kills your
boner I guess I never was.
There'll be do a lot of Jujitsu.
You're tired all the time.
Your testosterone's down,
you know you're worn out and if you get
laid all the time,
do those two things.
Keep your bonus from just occurring
randomly.
But if you're not getting laid and
you're not even working out,
you're not doing anything,
your bonus would just start firing away.
It's fuck who fucked bro.
If you're not paying attention,
have,
you know,
given your dick the proper maintenance
work.
And you know,
I had a joke that was in one of my cds
from way back,
I don't remember which one,
I think it was shiny happy Jihad.
It was a day you got to jerk off first
and then think about what you're doing.
You should always do that.
It's really important because your
biology will trick you.
Your biology will have you convinced
that you should go file some crazy girl
home,
live in a bad neighborhood and leave
your car on the,
on the corner and her cousin's going to
watch it.
Like,
why?
Because you're Horny,
you know,
you'll do some dumb shit.
You'll do some silly shit,
you know?
And if you jerk off,
you're much less likely to do any of
that.
Keep every play racquetball.
No.
That's the funny thing you say that
because I was just at a gym the other
day that had all these racquetball
courts and I was like,
that was one of the first times I've
ever seen racquetball and I was reading
a long time.
Now
you would seem like a scary racket ball
partner.
You'd be one of those,
man,
this is why I don't like my racquetball.
I've had two knee surgeries.
Yeah,
yeah.
I bet both of my acl reconstructed and
my had another a meniscus surgery on my
left knee and they work great.
Now I'm like,
I have no problem doing Jujitsu and it's
their fun and it's fine,
but I think if I did stuff like that,
like cutting back and forth all the
time,
you run the risk of injuring yourself,
you know,
Jujitsu.
I can kinda control the movements a
little bit more.
Especially if you pulled guard and he,
you know,
he control where your legs are going.
You know when you're going back and
forth like that,
you're putting a tremendous amount of
pressure on your joints and your
explosive movement like that.
It's really,
it's like,
you know,
it's,
it's an interesting thing to watch
athletically,
but like for your body eventually that
Shit's going to where the fuck out of,
you know,
what's the craziest thing,
man?
So you see like old football players,
man,
you got to respect the fucking
dedication that goes into that sport.
The amount of pain those guys have to
deal with.
Those guys get fucking clipped.
You know what I mean?
Some fucking football games that you
see,
like we see the clips on youtube where
dudes are running full steam and just
right into another dude and send him
smashing into the ground and another guy
fucking piles into it.
At the same time you're watching.
You just go,
Jesus Christ,
your body,
your fucking bond.
Just gonna get mangled.
And some of these guys like wanting
back.
So like not that big dudes.
You know these big fucking gorilla.
You're trying to get at them.
Wooo.
Football's a crazy ass game man.
You know when football will be the shit
when they can fix any injury,
anything they have,
anything that happens,
they just zap you and it's like they
have apple backup for your hard drive.
That's all we have for your life right
before you go in and do anything
dangerous.
They back up your life,
you know,
like a couple of weeks ago,
and then they reload your back into the
grid.
Like,
oh,
I'm back.
Did you die?
Die,
die,
dude,
I fucked up.
You know I got crazy.
You know,
how crazy would that be?
I mean,
look,
if you believe in like Ray Kurtzweil and
these futurists that believed that one
day we're going to be able to download
consciousness into a computer,
I mean at a certain point in time it
becomes.
The real question becomes what is
reality?
Then if your downloaded into a computer
who keeps the computer on the computers,
keep the computers on,
and then we're part of this new life,
this new world that exists inside of Huc
and machine,
and then your consciousness exists in a
machine and what happens to the original
version of your consciousness?
What does guy I have planned for you?
After you die?
Do you really go into some great well of
souls and you know,
and go to the next stage of existence.
Does that happen?
And if that does happen and you're
already downloaded into the machine,
does the well of souls except you or the
wellstone goes,
listen bitch,
I don't accept software piracy up in
heaven.
He can't be copying my shit and put it
on bit torrent down on earth and have it
all these,
you know.
C'Mon man,
you're time's up,
bitch.
It's over.
You have to move on.
You know,
maybe it doesn't accept you if there's a
version of you running this parallel
dimension,
maybe having one except you because you
gotta you gotta let go.
But that's the whole idea of living and
dying is to know that this is a stage.
Don't be greedy.
Don't try to live for a thousand years.
Just get the fuck out of here.
Go,
go,
go.
Don't download yourself.
Not makes you know,
it's almost like a kid who wants to go
down the slide and he's holding onto the
back of the slide and he wants to go
down the slide and hold on at the same
time.
Well you can't.
Did he go down a slide or you hold on,
you'd be a bitch.
So either downloads or something,
a computer live forever or you see
what's next.
Like,
like you're supposed to write.
Aubrey de Grey believes we will live
forever in biological form.
Yeah,
I've seen that guy,
that professor Aubrey de Grey Day
sleeper in 1988.
He's that crazy English dude with the
big long crazy beard who drinks a lot of
beer.
Yeah,
he's a fascinating guy.
He's a,
um,
you know,
some crazy,
mad scientist,
genius character who is working on a
changing human beings at the molecular
level level to,
uh,
to prevent aging,
the change agent and working all these
different science for our anti aging.
And the idea is that if you can survive
for a few years,
the next 20,
30 years,
so you're
likely that you could live forever,
which is really crazy.
It's just insane to think about like so
many people as it is right now,
you know?
Did you see Pandora them by the way?
Unsolicited plug here.
Hold on a second.
I'm going to grab this.
I watched this the other night on Blu
Ray.
It's called Pandora them.
And this is a movie that a con Lee is
in.
And that's,
I think how I found out about it the
first time.
And then a dude named angry Amadeus on
my message board made a post about it
and he's a pretty smart guy and he was
talking about how great it was.
I said,
all right,
fuck it.
I'll give it a try.
Like,
okay.
As an intelligent dude.
And it's a,
a space horror film and a Conley,
isn't it?
Dennis Quaid is in it and pretty God
damn fucking good movie man.
What is it?
Pretty Fun fucking movie.
It's a horror movie and space.
Kind of surprised that it didn't get
more people into it.
It was good.
What's the rotten tomatoes score?
I didn't even look.
Let's look.
The rotten tomatoes score for Pandora.
I pretty much trust that shit.
Rotten tomatoes.
Yeah,
it's pretty good.
It's pretty accurate.
Usually.
What do I think about the nexus one?
I think it's got a lot of problems now,
but once it comes to verizon,
it might be interesting to see what
happens.
I'm kind of more excited about the tour
to now.
I think what the thing about the tour
too,
which means a lot to me,
is that,
uh,
it's a world phone.
I need a world hot travel bitch.
I'm international and was saying
sometimes I'll be visiting my homies in
the UK,
Twenty eight percent tomatoes,
28 percent damn consensus.
While my approve somewhat satisfying for
devout Scifi fans.
Pandora was bloated.
Derivative plot an ultimately leaves it
drifting in space.
Okay.
I completely disagree.
Yes.
It was not perfect,
nor was avatar.
I'm not looking for perfect movies
anymore.
I'm looking for an escape.
I'm looking for some fun.
If I want to be intellectually
stimulated,
it's not going to be from your gay
fucking movie.
Okay.
It's going to be from a documentary is
going to be from some real life shit.
It's going to be from something on
space.
If I'm watching a movie,
I want crazy shit with monsters and
explosions.
I don't want to excitement and I want
some tits and that movie had all that
click on top critics and read some of
the bitch was kicking everyone's ass.
Top critics.
Yeah.
And then read some of just little blurbs
from what their reviews are because I'm
kind of interested to see if.
Because if you'd like it so much,
what they have to say about it.
Hm.
Throughout some obvious questions pop up
immediately.
Yeah,
no kidding.
Jesus Christ folks.
Lazy.
Derivative.
Perhaps.
Perhaps a bit,
but.
So what,
man?
It's like a fucking cheeseburger.
Tori Amos in soundtrack.
How dare.
Listen folks.
Yeah,
it's.
You know what?
I'm looking forward to the wolf man.
Okay.
The wolf man with Benicio del Toro's
coming out.
I know the fucking plot.
I know it's been done a thousand times
before.
I don't give a shit.
I want some escape.
I want to see the wolf man.
I want to see like it's an old school.
Wolf men too.
It's going to be bad.
And you like the old ones?
Yeah,
I loved all of them.
Dude.
I loved American Werewolf in London.
I loved the old wolf man.
I'd love.
There's so many different ones that came
out.
You know,
there hasn't been a good one in a long
time though.
Those likened movies,
the vampires and the fucking.
Those are cool looking werewolves.
They're kind of crazy looking,
but they're so CGI that's.
It's hard to take them serious.
They look dope,
but they look fake as fuck,
you know?
Anyway,
a lot of people felt that movie sucked
and you might think it sucks to be a
huge team wolf fan.
No,
but I like some science fiction.
I love horror and science fiction
movies,
aliens like that kind of old school
aliens.
Now.
This was one that was like that,
that I hadn't seen,
so it was fun,
man.
I'll watch that shit again.
I liked it.
I liked that.
I liked to stupid shit.
Stupid Shit is not always bad folks.
It's like what I was saying about
cheeseburgers.
Sometimes you want a fucking hot dog.
Sometimes you need to gourmet meal and
you want to have a nice healthy salad
first and we'll have spring water with
lemon in it.
You want to feel good about yourself.
You want to feel sometimes you want to
fucking hot dog and you want a hot dog
with Chili on it.
All right,
and that Shit's good when you want it.
It's good.
He notes pig ass holes and the horse
dicks.
You don't give a fuck if it tastes good.
And when we got sauerkraut in it and
mustard,
that's what this fucking movie.
I live by a wiener Schnitzel.
And have you ever been there?
I think so.
It's amazing.
It's pretty much whatever you want.
They a chicken corn dog hot dogs.
Oh yeah.
I think I went to one in Colorado
actually.
That was one of the first ones I went
to.
Corn beef.
Hot Dog.
That's great.
Unoriginal plot like Carlsbad Sia.
How dare you,
your Momma while you were doing so well
before the.
Let's not bring up that full red band.
Doesn't like old music.
Oh,
I do like music.
You don't know what you're talking about
frank over there.
Shit,
Bro.
I Love Beatles.
Mostly Beatles with my favorite zipline
is probably my second favorite old
school.
Old Music.
Yeah.
To hold out a love is one of my favorite
songs of all time.
There was something about the seventies
man,
they had a certain sixties and the
seventies.
They had a certain energy to their music
that like what was representing the
changes that were going on in the
culture that we haven't had in a long
time.
Like the thing about Jimi Hendrix and
the thing about the doors and the
Beatles and all the zipline,
the bands from that era is like they
really were,
they,
they were bursting onto the scene in one
of the most,
the one of the biggest changes and in
our human culture ever,
like between the fifties in the
seventies,
shit just went haywire and whacked out
of fucking control and all of a sudden
there's,
you know,
love power and stop the war and
everyone's doing acid and Ken Keasy and
the fucking Mary Pranksters and they're
all doing acid and hanging out with
fucking Timothy leary and Hunter
Thompson and everyone's trying to change
the world and everybody's fucking.
Everybody left and wide.
And Jimi Hendrix is onstage this jam
into his guitar doing the Star spangled
banner with his fucking guitars,
the craziest version of it ever.
And his dirty hippies on acid wallowing
in the mud in front of them.
I mean,
there was nothing like it.
There was nothing like it before.
It changed the culture,
you know,
so that music,
when I listened to it,
man,
I feel that shit in it.
When I listened to like some old Hendrix
or some stones from that error,
so like you feel the fucking,
the time you feel that era,
you know,
it's like imprinted in the really great
art of that era.
Like voodoo child,
you know,
like so many fucking songs.
Mother's little helper,
you know,
so many stones,
songs,
brown sugar.
Come on man.
Digital underground.
What you just ruined.
I didn't even know what you're talking
about because they were good to.
Digital underground was good when they
first came in.
You know what else was good man?
Um,
who does opp naughty by nature.
Naughty by nature.
Was young and used to be the shit.
Yeah,
but naughty by nature.
Yes.
But I,
I liked young Mc a couple of songs but
naughty by nature.
What I liked about them was that dude's
flow was so original.
Third Base,
you know,
they couldn't fuck with that dude.
Treach had that,
that rhythmic flow that was like,
he made all the words Ryan cool.
But he also did it almost like he was
singing,
like he was talking shit and singing at
the same time and doing it really fast
to show you that he's good at it,
you know?
I mean he was like way more skilled than
most of those guys.
Like way more transitions and wait
craftier,
you know when you have it with that duty
to do know that you dealt with LPP.
That was a great fucking song.
That was a great.
That's a perfect example.
That song I overcame,
I never went and listened to that song
and now I could probably listen to it.
Yeah,
I know what you mean.
Like back then after awhile it got to
the radio and you're like,
Jesus Christ.
It's like the poker face on it.
That's like enough enough Nwa,
express yourself,
express full capabilities in the
correctional facilities because some
don't agree with how I do this.
A good straightened meditate like this.
Yeah.
That shit was a revolution in the
morning just in black and what it was
freaking me out.
I first got into Nwa,
had heard about Nwa,
like a little late to the game,
and this is back when I was still
fighting and I was on the treadmill
doing my workout and I had a Walkman on.
It was a walkman back then,
a cassette one and I was listening to
it.
I think I've met a bit a CD player.
I don't know.
It definitely wasn't an MP.
Three player.
He might've been a CD player,
I can't recall,
but I remember listening to,
I think it was a cassette.
I remember listening to it and go,
God,
these guys are so mean.
Like they're all like anti white people
and white bitch and white.
This what they want to shoot people
like,
wow,
this is crazy.
It's a must have the music.
And I started getting into like
ghetto boys and shit.
It's all people want to kill people.
Ice Tea.
I know there was nothing before that.
You know,
like the,
the rockstars of like the sixties and
the seventies.
Nobody ever talked about killing
anybody.
Then all sudden in the eight,
all these rappers are killing people.
Colors see nightmare walking.
Psychopath talking,
let's get butt naked and fuck tonight.
Yeah,
that was like later stuff,
but the early stuff that he came out
with.
Yeah.
H U s t l e member.
What's the two live crew?
I used to listen to like two live crew
and it's weird.
Like I grew up listening to black people
talk about sex like nasty.
They're freaking were put in to live
greener jail for being too dirty.
It was so dirty.
They want to lock them in cages and they
did it.
You know?
That's how crazy Florida is in Florida.
You can get oxycontin's everywhere you
turn.
You can go to a store,
you know right next to a fucking
apartment building and they go to pain
management center and you go these pain
management center.
There's always oxycotton junkies who's
sitting around wanting to get their
shit.
That's okay,
but you can't have a black guy talking
about get his dick sucked,
you know what is that?
We're terrified of that.
Stopped doing it because I want to read
the Stream.
Faggot.
Why do you keep fucking on trying to
read what people have to say?
Public enemy minus flavor,
flave don't hate on flavor flavor just
because you got paid tornado flavor
because he figured out a way to turn his
eccentricities into a show.
Kool g rap,
Kool g rap and Dj Polo.
Fuck yeah.
The Beatles or the stones?
Depends on the mood or what do you
think?
Beatles or stones.
Beatles million really well.
The beaters were definitely the stones
too much.
You know who I really liked?
Man,
that I don't think got enough credit
with soundgarden.
I think soundgarden,
soundgarden,
soundgarden.
Just blow up the outside world.
I'm sorry man.
That's one of the greatest.
Tap on that dog.
Temple of the dog was great,
but blow up the outside world that just
that song alone.
That's one of the greatest songs ever.
Man.
They had some really creative fucking
songs and Chris Cornell,
his voice just worked so well with that
band.
You know this other shit that he's been
doing.
I'm not really into it.
Yeah.
I can't get into it at all,
but God damn.
He was awesome with soundgarden.
You know his new shit that he did like
the the pop shit like,
oh,
maybe I give the guy a chance once.
Fuck around.
People don't know.
Sometimes you take chances.
You don't want to fuck you.
Doing that new gorilla is awful.
Is it?
God?
They were so good.
They knew it's because it has like this
guy screaming,
bluesy,
jazzy type stuff in it.
I don't know.
It's pretty good.
The first time I made out with a chick I
listen to the comfortably numb like pink
floyd.
I was watching wwf,
number two,
the basement of my friend's house.
The first time I read steps,
wf number two,
whatever used to be called.
Which one was that?
I don't remember,
but it was on the TV and it was first
time I ran wrestling,
wrestling.
Wwe.
You were progressing while progressing
was on.
Wow.
Did she make like a little muffled?
I don't remember.
I don't remember when you get too loud
so nobody could hear some weird.
I don't remember now because it was like
after homecoming and my friend was
upstairs having sex on the family were
just jamming it so nobody was home.
Exactly.
So then you put on a show.
You're trying to try to make your
friends here.
How loud you right.
I did it.
I don't think I did macro around shit.
Fuck up.
It's soccer,
but let them know you're doing crazy
shit down there so they feel
uncomfortable.
If I didn't,
I don't remember it.
Trying to do that and try to kill your
friends.
Boner just by over over freaking.
No.
The room down the hall.
No,
no.
I'm a quiet sex man.
You got a gorilla?
Fuck them.
Every now and then dude.
You probably Purim and everything while
you're having sex.
I'm quiet man.
Style.
I drove into a pillow,
a lot of rape jokes,
a lot,
a lot of positional dominance.
I'm very good at guard passing.
I don't know what the fuck I'm doing.
Guard passing shit.
It's funny how you know you can date one
girl and think that like it's cool to
choke girls because that's what they
want.
Jumping and jumping and like what?
They don't like that at all.
I don't like that.
That's confusing that you don't want
that.
That was sacked.
Yeah.
Or He loves that.
He likes smacking girls too,
but as long so I can see them in real
life now.
Like slapping him when he's bone them.
I don't,
I don't want to connect those two things
together.
Violence and sex.
I don't because I think you can connect
things in your head.
You can set up a little pathways and
like it or not,
they're in there.
You know?
I think sometimes dudes get obsessed
with feet.
You don't know what the fuck was that
all about,
but it's a thing and dudes get horny and
excited about feet.
Well,
that same shit can happen with slapping
people.
Dunkin likes to be spanked and you could
date a girl and she likes you to slap
her and then you get into that and you,
you guys have logo sex because you're
slapping and fucking in the ass and
she's nutty and then you know,
that's your shit now.
Like you're all fired up and the next
year you try to slap her and fuck her in
the ass and she's like,
you fucking piece of shit and you ruined
like the best relationship ever.
Why?
Because you're addicted to ask fucking
and slap and bitches and that's just
wrong man.
I need to get your shit together.
It's funny how different every girl is
to.
Some of us want to be fucking.
Other guys are like,
why are you doing it so rough?
You know,
some girls,
they want you to look at their clit like
this.
All right?
They want you to go like this.
And the other girls who want you to
fucking shake your head.
Like,
I want you to punch it.
They want to get crazy with it.
Then asshole,
they want to go nutty.
You know,
some girls want,
didn't want the whole thing,
didn't want fingers.
They want you to fuck their face.
They want money.
Shit.
But if you try that with other girls,
you got problems son.
That's why I just let them take control.
Sometimes you got to take a chance.
Sometimes you got to roll
the dice,
but you got to know how how freaky girl
is at.
Some girls would have never done it
before,
but you just tried it and then all of a
sudden you parties on.
I would recommend as men have experience
in it in his elder years.
Don't get all excited about that ass
fucking.
That shit is not sanitary.
It's not good for anybody.
It's only.
It doesn't feel better.
It's just because it's taboo.
That's Nettie.
That's the trick and it's unsanitary and
you could ruin your wife's butthole.
Right?
You'll break that shit.
They're all going to have problems
shitting with like 20 years when they
get old dudes who are gay,
a lot of gay dudes just go with the blow
job,
a blow job jerking each other off.
They give up.
Yeah.
A lot of gay dudes.
They're like,
you don't target your asshole pounded
some big Dick.
Lexington steel type character.
Ripping your asshole part.
You know,
and there's a lot of that online.
We were talking about that,
about how easy it is to see porn online.
Like ass fuck porn.
Pam.
Like within a couple clicks,
you know,
I'm all you have to do is just put it in
your google,
go to a site and it's free.
You just pay a lot of money for like
little shitty ass tiny videos that you
can download online or in magazines or
sears catalogs,
but mean the porn.
Just the evolution of porn over the last
few years.
I mean now you've got like these youporn
science and you know,
pornhub meet your giant big pictures.
I mean it's a giant big image and it's
high quality and it's free.
Like how the fuck are they able to do
that?
Who's,
how is everybody getting paid?
Like how's that work?
And if that's happening,
who the fuck is buying porn these days?
There's any.
I mean what,
how down to their sales,
if anybody needs a bailout horn and
period is down,
there's no reason for pointing.
People have moved on.
Were people in with webcams are now
giving it for free on their facebook
page.
I've always said about porn.
Why would you need to make more porns?
They have.
There's like billions of points you
couldn't possibly have jerked off to all
of them.
It's not even possible.
There's so many,
unless you're so goddamn specific,
you know the like you follow one girl
and you know,
it's a fantasy adventure.
Porn,
it's all acted out as long.
Only three fuck scenes in the whole hour
and a half movie,
but there's a lot of bad acting.
There's dudes who are into those,
you know,
they follow like one particular porn
starting to get into it and get obsessed
by her and go to meet her at the Avn
awards and sign autographs with them.
You know,
some dudes just lock onto one chip,
but if it's just,
you're just looking to jerk off to
stuff.
You don't have to ever make new porns
there's plenty of points.
Nobody's seen them all.
It's impossible.
How many points are there?
Do you know?
Twitter verse.
Anybody have any idea?
Yeah,
it's a lot of these porn stars that
moved onto just paying per like live
like this kind of web streaming.
Like,
you rent them for an hour and you tell
them,
you're like,
all right,
I want you to put this into your
butthole and that's a good move.
She probably do the one on how much I
can get something.
My buddle.
Um,
what was I talking about?
Oh,
D,
I'm tyler night.
There's a dude who was a porn star.
His name was tyler and I played,
uh,
um,
who was in the,
uh,
the bill cosby one that bill cosby porn
that I'm Thomas Thomas Award was in
Thomas Ward.
Played Cosby,
right?
They did a porno up and he's a real cool
dude.
He's just
a,
he's just porn actor who,
uh,
is also a really good writer.
He's got this grant,
I don't know his blog title
unfortunately,
but,
uh,
he's uh,
no one,
I'm going to find it for you because
he's really write some crazy shit,
but he's a really cool dude and he does
a Jujitsu with us at 10th Planet Jujitsu
in Hollywood.
Yeah.
He's a really tough guy too.
He boxed.
He had a boxing match and Mario Lopez,
but Mario made them things on them.
Mario gave him a bed,
not a beating,
but he beat him.
I shouldn't say that.
Let me follow up.
Tyler Lopez fight a lot.
Uh,
I think he has fought a bunch of times.
He's a tough dude,
man.
He likes to box and he's really athletic
and he's really good at it.
He's um.
Oh,
here we go.
Tyler night.com.
Yeah.
You already have that in your bookmarks.
I don't.
He's my buddy man.
Don't be gay.
All right,
I'm going to book here.
Check out our blog.
Hold on.
Start again.
It's really interesting stories because
he's a porn star,
but he's a really intelligent dude and
uh,
a good writer and a really fucking cool
guy.
I'd go really nice.
Guy.
Board is not accepting new people to
register.
It's not that somebody just tweeted.
No,
it is.
I'll accept people.
You just got to give me a day or two.
I do it myself because I don't want
anybody getting crazy.
I don't want to keep track of this whole
thing.
I'm going to follow him.
Follow night.
My,
my large penis friends.
I haven't seen his car.
All right here go.
So hold on
when steam,
how dare you.
We're just getting started soon,
right?
That's it.
That's our next thing.
We're going to just a few more questions
and then we're gonna get it.
I haven't been doing it for two hours
man.
So we've been doing it for two hours.
No,
I'm just saying I'm just ran out of
steam.
Watch such great heights.
What are you talking about,
son?
Oh,
the video,
the porno video.
Um,
I'm sure you can,
you porn or something?
Those fucking things are everywhere.
What I want to know about these things,
about these,
um,
you porns is how they make money and how
to make money now.
I mean are a lot of people that are
doing that.
A lot of people that are there,
they still like filming things and
paying for them.
Yeah,
I think right now it's things like the
cosby show type porn stuff where it has
to be like a gag gift on those types of
wonder man because they're still filming
a lot of them.
Derek always working.
I wonder where.
I mean maybe I'm websites are eventually
going to start sponsoring their own
porn,
you know?
Well that's what I was saying.
Most porn stars have gone to doing their
own web cam type thing.
But what I meant was websites getting
exclusive content deals with porn stars
of film in their own porns,
you know,
and like people get to ride in
suggestions,
you know,
hey,
I want to watch Jessie James Suck.
Lexington steals deck on a boat when a
Japanese Samurai outfit and then okay,
we're gonna film that they filmed it and
put it online and pay for it.
There's no reason to pay for it,
but you wouldn't pay for it.
But if you felt like you were creating
it,
you know,
maybe it's like one of those builders
shoe websites.
We could put your own purple stripe on
your.
If you go to use dream at night,
you can find the same shit for free man.
There's a whole website devoted ab
dishes.
The future.
How about this?
Maybe the future is people will fuck
live in front of you.
You can tell them what to do.
Yeah,
but they already do that though.
Know what I mean?
Like hot checks.
Oh yeah.
I mean there's pretty good high.
There's a lot of websites that do sit in
front of the TV,
sit in front of the laptop and then you
go and suck his cock.
It happens all the time and it happens
every day.
Yeah.
That's been happening for a long time.
There used to be thing whatever that are
dirty pervert I'll talk.
Is that it's all piled talk is it's
people having sex going like there's
people that like people to watch them
have sex and people are just sitting
there like,
Oh,
do it in your book,
and then they do that.
Yeah.
That's been happening since like,
Hey,
well I'll talk.
That's the problem with having.
It's not even on pal talk.
I don't think anymore to cut it out.
It's on everything now.
It's on ustream.
It's on Justin TV.
It's not.
There's actually links.
There's somebody posted a couple of
weeks ago to watch people from.
What is it about about [inaudible]
that's so private?
You know,
it's funny.
It's like we want to do it so badly.
Everybody lives for it.
We all acknowledge that we all live for
it,
but if anybody catches you doing it,
anybody catches you.
Engaging in that sort of pleasure.
It's so intimate and revealing about
you.
It's like we're so terrified of
revealing things about ourselves and
that's the big one is people seeing you
fuck people seeing,
you know,
you suck someone's pussy.
People seeing fuck,
some girl never sucked a dick.
All crazy.
That's craziness.
You know,
there's something about that that
people,
people associate that with like almost
like madness.
You know,
like the people that are willing to like
watch standing there while people watch
them fuck.
Like wow,
they're crazy.
Too crazy.
Like they can just take it,
just do it.
Perform in front everybody like dudes
get creeped out by it.
If a guy,
if you're at a party and everybody's
having a good time,
it's over your house and this dude just
goes crazy and pulses to accountants,
girl started soccer at your party,
you're going to like be uncomfortable.
He couldn't be nervous,
right?
Why is that?
If because if,
if he had only anonymous Nag,
it's like,
Ugh,
that was killing me and his girlfriend
was like massaging them while you guys
were all talking.
That will be cool.
Like,
oh,
we're having a nice conversation.
Everything's cool.
She just making him feel better,
but if she's like,
oh,
I'm going to suck my dick real quick.
Well,
how come everybody can't go?
Okay.
He's getting uploaded.
I right there in front of us.
Whoa,
whoa.
No.
Everybody gets like really freaked out
because it feels too good.
It's like the background feels good but
sucking your Dick.
It's just too crazy.
Just kind of sticking them out for
everybody.
You know some about that.
Right?
It's weird.
Closer.
Weird too.
It's almost like clothes and covering.
You're covering,
you're pushing.
It's like just somehow or another
we've intellectualize that not only do
we have to survive and all these
different climates and we have to,
you know,
make sure that we have some stuff to
cover us and keep us warm,
but we also got to slow the fuck down.
Make it tougher to fuck.
It can't just be like right there,
it can't just be dicks hanging out,
pussy taken out because we're just gonna
fuck.
You could just going to make too many
people.
Even in hot weather.
It's totally unacceptable to walk around
naked everywhere and just start fucking
people at the supermarket that.
But that's what would happen if
everybody was naked.
If you lived in Florida when it's 110
degrees,
you don't have to wear fucking clothes.
Okay?
And if there was no laws against wearing
clothes,
people just started walking around
naked.
People would fuck everywhere.
They'd be fucking in bushes and trees
that fuck in the car.
There'd be checks sucking guys.
Dicks while they were driving.
Everywhere you looked,
it would be going on.
It will be everywhere.
You'll be way more crashes from getting
your Dick sucked dry and then it would
be from twittering or from texting
or it might be the exact opposite and
you're seeing people's floppy tate's
everywhere.
You're like,
oh look,
these floppy tits everywhere.
I can't see this floppy tip for about a
day,
and then you're gonna want to get your
dick sucked.
Right?
Trust me,
trust me.
Alright,
you're gonna.
You're gonna fucking starbucks.
And I'm like,
Oh God,
everyone's shits everywhere.
Yeah,
maybe you can handle it.
Maybe it's because the dude right next
to a giant snake dick or no fucking this
white bowman's math.
Well,
you're trying to.
Julia Latte can take one 80 year old
lady tits to ruin my whole day to say
that,
but if Jessica beals naked fingering
herself right next to that 80 year old
lady,
you'll snap out of it and they forget
about that old lady.
Jennifer has a hairy ass.
Hello?
And it's a razor and I got some free
time.
I don't care if she's got to hear about
it all getting there.
Oh No,
I'll clean it all up.
I'll Polish it down a buffet.
I put cream on it.
Whatever she wants,
whatever.
I got a shaver.
That's it.
That's kind of a weird thing that all
women agree.
That hair is gross.
It's like this is what we look like.
God Damn it.
Okay.
We grow hair.
We go.
I mean,
some women like this kind of shit that
like men to have hair or might have
inherit chest or hairy legs,
but they all agree that women with
Harris grows and there was no,
no one like it was like all psyched up
about girls being Harry,
something like that Shit.
Hairy feet,
fiery legs and shit.
Really?
Supposedly hippy dudes.
You think so?
Fuck yeah man.
Wow.
Well,
okay.
Maybe,
but you.
Almost universally.
I mean there's gotta be a few
exceptions,
but almost universally we've accepted
the fact that girls hair is not sexy,
right?
I don't think so.
Fucking hair.
It's disgusting.
Especially when they have it like on
their back and just that amazing though,
but
it's amazing that we make girls take
stuff off their body that grows
naturally to perpetrate some new,
some new sleeker model that's coming in
the future.
That's less monkey.
You know?
That's clearly what we're trying to do
when you're in a shave pussies and
shaved legs and even when dudes shave
themselves down and get all oiled up and
try to look all sexy,
what you're trying to do is you're
trying to get as far away from the
monkey as possible.
You're becoming some sleek,
you know,
almost like silver surfer looking thing.
You know where you're,
you're,
you're evolving.
You know you're a form,
you know your round and smooth and
you're not Harry and fucking primitive
and ape like,
you know,
like whatever.
We're trying to do weird.
Like that's like about evolution.
We're trying to get rid of as much money
as possible before we fuck you.
We don't want no crazy bitches.
Gonna go nutty and ate the babies.
We're try.
We're going to want this bitch to get
rid of all the hair.
Get rid of everything.
What's this shit with bleach that he
believes that?
No,
this is wax,
that shit.
Wax It,
watch it.
But if I'm going to keep boxing,
I just want to shave it.
We're gonna.
Get rid of it.
We're going to give you hormones.
Can't remember that you got to get rid
of all this.
Why is this down here?
Why you have you right there?
Can you ask that?
Can you ask that we.
Whatever we want to do,
we want to make you as less monkey as
possible.
That's weird man.
You know,
I mean when you see like a big hairy
dude.
Do you remember George the Animal Steele
from wrestling?
George the animal steele was fucking bad
ass pro wrestler and one of the things
about him was he was so hairy.
I mean it was incredible.
He was like an animal.
He really was like a monkey.
I mean he was just this thick fucking
bald dude who had just hair everywhere.
His back,
his arm.
He had been in a bunch of movies too
because he's such a character.
Such a unique look and God.
But man,
if there's anybody that ever looked more
like an ape,
me.
So Harry,
like that's why his nickname work.
I mean if it was the same guy,
but you shaved all that hair off,
you couldn't call him George the animal
steele.
That wouldn't be nearly as good.
The part was cool.
It was that he's a fucking gorilla man.
It was crazy to see three girls and a
cup made you gang.
This is one of those guys with fucks up
everything.
Yeah.
No,
you know,
those guys will tell you a story.
He said,
fucking guy,
three coats,
Tracy Morgan guy.
You know there was three girls.
One Cup.
I don't need to see that.
I saw two girls.
One Cup.
That was bad enough.
My.
I'm surprisingly soft when it comes to
shock [inaudible] stuff.
How dare you,
Eddie,
strike.
How dare you question my manhood.
Yeah,
no,
you're right.
I,
you know what I think too much.
So when I see something really fucked
up,
I don't just go,
ah,
faggots dead.
I think of all the different shit that
led up to it and how it happened and who
did it and what the fuck is going on.
Hook Dane Cook is having us alive.
Exclusive comedy show or order.
You have to pay for it.
Wow.
That's what they're doing now.
People are doing live shows and you pay
for some people when you know when
you're selling out selling out theaters,
there's a reason he's not selling out
theaters.
She's telling out arena arena and
there's a reason for that.
You got a different beast.
You got people that are just 14 and
ready to go.
Maybe it's the ejaculation at the end.
No one wants to get hit.
I don't know.
I was talking about like that was too
long ago.
Sometimes people post something about
what we were talking about five minutes
ago.
We don't remember what the fuck we were
talking about five minutes ago.
Mr Hans is horrific.
Yes,
it is horrific.
If you haven't seen it,
you must watch it.
What are my thoughts on breast implants?
Is it a ridiculous concept,
vic?
Norcal?
Yeah,
it is right.
Breast,
breast implants.
One of the weirdest things about human
beings that it makes a girl more
attractive.
Maybe stick some things under her chest
and parts of her body and pressed
forward in our larger finger nipples.
Anything like that.
I love it.
Who Do like like,
um,
silver dollar ones are big point.
You want big silver dollar area,
those are great,
but like big tits,
big tits.
You know what's strange is how many
people are getting jobs these days
apparently took a real issue by job,
by job or anything that's real.
No,
it's real apparently.
That's awesome.
She's always had that.
It's not like there's any pictures of
her back in the day,
you know,
she's just got those freak genetics.
But there was um,
um,
a buddy of mine and he was joking around
with this.
He's been dating this girl for like four
months.
He's joking around.
What'd you get?
A job like joking around about her ass
being nice.
And she goes,
actually I did.
And he's like,
what?
And it turns on like girls are getting
them left and right to getting butt
implants to make their butt stick out
more.
How about you just go to the gym?
You fucking lazy bitches.
Okay.
You crazy lazy bitches.
Put some weights on your back and do
some fucking squats.
Okay?
What is your whole 24 hour day failed?
You can't do some of this.
Yes you can.
You Lazy Bitch.
Don't go to a fucking doctor's office
having to cut a hole in your snatch and
stuff.
Some fucking airbags up there.
That's ridiculous.
Okay.
You need to go to the fucking gym.
If you want to grow an ass,
go to the fucking gym.
Jesus,
right?
Am I right?
Brian?
Now know you like fake,
but I think there's nothing wrong with
the difference between fake boobs and
fake,
but I think you're crazy.
You're not getting the real genetics.
Let me tell you something.
It's like fake steak.
Okay?
Girls who have like a real juicy ass or
that real.
The real wide hips,
small waist,
those girls are freaks.
Okay?
That's what.
That's why guys are attracted to them.
They have so much hormones in their
body.
They have so much going on.
Those girls are horny as fuck.
It's nature.
Little wings,
big ass.
That's why you're attracted to them
because they're the most capable of
giving birth.
They have birthing hips and we find
those attractive and they have enough
fat on the ass to ensure that they're
going to survive during the pregnancy.
We liked that with like a little
plumpness.
It's attractive to us and those that
feels better.
Trust me,
those girls are freaks.
Butter.
But yeah,
that's a real ass though.
That's her real ass.
It is,
dude.
It's a real ass.
It's been confirmed scientists and uh,
the fucking mythbusters got involved.
They know it's a real ass fake tits.
Look ridiculous.
He's like,
Yo will not go tell anybody.
It's fake.
Tits do ridiculous.
But they still do look good sometimes
too,
man.
You know,
I'm not gonna lie.
I know as a human being,
I know it's completely ludicrous that I
find a girl more attractive because
she's got these bags and her skin and
make her tits
hanging out more.
But it's still,
you do,
you're more attracted to the frame.
It's like there's something going on in
our bodies.
There's,
there's a frequency that we try to hit
physically that men try to hit and women
try to hit to make themselves attractive
to the opposite sex and whatever.
Whatever the fuck it is.
We,
we,
we try to,
we try to be in and we try to nail it.
It's being a certain weight and being
healthy and smelling good and it's also
being a certain shape.
There's like women want a certain shape
to men as guys who get like peck
implants because they can't grow,
they don't grow muscle very well I
guess,
and they try to do a lot of bench
precedent.
They get lazy and so they just stick
these plastic things in their chest and
make their,
their,
their own boobs grow out and they have
things for their arms to and for the
calves to make their bodies look bigger.
I mean,
it's all craziness.
It's all,
but it's all desire to be loved,
you know?
It all comes from some weird thing we
want to be.
We want to be the desirable shape that
everybody's looking for.
Very strange,
you know?
Alright,
what else we got here?
The painting behind me.
What is it?
It's not a painting.
It's a photograph.
It says an American girl in Italy in
1951,
and it's by this lady Ruth Orkin,
and she took a picture of this poor girl
walking down the street and American
girl and she's in Italy where my
ancestors are from all fucking savages
and they're all grabbing their dicks.
Look at this,
this picture,
mad magazine.
This guy's grabbing his dick is and he's
making them that face and these guys are
all laughing.
There's an old guy and he's going to
fucking cigarette out here like this and
this guy's got his pants up through his
rib cage and they're all staring
mercilessly at this one chick.
And she walks through this fucking snake
pit of men.
This gauntlet of Shitty dudes just
hanging out in the street looking for
trouble,
looking at stick the Dick and somebody
there.
Those people are savages.
Living Room.
They got loafers with no socks.
Nineteen 51.
And you know when people talk to you
about the good old days and you know,
you watch TV and see father knows best
and you think that's what people really
liked.
Now that's what the people on tv,
we really like.
This shit was still going on.
Human beings don't get,
don't get tricked.
We're not crazy.
We've always been crazy.
It's not like this generation's fucked
up.
Every generation's fucked up.
So that's why I liked that picture.
And on that note,
ladies and gentlemen,
I think that should be it.
Right.
Anything else?
What about stick?
Cam was a no go.
What do you stick?
Cam Junkie fellow.
Was that your favorite site?
I don't know if I'm,
I don't know.
Stiff Cam will be better,
but ustream shoots you pretty good
except right now it's frozen now.
I just paused it.
Oh,
okay.
Our upload is not as good as our
downstream.
That's way more sinister than I
expected.
What is sinister?
Alright.
Um,
the Taliban is putting explosives and
women's suicide bombers.
This guy just said.
Yeah,
I did hear about that.
That's pretty nutty.
Yeah.
Um,
I don't know how they,
I don't know how they talk those chicks
into what I heard.
What they're doing is they're raping
women and they're getting these women
and humiliating them and getting them to
the point where they,
uh,
Coco's butt implants.
Oh my goodness.
This gentleman here just nailed it.
And we're going to find out if you're
correct,
sir.
If this guy's right,
we've got a fucking scandal in our hands
and this will be another case by the
way,
if it is right,
a brian being able to spot the phony.
Brian is awesome at spot in the phony.
Brian spots more fake shit on the
Internet than anybody I've ever met in
my life.
I think that's true.
I think you deserve that designation.
We get that dirty bitch.
Oh,
that's her.
Oh my God.
It's a fake ass.
Fuck you.
Oh my God.
It makes you think that was real way to
measure what makes you think that's
real.
Really.
Oh my God.
It's so real.
Oh Jesus.
Coco before.
But implants.
God,
she ruined a perfect.
Asked to look at her ass and it looks
pretty fucking high now.
Hell yeah.
It's cartoon asked.
It's like Pamela Anderson back in the
day.
Now that I find out there's some bags of
shit in there.
No,
I'm not into it.
I liked the old hotel.
It was a beautiful ass.
Did you put it online?
Did you retweet that?
The gentleman.
Did you tweet that to me,
buddy?
I'll retweet that shit.
That's pretty,
pretty powerful.
So it looks like Coco has a God damn
button implant plant.
Ladies and gentlemen,
what the fuck man?
What the fuck is there anything sacred
in this world anymore?
So do twitter that to me man.
My friend told her that to Joe Rogan.
Got Net and I'll retweet it at Coco's
butt implants then otherwise if you
could post it,
post that link post that way.
Okay.
What is it?
I'll get it.
I'll do it right now.
Um,
so that's really what's important.
Moral Ladies and gentlemen,
we went from space to Coco's button
plants.
That's how we roll here.
And the Joe Rogan podcast.
Uh,
I think that was the end.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Brian and I are going to go get
something to eat.
I'm hungry actually.
Now I'm going to try to beat the
traffic.
The traffic.
All right,
Patricia,
to Jill Scott,
you can't leave me.
I don't know who that is.
I'm happy to.
Happy.
I don't know to ask.
These gentlemen have been inundated by
human beings and information.
I wish you well in your battle to try to
figure out what the fuck this is all
about.
Until then,
see you next week.