The Joe Rogan experience,
but then you see them shifting off of
the um,
yeah,
I was on an oil platform in between Iran
and Iraq and the middle of nowhere on
the ocean now.
And it's a mile long platform,
half American marines,
half Iraqi soldiers.
And we're teaching the Iraqis how to
guard their oil.
That's the theory.
And anyways,
the uh,
the Iraqi barracks,
I got to tour them.
Not so nice.
Like those dudes were shooting off the
side of the platform.
And then the fish that we're eating,
the shit they would fish those fish and
then eat the fish.
Yeah.
A
lot of filth.
The Thursday.
No,
that's.
I don't know if that's just negative
propaganda man.
Love Thursday.
That's what the American say.
That
100 percent fact
that
crime for
Shady Kagan
nasty though where mattresses were all
brown and brody and
don't give a shit like we do about it
because they don't give a shit or they
don't have the money.
Um,
well we were,
we were training them and providing them
with supplies.
So at the time they did have access to
these things,
like we gave them a bunch of water
bottles and we're like,
dude,
just put this,
you know,
and it was all over.
They will throw the water bottles.
It's just all over the floor as opposed
to like putting them in the refrigerator
that the Americans had provided.
So probably like really dissing chanted
country got conquered.
Everyone they know get killed.
I totally agree.
And you're like,
why are you telling me how to do my
thing?
Do you ever think about how he would
react to just one,
like example of what we do to another.
You could see it south the north to the
south and people call you a Yankee.
People call me Yankees before
I'm worse than a Yankee Dude.
I'm a foreigner because my family came
from other countries.
You know,
I wasn't here when your bullshit was
going on with those people until they
see Palicki
new.
But I remember this and I was on that
oil platform.
They had this thing where I was like,
operation win hearts and minds and this
is the.
This is the craziest thing ever.
Will just fuck the army.
Its mouth.
Oh,
you die.
So once a week they had ice cream
socials with the Iraqis and they would
fucking find a way to get tubs of rocky
road ice cream airlifted onto this oil
platform and then we would.
I would be having ice cream with the
Iraqis so that they would see how
amazing our American rocky road.
Isn't everything amazing in America.
Like,
don't you want this?
Yeah.
This is pretty good.
It's going to take back my grandmother
getting their head blown off.
Right?
I'm directing.
This is amazing.
It's got chocolate chunks in it.
You don't like this.
It make you forget about almost everyone
in my family,
but I think it was worth it because this
is
delicious.
That is so hilarious.
Remember your nephew now,
right now.
Need your kids.
You've got rocky road.
It's called the Ken Dirus.
The candy room a is a toothpick.
Fish or vampire fish?
A species of parasitic freshwater
catfish.
A native to the Amazon basin where it's
found in countries of Bolivia,
Brazil,
Columbia,
Ecuador,
and Peru.
Jesus Christ.
Oh,
swims.
Wow.
The smaller species are known for a
tendency to invade alleged tendency to
invade parasites and parasites,
the human urethra.
However,
despite ethnological reports dating back
to the late 19th century,
the first documented case of the removal
of the candy room from a human urethra
did not occur until 1997,
and even that incident has remained a
matter of controversy.
So it might be bullshit did they might
have anal catfish.
Well,
look at that thing.
How's that going to get into tip of your
Dick?
Unless you want it to my shifts.
That could definitely get into vaginas.
Yeah.
Of Girls.
Korean,
their fucking Amazon Shit.
Wow.
This is weird.
Okay,
so this might totally be bullshit.
Historical accounts,
earliest published reports of this Ken
dirus attacking human host comes from
the German biologist,
CFP Vonda Marty s in 18,
29 who never actually observed it,
but rather was told about it by the
natives of the area,
including that men would tie a ligature
around their penis going into the river.
Vendors were happening.
You know what that meant?
That meant dudes where they had cock
rings on and they got busted and then.
No,
no,
no.
There's a fish fry up your sound like a
robot to take a trip into the Amazon and
one doodle into bang an Amazon chicks
and you're like,
dude,
look at this man.
No,
it's bullshit.
I totally believe it.
It makes sense.
Yeah,
and all that kind of does,
but it seems like there was only one
case where almost pulled out of a dude's
Dick.
Maybe they just,
they're just comfortable with them and
live with them.
They just know,
well,
let's go google up.
Can dirus removed from Dick is probably
a kind of.
Put it in his dick.
Yeah,
that's what they're saying.
That's what they're saying.
They're saying it's Amazon girl vaginal
parasite.
Oh,
here's.
Here's something on aol.com about an eel
that's swam up somebody's penis and it
had to be surgically removed.
Okay,
well hold on a second.
There's a fucking.
There's a penis removal video.
Yeah,
Dude.
Oh my God.
Go to this Kim,
dear.
Oh,
penis removal operation.
Oh No.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
Get to.
That can derail a c,
a,
N,
D I R U,
penis removal operation.
Good googly Mowgli's.
All I have to say,
this is fucking crazy,
man.
This is fucking crazy.
Did you get it?
Hm.
Click on this.
Where do you see this shit?
They got one of them scopes,
so they're going down this guy's book.
He's got our fish.
He's got a little baby fish camped out.
Inside is packer.
You imagine in your fucking pistol this.
Oh my God.
It's got eyes.
It's a fucking fish.
Jesus Christ.
There's a fish in this guy's Dick.
This is madness.
This is fucking madness.
This is a real thing.
This fish really does swim in your Dick
and you got to send this dude in there
with a vacuum cleaner,
vacuum cleaner with a camera and the end
of it to suck it out of there.
And then the fishes swimming away from
your deck.
Is this in the Amazon or what?
It says this happened.
Um,
yes.
It said it lodged in the penis of Sylvio
Barboza after urinating in the Amazon
River.
Tributary,
doctor and noir somad removes that can
deer a fish in a two hour operation.
Dude,
he's got to keep going in there.
Look at how many there are in there.
Oh my God.
His.
It's like his ass is packed with Dick's,
but it's not as his penis.
Packwood fish.
Couldn't you just like put a poisoning,
killed them all and they would kill you.
You dig too stupid and had to be
something.
Check poisoning your Dick.
Wouldn't it breaks your Dick?
You gotta let the bad man with the
vacuum cleaner go in there and do his
business.
How did they deal with it before
doctors?
They didn't.
They would just die.
They just died.
They just have a fish living in the
dick.
You're not getting it out.
What are you going to do?
You're going to send a fucking fish hook
in there.
Maybe a shaman could do something.
Put a little baby calf blossom.
That would probably.