Three,
two one Brendan Schaub.
You got to say that he's the greatest of
all time.
Now we're talking about talking about
money,
man.
Say it.
Yeah.
We'll live our live mighty mouse the
greatest of all time.
I agree.
I said,
you know what?
I finally agree with you,
man.
Mighty mouse number one in my book.
Now I've seen everybody except fade or
live.
I would have to sing,
fade,
or live like in his prime to really get
a feel.
I feel like mighty mouse is better than
all of them.
That dudes aren't so many different
levels.
It's like he's like,
here's the,
here's everybody,
here's next level shit,
and here's mighty mouse.
He's so next level.
Yeah.
It doesn't matter if you,
if you come in and you were the best
striker on the planet,
he still gonna fuck you up.
He'll still fuck you upstanding.
I'll take you down and submit you.
Anyways.
You come in at the world class,
wrestler comes in and he's the best
restaurant in the world.
Mighty mouse mouse still gonna fuck him
up and take him down.
He got a guy who was just amazing at
Jujitsu.
Mighty mouse still gonna fuck you up.
Why didn't you still,
you still Wilson Hayes.
She's here.
Wilson Hayes.
After he went,
I'd rather get knocked out though.
So does demoralize Brazilian,
I mean mighty miles.
His strikings insane.
His takedowns are insight.
Jujitsu.
His cock confidence is insane,
but his work ethic ethic,
cardio the best,
the best.
The best of all time.
Do you have any sort of seen the
ratings?
Whoa stuff all time on Fox.
He needs to go up.
I just pulled out your cornflakes.
How crazy is that?
We need to see,
we needed to see him go up in weight.
I think that's the answer.
I know it's obvious.
Dana does.
Dana doesn't want that.
It's on.
Yeah,
but damn,
those are imagined him against Tj
dillashaw really hard.
It's really hard to sell an opponent
against him other than someone going up
like a or someone or cody going down.
Cody's talked about going down and he
said he's down.
He says he can make it.
Well,
it's hot.
It's not that uncommon that someone just
rules a weight class so much that he
goes up and the way they do it on boxing
and let's step down,
up or down generally step up.
Let's see if I could take a bigger dude
lets you know what I mean.
Like Connor's on that level.
He's like a fuck up to 45 hours but I'm
going to come up to 55 and they for the
challenge Bj did it.
It's how do you think it is rumor now I
haven't even texted Dana about this.
There's two UFC two 13 rumor have you
heard this?
Jim told me that about Matt Know
Mcgregor and Co and um,
and Tyron Woodley.
Yeah,
no I saw that 100% bullshit.
What do you think?
I think from what I hear it's bullshit.
I'm supposed to be utilizing my
connection.
I know.
See a text you heard it's bullshit.
I'm pretty sure I saw every should have
a rumor section,
you know rumor,
part of the show rumors,
rumors for Joe Bro.
Dude,
you'd have to best rumors show of all
time.
I had some deep I t shirt aerial,
shut that down but seidler I'm pretty
sure cyborgs fighting at UFC two 13
anaheim.
She tweeted that out recently like as I
was getting to know us something
recently,
we should tweet it out that a few of he
doesn't get her a fight,
let her go.
It doesn't work like that.
Like I love when fighters do that,
but it's like,
hey,
if you don't fight me soon,
I'm fucking out here.
You ain't going nowhere bitch.
Like you contract you have to but to
defend UFC here,
which is,
you know,
they offered her fights like too and she
wasn't ready so they're like,
dude,
we tried all right,
we'll figure something out but Jeez and
now you want to take off like give us a
second here.
And in her defense apparently didn't
mean there's the only way the that like
you saw it or would grant her there.
It goes to our 29 my first year fc fight
in the USA.
So who do you think she fights?
He's just fine.
Just says she's fights Duran to me.
She says she is fighting Duran to me.
What's up son?
And you know what's cool with that?
My goodness is Sunday.
July.
Oh Shit.
This is,
you can do both.
Oh Shit.
God Damn Dude.
And there's a big brown breakdown live.
Yeah,
everybody's all girl Ebi.
July 3rd oh shit.
UFC requested it.
The UFC asked us,
can you do an all girl Ebi?
And I said,
Damn.
I thought you'd never ask.
Hell yes.
Jump in that bitch.
She's not going to get touched and
coming in and just smash all your girls
all at once.
Get someone big.
No,
I just have all of them jump on her.
Be Sick.
I go to fucking King Kong was a little
plane Kong movie.
No,
it looks dope.
It's a dope from went for awhile when
you're,
you know you left at 12 year old boy and
your brain out.
It's fun.
But for,
that's really stupid hospital down to
see it though.
What's his face is a John c Riley's in
that movie.
He's hilarious.
Yes.
And he's done Ralph.
Really?
He's that guy in the movie.
He's,
he's comic relief.
Does he play for your health?
He plays,
it.
Does lead to crash,
landed there,
but does he play the guy from,
for your health?
Do you ever watch that on Tim and Eric?
No.
Do John C.
Reilly is humongous.
He's so huge.
But he'd love doing the Tim and Eric
Show.
You're saying size wise on no,
no,
no.
As a star.
And then tim and Eric is so crazy,
bizarre,
obscure comedy show.
It's fucking nuts.
It's like key and peele on,
on acid.
And there it is.
I've seen this big ass after does this
show and he plays a character.
He's like a news host.
He's Gotten,
oh,
I have to,
his name is Steve.
Dr Steve Berlin.
Of course,
I can't believe,
like,
I couldn't think of the doctor Steve
Brewer.
He's the funniest guy.
It does it for free.
Yes.
He don't give a shit.
He's also,
he's one of the funniest guys of all
time,
like that,
that fucking scene or him and,
uh,
him in the fucking Neil Farrell and not
in stepbrothers,
but in Talladega nights discussing,
shake it,
bake.
I mean,
come on.
Nobody tells him when he's uh,
he takes over and he's his girl and
paints his face over here.
Fuck you doing.
He's like,
I'm looking at man cause like you want
to hang out with nobody calls him up and
ask him how to use history.
Why the fuck would you want to watch tv
while listening to the radio?
Because I like to party that movies got
like the best timing of all time.
I came and will ferrell together.
You could just have them.
All you need is to just get a couple of
funny guys to write some loose format
for them and just let them go wild and
go.
They might be two funniest pairs ever do
cheat.
He was pleased,
played so serious in that movie.
Uh,
gangs in New York and met him in gangs
in His York.
Right.
He was a serious dude.
Nasty dude.
Top Daniel.
That must be so much fun for me in that
movie.
He's so shit.
I felt like it was like he was really
the butcher.
They said he's an asshole on set.
He was in character man.
He's one of those,
I'm in character guys.
Two people played a bad motherfucker in
that movie.
That movie gangs in New York is scary.
It's underrated.
Oh it's so good.
But it's scary because you imagine like
what life was like if you were born into
that environment.
Cause those were real on whether or not
that exactly happened with it.
Now how much,
I mean I'm sure there's some sort of a
dramatic flair that they added to the
reality of that,
but whatever the fuck it was,
there have been places on earth that
have existed where people hacked each
other up with axes and swords like that.
Just when you watch that and you realize
Jesus,
that was the only like,
you know,
a few hundred years ago,
not that far.
Not that far in the past.
Indians and shit.
I mean with,
they would,
uh,
you know,
I would retaliate,
cause white man came and tried to take
their lands so the Indians were like,
fuck yeah,
we spot a wagon.
We're gonna fuck you up.
Oh yeah.
You know what I mean?
So it was just back and forth.
You got to worry about not just fucking
a bears and shit,
but you got to worry about an Indian's
damn that if the Indian spot you and
they want to fuck you,
you're done.
Son Does a lot of cannibalism going on
to the people don't know about,
they probably love eating white people,
especially the Nez perce.
I just saw Steve Rinella told me about
all this shit when I was hanging with
them in the woods when Callan and mine
went hunting with him.
Are there any stories terrifying?
Are there any stories?
There must be stories of slaves that
escaped and went and hid out with
Indians.
You know what I mean?
Put on this to others and stuff like
that,
but the paint on,
I don't think the Indians are let you in
understand.
No they won't you.
No.
The Indians would be,
they understand for evil,
they understand that were guys are
running for their lives.
There had to be so you get to the tent
and listens to,
and there was all sorts of stories about
the mountain men meeting Indians and
fallen in love.
He didn't fall in love.
I've seen movies.
Well you know what,
it would have to be a white guy helping
the Indians out and,
and being on the Indian side,
understanding that that was being taken
rewards for you.
Dances with wolves.
Hundred percent.
Dude,
I watched it.
I want to see resonated in my mind it
seemed really than anything I watched on
the news.
Dude,
we fucked him up so bad.
We fucked him up.
So just our diseases,
we get like the flu and you take that
pill.
Can you imagine percent of the native
Americans like talk guys,
dead dudes are like,
do escaping.
We're going to go find some Indians and
live with them and fuck all the Indian
women to imagine or could you touch the
women even crazier?
Could you image show up?
They show up with these gigantic dead.
Yeah,
you're not coming in my fucking town for
Shauna's problems for sure.
I just don't think that if anybody came
from like those native Americans that
were here back in that day,
like you know,
they,
they were competing with each other.
You know,
I mean there was a lot going on there,
but like to say that the white people
feel better,
and that's true though.
Right?
True though.
It's true though.
You had a cold and you just watched
everybody die.
You like,
you gave them a cold.
Like you came over on a boat,
you got sick and everybody died.
90% of the people died.
They didn't know though.
But how crazy is that that we,
our bodies adapt to bugs and diseases so
well maybe they just said that.
Maybe they just slaughtered them all and
say,
dude,
let's just say they say yes.
Guess what?
We got some bad news to the Navajo.
Indians are wiped out.
They had disease and someone sneezed on
homes.
They're allergic to cheese.
Yeah,
they all died.
There was a gone now basically it's crew
knows what part of history is real
enough.
Indians in the UFC Indian can imagine a
Jim Thorpe and the U of C Some I don't
send your just from a reservation comes
in and fucks everybody up.
It'd be like Indian versus white gets
him from street fighter.
You never know.
Well,
I don't think so.
There's gotta be some bad ass Indians
out there like full blown up to go to
Canada.
Bad Ass Indians.
So you remember that one?
Native American that Bas rutten fought.
Remember that dude?
He was in King of the cage.
She fired a lot of uh,
different fights.
He was like a real good mid level guy.
Big Native American guy.
I don't remember.
Find out Bas rutten's last MMA fight.
He fought an Indian and the last one?
Yeah.
Or was the guy a white guy but claiming
one 16th Indian.
I'm trying to it as the card.
I think the guy was native American.
I'm pretty sure.
I don't think you're supposed to say
Indian.
You mean you want to off?
That's right.
Rubin Hurricane Villareal.
That's the last guy he fought.
That sounds Mexican.
Reuben doesn't sound very Indian.
Find out what nationality.
Oh,
warpath.
Yeah.
Oh God damn.
He looks Indian.
He does for sure.
Big Dude.
Six 14.
Sasa salty record.
Oh Shit.
22 wins.
28 losses.
This same for you.
If I'm answering their belly dump bus
route and doesn't give a fuck that part
Indian right.
Get that cheque right.
You'll have to be one 16th to get that
chance.
He has to prove that shit.
Do we got an MMA,
a wikipedia there?
Well either way.
Either way.
He's Indian.
His Fudge,
at least in my book he is,
he's it part,
oh he's full of patchy corn.
My book.
That's,
so that's one thing that I do know.
I don't know a whole lot about native
Americans,
but I know that the Sioux people,
they actually call themselves look Coda
and the other Indians would call them
the sue cause it means enemy.
So there was like all sorts of crazy
infighting.
Look at that.
Oglala Lakota fight gets first UFC went
okay.
Other than that dude looks super native
American.
The guy and the right or left left.
The guy looks white as shit.
He kind of left with the jury is totally
his Chin Deanna.
Right?
He looks like a straight white boy.
Crazy Apache to me.
He looks to see what Baskins moms come
on site.
He looks straight out of fucking,
I've seen this dude fight.
It's a tough dude.
Yeah.
Really tough,
strong American native as fuck.
You got that dude come on and say I'm
going to lie.
His name is David.
Well you know what they look like.
They look like people from Siberia.
That's the origination of the native
American.
They traced the genome back.
They did this thing for 'em when they
were,
uh,
the Mormons are trying to prove that
Jesus came from a,
uh,
native Americans like that say way more
than bars are trying to prove that the
lost tribe of Israel was the date of
Americans cause it's in one of their
books.
God,
good.
That's a good one right there.
Turns out that the Indians,
but you know,
in history we paint them out to be
savages.
Well,
we're so lucky that this fucking people
that studied this shit and so that we'd
know that we could sit here in a room
and just talk shit and Google.
How the fuck did people get here from
Asia?
They walked across the bering strait.
We know that.
It's like the fact and then once they
did the genome and the native American,
they went yup,
these people from Siberia.
So as people from Siberia,
if you ever look updated,
fucking strong features,
super strong stout shane bones and
fucking like rue salon prod mocad vowed
to cough,
providing a cough.
I don't know.
Since he said he was like pissing black
times,
like you know what I think I'm good.
He's one of 'em uh,
speed of sport guys.
This guy
is,
he's still working with him.
He's a friendly guy and he's a nit curse
on God and the curse on worked with
them.
He's the only man.
He's been in some wars.
That's what's up straight up the way
that guy fights.
You can't do that for very long.
You know,
there's guys like floyd mayweather that
can go an entire career and get rocked
like maybe three,
four times.
Like where he got tagged a little and
then you got guys like providing a cough
that just butt heads with everybody.
They tried to break everybody.
He had a back to,
he had to like back to back fights with
Alan.
Gerry.
And then with a homeboy,
the,
the black velour.
The beast though.
Desert Storm.
Yeah.
Tim Brown.
Tim Bribing him.
Hey Os wars.
No,
tim badly.
I have to fight.
Had a stutter for six months.
His wife was like,
please stop fighting.
He was sick for like months.
Not Jesus Christ.
I'm not surprised.
It was the fight of the year to chaos.
Chaos.
It was chaos.
Those fights,
man.
I'm so torn because while I'm watching,
I'm enjoying the shit out of it.
And me too.
But part of me is going,
fuck,
I know what these guys are doing
themselves right here.
It's we how you almost like you have an
extra bump of information.
That's too much,
but it's it,
it still makes like a UN Arturo Gotti,
micky ward fight even more glorious when
they walked in the room.
He just like Jesus Christ and they are a
man.
Like I'll never forget with Jon Jones,
when he fought Gustus Finn and I fought
[inaudible],
you know,
he had a war and my coach Tony Jeffries
has never been to UFC.
The UFC has ever been to.
And John Jones one and he's coming by on
a stretcher because he was so beat up
and his lips were out to here.
Both lives clogged and he's shaking.
That was when he went straight to the
hospital.
She's shaking,
she's fine.
I just,
from there I just grabbed him and I
didn't know what to say.
I went,
Dude,
I'm so proud of the champ and he just
put a thumbs up.
I'd probably be cutting,
see me like stewie eyes like [inaudible]
shit.
And my coach goes,
holy fuck,
that's the winner.
[inaudible] does some about Jon Jones.
I think this is,
I got a theory,
I got an older brother theory and I feel
like dudes who have bad ass older
brothers can fucking take it.
Like Weidman.
Weidman had an older brother and him and
the older brother apparently according
to some of his interviews,
they,
you know,
and his older brother beat him up and
Shit,
man makes you tough.
Like Matt Hughes,
two twins.
Imagine looking at yourself every day
just trying to beat up your shot wrap
and just a dead even every fucking time.
Just a war.
Jim Miller,
Dan Miller,
a lot of these two guys.
My brother used to beat me up,
but I never,
uh,
not beat me up,
but just like a sock my shoulder,
like about what?
Fart.
He socked me full.
I'd have to sit there and I would take
it.
I would never fight back.
And I was like in,
in box and there's the Smith family.
Liam Smith.
Uh,
although Smith,
there's four brothers,
a three are world champions called
Miller and Michael Miller.
I'll just fuck.
Yeah.
Savages.
Monsters.
Man Does a tums on brothers.
The lozan brothers,
brothers,
Nogueira brothers,
shit.
Twins.
They're right too.
There's a bunch,
man.
Dude,
so many mud shogun and Ninja.
Oh,
here,
here's something that fucking rock your
world or not rock your world.
But if John Jones wasn't such,
you know,
a fuck up for lack of better terms,
he would,
we're not even having this conversation
that mighty mouse is the best ever.
He'd be just going based off his regular
schedule now.
He'd be 13,
14 time world champ if no one beat him.
And he'd probably be fighting that
heavyweight and having that belt to go
down as best ever.
Well,
he's still got a chance.
I mean,
John John's only 30 years old,
which is crazy because that means he's
really about to jump into his prime.
I say like an athlete's prime for combat
sports.
I feel like it's somewhere around 30 to
32 for heavyweight.
I see.
I don't think everyone,
I think the lighter weight classes,
it's earlier,
but look at the welterweights,
the t,
the champs are always aligned around
that age.
Except for GSP.
I think he won a title when he was in
his late twenties,
twenties.
When is tyron Woodley's what,
33 yeah.
Yeah.
That's fair.
I mean,
he had wrestling background.
John Jones,
what was wrong?
How old's Robbie?
I'm Jon Jones is uh,
his suspension comes up in July.
Did you hear what Dana White said today?
I texted to you.
Yeah.
They're going to fight.
There was a Nakamoto,
right?
Yeah.
Brett accomo interviewed Dana White and
uh,
from espn he said that,
DC,
we'll fight Jon Jones if,
if,
but if John Jones isn't ready by it,
I think it's the July card.
Was it July 29th?
Yeah.
If he's not ready by then,
then he's gonna Fight Jimi Manoa and
then they'll fight down the road.
Crazy.
So no warm up for Jon Jones.
If he doesn't want one,
then what do you think about that?
Do you think that's smart for John?
What do you think John should take a
warm up?
He should take a warm up.
The UFC should give them a warmup cause
joe,
when has it ever worked when a guy takes
this much time off and just throw them
right to the top of the heap?
Think of chill,
sewn in like there's a lot of guys and
people go,
well dominick Cruz,
dominick Cruz didn't fight.
Cody Garbrandt,
Tj dillashaw after all that time he
found up Ms Asakia,
who's a tough guy,
but it's a cocky and then he went right
into tj.
Still a warm about Tj was,
no,
the teacher was a big gap.
I know,
but at least he didn't fight that first
fight back.
He ain't being tj.
Right.
But you know that he got injured after
the Mitzi gawky fight and it was another
year plus [inaudible] fought again.
And He,
and he might be the outlier here,
but I'm just saying he's not like,
but,
but he's not as good in the first fight.
If you look at them at the Tj fight and
then you look at him in the second fight
when he fought uriah faber,
he's way better in the of fape.
Correct.
He's more lean.
He's fitter and he's,
he dealt with a lot of the problems that
he has.
His serious plantar fasciitis,
ma'am.
Have you ever had that fucking
nightmare?
I've had to deal with it.
And you look at his style,
it's like,
uh,
this Fascia in the bottom of your feet,
tears.
You can't even like,
you can't get out of bed to warm up.
It's a fucking nightmare.
It's impossible.
Dominick Cruz is all footwork.
And what happened after he tore his acl.
He took a long time off and his feet
just weren't strong enough to keep up
with his training because this training
is so foot movement.
Yeah.
That's all my it back to the point.
Should John Get a warm up?
You're,
you're in the grand scheme of things.
I understand.
We want these big paydays and you want
them the big rating.
So he tossed them DC.
John Jones,
a huge raider,
right?
But if something happens like Rhonda
Rousey lost weapons,
we gave Rhonda Warmup,
so you get paid on that.
It's huge drawl.
And then she fights the huge draw.
But when you just toss them right to the
very top,
it's a one and done man.
What does it make sense to me where they
were worried,
I guess,
you know with the sale,
you know you buy something like $4
billion,
you want to,
you want to maximize your profits.
You know,
it's just the issue comes up with
purists,
which I think all of us are purists,
right?
When you consider like when you look at
it,
like at the end of the day,
I want to see the number one contender
fight the champ.
I ride the fence,
I get the business side from what the
they want to do and then I get from a
pure fighter standpoint.
I was just about to say,
but I'm a hypocrite because I was happy
when Dan Henderson got that shot against
Michael Bisping.
I'm like,
that's what we want to see or GSB.
It makes no sense.
He's fighting Bisbee well,
the problem with the GSP business fi's,
it ties up the division.
And when you have a guy like Robert
Whitaker who just ice is Jocko roy hole,
that's the best adjective to use it.
He's a killer.
Winokur's a killer.
Straight killer.
Who beats him in the top three?
I liked his chance to get to anyone.
Now Yoel Romero is such a freak show
such a free that sun.
Maybe you,
you,
you're 100% right.
That it's a hell of a fight.
I mean,
do you see Yoel Romero and chocolate?
I don't even think you'll beat jock
gray.
Really.
You could really give some of that fight
to Jock,
right?
Like you remember it was a split
decision.
He had that one moment where he spun and
Jock right with that spinning back fist
and put 'em on Queer Boulevard occur.
May jock caray looked like a fucking
amateur.
Just fucking hawked them down even at
his back's like,
get the fuck out of here Jujitsu
vehicle.
See it.
I feel like whittaker is better now than
ever and I think he's only 25 or 26 26
26 I think somewhat.
He's no,
no older than that.
He's a young buck and he's coming up
strong and he's another one that went
from one 70 to one 85 and improved
tremendously.
As soon as he stopped cutting that
radical amount of weight.
All of a sudden dude's got vitality and
power is not in the band.
Johnson fight,
the Bronson fight serious.
That was a big wake up call to people
cause [inaudible] was putting it on him.
Well Brunton rushed Adam Chin first and
I was like,
oh my God,
how's this gonna work out?
And he'd covered up you smart compose
and then just yet those Australian
fucking shovel.
I'm a fan now and I thought he's going
to lose that fight and I'm like,
oh,
that's my guy down.
I'm down there and see all the crocodile
Dundee means no.
There was me and my man,
a dude from Australia fights a dude who
calls himself the alligator.
She,
that's just,
that's a great fucking it out done.
Besides working now this is a knife.
Fucking now that's a Nazi.
Yeah man.
He's the new hotness and that divisions
eat some hotness like the new blood.
I love when there's new blood cause like
fun.
That's what we need.
Now we need that heavyweight and light
heavyweight
light heavyweight were like,
yeah,
I guess you know what dc John King has
his fight each other every other
weekend.
Well,
what did you think about rumble
retirement?
When I went,
when I saw here's what happened,
right.
They read off the submission.
DC raised his hand,
you know,
I'm going into interview DC and rumble
and DC are hugging and then DC puts his
hand on rebel.
Shoulders goes,
he,
you go first,
you go first.
That was a bad idea,
I think.
No,
I don't think it was a bad idea,
man.
I think it was classy.
You know,
d this is what I think about DC at the
end of the day.
Daniel cormier is a really good man.
Great Guy.
He's a really good man.
You know what I mean?
Hate.
I don't get it,
man.
I mean,
he's competitive and you know,
in before the fight he's saying,
you know,
it's too bad that Anthony Johnson's in
my weight class because they'll never be
champion.
You know?
He's saying all this shit that you're
going to say,
but at the end of the day,
it's true.
He's a,
he's a,
he's on another level when it comes to
his ability to compete there level,
there's another level,
and just to critique the fight,
they're a DC looked at in the worst
shape we've seen him.
I thought if Anthony Johnson can beat
them,
this can be the time.
Anthony,
I didn't know going into it and if
Johnson didn't want to fight or be in
there,
he had one.
If you even talking about retiring,
you're fucked with a guy like dc who's
going to grind it out.
It was just not going to rumble.
Johnson was about four inches from a
head kick knockout.
He caught him with the foot in the face
and broke his nose.
If he caught him with his Shin,
if he,
you know when you mean see where that
kick landed him and you feel like God
damn toes Daniel Cormier can fucking
take it.
He can fucking take it.
Cause he,
he took that shot right in the chin.
He went back to his corner.
Is Nelson's clearly jack,
we're looking at an in between rounds.
Like that looks really broken.
Went out there like it didn't bother him
at all.
And that was a good tune up fight for DC
too.
Not that Anthony Johnson's a tuneup,
but his game plan was crazy.
He obviously didn't execute the game
plan.
So I think that was good for DC cause I
think if that DC fights John,
he's in trouble.
I wonder what would've happened if
rumbled connected.
My question is,
look at this smack,
he catches him right with them.
It's almost better.
He bent down,
his nose absorbs hell.
Yeah,
those small knows to Jesus Christ in
combination.
We've never really seen DC with a gut
like that.
Well look it,
obviously it wasn't affecting them.
Who knows if he's injured.
He probably was always injured.
He's always doing some shit.
Scott,
he's got a problem with his knee and
he's had it.
He's had it worked on.
It just gets dumped cells in it.
She's going to have 38 cause he's like,
that kicked fully connected.
Right.
They just took out.
He went down into it,
which I think you didn't get full
momentum like you said with the Shin
where he met a lot of trouble.
It looked a lot harder than I thought it
was.
But it was certainly the foot.
And the thing about fetus,
you can knock some of the fuck out with
a foot,
no doubt about it.
But a foot gives a little bit.
Yeah,
I was just going to say it.
It gives a little bit,
you know,
the first time I ever realized like how
much of a benefit that was.
I worked out with Maurice Smith and
Maury Smith was showing me like the,
when Maury Smith faces a heavy bag,
it's really interesting.
Like if he throws a roundhouse kick,
the bag goes straight.
Like he hits it,
like he's hitting straight
on,
he's like stepping to the side and
hitting straight on.
It's almost like he's hitting it with a
front kick in terms of how the bag moves
away from him.
And in the,
the taekwondo and karate days,
everybody went round,
he's round kicks and it was more like a
slap.
It didn't have the same kind of
penetration.
And when you see like a Maury Smith
where Pedro Hisdo to Eddie,
do you remember when you and I went to,
we went to Beverly Hills Jujitsu way
back in the day,
way back in the day.
You are purple belt went to Beverly
Hills and Jitsu and uh,
we watched marco who was kicked the bag.
Oh No,
no,
no.
Pedro Huizar was Pedro.
His,
oh,
was kicking the back.
Who else was too?
But Pedro,
his,
oh,
I never saw anybody in my life who had
lake kicks that were as scary as Pedro,
his,
oh,
I remember he kicked Rico Rodriguez once
when they fought and the thud,
the sub walk and you looked at it and
you went,
oh,
you can't take those.
There's no way.
No one's taking those.
You can only take so many of those.
Even randy couture was like,
yeah,
but he,
he was on the show and he goes,
look at my leg that's from fucking
fucked up forever for,
it's like a huge dent.
Like someone took a bat.
Does the same thing to randleman.
He would leave dense in you,
dude.
Do you remember?
Why?
Do you remember I was watching and
kicked the bag.
Do you remember that?
I think it was someone else we went to.
Beverly Hills should use who?
You weren't there?
No,
I'd never been in a beverly hills.
I've been there once and it wasn't with
those that toffel faulty memory.
It was you and me,
man.
What was weird too without fives.
Anthony goes,
I'll move on to something else.
And then his twitter background changes
the Los Angeles Rams.
He put the Hashtag La Rams and ma.
So all my friends are texting me and now
I judge them for it.
They're like,
oh bro,
he's played for the rams with you
fucking moron.
No,
he's not playing for the,
you know,
he's not fucking suiting up for the
rams.
I don't know if he's being a special
teams coach or some shit like that.
But he is not touching the field.
Catching footballs to tell you that
right now.
No.
He's got some sort of executive job.
Correct.
Is that what I've been hearing?
So this the rams helmet,
that's all he had?
Yes.
Okay.
What does this say anything there?
Was it say just La Rams?
Rumba Square Hashtag Rams.
Huh?
Well [inaudible] up as if he's the
mascot and he's the new la Ram.
That shit would be dope.
I think sometimes the job for that.
I'm not playing.
No,
you knuckleheads.
I'm not playing for the ramp that you
crazy.
That's hilarious.
I love it man.
Good for him.
Cause it's,
you know,
this come from a guy who retired early
or maybe one too late,
but for him to be able to do that,
the balls it takes,
especially you're talking about,
he's tip of the spear.
Number two could be anyone not named
Dco.
John Jones.
He can beat everybody else and he did
for him.
Like I'm good man,
I'm out.
It takes a lot of courage and balls man.
So I congratulate him on and I love that
he just goes out and says it.
I don't want to hit get hit in the head
anymore.
I don't want to wrestle with dues
Just came out though.
And I think people are shocked by that
when they hear,
you know,
nfl guy where they don't sit one when
their plane,
but then you find out later,
he's like,
dude,
I fucking hated playing.
It was the only thing I was good at and
I was making tons of money with Anthony
Johnson.
He's always stayed like,
yeah,
I don't really like to train man.
I like to get out and shit.
I like,
you know,
it's not my thing.
Yeah.
I just happened to have this fucking God
given power.
I'm really good at it.
I'm finding that light heavyweight now
get fame and money.
Oh,
another opportunity.
Fucking see.
Ya know,
there's nothing wrong with that.
Man Does.
Definitely nothing wrong.
People are surprised when they hear
professional athletes going.
Yeah,
I don't really enjoy it man.
I'm just really good at it.
You know what I man,
I'll never forget.
Well I appreciate his honesty because I
think that's it's,
it's when,
when a guy talks about it that way,
it's important.
Like for everybody.
Like I remember when Matt Hughes got
beaten by Bj Penn and Bj took the title
from him and uh,
I asked him about it in the interview
and he said,
honestly,
I have to tell you to relieve the
pressure.
Being a champion is a,
you know,
everybody coming after you.
It's honestly a relief.
Yeah.
Like balls at that guy has to say that
in front of all these people that it's a
real,
it means being completely honest.
It's cool man.
Cause,
especially as an athlete,
especially for Anthony Johnson guy who
he identifies as being justified or he's
rumble for him to go,
I'm good man.
Number two in the world.
See Ya.
God Dang it.
It's inspiring.
It should be inspiring to people.
It is.
I think it's inspiring and it's also
inspiring.
If he decides to take a year off and
then he goes,
fuck this desk job,
I want to kick somebody in the face.
I just needed a break.
Fucking great.
I'm just waiting for someone else to get
the belt because I can't beat DC.
You fools.
I mean,
isn't that an issue,
right?
The kind of out of money,
I need some money.
Fight.
Well,
he was smart with his money.
We're on the street.
That's good.
Wasn't angel was smart with the money.
But even that guy,
like people don't,
you know Anthony Johnson,
number two in the world has god given
power in his hands.
You got to realize as as a UFC fighter,
a tip of the spear and that it's just
where the sports that he's not set.
It's not like,
oh,
I'm see a fucking yachts in Miami and I
can do whatever I want and he's not set.
He never had a seven figure payday that
we know.
If you don't think doesn't work for her,
one of those title fights,
what do you think you got paid?
Which topic you're talking about with
the first one with DC and the second one
with DC?
Uh,
maybe.
I don't know what he got paid.
I'm not even speculating on the,
on the book.
He didn't get seven figures.
So how many legends in boxing retired
and then later came back because I
needed money.
Oh Jesus.
Bro.
Crazy.
We're making millions.
Yeah,
back in the 80s for sure.
But I think more than that,
like sugar ray come back,
came back.
He was still rich.
Yes.
We'll come back for the money.
Our Hopkins is set.
Some Jones might have some issues,
but he's with HBO.
But our husbands with HBO,
they do it for the love of the gay.
Most of those guys are set like just
fucking sick.
You know,
Bernard still drives an 89 civic cause
he doesn't want to go broke.
Um,
Bernard has a Bentley.
Does he have a bed liner?
There's a whole story about him driving
a Bentley and some kid drove the Bentley
Forum and the kid dental wheels got damn
fucked his wheel up forever.
Here.
This is world champion a civic for
Google that,
yeah,
you can find that forever.
This is what you guys on broke opposite
now.
Where did you get your story?
You,
you tell him.
Where'd you get your story about this
last one?
It was a story about him,
um,
that he was doing like a,
it was helping out this kid that was
terminally ill and uh,
how did his roles get brought up?
What was the,
the car,
the kid,
he let the kid drive the car and the kid
like a curved one of the wheels,
like fake news.
CNN Dude.
Either from the library.
I let Callan's friend drive my Bentley
and he fucked it up.
I didn't know he,
he,
he doesn't drive.
He just drives a a bike in New York and
he goes,
oh,
we're doing this,
we're doing this bit,
and we're filming it.
And this cop goes,
hey man,
I'm going to tow this car if you don't
leave.
And I go,
oh,
fuck when the middle of it.
And he goes,
dude,
I'll fucking whomever right down,
move on the spot.
And I go,
I don't let anyone drive my drive.
Very rarely even valley.
And I go,
all right.
I trust the guy who got damn near 60 I
toss them the keys.
He comes back to all good.
It's all good,
brother.
Cool.
I walked out there to the right,
parked down the street,
and this guy comes out from the house.
He goes,
dude,
I don't know who the fuck was driving
that car,
but he hit the shit out of the curb.
You know,
Bentley wheels are tough to come by.
I look at it and I'm just like,
oh,
mother fucker.
I got it fixed.
But it was a nightmare.
Did you bring it up to him?
No.
Wow.
Interesting.
Just swallowed it to bring it down on a
podcast.
Well,
no,
I'm not going to call his name.
You know,
it's been taken care of.
I just,
if I was younger on a flipped out,
but I was like,
I sat my,
currently it's just a car.
It's all right.
He didn't mean to man.
Life is good for you.
Did you say you have a Bentley?
Yeah,
exactly.
Nice Bentley continental gt supersport
supersport dope.
Tastic oh man.
It's a dope cards.
Kerosene.
It podcasts life before you had a
weight,
like a beam.
No,
not a porsche.
Porsche.
That's right.
Yeah.
He had a red nine 11 no,
and got to trip him m six that yeah,
those [inaudible] are smooth fuck
around.
Good size cause it's [inaudible] Park
cruiser but still sporty granturismo
style.
Like it's comfortable.
It's comfortable.
The bentleys cool out dead.
The best car I've ever had and I'll
always be loyal to them in his porsche.
It was the best car you've ever had.
That little car.
I love Porsche's,
man.
I just let the quality,
the customer service,
it's just,
it's different.
Bentley I had to take to get my fucking
rims fixed.
I took them in.
I mean they could give two fucks.
You know what the game is?
A rental mom,
Volvo.
And I was like,
what the fuck is this understated.
Yeah.
And they're like character for a few
days,
protection for a month.
A friend of mine,
a student of mine that had a lot of
money on a bet lean because you want to
borrow it for a month and tell a little
story like why he couldn't drive.
It's kind of hilarious.
Why couldn't dry dry?
He couldn't drive it.
Do you remember?
No,
he went away.
Yeah.
But do you remember why?
Why he didn't want to drive it anymore?
Because he owned a weed shop and the
cops did not like when people were
flaunting the trash and lot of money and
weed shops.
No,
I forgot.
You're right,
you're right.
So he got a dodge charger cause the cops
like it when you would drive the car
that they drive.
Like he had a whole psychological
approach.
This,
yeah.
He's like,
I'm going to get a dodge charger and put
some cool wheels on it because these two
were case fucking smart guy.
Man.
He was right because he's like,
you know,
these guys don't want you drive in
something they can never afford,
but if you're driving what they're
driving,
guys like cars,
so like,
oh,
he's was good charge though,
Dude.
I'm telling you.
You're not a cop.
If you were a cop and you had a,
this is it.
It makes sense.
No,
it doesn't.
Cops are so cool to me.
I get pulled over all the time.
You're big brown.
They're fighting the kid fans.
No,
for real man.
I think he was right.
I think when he said it to me,
I was like,
that totally makes sense.
He goes,
yeah.
they'd like,
he was a friend of mine's a cop.
It's like they tell you they like it the
best.
Your best chances of them like treating
you like one of them drive what they
drive.
Drive a fucking charger,
charger fucking baby.
He says,
boy,
I would drive a charger.
Srt trying to drive a hellcat ridiculous
car.
I'd drive that demon challenge.
You know,
that's like $135,000 at walnuts.
How loan itself.
It makes my dick hard as dodge has come
out with the most preposterous car in
all of mantle hurts my heart and 850
horsepower,
it goes zero to 60 in 2.3 seconds.
It's called the dodge demon.
They took a dodge challenger,
put this ridiculous hood scoop on it,
but fender flares on it,
widen all the wheels and dumped the most
insane engine than anybody's ever put
into production because it's so God damn
American.
It's not even funny.
It's,
it's a eagle suck on that.
It's an eagle getting his dick sucked
while he's holding a flag gone.
And the other one with the Statue of
Liberty.
So Lydia,
I'm like just fucking go look at that.
808 horsepower.
17 pound feet of torque.
That is fucking insane.
There's only a thousand on he shit.
Fucking get one.
Yeah,
you can't get one.
Everyone's going to be clean asylums.
But why?
Look at the giant fucking hold on back
that up again.
Where the size tires in the rear.
Back it up just a little bit there.
A little bit further.
There it goes.
Okay,
so they got forties in the rear.
That's pretty,
what production does that mean at least
a hundred is that what they're saying?
Production car.
They keep calling it a production of
fastest production car.
It means,
it's not like,
you know,
super like there's not like 10 of them.
Why did they put little tiny wheels in
the front?
That's not the original.
That's not the wheels that are coming
with the car.
Right.
That's what it has to wheels.
Trying to make them do wheelies.
I think they put those little tiny
wheels in the front because they're
trying to make the car do wheelies,
but I'm assuming because it does pull a
wheelie.
It's the first production ever.
Yes.
I don't need a Wheelie,
but I think one of the ways they get it
to do a wheelies,
they put little skinny tires on it.
It comes,
it comes with one seat.
It only comes with one seat saying car.
This is a car that says,
fuck.
You just said you get the second seat
for a dollar.
Oh,
that's it.
But if it comes with one that's kind of
dope.
I want my friends to jump in.
It's just the biggest fuck you car.
You drive how we got one seat Bro.
That way,
that way you have a good excuse not to
bring the wife.
Oh it says it costs less than a hundred
thousand dollars.
That's what they say.
So hey,
it's only be $88,000.
Put the dealers do the markup to the
demand so you're fucked.
Oh the markups probably going to be
100%.
You'll get one right now if I could.
And just fucking cruise the streets
shitting on people.
You know,
it's hilarious.
They had this,
uh,
they're talking about the Ford Mustang
gt three 50,
the shelby gt Cobra Dope car.
And they're talking about it keeping it
around two to 2018 and I looked at the
numbers like the zero to 60 numbers and
they're really great.
It's like 4.1 with the stick,
3.9 with the automatic and um,
you know,
they have a 10 speed automatic.
I'm like,
what a bad ass car.
But then you compare it to that.
You like this,
all that thing.
What do you drive?
Who makes shitty,
shitty cars out there.
Really make shitty cars anymore.
Can't get away with it.
It's too many.
Look,
they're making new cars constantly like
that's one of the craziest things about
cars.
They need consistent innovation.
Every year there's zero to 60 time gets
better.
Their gs g force get better.
The Mile Mile per gallon get better and
better in your mouth.
Again,
Mary Ross 30 it's been 30 since I was 12
but a porch twin turbo gets 30 when the
fast cars on the planet and all wheel
drive at all.
Cars are not really,
not really it.
You don't try it like funny drove
supercar gets 24 miles.
It's crazy.
Put a bull up.
Nine nine one nine 11 turbo miles per
gallon.
It should be 200 miles to the gallon by
now.
It's like I smell conspiracy theory
coming up this up.
It's like if you see him getting ready
to go to for the twister role,
he might give you a little towel.
See the seminar.
I'm crazy.
He always went with it.
With the Indians.
Was there ever an md and the Indians
would have let him the slaves,
the Indians would have led to this lake.
That's a key and peele movie right
there.
Black Indians and there's a bunch of
butter is a book about it.
He goes to been some you fucked up.
They fucked up letting big dixon the TPU
knowing that it'll be different.
It'll be different now folks,
you girls are like,
all right,
well but I want to how many,
I wonder how common that was and I
wonder who,
what,
um,
whether it was white people or whether
it was,
you know,
White Europeans or slaves who bred with
racist town.
You,
they escaped
to the Indians so they can make go 27
highway,
20 city.
You have a super car.
It's amazing.
No,
don't get me wrong.
Look,
that car might be the best car in the
world and you just think about the best
all around car hands down nine 11 turbo.
You drive that thing.
It drives like a,
like a regular car.
It feels great.
Like it smoothed over bumps and shit.
It's the,
the dampening system that they have.
It's all electronically controlled.
It seems to be able to predict what the
ground is like and adjust to like
different bumps in the road.
Like really well the best.
Hey,
that was 2015 I'm talking about to then
18th they even better.
That was to them.
15 10th and then he got probably a few
miles per gallon.
Right?
Yeah man.
But those cars are zero to 60 in 2.5
seconds.
It's best code on the road.
Four wheel drive for pound money from,
yeah,
it's the best.
They just look man.
There's something about Japanese
engineering and German engineering that
is hard to fuck with.
I don't fuck with the Japanese.
They never branched tag,
no racist.
They never break.
I buy Japanese cars all the time.
That's like my always,
that's us.
Yeah.
Like I love Lexus because it's like,
you know when you get in that fucking
thing,
every time you press that button it
starts out on the stone every time.
Yeah.
Every time you bought a fancy Toyota
Tundra,
watch your mouth Toyota and drag.
Nothing wrong with Toyota.
I'm just saying it's compared to German
though and I just chill him.
That hundred bay.
But here's the thing Jeremy,
the interior on German cars bed the
best.
Yeah.
Well their engineering is so sporty too.
Like the Japanese don't really make a
car like a nine 11 gt three they don't
really make that.
They make these track cars that work
really fascinating track like like the
Nissan Gtr,
but that's like super electronic.
When you get in that thing,
it's like a spaceship dude.
That thing is incredible.
Like levels you out.
Like when you go in and take turns,
you actually feel it flattened the body
out.
With electronics,
it turns like this.
Like you're you,
you can make a hard turn and there's no
body lean.
It's weird.
What else?
And then the Acura Nsx dead,
the new ones,
insane.
The new NSX is insane to hybrid engines
and the front wheels,
first rye weapons grade nine 11 what
does it say there with the Myob ground?
2029 wow.
Yeah.
29 Porsche nine 11 it's my fave.
It's a beast car.
Those are super reliable too for the
most so reliable.
But it's just the engineering has to get
better and better every year.
So they're sharpening this razor's edge.
They're developing these cars that like,
like there's,
there's skid pad numbers that used to be
ridiculous like one g and a skid pad.
Like God,
it would have to be like a Ferrari f 40
or something like that.
You know,
now you get that shit out of a BMW m
three like everything does a g on the
skid pad and those corvettes like grand
sport corvettes,
they do ridiculous.
He received the Viper ACR.
Fuck,
you can just buy a fucking 660
horsepower race car from viper.
I'd be lying if I didn't say I was
online last night.
How about I've done it three nights a
week
for a month.
Three nights a week for a tough nut to
pull the trigger.
I've watched every fucking viper video
they have.
It's the most retarded American car
ever.
It literally but fucks the demon cause
it's so ridiculous.
The demons still looks like a
challenger.
I agree.
This things is Saint Paul,
but viper acr 2017 please people that
should just be like,
you know what?
Fuck you man.
How about that,
but fun or you do.
What are you doing?
Fast and furious.
Look at a wing on that fucking thing.
That is an insane car and it's breaking
records at every single race track all
over the world.
Heard it too.
It sounds amazing.
See that?
That one right there is a regular viper,
which is still pretty dope.
That's just look for the viper srt ACR.
The SRT ACR is the crazy one.
That's the one that they just built for
racing.
There's a margaret.
Oh,
fucking for sure.
Actually.
I heard they're having a hard time
selling them.
Well,
make sense?
Yeah,
because people are like enough terms.
We trump's president and this will you
remember when the vipers first came out
as 500 horsepower,
500 pounds of Torque and there's so many
crashes because guys just didn't know
how to deal with it.
They'd go around the corners and just
fucking also,
they didn't have antilock brakes.
The old vipers had nothing.
I rented an old viper once.
Beat the fuck out of borrowing to buy
one just to fuck around La didn't the
Viper Jack for a while it was a
shambles.
They were considered like vanilla ice of
cars.
Right?
Yeah.
See there he is with the extreme arrow.
Pat.
Such a good looking car.
Extreme aero package.
They literally have a giant race car
wing in the back of it.
But it's so ferocious that though I feel
like until you are so excited.
I know this is a car that girls would
get mad at you if you buy like your wife
like printing.
What the fuck?
That's like buying like getting bigger,
bigger tits.
Yeah.
You be like when you're trying it cause
I'm awesome.
Look at that stop right there in red.
I usually don't like a red car back that
bitch up.
I loved the way that thing looks red.
That's a,
that's a bad ass fucking thing is so
hard.
That is about as American as it gets.
I mean it's so much more bad ass look
and then a corvette.
Oh way more.
And of course that's pretty bad ass.
Look at corporates.
Don't do it for me.
Oh fuck with him.
You know?
At the end of the day,
man,
it's like we're still little boys.
Fuck yeah.
You said you look at him three times a
week.
Literally last night I was like,
God,
should I just buy one?
It doesn't make any sense.
It makes no sense.
Look at that thing.
It's a beast.
It's such a beast.
It must be so fun.
See Fun.
Yeah.
At the end of the day,
it's fun.
It's just a different kind of experience
and gets about three month negative
three miles a gallon with a really big
too.
Here's the other one.
They have that they're wide and they
have this really long hood.
It's not giant engine.
Yeah.
It's not like you're,
when you drive in a Porsche,
one of the weird things about is it's
rear engine,
so your front end,
you get a really good clear view of the
road.
Like you remember that Nsx and add
Eddie.
That's so renaissance yet,
dude,
I'd love that.
Thanks to day.
I reminisce about that car shit hung on
again.
Boom.
Started every time.
Not a fucking problem ever.
Boom.
You have problems like I haven't had a
lot of problems.
I had a porsche that shit out on me.
Nine 11 turbo.
Um,
2002 it did a lot of problems.
Turbos 99 long time for a long time.
Super.
Two and 93 or what the kid oh and a
Toyota super turbo in 1994.
Yeah.
You fucking with me.
I'm not to fuck with you Tara Grip.
So I just fucking walked in the door.
You got an m six and I spent every
goddamn dime I had to get punched in the
face on that thing and it was used.
Very different approach.
Oh I'm Oh us Hoodrich for awhile there.
That's what I had.
That's one of the greatest coaches of
all time out of silver one.
They're worth a lot of money now too.
It's crazy.
Well they there,
there's something special mat and do
those.
Hey heto hillis jump on it.
I know,
right?
Come up with a new one.
I think they are as a matter of fact,
but it's just,
you know,
there's something to stout that Porsche
has figured out how to capture where
they have a look that it looks like a
nine 11 every he is guys do it.
They have to start from scratch like a
new fucking car because remember back
then it was the Toyota supra,
the rx seven.
Those were like the ones like seven and
then there was the Mitsubishi gt 3000 I
like that one.
Look at that shit.
Go back to that black one.
That's the same car.
This is the new one.
Holy Shit.
Back what?
I said.
This one's doper.
If they come,
they actually come out with this was
this say it says ft one digital.
Get that down.
I'm not 20 is that a real image or is
that a computer created in image
computer shit,
isn't it?
It's hard to tell.
They're so good at it now.
I know.
You know I mean damn.
Oh it looks like it's real.
That concept.
But as that a concept is that,
oh,
it's all bullshit.
You can change the colors of it.
Never got the collars are gross.
Just give people like shit.
How about the fan?
The paint and the color makes no
difference.
Well it tells it some cars,
some cars just look goofy.
Certain colors.
Like if you ever see a yellow Ferrari
and you're like relax buddy,
just screaming.
I have a small deck.
It's just I dude,
I get it.
You're single.
You do spray tans,
a black Ferrari.
You might have like a crib in downtown
La.
We have incense burning before you even
walk in taking people.
Dan.
Yeah,
you Dick and people down and like one of
those warehouse apartments and you know
those types of the case Laura curtains
and you have a little wine fridge dress.
Well probably a good dude like one of
them movies where like that dude is like
a secret scientist and he lives in a
loft and he's got like his couch in the
middle of the loft with like a carpet
there.
But everything else is that Polish to
doesn't have a TV,
doesn't have time to watch TV.
TV's for pussies,
only wine mount here reading books and
doing Kung Fu.
Fucking fucking everything that comes in
that door.
But you get a yellow green.
No Sir,
you're up in the Hollywood hills.
You probably got herpes.
Just,
yeah man.
You can't have no,
they won't even let you in downtown with
Bro.
You gotta be more new.
Are you going to be darker and more
mysterious?
Windows?
It's weird.
There's certain things about certain
color cars,
but then there's like classics.
Like if a guy has like a 1971 red
porsche,
no,
it's beautiful car.
It's a classic color.
If it's in red,
it's a classic color.
But like a brand new red car,
like it's gotta be like that Viper.
It has to be some touch has to be
certain cars and then you know,
even a Porsche,
cause when I bought my porsche is red.
He goes,
you know,
they,
they don't make a lot of these,
cause a lot of people that don't want
red,
they don't want the attention.
Your insurance is higher.
The cops look for you like it's classic.
They're like,
people are going away from it.
It is weird.
Red is like,
go fuck you.
Look what about those magnum Pi Red
Ferraris or they classics now or people
bringing them g two three 50 40 gt 40
Gina said it is a three 50 bringing
those back.
The classics now,
right.
It should be worth a lot of money.
I want to,
I wanted to buy lower deloreans are they
or they come back,
they must be deloreans are back steel.
Yo girl,
I'm tired.
No socks.
Sling and Dick would an old school cop
called stash.
Ooh God damn has those boat shoes on.
Just that fat dick in the front from
magnum Pi doesn't even care if his feet
stink.
The sling sling dick with stinky shoes.
He was,
I would drive that conservative.
He's super conservative.
He's the guy that got on Rosie O'donnell
show and she famously sort of attacked
him for supporting the MRA and
connecting him to shootings.
He's,
which one of the greatest Americans
can't understand what she was trying to
do.
And I understand her sentiment.
I met Rosie O'donnell and I did her show
and I think she's a nice person.
She's just think that like things like
that are ill advised,
you know,
and that people got real mad at her man.
All those fucking NRA people due to
view,
if you talk anti second amendment,
they come with the force.
They fucking come after you.
Good.
Yeah.
Well if they didn't,
they would have lost the right a long
time ago.
There's a lot of people that would like
take those rights away.
My boy Tom Selleck went on there.
We can only hit diamond piece talking
about guns.
Tom Selleck didn't go on it and talk
Agree.
Went on there to talk about something
else.
Just promoting something and she wanted
to bring up the NRA and you know,
he was upset about it.
But I think if you're talking about a
gun violence,
like there's a lot,
there's a lot of factors and it comes to
gun violence and you can get really
crazy.
But one of them is that it's all men.
How about that?
How about we just ban all men because
all men are responsible for mass
shootings.
It's fucking all men.
It's never chicks.
So what
do we do?
We ban all men because without the men,
the guns don't even work.
So okay,
we're not banning all men.
So should we ban all guns?
Yeah,
we should definitely been all guns.
Okay,
well,
if we're going to ban all guns,
how come only a certain percentage of
the guns get used in these crimes?
What about all those other people that
are lawful law abiding Americans who are
kind and peaceful and keep John guns for
personal security or for hunting?
Do we take them away from them and who
gets to decide?
That's where the problem lay.
The problem doesn't lay in the idea that
she's stepping in because she's got this
thing in front of her and she sees it's
a problem.
She wants to talk about the problem.
The problem is that the problem is
multifaceted and it's not just all men.
The number of these men that are
medicated on pharmaceutical drugs is
fucking staggering.
And then they say correlation does not
equal causation.
So you can't assume that just because
someone's on pills that that makes
people shoot people.
But damn,
it's close.
It's,
there's something in there.
There's something going on there.
[inaudible] psychoactive drugs are
responsible for some changes in your
behavior.
That's a fact.
It's undeniable.
How much is debatable and how much of
these disassociative sorta drugs allow
people to just like blank out and go and
do wacky shit.
Different people with different brain
chemistry.
Who the fuck knows?
Did you,
did you see the facebook killer?
He actually committed suicide today,
but here he was going around killing
people and doing it live on facebook and
they were saying people were upset at
facebook going,
what the fuck man,
you allow him to do this?
And they're like,
yeah,
we're going to change some of the rules.
The cops said that he didn't do that.
They wasn't streaming.
He uploaded upload it later.
So they're like,
well,
you know,
we'll watch that more.
But then I saw a cop was like,
it actually helps us like in if you
didn't commit suicide,
like there's times where there's been
other crimes that people do when they
hear it live or upload it to facebook or
they rob a bank.
Then posts like could rich with cash and
they actually helps the cops track him
down.
So like,
I don't know if you should go away with
it because,
well there's not kill regardless.
Now they're just,
you know,
they can upload it on youtube or
wherever.
They might take it down,
but they're like,
we shouldn't stop it.
Cause that you're helping on a little
bit.
Yeah.
It's a good excuse to go in there and
control the Internet.
I mean,
who knows?
It sounds like that could easily be a
false flag.
Is there any,
uh,
well,
it's not a false flag.
There's definitely a dead guy and he's
definitely a guy who killed himself.
So same thing.
I think more often then they're being
false flags is a,
is an event happens and people try to
take advantage of that event and they
try to make it easier on themselves,
especially law enforcement might try to
make it easy on themselves and enforce
laws,
especially politicians might take it as
an opportunity to push their agenda,
their constituents want.
There's a lot of factors when it comes
into dealing with any kind of gun
violence,
but it's a multifaceted issue and you
don't take it up with Tom Selleck.
Okay.
Magnum fucking Pii is not the reason why
their school shooters,
Tak Mak,
just because,
because he has a lawful gun permit and
because he joined the NRA cause he
believes in the right to keep and bear
arms.
The real problem is people that are
willing to kill a bunch of other people.
It's not the guns.
It's not
that they're men.
It's not neither one of those two
incredibly common factors.
Guns and men.
I always think it's weird too,
whenever there's a shooter,
like with this whole facebook fucking
killer in Ohio,
ruins like,
oh,
mental illness.
Yeah.
God,
I don't know if you can just chalk it up
to mental illness all the time.
Some donuts it's medicated too,
but sometimes,
but then sometimes he just a fuck the,
there's a lot of bad apples to me.
Just a bad dude like when he was on
there and why are watching all someone
down a weird rabbit hole on Easter.
But when he was,
he was on there just talking,
you know,
coherently being like,
I've worked at this job forever.
People Shit on me.
My girl just broke up with me.
I'm fucking sick of this man.
I'm going to go around killing people
because I'm pissed off at the world.
Fuck this.
Yeah.
Well the problem is someone who has that
attitude lacks empathy and the,
it's not normal.
So the question is like,
how does someone get to that stage where
they're completely void of empathy?
That's what scares the fuck out of
people.
What doesn't scare the fuck out of
people is that people were willing to
kill to defend their loved ones or any
of that shit.
What bothers people is people that don't
have any empathy.
People that want to go fuck the world or
fuck you and fuck everything and then
just hurt people and laugh.
What would he be that way if he didn't
get whatever's coworkers were picking on
him?
Who knows?
Like,
is it a mental illness because he's
getting picked on or with is it this is
this,
is this backlash to that bullying or his
girl breaking up with them because it is
small.
Daikin,
he was fat.
There's lot of factors there that could
be a part of it.
I'm saying overall proximal and just be
a bad apple man and just,
it was like fuck this,
the world,
this world sucks man.
It's possible.
I mean we just,
I my my,
my whole thing here is,
I just think we chalked up mental
illness too easily.
Well I think what you're talking about
though is mental illness.
I mean what I'm saying is that anybody
that's willing to kill people like that
is mentally ill and you could say like,
oh,
how to define it.
Is it herpes?
You know,
is it the flu?
But I think the lack of empathy is in
itself a disconnect from the human race
and can make you mentally ill.
Like you could classify someone as
mentally ill.
The problem is anybody could be mentally
ill.
If you get born into the wrong
situation,
you get abused and grow up,
fucked up.
Your brain is all hardwired to have.
You're stressed out all the time and all
the people around,
you're all fucking crazy and you're
just,
your cortisol levels are off the charts.
We all have the potential to lose our
fucking mind.
All of us do.
Or He,
you know,
you grew up desensitized where you see
the struggles of life.
It's like life doesn't own shit.
You see your friends and stuff like
that.
You're like,
God,
this sucks man.
Who Cares?
And I think it's super important that we
have empathy for people like that.
Should we understand that?
That could have easily been us.
You know,
the people get born into terrible,
terrible situations and he probably
would have you eaten over there bro?
She's got bro.
She got bro,
which got bro.
Oh,
that's one of them.
Peanut butter bars.
Those are delish.
Those are good when they're called.
Um,
rx bars,
three egg whites,
14 peanuts to dates,
no bs.
That's all.
It's in there.
Those are legit.
Those are good.
It's better than the rx bar.
Um,
I like the peanut butter by,
but I like that dark chocolate.
When you a two you couldn't handle it
well.
Yeah.
Too much for you.
Too much flavor.
It's a little too much.
I like it.
I like fucked up flavors though.
I am convinced that what one person
tastes.
I don't taste.
I'm just fucking convinced why like real
bitter stuff.
Like my coffee,
I get like super strong.
Like callan tries like do this tastes
like cigarette ashes.
I'm like,
yeah,
like it's super like,
I like real bitter like coffee.
I like a strong coffee too.
I like a good a dark roast your ass on
that.
That light roast.
Get the fuck out of me.
I get super bummed out when someone
pours me and I see the,
the coffee going down right away.
See through any deal.
I'm like,
well if this place sucks,
they chasse coffee,
gas lemonade out of my fucking face that
tea out of my God damn coffee shop.
Sometimes it looks like d.
I can tell on the only I need to get the
fuck out of here.
I'm one of those,
you know those Nespresso things.
You have those little capsules.
I'm a curious man.
I don't fuck with no prep.
Nespresso.
I like him.
You know why?
Cause you can make espresso like that.
You can make espresso like that.
Like you're out there fucking with a
spoon.
It tap,
tap,
tap on the,
you need to get espresso with a tesla.
Like is that like,
you know what I'm saying?
Like grass,
like a goddamn gangster.
I like that dark as fuck.
I pour it little home and milk.
I take three espressos from an espresso.
I don't fuck with her.
Bad for the environment too.
It's great for my stomach.
Why is it bad for the environment?
The birds?
Yeah.
Then the guy,
the guy who created those craig things
in the nurse suppressed so they can't
recycle them and that was nothing to do
with him.
And he's like,
I fucked up.
I wish I could stop it.
But he gave the,
the,
the formula to someone who ran with it.
Often the espresso should and they did
it and now it's fucking people up.
Do you know that they could do that
easily with almost everything that we
make with hemp,
but then just refuse to because they
want the cotton business now they don't
have a full whole,
he just grabbed that microphone was
like,
we're about to spit knowledge.
[inaudible]
it's own.
Say cotton business.
Someone said conspiracy and have been
one sentence.
You know what?
I was like,
I was sitting here thinking,
damn,
this podcast has so much power.
You're gonna,
you're going to bring back cars.
You know you're getting me into cars.
Bring back cars.
Cars never went anywhere,
but they're fucking here.
I'll take it.
Cool.
For younger people,
younger people love cars.
Everybody loves cars.
If you raise them right,
not only rich people like cars.
That is one thing that is true because I
did ignore cars when I was broke.
I was like,
that is Karma.
Goddamn could cut that part of my head.
And then once I started making some
money,
I was like,
oh,
loosen up the reins z here,
man.
Time to go back to what I enjoy.
When I was a kid,
I had a bunch of muscle cars.
I had a gang of different kind of muscle
cars,
broke people that know everything about
sports cars and the latest shit.
Damn.
That wasn't new.
Right when I was a kid I knew a lot
about muscle cars.
I didn't know a lot about like Porsche's
or Ferrari's.
Those all seemed like way out of range.
But I know a lot about like 69 mustangs,
1970 barracudas that kind of shit.
I loved the Porsche's cause my Stepdad
was the best Porsche mechanic in Newport
beach day got kill was the shit as the
mechanic.
He worked in Newport beach and so he,
I knew about Porsche's through him.
Like I knew what a nine 11 was when I
was years old.
Nine 28,
nine 44 I was kind of hip to it just
because of him.
Um,
there was this one got strip club,
these to show up in a cause,
you know,
there's that nine 24,
those are the cheap ones.
He would switch it and he made it.
He put a nine 28 and he would drive to
the Strip club and tell girls got at
nine 28 and get the girls,
I'll wait a minute.
He said he got a nine 44 but you know
the nine 24 hours or the low level ones
right in the nine 44 was like you know
rich rich guys pull eight at nine 59 you
get dude suck your Dick guys.
I miss that one.
I didn't know that was a nine 15 due to
choose to work with on news radio who
was a camera man who got a nine 24 and
would race it and he said it was the one
of the best cars for racing is it's
really well balanced.
It,
it didn't have a lot of power but he
knew a lot about racing cars.
He must have.
Yeah,
he's like he did.
They don't have a lot of power but the
thing is around race tracks,
it's more about handling.
It is about power until you get to those
like crazy high end nine 11 turbo,
four wheel drive,
motherfuckers,
that kind of shit.
Those things are just ridiculous.
You know the,
the new nine 11 turbo,
the wheels turn the back wheels turn.
So when you're going around a corner,
yeah,
the back wheels,
they turn and make the corner shorter
dude.
And it's good.
They turn the opposite way in parking
lots to make it so you can,
you can pull in the spots easier.
The bus.
Yeah.
Like your attorney radios is off the
chart that they're ridiculous.
There's the engineering man.
You guys going to get into helicopters
and shit?
Nah Man,
that's too [inaudible] about that shit.
Helicopter money.
Do you ever look on Bill Belichick all
that's right,
huh?
Yeah,
he gets places.
He's like,
he goes from,
he's got a helicopter and he did a Gig
in San Diego and he flew a helicopter,
uh,
out of a la and fluid down to San Diego
with his,
uh,
instructor Pii helicopter.
Like the little bubble one.
Are we talking about like fucking Marine
One shit?
I don't think you can get a marine one
for rental bill [inaudible] my makes
good money,
but he's not stupid to me in the world
right now.
No,
Kevin Artists,
I'm saying as far as funny lies,
he's probably up there.
It's him,
it's him or Chappelle or Louis C k there
was,
that's probably the battle.
But they're new.
And I watched him back the back of the
comedy store and I was just like,
not,
it's so inspiring.
But his shit,
I was laughing so hard,
man.
Dude,
he's so fucking his,
some of his new
shit that I want to say the premise,
but it's so good.
I do.
I was laughing the premises.
I'm like,
of course,
man,
that's fucking brilliant.
And then I watched you,
I,
you know,
I see at the store at 10 so I'll watch
your sets.
And I was baffled how just I,
I,
you know,
I'm new to,
it's,
I don't know how you went from,
you did three sets.
I'm followed along with your three sets.
How he changed them like on the go while
I'm trying to figure out the right way
to do it.
It's good,
but it's bad because sometimes you go
the wrong way because I fuck around so
much because I changed my materials so
much.
I changed the approach,
I tried to change how I set it up.
I tried to figure out what's the best
way to do it.
I feel like once I settle in on one way,
our whole net one way,
but I don't even know if that's the
right way.
So I tried different ways and sometimes
those ways to take me nowhere.
That's how you know though,
right?
Yeah.
But that's what the store is for.
You know,
the store,
like what I'm doing is trying shit out.
No.
Says when I see them doing a set,
like once you do a special,
then the months after the special it's,
or like some of your materials fucking
shaking,
you know,
and it will eventually hammer together.
But on nights,
some nights it's perfect and on some
nights you don't really have the
approach.
Correct.
It's like coming in for a landing,
you know,
I,
I saw uh,
uh,
Chris rock get up there and just like
riff.
Literally he was just like,
what?
And you could tell he just had nothing.
Who's just going and it's off the
brilliant still.
Well,
you've always been,
you know,
very few people have seen you live war
than me,
very few people for a few years there.
I saw you live pretty much every time
you,
you did a show and um,
you have your bits that are worked out
and some that you're working out.
Um,
but every night you went up and you mix
the totally different like a DJ.
There were the same bits and you were
working on them.
But um,
it was a different mix every night.
You never did shit in a row.
That was nothing.
It was all you just flowing.
The problem with that is when you do two
shows and you're on the second show,
like what the fuck did I say?
Have I done this one yet or was it the
earlier show?
The second show just gotta be more rigid
and a show is a different mix.
You don't ever do the same shit twice.
It's a different mix.
I don't know if you've changed recently
because of all your specials,
but every show I've never saw the same
show twice.
Never same bits,
but always mixed.
It's always a different segue.
You,
oh,
it was,
it was fun for you.
And I thought that was just definitely,
that's part of it.
You want to keep it fresh,
but you also,
it's all about trying to figure out what
the right way to do it is.
And you know,
I got to try it like eight wrong ways to
get the right way.
I'll tell you what else was crazy.
As I'm reading that jet APP towel book
sick in the head and he,
uh,
they came,
I was going on the same show and they
come in like,
hey,
um,
judd's going to jump on before.
I'm like,
who's Judd Apatow Malik?
Oh Shit.
And he walks back.
Now you know,
you don't want to be that fucking Dick
sucker.
But we just started talking.
I didn't know how cool he is going to
be.
I don't know anything about him besides
that book in his movies.
And then I'll sit in there and he's
like,
you got a man.
I'm like,
I don't,
and then we started talking to super
cool now I was just like,
dude,
your buck and which gone to the book,
he was the nicest guy ever.
Man.
He's very,
very nice.
He's super down Earth,
easy to talk to.
People don't realize that.
Like he wrote for a Roseanne Barr,
Tom Arnold,
like Adam Sandler,
like he's wrote for a ton of guys,
which I find is interesting cause he's a
standup comic,
but he would write for other people.
That's just cause he's not a performer.
So you'd rather just write for them.
It's like why not do it yourself?
Well I think he just was real busy.
I think when you're producing movies and
stuff and doing all the shit that he
did,
I don't think he had the time to go to
the clubs and to do standup.
Right.
You got to go to the clubs.
He got to fuck around like like that
other night that I'm talking about.
We were talking about rather where you
see me doing all these different sets.
Everybody does that.
You know,
if you see Louie at the Improv,
you'll see him later that night at the
store.
You know these guys are,
they're hopping on and they're,
they're trying to mix stuff up and it
doesn't,
doesn't Louis say that you it to get
really good at stem should only be doing
that.
It's what he said the other night we
were talking,
he said he'd only,
he'd been doing nothing but stand up for
the last two years and he was saying,
you know what,
you could be good and do other stuff but
to really be your best you have to do
only stand up.
And I'm like,
I think you're right.
I think he's right.
I mean it makes sense.
Would you be happy doing just stand up
though?
I would always do a podcast I think,
I mean I don't think you would have to
just get rid of podcasting.
I feel like it helps you with Id.
UFC would definitely,
I would definitely have to get rid of
the OFC and I think that's probably
going to happen eventually anyway.
But the,
the thing that you get from podcasting
is you almost get like an education,
cause I,
it's a,
it's a pretty peripheral education when
it turns cer certain things that people
say to me,
cause I'm listening to you say it and it
blows me away,
but I only retain a certain percentage
of it unless I listened to the pot.
Like Lawrence Krauss is a theoretical
physicist that I had on was trying to
explain some theories to me and I was,
my stupid brain was just not taking it
in.
And then,
you know,
uh,
I had Dennis Mckenna on yesterday who's,
you know,
psychedelic pioneer and he's a,
what is his,
he's ethnobotanist and he's a professor
and he's a fucking insanely smart guy.
So I,
I'd have to listen to that two or three
times he's explained to me the,
um,
the reason why certain drugs work so
well,
like in particular mosque mushrooms,
and he was explained,
pulled up like our molecule chart.
It was explaining to us the difference
between the molecules that are connected
to silicide been versus the molecules
that make dmt to,
it's really just one thing off.
Oh,
it's off the charts deep.
So,
but I feel like those kind of
conversations they make me,
they make me smarter.
You know what made me more aware of
Shit,
which is great for standup.
It's better for standup.
Yeah.
I'll tell you who's a smart motherfucker
did change lanes here,
but I had a meeting with Aubrey Marcus.
He know,
I know Aubrey,
like you as a friend and we know we've
done some business together and we're in
this meeting and I looked down and said,
what kind of fucking Alpha brain a ut
and he came in a suit was all,
it's just start spinning like God damn,
there's a reason why he's at where he's
at.
And he's a smart dude.
He's very tuned.
I honestly didn't think he was a stupid
human being,
but he was dropping some fucking
knowledge.
Yeah,
give me whatever you're taking.
He's very smart.
And he also,
he knows a ton,
especially from this business about
nutrient absorption.
Yes.
What yet,
like you know,
certain foods that you can eat where you
really only absorb surrounded nutrients
if it's connected to fats and things
like that.
He's an expert on that shit.
He knows a lot about where man,
his mom was a,
she was like a natural path or something
like that.
Was She?
Yeah,
something like that.
Uh,
but he's,
he's been pretty knowledgeable about
that kind of stuff for a long time and
he's a unique dude who's a lot of,
you know,
we're really lucky.
We know a lot of really unique people,
you know?
Yeah.
Fo Sho.
Silas,
let's start Kim.
See those videos of people worshiping
him like he had the Beatles have to,
did you see the one where they almost,
it's almost too ridiculous.
Like they are chasing him through the
streets and soldiers acting like little
girls.
To me.
It's on believeable.
Yeah,
they literally have to.
Matt,
did you ever see with a curious,
fascinating.
It's very fascinating how that like,
it's a terrible mind boggling.
North Korea is,
it's amazing videos.
People,
we're shipping him and then you watch,
there's documentaries of people going
in.
They get inside and they,
and they're like constantly being guided
through North Korea.
There are people with them that there's
fake.
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
Most people think,
look there.
So communists they're putting on this is
like a,
yeah,
they're putting on a show.
It's obvious that they're,
they're,
they're giving them a tour of the city,
but they're being guided the whole way
through.
They got people on them and they're not
allowed to do shit.
You see Shane Smith saying when he went
to North Korea,
so most people are thinking,
man,
they're show communists or whatever or,
or,
uh,
the,
the dictatorship is so strong there
that,
look,
they won't even let people walk around
freely.
You know,
it's like,
it just seems like,
is that what the fuck is going on with,
I don't know.
I don't want,
do you think there's a conspiracy in the
conspiracy?
I think maybe.
Is this a double negative fucking double
cross?
Oh,
he,
oh,
they're testing missiles.
Did you see that shit?
If blue scene,
the parade show,
the clip of the parade where they show
them like the soldiers marching in a
parade and then the floods it on and
then the bringing out the missiles,
they said they'll show the show that and
then they'll cut the gym home long.
Or Jim?
Kim Jong Ou.
Yeah,
with his genitals.
Like there's a clip of like like they're
like,
no,
like kind of watching and they're kind
of,
and then they cut back to the brain and
it's the clip
and then they go back to Kim Gen ed
just,
I dunno and you're not buying it I
think.
Well here's what you have put.
Let me just wait before you go any
further.
Let me just explain what the
distractions do you stock footage when
they have stories on these guys and they
use it all the time where they don't
have footage of the guy currently,
so they have a story about Kim Jon when
they start talking about them and then
they show stock footage.
That stock footage could be him to open
his career releases video.
Understand that's what it was.
It was like,
this is lower buddies are trained just
to move like that though.
There's no head there.
It's a communist dictatorship.
Fake cities and shit.
Yeah.
Well that's China.
China has more than China.
It does to write out the board or they
have like two Indians.
The people of the south to come to North
Korea.
They,
I think North Korea really needs to be
looked into because you think it's fake.
If you go to war world son,
you think North Korea is fake?
I'm not saying it's fake.
I'm just saying it's saying that it's
fake.
I'm just saying that Kim Jong Il could
eat,
I think might be part of,
I think they're all buddies.
I think at the very top,
the top of Russia,
the top of the United States,
the UK,
they're just putting on a show and he's
designated villain.
When we need to distract people from
this or that fucking he,
Oh Kim Jong is a kill.
A lot of people testing,
testing and missiles did.
He's testing missiles.
He said he's going to fire off one,
but in China it's very possible that
we've changed our foreign policy and
that we're getting more aggressive with
them and this is their response and that
they also are very incompetent because
they are terrified they're there.
What they are essentially is a military
dictatorship.
There were terrified population and
their science is shitty.
They don't have any,
but we're getting all this from doing
hamstring media,
so like the head,
yet we can't miss the truth,
but we're getting this from everywhere.
You can't always assume that everything
from the mainstream media is not true
because here's the deal.
If something does happen,
that's a real thing that happens.
The mainstream media is always going to
cover it.
What does he say?
Stop and listen to me here cause this is
important.
Just because something's in the
mainstream media and I know you distrust
the mainstream media,
it doesn't mean that it's not true
because you always have to realize that
if something happens,
say like Mount Saint Helens blows,
right?
Love lava flowing down the street,
bunch of people die.
That's a real natural disaster that we
all know happens.
Fox News is going to cover that.
CNN is going to cover that.
Everybody's going to cover that.
Not every,
everything that covers fake.
Right.
So if North Korea does try to launch a
missile and it does fail,
everyone's gonna cover that.
So just because CNN has something on
her,
Fox News has something on it.
Doesn't mean that it's fine.
For sure.
I'm totally with you on the show.
Look into North Korea.
Who's the King of conspiracy theories?
I was shown out stone.
Do you see him?
He was like,
Yo,
I'm black.
I'm just playing a character man.
Real cause that's what I would say.
It doesn't take as kids.
Me Too.
I would do it too,
I would say.
But even he was like,
dude,
I'm just saying some shit to get Mr.
Jones belongs to a country club.
Mr. Jones is an outstanding citizen and
he is essentially just a really,
really popular Phil Hendrie.
He's an animator.
He was like,
I'm just putting on a performance man.
I don't believe that she has performance
artist.
He says,
I don't believe that shit.
Say Word for word.
No,
I'm just playing a character.
I don't believe that shit.
That's what I heard you work in him.
I see what you're doing.
He's working you out.
I'm just saying the savior of
conspiracy.
He was like,
it's a performance.
I'm out.
Well,
I'm just saying,
I'm just saying how fun.
Doolittle.
Apologize.
Don't be shy for pizza districts like
that ain't real.
No,
no,
no to you.
They were suing him.
Never going after him.
If you listen to him,
he's reading a statement like,
don't come after me.
They were going after him or trying to
shut them down.
That's what's going on.
He totally knows that.
Anyways,
he's,
he's watching his ass to come and after
hashtag tower seven anyways,
anywhere else.
Seven tower towel.
She see gates.
Did it catch pizza gate?
I'm just saying half look into North
Korea.
It's fucking hysterical.
It's hysterical.
I think.
I think I'm just playing a character can
into it,
but,
but Eddie,
this'll,
there's like a Pentagon to test a bill.
Get the shit down North Korean missiles.
I,
the video is the next video I played the
girl.
Well,
listen man,
this is strange time.
The fact that here's,
here's what's strange.
The fact that these people are actually
doing this.
The fact that you can get people to
goose step down the middle of the street
and ride a tank and salute the king,
like this shit's all real.
They don't know what,
you better find a video where they
worship him.
Yeah,
that's the greatest shit.
But,
but listen,
this,
what we're looking at right here is
actually happening.
This is not CGI.
So this is either a two levels of weird.
It's either one level of weird where you
have this populace that's so entranced
by the,
the military dictatorship that they just
act out every day of their lives like
this and they can't help themselves.
Or two,
this is all bullshit.
And these are all actors.
So they've got 5 million actors waving
Korean flags and we find the king and
whatever the fuck it is,
you got feet goosestepping let's do it.
There's a lot of people there.
I don't know how many thousand that is,
but there's a lot of people that put on
shows for people coming in.
You come in,
they're going to put a show on for you,
but not everywhere you go.
They're putting on,
so there's actors,
everyone already,
but this is just a lot of them,
but they're already understand that she
deserves like academy award already act,
these people,
goose step in and doing all those
things.
Just the fact that they're able to do
that save this is all fake.
Let's just,
let's just go deep,
deep,
deep.
Let's go deep,
deep,
deep.
What are the odds that you're going to
get that many actors who don't even have
top billing to stay in line?
What are the odds that you're going to
get them to perform like that and drive
tanks and keep their mouth shut?
And this one's on.
Everyone's pitching in on it's way more
likely that these people are under the
thumb of a military dictatorship is cut
ton of people,
right?
Because we've had a fuck load of
military dictatorships in history,
but what we haven't had is a country
filled with actors and who's playing
these actors?
Who's giving them that fucking who's
throw in North Korea crazy money?
Who's the Goddamn teacher and how do
they train all of deicing?
Is it one big auditoriums and one
episode of fame?
Well,
look at them.
Goosestepping dude,
this is crazy.
Look how many people there.
Look how they,
they turn their fucking tops over.
Whatever they're doing,
the changes to the flag goes.
It looks like a New Year's Eve parade.
Look at these people,
man.
They're all marching in tune.
Just the fact that they can get anybody
to do it either.
Either one,
either his regular businessmen right
there on the side,
because a few people that are probably
want you to sing.
It looks fucking fishy.
The cash is running rampant.
It's all,
again,
I'm just saying me ask you this,
Mister [inaudible].
Let me ask you this,
Mr [inaudible].
What is more likely?
Is it more likely these people are
fucking terrified and like many,
many,
many other civilizations in the past
session like this,
right?
It's ever existed,
but I'm sure it hasn't.
China,
I'm sure it has an ancient,
ancient Japan.
I'm sure there's been dictatorship.
We're talking about shit.
We know for sure.
We know the magazines,
the Mayans,
the aztecs killed 80,000 people after
they cut and built one of their
pyramids.
I mean they did over a period,
probably litigious.
He's probably legit,
but we've been lied to so much about
like what's a lie to all these people
were actors and they just live there.
They're all out on your own.
Just think of how crazy that is.
Wouldn't it be more likely that these
poor people are just brainwashed?
Because we know people get brainwashed
wouldn't be more like craziest when you,
when you're taking into consideration
all the lies that we've been told,
the fake moon missions,
all this shit.
Nothing.
I mean,
this is nothing.
They put together a bunch of people and
made a fucking parade,
but they think the moon mission six
times.
But everybody believes that shit.
But there are real events that happen
every day that are in the totals,
right?
So this is just too convenient.
It's too much of a distraction.
Eddie,
this,
my guess is we're not going to war with
the Eddie.
This is my,
one of the greatest options.
This will be one of the greatest
productions in the history of the human
race and the biggest movie of greater
production and the get all these Korean
people around.
That's a couple of thousand people,
Dude.
No one's wanting to do this.
They have to wait with snitch.
These are not the same people to fake
the moon missions.
Find,
find the people,
but don't say it's legit.
These people are these people that are
stuck in North Korea.
People that have escaped have told
horror stories.
Press.
It's like a giant cult.
It's horrible.
It's like this is a fucking,
you know,
10 million cult of the monies.
Not saying they're actors.
I'm just saying there's something fishy
about the whole North Korea thing.
I'm not saying that they're acting.
It could be anything.
I'm just saying.
I don't know.
I'm saying it's,
that smells fishy.
Something is not right about what
they're telling us about North Korea.
I Dunno most.
Here's the real thing that's most fucked
up about North Korea is it?
Even if you freed them from this guy,
they've been under the thumb of a
communist dictatorship for so long,
they wouldn't know what to do.
Institutionalized.
Yes,
they really are.
It's like a guy who's been into window
Fox people's heads up,
man.
Do you know how many people would be so
susceptible to some new form of
dictatorship?
Fuck man.
I mean,
you literally have a whole country this,
they always do that in these,
these countries when they remove a
dictator and then there's this power
vacuum in a way more horrible person
takes their place and like,
what the fuck man?
I like,
they got rid of Gaddafi and now it's
just the crazy isis strong stronghold.
Yeah.
Libya.
Apparently.
Man,
I don't know too much about it,
but they were saying that it's a failed
state.
Wild with that with with North Korea
though.
They can't even like that.
He controls their media TV like Internet
that they can't log on the certain
fucking sites.
Some don't get Internet.
No,
there's no iphone like you being an
iphone and I got Danny from the future.
They still got flip phones and shit.
Yeah,
they're there.
We're living in a really weird country,
a hamburger.
They flipped.
I think the globalists like it.
I think we need villains and they
probably help him out and fund him.
Well,
you know what I mean?
They like the shit he's doing.
They,
they need a distraction.
Anything happens.
We don't really boomed the testing
missiles.
Boom for two weeks we're going to be all
over North Korea a couple of months and
then it's going to be gone.
Watch north.
This is like the new Ebola.
Remember that was Ebola.
Ebola distraction.
Distraction.
North Korea is perfect to distract.
That's what you think.
Ebola was a distraction.
You don't think Ebola was a bunch of
like really smart doctors stopping some
shit before it got horrible because
you've got a hemorrhagic virus is
escaping out for fat.
People really got it.
Just because a bunch of shit happens at
the same time,
it doesn't mean that one of those things
that happens was a designed to make sure
you don't pay attention to the other
thing.
Just cause they dropped that mother of
all bombs in Afghanistan.
Did you see that shit like three people
killed 99 fucking thing.
Well,
they had to go through it had to go
through the ground.
The same tunnel system.
What's the story?
They launched a lot.
Biggest bomb ever created.
You know,
a number of little drops.
It's the heaviest,
most powerful bomb ever.
It's crazy.
When you watch this footage,
have you seen a jamie?
The blast radius is a mile.
It looks like you're dropping a straight
space ship and it killed at first.
They're like,
he killed 40 people.
That's damn several of our crazy mass
shooters.
We say 40.
We met in 1990.
The leanest fucking yeah,
you got it.
They got to drop it.
Parachute a parachute on it,
son.
I mean it hit and apparently devastated
this tunnel system that they were having
a hard time to because
they said that isis has this stronghold
out there.
That thing,
21,000 pounds.
A video of that from the Afghanistan
hit.
Yeah.
There is from the helicopters.
Military video.
Yeah.
I was expecting a little more out of it
to be honest with you.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
it's hard to tell what's going on
because it's black and white.
Why did they paint that bitch charger
horns,
that bitch know came from America.
Why did they put fucking rate white
racing stripes on the system?
It is a crazy little machine.
It's a big ass.
But you're not buying that shit.
Eddie nearly killed me.
Explosion.
It's a chicken explode.
The bomb bomb went off.
That's what we saw.
No,
it's the biggest bomb that ever has been
dropped in war outside of a nuclear
bomb.
All right,
well you don't believe in on nuclear
bottom grammatically is crazy.
I am.
Tell me,
I'm trying to figure out what's the
angle.
Why are they showing us this?
That's what I'm thinking.
That's how crazy I am.
I'm fucking so anything when it comes
to,
when it comes to military shit that's
blasted on the history channel or CNN,
um,
automatically what's their angle?
I don't.
Okay,
let me ask you this.
Conversation.
Sanity.
You need to talk crazy entity dinosaurs.
I'm crazy.
Dinosaurs.
Really not.
I don't trust that shit.
You don't trust too that I love that
triceratops cause everybody loves when
the triceratops fights at the
tyranosaurs rex,
everybody's rooting for the tricep.
If you're ruined for the Thai Rana
source wrecks in that epic battle,
he's a Douche bag.
Right.
So you did those like we'll do,
what about wooly mammoth?
Um,
I,
I would say a yes.
Oh,
you've got to fucking elephant.
You know what I mean?
It's a fucking elephant.
There's a new one where they're going to
bring it back.
Tie Rod of sorts.
Rex is a giant kangaroo.
That's what it is.
That's my guess.
It looks exactly the same.
It's got a tail hops around on two legs.
[inaudible] that's a fucking,
they found the giant kangaroo and when
they figured it out they go,
dude,
it's a kangaroo.
Skip off sock.
Well listen,
if it was a giant kangaroo,
be just as impressive with docents.
Hundred foot tall kangaroo.
How about that one?
Jack Kangaroo.
You see that one Jack Kangaroo that
lives in a park somewhere?
He's Jujitsu.
Tenax he's not that.
He's like the Kevin Randleman of
Kangaroos.
You ever seen this kangaroo ridiculous
on the phone?
You saw that guy who fought the
kangaroo?
Yeah,
the guy's an asshole,
but here's my thing.
It's like a kangaroo was 100 feet tall.
Just as impressive as a lizard.
A hundred feet tall.
Crazy triceratops.
Isn't the fucking look like just the
different kind of rhinoceros like Audi?
It is.
Why is he like that?
Dia is body like [inaudible] bitch.
I'm not surprised on the flush.
Look at him.
I bet.
Dot.
Kangaroo would fuck us up.
You think?
Oh God.
That's Vito Belfort vein on his bicep.
That's like Mark Coleman and 95 that's a
tank.
Do you think the three of us could beat
him up?
No,
man.
We're going to run.
We're going to get that Samurai sticking
his asshole destroy that fucking thing.
That's a scary animal.
It's a big fucking scary animals.
They can get like seven feet tall.
They're fucking huge.
Is that real?
Yeah.
There's certain ones that that's a real
kangaroo jack.
Well,
they're really,
there's two different kinds.
There's Red Kangaroos and gray
kangaroos.
I don't know.
Remember which one's the Big One?
I think it's a red kangaroo.
The red tones way more gnarly.
The largest google.
What's the largest kangaroo young Jamie.
I think it's a,
I think it's a 300 pound rip kangaroo
crushes my good Lord at a video.
But you,
so Eddie,
what do you,
you don't think that like t rex is a
real,
do you really,
when you look,
when you look into,
uh,
when dinosaur bones of first discovered
them,
I mean it says,
when you look into dot,
dot,
dot.
When you're looking at the timeline,
it wasn't just like,
oh,
all dinosaurs were discovered.
There was a timeline.
There was a lot of,
there was a lot of fraudulent shit that
was dude's like,
hey,
look what I found.
They don't bitch.
That's just a whale bone that I fuck
ever getting paid.
There was a little hot of fraud going on
in the 18 hundreds when they were
discovering that the birth,
but was that,
what about like the,
the way the earth is like the layers and
get until certain time periods from the
layers of the stratus?
Well,
if you're talking about carbon dating,
there's a lot of science that goes back
and forth.
I could ain't shit or it's real.
Oh,
it's not in the job.
There's almost universally acknowledged
a carbon datings effective.
Well,
not the stuff that I'm looking into.
I don't know all my shit on you,
so don't take my word for thank you,
chase it.
This shit.
Be Crazy.
Chase your tail with this shit,
man.
No,
I'm not.
I'm having fun.
Love it.
He loves it.
Figuring out how we're being bullshitted
is very,
I'm obsessed with it.
See how are they bullshitting us?
I love that.
I that like that and he's like,
I just want to eat people like this.
Like he loves.
This is a crazy idea.
I think we're being lied to about
fucking everything.
Your kids going to grow up just saying
skeptical.
Fuck.
I'm already telling him.
I'm already telling you don't trust
anything you see on TV.
I'm Martin.
No,
we don't let him watch TV.
We let him watch a little cartoons here,
here,
here and there.
A little bit.
Bunch.
Bob's corrupted,
but I'm going to race him.
Not Trusting TV.
Know I don't give a fuck what anybody
says.
You can't.
You can't say nobody would ever disagree
with that.
That does.
E V is not good for kids.
Why don't you have a show on the Alex
Jones Channel?
What has happened?
What the fuck?
I went total retard on him.
I wouldn't full flat earth on them.
No,
no,
no.
Most,
most most conspiracy.
Most conspiracy,
they think flat earth is the most
retarded thing ever.
When joe first just correct,
when joe first brought it up,
like about eat about a year,
year and a half ago,
he said,
dude,
he was trying to,
he was trying to basically say how
stupid people are.
He said,
do you know people still believe the
earth is flat and the sun is 3000 miles
away?
And I remember sitting there thinking,
Shit that what are the amish or
something like how dumb do have to be to
create the world?
This is how,
and then again,
you brought it up again like maybe six
months later.
And I and I said,
and I said on your podcast.
I said,
that's got it.
That is so dumb.
That's gotta be some kind of CIA Cya.
It's got to be some kind of disruption.
Go.
Weird lesson.
And then I was in class and one of were,
we were talking about conspiracy
theories and my f my buddy man,
he full blown conspiracy shit too
because he goes,
do you ever do ever my Jujitsu class?
He goes,
we're talking about my youtube class.
I was conspiracy class.
No God,
you go to school teachers I teach,
I teach.
People had to kill a brand.
So we managed,
manny turns me.
Cause did he ever look into flat earth?
This was like eight months ago or
something and I said [inaudible] he said
that you ever look into astronomy?
Yeah.
Right when he said Danny did you must
fourth grade,
right when he said that I dropped you on
your head.
I not smoking I law.
I can't believe anything that ever comes
out of his mouth again.
That's what I stopped.
I'm like Jesus.
And I'm like,
please don't ever bring this shit up
again.
You keep that shit,
dude,
cut to do that.
The turn.
Another guy comes,
I'm telling you the story and then,
and then earnest comes up to me and he
goes,
hey man,
you ever looking to flatter dues?
Jesus.
God Damn Christ.
So that's a dumb shit.
And he goes,
hey man,
I got a master's in engineering,
look into it.
And I just wanted to go.
I just went home and I was just going to
fucking school.
That was,
we can tell people.
Yeah.
Phoenix online and shit like,
hey man,
shit,
I'm so crazy.
I,
I so don't believe you want someone else
to do.
Yeah,
I,
I tried to,
I tried to debunk it.
I was trying to debunk it.
I was mister debunker.
There's a fucking Japanese satellite
that takes a photo from $22,000 worse
commodities.
Japanese though,
even if the pixel is all fucked up,
those pictures put up this Japanese
pictures from 22,000 miles away.
What pictures?
Phone.
I can't remember when you got a flip
phone dude and you,
you're the front facing cameras were
always dog shit always,
you know,
on the back face.
He Won.
It was pretty legit.
Yeah.
That's how it works for 22,000 miles
away.
It's a hard to take that iphone seven
have you ever seen a picture of a flat,
hold on.
No,
I didn't say that.
I don't say that.
The crazy thing,
I'm not saying it's flat.
I'm just saying,
damn,
you look into it.
I'm saying we don't know
what the fuck wrong.
Wait a minute,
Eddie.
That's what I'm saying.
We don't know this Japanese satellite.
Hold on.
Eddie.
This Japanese satellite that all these
hundreds of scientists worked on for
like a decade down's this space,
they take moon land picture every 10
minutes and you can download it from the
website.
CGI composites,
so constantly making CGI and some sorts
of,
some sort of a cognitive bank somewhere.
That's what they do.
Why do you think if they have the
technology to make CGI that looks that
good?
Why don't they have the technology to
shoot a camera into space?
The pictures from Massa.
How come they don't have any,
they don't have that space kind of
technology.
No,
they just never did it.
They also don't give a fuck about
proven.
That's round those pictures I've seen
them put,
they don't have that kind of show me.
Show me a real quick,
listen.
NASA does not have one of those
satellites.
Why do you think that's fair?
Why does it look famous?
Suck.
It looks like something you'd see in a
movie.
That's because when they do it in a
move,
they try to make it look like this,
which is what?
It looks real.
If that's real team and you don't think
it's real,
they faked six moon man.
Stop saying that because it's
irrelevant.
We're not talking about,
that's 1969 we're talking about 2017 I
think there's some gigantic conspiracy
involving the Japanese government where
they put up a fake picture of the Earth
from 22,000 miles up every 10 minutes.
High resolution,
downloadable photo.
You think it's fake?
Why wouldn't it be your real,
what?
Isn't it just as likely that the
Japanese actually did launch that thing
in this space?
Why would it be fake propaganda,
man,
they cared that they,
is there a photo of this flat earth?
No,
I don't.
I like I just said again,
that's is there.
There's no photo of,
of the flat earth from space.
There's no photo of the round earth.
That's not true.
Why do you say they're fake though?
They'll look CGI,
but you're not an expert in imagery.
Looks fake to me.
Convince you though.
When I watch Avatar,
be an expert to know.
It's like when I watched episode
advertise at the movies.
When you watch some ridiculous Kung Fu
video beat a martial arts expert.
If you were sitting next to someone that
told you that their Sensei can't compete
in the UFC because they're too deadly,
wouldn't you get pissed off because
you're an actual martial arts expert
that's just like you with no science
background whatsoever.
Talking about crazy photos.
I know crazy like that,
but why am you that I'm crazy?
But why not indulge at all?
Why not indulge the foam realm of
possibilities and not clean to the
conspiracy every single time it's a NASA
can get pictures.
They've been,
they've been doing CGI composite but
pleasing his whole question.
I forget about stating what NASA does.
Please answer my questions.
Why do you always go towards the
conspiracy?
Why do you never considered the
possibility that maybe he's not the same
people?
So everybody's looking at global thing?
Yes.
All the European space agencies like all
in on it.
It's a global thing.
I think all governments,
most of them,
the globalist
are all working together to,
to control.
There be advantages and the earth is
crazy.
What's the advantage that it's not round
then if they control you,
bro,
they just want to fuck with us.
Keep you on up.
There's,
I don't know,
man.
I don't know what it doesn't make sense.
It doesn't make sense.
You could find the sounds easy.
You put them on a ball because again,
I'm crazy.
You put them on a ball.
My guesses.
You're on a ball.
You're nowhere.
Don't try to go anywhere.
Just stay down in the world.
Oh Hell No.
We sat down and said,
you know,
well we got a release of fake math that
shows that you can demonstrate that the
earth is round.
We got to earth from space,
man.
What is that?
We just looked at one at,
he stopped saying it was fake.
You don't know that it's fake,
but you're saying,
look,
it's a real problem when you crazy,
but don't say that.
Just stop.
Just stop and think because you're,
you're communicating to millions of
people saying something that doesn't
make any sense.
It does make so that you don't know
anything about imagery.
You don't know anything about what you
don't know anything about that.
It looks fake to me.
Fake ass pit.
You don't have come on and you're just
looking at it with the naked eye.
It looks real to everybody else in this
room.
Someone that had made a confirmation
bias crazy,
right?
I don't think he made sure he was having
fun with it,
but you don't direct inclination to
always go towards a conspiracy.
Does it keeps your a piss anybody off?
It's a disservice to,
that's what you think.
Cool.
My doesn't have to get,
you're getting angry.
No,
I'm not getting younger.
Stoners,
stoners.
I'm like,
I don't believe that shit.
I'm not raising my voice when I'm trying
to do is corner your ideas.
I try to corner your ideas because
you're saying these things to your very
influential and you're saying these
things to millions of people,
but I don't think you're thinking
correct.
I'm telling.
I know.
That's why I've stated many times that
you're crazy.
But here's the thing,
online,
when you use it,
when do you think you started losing it?
I think I was,
you know,
as soon as I found out when I was 11
that everybody wasn't Catholic.
That was it.
That's when I started losing my,
wait a minute,
I'm like,
everybody's not Catholic.
I thought everybody was Catholic.
There's other religions and how do we
know we're right?
There's a bunch of,
what's a Jew?
Oh Shit,
there's more Jews and Catholics.
How do we know we have the right
religion?
I'm like,
okay,
you started the West right there.
Yes.
That's when I started going.
Chris.
So funny.
People to question authority are usually
looked at as crazy conspiracy theorist
CCIO coining the term conspiracy smart
dude.
There's a problem in the way you
approach these things cause you
approached them all knowing before you
even start that there are conspiracy and
telling you what.
So that's confirmation bias.
I'm telling you,
hey dude,
when you lie so much you've got to prove
it to me.
Utilize so goddamn much.
I'm never going to be saying the things
that a defense but what I'm saying the
thing I ended the prosecuting attorney
with solid time.
That's what I'm saying.
But it's not a good,
it's not a good analogy because it's
exactly how I look at filled with lies
then allows governments,
governments,
uh,
on uh,
being accused of lying.
I understand they've been covered line.
So they're there,
they're in court.
But here are you saying the government,
not the government.
Oh whoever,
whoever.
Just in general scientists,
it's all government scientists.
You think scientists,
you think there's these independent
scientists come.
It's all government scientists that
don't try to,
why would you?
Grants are all the control.
You don't think,
you don't think the globalist aren't
control having control the science and
information since day one you think it
was like a new thing there.
Name the globalists.
They'd be like,
yeah,
it's flat,
it's flat.
It be like no fuck.
These guys were globalists.
None of the globalist Alex called Eddie.
Let me,
if we just spent like a day together,
I think he just tried to make fun.
Hey,
I'm just having fun man.
I like finding,
I get,
I don't trust shit coming from the
government.
Does that make me crazy?
Problem?
Problem is this idea of the government.
The government consists of a bunch of
inner control science with a whole
history agencies.
Eddie fighting.
Do you know like the CIA and the FBI
each other?
Of course there's no one governments,
a lot of personal shit going on in
between.
Of course,
that it's not just personal shit.
There's a bunch of different factions
that you call the government.
I agree.
Idea that it's all like the government
can't be trusted.
I just say that cause I'm not gonna.
I mean you want me to pick out some
agencies.
Got Nasa.
I could pick out some sadness deck,
but just in general in general,
it's history,
science,
education,
energy.
Everything has always been controlled by
the government.
Since day one,
radio has been used as propaganda since
the day it was invented.
You think some independent dude just
invented radio and then he started
broadcasting that like his favorite
music and shit.
And he know what his thoughts.
No,
it was the government from day one and
radio.
It was the government in all countries
from day one in uh,
uh,
TV and the movies.
It was the,
it was all radio,
TV and the movies.
You remember always been about
propaganda.
Always in every country.
It's nothing new.
It's old school gangsters.
Are countries the most,
what does this have to do with the world
being,
no,
this is,
this,
this is how gangster are,
are,
uh,
government is,
there's a,
there was a war on drugs.
We started on drugs.
Turns out we're bringing it in.
Then there's a war on terrorism.
Turns out,
how do we create it?
Al Qaeda.
You understand why I'm crazy.
I'm crazy because of that shit.
I'm like,
you could believe that shit.
You want to believe that I showed you.
You just apply this to everything.
It basically,
anything comes from the government.
Anything coming from the government.
Dinosaurs don't come from the
government.
Just there's so much fraud.
When you look in government,
it comes from science,
so let's get into it.
Look into it.
But I have looked into it.
Look dinosaurs as a kid,
but this is,
you could,
you could go over these different
sections of the earth.
Look here,
we can look at the next one that comes
10 minutes later.
Maybe you won't think that one's fake.
Like,
oh wow.
That was kind of ready.
It's all fake.
It doesn't look fake to me.
It looks like what the fucking earth
probably looks like when you're 22,000
miles away to you.
It does not to me agreeing to disagree.
Yeah,
but why think that it does?
Because I don't trust shit.
Why think that?
I don't trust the government does make
these fake pictures of the earth.
Don't you think that would be that?
We could speculate.
You want to speculate?
I mean I could show it.
I want to hear you speculate that it's
easier to control people when they on a
ball.
I've been trying to tell people that
forever.
I don't know.
Like we've got to live in a ball.
I told it to my wife,
it's a very easy to get the kids to
listen.
I've just lived on a ball throw ball
house bull shit.
I don't know what to believe.
That doesn't even make any sense.
Why would it be easier to get people to
listen if they're on a ball rather than
they fun a plate?
Because if there's more land people
gonna want to work,
there's actually more land shit.
What do you mean it's more land?
Who knows if you,
if you exactly what he talking about.
I don't understand what you're talking
about.
Like more or less.
If the world is flat and the flat earth
model is true.
Okay,
what's the point of it?
What's the point of so all the math is
fake like that.
The Earth is going 24 hours in a circle.
Is that all fake?
That it spins and thousand miles an
hour.
I don't.
When you look into it works crash,
stationary,
devin screws.
There's,
if you look into the experiments,
if you look into the experiments to
prove that the earth is spinning,
all of them failed.
Look into it.
We've been in doctor.
No,
no,
no.
That's not true.
Okay.
I'm crazy.
I get it edited.
What Jamie would going to say,
I don't have the science in my head to
back it up yet,
but that's not true.
You can't say things like that.
That's what Eric Dubay says,
and he's not backing it up.
Where's the evidence that find the
evidence kids in high school right now
that can show you the evidence with
science if you can't show it to me,
because I'm not in class right now.
Just not up to date.
I'm doing jre work right now.
You're talking about,
you're talking about some shit,
but he,
you're saying I don't trust it.
You're saying something that people have
been proving for hundreds and hundreds
of Nicholas a Mickelson Morley
experiments.
That was,
uh,
Einstein said it himself.
Einstein said to this day,
Einstein said,
don't worry.
No,
we're moving.
Did you guys just have them do it?
That's all it is.
You're watching videos.
There's a difference.
You looking into it and watching youtube
videos,
so,
so let's say this offer the same
channel.
What if it's true that Albert Einstein
said,
there is no evidence that the earth is
spinning.
Would it be safe?
He said,
of course.
You said that's not true.
I saw it on Youtube,
but what if we find out that it is true?
Then what?
What if they find out leprechauns are
really but fucking genius.
And I thought that's what I said.
So you're saying,
Oh,
do you really look at what may be a 1947
there wasn't much evidence of the Earth
is spinning because they didn't
understand it yet.
Okay.
When we talking about something that
happened more than a half a century ago,
Einstein is,
look,
he compare all the people that are alive
today,
whether
it's Lawrence Krauss or Stephen
Hawking's,
most famous field
pyramid.
What does this experiment it was under?
Couldn't recreate it.
It was an 1880s I looked this up and I
was watching 5 cents.
[inaudible] know what he just said?
No already.
Exactly.
You keep using that.
Look at the Mickelson like experiments.
I did.
I read up the information on it.
It's an experiment that was supposed to
be able to be recreated.
It was not able to be recreated so that
evidence is used by flat earth
supporting people like you just said,
like go look it up.
Go look it up.
Look it up.
Repeatable.
You can't repair it.
You don't understand.
That's what you're saying.
I'm trying to tell you that that's the
evidence you trying to say.
The experiment showed the earth is not
spinning.
No one can reproduce that experiment.
That's why it's not real.
So this thing that you keep repeating is
bullshit and this thing that you keep
her but don't know.
Where did you get this information?
Jet Shamey where'd you get it?
Where do I get what?
This information.
What does this come from?
This is coming off the Internet.
Exactly.
Americans information I'm reading.
Some of them
slowly stopped their sources here.
There's a book called the American
Journal of Science.
I'm sure that
which is bought and paid for.
Well maybe it is.
It's part of it.
Here's the thing,
Eddie wiped the Washington Post.
Why would anybody be paying money for
people to lie about the world at a set
of very good question that everybody
asks coming in.
Everybody on stat clinic group have a
seat.
They're not,
they're not huge.
Not getting knocked down.
That's why we just read this thing that
you've been siting and you didn't even
understand it when we were reading it.
You read off how Internet,
but that's how I read many books here.
We're both getting our information off
the Internet.
So you were saying is peer reviewed
journals from sign from American journal
offense.
Come on.
And that is also,
that's like economists.
So you think it's more likely,
more likely that everyone is in on it
and lying than it is.
One guy doesn't know what the fuck he's
talking about and it makes a youtube
video and you get convinced and it's
attractive to you because it seems like
it would be an amazing conspiracy to be
ahead of,
and you get trapped in the fucking
rabbit hole and you'd go down to flat
earth rabbit hole and you find yourself
defending things with experiments or you
don't even understand,
which means you have some shit that he
pulled up off the internet and I know
you like all over.
I know you didn't understand.
You understand.
Explain it to you twice.
It doesn't matter.
But I understood it and he had explained
it to you twice and you didn't
understand that you are.
No,
no,
no.
This is the proof.
Now I understand it.
There was an experiment to prove that
the earth wasn't moving.
It was nothing.
And then they proved it,
but no,
they did.
No,
no,
no.
I get,
they didn't prove it,
but that doesn't mean that it's
spinning.
Oh,
Jamie,
I'm sure you can find some evidence of
the Earth is spinning.
Eddie,
people who have known.
It's spinning forever.
That's how you,
that's how the seasons work.
That's how you see the sun.
We spin around.
That's why it makes a claim.
That's why you can track time zones.
That's why he could put a piece of stick
in the ground asking all the actions
that it acts as a Sundial.
You're saying all the Shit Eddie.
There's where would set has a
fundamental problem with the way you
approach these things.
No problem.
The problem is you do,
but it's not that I trust Shit Eddie,
you know I don't trust you.
I don't.
It doesn't matter.
That's a flat around all back.
You keep saying that it's a bad fall
back because what I'm,
what we're saying is there are
conspiracies.
The problem is when you think everything
is conspiracy,
you act as a cyop guy and you fuck
people over that want to look at real
conspiracies because the real
conspiracies,
the Gulf of Tonkin.
That's what I thought too.
Like the Gulf of Tonkin,
real operation,
northwoods real things that really
happened.
When you look at those things and people
explore,
then they go,
oh,
I don't think they really killed
Kennedy.
Are you sure?
Why don't you look at this?
Look at this stuff.
There's a lot of really crazy evidence
when you start thinking that the world
is flat,
the dinosaurs aren't real,
all this nutty shit that you believe and
you just jump into it with the problem
is it discredits all these other things
that you believe that might be real
because the other things have some
validity to that.
You just haven't looked into it.
That's all I used to say.
The Sandy,
you're talking about the earth.
I'm signing the same thing.
You can do what you think they're all
wrong.
That's so insane.
You haven't looked into it.
I have like,
oh my God,
how could I not have?
You don't think I have.
I'm watching you go down the rabbit
hole.
You don't think I've tried to pay
attention to what the fuck these people
are talking about.
It doesn't work.
I don't think so at any there's websites
dedicated to debunking.
It is dedicated to showing you the
science,
showing you the math you can do when you
check the internet.
It's valid,
but when I'm on the Internet,
it's not,
you're not talking about the internet,
you're talking about Ah,
guys.
Youtube.
No,
it's a guy.
There's a lot of guys,
there's a lot of people,
but they're just youtube videos.
No science behind them and is not
verified by peer review journals.
The science of the Earth,
the Saudi government science that's
bought and paid for.
Of course,
you started talking about this,
so on the sizing third is flat.
I didn't say that.
I said,
I don't know if it's flat or round.
When I see a picture of earth from
space,
what we're sitting on from space.
When I see a real picture,
then we'll have the proof.
I'm just saying we don't need to have
neuro that it's round.
No,
we're looking at pictures while we're
sitting here.
Okay.
You,
you're not even taking into
consideration the fact that this is a
monitor that you look at this,
you're not,
it's,
you don't even get like the high
resolution.
I mean they must be gigantic files that
they get.
You would never be able to see him and
their actual resolution on a regular
monitor in the first place.
You're talking about a photo of the
earth photo of the Earth from 22,000
miles away and they take one every
fucking,
the only way you might look cgi to you,
you'd have to jump in a shape.
We,
your side could be wrong.
It could be real.
Too many things could be real,
but they've been faking them so much.
They look like all those other things.
I've seen so many fake ones that NASA,
a mitts that they're CGI composites.
There's so many out there,
so when you see this one,
it's like this is the same one I've seen
so many.
This is another one.
Posits is different.
I don't believe that.
Eddie,
please,
when you take one of these photos,
these,
what are those calls?
When you fucking do that,
when you do that,
you know what that is?
That's a composite.
You're taking a bunch of photographs and
they piece them all together.
It makes one enormous photo.
When you see these photos from space of
the earth from a closer saddle I knob
the nasa one that Jamie just pulled up,
which does show a full full size image
of the earth.
What you're seeing is they take a photo,
they take it on the front and they piece
them all together.
There's no scenes.
It's a composite.
Composite?
No,
no.
There's an actual CGI artists put them
together.
It colors everything.
Eddie,
is this CGI quick question for you,
is this CGI because it's,
it was made in a computer and it fits
the definition of computer generated
image because that's the compass one
could easily mean you made this.
I'll show you.
No,
no,
no.
I'm just saying,
but this could be easily a real picture,
but it is a real picture,
but that's not a hard picture.
Where I wasn't sure of earth from space.
That's where I physically was on the
ground in New York City had take that
with the camera I was using.
That building would not fit in my lens.
I wasn't far enough away,
but that's not what they're saying
they're doing.
They're saying they take strips.
That's what they're saying they do.
They're saying,
I'm going to show you a video of the
artists who actually did the latest one.
They go,
oh NASA,
here's the guy who did the latest house.
Tell us what to look at it.
It's awesome video.
Just put NASA artist a CGI picture of
earth and you're going to hear him
talking and he says it did his
photoshop.
It is,
it is photoshop but it has to be fought
a shot.
He says that word for it.
Can you do,
I was asking you to clarify that.
I'm trying to tell you that that's what
I literally had to do.
I had to have been farther away to get
the photo and one photo of that giant
building,
but that where I have in order to get
that distance away coloring with CGI,
there were buildings in a way you're
saying it and photoshop.
I put his stuff,
he's going through the video going,
I got it.
Cause I got,
I was sometimes I put green shades here
and I kind of,
I'm not an astronaut,
I never been to space.
So I have to kind of use my imagination
to,
to get the taking black whites almost
picture that NASA releases of earth.
Here's the latest one.
Real nice and tight.
This that day that's a little
exaggerated.
The dark,
they weren't that dark in real life.
The brights aren't that bright and real
life.
So yes,
I added color to it.
I did some artistry to it,
but that's bull shit.
So we got the fucking building looks
like,
Oh okay.
Now find that.
And then the CGI bucketing anything.
Do you believe anything?
I believe shit that I can prove for
myself.
Like I believe the science in like a
skyscraper,
skyscraper it standing there.
That's true.
But how am I believe in that?
I have you looked into like the science
of space travel?
How much have you looked at how much
work was done to try to put satellites
into orbit?
So you'd think we went to the moon.
That's not what I asked you.
I said,
how much
did you look in it?
We went to the moon.
Heti answer my fucking talk.
Ridiculous.
[inaudible] circle you talking in
circles.
They're ridiculous conversations.
Everything is the government,
the government,
the government's fake pictures.
While I'm just asking you a question,
punch up NASA.
CGI artists.
Picture of earth.
I don't see that up there head.
He's so crazy.
Would you like me to click on any of
them?
That one right there.
The second one right there.
I mean,
I just listened to him talk.
Well,
it's going to get more.
No guys,
Jeff [inaudible] today I want to share
with you this article that's going to
seem,
are we allowed to play?
This guy isn't a scientist or are we
listening to him or the the guy that
made the video.
You said we're gonna listen to a
scientist.
Well,
it looked like the right video.
I,
I dunno,
look,
but that is the guy that is the artist
and he has,
this is the,
that's a picture of the video talking
about how he created the latest picture
of earth for NASA.
Okay,
so they're celebrating
Goddard.
It's from the goddard webpage.
So he's doing a recap of something
that's written on the God or webpage.
So go to the God or web page,
find that guys page Robert Simmons
Photoshop.
There it was,
and we'll see what he's actually saying.
Is that a picture?
What do you think is the most
interesting that your role here at
Goddard?
How do you help support God's mission?
My role is to make imagery from earth
scientists.
Science is data.
I turned data into pictures.
I look for new interesting events that
nat NASA,
NASA satellites have seen or that are
hidden in the latest data.
Define anything interesting that shows
off NASA is unique capabilities.
Finding things is the fun part.
I rely on engineers and scientists to
produce the data.
They're reliable.
Real time stream of 1.7 terabytes a day.
Holy Shit is incredible tale.
About the same as producing 3000 cds a
day.
We know where to look for the
interesting stuff because each
instrument provides a very specialized
type of information.
So if I'm looking for something
specific,
I know where to look.
For example,
recently there was a volcanic eruption
in the Red Sea.
The only reliable imagery of this was
from NASA satellites.
We basically confirmed the existence of
a new island.
Okay,
so where's the,
let's get to some photoshop shit.
The one where he's talking.
Okay,
but this guy's talking about science
here.
Like some of the science has to be real,
right,
Eddie?
Like there has to be some subtle,
it's like direct TV.
Direct TV is not fake,
right?
Um,
I don't know.
But you could do all that with land line
stuff.
You don't need to go bounce anything
from space.
You could do audio,
wouldn't you?
You could just put it in space and it
just broadcast and shoot it up there and
shoot it back.
Why would you lie about that?
I mean,
there's a ton of fucking space.
Junk
satellite,
no faith for satellites,
no pays for satellites.
The taxpayer.
They,
they get bills.
We need nude telecommunication
satellite.
We got to throw it up there so you don't
need $35 million.
Don't think Niko.
Yeah.
Okay.
We're going to sign it.
They get the money to tax scam.
You don't think are real?
I don't think so.
Well,
Jesus Christ.
I don't think so.
Well,
what's happening?
What about,
what are those things up there that you
can watch from the ground?
Have you ever seen the space station fly
over head?
You could see it.
They can in.
I have pictures of it.
They timed it.
They told me it was going to be
overhead.
I took a picture of it.
Everyone was in a high altitude plane.
What's the difference?
Why would they do that?
Why would they lie?
Why would they pretend it's a space?
How high do airplanes go?
30,000 feet.
Right now they can go hire 59 or 50 plus
commercial airplanes on average,
somewhere in the 30s 30 35,000 right.
When you're on the ground,
early sealing at 30,000 feet,
barely fucking.
When you're in 30,000 feet and you'd
look down,
you wouldn't be able to see a god damn
it's true bus or a plane.
Now those satellites are supposed to be
like a hundred miles up.
Think about that because they're in
space and there a light.
There are very small pinprick of light
that moves across the sky.
You could see him with optics.
You want to,
okay,
but you really haven't looked and you
definitely haven't looked with optics.
If you look with like a big spotting
scope,
these people get these telescopes and
they look up and they know exactly
what's going to be.
You can actually program it into the
telescope.
There's things that you can download
where you could find the coordinates of
itch into each individual planning the
way that really super powerful
telescopes.
You said a amateur astronomers like to
use you in the key numbers and it'll
move specifically to a spot in the sky
where you can tune in to the moon or
tune into Saturn or into very specific
areas of the cosmos.
That change all the time because of the
fact that the earth is spinning.
We're catching all sorts of different
shit,
all,
all sorts of different times.
Especially no matter where you are,
if you're on the equator,
you're looking at a totally different
image,
you know,
at one moment in the sky,
then you are the next moment so it can
tell you exactly where the space
station's going to be,
where the moon's going to be,
where Mars is going to be,
and they punch these coordinates into
these little computers and they all move
to this thing.
I mean,
you believe the marvel Mars Rovers,
real man Eddie,
I don't think I'm going to do this
anymore because it's just like,
I don't see why.
First of all,
I don't see where's the money for.
Then I'll say,
well,
hold on a second.
I don't see where the money is to have
all these hoaxes that you don't see the
tax scam with the rovers land,
the,
they get the,
they just got nine NASA got $19 billion,
uh,
for trump gave him $19 billion.
What tells me possible so that they can
actually make a rover.
Tell me what,
tell me what the space shuttle has done
for humanity.
Tell me all that money that was wasted
on spacial and then they just trashed
it.
They went up,
I don't know how many times and then
they just trashed it.
I don't tell him how all those billions
of dollars has helped humanity.
Tell me,
well,
I think scientific innovation is very
important to us because in our minds we
constantly want newer bed,
better,
more innovative technologies.
Just a part of being a person in the
21st century what everybody wants.
Everybody wants a new computer,
everybody wants new things and a lot of
this new stuff comes from NASA
technology.
It comes from all the science and
innovation that goes names a part of me.
There's a list right there.
Why
do you say this when you don't look into
it?
I just love telling highway safety.
How does that,
how can we can read that down?
Hires,
how can that,
how can we can caddy,
but the,
the massive requirements that you have
on the gear when you're talking about
going through fucking space,
the insane stress of reentry,
they figured out all kinds of crazy
shit.
The speed in which you land,
they figured out a bunch of crazy shit
and rich baby food,
I mean portable,
cordless vacuums,
freeze drying technology.
All of this comes from space.
There's a shit load of things that they
figured out.
Harnessing solar energy.
There's a lot of innovation that comes
from the development of either the space
station or the shuttles or a bunch of
different things that they've invented
and they continue to innovate these
things,
these new satellites,
the shooting on the space are way better
than the humble.
They keep doing more and more,
better and better,
and it's this constant rush to see who
can get to the,
the furthest point of technology in
whatever field they're in,
whether it's the field of rocketry,
whether it's the field of satellites,
there's this massive amount of
competition between the top scientists
in the world and to think that that's
all fake.
Does it make any sense?
Because there are some things that are
fake.
So why assume that all this is fake when
you really could see the challenger,
you saw the challenger explode in the
sky.
If it's fake,
no one was there to engineer the shit
that failed.
Who said that was framed?
Well,
any of it,
any space travel because it's going up.
So high altitude,
you know,
the space shuttle goes up and they'd use
work on fucking satellites.
I do know that the space station video
that sheldon and amy hit it,
they do this.
The problem is,
is a lot of these things that you just
automatically want to fake six moon
missions.
Dude,
of course that on trust shows,
even if that was true,
those are people in 1969 they're not the
same humans.
Uh,
so some people,
they're not the same human beings.
That's just like saying that the people
who made the movies in 1969 are the same
people that made fast and furious eight
is that's what they make the movies.
They're not the same people.
They're totally different humans.
It's like saying the standup comedians
from 1969 but the same as the one nine 6
million missions.
How am I supposed to believe those are
not the same people?
Even if that was true,
there's not the same people in rich.
Richard Nixon isn't alive anymore.
Just write them all off though.
Eddie just off.
Got To prove that to me.
I don't need to believe,
hey,
but don't need to believe it.
How's it going to add on?
Believe it,
but if it's true,
I don't give a shit.
Okay.
It's true.
Oh,
that's true.
Okay,
but you got to prove it to me.
Otherwise the problem isn't die handled
the product.
The problem is there's no proven it and
you want to always assume that it's
fake.
You don't have like this empty,
prove it to me like I'm not assuming
either way.
You're assuming it's fake every time
they faked six moon mission,
but it doesn't matter.
These are not the same people living in
a different type of people they want,
they're not going to add all those
standard logic.
The logic is just because someone fakes
something,
one point in time before you were all
alive,
doesn't mean that those same human
beings ever managed to download their
brains.
And everybody that ever did that job for
the rest of time,
because they're not the same humans,
but so the scientists that are today,
the generations later,
whether it's NASA or these Japanese
scientists or the Russians,
the Chinese,
whoever the fuck is putting satellites
and rockets into space,
they're not the same people from 1969
you can't like look at them.
It's like in one ad,
one blanket,
or
I can't,
I can't blame NASA.
1969 Vena NASA,
uh,
Warner von Braun at Nazi.
I can't blame today's NASA for all the
lies from,
is that what you're saying?
From the early seventies I'm saying,
do you believe that the space shuttles
were real?
No.
I do believe the spacial Israel.
Why?
Just that I've saw plenty of video of
them and then they take it on.
That's it.
Everything else is bullshit.
No,
they made the Saturn five rockets and
they launched him.
Okay.
So do you know where they went into
orbit?
I don't know when the orbiter,
I don't know how high,
how high people are going.
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
Don't know.
I know they're going high,
but I don't know how high.
So why would you assume that any of it
is fake?
They fake six moon missions.
Okay.
You keep saying that.
No,
but that's why.
Yeah,
but we're not talking about the same
people at ea,
but that's,
but it doesn't matter.
It's the same organization.
The problem is worse today.
Turn them into va as soon as you say
they,
but now let me ask you something.
Let me ask you a Brendan,
do you see that?
That how I can't trust NASA because even
though it was different people in 1969
to 1973,
even though the p the massive today
aren't the ones that fake six moon
missions and stole billions of dollars
from American taxpayer,
just because the guys from today,
somehow they got weeded out.
And then NASA,
I don't know that they got weeded out
in,
in Nasa came this,
uh,
honest agency of the government.
But I don't know that I'm going to
assume,
I'm going to assume no,
I think you're the,
you're,
it's still part of the shit.
I could be wrong.
I couldn't be wrong.
You're good.
Let's say those six missions were all
bullshit and it was fake.
You're going off the exception,
not the general rule.
So it's like me coming into your academy
and some guy's a dick.
I'm like all those 10th planet guys are
Dicks.
Like you're just lumping all them in the
same fucking,
that was a big shit though.
It wasn't like side project mass
employees to roadmap.
This is no,
I understand you saying the same thing
he said.
He's saying that just because,
dude,
that was the mood swings were so
gigantic and so global and the greatest
achievement of mankind and they don't
even have the records anymore.
Joe,
you know what I'm talking about?
We're talking about this earlier,
man.
You were talking about this early.
You know all that moon,
you're not immature.
Data's missing.
They had an awesome video says,
he says,
yeah,
we don't have it.
It's missing.
Or maybe it's stolen,
but even if we did the head of NASA,
even if we did have the tapes,
we don't have the machines to play him
anymore,
so it really doesn't matter.
Come on,
man.
Dumb retard
detective on the planet would would be
suspicious.
That just smelled like mission,
but you can't just lump all,
all,
it's all bullshit.
Then everyone will the most.
You want to see some Brendan,
it'll make you think.
This is the most suspicious thing.
One of the weirdest things about the
moon landing is the post flight press
conference.
Have you ever seen it?
It's really weird.
It's real weird.
I mean they can swift.
They did.
Well,
conspiracy,
hippo,
skeptical.
Hipaa goes,
what the fuck is going on?
They're open to it because now you're
going,
you're open to the fact that maybe the
fuck I,
I maybe they did fake that,
but you can't just lump sum and I'm
saying they did the greatest achievement
of the time.
We got new people now.
Come on,
man.
That's hilarious.
How can,
how can you see how I can't trust shit
from assets?
Maybe they would,
they they,
they,
you know,
all those bad people have died and
they're all old and the new NASA,
they're the good mass.
They can't all,
but there was an agenda or believe in a
guy on youtube.
It says the world's flat and dinosaurs
aren't real.
What's better if that was my space like
that,
it's,
there's a lot of people saying it.
All those guys,
there's a lot of people in mental
institutions,
a lot of people in jail.
So how do people that are child
molesters?
There's a lot of people are racist
people.
Those people,
if you gave every racist person a video
camera and put made them a youtube
video,
you'll be like,
oh,
have you watched fit with races?
Have you watched history of flat earth
by Eric?
Do I see that?
Don't have an hour for that.
You're asking what is their side?
What?
What does Eric do?
I fourth grade,
my teacher,
I know what you don't care and that's
fine.
I'm not going to be mad at you for not
caring.
Of course.
Don't be mad at me for carrying.
Then you don't look into what from mad
cause you don't look into what
scientists say.
You don't.
You're just automatically dismiss that.
This fair to say the reason why you care
so much about Eddie believe in this shit
and you know Eddie going,
I'm crazy cause he said he influences a
lot of people and you to find enough for
yourself,
look for the truth and look into it like
uh,
like you're investigating and just look
into both sides.
There's a reason why it's becoming huge.
There's a reason because people don't
really go to school.
They don't learn astrophysics,
they don't study all these things.
It's hard to learn.
The,
the entry barrier is fucking huge.
If you want to study physics,
you want to figure out,
I can barely pay attention to it.
I listen to these books on tape and I
have to go back over.
I'm three,
four times just to understand a
paragraph.
Try to figure out exactly what the fuck
they're quantifying.
They're talking about really intense
shit that thousands of people been
working on in conjunction.
They all feed off of each other's
innovation.
There's so many people working on these
things.
Eddie,
the idea that they're all in on some
sort of a giant global lie is insane.
Yeah.
That's what everyone thinks.
Okay.
There's no,
yeah,
I mean it's,
there was no women.
No,
there's no one in history of flat.
I was looking into it.
It definitely can't.
So let me just say why I don't watch
game of thrones.
I don't watch breaking bad and better
call Saul.
Nope.
What do you watch?
I watch real shit like first 48 and
you're not talking about a show,
but if you watch game of thrones,
he knows it's fake.
It's fake.
But you don't,
I,
I'm just having fun.
What do you think?
Is the earth flat around?
I don't know if it's flat around until
we see a picture from space.
They're saying this bitch could be
squared be around.
It could be willing to a big camera with
fish.
I fish.
I had done it.
You guys are fooled by the Fisheye Lens.
C'Mon man.
Plenty of pictures without the Fisheye
Lens that you could find this fish eye
lens.
You guys buy some basic ass
kindergarten.
Do you understand perspective?
Do you do it?
I do understand for PSI,
if you didn't have a fish eye lens,
you looking at this tiny fraction of the
surface,
the reason why you shied lens of 1946,
how do you know that's real?
Because it's a picture.
I ran it on the net.
That's why I know he's like this.
Would you,
would you be,
it's real.
That's real to Eddie.
Would you be open to talking to you care
if you believe that's real?
I don't care.
Would you be taught in to talking to an
actual astrophysicist?
Yes.
I would love to.
Like what would you do if Neil degrasse
Tyson was here?
Same arguments.
You would have some questions.
What would you listen to them?
Like if you had to be told you some shit
that actually made sense or would you
just think he's in a total I round earth
society.
I think,
uh,
he's,
um,
you know,
there's people that they push to be the
spokespeople and there's really
brilliant people that are good at
talking and their educators like him.
And then they get on television and
people love it.
And so he comes back and then he does a
hit show called Cosmos or re-enacts.
But Carl Sagan show and everybody loves
it.
And more people understand science now
than ever before because he breaks.
It's hard.
Eddie,
you know,
it's hard because you didn't go to
school.
I'm not mad,
but look,
I love you man.
I love you.
You know,
I just don't want,
I'm just trying to,
I want to,
I want to be able to talk about flat
earth and have fun cake,
but it's not fun for me because I think
there's some 16 year old kids out there
that are listening to this and they
think he makes sense.
And the problem is,
it's the,
what's wrong with that?
Who cares about,
because those poor kids,
what's happened to me?
Am I am I,
my life was going to wasting time.
No,
it's heavy.
You're waiting.
You're wasting time.
You fucking come on,
come on.
And he'd go down and shit that you would
consider a waste of time if you don't do
it.
If someone was all in the pool pool and
he was obsessed with poor,
you would say you're wasting your time.
What are you getting out of?
When I hit those?
They're real.
Okay.
I hit those balls to go into the whole,
it takes skill and concentration and I,
it gives me something to occupy my mind.
It's a game.
It's a mind game and it's a body game.
When you're watching a fake video the
guy made about,
you think it's fake nuclear not being
real?
I think it's fake.
Okay.
That's what you think.
I mean I just feel like all the people
that study it at all the universities
have come to a conclusion and then one
guy makes a youtube video or 20 guys,
they're saying a thousand Santos Bonacci
good.
Why would you listen to them versus the
ability to,
they have free cause generations after
generations of studying the science
behind it.
The science,
there's a lot of repeatable science.
Right,
but you just told us about this one test
and you paired it out as some sort of a
theory that we should look up and when
we did it turns out it didn't even work.
It wasn't repeated.
Okay,
whatever.
Eddie,
I love you,
but I don't like the way you approach
these things sometimes because I think
it confuses the fuck out of people like
I was when I was young.
I was super gullible.
I believed all kinds of stupid shit and
I wasted a ton of time.
Like what?
Especially with successful guys,
all these certain stuff,
goddamned Ufo people,
man,
all those.
I'll Ulu ufo stories that bought it.
I never got any,
have you ever heard of the law of
perspective?
Yes.
You know that's not real.
It's not a law went about it.
It's that that's the deaf.
They're giving the definition of what
perspective is.
I'm trying to tell you though real
quick.
There are laws of conservation of energy
and such in physics.
There are actual laws that they can be
translated without even speaking
language.
It's math.
The law perspective is not one of those.
What is it?
Tell me.
It's just,
it's just the definition of perspective.
I'm asking you what the law,
what is it?
Cause it's not real well,
well maybe,
maybe.
So you're saying there's no uh,
love.
I'm saying it's not a law as definition
gravity.
It's a definition of the word
perspective.
That's not a law.
Well,
the law is a perspective.
Are the Herat one of the laws is the
perspective horizon not real to high
level.
That's,
I love that.
That's not how it always happens.
Always happens.
Not a law,
but it always happens.
It's a law.
If it happens,
that's not a law.
That's,
this is where you don't understand that
part of the laws of science.
That's not a law.
That's a definition.
Okay,
and then what is the definition?
Definition of a noun?
It's a person,
place thing or idea.
That's not a law.
Okay.
That's just the definition.
You know what else is,
I used to call this double lotus for
years and years and years.
And it's not double lotus.
It's full load.
It's not a lot though.
Right?
But it's not,
it's not double load.
It's not a law.
It's not double loaded.
That's what you're saying.
You're talking about a different word
for the same moodle.
What he's saying perspective Stephanie
Shot Better because hold on.
It's the same thing because of whatever
you call it.
You got,
well when you look up this stuff online,
I try to type in the law of perspective
cause I wanted to see what your,
what you and Eric Dubay believe.
That is the only thing I ever find with
the law perspective is the word flat
earth with it.
Or maybe there's actually there are
urban dictionary has a definition for
what does,
doesn't matter if it's law but it's not
the same manner but that,
but if the horizon always rises,
that's not a [inaudible] uh,
uh,
what would you call it then?
Um,
you don't believe in gravity though
thing of perspective.
I don't believe in gravity either.
That falls at a constant of 9.8 meters
per second.
That is a,
that's a law of gravity.
Gravity is a theory I had.
No,
no,
no.
You guys have this theory of what
gravity is.
Density,
but that's another scientific word.
You guys said that if it's more dense it
falls,
but why does it fall?
Why was it fall lower?
If it's heavier,
then why is it heavier?
Do you know what?
Cause it's 10 [inaudible] shortfalls.
A helium gas.
Helium was a gas.
We're only heavy then it's because of
where it's lighter.
It's less dense.
I'll explain.
It's lighter because we're in the
atmosphere of earth.
Isn't it less dense than if we were in
space?
There is no atmosphere.
That's why everything floats.
Gases and us were dense too,
but we would float in space just like
that.
We got in the space.
You're correct.
If we got out there,
so can we not go to space?
I don't know how far we can go up
the space station.
You said the space shuttle went into
orbit.
I don't know how far I want to say hi.
I don't know where it went,
but I know it took off.
Saw that and then I see it landing.
You see that more?
I went,
you know when we heard the plane,
right?
For sure.
Are you not confused on what laws and
stuff science are though?
Do you not see that?
Okay.
We'll call it definition,
but it's,
what do we call it?
But that's not,
what do they call it?
We'll call it whatever you want.
In science,
we call things laws.
We don't call them definitions and
science.
There are laws because?
Because so what does that,
that law,
which is most of them called in those
cases if hold on to,
in most cases it's math,
the law so that that math,
then that formulaic equation can go to
any country and work.
I don't need to speak English to the guy
in Germany.
That to explain to them what I'm trying
to get out of it,
he can test it with the same things,
the same variables and get the same
thing out of it.
That's why all these things are laws,
not definitely Cleveland.
Thank you for clearing that up permit.
Does that work?
Do you accept that or no?
People
use as verbose terminology because it
makes him appear smarter than they
really are.
No Eddie,
and they tried to say it in a fancier
way because they really didn't go to
school for this shit.
So they say a bunch of shit that's not
real.
Like the law of perspective and it's not
a law and it belies the real problem.
They don't have an education in this
stuff and they're just talking out of
their ass.
That's disrespectful,
disrespectful to the fucking generations
of people that have been studying that
their whole lives.
That one guy can figure out all these
different things that dinosaurs aren't
real.
Nuclear bombs are real,
the earth is flat.
It's ridiculous.
Satellites aren't real.
It's one guy is this must be the
smartest person in the world.
Well,
that one guy,
the guy that one guy that you're pals
with,
the love that stuff,
that guys got videos on dinosaurs on the
fucking earth.
He figured it all the time.
I had him on my podcast.
That's too much money.
He makes often flat earth.
I'd be interested to know that he's
writing a lot of books off in a lot of
youtube videos.
Know,
isn't everybody making money as a NASA
making billions and well,
he's got a youtube account.
NASA lied six times about the moon
missions and cat don't believe he kept
calling back from them.
That's it,
but that's the root of it all,
so don't be mad.
That's why you should understand that.
That's one of that.
Now,
because of that,
the most preposterous idea available
that every photo of the earth is fake
and there's no photos,
there's no photos,
there's no photos of the composite,
a special video.
If they don't find a problem that
there's no photos of the earth being
flat,
not one.
There's no photos of the earth being
round.
There's planning,
there's no photos.
NASA will tell you that about CGI
artist.
How can we,
how do we think?
We can't think.
We can't get anywhere else.
It can even get a picture.
That doesn't mean that has a meeting
every week.
Go to the artist was never proved.
It goes back to that for me and say,
Gee,
they didn't see anything in there about
the CGI that that article,
he puts together data and make photos
out.
He puts together data because it has to
be interpreted because you're talking
about 1.7 terabytes.
Treg the video of him talking about the
video you told me to try it was,
that was the wrong one.
It's a terrible bunch where he's talking
terabytes like a thousand gigabytes
isn't word for word.
He goes,
well,
it is.
It's photoshopped it.
It's photoshop.
It has to be.
It's,
it's,
that's a no shop.
He didn't say it in that article.
He did.
He did said come out of his mouth.
He's got to find that.
Okay,
but when you're talking to,
you know,
photoshop doesn't mean that they're
distorting the image.
It also can mean to the connecting a
bunch of different images to make it,
but when you watch him talking about how
we put together the official picture of
earth from space,
he's talking about cartoon animation
type Shit.
He's talking about his own imagination.
Well,
maybe because he's talking about this
insane amount of data,
1.7 terabytes,
maybe we don't understand how the fuck
that gets interpreted into an image in
the first place.
I don't even know if it's possible to do
it.
You know like to have an in perspective
when you're looking at it like a 12 inch
screen or 24 inch screen where the fuck
your monitor would be and you're going
to take this 1.7 terabyte image and
shrink it down so it fits in there.
I don't understand that messed with some
shit.
Damn.
That finished product is it admitted?
CIA,
CGI composite.
It's admitted.
It's not even the Japanese got real
ones.
The chaplain,
he's got real ones but that's again
figure it out.
Eddie.
NASA does have one.
That's what the problem is.
They keep saying they don't from 1972
saying the only real one that happens
from [inaudible] 72 I just pulled up is
up right now that there's pictures from
today that discover when you said that
that on some pictures I'd delete it.
Get rid of that.
Okay.
You guys,
that's way cool.
What is it six times to leave in the
space shuttle,
but you don't believe in anything else?
That's where it ends.
So leaving shadow goes up and flies
around direct TV on when it does
dinosaurs.
I don't know.
Here it goes.
This is this.
That looks fake as fuck.
April 16th,
2017 anything you guys toss up all the
fake ones off.
Do you have evidence that you would
accept as real?
It looks just like the ones that were
admitted that were,
let's say that let's try to thoughts.
They look exactly like the ones that
were admitted.
Fakes where you accepted.
We one's real.
Can I send you to space and like what do
you need to fuck with you too?
His ass up.
I seen a bunch of fake ones in the show
me that one I got that looks like all
the CGI ones,
like say I don't believe it.
Let's try to stick this lens.
Tams is a motherfucker of a podcast.
I worry about Yeti.
I really do.
You don't need to,
man.
I'm fucking group better than average.
You're doing great,
but I worry about you going down these
rabbit holes and strong.
What's the big deal?
Who cares if the earth is round or flat?
It's entertaining to me.
I understand.
So what's the big deal?
Yeah.
If kids started looking into flat earth,
good start questioning shit.
If you look into it and you,
and you have proof that it is around,
instead of going,
oh,
some scientists figured it out,
somebody figured it out,
somebody figured out.
But you figure it out.
You try to figure it out.
You know the one thing that all,
we know that we don't need scientists to
figure out as we know a couple of
things.
A compass,
a compass points to north.
It doesn't need a battery.
And there's this,
you know why?
No,
I know.
Let me,
let me explain it.
This is all we know.
It's pointing to the north.
There's,
it's,
it's a magnetic force in the north.
That's all we know that for sure.
I don't need a scientist to confirm
that.
I know that there's a force in the
north,
some kind of magnetic force.
What else do,
what else don't I need a government
scientist confirmation from uh,
uh,
the north star.
It's right over the north end.
You finish.
Let me finish.
Let me just finish.
Let me just finish the North Pole.
The North Star,
Polaris is directly coincidentally over
the North Pole where all the campuses
are pointing.
All the company companies are pointing
to the North Pole.
There's this magnetic force in the North
Pole and coincidence polaris.
No,
I'm just saying the polaris is directly
over the North Pole.
It's been multiple north stars is
Polaris directly above the North Pole.
You know that there's been more than one
northstar over the history of where'd
you get that information from?
From the Internet.
Exactly.
So you don't believe that any,
I don't know.
I mean it's Polaris,
the North Star Polaris because Polaris,
the Northstar,
let me read this please.
Cause it'll explain.
Right now earth's rotation access
happens to be pointing almost exactly a
polaris,
but in the year 3000 BC,
the North Star was a star called through
ban,
also known as Alpha draconian,
and in about 13 years from now,
the procession of the rotation axis will
mean that the bright star Vega will be
the north star.
That's according to NASA.
That's according to every scientist that
studies at Eddie from,
how do you know that?
Because that's why it's still a,
how do you know arena?
How do you know?
You just said,
you know,
I don't know list.
There's no dispute about this.
I bet.
I bet he jamie could pull up 100
different fucking things.
It'll show you the same thing on the
Internet,
but it's not just on the Internet and
it's okay if you get hit the internet,
but it's not okay if I get information.
That's what it is.
It's if you get your information,
there's no information on both sides,
but you don't think that's true.
But now when I look at it,
northstar changes over time.
University of what does that Michigan,
does that make sense?
That doesn't make any,
that's not science.
Why does that not make sense?
No,
I said it doesn't make sense that the
Internet only works for you and not
familiar what works when you,
when you keep looking at it over and
over and over again from all these
multiple sources,
wouldn't you just assume you didn't say,
you said over and over and over and over
and then you did.
Why you playing games?
This is like you're playing tic TAC toe.
You're not looking at the truth of that
sound like a little Jiu Jitsu.
If you want to believe Nasa App,
it's all assets,
government,
psyche.
Why is the,
why are you telling me then why does
that compass point towards the north?
I don't know.
We know,
we know there's a magnetic force north
in the mag in the North Pole and we know
the polaris is right over the north pole
and the constellations rotate around
Polaris.
Polaris is a fixed star and they all
wrote the constellations,
rotate around that and it's right over
the north pole spent.
Oh,
go on striking how much time you've
actually spent explaining what,
what did I say wrong?
You and Eric,
they repeat that over and over again
like the sky doesn't change at night.
No,
no,
I didn't know what I said.
I never said that.
I said,
well,
you said the stars don't star Polaris
Star.
Stay ahead of the norm over the North
Pole.
Yes or no,
and do the constellations rotate around
Polaris?
Nope.
Yes sir.
License don't rotate.
No,
no.
They started around.
When you look at time lapse photography
of Polaris,
you could you go watch time.
All the constellations gone.
Polaris is the fixer.
That's why they didn't go.
You're not,
you could find your way around and just
find the north star.
It doesn't move.
Explain that
and if the Earth is spinning like we
know it is,
what's directly above the earth would
stay the same because the earth is
spinning faster than spaces,
furthest spinning a thousand miles an
hour in a circle.
Even though the cosmos suspending the
cosmos changes as well.
There's a lot of things that change
and the sky looks different all the
time.
Change over the North Pole,
but if you were spinning and you talking
about a small window of time when
they're taking these time,
life time lapse photographs,
her take him over a few hours.
Yes.
Becky,
what do you understand that that if you
are looking up over a few hours and you
have one light that's directly overhead
and the other ones are circulate,
the one light that's directly overhead
over a few hours is not going to move
enough to register in the photograph,
but the ones on the sides are,
when you're looking at a timelapse,
you're at a time lapse over
a few hours.
If you are looking at a time lapse over
months or years,
you would see that thing spinning to
Polaris would still be on the same spot.
No.
You'd have the procession of the
equinoxes.
It changes the rotation of the earth.
Earth Act.
It wobbles on its axis.
They've been tracking that forever.
You got to watch time lapse photography
on your,
on Youtube.
Do you know you're not listening to one
time lapse photography is over a few
hours and and over a few hours.
You can see the earth causing a thousand
miles an hour and constellation circling
around Polaris.
That's one motion,
right?
You,
you,
you capture one motion and that time
lapse photography,
but science is telling us that there's
four motions going on.
There are,
they're just much slower.
You're talking about something that
you're looking at.
It's very quick.
Over a very short amount of time,
year after year,
decade to decade.
Polar look on the same spot.
Yeah.
None of these stars are staying in the
same spot.
You've got to find one,
a polaris specific one.
They find prolaris which cause that's
the only one that isn't and everything's
going around Eddie.
Eddie,
what are you looking at right there when
you see that that time lapse photo at
the SBAC,
Shit spinning the earth and the sky is,
is the sky spinning or as the earth,
what do you think?
I think the sky spinning.
Jesus Christ.
Why would people be lying about that?
I think,
I think the light's about Polaris.
Right?
You know why?
Because it's in the center.
Ready?
Yeah,
exactly.
There's always that no 32nd picture.
No.
You talking about something that happens
very often as other constellations are
moving really quick,
eddie,
if it's the ones directly overhead.
Okay.
If you have a ball and you spin it on
your finger like Michael Jordan,
the outside equator of the ball is going
to spin like fucking crazy in this big
long wide loop,
but the tip of the ball is going to spin
in a very short,
tight circle.
Okay.
Right.
When you see the Harlem Globe trotters,
you can test it yourself.
Eddie,
if you just point a camera in the same
spot out of your window for like three
months straight,
take a photo,
maybe even four or five tests.
I'm talking to you [inaudible] we just
want to give you an example to test it
for yourself to show you that the,
the stars,
the stars in the sky that you'll see
above your head like you've claimed to
go out and look out every night will be
different throughout the year.
No,
no,
they will.
They won't be different.
They're moving.
They are rotating,
the are rotating around Polaris and not
going to be in the same spot moving.
Okay.
They are moving,
but you're always going to see polaris.
Why would you think that this is a
conspiracy?
Why would they lie about the earth
spinning when it's really the the
universe spinning,
not stars trying to controls.
I don't know.
What are they?
People,
led's,
people looking down.
GRANDPA happy people,
their souls.
Angels.
You told me my grandma's up there flying
unicorns,
bro.
Grandma's flying.
Unicorn even told you the crazy.
Oh,
you don't do shit.
No crystal.
Craziest shit.
Can't tell you crazier than flat.
Why save it?
I don't.
How about you guys are already making
fun of me for from flat earth.
I'm trying.
I just don't.
I just don't trust mass.
I understand.
I don't trust it.
You're still,
you have a circle of trust once.
Do some crazy shit.
Please promise me.
End On this note.
I want to end up the crazy tee shirt for
next time.
Yeah,
just don't make it a giant now.
If you drop it now,
we'll never make it at six o'clock.
I know.
I just wanted to,
oh shit.
Yeah,
that's it's a clock.
Unless unless you want to hear it now.
I don't know.
It should.
It's too crazy.
Let's go do it.
Go do some crazy Chris talk.
We'll talk off here about this whole
crazy.
It will discredit the flat earth theory.
I can't hit my mind.
Can't handle daddy.
Everything is except this one.
You need a tissue.
He says everything is conspiracy.
You make life.
You will make Alex Jones look like
fucking like Gandhi.
Fuck.
Like Alex Jones is like Alex Jones is
like 90% of conspiracy theories.
Like,
well that's all bullshit.
You know?
But Eddie,
just these,
fuck you.
You got to appreciate the hustle by
Eddie is like a blue belt conspiracy
theorists.
You'd have.
Wow.
I can't believe you said that.
Let's end on that tonight.
Everybody much love blue belts are
fucking batteries.
[inaudible]
I didn't,
I didn't.