Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Boom,
boom.
Adam,
what's up man?
How you doing?
It's good to be here today.
It's good to be here too with you and to
talk knocking shit over there.
Can't be trusted.
Your book.
Alien worlds and the fate of the earth.
All about it.
That's deep shit,
man.
Just the,
just the title alone.
Like,
whoa.
I love aliens.
Everybody loves aliens.
Everybody does.
But what are your thoughts on actual
aliens and whether or not they've ever
visited here?
Yeah,
it's interesting because uh,
you know,
sorta two things.
So first of all we should tell everybody
you have a background in science.
I do.
I'm an astrophysicist at the University
of Rochester.
I run a research group that studies like
stars and planets.
And so you're not a crazy person I
brought on here.
No,
no,
no.
I'm a card carrying scientists.
I got my card and everything.
Um,
so yeah,
I've been doing research on astronomy,
astrophysics for a long time,
but I also do all this popular writing
like for Npr,
New York Times.
And the genesis of this book came a
because I love science fiction.
Been reading science fiction since I was
a kid,
uh,
but also I do a lot of work on climate
change and so I do a lot of climate
change denial.
And what I realized was that there's
this way we talk about it that is like
completely forgets about the fact that
like,
we're probably not the first,
you know,
and uh,
that led me to a whole bunch of research
that eventually led to this book,
you know,
including one paper that we did that
showed that the odds that we're the only
time it's ever happened,
only you know,
the only civilization in the entire
history of the universe.
The only way that that could be true is
if,
uh,
the odds per planet are one in 10
billion trillion,
right?
That's pretty low,
So,
you know,
the,
the odds of anything being one in 10
billion trillion at pretty freaking low.
So,
um,
it's probably happened before,
you know,
there's been other civilizations before
ours.
And once you realize that man that is
like,
you know,
changes everything about how we think
about ourselves,
you know,
and what's happening to us right now.
So other civilizations before ours that
have fucked things up.
Well that's kind of the premise,
right?
So that's what,
you know,
when you look at climate change,
right?
Basically what we it is,
is civilizations are giant machines for
turning energy into work,
right?
You know,
New York City,
right?
You sit over and you look at Manhattan,
you're like,
Holy Shit,
there's all this energy flowing into it.
And then there's all this work being
done,
you know,
to keep everything moving.
And uh,
you know,
there's no way not to have an impact if
you build a world girdling civilization,
which,
you know,
that's what a civilization is.
There's going to be impact.
So the whole point of my doing this book
was to start looking at ourselves as
just one of,
you know,
we're not alone,
right?
The only time this has ever happened
doesn't mean anybody's around now,
like that's a different question.
But the idea that like,
it's never happened before.
It meaning like,
you know,
civilization what's happening around us,
like these machinery and everything that
um,
you know,
that just in the new world of what we
understand about planets and shit that
is just like,
you know,
it's not tenable anymore.
We got to wake up the idea that some
civilization has to be the first one.
That's the only.
The only way you could ever think that
we're the only ones is that some
civilization has to be the first one.
Even in a universe that's infinite.
Yeah,
it has to happen one time.
But the ideas are the conditions ideal
in a trillion different spots all over
the,
the infinite spanse of the universe.
And that's the thing,
right?
So what we've learned,
so you know,
one of my trips right now is like,
this is not your grandfather's steady
anymore,
right?
Our understanding,
we went through this major revolution in
our understanding of what planets about
20 years ago.
So he looked back at the Greeks,
right?
And you can see them arguing about when
he were there.
Any other stars have planets other than
the sun.
And you know,
it goes back and forth,
you know,
some of the Greeks were like,
yeah,
it's definitely happening.
And then like,
aristotle was like,
no,
we're the only world in this whole,
in the whole universe that has life.
And then as time goes on,
it kind of goes back and forth.
And even at the turn of the last of
this,
uh,
the 19th century,
people thought planets were incredibly
rare that like,
they all,
they thought the only way you can get a
planet with two stars past really close
to each other and they kind of like
taffy pulled out stuff that will
eventually form a planet.
And the lots of those kinds of
collisions are so small that people were
like,
you know what,
there's just no planets and no plan.
It's no life,
you know,
unless something really freaky is going
on.
But then 20 years ago we discovered our
first planet orbiting that crazy.
When you really think about that,
20 years is such a short amount of time.
Nineteen 98.
Yeah.
And nobody knew before that,
like nobody knew whether there were any
planets.
Right.
You know,
when I was starting to drive,
people are like,
well,
we don't know whether there's going to
be any other planets,
and we went from a to z.
The first one was actually 96,
I think [inaudible] 95,
96.
Uh,
from that to now where we know that
every fricking star in the sky had the
planet at least one,
you know,
pretty much everyone pretty.
I mean,
the big giant ones,
maybe not,
but they're so rare that you know,
pretty much every star you see in the
sky has a family of planets around it.
That is so nuts.
It's so nice that this is such a new
discovery.
Yeah.
I mean,
when we think about what we know about
the universe,
we think that we've had a pretty good
understanding of it for a long time.
Right.
But the fact that we didn't even know
for sure that there are planets,
right?
Right.
In my own lifetime,
you know,
people were teaching me when I was
starting,
you know,
we just don't know.
Maybe they're rare and now we know for
certain that they're everywhere.
And I think people have to realize is
every one of those planets is a place,
you know what I mean?
It's a place you could walk around,
some of them for sure are going to have
oceans,
there's going to be mountains,
it's going to be rain falling,
you know,
I mean like they're all freaking places
and they're all places where things can
happen.
You know,
planets are basically like nature's way
of taking sunlight and doing something
interesting with it.
So you have 10 billion trillion planets
in the universe,
right?
And every one of them is an experiment
that's being run.
So you know,
the idea that like,
we're the first time it's out now that
we know that right now that we've gone
through that revolution and understand
that planets are like,
diamond doesn't planets.
Now we're not only talking about
planetary,
we're talking what plants are in the
right place for life to form.
So there's the idea of the habitable
zone,
right?
So,
you know,
mercury sucks.
You cannot,
you know,
mercury so hot that there no way
anything's going to happen.
And you know,
planets that are far,
far enough out there going to be so
cold,
you know,
they're so far away from their star that
they're gonna be so cold that,
you know,
it's hard to get liquid water on the
surface.
So we defined the habitable or
goldilocks zone is the place where you
can have,
you can pour water onto the surface and
they'll just sit there and will freeze
and it will sort of just evaporate away.
So,
uh,
all these 10 billion trillion planets
I'm talking about are all in the right
place for life to form,
you know.
And so like with that many numbers that
many experiments being run,
like you got to be a psychotic
pessimists to say that like this is the
only time a civilization has ever
happened.
Right?
But there's still no evidence yet.
Obviously we didn't even know that
they're really absolutely were planets
until 20 years ago.
Right.
But we don't know for sure that there's
something else out there.
No,
no.
This is an argument by a,
I call it like an argument by
exhaustion.
You know,
if I gave you a bag of 10 billion
trillion planets and you have to sort
through all of them,
right?
The odds that you're gonna you're never
gonna find another one that,
that built a civilization is now,
you know,
like I said,
you're really asking for really serious
pessimism,
but you know,
we're just getting started with this
game,
right,
of looking for life.
That's why I keep saying it's not,
this is not your grandfather's said
where you're like you're pointing,
you know,
a radio telescope at a star and you kind
of wait to see whether somebody signal
signaling you who knows whether they are
signaling who knows what they'd be
using.
Now,
what we can do,
because we got all these planets to
stare at his,
you know,
we're going to be able to like stare at
them as they pass in front of their star
and get the light that passes through
their atmosphere.
So we're going to like,
who knows what we're going to find,
you know,
we're not waiting for them to signal us
anymore over the next.
I swear to God,
man,
in the next 30 years we're going to have
data relevant to the question of life,
maybe not civilization,
so that could happen too,
but just life on other worlds,
you know,
and we've never had that for all the
arguments for the entire history of
humanity have just been two dudes
yelling at each other.
Right?
But in the next 30 years because the
stuff we're building and now that we
know there's,
there's,
uh,
planets,
we're going to have real data to argue
over with.
So now it's like this is where we're in
a whole nother ballgame.
Now.
I think the big fear for a lot of people
is what happens when we find out for
sure that there's something else out
there.
If we really do find like some other
Manhattan on some goldilocks planet,
yeah,
it's hovering some similarly sized star,
a billion light years away or whatever
the hell it is,
that's going to be very,
very,
very strange.
It will be,
it'll be a game changer,
right?
Because for religions,
for,
you know,
I mean,
wow,
you know,
what do you do if you find other
intelligent creatures were building
civilization,
started making them pay taxes.
That's what you do.
You Go,
you know,
get pissed off that they're not doing
what you want them to do.
You should be believing this bunk,
you know,
so,
uh,
but I think,
you know,
for me the thing is like it's about
climate change because what it means is
like there's no way.
But from my perspective,
you know,
that,
that if you have a civilization,
you push your planet,
you can't stop it in some sense of your
build a civilization.
It's,
well the only way around that is if you
have like a subsistence culture,
indigenous native American culture,
right?
Which it seems impossible,
but it existed here 200 years ago,
which is a blink of an eye.
I know.
It's amazing.
It's only 200 years since the ramp up
your that the world population only
crossed up the billion mark and like
1850,
you know,
I mean there were so few of us on the
planet for most of the time that you've
been.
We've been around.
Forget the planet's history.
Uh,
so,
you know,
I think like there is no discovery if we
were to get any evidence you don't want
to.
I think the way it's going to happen is
going to be more by accident than by
like signaling,
you know,
like the.
So,
so,
but if we had any evidence of another
technological forget any evidence of
just life,
right?
If we just find a biosphere evidence
that,
you know,
and we can do that from a distance,
right?
I,
even,
if the star is,
you know,
30 light years away,
if we get,
if we see as the light passes through
the star's atmosphere for those few
moments,
if we see oxygen in the atmosphere,
you know,
will be able to attack that.
That's what we can do with telescopes.
We can tell like what you can see the
fingerprints of the different kinds of
elements.
If we see oxygen in the atmosphere,
you know,
and methane that pretty much says that
there's a biosphere there,
that there's life because you wouldn't
get oxygen,
would just react away really fast if it
wasn't for life like in our,
on,
uh,
on earth.
It wasn't for life.
There'd be no oxygen in the atmosphere.
What are the possibilities of life that
exists in a completely different
environment than we expect.
Like I know that they found life at the
bottom of the ocean is volcanic events
at extreme heats,
boiling water that didn't expect to see
this.
And this is fairly recent as well.
That is that.
Yeah,
the idea that the.
Because right.
This whole definition of the habitable
zone was based on the idea like,
oh,
you got to have a surface and it's got
to be,
you know,
but now with the,
every,
not every but like a bunch of the moons
orbiting Jupiter and Saturn,
the gas giants,
they have oceans under them.
Like,
well,
this thoughts that you rope up might
have something below the surface,
right?
Yeah.
Because the Europa is a pretty big moon
and we know it's covered in ice,
right?
You can see it's covered in it,
you know,
and we think that layer of ice is maybe
like,
I don't know,
10 kilometers thick and then below that
there may be 100 kilometers of ocean and
because as it moves around Jupiter,
it's con the gravity of Jupiter.
So squishing the insights at this
probably volcanic activity happening at
the surface.
So you have hydrothermal vents,
you know,
heat escaping out of then chemicals
escaping out of the surface under the
ocean.
And that's how we think life form on
earth.
That's one of the arguments for how life
forms from formed first in the
hydrothermal vents.
So yeah,
it's a new day.
That's another game changer,
right?
So that we should also be thinking not
just about the,
the classic,
uh,
the habitable zone,
but now we've got to think about like
life and can you get civilizations in an
underwater civilization?
You know,
in an underwater you,
maybe you have a really rich ecosystem,
but you know,
with the problem with a,
uh,
you know,
an underwater life or forming
civilization is that you can't really do
fire.
Right.
Fire was pretty important for us.
For metallurgy,
you know,
to build advanced technology,
you kind of need combustion.
So,
you know,
that's kind of the open question with
that.
Yeah.
We're not really concerned with animals.
We're concerned with things that think
and change their environment.
There isn't that weird.
Like we are concerned with life,
but we're only concerned with life
that's it least similar or comparable to
us.
Microbes don't like.
We don't.
Yeah,
we don't that I'm going to go to Jupiter
for some microbes,
but we are excited about the things that
they've recently found on Mars.
Right.
I mean there's a very recent discovery,
right?
Yeah.
So,
you know,
the thing is actually from the,
so I'm gonna I,
I worked in a lot of fields,
but I would also consider myself an
astrobiologist.
Right.
Which is a pretty kind of a wild idea
that you can do astrobiology even though
you only have one example,
which is the earth,
but we've learned so much and now we can
start asking ourselves about the
possibility of life elsewhere.
So finding even a microbe like even a
frigging,
you know,
Amoeba on Mars would be,
or even evidence that there used to be
a,
but what is the evidence that they've
discovered on Mars?
What they found was um,
organic chemistry,
right?
And so our better organic chemistry man,
I hated chemistry when I was growing up
and I hated,
or was that just basically chemistry
involved in carbon,
you know,
so you can have non or organic chemistry
doesn't mean organisms,
but it's the kind of chemistry that
organisms live.
Right?
So finding evidence that there was like
they drilled nice and we sent a freaking
robot cars that could drill through a
rock,
you know,
and then ingest the rocket and then send
the data back.
Cross space.
We're pretty good for a bunch of
hairless apes.
Um,
so what,
what they found was evidence for fairly
complex.
Um,
uh,
you know,
organic chemistry,
which meant that way back when Mars and
this,
we know for sure,
right?
Mars had water on it.
We know that for sure now Mars was a
blue planet for Mars was hit by an
asteroid or comet or something along
those lines.
Everything got hit by comments.
That's how we have,
you know,
we have chunks of Mars here,
right?
That,
you know,
the thing in [inaudible] 96 or whatever,
when they were like,
ah,
we found life on Mars,
you know,
they thought that what they found was a
fossil bacteria in a chunk of Mars that
they found in Antarctica.
So the planets have been swapping spit
for like the entire history of the solar
systems,
fossilized bacteria that they found.
Is that been confirmed that most people
now think that the Allen hills a
meteorite,
that probably,
you know,
it's inconclusive,
but it's not conclusive enough to be
like,
yeah,
we found life.
It's like a tiny little squiggly worm.
Look,
that's what it was.
Yeah.
But it was so small that it was like
waist smaller than any of the
microscopic fossilized bacteria we've
ever seen before.
So people in general are like me.
Um,
but by fine.
But that's what started,
right.
That's when Clinton was like,
okay,
we're going to send a lot of shit to
Mars because after I went back in
[inaudible] 90 [inaudible],
early nineties,
people were kind of done with Mars.
And so that's what triggered the whole,
you know,
one space probe after another,
the rovers and like,
so,
you know,
the thing we found was a direct result
of that effort,
which was this organic chemistry which
says that back in the day Morris had had
a lot of this stuff lying around,
had a lot of these,
you know,
these,
these organic chemicals line around
which if your life,
that's what you're going to be using.
So that's like one more step.
Like we've been putting the Lego blocks
for the argument for life on Mars one
piece at a time since the.
Since the first rovers went there.
Yeah.
If we did discover just even plants on
some other planet,
even just a planet with some sort of
plant life,
that would be,
that'd be a game changer,
game changer.
Because right now we don't know if
there's,
we,
you know,
are we the only time in the entire
history of the universe that like this
crazy thing where you got,
we went from non life to life.
Like is that common or is that never
ever,
ever happened?
So that's the question we want to.
We want to answer.
And I,
you know,
I mean,
that argument was given before is I
think from the probable arguments.
I'm saying it's like,
you know,
it's,
it's almost overwhelming that you had
probably happened somewhere.
Again,
doesn't mean anything here,
but we need evidence,
right?
Science.
So we got to build that evidence.
Yeah.
And if we do find something,
the,
one of the weirder things would be if we
found something and there was a way to
get there.
Yeah.
You know,
we,
we find something and we're like,
yeah,
we find something,
but it's,
we're pretty sure there's some kind of
life and its 3 billion light years away.
Like,
wow,
that's cool.
Yeah,
what do we do?
it's nice to know that we're not the
only ones.
You know.
It's interesting.
Like how much would that change,
you know,
even if we found evidence for this,
this is a debate,
like if we found evidence of a
technological civilization we saw like
alien mega structures like that star,
they felt that.
What was that nonsense really nonsense.
It was something floating around.
Right?
So here's what they saw so that,
you know,
the way we discover planets is we look
for when the planet passes in front of
the star,
you get a little dip in the light,
right?
It blocks out a little bit of light to
the little eclipse.
Um,
and so,
you know,
we've now,
that's how we know that every star in
the sky has planets,
but there is like they found one that
just made no sense,
like the light would dip.
Then what stopped dip and then we'll
begin three times and it stopped
dripping.
Sometimes it was lower,
sometimes it was higher and you know,
for a year.
So people were like,
fuck it,
you know.
And so,
you know,
um,
uh,
Jason Wright and others,
Jason's a friend of mine,
you know,
they wrote a paper where they were like,
hey,
you know,
at least because this is what the
future's going gonna look like.
We can't say we can't.
We have to at least consider the
possibility that these are artificial
structures that are orbiting the star or
you know,
have to be ungodly,
huge,
ungodly,
huge alien mega structures.
Like that's the best word for like the
size of a country,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
These things would be huge,
right?
But that's what people think.
Like,
you know,
when people think about advanced alien
civilization,
the idea of building large scale
structures is you think that maybe the
next thing you do once you reach a
certain point,
like,
um,
you know,
the dyson sphere,
the idea that you could collect all of
the sun's energy and use it for yourself
by building a giant sphere around the
sun with solar panels on the inside.
People think like it goes back to Carter
chefs,
the idea of this Carter chef scale back
in the sixties where he's like,
look,
there's going to be a natural
progression of civilizations that goes
first.
You collect all the energy you can from
your planet and then you use that to do
amazing things and then you collect all
the energy from your star and then you
do that,
do amazing shit with that.
And then,
you know,
the whole galaxy.
So he,
you know,
Carter Chef thought there was a scale
that civilizations naturally progress
through.
So hopefully you don't blow yourself up
along the way.
Well,
I think that's the question.
I mean,
I've criticized the car chef scale in
one of the papers I recently did because
what it fails to take into account is
the fact that like,
you know,
on your way up to the type one type one
is when you harvest all the energy from
your planet,
which basically means somehow covering
your planet in our solar panels or
something that neglects what we've
learned since Carter Chef wrote his
paper in 64 is that,
you know,
planets don't like that shit.
Like planets.
The plan's gonna feed back.
You try and build,
you know,
massive shit on your planet.
The planet has its own biosphere is
pretty powerful and you've got to take
the biosphere in the counter,
you get climate change,
you get the planet being pushed off in
another direction.
So,
but whatever.
So for the,
um,
for the alien mega structures,
people thought like,
well,
maybe this is like a piece of it.
Have a dyson sphere,
right?
This is like,
you know,
now.
So,
you know,
when he proposed this,
people went bonkers over this,
right?
He was just saying,
he's like,
look,
here's the 15 different things.
Could be,
and I'm going to have to at least
consider the possibility that it's
artificial,
um,
but for me and some people got really
angry everything,
but I felt like this,
they get angry because there's been a
thing in the community over the years,
you know,
said he got a bad name,
right.
Setting for a bunch of people.
It was sort of thought as being like,
oh,
only whackadoodles do that and why?
Why is that?
Just because there was no results.
I just think,
you know,
I,
it is,
it's because of Shitty TV,
you know,
I mean,
I really in some ways,
right?
It's all,
you know,
it's prosthetic foreheads,
right?
It's the whole.
We've had so much kind of crappy,
you know,
speculation about aliens.
I trying to do anything scientific.
Always had this whiff of sort of being a
little,
you know.
And then there's the Ufo stuff which is
completely separate.
It's nothing to do with it.
He said he never really achieved any
results.
Right.
There was that one big blip that was
highly popular items.
Wow.
Signal.
But here's the thing about setting,
we never really did set that much,
you know what I mean?
Like people have this idea like,
wow,
we've got telescopes all over the world
and they're looking,
you know,
so the government never funded a study
study anything major,
right.
So people,
you know,
all that study has done is like
basically,
you know,
some dudes on a telescope get a little
extra time like,
hey man,
let's go look at a star.
Right.
So,
um,
Jill Tarter,
who's one of the founders,
one of the greats of Sadie,
she compares it.
It's like,
you know,
we've got an ocean that we need to look
at and which.
So far we've looked at a thimble,
right.
And she,
the Jodie foster care,
she's the jody foster character yet
we're in contact with today.
Yeah.
So she's laying on.
It's a good point.
Like we haven't really looked yet.
So the idea that,
you know,
the stars are silent or anything,
it's like man,
come on.
We haven't even begun to do a
comprehensive.
Said he makes me sad.
Why?
Because I feel like they're wasting
their time.
And uh,
there's a,
there was a documentary I saw wants
about some biologist who was convinced
that the giant sloths was still alive
and that there was examples of them in
South America and this poor bastard had
spent more than a decade looking for
this giant sloths in South America.
And there was,
there was this moment where he was
chasing down this suppose the dung pile
and they were looking for and someone
was there and he had this look in his
eyes were like,
he was like,
Holy Shit,
what if I wasted my fucking life in my
academic career,
chasing down something that's not even
real.
That's kind of how I've always felt
about setting.
Yeah.
But that's not the way the people.
I mean,
everybody was involved in it.
Um,
you know,
I don't do steady,
I mean,
you know,
I respect that people are doing it.
It's not.
Yeah.
But you know,
most of them are like,
look,
this is just a multigenerational thing,
you know?
And if,
even if I don't find it,
I'm laying the foundation.
It's like,
you know,
cathedrals,
right?
It took like how many generations does
it take to build a cathedral in Medieval
Europe?
Right?
So the first guy who laid the stone was
like,
I'm not going to see this,
you know,
maybe my great grandkids.
So most of them were like,
you know,
they're,
they know that this is gonna,
you know,
this is a,
this is a huge.
It's like the most important question in
humanity,
right?
Are we alone?
And they're willing to accept that.
Like,
you know,
you're going to do it scientifically,
you're going to have to do it brick by
brick,
you know,
and so you just have to accept that and,
go on.
So,
uh,
but like I said,
I think we've,
you know,
this is a new era now.
So the idea of like looking for signals,
which assumes that somebody is putting
out signals,
right?
That's,
that's a huge assumption right there.
But now that we know that there's all
these planets and we're staring at all
these planets,
it's kind of,
we need to be thinking differently
about,
you know,
we need to be prepared for what happens
when we see something we don't
understand.
Well,
it's also,
we don't even use radio anymore.
Right?
Right.
Gabriel radio is dying slowly but
surely.
Yeah.
Local radio is.
I mean it's,
it's kind of a thing of the past,
right?
The only thing that's really were
beaming out a large scale is a military
radar.
No,
that's the main thing.
So there'd be some kind of signal.
It wouldn't necessarily have to be radar
or,
or radio just have to be something that
we could detect some form of anomaly
that seemed to be artificial.
Right?
So here's like,
here's some of the suggestions that
people are talking about.
So Avi Loeb at Harvard talks about the
idea,
you know,
maybe what you need and you're gonna
need the sensitivity for this.
You're going to see like rocket engines
going back and forth between,
you know,
uh,
you have a plan that you have to a multi
planet civilization on,
in some and you're going to see little
flares is rockets,
decelerate,
accelerate back and forth.
People have talked about seeing city
lights,
you know,
the telescopes are getting,
we're,
we're building these giant telescopes
there,
like 30 meters and may be a potential
one day to see city lights.
You could see city lights when you're
going to see the planet come around.
Like this is all like,
you know,
we're,
we're not,
we're not there yet,
but people 20 years,
30 years,
40 years,
you know,
this is a long game and you got to be
playing the long game.
At some point we're gonna need to build
stuff in space that's even larger so we
can collect more light.
And multi issue will also be that if we
do see these city lights,
we're seeing city lights for millions of
years ago.
Well,
it depends,
like,
you know,
uh,
planets that,
that's a,
an,
a star 10 light years ago,
that's 10 years ago.
So it's not like,
you know,
these things could still be around.
Okay,
here's a really interesting idea,
like,
um,
because,
you know,
one of the things that I'm talking about
my book is like how long does any
civilization last?
Right?
That's the real question.
All of this stuff is rest super relevant
for us now because the question is what
is the average lifetime of a
civilization?
So you might be able to see artifacts
from civilizations that are gone,
like imagine of civilization covered one
of its moons in,
in um,
uh,
solar panels,
right?
The reflected light is going to show a
spectral signature of the,
uh,
the panels,
you know,
so it's like they don't even have to
necessarily be alive now that we still
might be able to see stuff from there,
you know,
are evidence of like artificial
structures or something that's not
natural around them.
So,
you know,
that's the thing,
man.
It's like we're really,
we're just,
we're about to take this step in step in
astrobiology we're,
we're,
you know,
we're already running models.
Have a Xcel biospheres,
right?
We're two.
We're asking like,
oh,
what kind of chemistry can you have if
you don't like if you have a
photosynthesis in s are on a planet
around a star that's smaller than ours,
that starts gonna be mostly red as
opposed to yellow light.
So the light that's coming off,
it's going to be different.
Kenya have photosynthesis in that case
and people are like,
yeah,
you probably could.
And what would it look like?
So we're already doing the work to be
ready for Expo biospheres.
So exos civilizations,
we kind of need to be prepared for that
too.
Looking for,
you know,
what,
what could be the traces,
what might we see from a distance from
an eco civilization.
They don't have to be signaling us,
you know,
they're just there and we're going to
catch some aspect of their being around.
Even if we did see rocket,
if we did see some sort of a signature
from rockets going back and forth,
or the w,
W,
we would have to assume that this is a
similarly aged civilization to hours.
Whereas if we saw something that was a
thousand,
100,000
years advanced,
we probably wouldn't see that anymore.
We'll probably see some sort of a
manipulation of time and space,
if that's possible,
if it's possible,
if it's possible.
Yeah.
So that's,
I mean,
of course that is one of the problems is
that,
um,
when you start,
you know,
when you start pushing,
it's just like saying like,
you know,
what is the,
what are,
what are we going to be like in a
million years?
You know,
I mean,
it's so long.
So I think you start with what you know.
And the,
the cool thing about the planet part
though is that,
you know,
unless they become like energy beings,
they're gonna have an effect on their
planet.
So looking at their planets to look for,
you know,
for spectral indications.
That's probably even after they die,
there might even be things,
so that's,
I think a,
you know,
a good way to go.
Yeah.
I'm,
you know,
I'm so curious as to what we're going to
be able to do in a thousand years,
10,000
years and 100,000
years.
Civilization does Dale around and we
figured out how to not melt the earth or
boil the oceans or whatever.
Whatever the ground we're doing.
Yeah.
Right.
But there's,
you know,
a bunch of science fiction films that do
speculated what,
what's going to be possible in the
future.
And one of them was a,
what was that recent one with?
What's his name?
All right.
The fuck's his name?
Mechanic.
I'm the one where they go through the
wormholes.
Right.
How much do those movies piss you off or
they don't?
I don't know.
I,
I do not mean but they get so of science
fiction so,
you know,
I mean I do not need my science fiction
to be correct to be correct.
I mean if they want to make,
you know.
So I love the expanse.
The is my favorite show ever.
I will talk about it.
What is the expanse,
the expanse I don't even know.
Thank you.
Help me.
Um,
so the expanse,
it's a series of books,
first of all that I think are the best
science fiction books in the last 15
years.
And then they made him into it and made
it into a show,
uh,
on Saifai and then had three years of
it.
And you know,
at first people were like,
oh,
this is kind of hard to follow because,
you know,
it's a lot of stories coming together.
And then,
um,
you know,
this year it got 100 percent,
uh,
ratings or what is it?
Rotten tomatoes,
rotten tomatoes.
A hundred percent or 95 percent if
people love Scifi,
cancelled it,
you know.
And so then Jeff Bezos just.
Yeah,
Jeff,
he just picked it up because people love
this show.
Fuck yeah,
I'll tell you why this show is amazing,
right?
So,
um,
it takes place about 200 years from now
and we are truly a multi planet species.
Like Mars now has,
you know,
billion people on it and it's become its
own political power,
right?
If it's separated from the earth.
And then the asteroid belt has also,
people are colonizing and you know,
living on the asteroid belt to mind
resources,
but the belters as they call them,
are like,
they're like second class citizens who
are basically like super poor and
they're,
you know,
they've got the boot on their next by
either earth or Mars.
And so there's this whole interplanetary
kind of political shit going on,
which is just great,
you know.
Um,
and then there's,
you enter into this,
they discover like the,
what they call the protein molecule,
like,
you know,
it was,
this is basically this alien molecule
that was really a device that some
aliens through our way,
billions of years ago that was,
you know,
how much am I supposed to give away,
I don't want it.
So.
No,
not too much.
No one's going to remember.
Right.
Good,
good.
Uh,
so that complicated so that,
you know,
that becomes kind of a weapon in this,
this political intrigue.
So it's just a great story to kind of,
people call it like the game of thrones
and space,
but I'll tell you what I love about it
is that this is what it's gonna look
like,
like they get the science on this show.
So write as much as you can,
right?
So,
you know,
in space if your rocket motors are on,
there's gravity because you know,
the rocket motors push up towards you.
And so yeah,
you got grabbed,
you can walk around when you turn the
rocket motors off,
you float around,
right on spinning things,
you know,
anything.
So,
you know,
in the,
in,
in this universe,
you know,
in this the fictional universe,
they've taken the big asteroids and they
followed them out and spun them up.
So people live on the inside,
you know.
And um,
so at one point like the,
that one of the characters that the
private eye,
they got this great sort of film noir
thing going on and he pours a drink,
some whiskey and the whiskey does this,
spirals into this.
So they got that,
the Coriolis I peed my pants.
I was like,
oh my God,
they got the coriolis effect.
Right.
So it's like,
this is really what it's gonna look
like,
you know what I mean?
This is if you want to imagine 200 years
from now,
which I think is completely feasible,
that we have millions of people living
in space making advances socially.
Uh,
no,
no.
People are assholes to each other.
And that's what makes it.
Yeah.
It's only 200 years.
That's a lot to ask for.
Well,
think about how different we are from
people that live 50 years ago.
I mean,
I don't want that different.
I think we're quite a bit different.
In what way?
What do you think?
Like,
well,
we have this ability to communicate now
that we never did before where everybody
has an ability to say their piece about
how they feel about how things are
going.
Yeah.
No,
that's interesting.
Right?
And that has changed a lot of things a
lot of ways,
but I mean it has,
it changed who we are.
I mean,
I think evolution,
I think it's chipping away.
Well that would be good if it,
you know,
because one of the things,
my thing,
so what's interesting about this
fictional world too is that like
climate,
you know,
the earth is dealing with client earth
has like 30 billion people on it and you
know,
New York is halfway under water and so
that's part of the story too,
is that,
you know,
so we're trying to navigate our way
through now becoming a multi planet
species.
Um,
so,
you know,
that is a version of at least 200 years
where you can really extrapolate the
technologies and ask yourself.
Because that's real.
I mean,
I think that's really gonna happen.
If we make it through climate change,
that's the,
that's the prize at the end of the,
you know,
uh,
of the,
of the story.
If we make it through climate change,
you know,
what the stuff that Elon Musk and Jeff
Bezos are doing,
man,
that's real like this.
This is what your number one concern is.
Climate Change.
Michael.
I'm a single voter.
Yeah.
Climate change because it's like it is
an existential dilemma,
you know,
and because of all the writing I did for
NPR and New York Times,
I have dealt with a lot of climate
change denialist men and it drives me
what is their big,
what's the big.
Because I,
I recently had a discussion with someone
on the podcast that didn't believe in
climate change and it was,
it was a weird thing is because I kept
pulling up all the different scientific
consensus studies,
all the different studies that show that
we were having an impact.
It's an undeniable impact,
undeniable.
Thirty years of science.
I know.
I saw that and she was like,
you know,
that's what you say.
I don't think that she's really thinking
about the and the hurricane it was.
I don't think she really thinks about
it.
I think she just has this stance that
she believes that that group that she's
a part of,
that's what a subscribes to.
So there's an ideological aspect of it
where you kind of.
You have a predetermined pattern that
you're supposed to follow when you're on
one side,
you have to be pro life.
You have to be pro second amendment
stuff stuff.
Yeah.
And that's,
I think it's a giant problem with our
culture.
There are two groups of people that you
can't like to truly be an independent
thinker.
You're like one of these Weirdos.
It's often the fringe to be independent
of either party.
Right?
Right.
And the thing about science is the whole
point of science is to be independent,
is to be,
and to have,
you know,
what science is,
science is a way of having public
knowledge.
You know what I mean?
Like everybody has their opinions,
whatever.
But science is about the stuff we can
all be like,
oh yeah,
for sure.
You know,
it's this whole process that we've
evolved over 400 years and with climate
denial man,
sometimes you know,
it's just.
Yeah,
you want to be like,
what?
What are you saying man?
Like what are,
you know,
read a book because they'll say stuff
like,
here's my favorite one.
Oh,
climate's always changing climate change
in man,
which is true.
So if somebody comes to me,
because you know what I want most for
people I don't like,
I consider myself an evangelist of
science.
I love science.
And so if people come to me they say,
hey man,
the climate always changing.
I'm like,
oh,
great question.
You know,
we actually know the answer to that yet.
It's changing but it's changing.
What's the timescale,
you know.
So it changes often on million year time
scales,
but like from the last 10,000
years since the last ice age,
which was 10,000
years ago,
which is amazing.
Like there used to be a mile of ice
above our heads,
you know,
text 10,000
years ago,
climate has been remarkably stable.
Yeah.
Has been little blips in it,
but no major changes.
Right?
So,
like,
and I can show them the graph of this
and everything.
So if you're,
if you know,
if they're interested,
you know,
I mean if they're.
So if they're asking the question
because they want to know I'm,
I'm all,
I'm down to talk until the cows come
home.
But that's not what a typical deniers
are.
Deniers climate change.
Well done.
But they're not interested in the
answer,
but it isn't it.
It's not only the not interested in the
answer,
they're just
trying to win.
It's not a real conversation because
it's a really complex thing.
If you dig an ice core and you tap down
to 50,000,
$80,000
100,000
years,
you see all these bizarre shifts of the
climate that could be indicative of
super volcanoes and asteroidal impacts
and solar flares.
A Lotta Shit happens over the course of
a million years.
Right?
But to
hang all your
ideas on the party's ideology and to
deny all this really interesting stuff
and,
and all these
variables.
That's what,
that's what pisses me off.
It's like,
you know what I try and tell people,
it's like,
look,
climate science is like awesome.
Like it's science.
It's got these amazing stories to tell
about,
you know?
Yeah.
The earth earth over the past four point
5 billion years,
the earth has gone through the most
profound changes and we've learned about
aren't you interested in that?
But no.
They basically have this thing where
like,
you know,
I'm,
I'm part of this group.
And therefore have to have this opinion
and I'm like,
dude,
it's science.
Science doesn't care who you voted for.
You know what I mean?
Like the,
the,
a rated of properties of a co two
molecule doesn't care whether you're
wearing a blue tie or a red tie and the
fact that people can't make that
distinction.
And here's the real problem.
Once you go down this slippery road of
denying,
saying like,
okay,
that kind of science I hate man,
they're all a hoax.
Well,
you know,
America's prosperity and our safety has
been built on science over the last 200
years.
You know,
you start to erode the whole thing.
You can't just like call one group of
Geoscientists Hucksters,
you know?
And so they're only doing for learning
and not have it slowly.
In fact,
everything else to the point where like,
you know,
China will be happy to eat our lunch
when it comes scientifically.
Chinese pumping,
huge amounts of money into science.
You're not doing this.
So like,
you know,
we're,
we're limiting.
And here's the other thing that really
bums me out.
Science is not a,
it's not a lunch buffet.
You know what I mean?
You can't be like,
Oh man,
can I have some of those antibiotics?
I Love Antibiotics and Oh yeah,
the cell phone's great.
I'll use that.
I really want to fly in a plane,
but climate change is bullshit.
You know?
I mean like,
you know,
either you accept that you live in a
scientific society.
It doesn't mean like your slave actually
adhere to anything.
You know,
it comes out in the journal it
yesterday,
but you know,
either you adhere to the idea that this
method has produced miracles for us or
you don't give me the cell phone back.
Well,
the terrific
method is what has established the
actual real facts of how things interact
with each other.
That it's allowed us to create
technology and I think they,
they,
they split that distinction.
They focus on the technology and
commerce,
which is more important than their eyes.
Then the,
the,
the consequences of the environment or
what's going to happen to the
environment.
Yeah.
There's the big hope is that we're going
to figure it out and I'm hopeful of that
too,
is that we're going to figure out some
way to extract carbon from the
atmosphere with devices or some
enormous,
like there was,
I don't know if it was a working
prototype or is just a concept,
but there was an enormous building that
was really an air filter.
The other starting to look
at carbon capture again with places like
Hong Kong and places where they have
terrible Beijing and they have terrible,
terrible pollution and more importantly
particulates in the atmosphere.
So it's not just a a like a carbon
thing.
It's like they have shit in there air
that they're breathing in your lungs.
Awful.
It's,
you know,
I went to Mexico City a couple years
back.
I've been there twice,
but I went there for a UFC and when we
were flying in,
I took photos and I put them on my
instagram.
So you find those.
They're fucking shocking.
Unbelievable.
Right?
What kind of a creepy animal is the
human?
The human is capable of burning smoke
into the very air that we need to take
into the lungs to keep our body a lot.
Oh,
you see it so bad.
People have never been to Mexico City.
Like it's a stunner,
dude.
My fucking head was killing me after two
days there.
Yeah,
well that's what like with the Beijing,
when they had the Olympics,
right,
they had to like,
you know,
they had to stop all industrial
activity,
but like the month,
right?
La used to look like this right before
the clean air act,
la would have,
that's what I wrote.
I wrote Mexico's La on steroids.
Mexico City's early on steroids.
It's just so dark,
you know,
the,
uh,
this whole question of what we'll do,
like this brings us back to the aliens,
right?
What's my,
my point is,
is that,
you know,
we're not the first time this has
happened.
It pretty much if you build the
civilization,
anybody who builds the civilization like
we've done is going to trigger climate
change.
Right?
It's like it's kind of unavoidable.
So that's,
it goes back to the denier thing.
And one of the things I'm trying to do
is flip the script,
right,
because you talked to climate denialists
and it's the same fricking set of things
that like,
you know,
man Dude,
we've been here before.
We,
the questions will be answered,
but I'm trying to like flip it to show
that like the whole question of did we
change the climate?
That's why everybody focused on did we,
did we not,
you know,
and you know from when you take the
10,000
light your view,
then what you realize is like,
what did you expect?
Like we built a world girdling
civilization that uses a quarter almost
of all the energy the biosphere uses,
right?
So you know,
every,
you know,
every day the biosphere has like,
200 terawatts of energy that it's
producing and sugars we use about a
quarter of that.
Like how did you expect there wasn't
going to be an impact,
right?
So this changes the whole way we look
at.
We don't need to argue about like,
did we or didn't we?
Of course we did.
This is what happens when you reach this
level.
And the other thing that,
you know,
in the book that I'm trying to argue to
also,
and it pushes back against the deniers,
is like what climate deniers are human
haters,
you know,
they're all like,
we did this amazing thing.
We changed the atmosphere of an entire
planet,
right?
Climate change shows on one level how
fricking awesome we are.
You know,
how far we've gotten and this,
if you look at the,
you know,
from the perspective of,
species doing this again and again
across the universe,
this shows that we've reached a level,
right?
We have,
we've leveled up,
right?
You don't play a lot of video games,
And so that whole thing when you level
up and you know,
you get the,
the sniper rifle,
we've leveled up.
And so now the question is,
are we smart enough,
you know,
to see what we've done and make the
right choices because that's what the
universe is going to be.
There's going to be species that trigger
climate change is gonna happen all the
time.
And some are going to be like,
Oh man,
we need to do something right.
And they'll make the actions,
they'll be able to work it out,
get it together,
and other ones,
you know,
which is going to end up in the cosmic
waste pile.
So we're like cosmic teenagers and just
like when you're a teenager and you're,
you know,
uh,
you get,
you start to drive,
right?
Either you figure it out,
you know,
either you're drinking and you're
partying and drive the car off a cliff
or you figure out how to handle your
responsibility.
And that's us now,
you know.
Yeah,
no,
I agree with you.
And,
uh,
I,
I feel like there's a fundamental,
fundamental problem with the way people
approach ideas and uh,
I think it goes back to what we're
talking about earlier about right versus
left or you know,
Republican versus Democrat,
they're not thinking of the consequences
of arguing for,
against the possibility that climate
change is a human caused thing.
They're not thinking of the
consequences.
They just want to win.
Right,
right.
And what their side to be,
right want their site to be.
Right.
And that,
you know,
what,
what bums me out is they don't
understand the consequences of that for
the both the American enterprise and the
human enterprise,
right?
I mean,
because,
you know,
uh,
if you,
if you keep calling one branch of
science a hoax,
then what's to say the other branches,
like what,
you know,
then you just,
you're down,
you're rolling down this slippery slope
where like the other countries you don't
like.
So most of the,
of the,
um,
Nobel prizes Americans have one where
people from other countries,
they came here to do their science
because we had the best scientific
enterprise.
The next generation will just go
somewhere else.
They'll go to China,
you know.
So,
um,
there's that part of it.
And the other part it's like,
dude,
it's just science.
It doesn't care about your political
views and you know,
it's not fair to use the cell phone and
take the antibiotics and then turn
around and like,
and then suddenly treat this thing as if
it was another thing in your bucket of
ideologies.
I think also people think if you somehow
or another compromise industry's ability
to work,
that you're going to kill jobs and
you're gonna damage the economy and
that's more important.
Yeah.
But I think it's the exact opposite.
Right?
And if people really saw,
right,
I mean,
um,
you know,
again,
just like I'm saying,
climate change shows how powerful people
become.
It also shows how powerful are our
enterprise.
Right?
We did this by,
you know,
building businesses by building
enterprise bi and we built this world
girdling machine of civilization and it,
you know,
the planet actually noticed.
Why do you like that term world girdling
because that's,
it gives me the hurdle of wrapping
around think it's because it's from like
a Shakespeare,
like from a Caesar or something.
I always thought it wasn't good,
but it's the idea that like,
you know,
the foundation trilogy,
the Isaac Yasmin Off,
you know,
classic science fiction thing,
that there's the city of the planet of
trend toward which is the center of the,
uh,
the empire,
the Galactic Empire.
And it's,
you know,
it's basically the whole planet has been
covered in city.
You know,
like the other planet,
you got to go down to like 500 levels
before you get to the surface.
So that idea,
you know,
what I like about it is the idea that
like,
you know,
we've done something,
we're kind of covered the planet in our,
our effect,
you know,
covered the planet in our enterprise.
So this issue of business is that like,
um,
there's a place I can stand in
Rochester,
I did this for MPR and there's the Erie
Canal.
I can stand right on the edge of the
Erie Canal.
Then there's a train tracks,
you know,
the tracks was laid,
the tracks laid back and you know,
the original line back in the 18,
whatever seventies.
Then there's a highway and then there's
the airport right over there for
different infrastructures,
you know,
which he took huge amounts of money to
build what of which we don't even use
anymore.
Right?
So the idea of building on an
infrastructure that will,
that will not be carbon polluting,
will not trigger climate change.
Like did,
this is what we do.
So the idea that there's going to be
more jobs that come out of this than it
could ever come out of fossil fuels,
you know,
it's not a big deal for human beings
because that's what we do to switch
infrastructures and there will be a lot
of wealth generated by,
you know,
just like there was,
when we switched to the trains,
you know,
where's the argument coming that we.
Because there are people that just adopt
the party line,
the party line that human climate's
always changed and human beings barely
affected.
And it's not something to concentrate
on.
Where's that coming from?
Again,
I think it's the,
you know,
the gradual political polo polarization
of everything,
you know,
because you look at,
in the,
um,
we're now at the,
what is it 30 year anniversary of Jim
Hansen,
who was the famous climate scientist
giving his testimony in front of
Congress in 1988 a hot,
sweltering summer day.
We said climate change is already
happening,
you know,
and that made news everywhere.
And that was the first public awakening
that this was happening.
And if you look at the first Bush
administration,
they were like,
oh yeah,
we're ready to do something about this
year.
We can do it,
you know?
Um,
and then it just gradually over time,
as the whole political polarization
thing happened,
you can actually see the,
uh,
the very purposeful denial,
right?
They took a page out of the cigarette
companies for years,
right?
Cigarettes were like,
cigarette companies are like,
no,
it's not a problem.
So they were purposefully,
the other people had money invested.
Right.
You know,
this is a documentary that,
that goes into that.
What is the name of that merchants of
doubt,
merchants of doubt.
It's a great book,
man.
That's a really good book.
And the documentary is really good.
It was purposeful.
You know,
it's,
that's also confusing.
It's like,
why are they doing that?
Like who's paying them to do that?
Obviously the cigarette companies
wouldn't be paying the same people to
put doubt into the idea that cigarettes
are addictive or cigarettes caused
cancer.
And this is what had been done in the
past.
You know,
the same people are involved in doing it
with climate change.
But why?
Uh,
well,
you know,
one time I wrote a piece for the NPR
that was kind of positive about like,
yeah,
we can switch infrastructure like I'm
saying.
And some guy wrote me back very angry
and he said,
you know,
the proven reserves,
the stuff,
the oil that's in the ground has a
wealth,
has a monetary value,
like,
you know,
that's in there in the oil companies,
banks,
you know,
the,
in their bank accounts of one point
$5,000,000,000,000.
And like I said,
dude,
you know,
people have gone to war for a lot less
than one point $5,000,000,000,000,
right?
So,
you know,
if,
if we were to really be like,
hey man,
we can't burn that,
you know,
you're gonna have to leave that in the
ground.
That's likely their bank accounts.
But I'm like zero pretty fast.
So what I don't.
So it's those industries.
I think that's part of it.
And then it gets,
you get linked to other things and then
it becomes this sort of like mass,
uh,
you know,
becomes the political poll.
They use political polarization to sort
of,
you know,
sort of make this happen.
It doesn't feel like other countries
aren't doing this.
Right.
That's the important thing.
You know,
other countries.
There's always a little bit of climate
denial going on,
but we're the only country that's got,
as you can see,
because we're the only ones who are not
part of the Paris accord.
Well,
it's one of the
weirdest things about this right left
things.
The left is always supporting the
environment.
The left is all about the environment.
The left is about clean air and
yeah.
Water.
How did that happen?
I don't understand.
I don't understand that either.
The whole thing is very strange.
Well,
I got,
you know,
I mean,
I have issues with environmental lists
too because,
um,
I think one of your shows I was
watching,
you know,
the whole idea of Eco Bros,
right?
And you get ECO Brode,
but people,
and I noticed I have a piece in the New
York Times today,
an op ed where I'm basically saying
like,
look man,
the planet's going to be fine.
Like,
you know,
long term.
There's nothing we can throw at the
biosphere that is going to kill it.
We're in.
It's not about saving the planet,
the Earth.
He's not a fuzzy little bunny,
you know,
the planet is powerful and it's really
about saving us.
Let's be honest about what's going on
and is going to be all kinds of ethical
choices that go on that,
you know,
the polar bears may not be able to come
along with us on the ride here.
You know,
we need a healthy biosphere with,
you know,
a lot of biodiversity,
but you know,
we're part of it and we're going to have
an impact.
There's no such thing as no impact and
you know,
already I'm getting ECO brode people,
you don't care about life.
I just like,
oh,
come on man.
I just put it in the thing.
I said we need to be wise and
compassionate,
you know,
but they're like,
no,
people have
convening opinions.
I mean this is,
this is one of the things you get
involved with when you start talking
with people about really important
issues.
I mean,
it's like we were talking about earlier,
they want to be right and they want to
be on the sides.
It's righteous and with virtue in
ethics,
right,
they find anything that you disagree,
that they disagree with it.
You're saying they don't ask you
questions,
they don't go.
What do you think the implications are?
Like how do you,
how do we minimize the effects and the
negative consequences of are they just
immediately want to say you are
insensitive.
You are an asshole.
You are the problem.
Yeah.
You didn't know my way around that and
that's what the whole book is about is
to like when you've got a polarization,
right?
You know,
where you're either this or you're that.
The thing that this is like a
mathematical idea is to go orthogonal.
You know when you,
when you go,
because you know it's a line basically,
right?
You're either on this side or that side
go 90 degrees to it.
Now you're in a whole new space.
Now you're up and down to the left and.
Right.
Exactly.
And now like the questions that.
So you see this in like revolutions in
science,
right?
So you look at Einstein and what
happened when Einstein came up with a
relativity,
everybody at the time was like,
you know,
um,
they were all concerned what they call
the luminaire forest,
ether,
you know,
light needed,
like to wave and everybody thought it
needed something to propagate through,
right radio way or,
um,
waterways go through water,
sound,
wave go through air.
So the whole thing was about this ether.
The Luminous Air Easter is,
this exist,
does not exist,
but I'm not.
One time I was like,
you know,
I'm not really interested in that
problem.
Am I going to do it?
He just changed the whole thing and you
just said,
look,
here's two new ideas.
They have nothing to do with the
luminous every either.
And like all the old questions,
all the old battles kind of just fell
away and they didn't even make sense
anymore.
So that's what I'm trying to do in the
book and say,
look,
when you look at climate change as a
planetary transition,
a predictable planetary transition,
the whole idea of environmentalism
versus business interests.
And,
uh,
you know,
right,
Republicans versus Democrats,
it just doesn't,
you know,
it's not even relevant anymore.
What matters is that this is going to
happen.
We should have expected it to happen.
And now the question is,
do we become a cosmic winter or cosmic
loser?
And we have to think about the biosphere
differently.
We have to think about our place in the
biosphere differently and the old
arguments.
So that's what,
you know sometimes with climate change
deniers,
I'll throw this stuff at them and it's
really kind of fun to watch and be like,
because you're expecting me to say like
a,
B and c and they've got d,
e and F and response and I throw this
stuff out them and they're just like,
no,
I'm not doing it.
Just a fight with climate change.
But I think it's true.
But.
Well,
who was it that was on the podcast?
It was talking about climate
stabilization techniques and that this
is probably the future.
Was it boy?
Um,
anyway,
what people are really worried about
when,
when you talk to people that understand
the history of the human race and the
history of the earth is climate cooling.
I think the climate cooling is far more
terrifying than climate warming because
if we go into a giant ice age,
again,
I mean way more people are gonna die a
terrible loss of resources and it can be
devastating to the human race that is.
Is that,
is that something that you agree with?
Yeah,
no,
I don't think so.
I mean it's true.
And here's something interesting.
We're kind of overdue for an ice age.
Yeah,
well that was the thing in the seventies
there were saying that we're in the
verge of.
Yeah,
I mean that there was just a couple of
guys,
I mean that whole thing because that's
often something that climate deniers
will throw at you in the seventies,
you know,
it was like,
there was like one or two guys who said
that and then it got picked up on the
news,
but the climate community at that time
was not like,
oh my God,
it's cooling.
Right?
But here's the interesting thing for me
and at the fits into this whole idea is
that like we're holding off an ice age,
like there may never be.
If human humanity is successful and we
navigate the Anthropocene,
you know,
that term the anthropocene that we've
now entered,
we've now entered the human dominated
era.
We've been for the last 10,000
years.
The geological epoch has been what they
called the Holocene.
That's all of human civilization
happened in the whole scene.
You know,
it's pretty warm.
It's pretty wet,
moist,
you know,
everything's not locked up in ice and
it's an inter glacial period.
And if we weren't around,
yeah,
and another thousand,
3000,
500 years would be another ice age.
But the anthropocene that were
triggering could hold off ice ages
forever,
right?
As long as we're around,
there won't be another ice age because
we've already added enough warmth to the
planet that it overcomes the effects
that trigger an ice age.
So like what are the ethical
responsibilities of that?
That's what I try and tell the,
you know,
the environmentalists like,
you've got this image like oh we got to
save the earth,
but they're thinking of like the whole
scene and it's like,
well,
you know,
the planet even with us,
even if we successfully keep
biodiversity rich and it's not going to
be the earth we started with,
you know,
because we're here.
So yeah.
What about the species that never form
because we held off the ice age.
No,
I mean forever.
Like what about the ethical
responsibility though?
So like it opens for.
That is a long equation though,
isn't it?
Uh,
in what way?
Try to contemplate what would have
existed
if we allow the earth to cool and our
responsibility for allowing the earth to
cool so that the potential for new
species to advance.
It's like fuck those pieces.
Let's keep,
let's keep this place warm so we can
stay alive.
Well,
all I'm saying,
the only reason I'm raising that I'm
not,
you know,
I'm raising that because we don't.
When we talk about climate change,
what you get sometimes when the
environmental movement is this sort of
like the polar bear,
the polar bear.
It's like what I'm trying to say,
look,
I love polar bears.
Kind of funny that polar bears always
think because polar bears will rip your
head off and drink your.
And not only that,
then one of the rare bears,
it doesn't need anything but me.
Yeah,
right.
Right.
And so it's so funny that we're like,
oh,
Kevin is a biologist,
and he said like,
when you get polar bear babies,
like right out of the womb,
you said they're like the,
like the alien from the chest,
chest burster steam.
He said that literally like right out of
the womb,
they're looking to kill and eat.
You're like,
oh,
you're so good.
That is a fucking.
Obviously people have tamed them and Fed
them to the point where they don't in
your head off.
Yeah.
But that's a fucking predatory enormous
animal.
Yeah.
So I'm,
I'm raising that point to say like,
look,
the thing we're going through now is a,
it's an epic making planetary
transition.
We were part of it,
right?
And whether or not we're still part,
that's the question whether or not we're
still part of it a thousand years from
now,
you know,
is the big issue.
So,
you know,
there are ethical issues about the polar
bear,
right?
But there are also ethical issue.
We can't just return the earth to some
pristine state.
We're here,
there's 7 billion of us,
you know,
so you have to,
we're going to have to understand like
there's this deeper ethical question
about what is an earth look like that's
been changed by us that's healthy but
still has us on it.
It may not have polar bears,
you know,
it may have rich phyto plankton,
uh,
and it may be a very species diverse,
but some of the species may not come
with us.
So like we can't this sort of like
things like,
oh,
the pristine or if there is no more
pristine earth,
we,
you know,
we've been changing the earth since we
were here.
So it's like how do we have a healthy,
a rich,
healthy biosphere with us and our
civilization still in it.
And the thing about things that have
gone extinct in the past and more than
90 percent of everything that's ever
existed is extinct.
Problem is we didn't know then.
Right?
We didn't have a,
you know,
a checklist like,
oh,
spotted owl,
check.
Got It.
No tree frog.
Check.
Got It.
Now we do.
And when one goes away we kind of freak
out.
Yeah.
And that's,
you know,
I mean,
we have to have compassion for life
because we're part of it without the
compassion,
you know,
we end up with a,
as a Gavin Schmidt,
a friend of mine calls economic.
We have ecological hooliganism,
right?
We just do crazy.
We're just dumping Shit into rivers.
Like,
yeah,
you don't have to do that man.
Um,
but,
you know,
when in my talks on this,
I'll show like the polar bear,
the lonely polar bear on the island and
you know,
like all you have once really bummed out
about this.
And then I'll show like a velociraptor,
right?
You know who's crying for the
velociraptor species come and go.
So we have to,
you know,
and the earth goes to these huge
transitions.
I'm not saying be like don't care about
those species,
but you got to have bigger picture with
us in it.
Here's the problem with the,
with the,
uh,
the environmental movements.
You know what though?
Sometimes the,
it gets framed.
It's not just the environment in which
the way we talk about climate change,
we think of ourselves as being a plague,
right?
A human beings,
we suck,
right?
That's the basic.
That's the only story.
You,
we have two stories.
It's not happening or we suck.
And my whole thing is like,
that is the raw.
Not only is that story wrong,
it's unhelpful.
You know,
we are what the biosphere is doing now.
millions of years ago it was grasslands.
Grasslands were a new innovation and
they changed the planet.
You have a lot of grass,
you know,
the biosphere evolved,
grasslands,
they swept across the planet.
They changed how the planet works.
And then the earth moved on with it.
Went onto the new experiment.
We are what the were exactly that we are
like the dinosaurs or the grasslands or
the blue green algae that created the
oxygen atmosphere and like,
you know,
we're not,
we're,
you know,
there's no difference between a city in
a forest on some biospheric level.
We don't suck.
The question is whether we're smart
enough to still be part of what the,
what the biosphere is using us to
trigger,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
What are your thoughts on the
reintroduction of extinct animals
through genetic cloning?
Uh,
you know,
I watched her risk park whether they're
talking about doing like with William
mammoths.
Yeah.
This is a real possibility.
Something I know the close ancestor of
the woolly mammoth is still alive.
I know I'd be down for seeing in my,
in my,
the moon,
the science museum in Rochester.
There's a woolly mammoth that they
found,
you know,
and sometimes looking at anything like
that giant hairy ass elephant man.
And it was walking around right in my,
you know,
I think like,
depending on what you do with it,
you know,
trying to reintroduce it into the
biosphere could be a little dangerous.
I mean,
the thing,
look,
climate change is a,
this is something I like say climate
change is not our fault.
And what I mean by that is we,
uh,
we found fossil fuels and they were
awesome,
you know,
and they were just a continuation of
what we'd always done,
you know.
And so we inadvertently,
climate change was a mistake,
you know,
now,
if we don't do something about it,
it's our fault,
right?
But,
you know,
and so you want to be really careful
about unintended consequences,
you know.
So this is my same thing with,
uh,
with geoengineering.
People talk like,
Oh,
we should,
you know,
put a part of particulates in the
atmosphere to make it more reflective.
I'm like,
man,
dude,
we triggered the whole,
we triggered a climate change because,
you know,
we didn't know what we were doing.
We didn't know what the consequences
were.
We put those articles up there,
how do we get them out,
get them out with a net?
Well,
no,
no.
They'll reign down.
You've got to keep putting them in.
That's the problem.
You got to keep putting them in.
So what happens if like one nation
decides they don't want to do it
anymore,
you know,
and there the whole thing falls apart.
Now suddenly are,
you're gonna get massive changes and so
like anything like that,
like why don't we just work on Matt
using fossil fuels?
You know what I mean?
I take the hardest solution that's got
the most uncertainty as opposed to the
simpler solution,
which just means building a different
infrastructure.
Yeah.
Well especially in California.
I mean this is one of the weirdest
places ever to not see solar power when
it never.
It never rained.
Should be everywhere,
everywhere.
Most things should be run on solar
power.
Why not man?
You got solar and so efficient now.
Like it's also very difficult to get up
and running.
Like I had a friend of mine who had his
done for four or five months before he
got approved because he said they,
they make it difficult for you.
Yeah.
Which is crazy to be on solar power and
not be on the grid.
So,
you know,
I mean these are all the kinds of things
that we're going to have to work out.
I'm hopeful people are like,
are you hopeful or not hopeful?
Because you know,
I mean I ran these,
I did these models.
One of the pieces of research we did was
we modeled planets and civilizations
like alien civilizations.
We,
you know,
developed a simple mathematical model
about how a civilization will use that
planet's resources to make more babies
alien babies.
And then how the,
you know,
by using those resources you feedback on
the planet.
Right.
And so what we wanted to do was we
wanted to model the possible outcomes.
Like what is the generic outcome,
you know,
if I've got 100,000
civilizations all being born in
different places,
what's the,
you know,
in general what happens?
And what we found is like basically four
different possibilities.
One was good news,
like in these models there was like,
you know,
the population shoots up,
the planet's temperature shoots up,
but they come to a nice steady state,
like,
you know,
the population stable,
everything's good.
So they're in those models was hope.
We also saw die off.
We're like the population skyrockets the
planet,
they overshoot the carrying capacity of
their planet and then you get something
like 70 percent of the population died
off.
So like,
you know,
seven out of every 10 people you know is
gone,
so you know,
but then you come to a steady state so
low maybe if you can survive the
disaster you can,
you're still there.
But we also problem with survivor,
the disasters,
how much of the information gets her
story,
right?
Because you think about if you killing
seven out of 10 people,
how many of those seven people,
the ones who know how to make cell
phones.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's a dark age,
right?
That's what happens to the dark age.
I remember the first time I went to
Europe and I smelled it was Roman,
you know,
the aqueducts man,
like five stories tall carrying water,
you know,
and by the 918 nobody knew how they got
built a few of those dips in human
civilization.
Right?
And so it's not clear,
especially with the society as complex
as ours,
right?
If the food doesn't arrive in my grocery
store,
what do I do?
Right?
You know,
I garden,
but I'm not,
not enough.
Not enough to keep you alive for a
complex civilization like ours.
Even if you don't go extinct,
you may not be able to have this kind of
civilization.
But we did find collapse.
We did find complete extinction curves
as well where,
you know,
the population went way up and then
boom,
dropped like a stone and wood even we've
and found those.
We built into the model as a possibility
for the civilization to switch from a
high impact resource to a low impact
resource like fossil to solar.
And sometimes because you know,
planets have minds of their own,
you know,
and there's an internal dynamics,
the planets and you push them far enough
and there's going to roll off.
So we'd have ones where the population
went way up.
They made the switch and then the
population started to come down on the
planet.
Started to cool down.
Did you factor in random geological
events?
Random solar events,
random.
This was really all about just planet a
civilization and it's feedback on the
plan.
And you could,
we could build models like that.
That would be one of the major issues
with any advanced civilizations.
It's a matter of time before something
happens,
right?
As we said,
you know,
we know that Mars has been hit before we
go or spin hit the moon's been head
everything.
I mean the moon is one of our best
examples would just look at it.
You see craters everywhere because it
doesn't have an environment or an
atmosphere on the moon was built by a
huge impact between earth and Mars on
Mars,
like bottom,
you know,
at the beginning of the planet's
history.
So yeah,
those happen all the time.
I think if you get advanced,
you know,
so like we're on the lip of being a
multi planet species.
Right.
And once you do that,
which means you become a space faring
race,
then I think like certainly the asteroid
stuff you can take care of.
Right?
We've already done,
we have identified like a huge fraction
of all the earth crossing asteroids,
like we're not really sure what to do
about them if we find one coming at us.
But we see some coming out us all the
time where they just recognize them a
few hours before near.
Right,
right.
But it doesn't happen a couple of weeks
ago and you know,
luckily it always passes.
You can always.
Yeah.
So we couldn't really,
you know,
we're young enough now that if we
discovered one heading right towards us,
we could just put down your legs between
your head,
between your legs and kiss your butt
goodbye.
Um,
but uh,
but in time,
right,
200 years from now,
we will have done a much better job of
mapping out all the major rocks.
Yeah.
Well,
I think so,
I mean I'm really says,
you know,
I mean if we have that kind of planetary
interplanetary,
we're going to be mapping them out just
because you don't want to run into them
or are you going to be mining them?
What do you think is a promising in
terms of the ability to prevent impacts?
Uh,
there's a couple of things.
I think the best one,
if you catch it early enough,
there's the gravity tug.
Will you just literally park a spaceship
next to it and slowly have the
spaceship,
you know,
move yo because you only have to do is
altered the trajectory a little bit.
You know,
you just don't have the long bonnet.
Yeah.
And it'll,
you know,
I'm [inaudible] shit and spaces just so
vast that a little tap,
we'll make it miss.
So the gravity Tokyo,
you don't have to try and do the pot.
What was it?
What was the movie apocalypse?
The one with the from the nineties with
the,
uh,
the space miners.
Oh,
Armageddon.
Yeah.
Thank you.
And then there was a deep impact to deep
impact was the smart one.
Yeah.
Armageddon was the rip each other's off,
right,
because they're both came out at the
same time and I think deep impact came
out first,
but it was developed second.
Ah,
yeah,
that'd be a bummer to be the one that
like,
you know,
they both come out at the same time and
your movie doesn't get any attention and
the other one becomes like a massive
hit.
Wow.
So,
uh,
so like,
you know,
there they drilled holes and stuff and
try and blow them up,
but then the problem there is you now
have a bunch of rocks and if some of
those rocks are big enough.
So I think the gravity tug is kind of
probably the best idea.
But you know,
because of um,
a mining asteroids will probably,
you know,
those little ones maybe the easiest to
to mind.
So what are you worried about more than
anything in terms of climate change?
Like you worried about the rising of the
ocean levels.
Are you worried about the heating of the
actual planet,
the temperature being unsustainable for
human life?
Like what are you worried about the
most?
Uh,
the one thing I'm worried about the most
liquid we're talking before,
you know,
technological societies are these like
overlaid networks,
you know,
you got the transportation network,
you've got the energy network,
you've got social networks,
you know,
and those are really complex.
And so I do a little what's called
network theory and what you find with
network theory is that,
you know,
you may have an individual network
that's pretty robust,
meaning like I can cut some of the
connections,
like you got your social network,
I could take,
you know,
20 percent of the people out of your
social network and the social like will
still function,
you know,
like most people will still talk to each
other or anything,
but once you start layering them,
so at the social network is now
connected to the telecommunications
network which is connected to the energy
network,
Blah Blah.
Then you can repeat a small change
ripples through the whole thing blows it
apart.
It just doesn't function anymore.
So you know,
I don't need like apocalypses to have
the fabric of technological civilization
fall apart.
Like,
so if the,
if just the weather patterns change
enough that agriculture becomes really
hard,
you know,
we're used to the rain's falling pretty
much the same way they do yearly and
everything that,
you know,
like we talk about,
you look at what the refugees,
how much trouble you know,
having a huge influx of refugees can
cause climate change is going to have
people moving all over the planet
because now they can't grow food
anywhere.
So it's like I don't,
you know,
like I said,
you don't need.
I do worry like ocean rise is going to
be huge.
Most people live in coastal cities.
Most of the wealth in the world is in
coastal cities,
but you don't really need too much to
like really shift the weather patterns.
And then the thing you're used to falls
apart
now when you factor in human beings and
our evolution from primitive hominids to
what we are today.
And you sort of extrapolate and keep
going and think about what we're going
to be in the future.
And then think about what these
creatures might be that live 100 million
light years away or whatever.
The fuck it is what I mean we've got,
I've got to think that whatever is
holding us back,
our primitive instincts,
these human reward systems that were
engaged when we were running away from
wild animals and fighting off tribes
have invaders that slowly but surely
those are going to either evaporate or
evolve and we're going to get to a point
where we can be more rational about
complex issues if we do do that.
Like what is the motivation for
expanding the human race?
Isn't sustaining the human race in a
healthy way on this planet a better
option than traveling to Mars or
traveling to other solar systems?
Like wouldn't we be better served trying
to achieve some sort of a balance here
on this planet?
I think the,
um,
I think one serves the other.
Like we,
you know,
you look at the human migration patterns
from when we started,
right?
And you know,
we started off as a,
you know,
a bunch of people in Africa,
Africa,
maybe a few thousand,
right?
And then you see this migration like,
or you know,
a bunch of us,
like a few hundred crossed the Red Sea,
which was pretty low at the time.
And then it's like they just worked
their way around the coasts,
you know,
boats over to Australia went all the way
back around through like we're
explorers,
man.
Like these,
you know,
it's really,
I think something fundamental for us
psychologically to have these frontiers.
Exactly.
That's my question is will we evolve
past that?
Well,
I don't think that's a bad thing.
I don't think so.
Yeah.
I don't think this bad thing because
again,
it goes back to the biosphere.
This is kind of like,
I think there's something deep in life
that wants more life.
Right?
So if we call,
you know,
Settle Mars,
right,
then it's not going to be really us
settling Mars.
It's going to be the earth's biosphere,
right.
I mean really are we are,
we're the agent of the biosphere.
Right.
And you know,
the biosphere started off as like,
you know,
single celled creatures in like little
tiny parts of the planet.
And then you have conquered the oceans.
And then eventually when they were,
because in the beginning there weren't
continents,
there was a water world when we started
off.
And so when,
you know,
there was enough continence,
um,
you know,
then they took over the life,
took over the land.
I think it's just Kinda,
life may be kind of like a cosmic force,
if I can get ugly on you,
if we do go to Mars and will essentially
be ultimate panspermia.
Yes,
exactly.
Right.
Yeah.
And that way,
right.
Panspermia,
which is we were always a weird word to
kind of pants for me because people feel
weird about sperms whenever I give an
academic talk.
And I'm like,
I know it's a strange when you say sperm
in front of people that are like you
piece of shit.
Yeah,
right.
It's like a scientific term,
man.
I swear a matter.
It's like saying niggardly.
Yeah.
Right.
So it's very difficult word to say.
No,
it has nothing to do with the n word.
Yeah.
So,
um,
uh,
you know,
I think,
I think it's part of life.
I think life wants more life.
And this is the question you're raising
about,
look,
what do we look like in a million years?
What happens to a species that become.
And you know,
now we're in the realm of science
fiction,
but it's all cool.
Um,
you know,
like what might we become like the gods
in some scenes.
I think that this is my theory and I've
thrown this out so many times,
people are sick of it,
but I think that what we're looking at
when we see these archetypal aliens with
the big heads and the big eyes and the
tiny bodies and no genitals,
I think we think this is what we're
eventually going to be.
We're going to move past that man.
I'll see you in your panspermia and I'll
raise you typically typically talking
about gender.
This is the problem and this is why we
need diversity.
Um,
I just think that if we.
So those are archetypes kind of built
into some sense that we're moving pat.
Like,
well,
what did we used to be?
Well,
we used to be monkeys,
right?
What are we going to be?
What we're going to be that thing,
that thing that can levitate things,
but it's mind the thing to communicate
telepathically,
that thing that has this incredible
ability to map out the cosmos and create
wormholes and the super advanced
advanced to a point where we can't even
comprehend.
So like if you think about how,
what,
you know w w we evolved from at one
point in time,
we split from mollusks like what?
600 something
years ago.
It's got to be on it.
It's got to be past the Cambrian
explosion,
but you know,
it's like,
yeah,
300,
400.
I don't know yet.
So awhile ago.
How,
how much does a squid understand about
cell phone networks and whether or not
it's sprint's unlimited data plan plans.
Really any good picked out.
We'll we'll extrapolate that to what
this alien creature is going to be in
terms of its understanding of time and
space and matter versus ours.
We are this crude thing that's weirded
out by the word sperm.
Whereas it is telepathically
communicating with a universal language
and it has this unbelievable ability to
manipulate matter and they've achieved
homeostasis with their environment.
No longer have this.
Well that's one of the things about,
you know,
there's the Fermi paradox,
right?
Yeah.
Like why haven't we seen so,
you know,
as I already said,
we haven't looked enough to say that
the,
we haven't seen evidence of life,
right.
It's like opening your door and goes,
well where are all the buffalo to go to
Wyoming.
But there,
you know,
there is a kind of a problem with
because we just do a paper on this now,
you know,
part of the permit paradox.
Let's go.
I don't want to go too far on this.
Can we can go back circle back?
Um,
I liked it.
So he had ducks is fascinating.
It is,
right?
So the,
so the,
the,
the idea that we had two people.
Okay.
So the Fermi paradox is the idea that
like,
uh,
you know,
what if there is,
if the paradox part is like,
if you're telling me that intelligence
is commented,
evolves everywhere,
then why don't I see it already.
Right?
So the,
the,
if you're asking about like why don't we
see signals from that,
I've already answered that,
right?
Because we just,
we haven't looked yet so yet,
but hit part of his question and this
was done by a guy in heart.
I mean,
so for me it was just,
this happened over a conversation in,
for lunch,
you know,
in 1950.
So he just posed the,
he said where are they all?
But in 1975 guy named Hart wrote a paper
where he really mapped out the here's
the main problem.
Even if you're traveling with a 10th of
the speed of light,
if you managed to build like world ships
that can travel across the stars,
you know,
and you're traveling at point one
percent of the speed of light in,
you know,
if you do that and you hop from one
store to the other,
build another ship,
hop to the next one in about 600,000
years.
You have covered the whole galaxy,
right?
So 600,000
years.
Sounds like a long time,
but it's a tiny part of the galaxies
history,
galaxies,
10 billion years old.
So in that case,
like why every,
if just one species has to do that and
they can cover the galaxy.
So why aren't they?
Why don't we see the colony ships here?
Right?
That's,
that's a much harder version of the
fermi paradox to get around.
Is it though,
because if we did.
Look,
we're already sending robots to Mars,
right?
We're not going to Mars yet,
but we're sending robots there.
What if we decide that there's no real
benefit in sending biological entities
into space and that the dangers of
radiation and asteroidal impacts on this
is just too great.
It's far better to send something.
I mean,
look at what we're capable of doing now
in terms of projection of video.
We can take a cell phone video and you
could send it to your friend in New
Zealand and they can get it almost
instantaneously to go to do a skype call
where we can get some sort of three d,
virtual reality imaging of these planets
like,
Hey,
do you want to see what it's like on
Pandora here?
Put these goggles on and you will go
wherever you want that robot to go and
you'll be there.
Right?
And maybe it'll get to the point where
you can actually smell it and touch it
and feel it and,
but not be compromised by its
environment in terms of your bio.
Well that's actually a huge point.
So that's one of the things we're
looking at in this paper is the idea
that,
you know,
good planets may be hard to find.
You know,
there's this great novel by Kim Stanley
Robinson who's like,
just for me,
one of the great science fiction
writers,
it's called Aurora and then you know,
the usual worldship thing go.
So they build the colony ship,
it takes three generations to cross
space and they get to the planet and the
planet socks,
it looked like it was going to be good,
you know,
but there's like prions tiny or super
small biological shit that just makes
you can't live there and then going
back.
Right.
So it's like,
it may be exactly like you're saying
that,
you know,
we think like,
oh,
you just land on a planet,
your terraform it and you know,
you just turned it into a habitable and
it's like,
that may not work and maybe it does,
but that's a science fiction.
I do.
So,
uh,
right.
It's entirely possible.
I mean,
there's a lot of possible solutions is,
which is just that,
uh,
you know,
one of which is space is really hard and
really interstellar,
not interplanetary,
but interstellar travel is really hard
and really expensive.
I was just reading the paper on this
with a guy estimated that in order to
get,
like,
say you wanted to have a thousand people
on a worldship to get to another star
that would take the economy that come
need like a,
I think was like 100,000
Earth economies
to build that Jeff Paizos are you
listening time?
We're ready.
You might have,
but it was just like it was so much,
you know,
you.
Unless you were.
He said,
you know what the conclusion he came to,
unless you were a multi planet species,
if you were like,
uh,
if you had conquered the entire um,
or settled the entire solar system,
maybe you'd have an economy that big.
So one,
one possible solution is good planets
are hard to find.
And um,
and uh,
you know,
it's just too expensive.
It really costs a lot.
And so yeah,
it's not really worth the effort.
You know,
you send out some probes once in a
while,
but yeah,
no,
it's not.
Well,
it's also finding an environment that's
not just habitable but stable in our
environment is habitable.
But look what's going on in Hawaii right
now.
There is a 400 year old lake that
evaporated in a matter of hours,
right?
It's the biggest lake on the big island.
It's gone.
Which is such a tragedy,
but it's not.
It's not.
It's magnificent.
Right?
And you watch that lava roll into that
lake and say that's a wrap.
Kids no more lakey flux.
And it really shows you the power of a
planet to that sources at work.
What makes continents?
I mean it made the island in the first
place.
You can't be upset at it.
Billowing off.
It is what made the island right.
It's continuing to make the island here,
right?
Yeah.
Right,
exactly.
That's right about your house.
But now you've got more real estate.
So shout out.
It's making the island bigger and it's
always done that.
It's been doing that for millions of
years.
It's a fascinating place.
If you've been.
I've been and I've seen the.
I want you to do the work.
Did you do the helicopter thing?
No,
man,
you got to do the helicopter thing.
It's crazy because you fly over the
volcanoes.
We can't now because it's too crazy,
but I did a few back and you could watch
it.
The lava go into the ocean and you see
these lava events.
Poor is red hot fucking.
It's like,
it's glowing.
It's going into the ocean that I saw
that part.
We went to the park to see it,
you know,
and then when you went to,
when you go to that volcano park,
there's just like vince were steams
coming out like New York City with the,
you know,
the manholes.
You're like,
that's just from this heat coming in
from the bottom of the planet.
Are you scared about yellowstone?
Uh,
like the uh,
what was that movie?
A 2012 map.
Like where did that.
Because that's such a.
that's like a,
that's what made the adirondacks right.
What was the 2012 movie?
I never saw that with ge Qa after
tomorrow.
Day.
Before tomorrow.
No,
no,
no.
It was a,
it was a climate change.
It was John cusack.
It's actually a pretty good movie.
Yeah.
That's another,
like destroy the plant.
Those guys who made that.
Hold on,
stop right there.
That was not a pretty good movie.
That movie sucked.
Thought it was good.
I'm moving so stupid,
stupid mistake.
Disaster by inches with the cars.
They never got a flat.
They always got away from the.
The world caving in.
Totally believable,
man.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
No,
I thought.
Well,
yellowstone is a caldera.
It's a super volcano and they're
experiencing thousands of earthquakes a
year and that eventually every six to
800,000
years.
It's a continent killer.
The last time it blew was 600,000
years ago.
So why aren't you scared?
Uh,
I don't know,
I just don't think about it.
I'm fucking thinking about it every day,
man.
I'll smoke a joint.
I think about once a month I think
about,
you know,
I should.
Okay.
I'm gonna.
Add that to my list of things.
I'm freaking out about it.
I have friends in Australia and that's
where I'm going because there's light
over.
Just start driving on the left hand
side.
That's the only thing you can go to.
I worried more about Seattle.
I lived in Seattle for a while and they
said the super earthquake that they're
looking at it,
it's going to turn the whole thing into
Jello.
Right.
You get an earthquake so bad that the
ground just literally becomes porous.
Is it really that scary?
They're,
yeah,
they're predicting because,
you know,
Seattle's got like,
I mean,
I don't know that much about this.
I'm way out of my.
I'm in the danger zone.
Um,
the plates are super deep,
you know,
so you don't get as many tremors but,
but you know,
when it releases,
it's gonna be a super powerful
earthquake and you know,
it'll,
it'll be so powerful.
Yeah.
That they said that like there's not
going to be even,
even with the earthquake,
proofing is not gonna be be left
standing.
Jesus.
So yeah,
dad,
Seattle,
you must be,
I mean,
because you're here,
right?
You feel tremors.
They might say they happen all the time.
Right.
I've only been a few times,
but not all the time I've felt them
before.
The,
the biggest ones I ever felt was when I
first moved here.
I first moved here in [inaudible] 94 and
it was right after the northridge
earthquake and uh,
I was in my house and I felt,
uh,
I guess it was like a five point five
where the whole thing just,
it was weird,
but it gave me the impression that the
house that I was living in or the
apartment that I was in was made out of
the same stuff,
like a box that a refrigerator would
come in,
you can move it around inside.
The whole thing was just moving like
easily and right.
I was like,
Holy Shit.
That was my.
I've only had a few times that I've felt
like I'm like,
it's like it's,
you know,
at first I thought it was a truck.
I thought the truck was rolling by,
you know,
and I'm like,
oh,
somebody says,
no man,
that was an earthquake.
And the one that I experienced was
nothing.
I mean,
there's a baby one ones that they're
getting,
you know,
right now,
somewhere in the world.
I mean there's,
there's always something that's like a
five or six.
Yeah.
So this goes back to your point about
the,
uh,
you know,
a lot of planets,
right?
We'll be like way more plate
tectonically active volatile than ours.
So,
you know,
I mean a lot of times and I think good
planets are going to be really hard to
find.
So,
you know,
it may be,
that may be the solution.
The other solution is,
you know,
I mean,
the way you guys found out about me,
so I did that article about the previous
civilization,
you know,
like what is it,
how do you know whether or not there was
a previous civilization?
And uh,
you know,
um,
one solution could be that,
look they were here,
you know,
that somebody did arrive and spend some
time on earth,
but if it was like half a billion years
ago and they only lasted,
right?
Every civilization has a finite
lifetime.
They only lasted for,
you know,
even a few hundred thousand years.
They wouldn't leave.
There'd be no record left to,
it'd be nothing,
there'd be nothing.
Do you think that's possible that
something's ever visited here?
And because that is the big question and
that's the,
the,
the thing that gets the UFO dorks more
jazzed up than anything is the
possibility that we'd been visited.
Yeah.
Not In the.
I'm definitely not UFOS.
There's,
there's two arguments against you if
owes a.
One is as,
as you know,
a friend of mine,
Jason Wright says,
it's like,
look as astronomers,
man,
we were finding all those aspects.
We're finding a little chunks of rock
movement.
You know,
nobody looks at the sky harder than we
do.
Right.
And you know,
if anything,
unless you want to go to the conspiracy
theories,
we would've found something.
My other argument is like,
what's with the headlights?
You know what I mean?
People always like,
Oh man,
I saw lights in the sky.
And then they moved around and then they
disappeared,
you know,
but they don't really want to be seen.
I'm like,
well,
why do they have headlights on?
Like why just turn off the fricking
nights.
It just.
Why would they have lights in the first
place?
You came from another civilization and
you can't get around without your high
beams.
You know the ideas like what the fuck
are you seeing?
What those lights,
right?
You're not seeing shit.
That was the last time you saw me.
Planes have lights so other planes don't
run into them.
They don't have the light so they could
see where they're going.
Yeah.
So what.
So why do they have.
Right,
exactly.
The planes have lights so other people
can seem.
So they're here but they're mysterious.
They don't want to be found in turn off
the fricking light.
So they.
Yeah,
they wouldn't have any lines,
but yeah,
they always have lights.
Yeah.
People are always seeing,
like eliminate.
I liked this guy and then they moved
back and forth.
And so also the problem with human
memory.
Memory's horrible memory of events that
are stunning or shocking or unnerving or
you think you saw something,
right?
They've done all that research even in
trials,
right?
Where people see things,
you know,
just kinda like.
But do you think it's possible that
there could be life on other planets and
it's possible there could be intelligent
life on other planets and we send probes
to Mars,
why wouldn't.
And I think that if they do send
something here,
they're going to send something without
biological life inside of it.
Yeah.
Well,
this is,
you know,
it's a really interesting question is
like you were talking about like what
will we evolve into in,
you know,
a million years,
uh,
you know,
it may be possible that biology is
a short period of intelligence.
You build machines and the machines
become,
you know,
you download yourself into.
I mean,
that's a real possibility that like,
you know,
silicon makes a lot more sense than
wetware.
Well,
the problem is we think of artificial
intelligence as artificial,
right?
It's definitely real,
Yeah.
No,
that's exactly.
It's not,
it's not fake.
It's right there.
You know,
it's like there's artificial milk,
you know what I mean?
But it's,
it's a liquid,
it's an actual liquid.
There's not an artificial life.
It's just silicon created life.
But again,
the idea of the biosphere,
this may be the what the biosphere
solution to spreading itself to getting
it maybe that,
like silicon,
that that's kind of a normal face.
I am super skeptical about the whole
trans human thing that we're going to
download ourselves and do intelligent.
You don't.
Have you ever gone to one of those
conventions,
knows dorks.
There's some pretty serious dork in.
Well,
there's geniuses in those dorks too.
It's really interesting.
It's like they're fully wholly committed
to this prospect of downloading
themselves.
You've talked Kurtzweil before.
Uh,
no,
but I've read his stuff.
I had a chance to interview him a few
years back for smart,
but he's just like beyond smart,
but God damn is he committed to it.
And then when you get to it,
you realize that what he actually wants
to do is recreate his father.
Yeah.
He's his father died when he was young
and he wants to be able to through
memories and photographs and what he
knows about his father,
literally recreate his father and to be
able to have a conversation with them.
He was talking about this.
Right?
But what he's doing is he's going way,
way into the future,
into the possibilities of he's not
seeing like,
well,
five years from now we're going to be
able to send,
you know,
gigabyte pictures to them,
he's saying let's think of if you keep
going exponentially and the electronics
and technology and innovation keeps
continually accelerating.
We could potentially get to the point
where it's the impossible.
Well,
you'd be able to recreate human beings
based on your knowledge of them and then
they'll be able to come up with some
sort of a program.
Will he'll be able to have a
conversation with his father.
Yeah.
See,
I think that misunder.
I mean,
I think it's,
you know,
it's true,
but like the possibility of a
singularity and technological
development,
but you know,
it's not going to be his father.
That's the sad thing.
You know,
I think we seriously,
I've done some work on this as an
interest of mine about mind.
What is mind and what's the relationship
between mind and matter?
And um,
I think we have like a serious
misunderstood.
We don't understand consciousness very
well at all.
So the idea that like,
oh yeah,
it's just got to be trivial to download
your,
you know,
your consciousness into a computer.
I think it's pretty,
you know,
there's like a shit load of assumptions
in there about like what mind is and the
relationship between your neurons and
you know,
awareness.
So that's why I think those guys,
it's a little bit of a religion,
you know what I mean?
It is a little bit,
you know,
so it's like,
well 20,
45 is the new benchmark for whatever
reason,
that's the new number.
They keep going back.
It's gonna be like every other,
every other rapture.
We thought it was 20,
45.
We really been 20 slash 65.
We went to this 20,
45 conference,
me and my friend Ran Duncan and we got
to talk to some of these guys and it's
really fascinating and one of them had
created some robot that was supposed to
be him but it didn't work well.
So they never revealed that at the
conference that had too many bugs in it.
It's intriguing.
It's like I want them to keep going
because I mean,
when,
when are we going to get to x Mokena?
When are we going to get to talk about
good movies?
Or did you like that?
One of my favorite movies ever.
So smart.
So like,
just like simple.
He's not beating you over the head with
it and know,
cut the shit most moving moments in that
movie.
You were like,
whoa.
The entire.
I think that's one of my all time top 20
movies,
which he stabs him just emotionless.
Just family.
I'm putting the blade in.
It was amazing.
Amazing alert.
Did you like annihilation?
Because I didn't like it as much but I
liked it.
It was very weird and the ending seemed
like some producers put their just in
the soup just like Pittsburgh,
what's happening here?
Who made this part?
Yeah.
Uh,
but I,
I enjoyed it.
So I think like,
you know,
the danger with anything when it comes
to ai.
And so when you.
Here's an interesting thing about ai,
like we're,
we are getting,
making amazing strides with ai now.
Now artificial intelligence is different
from artificial consciousness.
You know what I mean?
So,
but um,
but the ai that,
you know,
what we're getting out of it is nothing
like us,
right?
So the,
you know,
back in the day where people were like,
oh,
we're going to model the human brain and
that's how we'll do it.
Well,
like programs that are what and what
they've learned is like,
ah,
that doesn't really work that well.
So now this whole big data thing like,
you know,
network theory and big data and deep
learning,
we're like,
you know,
they're using statistical,
the power of,
of having huge amounts of computing and
statistical reasoning so that like,
you know,
get the computer,
like,
you know,
it'll find the picture of the cat,
but you have no idea why it found that
it didn't reason like,
oh yeah,
that was sort of looks like cat and I
like cats,
you know,
it was just like,
oh,
these kinds of lines go with that kind
of thing and it has no idea what it's
doing,
but it'll act intelligently.
And so that's,
you know,
I mean that's kind of freaky deaky in a
lot of ways too.
I think people are,
I think it's smart to think about the
dangers of Ai.
Not necessarily want to take some
pictures to us.
Yeah.
Not necessarily the dangers,
just the dangers to this thing that we
are this weird monkey thing that wants
to keep being a monkey thing.
Well,
you mean in the sense of like,
right,
that it's going to replace us?
Yes.
Yeah.
I think it's inevitable.
I mean,
don't you think that if you go back and
interview the single celled organism
before branched off into multicell
multicell bullshit.
I don't want to stay a single cell at
the bottom of the rock and roll music
and they're to mail cars.
Fuck that.
I don't want a car man.
I like stand down here.
There are some real thought to that,
that we are the wetware that is the
problem.
No,
no.
Listen,
I,
I think it's fully conceivable,
like I'm not going do it.
It'll never happen.
But as a guy knows,
a philosopher says,
you know,
there's a certain way in which
everything we do with ai right now,
it's not like,
you know,
Watson is playing chess.
It's like we're using Watson to play
chess.
It's our tool,
you know,
and I think the fear is the toolkits add
a hand,
not that it develops a thing where like
I hated humans,
you know,
dad,
I hate you,
but more that it's like,
you know,
these things which are not actually
thinking,
they act intelligent but they're not
thinking can have a huge.
Like it'll have a really negative
impact,
you know,
it'll,
what does it,
there's that example of like,
if you design something that is an ai
system to make paperclips,
it ends up consuming the entire planet
making paperclips because that's what
you told it to do.
Right.
You never told it to make a sustainable
amount of.
Right.
Exactly.
So I'm,
I'm more worried about that than I am of
like Sky Net,
you know,
coming over and like,
deciding that it's going to take a drop
all the bombs on it because it needs to
get rid of it.
Well there's no biological imperative
for a silicon based artificial
intelligence to procreate to keep going
and move forward.
Like why do they do that?
You do it because we came from biology.
Biology needs to stay alive and
everybody wants bigger,
faster,
stronger.
You want to keep moving and it's because
there's a real possibility that you
might get consumed by some other life
form.
So you have to protect yourself and you
have to look out for other people who
might want to breed with the viable
female that you've copulated with.
There's a lot of shit going on built in
evolutionarily to have.
But we assume that somehow or another
these artificial creations will have as
well,
which is why,
right?
I mean yeah,
like if we program it in.
So the thing is like,
but will it wake up like so that if it
does wake up,
will it have the inclination towards
scientific research?
Would it even want to send something
through the cosmos of us?
Yeah.
No,
that's a really interesting.
I,
you know,
and I think we just don't know if it
actually because listen,
we,
we understand so little about what
consciousness is and what its
imperatives are like.
Yeah.
Once you wake up and you're like,
oh,
you're dead,
you know,
dad,
I got to see like why?
Like,
who knows what really did you like
Battlestar Galactica?
I loved Battlestar.
God damn good.
Was that the new version?
I love the old version because that I
was 14 years old and spaceships,
but the new version was amazing.
Smart.
If there is a show that I wish they
would bring back,
it's Battlestar Galactica the ending.
But the ending though it was,
you know,
they had to end it is all right.
But the fucking series was brilliant.
It was brilliant.
You know what was amazing about that?
The way they wrapped,
like all the political shit that was
happening after nine slash 11 to that
man from the torture scenes.
Yeah man,
it was so.
And then they even had the whole thing
with starbuck about know what was she,
you know,
there's a couple of like it was five
years.
Right.
And there were a couple of seasons where
like,
it Kinda got a little ran off the rails.
But what's her name?
Katie sackhoff.
Is that her name?
Who?
Starbuck?
Yeah.
Is that her name?
Yeah,
she's so good.
She was really good in that role stuff
since she's got a movie out right now on
Netflix.
I haven't seen it.
Right.
But I'm saying like,
Oh yeah,
there's,
you know,
but she had rights.
You sort of disappeared.
It was so good in that show.
I was like,
well this is,
this is like the launching pad for her.
Yeah.
And you almost revolutionary about that
show to the way they did the special
effects were like,
oh,
the camera moved around.
Like there's a spaceship,
but um,
you know,
I don't have.
It.
Didn't do,
you know,
sometimes it did those long pants,
but it was kind of opened up a whole new
way of sort of looking at,
uh,
you know,
just sort of what it looks like to be in
space and stuff.
Yeah.
But it really scared the shit out of
people in terms of artificial life.
Something that we create the decides
it's done with us and it's taking over.
Well,
you know,
what's amazing about that,
and this is I've written about this,
this idea that like,
you know,
we keep telling that story over and over
again.
How many movies,
you know,
can you think of that,
have that.
And I think like,
so I'm really interested in myth,
right?
That,
you know,
the whole mythology,
the way like,
you know,
we can never get away from the myths,
coming of age,
the hero's journey,
Campbell,
Joseph Campbell,
Joseph Campbell Fan.
Um,
but like you know,
what's happening with us now,
we got,
there's nothing in,
there's nothing in the storehouse of
myth to take care of like building
machines that take over.
Right?
So the reason we keep telling that story
over and over again is we're preparing
ourselves,
right?
We're building the myths,
you know,
that sort of will help.
We don't know what's going to happen,
but we have to keep telling that story
because we can feel it coming,
you know what I mean,
like this is.
So we need to keep telling a story to
kind of explore what the options are.
And I liked that too.
I liked about the ending and I didn't
think the ending was great.
But the idea that like,
oh yeah,
this balance,
you know,
you get to keep going through these
cycles of trying to achieve this balance
between,
you know,
silicon forms and non silica and then
biological forms.
But um,
well we have not,
we were worried that we're going to be
taken over by something else,
but we're not overly concerned with
evolving our own biology changing.
And maybe that's the solution in terms
of our physical limitations is some sort
of a symbiotic connection between us and
technology.
That instead of artificial technology
and artificial life taking over usurping
us instead of that maybe we become a
part of it and it becomes a part of us
and we.
I mean,
you have glasses on,
you can see better with those glasses.
That's essentially a Cyborg.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Right,
right,
right.
And these things,
you know,
these cell phones,
my God,
my memories in there,
right to no cell phones.
My house two days ago without my phone
and I turned around in a panic on my own
street.
Where's my fucking.
I was like,
no.
You remember when you used to have phone
numbers in your head?
Oh yeah.
My wife's number.
I can't.
Like I got three digits.
Adam go further than this crazy.
But we remember a lot of other stuff
now.
I mean,
you have so much.
I mean I'm,
I'm really overwhelmed.
I think I'm in that weird zone where I
just don't have,
I don't,
I don't have enough data space.
I don't have enough storage for all of
us.
That's.
You've got to kind of pick and choose,
right?
Sort of like wikipedia.
We're all human knowledge.
Entire sum of human knowledge is right
there,
you know,
mean like,
Whoa,
what are you talking about?
Changes.
Right?
So you were talking about what
an amazing change that you can have.
Pretty much,
you know,
like,
I love comics,
right?
You know,
I was a comic marvel guy way back.
Right.
And back in the day,
you know,
you paid for your,
you had to,
you know,
first of all you got your ass kicked.
But um,
you know,
you have to go to the store every week
and get the comics and you know,
and now you know,
you just look up captain America and you
can know everything.
There was about his,
you know,
his origin story and everything.
So it's like that idea that like there's
no domains of knowledge that you can't
instantly access and have all the
backstory that you need to be a physical
comic.
Books are amazing,
but I have to be honest,
comic books on an Ipad or better because
you don't see the next frame.
Yeah,
yeah.
You just swipe and then you get the next
frame.
You don't,
you don't see it in advance.
Like if you're reading the left side,
Dr.
Change and the right side is an
explosion and you're like,
well I see that and see that shit's
coming next.
Like it's kind of a shitty way to do it.
No,
I agree.
I have an ipad.
It's fucking amazing.
Amazing.
Yeah.
No.
When you do that thing and now with the,
it's like embarrassing as a professor of
physics at a major university.
I have like $3,000
for the comic books.
Embarrassing.
It's not embarrassing.
Can't be still brilliant guy.
But he just also like cool shit.
Yeah.
Well shouldn't I be reading like those,
the Esky or something?
I don't know.
You fumble,
you know,
my dad was,
my dad was always like,
because my dad was a writer,
a comic books,
you know,
but I was like,
Dad,
I've learned that especially with
marvel,
right.
Marvel a great language,
right?
I mean the word synopsis from Marvel,
you know,
so uh,
especially,
you know,
some of the like doctor strange had some
great shit,
you know.
Fantastic.
Four.
Yeah.
No,
the doctors,
you know,
it's,
I was this the science advisor for
doctor strange with,
for the movie,
for the movie?
Yeah,
it was best.
I always say,
I said you have to correct anything.
No,
no,
not really because they called me in.
So I know Scott Derrick's actually had
lunch with or breakfast with Scott
yesterday.
I know Scott from my first book,
which is about science and religion,
you know,
so you know,
we've got somebody connected us and we'd
been talking for a long time and when he
got tapped to do doctor strange,
he contacted,
I got the email,
said marvel wants to talk to you,
you know,
it's like,
yeah,
I got out there for a day and met Kevin
fee man.
It was just like,
oh man.
And so we basically worked on,
he wanted to work on to two things for
that.
And what's funny is I never read Dr.
Strange,
right?
Because I was like a science guy was all
about Tony Stark or you know,
or you know,
or a spiderman or the x men.
So I never,
I was like,
Oh God uses magic.
So think we have to figure out was um,
first of all that that scene where he
first do the counters,
the ancient one,
you know,
and she has to kind of like,
school him on,
there's more ways to think about the
world beyond science and then the,
the multiverse.
That was the other thing because I've
written the blog a lot on the
multiverse,
but man,
it was awesome.
It was so much fun to be in the writer's
room,
you know,
with them and just like be throwing
around ideas.
Wow.
Yeah.
No it was.
And it'll probably never ever happen
again.
But I don't care.
You know,
how to care.
I got my shot.
That was a weird thing that when you're
young you like all this cool stuff,
but then when you get old you're
supposed to be more pragmatic.
You're supposed to abandon that stuff
and be mature.
But when I was a kid I was super
embarrassed when I became an adult that
I still like muscle cars.
It's like,
why do I like these stupid things?
And I loved them.
I would see one drive by here,
the rumble and go,
Ooh,
that's awesome.
That thing,
and then when I became an older adult I
was like,
who gives a fuck?
That's really what it is.
That's where I'm now looking at what
Karen's manager,
because I love video games.
I play a lot of video games and people
was like,
oh my God,
your children.
Yeah,
dude,
awesome man.
There was nothing.
There is no better way to kill an hour,
especially after a stressful day then to
go and shoot aliens.
You know what I mean?
This is like,
you know what I mean?
This stimulates the mind.
I mean,
Jamie and I have talked about this many
times,
that we have this deep appreciation for
chess and go and all these ancient
games.
There are games like starcraft and even
like one on one quake matches that
require intense calculating.
Right?
You have to think about the environment
understanding of the map that you're
right,
you're competing in.
It's,
there's a lot of strategy.
No,
that's really good about it.
I mean,
I,
I tend to be,
I do a lot.
I really like rpgs.
You know,
so with a map and everything,
so one of them everquest dorks.
Oh,
well I don't do,
I don't do anything multi player.
Right?
Because I'm so bad at it that like,
I know there's some kids,
some 13 year old in Korea.
It was just like your dad or your dead
spawn dies.
Spawn.
But I like something with a really good
story.
You know,
whether you would.
What's the game you like?
Oh God,
my favorite game is last of us.
What does that.
Oh Man,
last bucket.
Because I don't want,
I don't like Zombie Games because I
could scared being scared when I,
I saw um,
when we do the living versus zombies.
That's a nice simple one that might
work.
Uh,
no,
I still have the um,
now the living dead when I was 12 it was
on pbs and little screen and it just
like after that.
I'm sorry.
Zombies.
Wow.
Yeah,
it was,
I can't believe they put it on tv like,
you know,
for the 11:00
show.
So,
but last of us is kind of a Zombie
survival story,
but it's beautiful.
I mean,
it's really the narrative of it.
It's this guy your 20 years after and
the thing about this thing,
it opens up with the,
you know,
the Zombie outbreak happening and the
guy loses his daughter,
like you see him lose his daughter and
it's so,
well,
it's the same company that did,
um,
uh,
uncharted,
which are other.
I really like those as well.
Um,
and so she's like,
the acting in it was really beautiful
and then,
you know,
it's 20 years later and this guy is
broken,
you know what I mean?
Like he's just,
he's,
you know,
he survived in this,
you have the society's falling apart.
Um,
but,
uh,
you know,
he just track him as he gets this,
this young girl who is immune and he's
got to take her cross country to,
you know,
and you're following this guy story and
then there's zombies and there's a,
the theme of a movie,
a really recent movie.
Wasn't that like a,
a foreign movie with a Foreign Zombie
movie that was supposed to be very good.
But that was the idea behind it.
It was,
but it was his own daughter wasn't.
Maybe it wasn't the fact that they took
it from this because you know,
so last of us is one like huge amounts
of awards.
How old is it?
Six years,
maybe less.
Month two is just about to come out.
Well,
the sports center movies older than
that,
I believe because it came out right
around the time where his wife left him
because he banged the maid.
Whoops.
Downfall.
Lips.
He was the governor then wasn't even the
governor.
He's there.
He's posting.
It was post.
It was post post governor.
Um,
but that,
that theme is a reoccurring theme that
is a reoccurrence of telling you.
How many times is that comeback?
The plague wipes people out.
They come back to life.
There's zombies.
So you gotta wonder what's up with that,
like why is that something that's like
stirring around in our head?
I think the apocalypse is because we
kind of feel nervous about what's
happening with us because we can see
sort of sure.
Pushing up against boundaries.
We're also vulnerable.
Yeah.
Running.
We're vulnerable to disease and we're
vulnerable.
I mean,
there's so many different things that
people can get.
Rabies and malaria plagues we used to
have plagues all the time,
you know,
so yeah.
No,
but that's what makes this game so great
is that it really takes the world after
the fall,
seriously.
And it's heartbreaking.
You know what I mean?
That's,
it's beautifully done,
scarier than Shit,
but,
you know,
beautifully done.
And it's,
for me,
it's like everything that I love mostly
because like you're saying is you get
into these situations and you know
you're going to get killed.
You look,
there's dark souls were like,
there's no getting through dark,
dark souls.
Apparently the most hardest game ever.
I've never played it.
But you know,
this game is hard and you got to keep it
as dark souls.
Dark souls is a,
it's also a story based,
uh,
you know,
open world games,
single player,
I think that it's probably a multiplayer
mode,
but um,
uh,
it's like,
you know,
a kind of an elvish,
you're in that kind of world.
You're just trying to stay alive,
trying to stay alive.
And it's just like the hardest game
ever.
That's what they say.
Um,
but like,
you know,
I said a good hard game.
You gotta you know,
you gotta you can keep going back like,
oh,
I just died.
All right,
let me try it.
Let me try coming around from this side,
you know,
Oh,
let me use this weapon.
Let me get on this.
It's really that we did,
uh,
my,
um,
I had a text book that just came out a
couple of years ago and we did a video
game.
We built a full first ever full video
game for an intro astronomy course.
And the whole idea was like,
the coolest thing about a game is like
the first thing you have to do is learn
the rules.
Right?
And that's what makes being in a game
world interest there,
you know,
there's a whole set of rules,
got know how to craft.
You got to know which weapons to use in
different kinds of situations.
And our idea with the video game was
like,
just make the real.
The real rules make um,
the science rules,
right?
Oh,
you want to go mine an asteroid?
Well,
how do you know which asteroid has,
you know,
the,
the most,
uh,
you know,
or in it,
I'm just going to do what you're going
to do normally do an astronomy.
So I think like,
you know,
video games have not recognized.
They haven't,
like you said,
people don't understand actually how
important they are for teaching,
for all kinds of things.
Video Games and for entertaining,
you know,
for,
for a future of storytelling to.
Well people take them,
they think that it's a waste of time
until they find out how much these
professionals make it.
So saying that some guy,
what,
what is the number?
That kid was making $500,000
a month playing fortnite.
Wasn't that what Sean,
that sugar.
But it's way more than that.
He makes more than that.
So what is fortnight you?
Can somebody explain fortnight to me?
I'm sorry,
I'm still in far cry.
Five crazy third person shooter.
You're jumping around shooting be boomed
with third person shooters.
But like is it a story or is it just
like you're,
you know,
you've got other people people up.
I think the story is really just drop it
into survive.
Oh yeah,
there's no campaign mode or if they're
just,
there is,
but that's a separate.
That's not whatever.
That's interesting to me about
fortnight.
The graphics suck.
I don't want you.
To me,
that's a graphic style that those hit at
that it has like a,
like a,
uh,
xbox to sort of.
Yeah.
Somebody had a,
uh,
an image and it was from 2007.
It said,
man,
look at this.
I wonder what video games are going to
be looking like.
The graphics gonna be looking like a
2018,
and then it shows fort night and it's
like,
this is like,
dude,
they're just like,
they've turned the textures off.
They 100 percent.
You turned the textures off when you
play online,
if you don't have a powerful enough
computer,
sure you don't like claiming.
Right?
So it doesn't make your streaming,
it doesn't make your video game.
Video card works so hard,
but also it makes it easier to recognize
shapes because they're not like,
that was the thing that did with quake.
They would completely turn the textures
off when guys would be like playing in
high level matches and you would just
deal with these flat walls and then the
object,
the person that you were fighting
against,
what they would stand out and start
contrast.
Right,
right.
So you didn't have,
you know,
otherwise you'd be in this castle wall.
You'd have the incredible textures on
the wall and you wouldn't be able to see
them as easily too distracting.
Mean.
That's one of the thing I think I love
about video games too,
is like the scenery,
you know,
sometimes I just want to stop and be
like,
that's it.
The right side has full graphics,
not so it depends on what you were
actually.
The right side is reasonable.
I mean it still is a little bit.
That's not much different at all.
Yeah.
I mean sort of the left side is just
dark.
There's grass.
Yeah.
Look at the graph building.
There's still some movement on the
ground.
It's not flat plain like it isn't quick.
Go to quake,
play,
go to quake three,
no textures.
Make a video or pull up a video of that
and you'll see what I'm talking about
when I'm talking about is like literal
flat walls where people turned
everything off and it got to a point
where they weren't allowing it and
certain competitions because it makes
such a big difference because now you're
just like,
it's a target in front of a blank
screen.
They also,
you could also replace all of the
characters with a larger character,
like a,
like say if you were playing as this
girl,
so I get this one.
It's showing the mod in between.
Maybe I'm thinking,
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
I'm losers quake.
I've heard of.
Or you pitch.
No,
no.
Jamie,
pull,
pull up,
quake,
no textures,
pull up,
quake,
no textures,
and then you could watch what it looks
like.
That is not.
No textures,
that that's different.
You can see the difference in the colors
and things are moving.
It's when they turn off all the
textures,
you,
you get to see these flat.
Well,
that's what it looks like.
Seat.
Yeah.
Now that is a way different experience.
It would be much easier to see.
Right.
You can't see those still exist,
but all the textures are gone and if you
show a video that see if you could find
a video that jamie when in the videos
you see things moving around with no
textures and you realize what an
advantage it would be if you were
playing someone who's.
You're constantly dealing with all this
visual input.
You have all this different shit,
high visibility and quake three that
it's hard to find out.
Is this.
Which game is this?
Quake live.
Oh,
okay.
This is again,
I still got to ask what is quick?
I mean,
I know I've heard of it but I've never
played it.
Like it's the ultimate first person
shooter and it's the original one.
It was originally quake one and.
Well there was doom but it was doing.
I've heard of like I've even,
we did doom,
didn't they?
They came out with another.
Didn't they come out with another
version of Dune?
Yes they did.
And there's another one that's coming
out soon.
Um,
but what quake one was,
was these cool maps and you run around
and shoot each other and you'd have
these death matches,
so one on one death matches and shoot
rockets at each other and shit.
And it's,
you're seeing it through your
perspective.
Like,
so if you have a rocket launcher,
you see the rocket launcher in front of
you are there.
Now that whole idea,
what does this one,
oh,
this is quake champions.
This is the newest version.
I mean,
the graphics are fucking incredible on
these things.
Now they,
they're so excited.
We're gonna have.
We're setting up a land here,
a local area network here.
What we're going to stream live and play
each other.
Excellent and a waste massive amounts of
time.
And I'm sure I'm going to go bad
sometimes I'm sorta like,
oh,
three hours just went going to go to
sleep a little bit.
Oh,
well,
whatever do it will suck up your time.
It'll suck,
but you know,
I can't play.
I'm just,
I'm not good enough to play those kinds
of things.
Like it's just like spawn dice bond guy
can figure out how to do it.
You're a smart guy.
How dare you say that?
You put the limitations on myself?
Yeah,
you can't do that.
We just need to learn left wasd.
Learn how to move your fingers around.
The console's are bullshit.
I.
Lots of people say,
I can't get any real accuracy with a
console.
That's your problem.
How do you do with the finger?
That type?
I mean the console now.
Good.
I can send to you.
How do you learn physics?
How do you.
What is that?
All this fucking movie.
We were like,
you can do it,
man.
You can't.
It's like rocky or something that's
ready to karate kid or whatever.
Hasn't been ever done that for video
games.
He's never been that movie where someone
teaches someone how to play a video game
nerd in the beginning and he's like a
loser,
but you know it comes back and it gets
the girl.
Well,
one of the reasons why I wanted to talk
to you about this in particular is
because I am more and more convinced
that it's our future may lie in some
artificially created world and that
people are more interested and more
attracted everyday to virtual reality,
augmented reality,
virtual reality,
and what can change.
What was that game?
That one game where there was a,
you created worlds.
I was going to pull that up earlier and
ask.
It's called no man's sky.
Oh,
I
played that.
I played that.
I bought it because of course any space
game.
I'm like whoring though it is because
you know,
they have 80 trillion worlds,
but they're all this.
They're basically,
they don't look that different,
you know.
So it's like oatmeal,
$80,
million bottles
there.
You go there and people are shooting
each other and stealing money.
No,
no.
What is better for that kind?
Yeah,
right.
I mean it's,
you know,
it looked like it was people,
but what's better is I'm elite.
Dangerous.
So after this I was so disappointed in
this,
uh,
I went back and I found a leap.
Dangerous,
which is disappointing because there was
no action.
Yeah,
there was nothing.
You just ran around and your mind stuff.
It was sort of like,
it just wasn't nothing exciting.
There was nothing exciting.
There was no,
there was no,
like I said,
I don't usually play sort of these
massive multiplayer games.
So this is elite.
Dangerous is elite.
Dangerous end of this man.
The trading or you know,
you can decide like,
oh I want to be a,
I want to be a bounty hunter,
you know?
And it was so rich.
I just,
I spent.
There was like a good six months of my
life that I was working my way,
getting better ships.
I became because who doesn't want to be
a bounty hunter?
Right.
You know what I'm saying?
Like that's what everybody's and this
just this game had you know,
and there's like,
I don't know,
a few hundred thousand people in there.
You're creating the universe.
It's evolving.
They add storylines.
So you know,
while we are setting up an htc vive here
and we're,
we.
Danny was htc vive,
how dare you.
I know man.
It's like,
you know,
you call your nerd,
um,
they will never not have sex in virtual
reality.
It's,
and it's consumer virtual reality when
my friends never done the boy.
Yeah,
I know.
I've been waiting.
I've been sort of.
Well,
we tried to get one.
Jamie went out yesterday and look,
they're all sold out so we had to order
one and so we're ordering one.
We're going to have it set up in here.
Um,
and the,
uh,
the Games,
I played the games of two years ago and
I'm sure they're way more advanced than
they are now.
There's a crazy archery game where the,
you're on the top of a castle and these
little monsters that look like they
could be in south park.
They're not like detailed,
right?
Kinda cool looking monsters and you
shoot out on with bows and arrows that
are trying to invade the castle.
But man,
it's addictive because you really look
down,
you see them all around you.
You have like a real.
So how did they know?
Just always been my question about like,
you know,
I sit on my chair and I play my video
game.
So like our.
Yes,
see this guy has a thing in his hands
and he's moving around.
This is like a star wars one and there's
a bunch of different ones that I've
always got to be standing.
Right.
In some sense.
Yes.
Do you want to just like sit down with a
borrower and Ken,
but there's also a boxing one that you
get a real workout in.
So it's a game and I played it over
Duncan's house.
We think there's a video of it,
but it's weird because you punch wrong.
So like,
um,
the like if I'm holding my hands like
this,
which is,
I'm holding my hands vertically where my
thumbs are up,
right?
The boxing gloves would be horizontal,
like they would be if you were punching
someone.
So.
So it doesn't do the turn.
No,
it's weird.
So as you move your hands forward like
this,
which you really wouldn't punch like
that,
the punches come out.
So they've got an iron that I was going
to say that'll be something that'll work
out and that and make the,
the controller rotate the way a fist
would.
But as you're doing it,
you throw real punches and someone's
throwing punches at you and when they
throw punches you and they hit you,
you see a white flash in front of you.
That's good.
Makes you nervous.
Just like real sparring does.
Well,
you know.
And so like this question of like,
what are we going to do with virtual
reality?
Because like I said,
you know,
I already,
I see huge potential for like education
in gaming and that's why we built our
games.
Yeah.
Here's,
this is me over Duncan's house.
Just the one anybody to walk by.
You know,
I got to go get a beer.
Bam.
I'm beating this guy up.
Moving around them.
See,
that's the thing I've always wondered
because that guy was fucking duck enough
everyday.
It's like,
dude,
how did you.
I'm just like,
move around,
don't stand right in front of the rope a
dope.
Well,
you gotTa,
you gotTa have footwork and movement,
but you can really get a workout with
that.
I'm not joking.
You get exhausted and you know,
you,
you keep going and fight a tougher and
tougher opponents.
Well,
you know,
that's.
And that's the way,
you know.
So like talk about haptic suits.
Like eventually you know,
you're going to wear things.
I didn't see the,
I read the book but I didn't see the uh,
what was it?
The movie ready?
Set.
Ready player one.
I didn't see it either.
I didn't see you.
Have you ever read the book?
The book's really good because the book
is like full immersion.
Like the whole book is about like when
virtual reality is it and so everybody
has these suits that,
you know and you're kind of in this
ball,
you play the game and so he can run and
you know,
um,
but in some sense,
yes,
we're just starting out along these
lines.
Well,
they have these places you can go that
they have a warehouse set up and you go
inside of it.
And I went through one with my kids and
it's a star wars one at Disneyland,
Dude.
It's fucking why you go across.
You're walking across this platform like
they have all these different places
where you actually walk through and as
you're walking through,
you looked to the left and to the right
and there's fire,
but you feel the heat from the fire.
It's fucking crazy.
Like heater set up.
So that blows up.
And Storm troopers start shooting at
you.
This is it right here.
What is it called?
The void.
Yeah.
And um,
you do this,
I'm telling you man,
this is better than any of the rides at
Disneyland and it's just outside of
Disneyland in downtown Disney.
So you don't have to pay to get into get
it.
But it costs,
I think it's $35 for a half an hour.
It's not cheap,
but it's not too bad.
It's not too bad.
Like it's fucking awesome.
I mean it is awesome.
So.
So the question is what happens with the
future,
right?
Because you have virtual reality.
We're just on the cusp of,
right?
We're just beginning to like start
playing around with these technologies
because people have been saying it for
years and it kind of sucked.
It was sort of clunky.
Well,
we're,
we used to play Pong,
right?
That's what I started with.
I'm a 55.
I'm 50,
so I remember Pong.
We were excited.
I can't believe I'm controlling the TV,
making the thing move on.
The TV or asteroids flew the Star Wars
game,
I think it was called asteroids,
but you flew through the trenches
fucking wire frame,
but it was amazing time.
Dropped a lot of quarters.
Sure.
So go from that to what you were showing
us here with these crazy new space games
and then imagine what these mean.
The Star Wars thing today.
The void is really cool,
but you know that it's not real,
but it's cool,
but you know,
it's not real.
Well,
you're not going to be able to tell.
It's not real and 20 years.
Yeah.
Right.
And how much time are you spending suit,
by the way when you do this?
Oh really?
You know,
there's the pressure of you and you feel
that when you getting shot,
wow.
You feel like,
you know,
it's funny,
even with the controller on my crappy ps
four who,
um,
you know,
when it vibrates,
when you,
to sort of give you,
it's amazing how much the brain sort of
picks up on these signals when you're
using the htc vive and you draw the
Arrow back.
When it gets to the nocking point,
you feel it like it's cool.
You release is a feeling in your hand
seeing the Arrow.
It's really cool.
Yeah.
So what happens when,
you know,
right.
I can be sort of like,
you know,
Grandpa,
but like terrible people shouldn't be
going out in nature,
which I think they should be.
They should,
you know,
now.
Um,
but,
you know,
I always,
I'm always aware whenever I'm sort of
like,
oh shit,
this is gonna be terrible.
I always remember the whole you can see
in like,
I think at some point,
socrates,
2000,
five years,
500 years ago,
it was like,
Ooh,
kids to do the robots.
That's all right.
Um,
so,
you know,
who knows what we'll do with it and you
know,
hopefully,
you know,
maybe it'll help,
maybe.
I don't know,
I don't want to be like,
oh that's terrible,
but there clearly are going to be
dangerous with this.
A different game.
Jamie doesn't new one.
Oh boy.
I'm going to be fucked.
The.
Yeah,
just the hands.
Yeah.
And so your,
you have two little hand controllers and
one of them would be the Arrow and the
other one would be the bow and you were
them and that's the haptic part in
Italy.
There's controllers on them.
Well,
you feel the Arrow vibrating against the
riser of the blow as you draw it back
to.
It's really cool.
Well it's funny because you know,
we've talked about like,
you know,
for the game that we built,
which was awesome.
It was really a lot of fun to actually
go through the process of like,
how do you know,
how do you script it,
how do you teach people,
you know,
like,
because that whole thing that when we
get into when you're a good game,
right.
You know,
when the first couple hours of a game
and you're just learning the basic stuff
and you get excited like,
oh,
this is,
this is a cool world to be in.
Um,
but I'd be interested to think sort of,
you know,
at some point to try vr for the same
thing because what you want,
you can have people be tacked on.
They're not just sort of in their head,
what else can you do to show to show
them,
teach them things you know,
like glaciers or you know,
mean.
Sure.
Well that's another thing in Disneyland,
they have a thing called soaring over
the world that you sit in a chair and
you get raised up and there's a giant
like imax style screen and it flies you
over these environments.
It's incredible.
So beautiful.
And you have different smells are in the
air and the different places that you go
to.
Like when you go over the Allergan.
Yeah,
the elephants.
You smell grass and hay.
And um,
I think that it's just a matter of time,
like as we were talking about before,
where biological entities might not be
necessary for space travel,
you might be able to send a robot put on
a suit and be able to
experience these worlds like in real
time.
Yeah.
Well,
um,
so,
you know,
the simulation argument,
maybe the philosophy arguing about the,
you know,
and so that's a really interesting idea.
Should we just run through it for people
who don't know it?
So I forgot who it was.
Nick Bostrom now,
maybe not Brandon Carter,
you know,
there's this guy philosopher came with
this brilliant argument for like why
we're probably a simulate.
We're probably somebody else's
simulation self-aware simulation.
And the idea is like,
look,
if you get one,
you know,
we've been talking about like
civilizations when they get a million
years ahead,
what can they do that they're so
powerful?
They can build computers that can
simulate reality,
like fully simulate reality.
We're like,
you know,
just like in the matrix,
you have programs that are self aware
and so,
you know,
once they get to that and they start
running simulations in the world,
right,
it's cheaper to run.
It's cheap to run simulations.
So they just run trillions of them.
Right?
So the idea is that from that argument
there's more simulated realities then
there is the one real reality.
So odds are right,
you know,
if there's a trillion simulated
realities in one real reality,
you're probably in a simulated reality
are we a,
you know,
everything like right now you,
and I think this is real,
you know,
but what we are is an incredibly
detailed and we are self aware programs
in,
you know,
silicon matrix of,
uh,
so that argument is brilliant.
I mean,
you know,
just from the,
just from the point of view of like
numbers.
Yeah,
there's lots of reasons to say that's
not possible but,
but it's,
you know,
raises this issue of like,
yeah,
what is simulation?
But if you were in a simulation,
the whole matrix thing,
if you were in a simulation that was
that real,
how would you know now how could you
know they're going to be if you allow
technology to continue,
right?
If we keep moving forward at an
exponential pace,
there's gonna come a point in time where
we have something that's
indistinguishable from reality.
So how do we know that we're not already
in it?
Once we're in it,
will we create another reality?
Will we continue to create simulations
inside of simulations?
So fractals,
fractals exist in nature.
They exist everywhere in the universe.
And there's,
there's also the argument that the
atomic structure itself might really be
a universe,
right?
Right.
Yeah.
Which is super standard talk.
But you know,
it's really.
I mean,
what,
that's why I love science fiction,
you know,
the explorations of these ideas,
I mean they're way out there and there
an exercises,
exercises and there's a way in which
again,
when you think a million,
2 million years in the future,
this is why I hate the loop this back to
climate change,
but just like God,
if we could just make it through,
who the fuck knows what we're going to
be?
Right?
I mean there's the,
there's the whole universe.
One thing I did like about interstellar
was the idea that like our future cells,
which have now become integrated,
the very fabric of reality,
you know,
that's how far you've evolved.
You become the laws of physics that
they're kind of opening up the wormhole
for us.
So,
you know,
a million years is so long as he knows
what we can become and it's just like,
you know,
don't hold this back.
I mean I'm,
you know,
I'm not a fan of the people that deny
science,
but one thing I am a fan of is watching
them do it.
I like watching monkeys throw shit at
the zoo,
just something weird about watching
people argue like really obvious,
right wing talking points and,
and,
and most of them by the way,
have no financial interest in climate
change one way or the other.
They're not,
they're not the wealthy elite.
There are these Weirdos that are like
vampire familiars,
like they want to be recognized as like
an eight,
an ally of the elite.
They think somehow under that that's
going to get.
That's really what it is.
Right?
You know,
and it's like,
you know,
and again it's the tribalism,
but as you said,
it's like watching them do this and the
part that's so frustrating is just that
like,
dude,
you're using science.
It's not fair.
Of course they're like,
oh,
you get like,
you know,
you get into an accident and you're
like,
Oh God,
please give me the MRI.
And then,
you know,
as soon as your arm healed,
you're going to be tweeting about how
climate change is all bullshit.
The earth is flat.
Yeah,
sure what to do with that.
I mean,
is this something we should pay
attention to her?
We should we just be like,
okay,
you know,
fine,
go ahead,
do your thing.
Isn't interesting.
Conversation with Neil degrasse Tyson
about it and he said one of the real
problems with debating these people
elevate their profile and they're never
going to believe in the first place and
the reality is there's a mental illness
involved in a lot of these people to
schizophrenia.
There's something wrong with them.
They believed this and then there's
this.
There's this massive lack of education
and lack of reading.
They're not interested in understanding
how they know that the earth is round or
how they know that every other planet in
the solar system is round or how they
know that every other planet that we've
observed,
all the stars are around why they're
round,
why it's a matter of mass and gravity
and all these.
They don't care about all that,
but what they don't want to think
because the government as if it's the
government is like one cabal.
That's what it is.
Equally minded people that are all
working together to fuck you over
somehow by convincing you that the earth
is round.
It is one of the dumbest things,
but it's also a sign that we've created
this world that's really easy to survive
in.
We've nerved all the hard edges and we
keep the wolves off the streets and
there's still these fucking dumb dumbs.
Uh,
and then they get online with computers,
which is hilarious.
Yeah.
So these idiots did research,
like what'd you looked at?
A website like youtube videos.
Two videos.
Yeah,
I mean it's,
it's,
it's kind of stunning.
Yeah.
Well actually,
no.
I think your point about actually we've
made the world so safe because yeah,
there's a certain way like it,
you know,
in a hunter gatherer or those people
would be food.
Those are the people who were standing
there looking at the tiger being like,
that's not a tiger.
Yeah,
exactly.
So,
uh,
so and it's right.
But what's weird about that?
So that is like the,
the,
that like that is the dumbest shit you
could possibly imagine.
So,
but oh,
there's dumber.
Oh Gosh.
Dumber people think there's aliens
underneath the earth and there's
Reptilians a secret cabal of kid fuckers
that run the world.
And you made
a really excellent point,
just admitted to go,
right.
Which is like the philosopher Karl
popper once said,
if there was a conspiracy,
it failed.
Right?
The whole conspiracy thing is that like,
oh yeah,
everybody's in on it.
Like,
as if like,
look,
there are the powerful.
They are the ones who control,
you know,
but they have their own agendas.
They're beating the crap.
That's the whole history of the world
going after each other left and right.
It's about finances.
Right.
And the idea that like,
oh,
somebody's gonna be able to keep this
amazing secret,
right.
You know about the earth is flat and
never.
I mean,
you know,
it just,
it gives people way more credit than you
know,
than,
than they deserved.
So you'd have to have everybody on the
same page,
all the different governments all over
the world.
They're all a lie about like where's the
benefit in lying about the shape of the
planet.
Right.
Right down the man was making money.
But,
you know,
here's what I,
here's what's really messed up is that
like,
you know,
climate change denial is just like a
slightly less wackadoodle version of
that,
right?
Because,
you know,
um,
uh,
there's a guy,
writer,
philosopher,
uh,
I forgot his name,
Morton forgot his first name,
but he talks about climate change being
a hyper object,
like,
you know,
that modern world.
We have things that are hyper objects to
me just so big that we just,
we have a hard time wrapping our minds
around them and that hyper objects,
you know,
if we're going to evolve,
right,
we're going to evolve new behaviors.
One of them is the capacity to deal with
hyper objects,
but people want everything to be simple,
you know,
I mean,
which cracks me up because they're fine
with this being complex,
you know,
their cell phone can be complex because
I like to use it.
But like,
you know,
the idea that like,
uh,
the climate change,
climate change,
they,
they need it.
It freaks them out because it's too
complicated or something.
So they go for the simple answer,
which is that it's a,
it's a conspiracy,
it's a hoax.
I love this one.
The scientists are all doing it for the
money as if my pay was that good that,
you know,
I mean,
I think a big issue happened with Al
Gore when Al Gore came out with an
inconvenient truth.
Everybody connected Al Gore with the
left,
he's a Democrat and then they found out
that he flies private jets and then like
this motherfucker like this is all
bullshit.
And so there was enough.
There's enough holes where they started
poking through and then looking for
conspiracies and then looking to deny
the whole thing.
I totally agree.
I really wish,
you know,
I got nothing against Al Gore but.
But I wish he hadn't.
I wish he didn't become the face of
climate change because it just pushed.
I mean I've only,
you know,
Neil degrasse Tyson or Sagan was still
alive or you know,
had done it.
It would've been a totally different
thing because it wouldn't have happened
it off of it in an extreme way.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't know.
I don't know what,
but,
you know,
pull up this article,
Al Gore may be the first,
um,
climate change billionaire or green
billionaire that he's,
he's made so much money doing these
seminars and speeches and the film
itself and they're doing this film,
right?
And then people,
I think it actually came out.
It didn't do that well.
And then people in the amount of
reading.
I think.
So I thought I saw Al Gore could be the
world's first carbon billionaire,
formerly vice president become the
world's first carbon billionaire after
investing heavily in green energy.
That's okay.
That part's okay.
Because if he's investing in these
companies and the companies start making
money,
which like already so sure,
solar employees,
more people now than cold does.
That's amazing.
Well,
coal,
but that was one of the dumbest things.
When,
when trump became president,
I got to bring back coal,
like how about bring back knocking rocks
together,
start fires.
It's like fuck man Cole.
It's as if the typewriter companies got
together and made sure you never bought
a computer.
Like we're going to computers illegal
because you got to keep using
typewriters.
Fucking terrible anymore.
It's like,
you know,
it's just,
but listen,
I got it.
One thing that you always got
acknowledged is that like this,
you know,
when you change infrastructure is people
are going to get hurt.
You know what I mean?
Like I mean for those coal miners,
man,
that's what they've done their whole
life.
It's been an honorable fucking thing and
they've,
you know,
so you can't just sort of be like,
hey,
we're switching infrastructure.
See Ya.
You know,
there's gotta be some deep understanding
of,
of navigate have consequences and
helping people who are going to be,
you know,
put,
train them how to put up solar,
you know,
solar panel.
How do you feel about universal basic
income?
Have you ever looked into.
Yeah,
yeah,
no,
I've thought about that a lot.
You know,
it's a big thought and consideration
when it comes to automation technology
and you know,
with the automation thing,
it's so true,
right?
Because you know,
when you think about what's been going
on with the last election,
you know,
and everybody was like,
oh,
you know,
like you know what's happening with blue
collar people workers,
which is totally true,
but like man,
it's not China,
it's automation.
Right?
And that's what really is going to screw
up the whole nature of work,
you know,
for everybody from truck drivers,
even to meet a university professors is
we got this,
the Ai,
you have the automation coming on and
write what do you do?
What are you doing here as a university
professor?
Is One day going to be retro that kids
are going to want to learn online,
they're going to want to learn through
some sort of an interactive course so
that you can get on your phone rather
than go to an actual physical place.
It's possible,
you know,
I mean it's possible,
but I think,
and this is going to be the whole
question with the new economy or
whatever,
whatever happens,
whatever we're moving into is finding
those places where,
you know what,
I don't want a machine,
right?
I mean,
so right now like,
so when the,
what is it,
the moocs came out the massively online
courses,
you know,
that was like five years ago.
Once I catch it,
universities are done and everybody's
going to take these online courses and
it never happened.
You know,
because people want to be together.
They want to learn,
they want the experience of happy,
you know,
my part of my students,
it's not just lecturing them,
agree,
lecture.
My students are probably.
I bet you are man,
you're a good talker.
I had one student say,
I,
you know,
the,
the reviews you get at the end,
the guy said,
hey,
I hate to say this,
but you know,
you should make those tapes for people
to go to sleep because every class your
voice.
And He meant it in a nice way.
He's like,
you have a nice voice that's passive
aggressive.
So,
uh,
fuck whoever is,
um,
I think that,
uh,
I think people will always,
with education,
there'll be some component of it that,
yeah,
sure you can learn it online.
Went to,
but I think like,
you know,
we're going to have to,
they'll,
there'll be,
there'll be a place for like people
coming in and like learning in groups
and somebody who has spent their whole
life studying the thing,
telling you,
you know,
what's going on,
right?
Like there's a lot of things were like,
and we've lost a lot of this.
I'm a mentorship or apprenticeship,
right.
There's a lot of things she needed.
Somebody who knows,
you know,
who spent their whole life going,
oh,
you know,
you crank it this way.
Not that way because you got to get that
way.
It'll never work.
You know,
you can't learn that from watching a
video or something.
Well,
there's certain things.
A martial arts,
which is a big part of my life.
You have to learn from a person can,
you got to have tiny things that they
must show you while you're doing it,
but you can learn a lot of things from
videos.
No doubt.
Yeah.
There's a lot of things that people are
putting up online,
instructional courses and stuff and I
use some of them,
you know,
if I have to fix my sink and we're all
going.
Oh,
for sure man.
Yeah.
It's kind of amazing,
you know,
so,
I think like with everything,
so we'll circle back to the UBI.
Um,
you know,
like with everything we're going to have
to invent new ways.
We will because we're just human beings.
Like there's a way in which we're going
to find,
you know,
niche places that there will be
economies where people make things.
But yeah,
in the end,
I mean ubi may be necessary.
I think it may really be necessary
because if there's no work,
you know,
I mean that's a recipe for disaster for
your democratic society.
Know.
Yeah.
Just hope we can move past this idea
that everybody who needs that as some
sort of a welfare brat.
Yeah.
Right,
right.
Well,
you know,
once there's no work at all,
I mean they're good because like,
you know,
this is the thing that I like with a
self driving cars.
Right.
So I asked this question a lot and I've
written about this sort of like,
okay,
everyone's like,
we got to have self driving cars,
we're heading toward self driving cars,
self driving cars will destroy the last
good blue collar job in America,
you know,
truck driving.
Right?
And that's a really good livelihood for
a lot of people.
And it's like,
oh,
we're just gonna eliminate it.
It's like,
why do we have to like,
okay,
yeah,
there's,
you're telling me there's got to safety
sake.
That's what they say,
right?
But in total it's not entirely clear,
right.
You know that,
that,
that will work.
And I,
you know,
what are the for the,
for the lives that are lost in the
driving,
I mean,
you know,
the car crashes,
is that going to be worth the social
upheaval that comes from not having any
work anymore?
So I mean just like they're these huge
bearing down on us.
If it's your friend or your mom or.
I loved ones.
Yeah.
But these are the kind of calculus.
I mean,
you know,
if,
if it tears down,
if the,
if wiping out these jobs destroys
democracy,
right.
And you end up with really though that
doesn't seem possible.
I just think that what it's gonna do is
gonna make travel safer and then we have
to figure out,
well these jobs that people got from
traveling,
how do we replace that?
That income.
Right?
Well,
one of the things is we're going to,
we're going to have to start teaching
kids to be creative.
Yeah.
That's the niche that I think there's
going to be places where like the now
you'll have.
So listen,
I'm not arguing that we shouldn't have.
No,
I know you're not just being,
you're just looking at all the
variables.
Yeah.
And I'm asking like the CA,
you know,
we're moving so rapidly into this new
world,
right?
That like who's deciding for us,
who's deciding
that we want cars and we're told that
we're going to get it.
But like a lot of these things I think
there,
you know,
there needs to be a little bit more
dialogue,
democracy rights and having this stuff
shoved down our throats and told like
it's the best thing ever,
you know?
Well,
you know,
how about Cell Towers?
They're fucking everywhere.
I mean there's no getting away from it
if you could.
I mean,
is there a community anywhere that has
made some sort of an agreement?
Will there be no cell towers in our
community?
No.
But there are communities that have
decided to,
like in the southwest that no lights,
no lights at night.
That's amazing because they wanted to
preserve their nights guy.
We should really have some sort of a day
where everybody shuts everything off,
sees the sky and see how crazy it is
that we live in this weird state where
we're on an organic spaceship flying
through infinity and we don't see that.
Right.
Because,
you know,
if you're wanting to do backpacking or
something,
you're in the back country,
you know,
a couple of days.
You notice things changing like Oh,
the mood's not as quite.
Yes.
And so nobody looks up now on your right
because there's nothing to see because
you don't see anything because the light
pollution.
I went to the Keck observatory and the
big island.
Have you been?
I've never been.
I'm a theorist.
I don't do it out.
Nobody's going to get me close to a
telescope.
Could fucking just.
You don't even have to go all the way to
the observatory.
The visitor station,
which is,
I forget where it's at.
I think it's 14 or 12 or something like
that.
It's really high.
Right.
But there's.
They have diffused lighting,
all of the big island.
So there's no light pollution and when
you look up it is just stunning,
right?
You look up your leg the Milky Way,
right.
And most people have never seen the
milky way right there.
Look,
I thought you have to have a telescope
to see out.
No,
it's right there.
And you feel like you're flying through
space and you have this,
this really humble feeling that I think
people get into a couple of different
places.
People get when they live next to
mountains,
they get it when they live next to the
ocean,
but you really get it.
If you could see space,
and I think one of the things that is
haunting the human race is the arrogance
of humans,
which is compounded by the fact that we
can't see the cosmos,
that we only see what's in front of us,
so this is the world that we live in.
We put a roof over our head.
This is the box.
I've got my blinders on.
I'm moving ahead because I want a new
lexus or whatever,
you know,
whatever it is,
whatever material thing you're trying to
possess when this,
this unstoppable force in front of.
When you look up and you see the cosmos,
it's like it's an undeniable reality and
you go,
oh,
okay,
okay.
This is just a small thing.
My existence is just a small thing in
this mystery,
this giant mystery of what we just found
out 20 years ago.
There's plant itself,
right?
I mean,
this is a giant mystery.
You're looking up at a hundred billion
stars in this galaxy alone.
Man,
I couldn't.
You're speaking my language,
I mean the,
you know,
the loss and the myth that the capital m
word,
right?
So I'm a scientist,
I'm an atheist,
but I believe in mystery.
I believe that that kind of at the core
of our lives,
it's just,
I wake up everyday to forget here and
I'm not going to,
I'm going to be here until I die and
then I have no idea what the hell
happens.
So,
you know,
and the,
as you said,
like mountain mountains in particular,
you know,
I would think for mountains,
um,
the,
the night sky is,
it reminds you,
it opens that space up,
right.
You know,
when you're sort of like,
you know,
and you're right,
you can,
you know,
we can talk about it or you can,
you talk about it,
but it's really,
it's an experience.
It's the experience that just shows you
your part of this.
It's more than you put your,
you're here and you know,
and I think,
right,
a lot of the stupidity of the modern
age,
you know,
as you said,
the consumer is in particular.
All that matters to me is getting my
next pile of shit.
Um,
when you're out there,
you realize who cares,
you know,
who freaking cares,
like,
you know,
for a moment even you just get the sense
of that mystery and it can be
transformative.
You know,
I think what's happening is we've
created these civilizations as
civilizations need to be lit up.
The lights keep us from seeing the
universe.
The universe humbles us,
so we're not humbled.
Then we moved towards acquiring physical
possessions,
material objects because we think that
that's going to make us happy and our
entire society is geared towards
innovation because everybody wants the
newest shiny shit that is,
that is what's leading us to artificial
life and that all this shiny shit is all
innovation and it's eventually going to
move to this one singularity.
And that singularity is some new being.
Yeah.
So it's funny because,
you know,
one thing when I think about like all
these other,
you know,
my,
my argument,
all these other civilizations is that,
you know,
whether or not you make it maybe that
the evolutionary heritage you get,
right?
So we evolved from,
you know,
both chimpanzees or the chimpanzee
ancestor in the Bonobo ancestor.
So we've got like,
we fight,
we're hierarchical,
very hierarchical,
right?
Um,
so,
you know,
we've got a lot of aggression this,
but we also got the vanilla both kind of
like this,
just have sex,
everything's cool.
So we're like,
we're sort of,
we've got this really weird mixed
evolutionary baggage and whether or not
you can make it to the next side with
the existential challenge of trigger and
climate change is kind of like a,
what your evolution evolution gave you,
you know,
because you can imagine species like
hive minds,
you know,
if you came from termite and intelligent
termite species,
it might be a lot easier to deal with
climate change.
You're like everybody,
you know,
get on the,
uh,
get on the courts.
Um,
but uh,
most essentially is,
can you evolve new behaviors,
right?
So we've been on this track and it's
leading us in a way that,
as you said,
you were,
it's like the shiny thing dangling in
front of us is leading us off on this
one track.
And the question is,
can we evolve new behaviors,
which I actually am going to say this,
I think they're,
part of it is spiritual,
you know,
or at least in my atheist way of
reconnecting with mystery to see like,
uh,
you know,
we're part of this and we need to
respect it.
And you know what,
when you say spiritual,
what do you mean?
So in my first book was about science
and religion.
You know,
I'm an atheist,
but I'm not Richard Dawkins atheist.
I think that whole idea is the
difference.
Well,
you know,
Richard Dawkins is what I would call a
strident atheist and he's like,
Yo,
anybody who has any spiritual or any,
you know,
any inclination towards mystery is an
idiot,
you know,
and she needs to do LSD,
right?
In sf or Dmt,
robin or something that just gives you
an experience
of mystery.
Right.
Exactly.
You know,
so I've been doing zen meditation for
like the last 30 years,
you know,
and like,
so I've been staring at a wall for 30
years and the first thing you learn is
it's really boring.
And then the second thing you learned is
that their stuff onto your thoughts.
You are not just the shit you're
thinking,
you know,
there's just sort of settled down and
there's just like this openness,
you know.
And so,
um,
the spiritual part,
it's like you said,
you know,
when you're in the mountains,
right?
So I love doing back country hiking and
union.
When you get above tree line,
there's that weird thing that happens
when you're above tree line and just
like,
you know,
you got this panorama around you and
that thing is,
you know,
the earth,
right,
of which we are part and you know,
so this is an interesting question about
how can virtual reality do this or do
you actually need to get out there and
kind of think you need to get out there.
But maybe virtual reality can give
people the impetus to get out there.
You know?
Well,
it'll be a different experience.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with the virtual reality experience of
being in the mountains.
I think it'd probably be pretty fucking
cool,
but it's not going to be being in the
mountains.
Something about being in the mountains
is also,
there's a,
there's a weird feeling,
and I don't know if it's real,
but there's a weird feeling that there's
no signal out there in the places where
there's no cell signal.
There's no.
There's a feeling you get when you are
absolutely not connected.
Yeah.
And then you see wildlife and the
wildlife out there.
They're almost like these mystical
beings,
like when you see a deer step out of the
tree line and it's like Hashtag.
Yeah.
That thing has been that way for a
million years.
That's that species has not changed at
all in a million years.
And the signal what you talk about the
signal lights,
it's really the thing is what for me
it's like when I get far enough back
that I know that there's just not
another human being,
you know,
this just like when I leave this exact,
it's going to still be happening.
Like it's doesn't give a shit about you
and it's just moving along and as you
say,
it's been moving this way for millions
of years and you just realized like.
And that's why,
you know,
part of the thing I'm saying with the
book is that like,
look,
if we trigger climate change,
that's just the earth way of like
creating the next set,
you know,
it used us to create climate change to,
now move onto something else because
that's what the earth does.
It's just this animal power,
you know,
and when you're out there you feel that,
um,
you know,
on the thing that I think we need to do
is sort of,
we established our connection to that
were part of that were from that we're
not evil,
we're not bad.
We need to reintegrate ourselves in a
way that we still get our civilization.
But you can.
That's what I mean.
So you ask why spiritual?
Because when we connect to that mystery,
then we're in a better place to make the
right decisions to understand what the
decisions are.
If not,
we're like,
oh,
we've got to save the polar bears and
we're not looking at.
No,
no.
It's the biosphere as a whole that we
have to understand well,
operating out of ego and ideology and
not out of rational thought with all the
information at our disposal and really
verifying that information for
understanding what's correct and what's
not correct and whether or not there's
bias behind it or scientific research
that was funded by people that have a
vested interest in it leaning one way or
the other.
Right.
All that stuff is very,
very slippery,
very dangerous,
and when you find out that studies have
been influenced,
special
interest groups or lobbyists or whatever
and that they,
you know,
like especially pharmaceutical studies
of the creepiest where they,
they can do a series of studies and only
one of them show some sort of a positive
impact for whatever weird reason and
that's the one they use and they don't
have to publish the fact that they ran a
hundred fucking studies.
Right.
Do it.
I try and teach people.
I'm sorry,
go ahead.
No,
no,
go ahead.
Yeah,
I think the most important thing that
people need to understand about science,
it's not so much sciences results,
but how science works,
you know,
because it does work,
right.
That's why we have all this stuff and
so,
so they can distinguish.
So I,
you know,
I say that science is three things.
It's spitballs supertankers and
stadiums,
right?
You know,
the problem with the news,
there'll be like the latest study shows
the color red,
you know,
will make you have better sex.
It's like,
you know,
then it lets the latest study that can
get you to click on that USA today or
the media reports.
It's as if this was science,
like every day a whole bunch of new
articles come out.
You know,
I write scientific articles,
that's the currency of my profession,
but like one study is,
is just like,
it's a spitball,
right?
It's like basically we're shooting
spitballs at each other,
but science is like a super tanker,
right.
You know,
we're like,
it takes seven miles to turn a super
tanker around.
That's what really science is the things
that we think we deeply understand.
Science is like the super tanker and
people are shooting spitballs at the
papers every day and if you get enough
spit balls on one side of the,
you know,
the prow or whatever it starts to turn
it right.
So the science will turn slowly if
enough of the spit balls are lined up.
So people,
you know,
it's not about the single study,
it's about have there been 300 studies
over the last 30 years that say the same
thing?
So like,
yeah,
the coffee stuff,
coffee's good.
Coffee's bad.
Clearly the fact that we keep getting
both answers means we don't know.
That's all we don't know yet.
It's just not clear.
Climate change 30.
Not even 30 years.
A hundred years of the same results.
Yeah,
we got that.
You know,
well there's always a problem with diet
in that you're not taking into account
how nutrients interact with other foods
or different foods interact with foods
and different.
You know,
you know,
when you say coffee's bad.
Okay.
Was it bad when you're smoking
cigarettes are bad when you're eating
grass fed meat or bad when you're on a
Vegan diet or when is it bad?
Right,
right.
Who are these people and what are they
putting in their system and how much
sugar are they taking in and how much
sodium and you know,
what,
what's the nutrient levels,
their blood.
Did you test them for b12 deficiencies
and all these different things.
Like that's the real problem with any
dietary studies.
They don't take into account the
extremely varied diet of and the
complexity of the system.
Right.
So that's,
I mean,
so I would tell people that like,
you know,
when it comes to like health sciences,
anything in general about human beings.
Look,
this stuff is really complex and as you
said,
there's a thousand different things that
can interact.
So you gotta really take that stuff with
a grain of salt.
Like okay,
does smoking cause cancer?
Yeah.
Got that.
You know.
But like yeah,
it's coffee,
good or bad.
We just,
the studies aren't there yet,
but that's different from climate change
or you know,
a gravity,
you know,
or is there an round?
Yeah.
Those are,
those are stupid.
So I'm.
Listen man,
thank you very much for being here.
I really,
really appreciate.
It was really good to talk to you.
Is Fun.
Do you have an audio book out?
A.
Yeah,
there is an audio book.
Did you read it?
I have not read.
Did I read that you read the words that
are in the audio book version?
Did you,
were you narrating it?
No.
No I didn't.
God dammit.
Sorry.
That they didn't talk.
Man.
Did they have been really animated and I
hate that when I really.
When I buy audio books and I know that
the guy who's reading it doesn't have a
fucking single bone in invested in this
idea that he's saying he's just
repeating the words.
Well the guy,
I'm sure whoever did it was like,
you know,
totally channeling.
I must've felt it in the astral plane.
You'd be better if you read it,
man.
They should have let you do it.
Why the fuck didn't they let you do?
Just don't push for it.
Oh No,
I didn't even know.
You know that part of the.
No,
I didn't.
I didn't understand.
Part of the publishing.
Tell people the title again,
a light of the stars.
Alien worlds and the fate of the earth.
Don.
Don,
your twitter is Adam Frank for why?
Four?
Because that's the only one.
Everything else was taken.
So I was just like,
I got to come up with a six years ago
when I got on Adam Frank for.
And do you have an instagram as well?
No,
no.
I have a facebook author page and
website.
A website is Adam Frank Science.
I think if you just Google Adam Frank.
Thank you Adam.
We really appreciate it.
So much fun.
Really Fun.
Bye.