The general good experience,
I told my dad,
I wrote my dad this letter recently,
this getting real deep,
our number three of the podcast.
We get real deep.
We're pro nuance.
I'm ascending to my dad,
but he won't listen to this book.
I wrote this letter that was like,
listen man,
because I,
I had seen recently like his developing
relationship with my son and like it
shot it,
put this thought in my head that,
you know,
my relationship with my dad,
the kids caring for me.
The fact that he stayed with my mom and
they developed this like place for me to
grow and nurture me and allow me to
become a person in that environment.
Like there was a north star for
me when I left that environment.
Like I always,
I never wondered what
my path was going to be.
I always could look up and be
like that bond that I developed,
my family,
their love for me is like
the thing that I'm always,
you know,
I'm looking back too,
but also looking forward to.
Because that's what defines me
and regardless of what I do,
I can always fall back on that,
that my dad loves me,
my mom loves me,
I love them,
and I grew up like with the strength
of soul because I knew I don't have.
I have friends that came from
the same place that I did.
Same town.
I didn't Marilyn that odd on heroin.
They live in the same little suburb
suburbia community that I did.
They had parents that were the same age.
They went to the same high school,
they lived in the same environment.
They went down one way.
I went down another and I truly do feel
that that me going down that way was the
way that my parents like built
this structure around me.
That was always a route,
that bond and that love and
the things that that's very,
very fortunate and I.
and that's what in that me
being able to later on in life,
see how fortunate I was to
have that drove me to not fail
for someone like me.
It's so interesting to know that
there's still a considerable amount of
speculation.
Yes.
Oh yeah.
Well,
it's,
there's a lot of speculation,
but it is pretty off the wall and then
other people who think mine are off the
wall,
who's to,
who's to say,
okay,
I'm um,
I don't know man.
Okay.
You know,
did decent things in the past,
but you should just trust this abuse now.
So I guess that's what people think.
I don't know,
but you see,
if it was just me,
I could understand that,
but I've got these posts and I have a
colleague who's done things on this too
and it can't be that we're
all a little off the rails.
I think.
No,
it can't be.
There's something out there and
now with their hawking points,
there's something people can really go
out and look for and if they don't see it
in,
there's something funny
going on somewhere.
If they do see them,
there's something else
going funny on which,
which they'll have to think
of another explanation,
unless it's my explanation.
They'll have to think of a different
view from the current conflation view,
which is in real trouble
with these observations.
As far as I can see,
there is hate speech in the world isn't
you know you don't want it on your
platform,
but you got to decide what is hate speech,
when is
it really hate speech and
when is it just ignorance,
and sometimes the best way to combat bad
speech is to let that speech play out
and let good speech overwhelm it with
logic and reason and a better argument,
right?
That's really what freedom of speech is
supposed to be all about that we work
all this out.
As soon as you start censoring voices
and telling people that you're not going
to allow them to talk,
boy you,
you start,
you create this atmosphere where you
can start to choose what you're going to
allow through and when you're not going
to allow through and then you're gonna
start censoring things
that are far more subtle.
You're going to start censoring things
that you know they don't seem reasonable,
but you've decided that
it's already okay to sensor,
so you've censored this person,
negative sensor.
The next worst thing,
you're going to go down the line until
it's just people that disagree with you
and then you're like,
oh,
well my world is perfect now when in
fact it's actually just a bunch of people
that are talking shit about you.
Would you use just don't
happen to know about it.
The dove,
the Dove Company,
they're probably their most successful
campaign of all time has been one where
they argued that beauty
is a social construct.
You're all beautiful in your own way.
Now that again is a beautiful message,
right?
Because if,
if I am someone,
if I'm a woman who doesn't score well
on the typical evolutionary cues,
then what do I want to hear?
I want to hear that there is no
such thing as evolutionary cubes.
It's all socially constructed,
right?
If I have sagging breast,
if I have poor skin and so on,
if I have wrinkly skin,
I'd like to believe that there is
no such thing as an universal beauty
standards,
and in that sense dove has been incredibly
successful because by peddling false
hope,
they've actually been able to tap
into women's insecurities and incense.
That's good marketing,
right?
The cover of Cosmopolitan magazine that
was widely criticized because they had a
morbidly obese woman on who
was a bikini plus size model.
Yeah.
And they were challenging beauty norms.
Like this is a person that's
eating themselves to death.
You've got fucking assholes.
And so your lack of discipline and your
desire to shame people who exercise and
is what you're doing to make them feel
bad because you feel bad that you can't
put the fucking cook cookies and cupcakes
down as a lead you to try to push this
ridiculous standard.
And one of the things
my point of view was,
could you imagine if the cover of men's
health had an enormous fat guy with his
gut hanging over his belt and,
and people were saying the new standards
of attractiveness for men have been
changed by Mike who just drinks
beer and eat cake and be like,
get the fuck Outta here.
That's never going to fly.
It's not going to fly with men,
but it does fly with women.
Right?
And
by the way,
the fat acceptance movement doesn't
just argue that you know not being 500
pounds is unattractive
because of the patriarchy.
They actually argue that the medical
evidence suggesting that there is a link
between obesity
and downstream bad
effects is all bullshit.
They not,
not just that they there,
they also point to one incredibly flawed
study that has been wildly disproven
that says that there's some sort of
vigor or vitality involved in being
overweight because they get sick less.
There's no,
no truth to that whatsoever.
They only,
they only analyze people who
were healthy at the time.
Like it's,
it's,
you can go and Google the study and
find out the criticism of that study,
but it's 100 percent horseshit folks.
Being fat is not good for you.
It's really bad for you when you're
as big as that woman on the cover of
Cosmopolitan magazine.
She's literally morbidly obese.
She's fucking dying.
She's addicted to food in a horrible way.
And to promote that and pretend that
somehow or another this is okay,
and we're gonna.
We're gonna show new standards of beauty.
You Go,
you giant gelatinous
bag of meat and tissue.
No,
that's a dying person
who is addicted to food.
She doesn't want to look like that.
Most of my friends,
we all got busted for
drinking and driving.
The best one was a buddy of mine.
They read his was like,
you know,
approximately four in the morning.
We noticed a Maroon VW,
Fox blowing its horn,
trying to pass on the right.
We pulled the defendant over
after repeatedly asking the
defendant to stay in the car.
He got out of the car,
threw his keys at my feet
and repeatedly stated,
lock me up.
I'm fucked.
And this was funny was my
buddy was a good look can guy.
And the judge was a,
was a woman and when the guy read that,
you know,
lock me up,
I'm fucked up.
And he wasn't the brightest
guy and he just kind of,
when he went like,
Ugh,
he's like put his head down like that.
And he was,
you know,
little pound puppy fucking looking dude.
And she,
uh,
she,
she gave him like a lighter sentence
and because he was good looking.
I think so,
yeah,
plays in because my ugly
people are complaining so much
they won't take the time to
develop a fucking personality.
Right.
Some jokes do it.
The rest of us have to do like
I don't get mad at Brad Pitt,
you know,
and have it be fucking because
he's fucking beautiful.
I'm a fucking bald redheaded mail.
I know where I am in the pecking order
in some of these fucking people who
planning right now who are mad that
beautiful people get treated differently.
I understand racially speaking,
but you're not going to
do the beautiful thing.
And then that's another
thing they tried to say.
Well Society tries to,
you know,
they're the ones that fucking like,
like I love when like
there's a supermodel,
like the,
this is like an impossible standard
of beauty to try and live up to.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's why she's on the
cover of a magazine.
She's that level.
Beautiful.
And you're going to try and sit there
and tell me that that was learned.