Good.
Five,
four,
three,
two
[inaudible]
motherfucking warehouse traveler shift.
That's such a nice way to start dude.
Cause you did one of the most puzzling
and fascinating and admirable things any
of my friends is ever done.
Well checked out.
You checked out for four months.
Really checked out.
You got rid of your phone,
you didn't answer any emails.
You're like,
I am going to disappear for four months.
You didn't even give it time frame.
No,
he just said just,
just going to go.
Dude said one to three ish.
Um,
I don't know.
Maybe too,
Just we'll see.
Did you get the inspiration from the
Henry Rollins podcasts?
I was already going to do it.
Wow.
Yeah.
What?
He said like come see me at a December.
I think he was having shows that Largo
and I was like,
oh,
I'm already going to be,
I think I'll be gone by that.
Wow.
I was waiting until I finished off the
work I had to do through my special.
Right.
Um,
you know,
finish up a season that show just like,
just like get up,
get up.
So I'm not like just leaving every,
I'm not sure spelling anybody.
Yeah.
You know?
Right.
Chappelle.
And he played her
dude that rollins podcasts you did was
one of my all time favorite ones of
yours.
It's great.
It's Barbara Wells out there though.
Your podcast is great,
but it's really good.
It's really good.
It's one format,
the trust.
Fucking great.
It's great.
I love your intros.
You know,
you're sucking cooking onions and just
talking.
It's so raw.
It's a really good podcast,
man.
You,
you've done an amazing job with it.
But I liked your music selection.
They're not guests.
Yeah,
no,
you're,
do you do a great job with it?
Like whenever the guest comes up,
I was like,
okay,
what kind of fucking song is he going to
play that it was,
I just did one with him about to having
diabetes and um,
and uh,
he was like,
did you put,
pour some sugar on me at the beginning
of it is about diabetes.
Like,
yeah,
you gotta you gotta have something like
that goes,
that's hilarious.
Working grows one of the most underrated
guys out there.
I've seen him kill at the comedy store
lately.
He kills a lot enough for people.
I've always said,
can you not put me on after him?
Yeah.
He's one of those guys.
He's a funny dude.
Very funny dude.
Good guy too.
But um,
yeah,
that rollins thing.
I did see you some of that while I was
out there that when people say like,
what are you doing out here?
Yeah.
Um,
I tried a few times,
I'm like,
I'm here to meet you.
And it just gets a conversation going
because they want to know.
I think with him it was more his
celebrity booth.
It's just like you're white.
What do you,
what are you doing here?
Right.
What are you doing some small town in
Nowheresville.
Did you feel threatened anywhere?
Um,
any sort of threatened I,
this is a good question.
And He sorta like threatening I felt was
just me.
Um,
it wasn't real.
It was me looking at people that don't
look like me and going,
oh,
I'm scared.
You know,
there are others.
Hmm.
And then you find out like,
like me and mark is,
I mean 90 something percent Buddhist.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's a massive,
massive part of their culture.
Is that where you went first?
Yeah.
Why'd you pick that place?
The best weather.
Oh,
I got my ticket the day before,
so I just didn't want to go somewhere
where it's going to rewrite in.
Wow.
So me and my had 10 days to clear and I
was like headed to me in more I guess.
Wow.
Yeah,
it was great though.
So what do you like,
what do you do?
Like how do you set this up?
Do you set up the region?
A region?
Yeah,
it kicked out of South America and
Southeast Asia.
He just decided like that looks like a
good time.
Yeah,
exactly.
I would love to go to Europe.
Fucking backpack around Europe,
but not genuine non January and February
now.
It's not an enjoyable,
whenever I think of Europe,
I mean even though I've been to Europe
and I love it,
I think
World War II movies.
Yeah.
Them having to like the buckers freezing
food out of cans,
hearing bombs go off in the background,
just coming down from the ceiling.
Well,
you know,
I was thinking the other day when I was
looking at all this crazy shit that's
been going on in England,
these terrorist attacks and uh,
what happened in France and I was just
thinking how long that section of the
world has been in turmoil.
I should always fighting.
Always fighting.
Yeah.
And then I was thinking that like
America is one of the only places where
very little shit has gone down.
Like little things have gone down there.
There were obviously big at the time,
like Pearl Harbor is huge at the time,
but very few.
And then nine 11.
And other than that,
it's like,
Whoa,
boy.
What else?
And then you look at Europe,
like,
Holy Shit,
dude,
there's a part of France that's the size
of Paris that you can't go into because
there's so many bombs.
There were so much munitions from the
world wars.
Oh really so bad that they have like a
area,
the size of parents' minds and stuff.
Just musicians.
Just fucking missiles and shit.
Things that were flying there that
landed things,
things that blew off all sorts of
chemical waste.
Oh Dude.
It's toxic.
See if he could pull that up.
Really?
Me?
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
I feel like it's outside of Normandy.
I forget where it is,
but there's a section of,
of France that is literally the size of
Paris that people can't go into for like
a hundred thousand years.
Oh yeah.
Just cause it's all this like chemical
waste just because of all the waste from
the bombs and all the different fucking
missiles and rockets out guns and shit.
Dude.
It's crazy.
Wow.
But obviously I don't have the facts in
front of me until Jamie it up and I'm my
shit.
Shitty memory.
But I know that this is a real place and
I know that there's leftover like wings
of plans.
I think it's mostly like things they
shot at each other and unexploded,
some of them on unexploded,
some of them exploded.
Like the waste from them.
Oh yeah.
Here it is.
This is a map of the space.
All these fucking bombed.
That didn't go out on the cobblestone
streets.
They'll get those things,
dude,
these are all bombs that didn't go off.
That guy's there.
Yeah,
with that guy knows what he's doing.
He's just touching it.
They pulled that one.
Ask God.
Imagine if it went off right next to the
water or water area.
It says founding contains certain toxic
levels of arsenic that were 300 times
above.
The tolerant tolerated amount and a
abnormally high lead levels were
recorded in some animals,
particularly in the livers of hunted.
Wild boar.
They buried it all.
I think it's just there,
man.
I think it did just have this area.
I don't think they burry.
It looks like they put it under under
mountains of dirt.
Is that what's going on?
And then shook.
Grew.
Does it say that?
No,
because mountains look like that.
I don't get up to the top.
Cool freaking no go zone of France
forbidden.
No Man's land poisoned by war.
Ooh Dude.
I mean look at that guy with the gas
mascot.
That is awesome.
Yeah,
it is up.
There was up to is.
Why does it even look a little bit so
clearly?
It's not even like it's like chalk
paper.
It is a dope picture.
But I was reading and looking at the
photo.
I was that guy in a gas mask.
Oh that's not a real picture
dude.
I've seen some tattoos recently.
People on instagram.
That's one of the best things to
instagram's for cats.
Tattoo artists.
There's some people that have done these
super realistic photograph tattoos that
are just flat out fucking freaky.
They can do flat out free tattoos.
I've seen those.
Wow.
Incredible.
Godly.
Yeah Dude.
Tattoo artists.
Like all artists I guess or just because
of the Internet,
but yeah.
And then they're taking things to
another level because they're seeing the
level of all these other people in like
a guy in Germany can compare itself for
the guy in Japan and the guy in America.
Yeah.
Like Jesus Christ.
God Damn Hat.
It looks like a skin is falling off.
Yeah,
there's a lot of fire was great.
Really good tattoo artists out there
right now.
Really good.
Some hot chicks getting them to,
yeah,
like all over the place.
He says,
and guys love that.
Uh,
I'm one of those guys.
You know why?
Cause you know she's dangerous.
That's how reckless gow Johnny Depp
tattooed on her foot.
You know
that girl's crazy.
Like girls like love and hate
on their hands.
Like,
okay,
here we go.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's like you're on a roller coaster
rides glen.
Click,
click,
click.
And you're at the apex.
Yeah,
you can never just have a nice quiet
dinner with a girl like that.
Yeah.
It's got to be on every night.
Something's thrown at your head.
Oh girl has Los Angeles tattooed across
her stomach.
Whoa.
Yeah.
No,
in like that Gothic,
like a gang sign that's behind your ear.
Face tattoos is when you're really
making a commitment.
That's a weird one,
right?
That's like,
I'm willing to like some people get,
I'm a little crazy.
It was like a leave.
What types?
Yeah.
Well how about Gucci Mane got a fucking
ice cream cone tattooed on his face and
it says burr rarely.
Yes,
dude.
He got an ice cream cone tattooed on his
face and it says birth.
We are our our call
this,
I'm not kidding.
He's not like an ice cream guy though.
I like his music though,
but it's not all about ice cream.
Look,
God damn.
Wow.
It says Burr burr and then the meme
spelled [inaudible] wrong.
Does lightening bolts off the ice cream
cone?
I feel like that was put in later.
No,
I think that was the same time.
Ice Cream and ice and lightning.
Yeah.
Ice Cream in lightening.
That's real.
That's his tattoo.
The this case like three scoops of ice
cream.
Oh,
good for him.
It's give me a hard fight for him to
find a job though.
Yeah.
He doesn't have a job.
He's a rapper.
He doesn't need a job.
I mean,
okay.
I don't want to see inside of the lip on
the inside of the lip on,
it's weird.
It's like I'm going to swear right free.
It's that.
Yeah,
it's out of the way.
I sneaky freak my freakiness inside my
face.
There's no versions with tattoos.
Well,
I'm sure there must be.
Maybe.
I'm sure there must be,
but not really though.
It's not even unusual.
We don't think we would.
It a little bit about asexual.
People do believe in asexual people.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
definitely.
Right?
Yeah.
I've seen a couple.
Some people just don't touch,
don't touch me.
Thanks.
Sorta of thing.
That's a horrible word to stamps.
I have.
It's not like they just are antisocial.
They just don't want to play.
You have no interest in it.
Yeah.
So what about them?
Oh they,
what?
Did they get?
Tattoos?
Yeah.
I don't think it ever happens.
Wow.
You're a,
so there's a tattoo is stick to like
commit to it.
Yeah.
Opinion.
Yeah,
exactly.
Does it matter if I didn't research it?
Sure.
You're not even totally sure.
A hundred percent short man.
Wow.
It's just doubling down.
Interesting.
I like how you did that.
You've raised your voice.
Yeah.
There's something about movement.
Have you seen this fucking video?
I don't know if you know what's going on
in a evergreen college.
Do you know where Evergreen colleges,
evergreen state college in the north.
It's in Pacific northwest and there's
this crazy shut down.
I this professor on
the podcast because they,
um,
the kids had asked him to not show up at
school and not know why people shortage
because yeah,
they wanted a a day where whites didn't
and he's like,
that is the opposite of inclusiveness.
Like this is,
this is not what we're supposed to be
doing.
So they kick him out,
right?
He's instead of saying,
no,
how about everybody day?
Well,
this is what they did.
They didn't really kick them out.
What they did is they protested,
they yelled and screamed and he felt
unsafe and he left the college and then
the college got shut down due to shut
down.
Oh,
really?
Threats.
Yeah.
People would call it in.
They even played the threats on the air.
What did we threats with the,
he was already gone.
No other people called in like threaten
the college.
Yes,
because like right wing people called,
they called them a bunch of commies.
The left like a voicemail saying I was
going to come,
I'm going to come down with my 45 magnum
you that's know too far.
Yeah.
44 magnum,
maybe 44.
He specified the round,
which I thought was hilarious.
Like the exact type of gun.
I have to come with a shotgun.
I know it's just a game like,
um,
but uh,
anyway,
the college professor got in trouble
like talking to these kids.
They told him to put his hands away
cause he was gesturing with their hands
and there was,
there were yelling out that it's a micro
aggression and they got him,
they got him to put his hands down and
then they started laughing at him.
Oh Dude.
It was like put your hands up,
fight,
see if he could find it.
Jeremy was,
I think his bladder aggression.
I think I,
I'm trying to figure maybe Bret
Weinstein had it queued up on his,
um,
his twitter page.
He's the professor.
That word by the way,
it was dead on.
It's just the connotative meaning now
it's become something super negative.
Microaggressions,
micro aggression,
not even a small aggression.
Well it's like the smallest possible
thing you can think of in terms of
aggression and you're like,
okay,
sure,
whatever.
But if you watch the video of this guy
is just moving his hands,
he's just talking like this and they're
like,
put your hands down at your hands are
aggressive,
let's do it.
And then they laugh at him when he
complies.
They openly mocked him and laugh.
We're fooling with it.
We didn't really believe that we turned
it into a cook there little kids,
these are little kids that you're,
you know,
when you talk to people who understand
how brains develop,
one of the big things that they always
say is the frontal lobe.
The frontal cortex doesn't really
develop until you're like 25 it's not
fully developed there.
They're just,
I was in college.
I understand.
Yeah,
we're not going to power.
We're learned a few things.
We don't know how to put it into play
yet until you just say it.
And that's by the,
by the way,
that's my theory and why people send
their kids away to college.
It's because they're fucking
embarrassing and they don't want them
anywhere near them while they're trying
to grow into real people.
Oh Wow.
They're learning stuff and they're like,
wait,
we don't have anything grow.
Think does that.
Oh yeah.
A little bit.
Also they say for the experience of
going away,
but like,
no,
it's like,
hey fucking be an awful developing thing
away from me.
Go embarrass someone in Wisconsin.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Here,
this Nyu girls talking all the time.
I stand behind them and like listen.
Oh yeah.
You know the conversations,
girls and boys,
you know,
mostly girls you create,
I mean,
you know,
he creeping sort of short,
obviously super into that,
but like,
uh,
but yeah,
they're just dumb.
They're dumb when you listen to them and
you're like,
you're just well read and dumb.
Well,
there's a lot of people that,
I mean are 18 years old and you have
very intelligent conversation with them.
I'm sure.
Some,
yeah,
there's a lot of medicine and there's a
lot of people who are 18 who are
basically 12.
They're basically like a grownup baby.
It's not their fault.
It's no one's fault,
you know?
It's just,
uh,
take some people longer to kind of get
how to,
you know,
sort of factor all the aspects of life
together and make it some sort of a
manageable plan for yourself.
Live your life.
But the idea of those kids being able to
run that,
that principle and run that,
the president of that school like that
and just tell you,
put your hands down and laugh at him.
Dude,
they laughed at him.
I heard a few smart people going about
trump and people like small hands,
you know,
and the,
and the left we'll,
we'll attack that.
It's like,
oh he got a small dick or your master's
here.
And I saw one,
I think,
I forget who comedian I used to open
mikes with any show writer.
Now I forget who it was.
But um,
she was like,
don't say that.
Don't take their tactics.
Don't say look sir,
an important thing here.
Yeah,
that's,
that's that we believe in.
So stop saying that.
Not only that you're going to shame the
shit out.
All those guys that are out there that
actually have small,
her point was like,
don't,
don't just cause you know,
that will affect him.
You're doing the same thing.
The right does.
Don't do that.
Yeah.
He's not amazing though that that is
what we decided to do as a collective
group of humans to find the thing that
you can mock about him physically.
Like his Dick is little,
he's got small hands,
look at your small hands and then
there's people in the audience and
actually have small hands.
They're like,
fuck trump's a big giant guy.
Is it really tall?
He's like six two,
he's probably like your height.
Oh Wow.
He's a big guy.
Like he's a big imposing guy.
Like if you see that's,
that was the one of the speculations
about Jim Comey that um,
James Comey that trump didn't like him
because he was six foot eight.
Oh.
Cause he's huge.
James Comey was like this giant
basketball player.
Like,
dude,
you're like,
yeah.
And he just towered over everybody
including trump.
Trump's like,
get rid of that fucking guy.
I'm sure it was more card is my,
because he's investigating.
But that's more of shaming.
People love to do that.
Oh,
you tiny little man.
Yeah.
It's weird because you,
you're attacking something that's the
person can't change at all.
Like what do you like?
What do you care if he had small like
look how big call me.
It's called me.
He's a giant.
Wow.
Super person
who's going to size it morphs everybody.
Oh my God.
He's huge.
He didn't ignore this guy.
You know,
you,
I,
if I was Donald Trump and I was in this
sort of a dispute with a guy like that,
I said,
yeah,
you grew.
I would worry about,
call me running for president.
Really?
Fuck.
Yeah.
Watch house of cards,
son.
I know how this game is playing.
The next move is called me,
runs for president.
A bunch of people that get in the room
with him.
This is bankers and this was one dude
who's an internationally successful
businessman,
but he keeps like a humble lifestyle and
a normal house and he likes to bird
hunt.
Hey,
everybody watching at home right here is
what Joe Rogan explained to me.
How it works in politics,
not back to the actual show.
Yeah,
they do a little too much of that.
Sometimes the camera,
they get away with it sometimes.
Here's what I want.
I want Claire Barnes to do those every
now and then was Claire Barns I Claire
Underwood.
Yeah,
his wife.
Yeah.
I want his wife to do it.
I say under what?
The second time,
but I said the second time.
Who the hell's Claire Barnes?
Who reporter is that the girl's name and
homeland?
I've run out of space in my head.
I don't have any jumbled together.
It is it.
They're all jumbling together.
13 Zoe bonds.
That's who it is.
That's right.
Clear under what I want to hear.
What she,
what she says.
Yeah,
she's not allowed.
Why doesn't she look in the camera?
Look,
she's mysterious.
They have that as directors cuts show
him.
We network on the we network.
It's only the women up points of view
they have to or take us chromosomes
before they'll let you watch it.
You hold onto your remote and test to
make sure you're double x?
No.
Why No?
Why
we network.
Does anybody watch that anymore?
Chicks?
Yeah.
I got some people like hallmark.
Nobody really watches either of those
though,
right?
Nobody really watched it.
Somebody watches.
But nobody really dude go to Nebraska.
But like they watch it more than like
NBC Day Dvr the shit out of it.
David Taylor once said he was trying to
write,
they were buying like dump scripts for a
hallmark channel and he said he'd
watched a research,
a bunch of them and he goes pretty much
every one of the movies that work,
it's about a pet,
um,
a family reunion or a holiday.
So he had a,
uh,
lost my dog,
Christmas time,
a movie that he wrote,
try to get,
he was like,
I'll fill all of this stuff.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
Those,
the,
remember that,
um,
billboard across the street from the
store was always the hallmark channel
forever two,
one of my favorite comments you ever
made because it was just like cop show.
Whereas to a woman in the front woman
behind her.
I kinda like Charlie's angels a little.
It took him tough like a dude way,
way in the back.
Maybe three women to one guy,
but the other good hardnosed detective
and you're like,
hallmark channel is Psi Phi for women.
Like in what world does this exist?
This is,
I forget.
It's so true.
I was doing that on stage for a while.
Yeah.
Now that I'm remembering I was doing
that.
I'm saying that on stage because it was
right there.
A series of fucking billboard across the
street.
I need you to go out there and look at
it.
I'm telling you after the show,
look at it.
This job's going to be better after the
show.
It really was like,
see what's possible and you're like,
that is not possible.
The guy would be like,
give me the fucking gun.
Where is he
at?
Guys like hanging back there.
Like he's waiting for these chicks to
save him.
Fuck are you watch on.
Me and Jay went on a rabbit hunt over at
his place of looking for videos of women
cops getting beat up.
Oh God,
they're awful.
It's like fuck cause a huge power
difference here.
Oh,
disturbing.
There's one,
I'll never forget this one because the
guy's child,
it was his child I think,
or his girlfriend.
I forget who it was.
I think it was his kid was screaming at
him to stop,
stop,
to stop.
And he was beating the shit out of this
cop.
Yeah.
He got out of the car with her and it
was a woman and she was really little
and um,
she was pulling him over and he got out
of the car and I don't remember the
exact chain of events,
but I remember he was punching the fuck.
He Kod already on the ground and he
smashed in the face a bunch of times.
Yeah.
And His kid was screaming,
I'm pretty sure it's his kid
screaming to stop hos.
Oh.
So scary.
But it was like,
this is the reality of being a cop.
Let,
this is why it's not sexist that think
that it's a scary thing to have a 130
pound woman on her own out there driving
around in a cop car with a gun trying to
pull over six foot four.
The guy was a stacked looking black
dude,
like he looked like a big guy and once
he got ahold of her and start punching
her,
Holy Shit Dude.
It was awful.
He beat the shit out of her and he did
it super easy.
And you realize like once you got it on
video,
yeah,
we want to show a little of a choke us.
It's awful man.
So this is big dude,
right?
He gets out of the car and I think it's
his look at that.
He just punches her in the face and
don't get in front of his daughter.
Oh,
that's what it was wailing on him.
Oh Dude.
He beat the fuck out of her.
Well,
she's old.
She's out cold and he takes her gut,
takes everything in.
The daughter is freaking out,
dude.
It's hard to watch.
Get back in the car.
Oh yeah,
man,
there's a bunch of a man.
It's such a dangerous job 10 times.
It's such a dangerous job.
And to say that it's too dangerous for
women,
whose to say that's,
I don't know,
to quit after that,
if she kept working,
I think she kept working.
I don't know.
I think she might have brain damage
after that.
That's horrific.
It's a big dude.
And I bet she was twiggy full.
Yeah.
I mean he's really,
and I bet she was totally defenseless
after the first punch.
So it was just colleen clean punches
right to the face,
boom,
boom.
Put me the damage that a big guy like
that can do to just a regular female
face.
What's,
I can't with that because daughter too,
bro.
Oh my God.
It's terrifying to be around that kind
of violence when you're that little.
So that's,
that's what it was.
Why I think that the video showed the
kid in the car out of the car.
Shit,
man,
it was terrible.
But I mean that's probably one of a
hundred of those things that have
happened by the way,
in terms of if I felt unsafe when I was
traveling,
that shuts here.
Sure.
You right?
Yeah.
No,
I was known as unsafe.
It's like Chicago.
Yeah.
That's what I say about Mexico.
Like people will like,
do you ever go to Mexico?
And Mexico is like mostly Nice,
nice people.
They're really nice people.
Like Mexico is not the problem.
The problem is parts of Mexico border
towns,
some.
Yeah.
But it's also like that's the problem.
Like you said with the Detroit,
that's a problem with Chicago.
It's problem with a lot of places.
There's spots where it's fucking
dangerous.
Even most of Chicago's good.
Yup.
But Chicago's great.
550 murders last year,
but sick pick how many people weren't
murdered to marine outlook.
You're a glass half full kind of
guidelines of not murdered people
running,
running Chicago.
Really enjoying their freedom.
So yeah,
I mean if it affects you or someone that
you love,
it's terrible.
For sure.
Yeah.
So in all this traveling,
did you come out of this with anything,
you know,
a few things for sure.
Cause you seemed like to tell you from
the outside you seem like almost like
you a
had a different purse.
You all's each seemed,
I don't know man.
It was nice to see you when I first saw
him when he came back.
But you seem like a little different.
He seems like you,
um,
I don't know.
You've seen another level of stuff.
Like you see you've got another level of
perspective from this travel thing that
like added to your,
your vision of the world,
your,
your overall world view with a lot of
time to think also he goes,
you're seeing stuff,
you know,
certainly as everyone would see out
there like poverty levels where you're
like,
oh,
I'm doing fine.
Yeah.
But not even that,
it's more specific.
It's just like,
I don't know,
friendly people and like,
yeah,
just different versions of it.
Plus with travelers and plus really
getting to a place where you're like,
don't need to do anything.
You know,
after a month of that it's like,
okay,
you just settle into this.
Like,
I dunno what's today going to bring
Ryan.
You know,
you wake up and you're just like,
I heard there's this cool temple there.
We'll go check that out.
Maybe those get on motorbikes and go
somewhere.
I heard there's a cool,
you just talked to other travelers and
black,
there's a canyon up there.
It's really neat.
Go check that out while you're here.
And so you just do.
And at some point like
you know how when you haven't got enough
sleep for like a few days in a row,
you got four hours,
four hours,
four as and you sleep like 11 hours and
you're like,
I am completely caught up.
Right.
So like not having any responsibility,
the stress level goes down,
down and then it's just like waiting in
that zero responsibility life for like
three months in that level I guess.
Wow.
You know,
after the first couple of weeks and it's
just like I don't have anything to do.
Just like,
oh,
I'm just like fucking relax man.
I would leave a city when it felt like
the right time to leave a city.
You know,
it wasn't even like a regular vacation
where you're like,
come on,
we got to do this,
then move right it reservation
somewhere.
Yeah.
It was just like relax and then I could
just think about things.
My art form in general,
people in my life,
you know what I want and don't want to,
I'd have like moments of just like,
hey,
take a 10 hour bus.
There's no Wifi.
No,
you're just like thinking for a while.
Okay.
Yeah.
Tons of moments like that.
How did you know when to end it?
Um,
so I um,
I was going to come back for this show.
Um,
but then I remembered my,
my manager,
my friend Eric,
they wanted to do a show at third man
records in Nashville,
uh,
for the,
for the wild west comedy festival.
And I forgot about that cause that
people ask me when do you have to go
back?
But travels,
I meet and I was like,
I'm open to,
there was so many people that are just
traveling open.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's really common.
I mean,
three months is like a norm.
You have some people in six months or a
year I've met,
I'm in an Italian girl who was going on
her five and a half,
fifth and a half years,
just traveling five and a half years
just traveling.
She find jobs every once in a while.
Wow.
Yeah.
And uh,
it's just
goes where she wants.
It's very appealing.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Very fascinating.
Right?
That's like nobody writes books about a
guy who stays in his town that he grew
up.
The book is about the crazy traveler
person.
Yeah.
It was all over the world and a backpack
and yeah,
there's three months people all over
America doing that.
I know there's a lot of tent people,
there's a lot of people that like
they'll get like a truck,
you know,
like some sort of a get off the grid tv
thing and they drive it around a camp
grounds and they camp and they use the
showers at the camp grounds and then
they do stuff enough for money so that
they have gas and they keep traveling
around and hope their car doesn't broad.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
This girl picked oranges and Sydney for
like two months.
I had this dude on Chris cage.
He walked the Appalachian trail.
Wow.
Yeah,
it's Georgia with animals and stuff.
I don't know.
How do you survive?
You will never make it.
You would never make it.
What do you mean?
Well,
you'd never make it.
If you're just trying to kill animals
all the way,
you'd never make it.
So how do you even have to be an elite
hunter and you still might not ever make
it because you're not.
If you're carrying that food around,
it's going to go bad.
You're walking through Georgia and the
summer.
No,
I mean,
you know critters credit.
Do you not going to get enough?
Just really.
Yeah,
you'll starve.
It's way harder to kill an animal and
people thinking in a movie,
that's,
that's what's camp.
Get some dinner,
dude.
It's way harder.
Yeah.
You're not getting,
unless you're walking around with
several high powered rifles and scopes
and you're setting up and know where the
animals are,
they,
here you come when you're walking,
you're not going to be able to walk all
the way to Maine.
Oh,
maybe that's your
stance.
You have to get our heads.
Bam.
They go to restaurants.
Yeah.
They buy food.
They stay in hostels.
You know,
they,
they have,
um,
these little,
uh,
camping spots where they have covered
shelters and people share them.
Really?
Yeah.
There's a lot of that too,
where it's just like,
oh,
forget about your,
like what you need in terms of like
hotels.
Yup.
That's all out.
You need a bed.
That's all you need.
So some people that carry it on their
back,
there's a thing called a bivy sack.
Every sack is a baby sack is like either
a baby Sacra,
Bibby tent.
Um,
they're like essentially like a
combination sleeping bags tent.
Oh cool.
And it's super light pull,
pull up.
Um,
a picture of a big tent.
Yeah.
That's one of the reasons I didn't go to
South America is cause I was like,
there's gonna be more camping,
it seems like up and down the coast and
stuff.
Yeah.
Like cities.
And I'm just like,
I don't know if I can camp alone for
that long.
You might freak out.
Yeah.
Be Hard to get a good night's sleep
around a bunch of Weirdos.
Speak their language.
This is what they look like.
Oh,
neat.
So you keep that thing,
they,
they wrap it up,
put it on their back.
It's pretty light.
Carrie,
that was the fucking rain off.
Yeah.
It's basically like just this tiny ass
little tent.
And like if you were a minimalist hiker,
like if you're,
some guy was trying to walk 50 miles or
something crazy.
Like these guys,
they try to carry as a light of stuff as
they can.
They try to go as minimal as they can
and that's one way that they do that.
Yeah.
And then a lot of times I'll use like a
little air mattress.
Like that dude has a little law.
Wow.
Blow it up.
Don't take up any space.
Yeah.
Just got to hope it doesn't pop.
Otherwise you're sleeping on rocks.
Yeah.
It's hard.
But that was what everybody did to
traveling for this backpack.
We just got to make it work.
Space was like a a,
that's another thing you learn too.
It's like I need much stuff.
Yeah.
You'd go down to like,
you know,
just the backpack full of hats,
all your belongings.
Did you buy anything?
You got to tow something about?
Yeah man.
Like there's a real movement right now
towards minimalism or where people are
trying to pair the life down as much as
possible.
Yeah.
I think people don't want to get
involved with like banks and fucking
having to like mortgage themselves and
their,
their lifestyle just for the sake of
having things.
Yup.
When they're like,
and so they get into like stuff like
camping and hiking.
Well it's also,
you got to think like what do you really
appreciate?
What's important to you?
Like what's really important to you?
Yeah.
Cause you don't have forever.
Right.
So what is important to you?
Cause you only have 24 hours in a day,
so what's important to you?
Find out what the fuck that is and do
more of that and try to figure out like
how to,
how to make enough money so that you're
not starving,
that you're doing well,
but don't just chase that chase what
you're trying to do.
I did the point system attached to it.
The monetary point system,
it can get you all fucked up because
it'll get you working like 12 hours a
day,
13 hours to get what?
To get more stuff to get better stuff,
to get more prestigious stuff to get
stuff that you know all your other
stuff.
Having friends are really jealous of
your stuff.
Yeah,
just going to die bro.
And it's not that you can log term.
I mean like what are you getting out of
it now that that's what's most
important.
Yeah,
a ton of people that are like,
I don't want that shit so I'm just going
to do a job.
You know,
working on a tugboat and Seattle for few
months,
save up money and then go fucking enjoy
myself.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people that are just
choosing to look at everything that they
can see experienced every new place that
they can go to.
That Henry Rollins podcast,
man,
it's a world changer.
That crazy fucker is fascinating.
He's a fast,
I never met anybody like him.
He's really fascinating.
He goes and does stuff and see stuff.
It was just also is lik outlook,
how he simplifies all the things that
are wrong with him and all the things
that are wrong with the way he interacts
with people.
And so this is an I'm going to do and
this is good.
I'm like,
you know,
like he's like his,
his um,
story about being given lose a Ritalin
was Ritalin right from the time he was
like five fruit as a young boy.
They gave him Ritalin till senior year
of high school.
So he was like,
I would just be on these pills.
I'd be like all day at the end of the
day,
like boom.
He was like crash.
And then they do it again.
I mean they were dead juicing them up
with this crazy stuff from like he was
an experimental case he grew up in,
from what I understand,
he's from Potomac,
Maryland,
which was same county is where I grew up
in.
But that was the richer part of town.
Um,
nothing was a rich kid,
but like Montgomery County is one of the
richest counties in America.
And like that was just a standard thing.
Like your kid's not performing.
Ideally he's learning disabled.
Give me some pills.
Right.
Crazy that people thought for that was
the way to go.
I just uh,
it just fascinating that he so like
Henry so intense and he so like his,
he's got like these rock solid test fix
and this view of the world.
It's very egalitarian,
very open,
but also very aggressive.
Very interesting.
This started out though,
it's just this is what I believe no
matter what.
Yes.
He was like,
Oh yeah,
for sure.
I thought about this and here's the
answer.
No,
I super enjoyed talking to him.
Thanks for hooking that up.
I'm glad it worked out.
I was gone.
But I was like,
hi,
I got back.
I was like,
trim it,
link up with him.
You're like,
yeah,
we did.
It was good.
Yeah,
I guess like,
Oh hell yeah.
Yeah,
it was really good.
He's a,
I just love when someone is just soaking
in as much as they can get.
Yeah.
Just out there like,
let's go to Bali and he just goes to
Bali.
Let's go to Africa.
Now we're in Tanzania,
lauer in Botswana,
you know,
and just meeting people and going out on
the fucking sand dunes and shit.
And it's like with Bedouins.
Yeah.
I mean if you get away from like the
backpackers path,
you know the tourist path and sometimes
it would get like too much,
but you just go out and then you can
like,
yeah,
I really see some shit.
Like basically what it is.
Yeah.
My friend Jessie is going back to
Liberia.
Wow.
December.
They'd left after it when Charles Taylor
was taken over.
Um,
and so,
but now it's safe again,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Wow.
And they're trying to convince the world
that it's like a decent,
like tourist place.
But Jesse's going back into town.
We're like,
dude,
I'm coming with you.
I'm staying with your fucking family's
House hotel.
But like let's see what Shit's really
like out there.
Yeah.
So let's see.
Yeah,
I bet it's a trip.
Yeah.
Did you ever see the vice piece on
Liberia?
Vice Guide to travel?
Um,
and they went to Liberia and my man
Shane,
he was over there in Liberia talking to
this dude who his name is general button
naked.
This guy was famous for going into
combat during the war,
but he would take all of his clothes off
and he'd run naked killing people.
Naked Dude heat.
He admitted he was talking about how
they would capture a child from the
other tribe and they would kill him and
cut pieces of the heart out and eat it
to give them a invincibility.
Like he was talking about this and he's
free on the streets and they,
they exonerated him because now he's
like a Christian minister.
Yeah.
It's pretty much the only Charles Taylor
got punished.
Everyone else was like,
you're all done.
Go be part of the government.
It's okay cause this guy like openly
talks about all the crazy shit that he
did.
Wow.
About cutting the hearts out of
children,
eating them.
You know how Libya was started?
Yes.
I didn't know that til recently.
Tell everybody slave thing.
Freed slaves.
Yeah,
there went back to chip president monroe
freed up and said we'll ship you back
there if you want.
And a lot of people are like,
yeah,
I don't trust you guys so I'm going to
guess I'm going to go back to Africa.
Crazy.
They never grew up and so they call it
the barrier for liberated and that's why
they all speak English.
It's there is no,
they don't have any African language
anymore.
Wow.
Yeah.
Monrovia is our capital President
Monroe.
The idea of it is so crazy.
I know.
Use the expression too much but going
back and starting up a free slaves
countries,
taking them and throwing them onto a
patch of land,
good luck.
I mean it's like setting out a zoo
animal into the wild.
Right?
It's like have fun surviving.
Holy Shit Man.
And just talk about feeling displaced
and confused.
You didn't even grow up there.
And how many lions in fucking Georgia
and you must be thinking of yourself
like what kind of shit?
Luck too.
I have,
I've double Shit La Shit luck that I was
a slave and then shit lock that I was
thrown back to Africa and to stick.
That might've been the way to go.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
It'd be free.
Better.
Oh yeah,
a hundred a semi free post slavery.
But I'm just saying like it's still a
bad
shit luck.
Yeah,
you only got three cards.
The best you can do is three of a con
would these general button naked guy
turned to dude in because the dude was
selling human flesh and he knew because
he had eaten human flesh,
so he knew what it tasted like.
So that's how when he was buying like
shish Kabob from this guy,
he turned him in.
He's like,
this guy was selling human flesh.
I could tell because I've eaten it
before.
What the fuck did you just say?
You can tell what it tastes like.
If I give you a piece of lamb,
would you know for sure that was a lamb?
I'd have an idea.
Yeah,
no idea.
But I could maybe sneak in like a piece
of wild sheep or something.
You might,
maybe that was,
you know what I'm saying?
Because this mother fucker,
no,
that's him right there.
He went flush.
Tastes like that's him right there.
A general button naked.
Wow.
Yeah,
it tasted,
I got a taste.
It was human.
I called the police.
Wow.
Nice.
Todd knows what human tastes like,
dude.
Yeah.
Fuck.
Just said they went on the test they got
when they were testing out like rocket
launches to sell them to people there.
They will be like,
let me show you.
And they're just blow up a dam,
you know.
And so the infrastructure is totally
fuck cause everyone is testing out their
weapons all like,
no,
we need that building.
Oh my God,
that's so crazy.
I'd be like,
cool,
I'll talk.
Take him.
Well maybe it'll eventually like calm
down and be like Australia.
Right.
Because Australia was a place where they
wanted to get rid of prisoners,
shipped him off to Australia.
Now the best people ever.
Maybe that's exactly what's going to
happen in Liberia and they just need a
couple of generations to knock the dust.
Got Rid of Taylor.
So there,
there should be.
Okay.
Yeah,
maybe that'd be fine.
It just takes a while to rebound from
some shit like that.
Yeah.
But Henry Rollins has that of like going
to a place and like,
let me see what this was like.
Yeah,
man.
Inspiring.
There's not a whole lot of people that
do it,
that's for sure.
Yeah.
Any works.
Like his work ethics,
insane.
Like I'm talking about his writing and
what he's doing and he's always doing
something.
He was writing columns and you know,
he's just,
he goes and does stuff and then he comes
home and takes care of business and then
he's like,
cool.
Took care of it.
Go.
I think I would do this again after my
next special.
Yeah.
He's just going to just every,
it's like once you're finished with
work,
it's like all right,
before I start building up again,
do a walkabout.
Yeah.
I Dunno.
So you didn't see some of the world.
Yeah.
Do a walk about,
I met a bunch of people doing gap years.
What's a gap here?
Yeah,
exactly.
What's the gap year?
It's all over every other country.
Just not ours.
What's that mean?
In between high school and college?
You're leaving your friends,
you're about to make new friends.
Oh,
take it out of here for a year.
In between college and Grad school or
college and,
and,
and your first year of work now is the
time.
Well,
European countries have a point in this
more relaxed approach.
Yeah.
To like the future and your life.
They really do this,
this conqueror's mentality.
I wonder how many heart attacks we have
in comparison to European people.
I don't know,
but it's like the world.
We're not living our lives,
you know,
Germans get off.
How many are you familiar with the,
uh,
vacation time leave in America?
What is it?
It's two weeks.
Pretty much two weeks vacation,
two weeks sick.
Do you get paid vacation?
Paid vacation?
Two weeks.
Is that standard?
That's the standard.
Okay.
That's nine to five 30,
you know,
um,
in Germany and most of Europe,
definitely all Scandinavia.
You get 25 days off,
five weeks,
Jesus.
And if you get sick during those weeks
off,
if you had to go to the hospital in,
in whatever country you're in and you
showed them I was in a hospital,
you get those days back,
they'll kind of get your sick time
instead and they expect you to take this
to the vacation time too.
Not like here with like,
come on,
you can't really use it.
You know what's fucked up?
Sick time.
Okay.
I've ran out of sick days.
Yeah.
It's like why?
What do you mean?
Like you're sick.
Like either you're a fucking liar or I
trust you now if I trust you,
you just really unfortunate.
And if I love you and we're friends and
we work together,
um,
I want you to get back,
so I don't want you to motto,
so,
okay.
Yeah.
You.
You don't have to come back to work
because they're already used definite 14
days,
but you're going to exactly sick the
same amount of time every year to
imagine telling somebody like,
buddy,
you're out of sick days.
I'm going to have to dock your pay and
you,
you're dying,
but I can't praise ivs and shit.
I don't care.
You're out of shape days.
The calendar doesn't say that.
It doesn't back you up on the other
statistics.
In order to keep revenue flowing,
it must keep you in the process.
You know what?
You have a certain amount of days you're
allowed to be sick.
That's fucking ridiculous.
Like hopefully there'll be zero.
Well,
I'm saving up my sick days.
What?
You save up your sick days.
What does that mean?
Like you're your sick days pair of carry
over.
Yeah,
exactly.
Get extra days where you can pretend
you're sick,
sick days.
You can save up vacation days,
but I don't think you could set up sick
days should be able to
move them around like cards who?
He's give you half of them back.
I took four.
I've tend leftover.
Give me five for next year.
People real jobs are so mad at us right
now.
Yeah.
You mother fuckers don't know shit about
sick days are work days to be under the
thumb of an oppressive dictator offsite.
It's terrible.
Yeah.
All these expectations that you never
take off.
You have to pull your whole life into
that shit and it's like,
Oh man,
go do some stuff.
Okay.
Let me play devil's advocate because if
I was one of the people out there that
likes to complain about,
should it be like though,
it's easy for you to say are you haven't
had a job,
you don't have the responsibility,
so I have.
Yeah,
that's true.
All right.
I'll be quiet and a podcast.
Not at all.
I'm saying though they'd demand better.
They get it better and other places they
absolutely should.
First of all,
Haitian that you go fucking see the
world and go do stuff for 40 hour work
week is bullshit.
Bullshit.
Shut up that level.
Nobody should do it.
I shouldn't be standard.
Everyone has to do the same amount in
less.
I want to buy something that you make,
then could you please like get up and do
over time and put it in night shift and
give people a time and a half for
overtime so you encourage them to go
over time?
Yeah,
time and a half you can get out of the
mindset of having to work this time.
I just demand something better or more
interesting for your life.
Well,
it's just a weird standard that we've
all accepted pretty much across the
country.
Nine to five.
Nine to five [inaudible] morning Bob.
It's not a five 30 or six oh yeah.
If you want to take a lunch break,
we'll get paid for that anymore.
You don't know.
It's not nine to five anymore.
Is that trump?
Did he do this?
No.
It's been a long time.
Nine to five and Oh shit.
Nine to five.
Could you imagine what a weird,
weird decision to make the most
significant thing be the productivity.
It's pretty new on a month.
Where's that horn going off young,
Jamie,
you hear that?
Is it in the back?
Just give it a little double check.
Go through with a baseball bat,
tell him to shut the fuck up,
but like walk towards them and walk out
there with your Dick in your hand.
That way you startle anyone you see.
And you always have the first mover.
Yeah,
exactly.
They had to react like this guy's crazy
came out with his dick out.
Yeah.
Like if you,
if you're getting ready to fight and you
just come out holding onto your Dick,
people are like,
Whoa,
what's he planning?
A lot of people would back down from
that fight.
A lot of people wouldn't,
people would be worried that Dick would
touch you,
but once it did touch you,
we realize it really doesn't do
anything.
But to be the chief people would have to
like lean back with their hands forward
and try to get as if your punches don't
matter.
But the dick touching your toes.
Yeah.
Like he's going to touch you and give
you cooties.
Yeah.
Because the happy,
you look at like an electric eel Dick,
I gotta pee right here.
You know,
I don't want to leave.
You can use a Kombucha bottle.
Yeah,
man.
It's the healthiest probably.
Look,
I've done this twice.
Really?
Yeah.
We've done this in the podcast before.
Great.
For sure.
I like the fact that you're willing to
do that too.
I don't think we could show it on
youtube though,
so we'll have to,
we'll have to move away.
Oh,
he's got his dick out.
Got a big opening.
Yeah,
so it doesn't vacuum up.
How often?
DUP DUP.
Several Times.
Every day.
Do you like one of them are healthy
water drinker dudes.
I pay a lot.
Do you?
Are you a healthy water drinker?
Dude?
Interesting detail.
This just happened.
Oh,
you ran out.
Don't know.
Uh,
hold on one second.
Jamie.
Go to the recycling.
Get me something.
It's all right.
I'm pitching.
I've got a strong grip.
Everybody.
You can move all I have to take it to
touch the bottle.
A cop,
not a bottle.
He's like,
oh man.
It's going back in though.
I can feel it starting to swell back
yet.
That's,
that's unhealthy.
I've been pitching too long.
Should I pay under the cup or bottle
yet?
Oh,
you emptied it.
thanks for that.
Oh yeah.
A lot went back in and my urethra are,
you should fear,
uh,
couldn't hold in his Pe,
ladies and gentlemen,
couldn't means wouldn't filled up one
Kombucha bottle.
Here's a cap there,
felon,
and then filled it up again.
I had to go empty it out for him.
Thanks for doing that.
I on the front.
I didn't want to leave you hanging in
there,
dude.
Really?
There was only one solution.
I almost went to the kitchen sink and
then I put it like,
Ooh.
Then we'd have to rinse that out and
show it would be nasty.
Did that bathroom sick is nasty.
You're don't have a cleaner in here.
No.
It's like,
it looks like a bachelor.
We're on their way out of this.
Oh Man.
I was like,
it's not that bad.
You're just got used to it.
You've slowly seen it get worse and
worse.
Gas Station bathrooms.
Trying to recreate that here.
I should definitely have someone come in
and so fucking far nine.
Uh,
do you,
um,
do you like doing your podcast?
Like the way you're doing it?
You just like have a subject?
Yeah,
for the most part.
I mean,
you can deviate once you start talking,
but you have like a set thing that you
wanted to talk to someone about.
Yeah.
Keeps me focused.
And then it's also like a,
I get to ask real detailed question
myself.
I want to ask about,
you know,
um,
and usually I get it with some level of
expert,
not like the best in the world,
but someone has experienced with
something,
right?
Like I'm an expert on standup comedy,
you know,
I've been one.
Right.
So if you were doing that,
I could tell you all about standup.
I know more than most people in the
world,
you know about hunting more than most
people,
you know?
Not really.
Yeah.
But you've done it more than like words
in the average person,
but people who actually know it.
I'm very novice.
Right.
I'm always aware of it enough to be
like,
yeah,
I know about that world.
Yeah,
I know.
Tell me some stuff about that world.
Yeah.
So yeah,
I liked doing it that way.
But then like,
imagine if a five year comics started
talking about what standup is shut up.
But knowing,
boy,
it does take a lot longer with stand up
to like with hunting.
Really?
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm a five year a hunter,
so for me,
I just shut the fuck up and listen to
the people that actually know what's
going on.
Or Parrot,
they say it's too complicated.
A hunt hunting is a super complicated.
There's a lot involved in that.
Yeah.
But generally it's like Theo Vaughn
climbed Kilimanjaro.
Teddy really are up to base camp or
something like that.
Oh,
he's great.
He's so funny,
man.
Yeah.
He's really hilarious.
So funny.
He had,
I was in the back of the,
or the other night and he was killing
me,
killing me to a point where I was,
I was crying.
Tears are rolling down my face.
He was so silly.
That pit a bit.
Uh,
yes it did.
It did.
Yeah.
He's,
he's real funny.
He's really funny.
Like,
if you get a chance to see him,
folks,
if you're out in the road,
unless Ari's in town.
[inaudible] was an impression of him for
punchdrunk Desi,
yeah.
Will just come in and sometimes you to
do del Ray.
He just like,
Oh,
I'm talking about the yoga.
It doesn't so go with that accent heads
Larry.
I know.
That's part of what's funny about that
too as his dog scent.
He's just fucking great.
So many funny guys.
They're mad.
That's what he did.
He stayed at my apartment one month,
I think it was an Edinburgh last year.
So he stayed at my place and uh,
he was like,
aw man.
All right.
I got heavy into coke.
It
fucking nuts.
It's hilarious.
Boy,
that's a clean better than anybody
else's stay there.
Yeah,
but duck had left it pretty nice too.
Yeah.
Dot.
They kept me out a little bit.
Is that I was like talking,
you can stand by it because he was
moving to New York.
Right.
Then he was like,
oh,
don't get an airbnb.
Just stay at my place.
But I was like two days in when I got
out there and I was like,
I've made a huge mistake.
I should go back home two days.
Priya right away.
It's so different than him.
Like what am I doing?
This is definitely a mistake.
What,
what was the initial thought behind it?
Like what did you think?
Do you think that this is what I need to
recharge?
No,
I've been wanting to see the world for a
while and you know,
I had,
I had one good,
this Guy Turner brought me out to a tour
of China.
Um,
and I just sort of saw some of that
place and it was like,
just so like the really the meaning of
the word foreign,
you know?
Yeah.
Just way different.
And they're just like,
I just wanted to see more of that world.
And I went with,
with PDC to Thailand a couple of years
ago.
Went one of those full moon parties and
it just got more like I want to see
things.
I did a Scandinavian tour last year.
I made sure to leave days off in between
shows.
So like a really see some of the cities,
I don't know man.
I just get off and like seeing new
new versions of the world and new
experience of what people care about.
Well I think we love to um,
to compartmentalize and to like look at
our specific area because I think it's a
part of being a human until recently.
Like until you could travel like this,
like what people liked was knowing the
sort of security of their environment.
They know the environment well.
They're around it all the time.
There's no surprises.
I got this place a lockdown down on
safe,
but it's not adventurous.
It's not adventurous.
So this new thing that people are able
to do only really within the last
hundred years while you could just get
up and travel and just,
I mean,
I guess there's probably world travelers
before.
Yeah.
Before for sure.
But I mean how many of them did it
recreationally?
Like,
so easy now.
Yeah,
you can stay at hostels for cheapest.
Fuck,
you know,
meet people and have them tell you what
there is to do where you are or where to
go or not go.
When do you think that that was really
an acceptable thing?
As far as,
no,
no.
I mean world travel.
Oh,
like when,
when were you an invader?
Oh,
right.
And when did it become okay to be a
tourist?
I think it was always sort of okay to be
like some guy in foreign lands if as
long as there by herself and not like an
invading force,
but if you want to just visit somewhere,
right.
I mean I just wonder how many people did
it no steak.
Like here's what I noticed in Hong Kong
and Shanghai,
which our banking centers and the people
that would come to the shows,
ex pats,
Hong Kong,
you had more locals because they don't
speak English there.
But in Shanghai,
let's say,
and it's like if you're an English
banker from London,
or if somebody from New York and you
took the job in Shanghai,
China,
like your,
you'd have to have some adventures bone
to you.
Instead of staying in New York or
staying in London,
you'd have to be saying like,
yeah,
I'm going to go with my kids or without
my kids.
I'm going to go fucking do this new
thing.
And Yeah.
I mean,
just to want to go do that.
You can do it now.
There's jobs everywhere.
Yeah.
My friend William,
uh,
children's,
he moved to me and Mario got a job
offer.
Who's an architect.
Wow.
So He's building prisons.
Prisons are designing them.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
But like,
it just opened up the army,
just letting people,
and he was like one of those first wave
of people and they started doing stand
up out there.
Dude,
that's gotta be a creepy feeling.
Building prisons,
something like that.
Yeah.
Designing them.
And now he's doing standup.
He,
yeah,
he did all of his time there.
He had the show.
I didn't Bangkok.
He brought me out there from Emr.
He took a trip there and met me in
Bangkok.
Cj,
do you think he's doing comedy to
balance out the building prisons?
No.
It just does comedy.
He's back in America
building prisons.
Not that we don't need prisons.
Not there aren't bad people that should
be locked up.
Yeah,
that's not what I'm what I'm saying.
It's like you guys got to design them so
he's going to make it more comfortable
maybe.
Oh,
whatever.
Yeah,
because that's what make it so they
can't get out.
That's what it
is.
The sunshine,
the wall situation.
It's a crazy thing when someone escaped
from prison,
Wham,
and let the dogs who's wherever,
wherever I wrote.
Can you imagine getting out of prison?
Oh my God.
That must be so exciting.
A tunnel every night or finding you have
to find the way out.
How do you know the way out?
How do you escape?
How about El Chapo walks down to the
whole that's under his toilet that goes
a mile plus in the ground and then pops
up at some goofy ass house and gets in a
car and drives off.
Wow.
See US suckers.
Is he still free as he know?
No,
he's back.
They caught him of Chapo.
They did something and he got injured to
something happened to him.
He like hurt his leg or something like
that through the tunnels.
I think he might've like broken his leg
falling and they're trying to escape.
You know,
he didn't look like he was the most fit
fella.
He's too busy running shit.
Yeah.
To actually be running.
Well we'll it if you can hear this.
Uh,
July 18th,
my netflix special comes out.
That's so amazing.
Shout out to El Chapo.
I checked that out with Chapo.
He speaks English and when he would the
comedy translate to him?
I think some of it would if it would fit
after they've subtitles on Netflix.
So,
right.
That's how I always wonder,
like that's one of the unique things
about like learning a language.
It's the way they structure their
sentences is very different.
So it's,
you can't,
it's not just this word means that that
word means this.
So just replaced them.
No,
it's interesting when you talked to
people from other countries,
when you're out there and you start to
the event,
be able to translate their
mistranslations easy things like what
time it is,
right.
They don't realize that that's a
statement,
not a question.
Right.
But like you just get to like,
when they say five years more,
it means like,
I've already been here five years,
that they're not really,
so you have to understand what they
really mean.
Sort of like that 72 virgins expression,
what it means.
Like it must glowed.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That's what it means.
72 is like a shit load,
you know?
Yeah.
It's not like a specific number.
Like we,
when we see a few,
it's like technically it means three,
but really it just means,
I don't know.
Som mungus amount,
72 virgins.
Right?
Oh my God,
you have,
so we all took that as like,
you think you're getting exactly 72
virgins,
exact glow.
Yeah.
We don't.
Yeah,
I used to do a whole bit about that.
Seven suicide bombers.
What page is this whole 72 of our
agenda.
Something written anywhere to shop.
It's doing
okay.
I just want to know why can't you just
tell me what page it's on.
What a crazy world to think that there
are people that will go into crowded
areas like in Manchester?
Yeah,
and just blow themselves up and kill a
bunch of people around them.
But halls or just like belief.
Oh belief for sure.
And then some sort of mental illness for
sure.
There's a lot of issues.
Abuse,
maybe.
Maybe there's physical abuse.
Maybe they're like have no idea what
have an extreme desire to show their
love.
You just think you were at war,
right?
Who knows?
Who knows why you think
you would,
you know,
to break down the psychology of,
so when there's a suicide bomber would
be very like you would,
you would have to do a tremendous amount
of research before you started drawing.
Any are hard to find
them to talk to them too.
That's what already done a problem.
The theoretical suicide bombers do not
apply.
I'm thinking about you have to get guys
who,
whose best don't go off.
Okay,
we got to talk to you.
Even then,
like what are you going to get here?
This is a recovered person.
They got,
they got through that moment where
they're going to blow themselves up and
it didn't happen.
Now they've sort of had a chance to
think about it.
How do you charge that guy?
Yeah.
You know?
Oh yeah,
I would do it again.
I realized I was about today.
Do you notice a different in,
in,
uh,
in um,
deviant sociology does a different
category for,
uh,
people who attempt suicide and people
who commit suicide really in the psyche
of it.
Oh,
I see.
Because their thing is if you attempted
it,
he weren't really trying.
It ain't that hard to do.
You were probably trying to cry out.
And the people who do it generally shut
up about it more.
They just do it without telling people
like,
I'm going to kill myself.
I want to kill myself.
So somebody said it.
People say they want to kill themselves.
That's a good sign that they need help,
but that they're not going to kill
themselves.
Hmm.
There's,
is there a different,
there's a different mentality between
also someone who wants to kill
themselves and someone who wants to
literally be the
bomb that kills a bunch of the,
yeah,
that's a,
if you really believe in heaven and
you're going there though,
fucking great.
Get there.
Why wait?
Wow.
I mean,
you're for sure going,
it's,
it's like,
you know the Catholic confession on your
death bed and then you go straight to
heaven,
but it's hard to time it,
right?
Yeah.
You confess all your sins right before
you die.
You're going,
shit,
you have no sense left.
You're going to heaven.
Right.
But you don't time it,
right?
Yeah.
And that's really hard.
These guys figured out the way to time
it perfectly.
My Act of blowing myself up gets me into
heaven by the way.
All my sets,
right.
One shot.
Unless as he blew it up,
part of it goes,
fuck.
Right before he died,
he goes to hell for eternity
to Callis Jamie.
No,
I don't know anybody from Manchester.
I'm sorry.
Just
what if,
what if you do it?
What if you do it and you think you're
going to be in heaven and you press the
button,
boom,
and then all of a sudden it's just you
disembodied and an infinite black room.
It just you forever in the blackness of
infinite space with no stars,
just you alone with nobody.
What's floating through eternity.
You just,
you,
you can experience the blackness of
space,
but with no stars and nothing to look at
women forever.
Just you just,
you just use your conscious
consciousness and realizing how huge you
fucked up.
Oh,
forever.
that'd be pretty bad.
He'd go crazy.
Right?
Then you'd come back,
we'll come back and crazy.
What would even be crazy?
Imagine if you have your consciousness
forever.
Nothing drove by it too.
Nothing to apply to and you're floating
through infinity and you don't have a
body,
so you're not to bad man.
That's
a pretty bad punishment.
That's pretty bad.
It's not good.
Wow.
That would be real tough.
Still not good enough.
That's you should float.
Unable to turn to d while you're feeling
like you're choking on Dick's.
Wow.
Like that's a little
for eternity because if you can exist
for a second way choking on a deck,
you could exist for eternity while he
choked it out on deck.
Yeah.
So that should,
that should be the punishment for
suicide bombs.
They have the simpsons where
homer going to hell and then,
uh,
the devil,
one of the demons was like,
so you would like donuts?
Do you try eating?
I'm merely and go nuts.
And it's just conveyor belt that keeps
like shoveling donut to do his mouth and
he keeps going more pleased
that he's gotten off that big.
It's like please more.
Another one please.
Oh,
you ever do the simpsons ride at
universal?
Nope.
It's fucking amazing because it really,
it's crazy.
Giant animated ride.
You just sit in a car.
It's one of the best rides ever.
So good.
Yeah.
And it's all happening on a screen,
but the cars moving around so it feels
real and it's an enormous fucking really
high resolution screen where it's
showing this huge cartoon where this
whole thing plays out.
Oh,
it's fucking great.
It's really good.
The simpsons are a national treasure.
Yeah,
they really are.
It's pretty great.
My whole adulthood,
I guess they've been on since I was in
high school.
Really?
Yeah.
Tracee Ellis,
dude.
They were one of the first.
There's something crazy like that.
30 30 yeah,
me too high school,
Dude.
It's forever.
It's always been there.
I'll never forget it.
I remember like what a great show.
Remember one,
a homer Simpson went to a chili cook off
and the peppers were so hot.
He started tripping.
He had psychedelic trips.
Peppers were merciless.
The ghost peppers,
right?
Isn't that what it was supposed to be?
The of quit.
So sockets a Nunga.
What does that,
is that what they call it?
Ghost peppers and puts a sockets manago
grown to the deep and the jug of
primeval by the inmates up a Guatemalan
insane asylum.
Yeah.
That was a great show.
Caught.
Damn.
What a creative,
see,
that's the thing about like bill burrs
show F is for family too.
I haven't seen the new ones yet.
I heard they're great.
I heard they're really good.
Of course it's great.
Bill's Hilarious,
but you could do so much cool shit on a
cartoon that you can't do in real life.
What's the head back it up?
But then there's that again.
We'll get decapitated.
They get blown up.
I mean how many times it South Park
Killed Kenny.
Yeah.
So many of them comes back and he didn't
care that he came back.
He just comes back.
I love how later they sorta like dealt
with it with like the reincarnation sort
of stuff.
And he said,
I'm going to saying things.
Yeah.
He remembers all his past lives.
So ridiculous.
Yeah.
I love when I F is for family cause
there's a,
there's a real type characters and they
look real.
They don't look all like Weirdo,
like uh,
like squid billies type stuff.
So it's like this is,
you can believe as a people and when the
father saying to his son,
fuck you,
it's like a real sharp,
oh my God,
it's like a cartoon.
But in my opinion,
like if you got to give,
wow,
I mean,
I was going to say like the all time
best is south park,
but I don't really think there's an all
time best,
but it's in terms of they're all
awesome.
I don't want to like say this is number
one is number two,
but like south park has had some fucking
money.
I won't miss that show is South Park.
I mean for,
and for years it's been that you just
don't miss any episodes.
There is no falling behind.
There's no like,
oh yeah,
it's,
I just stop watching a couple seasons
ago.
It's just like every year I get so
excited to see those posters and the
billboard now on the,
uh,
the billboards and the subway.
Yeah.
And it's like,
oh,
it's back.
It's fucking amazing show.
And it's been amazing forever.
You have trey Parker on here on this
podcast would for sure.
Oh,
you should.
I would.
I'd have them both.
I'm at,
yeah,
you left matt out.
How dare you,
you don't even care about matt the ever
see that show.
Um,
a boy,
they show the making of a soft start
there.
Yeah.
That's great.
Fuck yeah.
Documentary.
It's great.
He's humbling,
right?
Trey Parker,
like his work ethic and the way he goes
after it,
it's like,
whoa.
It's like get the fuck out of that guy's
way out of his way.
It's pretty much sets that you guys come
out for a second.
What can I do with it this?
And then someone would say something
cool and then right back in.
Yeah.
That dude from snl working there that
week and he barely had anything to do.
Wow.
I four was his name.
It was hater.
What's his name?
John Hater.
But later it was John hit her own
Napoleon dynamite.
Hey,
let me ask you this.
We didn't think a Bill Maher.
I'd never been a bill Marfan,
but do you think of this whole recent
controversy of him just casually drop on
an Bob?
Yeah.
You know,
he was trying to make a joke.
Exactly right.
Yeah.
I mean it didn't work,
but he's trying to be naughty.
Yeah.
That's all.
But they're making it seem like it's
something more that it's words that,
like you said this and said,
yeah,
said,
said not did,
did is worse,
but it's totally not hire black people
is that,
that's a major issue if he's never hired
a black person.
But I don't think I've heard of that.
So it's like his actions aren't,
we were talking about before the
podcast,
this thing where the,
where they were talking about the
Clintons in Arkansas,
in the governor's mansion.
What,
what show was that?
What show was it?
Did you see Jamie?
I read it.
I didn't see it on the show.
Oh,
was getting passed around the Internet
yesterday.
Mm.
I'll pull it up.
It's gotta be Russian disinformation.
I could be,
who knows?
But apparently when Bill Maher,
when they go like troubling from bill,
I mean,
I get to even the Republican senator,
they was there with,
it was like,
what?
Like I'm a little uncomfortable,
but sure.
Be uncomfortable.
And if a guy,
I'm watching a guy who uses words that
make me uncomfortable at time,
I'll stop watching.
I guess.
You know,
twitter erupts over news that Hillary
Clinton used black prison labor while
first lady of Arkansas,
newsweek.com.
And what does it have to do with,
um,
JFK?
JFK pushed the Democrats to Democrat
running for connecting,
pushed them to the right and Hillary
Clinton physics too,
Huh?
I don't know.
Um,
okay.
When we moved in,
I was told that using prison labor at
the governor's mansion was a
longstanding tradition which kept down
cost.
Clinton rights.
She has it.
Most of the workers were convicted
murderers and she became friendly with,
in quotes a few of them,
African American men in their thirties
who had already served 12 to 18 years of
their sentences.
Woo.
Despite their alleged friendships with
these men,
Clinton tells her readers we enforced
rules strictly and sent back to prison.
Any inmate who broke a rule despite
having no psychological qualification,
she later asserts that these men did not
have inferior iqs or an ability to apply
moral reasoning,
but instead they may have been emotional
illiterates
emotional illiterates.
I don't know.
That's what she said.
But I like how it says,
despite having no psychological
qualifications later asserts,
despite having no ability to say this,
she said,
yeah,
it's kind of weird though,
that slave labor.
Yeah,
that is exactly what that is.
I mean,
let's know,
but it's just tradition.
It's like,
yeah,
but that doesn't mean he should do it.
Let's be honest.
Like how much are they getting paid?
Zero.
What?
The fucking one pack of cigarettes a
week.
Yeah.
What did they get?
They did not pay inmates at all.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Clinton makes no mention of whether or
not these men received any money for
working for her and her husband at 2016
article for Mother Jones notes that when
it came to prison,
when it comes to prison labor,
some state states include Texas,
Arkansas and Georgia.
Do not pay inmates at all.
Holy Fuck on twitter.
Djing wrote that.
Hillary Clinton was a direct participant
in what?
Sam Sue Sway Samsung.
Uh,
it's at Samsung pay on twitter,
I guess correctly described as modern
slavery.
100% well,
dude,
that's 100% slavery if you don't pay
someone.
And you make them work because they did
a crime.
That's a crazy thing like boat,
but you're making them work.
That's what's crazy about it.
It's like,
it's not just that you,
you,
you were your freedoms taken away and
they lock you in a box,
but they also make you work.
Send your lives aren't worth anything.
We can make it do whatever we want.
Yeah.
And that dude from a Phoenix makes you
work in pink.
Oh yeah.
That,
that Gelato Cryo guy.
Yeah.
He's a,
he's an interesting case.
It makes you put pink on to embarrass
her.
Yeah.
Do,
do you get embarrassed when you were in
pink?
Epic?
Sometimes I don't give a fuck.
I'm not a big pink where I will
occasionally wear pink.
I'll admit I'm not a big pink where,
yeah.
But at the same time I don't care about
it.
I'm not scared of a color.
I'm a rational person.
I remember in high school,
like 1314 wearing pink ties and stuff.
Like she'll bring a little embarrassed
but also been like,
this looks good.
And then learning the word salmon makes
it way more easier.
You know,
gene,
the Belo is wore a pink judogi.
Really?
Yup.
Why?
It's clean and sober.
It says an all of them clean and sober
with pink shirts.
Probably because they,
uh,
were drug offenders.
Right.
He gets upset.
He wants everybody clean.
I mean it's better than then they
combine sober.
Oh,
there's an ang and quotes around it,
that silly rascal
and he's not taken out ever pink.
Um,
so judo,
gene labelle was like one of the
toughest men that's ever lived.
Did his judo with a pink Guiana.
Why?
Fuck you?
That's why
Google judo,
gene labelle judo.
Gene Labelle was,
uh,
he was,
I know he was a national champion in
judo and I think he won a gold medal in
the Olympics through,
I saw clay Guido see him once and
there's real quick what was coming up.
So it wasn't like he was in the cheap
seats with us.
Right.
And he started judo gene and like the
section,
whether you sit and he was like,
oh fuck.
He just jumped.
I don't know how it got past security.
Just like ran past them just to go get
that guy a hug.
What is gene?
There's gene,
the balance Pinky.
What does gene labelle's um,
his accomplishments.
He said a shitload of accomplish.
That's the judo,
but clearly on the guy.
Yeah,
he definitely did some training with
Rhonda and he's also the guy that
exposed,
um,
Bruce Lee to grappling.
Oh really?
To joint locks and joint manipulation.
It's,
what does it say here?
National Champion.
So he won the Aau national judo
championships in 60 and 54 and 55
North American heavyweight championship.
See Nwa.
All that stuff I think is like fake
wrestling.
Oh really?
Yeah,
he is real wrestling and perfect.
Nwa,
professional wrestling.
Yeah.
There's no tag team in real wrestling.
So he was a national champion.
Is there a real,
some reason I thought he was a,
an Olympic champion than I might've made
that up.
Is there a Greco Roman tech team?
Uh,
no.
That's not real.
Oh Man.
The show.
Um,
you could see like a,
there's a million pictures of him
wearing this ridiculous pink gee,
how do I not know his,
his,
uh,
accomplishments in judo but,
and as far as like a pinky.
Yeah,
he's crazy.
He's always been crazy too.
He had a one.
Yeah.
He's a great guy.
He had one of the first mixed martial
arts fights too.
He fought a boxer.
Simone said he could,
uh,
he would go down there with Piper,
I guess pipe were trained with them.
Um,
and uh,
he said we'd go down there and get calls
all the time for people challenging him.
Judo gene,
like I can beat you up and he would just
answer the phone all day.
Just aren't,
well,
come on.
Prove yourself.
I'm here.
I'll take you.
All right,
well I'm here eight to seven every day
by just saying sound people.
I fuck you.
We'll come over all with you.
I'll beat you.
He was like in his sixties and he caught
some kids breaking into cars and his
neighborhood and a one kid came after
him and he just fucking man handle this
poor kid.
And throw him on the ground.
Imagine being thrown on the ground.
65 year olds,
65 year old judo black show.
This guy,
what's up boy?
What the fuck?
Yeah.
He put two dudes to sleep when they're
trying to break into cars.
He's just a different kind of human
being.
It's just like if he got ahold of you,
it's like it's guy being grabbed by some
sort of a primate,
you know?
I imagine the pride.
It's of your face.
Yeah.
You just feel so weak.
If once you were in the air,
he'd be like,
how is this happening?
Like before he slams your head off the
ground,
you've got to be thinking,
how has he just throwing me around like
this?
Well,
weird specialty.
The specialty of throwing.
You can become really good at throwing
people's bodies around.
You'll see that.
Uh,
did you see that?
What's it called?
Boom.
That's beautiful techniques and given
some kid technique off the sideline
here.
Oh Wow.
Wow.
That's,
boom.
That kid has some technique.
Oh,
so pool.
He's like,
hell yeah,
Bro.
Man.
Putin walking on the maths,
but it's shoes.
Come on,
dude.
Putin would fuck up.
I would get,
I would bet Putin would fuck up all the
world leaders if we had a round robin
and then may contest with all world
leaders.
Yeah.
But I got my money on Putin.
Definitely the big powers must get out
of doing shit.
Yeah.
He's going to win.
He's an actual judo black belt.
Oh yeah,
Bro.
Weird.
This looks like this bird.
Literally.
It looks like it's salutes in back.
Should Goddamn Putin bird knows his
place.
So live on the fucker.
So look,
well I,
that's gotta be fake.
How did they bend his wig over?
You know,
man,
the real question with a guy like Putin
is not like,
how much does he control?
It's like,
what happens if that guy dies?
Oh yeah.
Who takes over that power to the vacuum
of power behind that guy must be
stunning.
They're a democracy,
right?
Russia sorta totalitarian developers,
they know they have some sort of a
democracy.
They have some sort of election process.
Yeah.
It's President Gorbachev,
right.
Present.
As long as you're not running against
Putin seems to function fairly well.
He just took over again and he like,
he was the president.
Then he went away.
He just came back like,
fuck you guys.
I took it over again.
I think he came back again in 2012 this
has been back for a while.
Not that long.
Yeah.
He was gone for a while and then some
other dude got into power and he's like,
hey man,
you're the president and the guys are
okay.
Okay.
Oh,
it's,
look,
it's not admirable.
That's what a
guy from narcos did.
Right.
He wanted to be just in governments.
We run shit.
Yeah.
What was his name?
Um,
Escobar.
Yeah.
Pablo.
How good is that?
Accurate plays him.
Good name.
What is his name?
That dude plays Pablo Escobar.
God Damn,
it's good.
That guy's good.
And he's smoking reefer all day.
All Day.
Just like a normal thing.
I forget his name now.
Respect God.
That guy is good,
by the way,
if you're watching a,
uh,
what's it called?
What's that name of the show?
Narcos.
When you're done,
make sure it's on July 18th and beyond
to catch my Nunez.
Double special people are going to be on
Netflix.
No sense of going back out to the apple
TV.
Oh my goodness.
What Day is that again?
July 18th Joe.
It's Tuesday,
July 18th all over the world.
Fantastic.
At midnight Pacific Time.
Are you going on the road at all?
No.
No,
just fucking around coming up with
material in town in 15 looks like you're
having fun up there.
Oh yeah.
Was it weird to not be on stage or did
you go on stage at all?
I went to one show in Phnom Penh,
saw show get the itch and they asked me,
they knew me,
they asked me to go up.
Why?
And you said No.
I was like,
no.
Well what?
I was like,
I really want to see what like the fully
long break would do those sorts of
breaking it up.
Right.
Just for one set somewhere.
It would be cool to perform in Cambodia
to mark that off of list.
You know,
I like doing that.
That's my like bird watching kind of
stuff.
Countries that performed in Cambodia.
Yeah.
Wow.
Um,
but I was like,
no.
Also,
I didn't want to be going around for the
next two months with the fucking bomb on
my shoulders,
like,
you know what I mean?
I don't need the fucking walk around
with that as like my last set.
Oh,
so if you went up there and eight Dick.
Yeah.
And then I'm like,
have I started losing it?
Oh,
gone.
I'm already nervous about that.
I don't want to fucking people like,
what are you doing?
I'm like,
I don't even know anymore.
What was it like the first time on stage
after that long break?
A little weird.
I tell the story.
So I at least base myself in like in
like,
uh,
things that happened,
you know,
a narrative,
less as expected.
But then the next day I did a,
our gatsy was there and so Nashville,
I was at,
that's when I came home.
So they wanted to do this show in a
third man records.
So I just wrote them a letter and I was
like,
Hey,
if you still want to do that,
mmm.
Add it to the website.
I'll be home.
I'll just come home.
I'll see it.
Right.
I'll check it.
Um,
so I did nate Barr,
gatsy and friends the next day.
Uh,
and that was just stand up and I was
like a little lost was weird.
Yeah,
I was,
it was Russ,
you're on the edges and I got to like 12
or 13 minutes.
I didn't want to do anything from the
special.
So I was just like,
what do I have new?
And I tried something that I thought
I've been on the road,
which wasn't much.
I kind of shut my brain off to that a
little bit.
Like instead of like writing jokes,
but he was like,
Nah,
a couple of topics.
And I was like,
but that's it.
What if you had an awesome idea that
just came to you?
I didn't know where it should bother.
Right.
And toss it.
Yeah.
I wrote that like,
just an idea.
Mm.
MMM.
Like I saw two d this hasn't worked,
so to say it.
And I saw two dogs at the end of fucking
so many stray dogs out there.
It's everywhere.
And eventually it ends up on menus to,
Ooh.
Just cause it's like,
it's like fish man.
They're everywhere.
Jesus.
Yeah.
Why wouldn't you kill one to survive?
Did you eat any dog?
I did not.
Uh,
only because I,
when I saw it on a menu,
it's called [inaudible] in East Timor.
Um,
it was like a,
they have this,
the Indonesian style of food,
which is while ruined.
So just like windows with like food left
out.
Do you know how like pizza places in New
York,
he points to a slice and they'll take it
and warm it up.
So it's like that,
but they don't warm it up and it's meat.
So it's like bits of fish or chicken or
beef.
And then that was like dog.
So if it was hot out of the oven,
I might've gone for it,
but not leftover cold.
Cold Dog over rice.
You look good though.
It looked good.
I had ask her four times what she said.
I had to keep checking my like
translator and I was like,
no,
I think you're saying it wrong.
She was like,
yeah,
she had an act out like walk,
walk,
walk.
Now that's not a dog.
Ruff.
I just do chicken trying to do dog.
My friend Steven Rinella was telling me
that they regarded as a hot food.
Not necessarily even just meaning spicy.
Oh really?
A dog is like a hot food.
Meaning like there's like there's
something to it.
It's like there's a special energy that
you get from eating dog.
Yeah,
that's dark.
I could say that because they seem more
like intelligent,
you know,
they have seem to have feelings.
Jesus hot food,
like human meat.
You came their souls.
He did a show with the sky where they,
uh,
they shot in eight a coyote,
you know,
they cook the coyote like they would
cook like wild game and they uh,
opened it up,
they burned off all the hair and then
they split it and threw it over like a
great and cooked it on over coals just
through some seasoning on it and it's
crackling and cooking and then they just
cut pieces of this coyote off and it's
like,
I was watching this going to,
why is it so disturbing when we choose
one animal?
Oh yeah.
Why is that so disturbing?
Like,
why is that coyote any different than a
pig?
Which is totally normal.
It's just pet wise.
That's,
I think it's all boils down to,
I mean,
you don't have that.
You don't have it.
It's even weirder than that because
nobody's got a pet.
Coyote did.
I saw something.
Yeah,
it's close enough to your dog.
Fuck your dog and get it pregnant.
Yeah.
I was like,
oh we don't like that.
Yeah.
It reminds me of it's,
it's so close to a dog.
It's so close to a dog that if it fucks
your dog it'll make puppies.
Yeah.
I went to a
rooster fights that seem so crazy.
Does that seem so crazy?
Yeah.
Imagine if a chicken can fuck your
parakeet and make something still pair
Katie Kate and gets to the parrot cage.
It's fucked the shit out of him.
A chicken.
A parrot's cage would be hilarious.
Yeah.
The different species.
Yeah,
but she makes it look like the same
thing.
Chicken just shit out of that parent.
Oh,
that whole time you thought you had a
girl parent,
you know the chicken laying eggs.
Chicken gets in there plug too.
Shit.
Roosters are ruthless man.
I don't have any,
I don't have any roosters.
But we were really worried when we're
getting chickens.
Yeah.
That when I was growing up but he wants
it to go away cause I made it so I had
to bring him into the garage every night
cause we got the neighbors the fucking
middle of the numbers and they're just
like,
what in the flaws for Sun up?
Yeah.
It's not set up it's way before it's on
up.
Really.
They can sense it coming.
Oh it's cons.
Oh
yeah.
Just screaming next to your neighbor.
Like what the fuck?
Yeah.
We were in Santa Barbara and some guy
had one but he had it like
thousand 2000 yards away.
Really?
Yeah,
it was far.
But you could still hear it but it was
kind of cool because you ain't here.
It wasn't obnoxious.
Like if it was right next door,
like it was way across this canyon.
I was like wow,
that's kinda cool.
Like that won't even bother me.
I got used to it being out there.
All those countries,
they just had them around.
So wherever you are asleep and they were
thin walls,
he would just hear him,
dude,
I want to get peacocks.
Cool.
We had peacocks.
I want to get pet peacocks.
I'm going to go full hunters Thompson
and have some pet peacocks.
I had to bury one of them.
Did you fucking reaches head of the
lattice work that tried to like eat the
grass right outside the Fox.
He was waiting for him.
Took his head,
left the body.
Inside foxes are clever.
Very clever.
I went to a rooster fight in uh,
in Timor-Leste day.
Did you really?
Yeah.
In terms of like what we accept and what
they will,
you know,
different things too.
They're doing that shit and encino or
they really so,
right.
I know place.
Wow.
Then you can go to,
there's,
there's places I wanted to go down for
sure.
There's places in the valley that might
as well be Mexico,
like you said,
one neighborhoods.
I've never seen the actual fights,
but I've seen the fighting roosters.
I've seen pens.
There's a hundred is a dude that I know.
Who knows the dude who's got like a
hundred of them in his backyard.
Wow.
Yeah.
Quite fighting roosters.
Wow.
A lot of these like Mexican
neighborhoods,
it's like super normal.
They don't view it as weird at all.
Where I saw it,
they were like,
you're not taking pictures.
I'm like,
oh,
I didn't want to like,
you know,
get your guys in trouble.
Like,
why did it get us in trouble?
What do you mean we're outside in those
countries.
It's not bad at all.
The general owns the fucking ring where
they all put to it.
It's hilarious.
But then if you can do that,
then you can justify dogs like,
well,
what do we do about dogs?
Well,
dogs are a little smarter.
It's a little different.
There should raise out there,
right?
They are straight a's.
California authorities sees over 7,000
birds in the largest cockfighting busts
in US history.
Wow.
Jesus Christ took three weeks ago.
Jesus Christ in the valley.
[inaudible] valley.
See,
I told you
I'm making this up.
That's Meth town.
Anyway.
You say meth town.
I say a rooster town.
Zip.
Gasser.
Slashers.
Yeah.
They put these razors on the back of the
back claw,
isn't it?
I mean,
they give him steroids really for the
animals.
We're also recovered.
I didn't see any of that.
Oranges and steroids.
They got juiced up.
Chicken's ready to fuck you up.
Can you imagine?
I want to like do a vice land piece on
that.
Watch these dudes shoot their fucking
chickens up with steroids and have them
go out there.
I'll look and hulk out
700 birds.
They went back to the same spot,
but here's the thing,
man,
it 10 years earlier,
it doesn't bother.
It doesn't bother you or me like it
would if it was dogs.
No,
it doesn't,
but I'll be out.
Yeah.
No,
they don't look like us.
Not nearly,
but I was.
I thought it would be like really
barbaric until you see it and you're
like,
oh,
that's not really that bad at all.
I've seen dogfights.
I was in New Orleans.
I saw a dog fight.
You did?
Yeah.
Impromptu.
I don't know if I was out with my
friends.
It was a pit.
One fucking pit bull came in and another
pit bull came into this pit and we're
like,
what's going on?
And they did it and it was,
I mean vicious.
It was vicious.
These cockfights are just like,
they fly each other a couple times and
then one gets like woozy need and then
falls.
It's a cockfight room.
Yeah.
That looks like why inside?
Huh?
See the dog fighting thing is the dog
fighting thing to those people that mean
the people that believe in it.
I'm sure they would argue with you that
there's no difference between dog
fighting and rooster.
Probably not.
Most people think there is because dogs
are smarter.
It was just,
but it was also bloodier.
Oh yeah.
It was just like more like them ripping
each other's fucking everything out.
Yeah.
Th Th th th the father fights of 30
seconds and you don't even see blood
most of the time it's just,
it's just there.
Yeah.
But,
but yeah,
in terms of animal,
if I saw a dead animal on the side of
the road,
what would probably be more of a dog or
a rooster?
It's on youtube.
They have cockfighting on Youtube Cup.
Oh,
the world's Slasher Cup,
dude,
I dvr this.
That guy's gonna hit the other one in
the back to move him or he's going to
pick him up and throw him towards the
other one.
Is that what they did that they're not
going at each other yet,
so they have to really throw them
towards each other.
So most of the time if they put a
rooster near rooster,
he's got,
he's got a tight,
yeah,
they'll come out to each other.
They're probably like,
what the fuck is going on?
So in their back foot,
here we go.
Oh.
Then they go at each other.
Oh my God.
What will start pecking the other ones
soon.
So they're catching each other with
these feet and that happens a normal way
of fighting to say the other ones that
blocked that one.
That's fuck God.
Yeah,
he's down.
It's dad.
They stopped that.
God,
they must be both mangled though.
Yeah.
He gets tasteless.
Little blood pack had them.
The Ref has to choose when it's over.
He's called,
that's called it.
Wow.
That rooster got fucked up.
They'll fast.
That is,
yeah.
So you don't even see really how it's
like barbaric.
It's just quick and over.
Do you think that well,
yeah,
because covering a little strap
one tonight.
Today.
Oh yeah.
So when I saw the winner or the owner of
the winter,
it gets to eat the loser.
They take it home with them on their
bike and they're eating chicken tonight.
I went weird.
And do you think that rooster fights
again?
I saw them selling a rooster up.
I don't.
Jesus Christ,
they said he gets two months off,
gets to live a fun life for a while and
then I'll be back and fighting.
But he didn't.
So sometimes the winners get,
nothing happened to them.
Sometimes they get a little fuck to
Jesus.
Sometimes they both die.
Wow.
These are the rooster houses.
That's in Kentucky.
Hold on.
Shit.
But wait a minute.
That looks like a dog house.
That looks like what they do with pets
because they do.
Is that really roosters?
That's crazy.
There's a on top of it then place under
for the rains.
Yeah,
I guess so.
The places where they,
um,
they fight dogs.
They'll have like a giant yard and
they'll have like 10 dogs plus out there
on chains and they're all connected.
These little tiny houses just like that.
It's really creepy because they're,
they're not really dogs.
I mean their dogs in the sense of
they're at the actual animal.
They are his dogs.
But there are these things like at all,
no,
there's no pet to them.
They're these things that had been there
just bred to fight and I'm sure that
they can handle them.
You know,
I'm sure there's like a few commands
they understand,
but their life is not about being pat
and love climbing on the bed.
He's army.
What's,
what's their name?
What do they call?
Jamie was one with the tickets cut off.
Oh yeah.
We'll just call play is trying to fight
their Unix,
but that's not what they call
themselves,
but
I don't really know.
God Damn it.
Yeah.
Fuck that.
She needs to come back.
It takes a while.
This ansel and sally the unsullied.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's what those dogs are there.
Like ansel.
Hmm.
Yeah.
Well,
they just,
they have their dicks and balls though
the unsolid.
The problem with those guys is they've
been neutered so they can't fight that
good cause they don't have any
testosterone.
These dogs have everything there ready
to rock and roll.
They just live to fight and that,
that moment that they get to fight,
it's like the only thing they're looking
forward to and they were brief and like
really miserable existence.
So the more they exercise them,
the more they just train them and get
them ramped up.
They're just prepping them for this one
moment where he gets to do what he
actually wants to do,
what he's made to do in the side of his
fault.
It's like that dog is bred that way.
They've encouraged that behavior like
generation after generation,
like careful selection calling dogs that
don't fit the criteria.
Like it's one of the reasons why people
love pit bulls so much.
Like once you have a pit bull,
other dogs seem so dumb because they're
so smart.
They're so tuned into you and they're
like,
like I remember squeaky fromme.
She was like a little demon.
She was like tuned in to me and she
would lock onto me,
but if any other dog got anywhere near
her and tried to take my attention,
she would kill it in front of me.
Really?
She would just want it dead.
It's like get the fuck away from him.
Like Shit.
Yeah,
they just,
they're very intense and tuned into you
and a lot of people like it.
Well she,
I got her,
she was already,
she was a pound dog.
I got her,
she was like 11 months old and she was
cut up.
She had,
she had definitely been in some sort of
a fight,
whether it's an organized one or
something,
but she was a mess from the moment I got
her.
She was just such a cute little dog and
loved you to death.
Just couldn't,
couldn't leave you alone.
Want to sit right next to you.
I'll put her head in your lab.
Just a big sweetie.
Just the sweetest dog ever.
But like these eyes,
there's like the,
they had like,
I'm ready to die for you eyes so that
the one you had to put down.
Yeah,
the rest.
Killing my other dog.
Yeah.
It's not good.
Fuck yeah,
there,
um,
the nature is not their fault.
I mean they,
they've,
they've essentially been selected over
many,
many generations to be incredibly dog
aggressive and incredibly prey driven
and almost impervious to reacting to
pain.
That's what's so terrifying about them
is that they don't care.
They don't,
they don't,
they like to fight.
They're not worried about getting hurt.
They looking forward to this.
They want to do it.
They're wagging their tail and they're
biting each other.
It's crazy.
They wag their tails,
they're locked faces on each other and
their tails are wagging back and forth.
Like they're having the greatest time.
I saw a thing for some like,
oh see county fair.
They train their dogs new tricks and
shit and they said they've gotten to the
point where this reminds me of this,
where the treat they get for,
for crashing the frisbee eventually
becomes the Frisbee.
So like they're trying to catch like,
cool,
I got to grab that Frisbee.
Thank you.
And that I could throw it again.
So like I got through about the Frisbee
again,
you know,
instead of like I get the Frisbee so I
can get this fucking piece of meat.
Right,
right,
right.
So it seems like those dogs too.
It's like,
Oh,
I did the task and thank you for letting
me do that.
Yeah,
that's what I wanted to do.
They get those.
I'm working dogs.
You ever been around like a real working
German German shepherd?
No,
dude,
there's so intense.
They'll look a live wire.
First of all,
they're like a real big German shepherd
is probably like,
I want to say like 90 pounds.
Like let's Google.
What's a big German shepherd?
It's not the hugest dog in the world.
They're not like a mass deaf,
but they are so fast and there's so
taught just like fucking ready,
ready to go and looking at you.
And this dude was a demonstrating
different,
uh,
he's a,
he trains dogs for the police
department.
He was demonstrating different things.
71 pounds is a big one.
Oh,
adult male.
88 pounds.
Say Yeah.
Close to 90 pounds,
attacked by one of those were in a suit
once.
Dude,
it's so strong.
Oh,
there so strong.
They just keep regular in your hand
until you're on the ground.
They're just so,
they're so fast there and you've got to
think there's so fast.
They're on you.
They let him go.
Like jump now think that right.
That's a 90 pound animal.
Now think of a wolf double.
Oh Wow.
Double that.
And have it more athletic,
stronger,
much harder bite.
It was seen a wolf in the wild.
No,
almost.
I think I might have,
but it was,
it was so dark.
I could only see that it was some sort
of a dog,
like creature that was running across
the dirt road ahead of us while we were
in hunting camp waiting to get picked
up.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Nervous.
Yeah,
a little bit.
Yeah.
When you're standing outside in grizzly
country and there's wolves,
so you can't wander off to go pitch no
fucking way.
You're off to be together.
You have to be together and you both
have to be paying attention and you
should talk and since it's out,
it's late at night.
You don't have to even worry about
whispering.
Like you're not trying to,
like,
you're not trying to scare anything.
You're trying to let things know that
you're there know.
Right.
So todd,
I surprised by it.
Not surprised by you.
They hear you come in,
they can avoid you if they choose to,
but if something decides that it's going
to come towards you,
like cause this size,
these wolves.
Damn Dude,
if you saw a wolf in the woods,
I wouldn't even be trust avenue.
Trust.
That with thing was dead.
I'd be like,
ah man,
at this size of these things,
wow,
these are enormous wolves.
The dead one,
the one of the top middle.
And you know,
it's really interesting,
these wolves that you're seeing,
although they're all just wolves,
these wolves are wolves from Canada and
it's one of the reasons why they're so
big.
One of the reasons why they've been so
devastating to elk populations and deer
populations that was got deer in his
mouth.
Half a second leg is the leg with the,
ah dude.
He looks thin too.
They're so powerful.
They're just incredibly powerful,
incredibly cutting killers that act in
packs.
I love the snow.
They love it.
They can do shit in the snow where other
animals are fucked.
Like they can run through the snow.
They thrive and ridiculous cold
environments because that's when the
other animals are vulnerable and they
can wreck havoc on them.
There are crazy animal man if,
but they look like a dog.
So we have this weird connection with
them where we think of them as dogs like
fits our friend.
It's mister [inaudible] the same way.
Exactly.
I mean they do look nice.
Yeah.
And when you'd see him alone and you're
like,
Oh,
if that was,
you know,
with no scale off,
if I can remember,
I'll tell you this bit I'm doing about
it,
about wolves.
Cause a real encounter I had with a dog
and a wolf or a dog met a wolf for the
first time.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I'll tell you later.
But it's,
it's um,
that animal is not the same animal.
It used to be here.
They killed a bunch of wolves.
So they had to reintroduce wolves to try
to bring the population back.
Oh really?
Well,
when they reintroduced wolves,
they brought him in from Canada.
Canadian moves her bigger,
they're Canadian.
People are bigger.
It's like it's a polar bears.
It's a fucking hardier climbing up
there,
man.
You get a different,
different sort of an animal.
Oh,
you got the wrong one.
They got a big ass wolf.
It was way bigger.
So you can't ever just like go off
because they'll see,
they'll wait for you to be alone while
they definitely could if they chose to.
Most of the time they avoid the fuck out
of people.
They seem to know that if they fuck up
and do something to people,
then will it start coming and then
everybody dies.
Like they're smart enough to kind of
understand that they are not smart.
Like they wouldn't,
you know,
they wouldn't do anything that you would
think would be extraordinary from an
animal.
It's not like they have like superhuman
powers,
but they have an unusual ability to plan
and coordinate and they talk to each
other.
They yell out and talk to each other and
they,
they give locations and they all kind of
intuitively understand what the task is.
But when they're operating together,
it's like,
it's pretty stunning to watch,
man.
I've watched a bunch of videos.
I never,
never in real life obviously,
but a bunch of videos of them
coordinating like an attack on,
on animals.
Dude.
It's amazing.
Like
we heard were I had a um,
which campsite?
Malleable Creek State Park.
You heard coyotes or wolves.
Coyotes.
Um,
but I just liked the way they were like
sort of talking to each other too.
We saw a skunk or first we s we sort of
smelled one and we heard to coyote is
kinda like yelping and we're like that
they got sprayed by a skunk.
Wow.
For sure.
We're just filling this and we have no
idea.
But it's really seemed like that hearing
them or like just a couple of them.
And then later we saw skunk,
um,
tried to spray us,
didn't have much and we think that's the
same skunk that like sprayed out and now
he's got nothing left in the tank.
Does that work like that?
I don't know.
This is what we all think.
And then like a little bit later,
um,
it's just kind of kind of like came with
us but didn't like he tried to spray.
Got the dog.
He's stopped my friend Mervis as you
know Mervis a yeah,
they got his dog but just like a little
bit just bid it.
No,
just like with a little bit of like
spray,
but like not much.
Not enough where it's like terrible.
It was bad.
And then we heard like 10 or 15 coyotes
all howling.
Don't want you to write this concept.
Predator.
Yeah.
He was coming out with bared teeth and
stuff.
I had a skunk trying to get into my
chicken coop.
Really?
Yeah.
And then I read about it.
I'm like,
that's one of the things they eat.
They'll eat chicken.
I make sense.
Yeah.
That's the sprays for self defense,
not offense.
Wow.
But they'll fuck you up.
I just fucked up by a skunk.
Like you fucked you up and you smell
like shit.
Heal your wounds.
It,
nobody wants to help you.
Yeah.
I mean,
imagine if like you got a fist fight
with a skunk in your backyard and he's
Zaps you and then bites and fuck out of
here up and rabies.
He jumps over your fence and you run
inside,
you're covered in blood and you're like,
oh my God,
this skunk bit the fuck out of Wesley's
out of here.
Get away.
Didn't even know she doesn't even care.
Oh my God.
You have to wash yourself outside.
It's cold outside.
Get Out.
You saw like skunk.
Oh my God,
I'm never going to clean this up.
this house didn't smell like forever.
I'm so mad at you.
I'm Gee,
you're mad at me.
If I got fucked up by a skunk.
[inaudible] skunk biting your deck.
It's a skunk.
Oh,
you're like this.
You love fucking creatures.
Or my trip,
I saw Komodo dragons.
Ooh,
in the flesh.
Yeah,
out in the wild.
You went hunting though.
Like not to like kill,
but just to find them.
Yeah.
I try to touch her tail to what I found
out.
Not supposed to do that,
but
I didn't know a man.
I was really close and I just touched
one.
No you didn't.
Oh my God,
dude,
that's so scary.
So we're walking away and it was like,
it's so close.
And I was like just grabbed.
Oh Yeah,
they have these guides is weird.
Pointed like v sticks like long sticks
with like a little tip at the end that
like Kinda like,
it's weird.
But this one guy,
when he had it was like way into snakes
and reptiles and shit and he's like,
let's go.
Let's go find him.
We went out into the brush.
Komodo dragon was the inspiration for
that thing that the alien would do from
the movie.
Really?
Scott movie,
Alien.
It would open its mouth and all the
slime and everything.
They have all this bacteria,
their mouths.
Yeah.
Like it's a bit,
you're going to still going to lose your
leg.
We've gone over this at least twice and
I always forget which it is that they
used to think that it was a toxin and
now they think it's bacteria or they
used to think it was bacteria and now
they think it's a toxin.
Well,
I wanted the bacteria.
Yeah.
It's like a botulism,
lots of different types of bacteria in
their saliva and it's toxic and they
know it.
And so they'll bite an animal and fuck
it up and then they'll follow it around.
So I was reading this thing about a
water buffalo that this Komodo dragon
attacked.
They saw it,
bite it,
and then it followed it for like two
days.
Really just waiting for it to grow.
So this button,
this guy I met and uh,
it's somewhere deep in.
Okay.
So it's the island of Flores is where
you can sort of like b and then that's
where the hobbit people were.
Flora's yeah,
in Indonesia.
Yeah.
Really?
We,
you mean the hobbit people,
this little hobbit people that they
discovered.
Oh really?
Dude,
they discovered that within the last
shit,
I want to say 14,000 years ago.
Is that what it was?
It was in the last 14,000 years
somewhere.
It's somewhere in that range.
Humans shared time on earth with another
kind of human being.
It's a little tiny,
three foot tall human being that had
completely different features than us.
Yeah.
Really Contract Homo Floresiensis or
Florida.
What's that?
12,000 years ago?
Yeah.
Okay.
That's nothing 12,000 years ago.
Like I'm,
I mean I'm trying to imagine plus as
long did they were,
those people were just like us 12,000
years ago and they were a tiny little
thing.
Almost like a,
like a cross between a human and a
chimp.
They don't really know exactly what
their skin color was.
What did it look like?
Put it next to a drawing of a full
grown.
Like now,
man,
he's shredded and he's jacked.
He's got,
I'm going to fuck this whole perfect
muscles.
Doesn't it ever eat fast food?
Troll some Dick and this little critter.
Wow.
There's even,
there was even speculation that they had
eaten humans or attacked humans.
Do you think they bred with us and
that's why they're shorter out in Asia.
How dare you know?
That's what it looks like.
See that one,
the drawing and the far left Jamie with
the guy holding a spear.
That's what they think you live.
If there's a full size version of that
and see if he could find that.
Oh Jesus.
So they,
these were like all most like what we
were like,
I guess when we were on our way up the
food and they just developed a chain.
Yeah.
Well all three Australia kiss or
something like that.
Like one of our earliest ancestors.
Australia.
Yeah.
Well Australopithecus is like a modern
human,
but like the one of the first versions,
I think,
I want to say it a million years ago,
but I'm probably just making that number
up.
But you know,
human beings in this form,
they don't,
they don't know the exact number
obviously,
but they think we've been around in this
forum for only about a quarter million
years.
Give or take a few little dragons have
venom.
They do have.
Okay,
thank you.
so the use of thing,
it was bacteria and now they think it
was van.
Okay,
I'll show you his picture.
I was,
I saw it one way.
So I went on a rock and you'd go like
right behind like some bro,
like uh,
like some leaves and like some,
some branches.
So you get an up close to him and it
still sort of scary cause you can
probably get through the branches but
probably not,
you know,
and you could just take a picture from
Mick that close all this Hawaiian was
coming out.
Dude,
I show you this at the store one night.
Can you imagine the horror that you
would feel if a Kimono Jag and was
clamped down on your calf?
Yeah.
You felt all that hot poison going into
your body and you were trying to get
away.
Yeah.
And you,
you broke free with a big chunk taken
out of your calf and it's a bad about to
leap on you and you're trying to run
away with a limp hobbling duane
screaming no and no.
And running through the bushes and you
look back and you see it just taking its
time,
walking,
coming towards her,
taking its time because it knows it
doesn't have to chase you just tracks
because you can't,
you can't go far.
You're all fucked up now.
So it oh yeah,
they are.
And you know,
eventually it's going to catch you sick
and shivering and it's just going to
start eating your asshole first.
Yeah,
they,
they just bite them in the legs and shit
or they got to be careful.
They don't get stompy smells with his,
with his tongue.
Jesus Christ to use a tongue to smell
what?
A creepy fucking creature.
A jetson.
These,
these,
these buffalo,
they're not natural to the area they've
been added in,
so they don't know what the fuck this,
oh,
they've been added into feed 'em.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Shit.
But they died.
They'd say go to the watering hole and
the Komodo dragons node,
they're going to go to the watering hole
and they just fucking wait for him.
And so he jacked him on the leg and then
he slowly making his way towards him.
Imagine if that was you and you had to
see that thing walking up the bank
towards you.
Some guy got killed.
The boy,
I'm a person,
you're not supposed to eat me.
I can think and I can reason.
And I'm progressive and I have health
insurance.
I have two credit cards.
They be killed.
The kid,
I have to call someone,
don't eat me yet.
I have to make a call.
Hold on,
let me get this task.
Don't hate me.
Yeah,
I have to choose my face.
Eat me.
I'm checking twitter.
There's a bunch of them around that one.
Just go an ass hole first and you're
feeling all the blood rush out of your
body while this creepy lizards chewing
on your butt ate everything except
those,
those bores heads cause of the horns.
Really.
If they get bored,
I mean an ox.
If they get a bore,
they finish the skulls to Jesus Christ.
They,
the skulls and
everything.
So just those fucking what the called
heads are the only ones left because of
the horns.
What thoughts come up on the inside?
So they eat the bones.
Yeah,
they killed the kid.
They just stomach out.
He went to pee,
but alone and they're like,
oh,
this one's by himself.
So this guy I met in floors and deep
Laura's,
his guide found a board that had been
bitten and was dying and the bushes.
And,
um,
so he was like,
Hey,
you guys want to see some shit?
It's,
his board is kind of like,
ah,
like this.
The Venom,
it started catching up and he took them,
he dragged him to the watering hole and
he threw it in there and they just
ripped to shreds in front of them.
He showed me this video he made.
It was so fucking cool.
What does it look at the size of the
bone?
That guy's eating?
Yeah,
they're all on [inaudible].
Oh my God.
Look at that.
There's something about them.
They're the cold,
unfeeling look in their eyes.
Like when he opens his mouth and you see
all those teeth alive.
But that I,
yeah,
that's a real,
an all black.
That's a thinking creature that's trying
to eat you.
It's trying to eat either you or a
buffalo and eats a water buffalo man.
He doesn't use knives.
It's not using and there's no fork.
There's no bullets.
It's eating a goddamn water buffalo.
So we're going through waist high grass
trying to find these things and then you
see one pop its head up like the zone,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
You got to like get behind it and try to
like force it down the mountain.
But there's other ones around so you got
to stay closed,
keep your eyes up.
It was pretty cool,
man.
Do you would love that?
No,
I read the monsters like that.
You would love that.
Fine.
I'd be terrified.
I don't want to be around them man.
Why are you around them?
Oh it was so cool.
Well I found out what I was in Bali and
I was like,
I'll probably go to somewhere else from
there and this guy met from Jakarta was
like,
you know,
you're right next to the Komodo dragons.
You can do that.
And it's like what?
That's here and it was just a couple of
boats and you're fucking there.
Wow Dude.
Fuck that.
No Man,
you don't love it.
They almost got Sharon.
What's her mace?
[inaudible] Sharon Stone.
Sharon stone's husband.
Rarely.
Yeah,
even they almost got him.
He was a newspaper man.
He was a like a reporter and,
or a journalist or rather,
and he went to do something in a cage
with Komodo dragons and he had socks on
in the fucking thing.
Thought it's white foot.
It was a zoo and he went and got him.
What do you mean bid his foot bit the
fuck out of his foot.
Dude went to the hospital.
Crushing his toe.
A thrashing it's body around?
Yeah.
Um,
what he had to undergo foot surgery.
Oh,
come on son.
Yeah,
I was a shoeless foot.
Oh,
I thought it was a sock crushing his big
toe.
Ouchie Wawa.
Oh.
The zookeeper asked him to remove his
white tennis shoes to keep the five foot
long reptile from mistaking them for
white rats.
So,
hey yo dude,
take your shoes off.
You'll be cool.
Don't worry about it.
As long as it knows.
And then they attack that foot.
It's like,
why don't you tell me to take the shoe
off?
I really still had a shoe on the feeling
you must've had.
As that thing is biting his foot that's
here must been like,
I'm really sorry.
My severed the tenders.
They had to reattach severed tendons and
rebuild his big toe that was crushed by
the dragons jaw.
Jesus,
you have to piss again.
Yeah,
but do you have enough room in that?
Do you want to empty that?
Come on,
man.
He sure.
Yeah,
but there was only a little bit left
cause I had to pitch on again.
Overspill don't overflow.
I want to repay in professional at this
man.
But here's the thing about animals like
Komodo dragons and wolves.
I love the fact that they're real.
It's one of the things that makes life
fascinating is that there are these
ruthless merciless predators.
Jamie's shielding his eyes from Laurie's
deck.
Oh,
the image.
Why don't just put the image on me for a
sec is educational.
You don't want to show his,
Jamie,
could you get away with doing this on,
on youtube or instagram where taking
might be in trouble just because we
mentioned that your opinion,
that level of censorship on the
Internet.
Here's the deal,
dude.
Do you know that if you whipped your
dick out and took a leak in front of a
school,
you'd be charged as a sex molester?
Dude,
I do that all the time.
And thank you for telling me because I
will stop.
Yeah.
For Real.
Like if,
say if you're walking past the school
and you're like,
ah,
I gotta take a leak and you just
innocently walked towards a patch of
trees and you piss there and someone
from the school calls the police because
you had your dick out.
You have your Dick says that the school
doesn't matter.
Guys.
You know I was doing,
I know a dude who got charged with that.
I know somebody who,
we both know.
Somebody who got,
who's hooking up with a girl on school
property late at night.
They needed a place to pull over so they
can fuck in the car.
Oh,
what's was on school property,
but it's fucking 2:00 AM,
you know?
Yeah.
They're trying to discourage that
robbery.
Yeah.
I get that condoms thrown out the window
at a fucking,
she has to get showing up for school in
the morning and drop your kid off.
You could slips,
breaks her hip because she stepped down
a condom.
Those a little shiny school shoes.
The kids were with the hard bottoms,
don't get good traction.
What?
Like rules about doing stuff within a
thousand feet of schools.
Yeah,
stuff like that.
So many schools in Hollywood,
you gotta be so much shit happening
within a thousand feet of them.
Wasn't that one of the issues too with
pot shops like
yeah,
I fucked with them too.
I can't be anywhere near a church.
The church parts.
How Larry this,
it's like if that's really the case,
does it,
is that one?
If that really is still the case,
but I get it though.
If you really believed and you really
believe that your church was sacred and
important to you,
you wouldn't want like one door down no
door,
but you not sign.
All churches are not,
they're not the ones.
I'm like that with the lawn.
It's like you see in the movies,
a lot of them in in la or just like in
between two apartment buildings.
But also the question is who gets to
choose?
Who gets to choose that?
Like what?
How much distance between a church and a
liquor store?
Well let's,
I want to know is selling liquor okay.
Is it okay?
It seems like it's okay.
It seems like a lot of people are doing,
it seems like a lot of people are buying
it.
It seems like we all agree.
Okay,
so if it is the case,
w w why that radius radius of a,
not even like up blog.
The rules in Detroit was the same shop
saw also prohibited from operating
within a thousand foot radius of a
church school park,
liquor stores or other dispensary or or
a drug free zone such as a library.
Hmm.
They all somewhat close by 8:00 PM other
dispensary liquor store,
other dispensary.
Okay.
This is all this is a result of people
got,
well I didn't want them right next to
this while I'm doing that,
but this is saying that they can't be
close to a liquor store.
Like a liquor store is the same as the
church.
That's what I'm saying.
You were saying a pot,
a pot shop can't be the alternative to a
business that's already established.
Oh,
like a liquor store.
That's what they're saying.
Don't quit booze.
Yeah.
Well they saying you cannot wait.
So the liquor stores must've lobbied to
have that put in there.
They must have figured out a way.
Zero Liquor Store Union
liquor board.
So yeah,
I mean,
yeah,
I mean there's obviously that doesn't
make sense like the church makes sense.
Reluctantly I get it.
Makes Sense.
The liquor store doesn't make any sense.
Know like why can't I just walk right
next door after I buy some weed and buy
a beer?
Why do I have to go 500 feet further?
And they don't have them here,
but no.
How'd they still drive through alcohol
places?
You just driving a car?
They haven't been Phoenix,
Louisiana.
Yeah.
This place is,
we can drive through and get,
they'll give you a mixed drinks.
Mixed drinks.
Yeah.
That's like how you're going to justify
it.
I'm not,
I'm having the drive thru bar.
It's my a passengers drink.
Well I wouldn't drink and drive officer
and Louisa.
I don't think I looked that up.
Your drink,
your passengers can drive,
can drink,
can drink while you're drawing the
driver.
Cantors and Louisiana is on another
level.
New Orleans is on a totally different
Yeah.
Will you with me in New Orleans,
we had this driver,
we didn't know we had this driver who's
hilarious,
funny fucking dude.
I wish I could remember his name,
but he was cool as shit.
We had them for a couple of days and a,
when we're hanging out with this dude,
he was telling me that he got pulled
over outside of New Orleans because he
was walking down the street with an open
beer,
I forget where it was,
some other city.
And uh,
they pulled him over and he had two
beers in,
in a paper bag and when they're pulled
him over,
he was talking to the cops,
the cops like,
where are you from?
And uh,
he's talking to the cop.
He pulls out the other beer and cracks
it open and starts drinking it.
And the cops like,
is there something fucking wrong with
your head?
And he's like,
what?
He goes,
wait,
where are you?
Where are you from?
He goes,
New Orleans.
oh,
okay.
Oh,
you don't know.
That's not allowed out of the bushes.
Do that anywhere else.
And he's like,
for real?
He's like,
why I'm not doing anything wrong.
I'm just walking.
I forget where the trashcan was,
what he was outside of New Orleans for
sure,
but he was saying that they,
that he had no idea that you couldn't
crack open a beer and start drinking in
front of a cop when he's asking
questions.
I had done nothing.
That's the best about Southeast Asia.
You get a beer with your walk with it
like a fucking free America.
You're just like out there.
You're not going to do anything.
Have a good time,
man.
Just too many dumb young dudes that
would bring drinks and him on people and
be walking on the street with open beers
and be goofy.
I guess so maybe just here,
maybe here,
but London's got a little bit of that.
They drink outside.
Nah,
maybe not in this trace a drink like an
outdoor pubs do.
I've seen it in England.
Would people boozed up on the streets?
Yeah.
Beating the shit out of each other.
Oh yeah.
I mean that's going to happen.
It's like don't put yourself in position
where you have to fight all the time.
What the argument is for.
It's not about drinking outdoors or not.
It's about like don't drink so much.
Right?
Yeah.
Don't get so drunk.
Decab and you can do that in one space
or you can walk and do it.
That doesn't matter.
I wonder what the argument is for a 2:00
AM like cut off time.
It's all Christian Shit Dude.
Is it?
It's all remnants of Christian Shit.
Who Cares?
Why can't we just be up longer?
Miami,
it's like 5:00 AM and New York.
It's four or later.
A lot of places it's not.
If that heard they're gonna change the
La two to four.
Four.
Yeah,
I heard that will make change.
That comment store super weird.
They'll stop close it too.
You don't have to until then.
Why?
Yeah,
because there's guys who want to go up a
good point.
We didn't have some weird ass shows,
man.
I might do a 2:00 AM set.
If they ever do that,
I might.
I might book myself for a 2:00 AM set to
the comedy cellar.
I go a lot after 2:00 AM two packed
rooms.
Yeah.
Packed.
I mean like what time of those show
starts?
They start late,
I suppose.
Start at like 1130 and I'm up at like
one 45 to wow.
And it's just like,
and it's all great crowd.
Yeah.
If those are the kinds of people that
are up.
Yeah,
sure.
Come on.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people that are on
different schedules.
A place like New York,
you can find 150 of them go at 11:30 PM
and I can start my night.
Oh yeah.
And you're still have a great long time.
Yeah.
And people in New York,
like,
they fucking go hard.
They go so hard,
so much drinking in New York and meet
people at their show.
It's not like,
give me a number.
It's like,
let's go somewhere right now.
Yeah.
Let's just go to a bar.
There's 30 within walking distance.
Yeah.
Let's keep going.
Let's just talk.
They just drink.
You know,
Dunkin had,
um,
Greg Fitzsimmons on his podcast this
week and,
uh,
I've only listened to the first,
like 10 minutes or so,
but a Dunkin was talking about how
different New York is in terms of like
diversity and all the different colors
each other.
Yeah.
He's liking it.
I see it a couple times.
It's been pretty fun,
man.
Just be able to like booze up and like,
not to worry about getting home.
Yeah.
He loves it.
I walk home from the stand.
He takes a cab,
you know,
it's in the normal,
he's a,
is he living in Brooklyn?
Living in Brooklyn?
Of course he is.
That fucking hit.
No,
that's right for him.
For sure.
That's the spot.
Yeah.
I mean,
he was a silver lake kid and then he
went to,
he's doing the same thing.
He seemed like Williamsburg.
Right.
I think park slope.
Same Shit,
isn't it?
It's past like,
it's over gentrified.
Oh,
that one's gone too far with style.
Can afford it.
Ooh,
I like it.
I might move in.
Yeah.
That's my style.
Um,
I saw,
I was watching one of those house
flipper shows.
Yeah,
it was uh,
you know,
what is the,
some of the real estate million dollar
listing,
that's what it's called.
Million dollar listing,
New York birth defects.
And um,
they had a house that was for sale in
Brooklyn that was like a,
they built like a Georgia mansion in
Brooklyn,
Brooklyn in like 1920.
And they,
you know,
they were trying to like put mansions
like southern style
mansions in Brooklyn.
It's like 11,000 square foot house.
I can't afford Williamsburg.
Really?
Yeah.
I thought I had to go there cause they
won't be able to afford Manhattan.
And then I found out when I got there
I'm like,
oh no,
no.
Manhattan's cheaper now the cool parts
of Manhattan where I live,
it's cheaper.
Jesus and the cool parts of Brooklyn.
Why is that?
It got this.
Gentrification has his path.
At first you have bad neighborhoods.
We're not talking about warehouse
central Pike.
That's different.
But like,
you know,
ethnic gentrifying first to have
actually both.
So first you have criminals or
warehouses and then the people can like
are cool artists who have no money.
They'll move in,
they can get a giant loft for basically
nothing cause you gotta worry about
getting stabbed or having nothing around
you.
They start adding the arts to the,
to the area,
making it more interesting than people
like Dunkin and me come in,
what we're like,
we like it.
I'm going to be the front lines of this
shit.
You know,
I need someplace to go like you know,
get some food but they're still
criminals around or like lack of stuff.
And then the rich people who don't have
style of their own,
they move in and Co op the other
people's style and then you start
getting too many like coffee shops and
then they start changing the law to
drive out the people who lived there.
Like,
and this is a park where they all are
camped out and go on us.
And every Sunday they would cook out
there and they started saying,
the rich people was like,
oh the smoke is going to my windows.
So he started making laws.
About how you can't have cookouts and
that pretty much just drove out the
people who wanted to have that as part
as their life.
They were just like,
you don't make the laws saying it's
illegal to be ethnic,
but you make laws around it.
Do.
There's a,
there's a park down the street from
here.
Yeah,
we could go to,
it's like only a couple of minutes away.
Yeah.
And if you go there on the weekends,
it's,
it's like a festival.
It's like people use those barbecue
grill to have out there that gets,
then they set up a picnic tables.
They lay out a,
uh,
a cloth and the picnic tables and paper
cups and shit.
And they got coolers at porn,
like Koolaid and shed and they,
they're cooking all kinds of different
things on these,
these racks.
And there's like maybe five,
six families spread out in these areas
that are doing that.
And then as kids are playing and
everybody's running around,
it's a lot of people that live in
apartments that don't have a lot,
like they don't have,
they don't have a big backyard.
So now they just go to the park.
It's great.
And there's like this sense of
community,
but he's laughing.
They got music playing.
People are drinking.
Yeah.
Are you allowed to drink booze in the
park?
How's that work?
I Dunno,
I don't tailgating you gotta use cans.
You can't use bottles.
But if you're sitting there on a python,
Kenya,
I think just look the other way kind of
stuff.
If anything,
that would suck.
I mean,
you gotta be able to have a beer,
some beers,
you having a cheeseburger and the park.
That's how I meet.
Some of these freedom laws are like,
I'm not going to do anything,
man.
Let me have a beer with my family.
This doesn't hurt.
Well,
if everyone did that,
you're going have drunks,
my kid.
But that's not me.
I'm not that.
So let me do it.
What kind of diseases can you get from
one of them?
Park grills,
who's cleaning that grill through?
One of the best barbecues I ever had was
on top of in Vail,
on top of the mountain.
So we were skiing,
I was skiing with his chef and he had a
bunch of fucking chicken in his back
marinating in the of the sags are those
boxes?
These ziploc bags?
Yeah.
So he's kept shaking it up,
his snowboard and hitting jumps.
He's just marinate in this chicken and
then he's like,
hey,
you want to eat with us?
I'm like,
yeah,
sure.
He's like,
oh no.
I was going into the restaurant party.
There's no out here and just use that
thing and it's just make grilled fucking
chicken up on top of fucking wow.
The rockies.
It was so good.
So did he have like a little grill in
his pack too?
Oh,
they had the public grill up there.
that thing.
Yeah,
just got some wood and stuff.
It was just coal's going,
I guess.
Oh Wow.
People would like to do that up there.
Those things are so nasty,
so nasty.
It was like the bird shitting on them.
Nobody's ever claimed anywhere else,
but like,
I guess the idea is once the fire gets
going,
nothing's going to stay alive on it,
I guess.
Yeah.
When that motherfucker gets red hot to
the point where you could see her a
steak,
nothing surviving on that.
I mean that's,
isn't that the whole principle behind
cast iron pans?
Like you don't really wash a cast iron
pan.
You don't,
you just sort of scratch out.
Everything's dare throw some water on
it.
But like that dark blackness that you
get from a cast iron pan.
I don't know why,
but when I cook on one of those I feel
like a fucking man sign grill man.
It's about,
I feel like a man in frying pan.
I feel like a man,
if you give me a choice and there's a
cast iron pan and some bitch ass fucking
heats the whole take on the skin.
It's one of those ones that you could
like flip a cheeseburger without putting
in a non stick.
Those are so gross.
And me and Martha Usos nonstick pans and
now a lot of that got into your food
cause they'd been cooking that shit for
like 10 years on the scratch and just
cooking.
Just fucking,
here you go and you're like,
ah,
shut off to it.
Let's go.
Just date it.
Yeah,
it's going to come out and metal flakes.
My dog ate a packet of glitter.
Really?
And he shit.
Yeah.
Shit.
Glitter.
It's like in roped up in his shit.
I was going to take a picture of it,
put it on Instagram,
but I was thinking it's probably like
they could probably take that down.
Get mad at you for shit.
I guess.
I bet they could.
I bet there's rules.
You can't show tits on instagram.
Why on twitter?
It seems like you could show people
fucking this guy stop bro says comedian.
He,
he,
he's a fat guy.
Fat,
cute Greek guys on my podcast this week.
But like,
uh,
again,
I thought it was he to take these naked
pictures.
He just liked his big fat naked body.
If somebody see but never dick.
And he would just be naked with like one
foot in front of the other.
They were hilarious pictures and
instagram was like,
Nah.
Wow.
It's like,
come on.
How rude.
Yeah.
People wrote blogs about him saying he's
be like body,
body positive.
Hmm.
Instagram picture is accounting.
Accounting bring back stabby baby stabby
baby.
Stobby t a fucking marry your brother's
ones.
Yeah,
they're funny.
Um,
you just see a butt cheek.
You don't see like his asshole or
anything like that.
Nothing wrong with 20s doing,
come on instagram.
A sad picture with fucking ice cream
over his,
over his dog.
He dropped one.
Yeah,
he's funny.
It's funny pictures.
Why would that be offensive?
Like scared of nakedness.
I had one way to pay off a bag of bets
on punchdrunk ag of Bats,
but we put bets in a hat.
And so when you have it like,
uh Oh,
I think so and so it's definitely gonna
win.
You know,
I think all of those other,
what I think the other guys don't think
of went and you're like,
well let's,
let's pick out of the hat.
So you have to do whatever the bed says.
Well doctor do wear a diaper for 24
hours.
No shitting anywhere else or pissing
anywhere else except in the diaper.
One change.
One,
change a diaper.
Yeah.
So I had,
I would have to Piss in one and I did it
in the,
in the shower and I took a video of it
and youtube was like,
nope,
no loud.
Wow.
What do you mean naked?
Wearing a diaper fully wearing.
Hmm.
I think youtube is like super,
they're super worried about being able
to put ads on things,
you know,
and being able to uh,
keep things.
It's lame though.
It should be free.
I agree.
But who's got to pay for that
infrastructure son?
Yeah.
You know what I'm saying?
I guess so.
It can't be showing people fuck.
That would be what?
Youtube not be cocky.
Okay.
Not Fuck you.
Attrition.
I care.
You care.
Be Fruit.
You're absolutely right.
24 bit yet absolutely should be able to
show puffery.
Show some suck.
And parents you want to put some
blockers on there?
Go ahead.
Do you know the story of a,
that Guy Vincent Gallo,
the actor?
No.
Made a movie called Brown bunny.
Oh yeah.
It got fully got full head.
H and M.
Chloe's if I get to close seven g and g
every scene name.
Yeah.
And she just blew him on camera.
So she's second wave of gentrification
when she comes into your town.
You know,
it's about to be,
you're still on.
It's cool and hip.
But the Wall Street people are going to
come into the second wave.
Yeah.
What's first wave artists?
Poor artists who that's they therefore
to put up with a crime.
Right.
And then they bring the coolness factor
to the area.
You know,
they use the whoever's living there,
the indigenous mm.
You know,
cultures.
Yeah.
Like what they're doing downtown La.
Right?
Exactly.
Yeah,
exactly.
What does that shirt,
what does it say?
Oh cool.
Blue rebels.
Cold blue rebels.
You know Tandy Lucas sound guy in the
minerals.
Oh no shit.
Yeah.
I love Danny.
It's a,
it's a Zombie Zombie.
A rockabilly.
Tommy.
Billy,
I guess.
Zombie rockabilly.
Yeah.
It's pretty cool band.
But I think that break it up.
So what's next are you should fear,
well,
so I've got this netflix double special.
No,
I'm good.
Um,
July 18th and building my new hour.
Oh Shit.
Let me get back on the road and see more
places.
I want to see more things.
Um,
yeah,
everybody,
it's going to be a great double special.
It's would be really cool now when
you're writing your new shit,
like when you're doing it now.
Yeah.
Are you incorporating experiences that
you had when you were on this walkabout
and now you love it?
I love the term walk off as well.
Oh,
you physically writing them or are you
like having these stores that you trying
to work out on stage or,
I do some of that but,
but my new hour is not going to be that.
So that those will be like side bits.
Um,
mostly I'm,
I'm kind of hearing what rollins said
too about how he does it and it's like,
oh,
some time to process it,
you know,
use it as like references and things
instead of like bits about that,
you know?
Right.
You know,
we have like such as a tag line about
something and not the whole bit about
something.
Right,
right.
Um,
so just in terms of like,
yeah,
I incorporate it when it comes up,
when I start thinking about it,
bill bursts out at once where it's like
with cigarettes in a long time ago.
Like how do you write a new album?
Like what,
what,
what's,
what do you write about,
because I don't know what's on your
mind,
what gets you angry,
what gets you like riled up when you
talk about it to your friends,
whatever that is right about that burst.
Kind of an interesting thing going on
too because he does that podcast where
he rants.
Yeah.
So he just,
it's just him ranting.
So his,
his like ranting muscle and his ranting.
Good.
Durrence it's incredible.
I tried to do that in my intro,
so my podcast a little bit.
Your intros.
A great,
thank you.
I appreciate it.
Really good man.
I really loved the one about Tom Cigar
and the baton has expensive tastes bow
and very funny.
And that was your first one back to
yeah,
look towards it.
Look at that left going like the choice
of me out of here.
I cannot hear him.
Narrations and those things.
Those are some of my favorite parts of
your podcast.
You're breaking down things and getting
excited about things.
Your enthusiasm for these things.
Yeah.
I tried early on to realize like,
Oh,
this is where ads go,
so I don't want to make it just addie.
Right.
But like let's make an actual more
content and then if you have to throw an
ad in there to a fine,
but like he was going to be some good
times as well.
Yeah.
And sometimes I don't even have that.
They still do fucking 25 minutes.
Yeah.
Why not?
If it's funny,
if it's not,
I'll be recording our funny and it's
also,
it's a different thing because you're
getting a chance to see you sorta
unedited,
just ranting.
Just,
just thinking about stuff and talking.
Yeah.
Somebody told me when I had one after
Anderson loss for the first time and it
was just part of a podcast about this
girl cuts herself.
We'll talk about that.
But like in the,
in the beginning it was almost an hour
on what Anderson silver met Tamir was a
UFC fan.
Wow.
And how would he,
it was just this weird way to lose and I
kind of forgot about it now,
but it was like,
yeah,
yeah.
I Dunno.
It's fun.
But that went on for like so long.
Yeah.
Well that's was something that was a
real thing to you.
It meant something to you and that's why
it's interesting.
He was at my first UFC,
he fought Chris Leben my very first UFC.
Yeah.
I saw him become a champion.
He was like my guy.
I was at the fucking five and a half,
four and a half round.
Crazy ending.
Yeah.
To uh,
to jail.
I remember being in a ring with you and
Dana and a and M fucking superman.
What's his name?
He won two championships at heavyweight
and light heavyweight ready to get tour.
Superman or whatever his name was.
What they call,
they call it the natural whatever.
Yeah,
that's Super Man.
Fuck is he talking about?
He looked at me in a way like,
I definitely got the wrong name,
but whatever it is,
trying to figure out what nickname,
like who had the nickname superman.
Yeah,
but we're all in just a ring and it was
like we're all talking about whatever
stuff and then one at a time,
one of us,
you could see them like thinking about
how that fight ended four rounds plus of
dominance by one guy and a last minute
fucking triangle out of nowhere to keep
this one of the best champions of all
time.
Still in power.
Yup.
It was just so fucking nuts and you'll
see one at a time,
randy or somebody,
I remember Mandy doing f for someone
else did it.
They would just kind of go off like you
seem to thinking about something and
they were just like shake their hand,
go
and you're like,
oh,
you're thinking about that fucking
fight.
It was right in the hallway right
afterwards.
Yeah.
God,
it was crazy.
Yeah.
There's a unique feeling that you get
when you're recounting like a crazy
event where someone knocks somebody out
or chokes on the hour.
Jesus look on your face times after the
fcs and we'd gone to dinner and be like,
Fuck Jesus Christ.
And I saw a burger at that same look
after at the comedy store in the front,
after the baby bird don't go in there.
I saw him from far away talking.
I was like,
Hey,
are you talking about the Bay Birdie?
Cause yeah,
I could tell.
I could tell the way you're doing it.
Yeah.
So that's all I'm working on.
Just building my new hour and then I can
get the fuck out of this garbage dump
again.
Just garbage dump Los Angeles.
That what you're saying Hollywood.
How dare you.
How dare you?
This is the place where you've buttered
your bread,
sir.
No,
I like it.
The business I ended up,
it makes me a little mad sometimes.
The business side.
Yeah.
I think as p or had friended and
advisor,
I wouldn't say it's time to remove
yourself.
The other side,
you no longer need.
You negotiate.
So it's fun to travel and stuff is what
I made do.
I think you're right.
Oh,
100%.
Listen man,
you'll all get along way better when you
don't need them.
Yeah.
Everybody will be your friend.
Um,
but anyway,
yeah,
that's all I'm doing.
I'm working on a new,
I'm just gonna do it all about Judaism.
All about Judaism.
Think so.
Well that's a good way to alienate the
white supremacist.
Yeah.
Asshole.
You don't even care about the people
hate the Jews.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Sorry guys.
A bit culturally insensitive.
You're not even thinking about them.
Know where on,
we never found that video of the
evergreen professor throwing his hands
around.
Oh yeah.
There's one video.
I'm pretty sure it's in,
but I need to like double check and
listen to make sure it's the part
they're talking.
Okay.
Sent it to me and I had,
they sent it cued up like right where it
is and it's,
it's so hilarious.
There's probably,
you know what I queued up in
a website,
if you Google Evergreen,
uh,
at what does he,
the president ever gain Pr.
Oh,
I'm in evergreen hand.
Motions are a micro aggression.
Google that emotions are a,
and they have it.
There's a website for sure that as an
article where they show the video and
they have it queued up and when it's
queued up you can see the kids laughing
when they get the teacher to put his
hands behind his back.
Well,
see it.
But that's them not understanding what
they really are looking for.
There's a part of it feels like,
ha ha,
major do it,
and another part says that's a
microaggression.
Don't do that.
Where it's like,
if you believe that,
that don't laugh at someone for not
doing it anymore.
What they're doing is just enjoying
power.
These kids have taken over the school,
right?
Yeah,
that's it.
Okay.
Gimme some gimme some volume
that's
not appropriate.
He's apologizing.
Walks up to the presence,
like put your hands down,
puts your,
got to with his hands to his side.
Yes.
Dude.
And they're laughing at him.
Pastors were slaves and your ancestors
were not.
Your ancestors came here.
I'll free choice and decided to bring
along my people.
Oh,
they're not out their own.
Free will to work and build this country
who's really letting you know that
slavery still has repercussions in
society today and that is what we're
here about.
Three per classroom.
She went in for an applause over.
Thanks.
Yeah,
she seems to not know.
Oh there she goes.
Trying to get off,
but what does he do about that?
He's clapping as well.
He's clapping too.
He needs a,
he needs to seriously stop.
He's clapping too.
Like he had a really good point.
You can't sing something.
We know.
We already know that about,
you know?
Okay.
The version of that,
that super liberal left is the
feminists,
you know that version of that.
There's a version of that which is just
the feminists like that version of
feminists.
That erosion.
Yeah.
There's like this version,
this version of masculine too,
right?
This isn't built right I guess.
Is it though?
I don't know.
I don't really understand.
It seems to me like the alt right for
more,
more than doubled.
A lot of what they're doing is having
fun.
It does seem like a troll.
Like some of it's like show straight
trolling is a lot of it is yours todd.
I can't believe it.
It's like,
can't you believe it?
Well,
maybe it was a job.
I mean like Milo,
Milo Yiannopoulos.
Surely that guy gets him so mad.
Yeah.
Milo is so like,
it's so,
so much of
what he's doing.
It seems like he's having fun.
I love it when they get on somebody and
you just like shit on them a little bit.
They get like someone's a god to them
all of a sudden beyonce after lemonade,
things like that.
And if you shit on them a little bit,
you could get people so fucking angry
or,
you know,
it's great.
It's great.
It's never been a time like this art
fair.
We get so many morons mad at you.
I love it.
Um,
but yeah,
but it's,
what I've noticed is that all of the
Super Liberal,
okay.
You know how like American sports fans
are kind of dumb.
How dare you,
you know,
not all the leads I'm hearing Moreso
that other places we're not very thought
out.
Rude political like analysis.
Isn't that smart?
No.
Same way our liberal left our feminism
is some of the demos feminism in the
world.
Like other ones are more thought out and
more interesting and more like just
thoughtful in general.
Dude,
I think you left America and became a
fucking turncoat.
That's what I'm hearing.
I'm hearing a bunch of bullshit.
Yeah.
So what do you think though?
You should hear people talking.
They're way smarter than the people we
have.
Like,
like,
so our people are just dumber saying
this microaggression shit.
Right.
That's us.
That's having too much fucking free
time.
Is that,
what is that?
As you've left behind what's actually
wrong and you're jumping on,
which is a lot.
There's a lot wrong.
Yeah.
So like worry about that and calmed out.
Mike Goroka show you guys,
it's not like this better shit to do,
so you shouldn't worry about what
actually bothers you.
This shutting bother you.
Right.
You know,
take that same venom and put it into
something that's actually happening.
There's this forced,
okay.
But like that girl,
that circumcision,
the girl that's set up there and it's
like your ancestors were not slaves who
were brought here at mind were,
you know,
and slavery has repercussions and then
everybody starts clapping and it's like
you are,
you're right.
But what is the point?
What are we doing?
Like,
yeah,
it's all obviously ancestors.
Like when do we get over this ancestor
thing?
Like how many generations in do we do we
just treat people as individuals and as
people,
it's nice.
What do they want?
Some people got an advantage for sure.
White people got an advantage for sure.
But it's not,
it's,
it's more so,
but it's not 100% of the time.
So if I came from,
uh,
from,
divorced household,
I didn't write,
you know,
and my dad wasn't around and my dad beat
my mom,
you know,
that can be a way worse and harder
experience then the cosby kids.
Right.
You know?
So it's like,
just because you're this,
it might make the odds harder for you,
but it's not 100%,
but there's an origins thing.
And one of the origins that every black
kid has to face when they think about
it,
is it someone down the line was a slave
and they're not slaves anymore.
But that's why people who look like him
are here.
They're all here because someone brought
them over here in chains.
Yeah.
And there's still true with remnants of
that.
Right.
And there's some,
there's gotta be a weird self esteem or
a self identity issue attached to
knowing that everybody knows who your
ancestors were.
Slaves.
And there's
a certain,
like there's a certain thing that people
do when someone has something and
someone else wants it.
Okay.
You,
if you have a,
a group of people that's different,
it's like really easy to almost think of
them as not you.
Like that's how they've justified wars.
That's how so many people I by
dehumanizing the other,
you know,
and this,
this thing that has to balance out that
I cass is,
I guess just the echoes of that.
It's like we have to get so many
generations away from the,
from people being slaves and any
repercussions of it.
Socially I cannot,
we have to get so far away that it
doesn't factor anymore where we don't
care.
Okay.
That's well expressed for sure.
Yeah.
I like that.
That kind of like calm way to explain
something.
Rarely gets put out and of course
screaming and yelling.
You know why?
Like you're not teaching anyone
anything.
The biggest problem on the left and the
right,
but the ones that are angry,
the angry mobs is they never seek to
educate.
They only seek to like punish.
Also grandstand.
They want to make this bigger here in
that lady's voice,
she was going for audience.
The audience clap two,
three times,
didn't get it.
And it was like,
I'll keep going.
She's seen Oprah.
She knows how to manipulate a crowd.
She knows how to get those people riled
up.
Yeah.
Well listen man,
that's part of being a person.
Like that's half the reward for saying
something that's right is the love that
you get from people when you say that
it's right and they recognize it.
And they go,
yes.
So people get addicted to that.
Yes.
So they constantly do things that they
think are at least perceived as being
right and they get very vocal with
things when they perceive those things
are going to get a very big reaction for
standing up against them.
And it becomes this moral high ground,
sort of grand standing peacocking sort
of a thing where they just are
constantly trying to let everyone who
know how uncool it is to do this and how
wrong it is to do that.
Like settle the fuck down like weird,
weird thing.
And then sometimes they'll see something
that doesn't quite fit in.
Like they'll sit there was trying to
make,
you know how they make rape a broader
and broader and broader.
Oh yeah.
Which was really does think does a
disservice to ripe it does to be able to
make it seem like anyway,
there was some coercion is rape where if
you talk someone into it,
yes,
that's right.
And then a bunch of men was like,
oh well if that's true then I've been
raped a bunch of times.
This is the super liberal left.
It's like,
oh,
we don't want to make that.
We were on wanting to make you be able
to evict them,
so okay,
that's no longer rape.
Coercion was one,
someone under the influence of alcohol,
which was very questionable.
That's a weird one because we all know
that there's different states of mind
and that a woman who decides to get how
to get a couple drinks and then wants to
have sex if the man is sober and it was
a weird one.
It's supposed to be that you're not
supposed to do it because she's under
the influence like that was,
that was the argument that was be
opposition to black and white.
So it's like I know a lot of women who
were like,
oh,
I can't have sex without,
I have to drink before I have sex.
And it's like,
oh,
what's so then,
okay,
it's a split.
Said they don't all think the same
thing.
Of course.
So some of them,
the militant ones want to say you're a
rapist now,
and some of the other one's like,
no,
no.
Women could take control of themselves.
They can have some drinks and lubricate
themselves if they want to.
It's also really the only time we're
ever asking people to the,
like we're saying like you don't have
control,
right.
You're not even responsible for what
you're doing as opposed to like driving.
Like if you're under the influence and
drive,
like no one says,
hey,
it wasn't your fault that you plowed
into that school bus full of kids with
your car because you were drunk,
but used to be the rule.
You couldn't control it.
Well,
it still is the rule,
but I'm saying like it's,
they'll say that if it comes to sexual
intercourse,
but they won't say that it comes to
driving.
Like no one's going to say you couldn't
consent to being behind the wheel.
You were under,
the influence is not your fault,
but you're supposed to know enough.
Like it's supposed to be deeply embedded
in your head enough that you don't go
into that car and started,
even though you're drunk,
but sex,
you're like,
no,
no.
Yeah,
that was,
you can't handle it.
Yeah,
You don't know what's going on.
It's like desperate drunk driver.
You ran over somebody while you were
drunk driving and they're like,
I'm sorry officer.
I was like,
you know,
self defense.
I was drunk.
Same Shit.
Right.
I wouldn't do it on purpose.
I didn't do it on purpose.
I was drunk.
That's why I lost control the car.
Obviously it's hard to control the car
and you're drunk.
Right.
So that's what happened to me.
When did it become illegal to drink and
I don't know.
That's a very good question.
Yeah,
I look that up.
We're not too long because it sees my
peers,
my friends and whatnot.
They did it.
Or like in the 70s or
like what your thoughts on it?
Let's Google it and find out.
Liberal.
Let's take a guess.
I say fifties fifties I 61 that's how
late in the fifties I'm going to go with
69 okay.
This is fun to say that.
I think I'm wrong.
No,
73 73 that seems so late.
Maybe.
Hmm.
I feel like I should stick to the
sixties
first state that adopted any sort of law
was New York in 1910 but um,
port we off.
I didn't know what that car is that I
feel like when I looked this up before I
thought cars like late twenties people
were drug two years into having cars
don't get on your horse.
It's hilarious.
Remember looking this up,
I think like if sometime in the fifties
or sixties or maybe even as up to like
1980 when mad started data,
the states that weren't adopting it,
we're going to get stopped getting
funding for federal road ladies like
that.
So they had to adopt all the laws.
That's like how they forced everyone.
Dude,
of course people would drink.
It would be a bunch of people drive.
But have you tried driving yet?
Dude,
it's awesome.
And the sun was like,
have you tried to drunk?
No,
I'm for sure going to do that.
Sounds like a great idea.
See that's where a horse is superior
because the horse isn't going to crash
because the horse is so bought a pilot.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's almost like a form.
You pass that on top of it.
Oh boy.
Here your form of travel and a lot of
ways you have a relationship with this
animal.
You know like you up to hey there,
mister flapjacks or whatever the fuck
his name is.
You pat them a good old boy and we get
you some feed and give you put the
feedback,
chooses food like what the fuck man.
That's probably a way better way of
getting around as long as you're not
allergic to horses.
Yeah.
That's why I said,
well,
if you're allergic to horse in the West,
too fucked you're living here.
Not a fuck is a person allergic to
horses.
This is how weak our gene pool has
gotten folks.
Yeah.
That's sad.
I feel sad.
I feel so bad for people that are
allergic to animals and people that are
allergic to pollen and people that are
allergic to a lot of people close to me
have allergies.
It's,
it's so hard to watch because it's
annoying like that,
that there's a thing out there that can
do that to them.
Like what the fuck is that?
Doesn't even make any sense.
And it's not that,
it's not the thing.
Self defense mechanism.
Now it's dumb.
It's like grass.
Some kids are super allergic to types of
grass.
There's kids that will um,
like they have celiacs.
My kids are friends with them and you
know,
you have to be real careful that they
don't eat anything that has any wheat.
Uh,
if they're going to tell you this brief,
careful of it become too much friends
with them now they have,
they can eat or to your home.
They have to very strict science is,
yeah,
it's crazy.
Real super strict diets cause they have
an allergy.
I've heard about your phone gets all hot
things happen to you.
Did it?
How much is your fucking straight like
peanuts.
Like if you have that like
two rows behind you in a plane,
you're fucked.
Brian Collins Mom,
he said on the podcast he was talking
about if she eats Brazil nuts,
she gets like terribly ill.
Well I got the resilience of ones that
gross though.
They're not that good.
They're big.
Yeah.
They ain't shit big.
They ain't shit macadamia nuts,
macadamia,
Damian.
But nobody's putting Brazil nuts and
chocolate the fuck out of here with that
big stupid not
big stupid weird tasting
that you didn't have to buy a shoe and
you eat that piece of shit.
You've got to fucking give me half of it
now and half of it later.
If you have like if you told me Dude,
you get a pass on one nut for the rest
of your life right off the bat it over
show that,
think about it.
Yeah,
like I kind of like walnuts.
It's an unusual dry flavor at that weird
once in a while with some salt on them.
Imagine if there was like some on yeas
for nuts.
Same way there are for like ones like
sat you down and was talking to you
about the cashews he's about to serve as
a cashew from the Himalayas.
You could open a whole restaurant called
these nuts.
Joe,
I got to go take pictures of my netflix
double specially called double neck.
That's what I hit.
July Ari Shaffir rocking in and Roland,
I'm very excited that you're going to
have your special on
Canadians and Australians and you
finally get to see something.
Um,
well,
you come all on the day.
You're going to release it.
You're going to be out of town.
Jesus,
Bitch,
what day is it?
Uh,
July 10th.
What about the day before that?
I'm out of town then.
Yeah.
You're,
you're going to be on vacation.
That okay.
Shit.
Yeah.
Well,
we're working at a time.
Um,
when I,
when are you leaving from here?
Yeah.
When are you getting worse?
That's when you're going back to that
dirty,
stinky,
stacked up.
We could really fast forward one off
this and release it later.
Record one off this off.
Not In the studio.
Let's go up on a hike by your house.
Let's do a hike and we'll do a hike.
Podcasts,
podcasts.
You can put it out the day of.
I like it.
Would that work?
Yes,
absolutely.
Beautiful.
All right.
That's what it is.
Okay.
Ladies and Jan.
Oh Man.
Make sure you download Arusha fears.
Skeptic tank.
It's one of the best podcasts in the
known universe and it's one that I never
missed a lunch trucks,
sports as well.
While you're always missing it.
Punch drunk sports too.
Yeah,
but yeah,
but you listen to skeptic.
Thanks.
That's great.
Yeah,
I do worry about that.
I'm not a sports fan so much.
So the punch drunk.
I listened to you guys when you're
talking about fights and I always want
to call in and go now.
Now,
now,
now.
No,
that's not how I got my asshole beliefs.
Just heard.
I heard.
I heard a saw pictures,
Tripoli.
I mean a serenity set up.
Hold up on my butt cheeks.
How'd that feel?
Weird,
man.
Imagine if you were comfortable with it
then it'd be a problem.
Right?
Dude had his fucking finger right under
the rim.
I kept thinking of just going to go
forward.
So he had a touch your asshole.
I was bleaching it.
Yeah.
What does he look?
He had a glove.
What?
This guy looked like.
Uh,
can I class?
Can I guess?
Sure.
I would guess the Diaz like,
um,
like limp and plants and botox and just
like an oddly shiny forehead.
And He,
um,
he's got a perfect haircut and he's,
he's very feminine but in a weird sort
of way and he's just rubbing and he's a
suit on and he's just,
he has white gloves,
their white gloves,
like with the lines in the back of him.
Like Mickey Mouse has
like a Butler's glove,
both to give you a hint.
[inaudible]
who got the person?
So it was an Armenian?
No,
he,
well,
he was a gimp wearing a mask with a
leather leash around them and a
codpiece.
Hmm.
That's better.
It was looking for a porn star,
but one couldn't do it,
so he got this instead.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
It was the person nice to you.
Yeah,
it was plenty of pretty nice,
beautiful mustache through his,
through his gip mask and that's it.
Wow.
Well there you have it,
ladies and gentlemen,
that contact for you.
A lot of content,
a lot of contact every week.
I'm not doing too much travel and stuff,
but yeah.
All right.
I want to get killed her mic on.
Yeah,
me too.
The revolution.
Okay,
well let's go get them in town.
We'll do have them do both.
Okay.
Or we could do a swap cast.
Ooh.
Put it up wherever you want.
Yeah.
You know,
swap cast is sort of Bab burt and uh,
doug do it like it'll go up on births
and we'd go up on Doug's is where I'm
sort of like we did with the end of the
world.
Like everybody put the end of the world
up right when we did the end of the
world podcast on election night.
Um,
everybody got it.
We just sent a copy of it and everybody
just put it up.
Swab cast.
That's cool.
I do.
Yay.
It's democratic or something.
Yeah.
All right folks.
That's it.
Love you.
Bye Bye.
See Ya.