The joe rogan experience,
I decided I try to work on this calmness
and all that.
And for me,
driving and road rage was the worst.
I used to have the worst road rage ever.
Oh Dude,
I was terrible man.
You would not,
you would not recognize me.
I once got taken to the police station
because someone accused me is this,
this is a while back.
But they accused me of a,
exposing myself,
we'll driving.
Uh,
and what the truth of the matters that
someone cut me off and I got pissed off
and I said,
you don't want to,
you,
you know,
Hong Kong Bobo here and uh,
so uncommon Bobo here,
you made a,
you made a like a blow job,
sort of a case against you.
And I'm like,
yeah,
here you go.
Write as a new hash.
Exactly.
Hong Kong.
And he said to people while they were
driving,
no,
no.
I just,
I mean I made the,
I made the,
the,
the graphical motion to have them blow
you.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Like basically,
you know,
blow me a few.
And uh,
so what did the same exactly.
Anyway,
I was kind of like,
I'd forgot about it and this police
officer leaves her business card on my
front porch and apparently whoever cut
me off was just a complete idiot of a
driver and like really apparently
thought I did this.
So this,
this little police officer,
woman is like,
Hey,
uh,
I know you at the beginning of a porno.
I swear to God in the police station.
She's like,
I know,
I know you did it.
And I started laughing.
I look for cameras.
So I thought it was a joke.
Like I thought some friends of mine had
really seriously hooked me up on this
because there's no way it was so far
from my reality.
And she goes,
no,
I know you did.
I have witnesses and I'm like,
you can't have witnesses because it
didn't happen like you're lying.
And we went back and forth for two hours
about this.
This is how bad my road dredge was.
Two hours she was full on,
I'm going to go to the DA.
I'm like,
you can't go to the aid.
There was no evidence.
And furthermore,
anatomically,
okay,
this is my lap,
this is the side of the car and this is
where the steering wheel is.
So unless I'm like hung like a horse,
it is not possible to drive and expose
yourself at the same time to some in the
car next to you.
I'm like,
you can't do that.
So finally I did this lie detector test
and I passed out.
I volunteered to go.
I'm like,
I got,
there's nothing going on here.
It was so good.
Stopple I can't even tell you,
but that's how bad my road rage was.
Like no wait.
He had to go to the station to get it
light or did they have a lie detector?
You're testing the car.
She's got one.
Oh No,
this is bad.
This is a month after it happened.
Like I,
Oh shit.
It was scary actually.
I was,
I realized I was absolutely guilty.
So many girls that have turned down the
$25,000 offer from some king that just
like just goes.
It hits all the ladies like 25,000 week
in there.
But I know so many people that have
turned it down,
but I also know a couple girls that have
done it and that's his fucking crazy.
I think there's quite a few of those
guys out there.
Well,
I've been to Dubai a number of times and
there's $50 ones.
They're $50 for a prostitute.
Yeah,
but what I'm saying is that these guys
that get girls from America and have
them shipped,
oh yeah.
That to me,
that's crazy shit.
That kind of money.
That's a way,
this is a weird reality.
You know when you have like trillions of
dollars,
like there's people who are like,
I think as far as private wealth is
concerned,
like what we know and you see like the
richest man in the world,
man,
not really.
Okay.
Because what you're getting is the
richest man in the world who has assets
that are measurable,
like in the stock market.
When you're dealing with canes,
you don't have any fucking idea how much
those guys have.
You don't know.
Why should you know?
I got a buddy who,
they have a bank.
I got a buddy who's a billionaire,
real live billionaire and uh,
never knew he had money for years.
He was just,
um,
my friend's friend and uh,
never knew.
We hung out in New York and everything.
And then one day I was reading about his
family in the newspaper and I went,
Holy Fuck.
And I called him on the phone,
I'm like,
you have money?
And he's like,
yeah.
I'm like,
no,
no.
You have like fucking money.
Family does.
Yeah.
And I said,
this is bullshit.
We have never gotten to take advantage
of this.
I said,
you have like crazy fuck you money.
So years later he came into the money
like where it was his,
oh,
that's so creepy.
Just sitting around lazy waiting for it
to happen.
We worked hard,
but,
but someone did die.
I don't want to give away who we
possibly is,
but okay.
But in one year he went from fucking
Zenith,
the Nadir,
like he,
he straight to rehab,
like in the year end,
a year from when he like took over the
money to,
he was,
he would call me and be like,
I'm in Vegas.
I got the top floor of the,
when rented,
I get slip and slides down the hallway.
There's,
there's strippers and hookers
everywhere.
And we got midgets in a storm trooper
outfit serving the strengths and he'd be
like,
I'll have a private jet picking you up.
Get here.
Now how much money did he inherit?
A bout $5 billion.
Ooh.
Oh my goodness.
And he's not fun anymore.
That's the best clip right there.
He's not fun anymore.
That's a complete ball changer.
God Damn.
He's not fun.
$5 billion.
It's the one guy that I,
not fun because the rehab kind of killed
it.
Killed?
No.
You only needed a year before he went
into Rehab.
Yup.
Wow.
That's hilarious.
And what was it for coke?
He was smoking crack.
Oh,
the merits.
Rancho
freaks and Geeks.
Lovers and children.
What's going on?