Ma, can you turn it off? Unplug it or does
they're like, yeah, I should, Huh? Yes,
totally.
It's Kinda Nice.
This is the early menu screen.
I guess the Ustream users are seeing
us live right now. That's good.
So Hi Duncan. Hi. In the
sovereign. Yeah, cause I tried to,
I thought you guys are going live
so no, but extra bonus. But it's,
this is how fucking disorganized as
bitches. This is how we roll. All right.
Three this organized to
like a motherfucker head.
Your cell phone.
[inaudible] your bank card
or license your thoughts.
No Sim card. No disco, no
photo here. Your blood,
your sweat, your passions,
your more fashion.
You were saying [inaudible]
around [inaudible] lesson,
your habits,
your fats,
your fears or address your
shoe size to one year's
schedule online.
I want you to look in your home here.
Take credit controller and sake
alone. Get a job, get a pension,
get things a laundry.
Play the flood wall into fields north.
Them tuned [inaudible] George
[inaudible] your emotions during those,
your dreams, your checkbook, your
essence, your sweat, your screens,
your security, your sobriety. You're
in a sense, your society, your cells,
your taste distance.
Go back to bed. America. Your
government is in control. Here.
Watch this.
Shut up.
You are free to do as we tell you
me back. Here's Macker's.
You can use cold.
Here's TV,
clear some and some older commercial lots.
Jeremy [inaudible],
so forth.
Here's popcorn. Deers magazines.
Here's milkshake cares blue Jean.
Here's Patty bar.
Here's Lauren piers with balls.
Or here's baseball catheters
on competencies. Video
game. Here's coal a lot.
Here's 10, here's
college. Here's all night.
[inaudible]
no,
go on.
Go back to bed. America, you're a
government is in control again. Here.
Here's American gladiators.
You watch this show,
go back to bed America.
Here's American gladiators.
Here is 56 channels of it.
Watch these picture where we recharge.
Bang their fucking skulls together and
congratulate you on living in the land of
freedom.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].
No strings, no, no games, no left here,
no way. No teenagers, no
fat, no freak, no scary.
There's no between, no
trouble. Here's magazines.
[inaudible] patty bars.
Here's Lauren [inaudible] baseball cap.
[inaudible] very means there.
May 3rd meet their needs.
Their May 3rd me long in the summer show.
Huh.
Wow. Pretty intense, right?
That's good shit. Yeah.
That's Adam Freeland and the
song is we want your soul. Fuck.
That's apocalyptic man. That, that
song scares the shit out of me.
That's a brilliant song, man. It's Google.
That thing scared the fuck out
of me. They definitely summed it all up,
dude. It was brilliant. It was brilliant.
That was brilliant.
The funny thing about it is though,
like if there was a way to
authentically sell your soul,
there wouldn't have to be any
trickery involved in that.
Like people would just do it. Some
people would definitely do it. Well,
there's people out there
called bug chasers that are
gay guys that are trying to
get HIV. Trying to, yeah, I know. Trying
to find sick guys to bang them in the ass.
Yeah,
they have bug chaser parties.
What the fuck you just told me about
this last time I hung out with them.
Surreal Shit, man. It's real shit. Well,
it's because apparently if you're gay
and you are having unprotected sex,
then there's this always this paranoia.
It's kind of floating around you that
you might have aids because isn't it?
I don't know that how it works.
But when you get aids,
it doesn't it take some time
that show up or something.
Like sometimes he doesn't show.
It's a very, very complicated virus.
It's a very controversial,
you know, I've never heard,
there's no major virus that I've ever
heard anybody say is fake except for aids.
Have you ever heard them? No
one's ever said that. You know,
I mean if you ever heard like the
gonorrhea is fake. You've heard the,
the AIDS is the only one that I've ever
heard. Like this is not a real thing.
Yeah, that's right. You can't get aids
with a flashlight. And it's a tricky,
it's a tricky one because yeah,
we're sponsored by the fleshlight fuck
a flashlight instead of letting people
with aids. Fuck you. So you can get a
bug. That's ridiculous. But, well, I did.
The idea is that you have HIV first and
that HIV causes AIDS, right? That's,
that's the, that's what
they're saying. Yes. So it's,
but how come it's not like one thing?
Why isn't it like, you know, you,
you get boom, you get syphilis
areas, their syphilis.
Why is it this tricky thing where you
know, you, you know, you're, you're sick.
Oh No. You know what I'm saying? Like
you get HIV and the HIV becomes aids.
It's like, aren't you dying
of HIV then? Like what do you,
I don't know why they do,
they describe it in two ways.
There is a thing that I saw how it,
there's different ways to define whether
you have aids cause there's a certain,
isn't it like the eye you're with aids
means is your immune system is broken
down, right? Right. Does the in that,
is that possible that you can get that
from both the, from different things.
So it's like what they're
saying is HIV causes AIDS,
but it's not the only cause of aids.
Is that where they're saying, well,
I mean like maybe some other
immune system breakdown type shit.
Like there's other people that
argue for like, there's a guy named,
what the fuck is his name? Uh, he's
uh, we'll, I'll look it up real quick.
But to Peter Duesberg, Peter Duesberg,
and he seems to be like this,
like really credible biologists from the
University of California Berkeley and
he's got this crazy theory that aids
isn't real and that what it is is a
conglomeration of a bunch of other
diseases and apparently he's been totally
discredited.
And you know,
all the mainstream time Tiffin studies
have pointed to know there is a very real
connection between HIV and aids and this
is very irresponsible what he's doing.
But this guy's still deal in it.
Like you still saying it and he's got
like all these papers that he's written on
it.
It's like it's such a weird fucking,
you know that's a tricky
ass topic made sure is.
And it's tricky to cut through the,
you know all the information sources you
have about it. You have to think, okay,
are these information sources that
came from pharmaceutical companies,
manufacturing drugs does happen.
Oh hell yeah.
I just read this thing that there
is a famous book by an advertiser,
I can't remember his name,
but it's supposedly like the one of
the old bibles of advertising. And he,
he said that rather than just selling
a product, don't be ridiculous.
What you should do is create a demand,
create the demand first and then create
demand for something that doesn't exist
yet. Create a mythology around
the thing you're selling.
So I'm kind of describing
it in a clumsy way,
but he said what he did is he
started advertising and papers, um,
pianos, no, not pianist.
He started in papers putting articles
about how it's popular right now for
families to,
uh,
be learning music and taking music
lessons in their living rooms that,
but he ran a piano company.
So the idea was instead of
just selling pianos flat out,
he created this new thing in
society and in the, in, in the, uh,
Zeitgeists, which is that, you know,
a really good family does have
a piano in their living room.
And so then people naturally
decided to start buying the pianos.
So in the same way with aids
or with a swine flu or with,
uh, you know, God,
it's so funny to watch
like the pharmaceutical
commercials cause it'll be like
some problem you've never
heard of in your fucking life.
Like do you have minor ankle inflammation
or one thing I saw was like a,
do you have particularly heavy bleeding
on the 31st month of your menstruation
cycle? You might be a double heavy
bleeder. You know, like they said,
they come up with this
thing in all of history.
You've never heard of
a double heavy bleeder,
but like they just invent this thing.
It just start selling the drug. And so,
you know, thinking, I don't know,
you're probably not a hypochondriac.
I'm a bit of a hyper contract.
So think if like you're a woman and you
have noticed like a little more flow
than normal, you're like, I might be a
double heavy bleeder. That's a real quote.
You're being serious. Yes sir.
Yeah, that's true. The real costs.
All you were just joking about the piano
thing. No, but the double heavy bleeders,
no, it's, that's not that
scientific name for it.
They have a different name for it,
but it is.
She fucking double heavy bleeder.
They is the worst name for anything
but it like a triple heavy flow.
It's got a weird name for it. It's so
ridiculous. But yeah. So aids, you know,
this information you're getting,
is this coming from Pharma pharmaceutical
companies selling bullshit medicine or
is it coming from actual scientists
who weren't hired by the pharmaceutical
companies to prove that their medicine
is necessary? It's confusing you.
Do you think there's that much corruption
that they really get a chance to
influence studies and findings
as you really think there's
that much corruption? I think it's
cynical to say that when you live in,
it's an interesting idea though, right?
Like how much corruption is there really?
We know there's definitely
some corruption. Well, they
saved us from swine flu.
I remember how bad that
was. Such an industry, man.
That's the tricky thing is you people
don't understand like there are billions
of dollars to be made and so the idea
that someone would invent a disease, no,
well that's ridiculous.
I'm not going to invent a disease,
but they might make a much bigger deal
out of something that really needs to be.
It's like, you know, all of the sudden,
you know, it was a particular type of flu.
It was connected to a pig and you know,
some people died from it.
Like it's a strong flow, but there's
strong fluids every fucking year.
People die from the flu every year.
Flues are terrible. Yeah. But it's a,
that's a thing that's, you know, they all
come from livestock. No, I didn't want,
not all of them,
but a lot of them come from birds and
pigs and like that's where they come from.
They come from, they come from our farm
animals man. Fucking living together in,
in, in, in terrible conditions. Yeah.
I think it might be making that up.
That's what it is. Because, I mean,
if you look at some of the video of
slaughter houses are like the really bad
cattle farms. That's the 10th
circle of hell there, man. So,
so strange how we're evolving as a,
as a being,
but so we have disconnected our own
personal lives from the murder of animals
for food. Like the connection between
eating animals and having food totally,
completely removed. Like I know so
many people that love cheeseburgers,
but you say, hey, you want to go
hunting? And they'll look at you like,
Oh fuck that are you are redneck?
Yeah. What are you going to do?
You're going to kill an animal.
Like, oh my God. Like, you
know? Yeah. The, the, the,
they'll look at you like
you're a piece of shit. Yeah,
but they'll have bacon on there.
Their cheeseburger.
I love thinking it's a
double murder sandwich.
Cow and pig slaughtered,
by the way,
if you are like,
if you run into someone who's a hunter,
that negative stigma attached to being a
hunter is, is pretty intense. It's like,
Oh really? JETHRO, do you go out
there and hunt deer out in the forest?
You fucking barbaric man.
And meanwhile you're stuffing your
face full of mystery meat from Bhagwan
yesterday. What the fuck it is.
Yeah. Burger king meet. Yeah, it's,
it's just, it is a very curious thing.
And also the other thing of it and that,
you know, I've, I've really,
I've got Terrence McKinnon the brain right
now because I've been reading food or
the food of the gods. Fuck
man. Um, credible book now,
incredible staff ideas behind
it. So fascinating. The idea,
the big one is the mushroom,
the stoned ape theory for the folks
who haven't heard us. We've talked to,
and we've talked about this before,
but turns for Ken,
his theory was that the reason why the
human brain size doubled over a period of
2 million years,
it's like one of the biggest
mysteries in the entire fossil record.
And he equates it to the time where the
climate changed and rain forest receded
into grasslands and monkeys climbed down
from trees and start experimenting with
new food sources and they would flip
over cow patties to find like bugs and
beetles and shit.
And like they do that today.
And when they saw mushrooms
growing in the cow patties,
certain groups of these monkeys started
eating these mushrooms and two things
happen.
One,
it increased their visual acuity and
made them be able to see much better.
And then the other thing that
happened is it made them horny.
So here you have these better hunters
because they can see things better.
There are probably,
they can throw things and they're
more accurate and then they're horny.
So they're going to fuck.
And then of course,
if they're eating plates
of these fucking things,
they're going to have
psychedelic experiences.
Sure. Even if you're a monkey,
maybe. And if you have psychedelic
experiences like every day,
maybe it's just like, it's like a
forced fed, you know, evolution thing.
Well, can I throw a crazy idea? He so,
and he has a very scientific
mind and I think he,
I mean he hated mentioning
the idea of Sa. Oh, he did.
I don't think he hated mentioning
about if you look at his live lectures,
he always like at one point he said he
would much rather look at what happened
to him when he was in the Amazon and
figured out the thing about the eating,
I don't know the exact
quote but he said um,
he would much rather be able to call it
psychosis then channeling because he was
so anti the new age stuff
and the new age movement.
But if we kind of talked about this
the last time I was on here and I don't
think we ever like the answered it,
which is the question is when you're
having a psychedelic experience,
are you just seeing a hallucination
or are you tuning in with some higher
vibratory,
higher intelligence?
Some higher force of Mackinac talked about
extra terrestrials and if you've ever
been in on a psychedelic and sometimes
you do experience something that you
would think is extra terrestrial.
So this is where it gets weird.
You know how people say aliens like landed
some ship and dabbled with the DNA of
the apes and that's what
caused the super evolution.
What if it wasn't dabbling
with the DNA the aliens did?
What if it was the communication,
like Mckenna said was
coming through the mushroom.
The way they were communicating with
these apes that were eating them was like,
oh wait, hold on. We've got
some potential here. These,
they have brains that could develop their
kind of tuning into us a little bit.
Let's start feeding them some information.
It's like,
imagine if some primitive species on some
other planet found a transistor radio
and they could kind of in
some way understand the
communication coming from it.
They were still super primitive,
but there's some way.
Maybe there was a video thing on it and
you could show them how to make a fire,
like just hit Flint together.
You can make a fire if you
had the intention of like
speeding up their evolution.
Maybe it's the same thing, only
happened organically, you know? Yeah.
I would think the same.
I would think that
more than the other way.
I would definitely think that there'll
be much more willing to travel that way
than by ships. Why? Why do we think that?
If we figured out eventually that
we are all one thing, you know,
if we figured out eventually that all
life in the air and space and everything
combined is all really
connected in some sort of a,
a strange way that we
don't totally understand,
but there's some sort of a connection.
Well then these little like
we're these spores, you know,
these spores are all like they
can go in a vacuum in space,
they can travel in extreme
cold and extreme heat.
They can absorb radiation and not get
damaged and they can travel from other
planets.
Like if,
if a meteor hits a chunk of this planet
can get knocked off and that gets sent
flying into space and it lands on
another planet and those spores,
all of a sudden that we're in this rock
get to give birth on this planet and
just communicate with all
the animals that are here.
That's it. That's the idea. That's
the idea. Yeah. That they're trying,
that they're a transmission devices of
some higher intelligence and they're not
causing your,
I just am so over that notion that uh,
hallucinating or being stoned as
an artificial experience, you know,
like,
cause I,
I realized like I was really high the
other day and I was walking down the
street and I was like, man, this is
fucking beautiful. It's a beautiful day.
I feel great. And then another part of
my brain snuck in and it's like, yeah,
but you're stoned. You're stone.
This isn't real happiness.
Real happiness can only come without the
influence of a truck and that is such
fucking conditioning. I realized, oh
that's conditioning. This is a valid,
perfectly normal, good
experience. Yes. Yeah,
absolutely. And why, why is,
why is it a good experience?
I think one of the reasons is because
your body is tuning in to this plant.
I think marijuana in,
in as the psilocybin has
a plant intelligence.
And I think when you absorb it into your
body, it gives you something different.
It's not just you because
you, you what? You are flat.
All right, you're a receiver.
And when you put things into your body,
there are certain things that you put
into your body that have a very extreme
result. A very, the, the, the, they
bring about a very extreme condition.
Mushrooms are one of them,
right? Marijuana is one of them.
We have to assume that there's,
it's not just go, Whoa,
you're just tweaking your brain. You're
just screwing with your chemicals. Maybe,
or maybe you're tuning in to another
frequency, maybe allowing, you know,
eating these mushrooms,
eating marijuana,
all this different shit
that you do pay AOD.
Maybe it allows you to just
tune in to their frequency.
Yeah. And, and, and
maybe it's not just, um,
a real experience.
Maybe it's a better,
more advanced experience than whatever
the normal non stone state of being is.
I was just talking
sometimes, but sometimes not. I mean,
when you, when you smoke like heavy,
like oh Gee Kush type weed
and it turns you into a moron.
That stuff's not that good for the cause.
But if you follow that,
if you call it uses, you remembered
the, hold on a second though.
Do you remember the time we were all in
Houston and we smoked Joey's we'd, yeah,
and Joey is smoke sativas now. But back
then he was smoking the deep indicas.
This was 400 pound Joey.
This was,
he would go with the old g Kush dog visit.
That's all I, that's all I roll with.
And you, we smoked it. We were all in
the car and we smoke Joey's and when we,
when we got to the hotel room,
we were all standing in the lobby going,
what the fuck
can, can I, do you remember what happened
before it got to the hotel room? No,
cause it's the only time that's
ever happened in my life.
We went up train tracks. Do you remember
that? We were driving on train tracks.
Do you remember that?
Oh yeah.
You were on the very right and you were
on the train check lane like Oh yeah.
It was very confusing.
Yeah. Yeah. We were fucking,
thank God I was sober while I was
driving. Yeah. Yeah. No, I know.
But like just a weird wrong turn.
Yeah.
The real problem with that weed is that
it is your fucking crushes your memory.
Like you don't remember what you were
talking about five seconds ago like we
were standing there. Just be dazzled
going, what the fuck man? What's wrong?
And then somebody said it,
I don't know who said it.
We smoked Joey's weed and they were like,
yeah,
Oh shit. Yeah, I know
that stuff is narcotic.
That shit is cough syrup is
narcotic. It is. And Cough Syrup.
It puts you in this car.
It feels like you're taking
like, uh, they got that shake.
It enters. Yeah. It's not good
people in leg, extreme pain, I
guess. It's probably really good,
but some of it is not good and you never
know what the fuck you're going to get,
man. You know, that's the thing, unless
you're, you're going to a dispensary,
unless you're like,
you know,
talking to the people that work there
that are professional stoners, you know,
you never know.
What the hell are you going to get if
you're just buying weed from some dude,
you don't know. You get a
Goddamn crap shooting your hands.
You can get that coma weed.
Yep. Not to mention, I mean, well
I guess it's true at all week,
but it's like where did
it fucking come from?
Like I wish he could just see with every
weed you could just rewind and watch
from inception to like
making it into your pocket.
Cause it's such a funny
journey that stuff has to take.
Marijuana is a fascinating plant.
And what's more fascinating?
The fact that it's illegal.
I mean that's of course fascinating.
But what's really fascinating is that
it's one of the most useful plants in the
world and it's illegal.
Like just forget about the psychoactive
effect just for nutrition and for use to
make it a far superior paper,
far superior cloth.
And it's illegal to grow at eve.
It's illegal to grow.
Even the shit that is non psychoactive.
Yeah. You can't even grow hemp.
Like the stuff that can't get you
high at all. You can't grow them
but what,
but you think like him,
you can grow in Canada and Canada's
not like food school and crazy.
Everyone's coming, you know, making
a shitload of money on him. You know,
went in it be like, I mean,
couldn't we judge what hemp growing,
you know,
financial shit would be by Candace.
Yeah, but it's not really a not, but it's
not based on logic. That's all thing.
It's like the moment you think that.
No, he makes a good point. I mean,
you know, it's not like they're,
they're fucking never hear the
lease oil barons. Right. Shit.
Look at dollar Ham bitches and
may box and shit and diamonds.
It's bullshit. It's hemp empire bitches.
This is how we roll here at him. Socks.
Not that good and cognitive
are way better, but is it
really? Yeah. Try Him closer.
Great.
Yeah.
Can you give a a Chica hemp. Roz.
She's going to have bloody nipples
at the end of this kind of stinky feet.
What's good about him? It's stinky feet.
You found out the girl that I had
brought him like how bad your feet sweat.
Great candle at your feet.
Smell you stink. You little
bitch. You the best candle.
Fucking hippie bitch. The best
candle collection ever though. Yeah.
With your flower paint on your face.
Oh Man. What is that? Or
the dragon fly on this fine.
Oh, that old girl. Why do your feet stink?
Wasn't it, wait, wasn't that a
Donovan Song? Why do your feet stink?
Damn girl,
could you imagine if you're living in
the 60s when people just discovered like
drugs and marijuana and the
whole culture completely shifted.
You imagine being a part of that time.
You know,
we kind of accept the fact
that LSD has been around. Yeah.
And we were in high school.
We all knew some guy who fucked up.
It took too much LSD.
Now we imagine in the 50s man,
from the 50 to the sixties what
a giant transition that yes.
Straight after the forties right after
that sweet Hoffman made that wonderful
experiment in the laboratory
and it exploded into culture.
And then before the CIA could start trying
to beat it back into the bottle, like,
oh fuck, we gotta get this shit back
in there. People are growing beards.
Nobody wants to fight.
But before that could happen when it
was just billowing out and just Ginsburg
was giving speeches in front of
just thousands and thousand people,
not Justin Bieber singing about bullshit,
but some bearded gay dude reading poetry
in front of thousands and thousands and
thousands of people on acid and Timothy
weary doing experiments with Rom Dawson.
It was just this incredible moment.
And then the fucking CIA got involved and
the government got involved and all of
a sudden that's when they started pumping
shit into the zeitgeists where it's
like, Oh yeah, Smoking Pot,
Huh? It makes you lazy.
LSD will drive you insane mushrooms.
That's what communists eat. Who
knows what it all is. But yeah,
all the shows that you're saying, they
did this through what newspaper articles?
The Reagan administration. Look at what
the Reagans did. Now it's 10 years after.
It was like a, uh, it took, uh, it
took some time. But this is your brain.
This is your brain on
drugs. It's like, oh,
really? So you think that like
the sweeping act of the wood,
the 1970s psychedelics,
when when they made everything,
whatever the act was that
made Lsd, mushrooms made all
that stuff scheduled ones.
Yeah.
So clearly that was because they saw
there was a big culture shift that was a
culture shift decision,
right? Absolutely. Yeah.
You cause you can't, it's,
you cannot successfully pull off the
level of conditioning that is omnipresent
in this country or in any tyranny.
Uh,
if people are taking psychedelics where
they're communicating with some higher
intelligence, whatever you want to call
it, plugging into the plenum, uh, okay.
Murder even accelerating your
mind to a higher frequency.
That's the other argument
that maybe it's not,
you're not taking in an alien
intelligence when you share a dog,
but you're just pumping your own brain up.
Like it's like taking caffeine.
Does that give you a super intelligence?
No. It just makes you accelerate.
It makes you more, you, you have
more, you know, you're, you're,
you're getting amped up.
If you're on a site,
it could be that.
Imagine taking a powerful psychedelic
and sitting down on your couch to watch
your nightly Fox News and
why I want a psychedelic.
You see a Fox News reporter talk about
someone who won the medal of honor and
the Fox News reporter says he died
fighting for our freedoms and Afghanistan.
Now maybe if you're just some diluted
alcoholic redneck in a trailer and
somebody says, somebody died
fighting for our freedoms already.
Freedom is a very mysterious word,
but someone's fighting for
our freedoms and Afghanistan.
Maybe you can hear that and be like,
God damn it.
I don't know how our
freedom got to Afghanistan,
but someone needs to
protect it over there.
But if you're on a psychedelic
and you hear someone say that,
you're going to be like, wait,
hold on. What the fuck is freedom?
What is freedom? Is that something
you can even really fight for?
And Afghanistan? Wait, terrorists
are supposed to be in Afghanistan.
You mean that's the only place you can
plan terrorist attacks and the rugged
country of Afghanistan. You can't do
that in China, Japan, Europe, France,
any place where there's a hotel
room with an Internet connection.
Are you serious that we have to be over
there fighting some s Cobra commander
when in any part of the grid you can
eat just a 12 year old with some fucking
matches can do some pretty heavy
damage to the infrastructure man.
Are you seriously expecting me to believe
that soldiers are right somehow in
Afghanistan fighting offs, some kind of
imminent threat that isn't anywhere else.
Cause if I was a terrorist and there
were a shitload of American train death
machines in my country and I wanted to
plan a terrorist attack without getting
interrupted by machine gun fire,
I'd probably just head somewhere else.
Just get on a bus and go somewhere where
I'm not going to get shot at while I
plan my nuclear attack on
the New York subway system.
So emotional right now. Wow. I'm
sorry. I'm Sarah Pailin gave a speech.
You Sarah Pailin recently.
And in the speech she was talking about
Pat Tillman cause she was like in Pat
Tillman's town. She was
talking about Pat Tillman. Uh,
sacrificing his life for
our freedom and you know,
and she actually quoted that in a speech
and it's like, it's really well known.
Two things.
One that Pat Tillman was
extremely disenchanted with
the military once you got
in it and realize how disorganized it was,
how fucking chaotic and fucked up it was
to the point where some people on the
Internet speculated that they even killed
them on purpose cause he was talking
to them, you know, let me know.
That's probably Wacko talk.
But it's just the fact that
he was very vocal about it.
And the second thing being he
was killed by friendly fire.
He was not killed defending the enemy
and they tried to lie about it and they
tried to lie about it for a long time
and it eventually got out that he was
killed by friendly fire.
But they tried to make it seem
like he died in this heroic attack.
I know he was killed by an American
and a cluster fighting for freedom.
It's a cluster fuck man.
These poor fucking kids, man,
that you imagine being 19
being talked into doing this shit for a
bunch of blood thirsty motherfuckers who
just are trying to get whatever
they're trying to get over there.
Whatever the fuck it is, whether it's
lithium, you know, whether it's, you know,
minerals in the mountains that
they use to make cell phones,
whether it's 90% plus of
the world's opium supply.
90 fucking percent. I mean, God dammit.
Heroin is absolutely
addictive. Okay? Yeah.
People who try heroin get hooked.
Heroin is everywhere. Okay,
so you need to sell it. Someone's selling
it. Who's selling it? I don't know.
But 90% of it comes from this one place
where we have to be to save our freedoms.
Yeah. Like really? What the fuck
man? Yeah. What the fuck? And that's,
that's the thing, man. And that's
what's so frustrating and it's not,
here's the thing,
I just want to say this.
You can't criticize it because if
you criticize it, you're a shithead.
You don't appreciate the troops
and what they're doing for you.
And that's not the case at all.
I just don't like the idea of these
fucking people leading us in any direction
where you need to sacrifice your life.
Well,
I don't believe it if
I don't believe them.
Every time I meet anyone
who's been in the military,
they're authentically fucking
good people. Are you very, I've,
I have
yet.
I want to let someone know why.
Because they're warriors and warriors
have discipline and the things that they
go through. I feel the same
way. Most military guys that
I know are cool as fuck.
Yeah. Cause the, first of all, they get
broken down in training. You go through,
once you,
once you go through all the fucking
physical reserve rigors of basic training.
Yeah. That's brutal to,
to the average person.
And then you become a part of a group
that has a code and you feel honored to be
there and it elevates you as a human
being. Yeah. It elevates them together.
You know, it removes a lot of your ego.
You know, there's a lot of like the,
the regimen of the
discipline they did develop,
they can apply that to the rest
of their life. Like very easy.
That is why it becomes
incredibly infuriating when you,
they're being used against trapped in
a meat grinder for no reason for and
reasons dropping.
Like some of the coolest,
most fascinating brave is to rope
people in a fucking meat grinders in the
military. Industrial Complex can
sustain itself on their blood.
Right when there's been so many fucking
lies. I mean, the more you look it up,
the more they may go go into any of
the stories on the weapons of mass
destruction before we invaded and,
and compare them to what we actually
know that they really knew when they said
that.
It's like they did it on purpose.
They wanted to get in there for
whatever fucking reason. Yeah.
And if it's some crazy, the world
is gonna end. If we don't stop this,
but we can't tell you shit. Like
I would love to believe you. Yeah,
I would love to. I would love to
believe that the reason why you're a,
you're not telling us exactly what the
fuck is going on is because you're really
protecting us from some insanely evil
thing that if we knew about it, it would,
society would collapse.
But our strong, brave,
powerful leaders are going to
guide us without our knowledge.
I would love to believe you if
you weren't all full of Shit,
if she weren't all getting busted left
and Ryan cheating on your wives stealing
money, jerking off on babies at the
Bohemian Grove, you worship the owl
God molec he's that slow
having gay sex.
I mean,
how many of these fucking guys in
the Bush administration where day,
how many of them did? There was a
ton of them. You know how you know?
Because there was a guy who
was an embedded reporter
named Jeff Gannon, right?
Jeff Gannon ran a website
that was all dedicated to gay,
like military men. It was like military
studs would like, did have dog tags on it,
a little towel over their cock and it
was like a gay escort service and this
fucking guy was running it.
And he was an embedded reporter.
He was in the White House throwing all
these lob questions at the pleasure of
the president. Like, when
are these Democrats going to
come to their senses, sir?
Like, like what kind of a fucking
question is that? You know,
like that kind of Shit and me why I was
just sucking cock sleeped in the White
House,
slept in the fucking White House and at
least one occasion like what the fuck
man,
he's not, I mean it's the
funny thing about it is what,
the only thing that's surprising about
it rather it becomes extremely surprising
according to how conditioned
you are a [inaudible].
And one of the first things you have
to realize in any country that you're
living in is there some percentage of
your mind is filled with information that
has been placed there intentionally
to make you a good citizen.
You are conditioned.
Uh,
I just say Great National Geographic
documentary on North Korea and everyone
should watch that. It's on
Netflix instead of view. Watch it.
And the reason you should watch it is
because you get a very extreme case of
conditioning. And the way these
people act. And uh, you know,
it's basically the way they got
in there as they followed. Uh,
a doctor was removing cataracts,
uh, of North Koreans and um,
they told them that the camera crew was
there just to monitor the, all right,
what he's doing, they didn't tell North
Korea it was national geographic. So they,
you know, at the end of the thing that
people who can see stand up in this room,
they're pulling the bandages
off their eyes and they can see.
And the first thing they do, they don't
think the doctor that helped them,
they stand up. There's a picture of
Kim Jong Il and they go, oh, thank you,
great heater.
I will work five times harder
in the salt mines for you.
It's, yeah, I saw them say
that. It's true. That's real.
That's the conditioning.
That's conditioning. And it's, if
you think as an American citizen,
you don't have some of that in your
fucking brain. You're out of your mind.
You're conditioned. We all are in
it. Because when you're growing up,
that's what they do. What do you do? Use.
And it's also that we would
like to believe that there
is some sort of a higher
ideal.
We would like to believe that America
is something that's above everything and
we are noble and brave.
We do do the right things and we are the
police force for the world because we
are the only good Christian nation that,
you know,
is here to support the right values.
Yes, we have. Everyone's good in mind.
The conditioning. Yeah. I mean, but
there's a lot of pride behind that.
It's like it's, it's similar to
the idea of being in the military.
It's like you're a part of
something bigger and greater
and more noble condition.
And so the whole, that's like military
is like the highest level of that.
And then being a proud citizen,
it's just just slightly below them and
that's all. But it's also an ideal,
I mean it's also like it is
conditioning, but it's also like, wow,
wouldn't it be ideal?
We all did have a moral code that was
like really responsible and we were really
cool to each other and we were really
disciplined and we did the right thing.
And we didn't, you know, I mean if
the codes, you know, it'd be the,
they exist on paper so that
they are an ideal, right?
So if we're all proud of that ideal
and we subscribed to that ideal,
that does kind of elevate us.
Well. I think that, um,
it's, I think it's better. I honestly,
I do think it's conditioning,
but I do think that framework of
conditioning is better than a wild,
like free for all.
The thing is not that the, I mean I
think that if you look at a beehive,
there's conditioning happening
with Carmen's from the queen.
I was around the Bi to be,
it's not to say that like, uh,
we should allow society to fragment
into like individual units that are all
running around screaming that there is
nothing to believe in. It's just, uh,
the idea is that yeah, of
course, man at the, the eye,
the human ideal. The ideal of making
sure that, you know, if you hear it,
if you hear about life, liberty,
and the pursuit of happiness,
if you really think about that ideal, the
pursuit of happiness, life, your health,
and being healthy and being able
to evolve and be strong, liberty,
your freedom, your ability to do
whatever you want and to do that,
to pursue whatever happiness that you
want with that liberty, that's amazing.
If this country really stood up for those
ideals and people were really fighting
for those ideals, we will be in
some kind of like techno utopia.
There'd be Cordova milk bars and masculine
cocktails that you could drink and
perfectly, perfectly, uh, uh,
engineered pharmaceuticals
to enhance your intelligence.
Because in the 60s,
they didn't cut off all research on
psychedelics and they would have made the
leap into really why it was working and
why it helps people who are depressed,
why it helps people who are alcoholics
white helps people who are dying.
They wouldn't have gone underground and
we would have so much more research,
but the very fact that psychedelics
are illegal marijuana is illegal.
The very fact that the, that we are
not allowed to put into our body.
Anything that we want shows us that
those ideas that you're talking about are
not being upheld but suppressed
right now.
What's behind that meets the man man.
What is the machine behind it?
How does it happen?
How is it in the same situation today as
it was in 1970 with all the information
that we have, you would think that 40
years would go by. Well that's ridiculous.
That's a long ass time with all
this information that we have.
There's so much work that needs to be
cleaned up and there's so many assumptions
that we had made in the past about so
many different things in our society that
we have found through the age
of the Internet to be not true.
And one of them is everyone can access
marijuana studies. Now, when I was a kid,
I thought marijuana gave you brain damage.
I heard all kinds of crazy shit.
I thought for sure you could probably
die from marijuana. You know,
you can o d on it, you know, there
was so much misinformation. Yeah.
But now we know now it's all very clear
now it's everywhere online kind of. He,
the only way we can trust the government
is if you amend shit when the shit that
doesn't make sense anymore
is inapplicable. You know,
the, the, the, the, the,
these drug laws that were put into place
when people didn't have the Internet
where you couldn't go research all the
positive benefits of siliciden mushrooms,
how many people have quit,
you know,
like really like they've had like
people that were like lifelong cigarette
smokers, one cigarette,
you know, uh, they,
they are one mushroom trip rather and
they never smoked a cigarette again.
They realize like what the fuck
they're doing to their body.
They think about the whole situation,
how ridiculous it is,
how they get sucked into it and they
never smoke another cigarette ever again.
There's nothing that has that kind
of success rate like Ibogaine.
It's another one that's
another psychedelic that
does that. Heroin addicts,
people who get hooked on pills,
they go and do it. Bam. They,
they completely dropped their addiction.
Have a totally different way
of looking at life. Well, yeah,
cause it's a blue stopping it.
How does it get stopped?
It's a, um, I mean,
I think a Terence Mckenna sums it up by
talking about the dominator culture and
the partnership. Uh, but it's gone
ignorance on the part of the people
that are in the position of power.
It must be ignorant as to the effects of
the psychedelics because if it wasn't,
and they were doing them,
if they were doing it and they knew how
powerful psychedelics are for elevating
your consciousness,
if they knew that there's all this
potential that you could take it in a
shamonic fashion if you were,
if you do it intelligently and you do it,
it's like a massive vehicle for,
for human growth.
If they didn't know this or I,
then they're, they're acting on,
they're acting on ignorance because
if they were experiencing it,
if they were doing this, they would
change everything. They change everything.
I firmly,
absolutely believe that of all the people
in charge were doing like weekly and
monthly mushroom rituals,
they would completely rethink every fat,
everything. So you know, they're not doing
it right. They're not. So they're key.
Whoever is in charge of Cape, me
keeping things on the schedule one list,
you know,
whoever is the person who informs the Dea,
like there's these are things we want to
concentrate on. This is, you know, blah,
blah, blah, chase after
this, go after that.
Whoever's doing that
clearly isn't experiencing
follow the money.
That's how you find out who's doing it,
that people are doing it are the people
who make money enforcing the law. Right.
But my point is we need to get
those people on mushrooms. Well,
that's really what needs to happen.
Yeah. I mean, that sounds crazy,
but that might be the way to fix the world
as a way to fix the world might be to
get all the leaders on mushrooms. I
think that I, I've thought about this,
fuck yeah. For Real. It sounds like Hokey,
16 year old parking lot
bullshit. Yeah, man,
we need to [inaudible] mushrooms,
Bro. But it's not just,
it's not just a really, I mean, how much
is mushrooms helped you? Yeah, but I,
I don't, I think I would've been fine
if I didn't have my showrooms. You know,
you're not fine now kid, you
know? But seriously, like, yeah,
I think I like the wet mushrooms
did to me, but if I didn't do it,
I don't think I'll be
fucking like freaked out.
My drawings just wouldn't be as good,
you know? Oh, I think you're discrediting
the information that you get when you have
a good trip. When you have a good trip
and you come back, you're like, Oh
God, I'm such an idiot. You come back.
You're like, wow. Yeah, so
humbled. You know? I'm just like,
I was thinking so foolishly and
now I see it all. It's like, why?
Why wasn't it here to me before? It's
like I was just out of my grasp and yeah,
I have this elevated,
uh,
point of view and it lasts as long
as you can hold onto those ideals.
It's like as time goes
on in between trips,
they slowly became more and
more ether all, you know,
they slowly became more missed. Like you
can't quite grasp onto that feeling of,
of being connected. It's like,
you're like, Huh, it's running out.
You're going to have to go in there
again. Is there a library card? Yeah.
Go into the store to store
your store settings. Yeah.
And, and, and, and I think that, um, what
you're talking about is absolutely true.
And I was thinking like,
you know what,
if somebody engineered a virus that
somehow was like gap gave people a
psychedelic experience that was
contagious, that if you sneeze,
the person you sneeze on is going to trip
out so that there's sort of like wave
of people tripping from some
kind of bizarre new virus
spread across the country
and, and induce the state that you're
talking about. It's gotta be possible.
That's, look, I think, you know, like if,
if animals can spray toxins
out and kill you. Yeah.
And animals also excrete
psychedelic compounds like
toads that have five Meo DMT
on their back. Right. They secrete
it, you know, if that's possible.
So we know they can spit and we know
that they can screen psychedelics.
Well sure they can spit psychedelics at.
Yeah.
That would be nuts,
man.
A fucking frog that just jumps in front
of you and crazy and makes you trip out.
Could you imagine mood ITTO the dad
too. It just hops on you. It's a frog.
Like you're chilling with your boys.
You guys are like having lunch and shit,
fishing, whatever, and all of a sudden the
frog jumps on you or you're like, dude,
he got zapped in the kid's like gone for
like five hours to doon doon doon dude.
Do you remember what town?
Do you remember when aids first came
out and there was that whole thing with
miskitos having aids blood. You
remember that there was like, oh no,
the eighth mosquitoes I
do. Yeah, it's true. Right
work and be like, dude, I got zapped
by a trip and frog. I can't come
repping [inaudible] you'd have
to have your mom calling for you.
You wouldn't be able to
pick up the phone man.
You'd be wrestling with that thing.
You know what?
I figured that the frogs Jack
to the frogs have like a smile.
They're like a smiley frowny face.
It just jumped patio [inaudible] came.
Don't, don't, don't you always hear
that? Seems like you don't know.
Can we do and do you find yourself
falling into the fucking die?
That's what it's Chirp would be. It
would be that song if I did it. Yeah.
You hear about in the field.
Ah, been waiting so long.
They get fucking sing in the car.
Your grandma gets hit with it once.
Who Scrambles Song? Where's the song
coming from? God, that was great.
I'm go, what the fuck man. I'm hearing
singing that you hearing that jump up.
Oh Dude, I have an important
man. Don't, don't, don't,
don't tell me.
Yeah man.
For sure. That's possible for sure. That
happened to me know. I was thinking,
this is a weird thing that I
was thinking the other day.
What was life like before
eyesight was invented? Okay.
Because there was life before ice,
right?
The first life was like single celled
organisms. Yeah. And then it, you know,
they started combining and mutating. Yeah.
And then eventually they picked up the,
the ability to see how fucking insane
most of the world been when there was no
eyesight. Yes. Something
that someone developed that,
but stop and think
about that for a second.
Organisms developed this
ability to see things, right.
To recognize the space in front of them.
If we didn't have that,
if no organisms had that, yeah. This
would never have taken place. Right. The,
the evolution of human beings,
the ability to do what we do,
we have to be able to see
things and touch things. Sure.
You falling in a forest did it
really fall? If no one has solid,
you know what I'm saying is what if
there's other senses that we easily could
develop just like eyesight. They just
haven't gotten here yet. Yeah. Yeah.
That's it. That's totally, yeah.
I mean, if we're, we're okay.
The idea is we'd like to think that we're
the most evolved things ever because
we are for earth,
we're the most of all things,
but we're not as evolved as we're
gonna get. Okay. If like if you,
if there seems to be, if you look
at like the way life has evolved,
just seems to be things just keep getting
more and more complicated and seem
like there's like it gets
like accelerates, right? Yeah.
And whether or not you believe that
there is some sort of a magic man who
created the whole world or some sort
of a, an all knowing, you know, uh,
intelligent design entity
that's, you know, and you know,
non visual.
That's a part of everything.
Whether or not you believe in any
of that stuff. I mean you, you,
you still have to look at the
whole picture and go there. It's a,
it's a very strange existence,
you know?
Yeah.
And you know,
what was weird is back in the primordial
past when blind things were wandering
around, you could have three keys,
we can be a bunch of other shit.
They could talk that blind things
back then if they could talk.
And the ones that just started to see
looked around and they were like a John,
I don't want to sound crazy man,
but we're surrounded by water and
what appears if he coral reefs, like,
what's fucking wrong with you,
man? Larry went insane. Juniors,
nonsense dog about the coral reefs
in the water would fucking idiot.
It's the same thing now.
People start having these
visionary experiences and
they're like, you know what?
I think we might be surrounded by a
matrix of infinite intelligence that likes
to personify itself in the form of extra
mentionable entities that seemed to
look like Elvis. People are
like, dude, shut the fuck up.
You sound great. You sound
like a retard, retard.
Um, but you know, as we advance, you know,
maybe that is what we will begin to see
in some way without having to smoke.
Well,
it's gotta
be something next. There's
gotta be something next. I mean,
human beings evolved out of the lower
primates and the lower primates would make
noises and gestures. And then
eventually we figured out language,
then written language,
recorded history,
and then we evolved to where
we can communicate. Today.
It's got to keep going as to,
it's accelerating.
The changes are happening quicker
and quicker than before. Yeah,
I think you're going to eventually
get born with Bluetooth. You know,
like your body's just going to have
some kind of robot electronic in it now.
All the signals that we send out, you
know what I mean? When you think about it,
signals are relatively recent
in terms of human history,
the history of the human biology,
you know,
I mean signals have only been
around like radios for awhile,
a couple of hundred years
or something like that.
Like how long has radio been around?
1920s wasn't really something
like that Saturdays,
but whatever it was in the 1800 yeah,
so before that there was nothing man you
didn't know signals in the air and then
it was radio and then it was CB radio
and cell phones and satellite there
satellite sending signals or
signals all over the fucking place.
What if we start evolving the ability to
pick up these new things called signals?
Like what have,
the only reason why human beings needed
eyesight was because they had a climb
out of the primordial Malkin and figure
out their way around and it was easier
to not fall off cliffs.
You can see where the fucking cliff was,
so they started to develop this
like what if that's what's going on?
What if we are going to develop the
ability to tune into signals? No,
I don't think it's going to be genetic,
but I think you're going to be able to
talk to each other without saying words
like the more we start getting an
advanced with computers and we're doing
symbols and signs,
I think pretty soon we're going to be
able to start communicating without
talking. Like kind of like I could just
sit there and like look at you in a tent.
You know what I mean?
I think that's the sense that's
DM come when you have a DMT trip.
That's what it feels like.
It feels like communication without
within intent but with no words so I
understand exactly what you're saying.
I understand.
I understand it more of like as a,
like a wave,
like blocks of numbers and letters is no
blocks or number of numbers and letters.
The communication is like,
it's like a very clear and
obvious wave of information.
That thing. Yeah, that's it. Yeah.
I know what you're talking about.
Whatever that wave is that it'll talk to
you in your own language because that's
what you need to hear. But you realize
while this is happening a while, it's,
it's talking that you're,
no, that's not your job.
You're just interpreting what it's saying
and, and relaying it back into English.
That's what you're doing.
Yeah.
Your fax machine is picking it up and
printing out and yeah. Well you just,
you can't, it's like, remember
when you used to have um, uh,
an emulator for windows you had back
and sort of opened up in a window? Yeah.
Like it was all like junky and
didn't want, that's exactly,
that's what's going on. Yeah. You can't
quite understand what they're saying.
So you have to do it through
an emulator software.
You have to like run it
through your own vocabulary,
but you're getting pure intent from them.
You know? That's why like when I, I saw,
um, the, one of the Times I had
this DMT trip, the DMT things,
um, they always, they always
say a bunch of the same things.
So one of the things they say is relax
and don't give into astonishment.
And when I heard that,
I didn't know if the reason why the
said that to me was because I had heard
Terence Mckenna say that. They said
that I didn't know. I was like, fuck,
like what is this?
And are they saying this to me because I
knew they were going to say this to me.
So they're like reinforcing it or is
this just something replaying in my head
because I expected it.
Maybe it's a total hallucination,
but it seemed like what they're doing
is trying to say that they're trying to
say that,
but they're saying it with pure intent
and you put it into the words that you
would use.
And the words that I would use was the
words that Mckenna would you have used
[inaudible] so it's like they're saying
to you, relax and try to take this in.
But they're not using words and
they're saying, look at this.
Like they're showing you things like that.
Keep showing like more and more complex,
crazy images.
And as they're showing you these different
things, they're saying, look at this,
look at this. But you don't
really hear it. It's like,
you know, they're saying it,
but you don't really hear it. That's
the next shit man. Right. Pure intent.
Pure intent with no mouth.
Yeah. That's really good. I like that.
Cause I always, as you guys were talking,
I was thinking about like, well yeah, I
mean I'm sure there's going to be, uh,
you know, through technology and ability
to transmit thoughts in some way.
But yeah, what you're saying is tuning
into something else, which is, uh,
something bigger than
like human communication.
It's tuning into what a Mackinac cause,
uh,
like the guy in my mind or like the
mind of the earth and mine of the earth,
tuning more into that.
And like hearing what that message
is or even more tuning into the, uh,
the,
you know,
universal consciousness or the thing
that connects you to all things and,
and you know, what would be awesome,
man, and this is another part of it,
and I don't mean to keep going
back to the conditioning bro,
but it would be so awesome to be able
to have the experience you had and just
accept that it was real to not
have to go back through your head.
Well, no, I think it's important to
question whether or not it's real.
I think it's important to question whether
or not it's just a pure hallucination.
Yeah. It's just your brain
is been dumped with a,
an extreme amount of
chemicals that are usually,
they're in small doses and your
brain is hit with is Overwatch.
And because of all these synapses go
off and it creates these beautiful
hallucinations. Yeah,
it's possible. I'm not,
I'm not absolutely convinced that
what's happening when you have a DMT
experience is that your,
you're going into an actual,
another dimension and communicate
with actual other entities.
I know it feels like that,
but he could be that my imagination
is on fucking hyperdrive. Yeah.
It's a possibility that you have to
consider as unlikely as it is or rather as
unappealing as it is to me. Yeah. I
would love to think that like it's,
it would be way cooler if there's
a drug that your brain makes.
It lets you talk to aliens.
Yeah. That's way cooler. Yeah.
It's possible that it's not,
that's not what's going on.
Your brain is just getting like walked.
But if Duncan came to you and said,
I believe my dreams,
I think my dreams are trying to commute,
can communicate with me,
you have to at least think
that maybe that's possible too.
That's kind of like same.
You know that your dreams are
trying to communicate with. Yeah.
That's the other thing of you're a dream
master of like push things into the
back of their mind and then in their
dreams they're trying to work out those
issues and those issues come popping up.
That's,
that happens sometimes
people in their dreams,
well I have a variety of
different types of dreams.
Some dreams clearly or whatever
just happened. Like you know,
like Glenn back is like
having a conversation with
me about a pasta because I
ate pasta while I was watching Glenn Beck
and fell asleep. There's, there's that,
those kinds of dreams,
right?
And then there's the other kind of
dreams and the other kinds of dreams,
if you're lucky enough to remember them,
are much bigger than that.
Like sometimes I'll wake up and I can,
it's almost like I'm waking up from a
lecture where somebody in like an almost
like monotone voice is like,
and then the true reason for loving other
people creates a unified consciousness
that allows the furthering of the
evolution. You know, when you wake up,
like what the fuck was that? But like I
think you're kind of like, you're sinking,
you gotta talk more into
the microphone cause your,
your volume is all over the road.
I think you're kind of sinking.
They're pulling their iPods would just go,
fuck sorry guys.
I think I just got a little
too casual. Their fellow, my,
for the last time I did this podcast,
we have shitty likes last time.
These are way better.
They pick you up way better,
but you adjusted and moved away for the
top. I wasn't talking about the mix,
but the last,
the last time I did this podcast,
I got contacted by some of the coolest
fucking people have ever been contacted
by an internet like mind blowing people.
Like people were sending me their art
on Facebook that was like insanely
psychedelic and like I got real,
I got a flood of like the most mind
melting youtube videos of different people
giving lectures. And one of them, and I
can't remember the guy's name, dammit,
which isn't fair to the person who sent
it, but I wish I could remember it.
He was talking about how they're
finding out that in, in, um,
there's no such thing as empty space.
It's just filled with intelligence.
It's just,
it's condensed information in every
single quantum molecule of the universe is
just pure information.
And like what,
what my theory is right now,
um,
is that maybe when you're getting high,
you're tuning into that information
field and it's some kind of extra
terrestrial and library that,
uh,
where the books transform into a words
and letters and ideas that you've
experienced in the past because
there's no other, you know,
there's no other grammar for it.
There's no way to communicate the
information to you because it's outside
language. It's pre language, right? So
it's shaping and according to, you know,
for you, like you said, you Mckenna
talked about don't give into astonishment.
And so that's what you read or saw as
this wave of intent was coming to you.
But to me to dismiss that wave of intent,
uh,
as a hallucination is,
and I know you're doing it speculatively,
I think that you are,
I feel like maybe you're just saying that,
but I think you may have made a
decision about it already. I know, you
know, I honestly, I have and I haven't,
I'm still open to the possibility
that this is all horse shit. Yeah.
But everything is horseshit.
But I absolutely believe that
there's a benefit to this horse shit.
There's a benefit to the quality
of life for the person that's,
that's done it and had the experience.
I think there's a benefit to
the people that are around him,
the people that he interacts with
or she interacts with that you'll,
you'll create more positive energy and
you'll have like a better base to operate
under.
Like the thing you said about like all
these cool people contacting you in the
Internet. Yeah Dude, I have
so many fucking cool fans
on my message board and on,
on Twitter. There's a lot of cool
motherfuckers out there, cool people.
And one of the things that I'm finding
when I'm talking and all these people
that I'm running into,
like we did the, uh,
these shows in England and
a huge percentage of the
people in the audience were
podcast listeners. A huge
percentage. When I yelled out like,
how many guys watch podcasts? Fuck,
they went fucking crazy. That's awesome.
So I'm thinking, you know, wow, this
is nuts. Like this. It's so cool.
They could just download
it all over the world.
But it's so free and open and out there.
Right.
And I was talking to this kid afterwards
and they were telling me how like
there's no one who talks like
this near them, you know,
they're like four for two
hours every week or you know,
if you do two of them
four hours every week,
we get to sit down and talk and listen
to people talk that we don't know anybody
like that. We don't know anybody who
just considers all the different, uh,
options in an argument.
And it has these weird,
bizarre topics that they talk about
and puts themselves out there and it's
really honest about shit like this.
And these dudes are like, dude,
you're change in the way we look at
the whole world. And I'm like, whoa.
I thought about that.
And I'm like,
I wish I had something like that when I
was young. I wish I had something where,
where there was just some,
I could communicate,
basically sit and listened to people,
communicate with anyone,
law and sit and learn. It's almost like
sitting at a table with your, your,
your fucking, you know, you're cool
dad. And his friends, you know,
when you're a little kid, if
you, if you had a cool dad.
And My stepdad was really cool guy and I
would sit around with his friends and I
listened to them talk and I was like,
you know,
12 or 13 and they would let me stay
up and you know, and they would,
they would be sitting around talking and
there's all these architects and shit
and like really intelligent, interesting
guys. And I was like, wow. I'm like, yeah,
I'm kind of thinking in how they think.
And I was like tuning into the way they
thought and it was like helping me,
it was like helping me like see things
like a little differently than being
around a bunch of other 12 year
olds. You know what I'm saying? Yeah.
I totally know what you're, so for a lot
of these people, like they're like, dude,
we don't know anybody like you. We don't
have anybody like you in our town over.
Everybody's thinking inside the box and
everybody wants you to just get a good
job and,
and,
and just move on and get a family and
don't consider anything to go to church to
be a good person. And you know, there's
a lot of people that we're talking to,
they're like,
they're starting to look at this thing.
They're starting to back up and they're
starting to look up at the sky and
they're starting to look to the left
and look to the right and go, Whoa,
what the fuck is this?
What is this thing we're doing here?
Because this isn't just, we're
living life. In the beginning,
Bob was a baby. Bob went to
high school, then college.
He played a bit of
football before down with
his lovely, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no. That's not what it is.
That's just some shit we made up to
make ourselves ourselves feel more
comfortable. I mean, those
events are actually taking place.
Probably is going to school. Bob Is,
but that doesn't mean shit. Okay?
What really means something is we're
flying through the fucking universe.
We are in space. We are in a
ship. It's an organic ship, right?
We're not, we're not on the ground. Okay.
We're thinking we're on the ground now.
We're flying. Oh, am free to
be in space. In a space ship.
You're on a spaceship right now.
It's just fucking huge.
It's a 24,000 mile across space
ship. Yeah. Okay. It's a spaceship.
That's what it is. We're
not, we're not grounded.
It's not like the universe is a
solid mass and we're sitting on it.
We're flying.
We are right now holing,
and we're spinning a
thousand miles an hour. Yep.
Spinning a thousand miles around
around a massive nuclear explosion for
work.
Fuck,
I've got to get my blockbuster video back.
I am Meg Whitman polite.
I am going to clean up California
with conservative thinking and values.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We're caught in a massive field
of time were being carried on the,
on the river of time towards some unified
future where either we get blasted by
a nuclear holocaust or something happens
where you all merge into the, the,
the universe through technology or
skynet goes live or skynet goes live. Oh,
that was fucking Japanese dolls too.
We were talking about that before the
podcast. The Japanese doll that sings.
It was a new job. Oh wait,
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Can I make one more point about where
you're just talking about and then we'll,
we'll talk about fucking
robots. Uh, but, uh, but, um,
the thing that I was thinking to address
the point of like doing a podcast and
getting these kinds of ideas out into
the places where they might normally get,
it's like there's two, two
points. One is this technology,
this technology is only existed for a
very short time. Yeah. Like the 93, right.
[inaudible] became accessible by them.
Yeah.
To have the money to get this kind of
a gear together and then put it on the
Internet. It costs so much less
than it used to cost. Yeah.
So anyone can create these little nodes
transmitting the information. Number two,
this is what I was thinking. Um, there
is an idea coming, I don't know what the,
like when Tesla had his idea
for a alternating current, uh,
this idea came to him in a vision,
right.
So there's an idea coming and that idea
just transformed society and there's
been so many ideas like that
that transforms society.
There is an idea coming,
I don't know what the fucking ideas, it
could be a drug, it could be a machine,
it could be an movie. We don't know
what it is, but there's an idea coming.
That might be the next transformative
idea in the last transformative idea that
finally pushes is outside of uh,
um,
being stuck in the ego structure and
becoming part of everything else.
And I dunno what the fuck
it is, but um, what we're,
what you're doing here by like
putting information like this out in,
anytime you put information that
goes against the conditioning,
what you're doing is like sending out
little messages in bottles and eventually
one of those things might wash up on
some super intelligent person. Sure.
And they might open it up and be
like, wait a minute. Holy Shit. Wow.
I just thought of whatever it is.
They're non 49.
The device that opens up a portal into
the future and creates the machine
Mckenna talked about.
It's like the idea of spreading this
information is to crew is still lay the
framework so that whatever this fucking
thing is that we all know is in the
works and it's a lot more
than a sweet Asian android.
You can fuck in the mouth,
whatever this idea,
whatever this idea is,
it's like snuck in the end.
There's a lot of what people have to,
people have to realize
it's not going to end did.
The real thing is we're living our lives,
we're going through this,
what we think is a predetermined pattern
of behavior following the same roads to
get to work every day and we're
thinking that it makes sense,
but all the while we're doing this,
we're supporting technology.
[inaudible] technology is developing,
developing at a far,
far faster rate than
our biology can process.
You know what I've always said about
movies and songs and everything that it
kind of freaks me out. How
much they get to me. I call,
it kind of freaks me out when I see
like Avatar and I'm like this fucking
amazing and they're like
ropes me in and I'm like, God,
I want everybody to be okay. Fuck those
assholes and want to fuck up your planet.
And you know, you get roped into it and
then you leave like in this like, Gee,
I just went through like a journey.
You know what I'm saying?
My brain and all my room,
my reward systems got hijacked and I
went through this journey and it felt
really good and it felt really cool and
everything. But I was thinking about it.
I'm just like,
that's one of the reasons why people are
so fucking child like and delusional.
And it's not because there's some grand
program or that's trying to keep us in
line.
It's because the media itself,
the ability to create movies
that are super satisfying,
the ability to create these happy endings,
that's what we want to see.
That's like, even though, right,
that's not what happens every day.
That's really what we appreciate cause
that's, that's the highest rewards ratio,
you know, that we can get from,
from watching it. Performance. What,
we're not set up the process that we're
set up to process real events and we're
set up to imitate successful behavior.
We see the one monkey that's a bad mother
fucker that knows where the snakes are.
Any beats a snake with a stick and
everybody runs away. I want to fall back.
Guy He rides with a fucking snakes are,
that guy's cool and you imitate his
behavior. You whacked us the ground.
Find out where the snakes are.
You know what I mean?
It's like they pick it up from the leader.
They get your information. You know, we,
we need to think about
it that way I think.
Yeah. So like what the information coming
from the media now is what it's like.
If I just can't find a man to love me,
you know what I mean? It's like how many
movies there based on some, some woman
either having to choose between
two guys and she can't pay her.
The marriage isn't going that well,
but she meets her or lover from the,
it's all about where their reproductive
cycle it's are the movies are all about
like the, the great conclusion is
a successful reproductive cycle.
Yeah. These, these things
hijacking our reward systems,
these meet music and everything and,
and you know, the, the beauty of music,
it's like the beauty of birds chirping,
you know, get to appreciate nature.
It's like we have this built in beauty
of recognizing rhythm, you know,
thumping on things and
tapping on the ground.
But when you hear a real song that moves
you with beautiful lyrics and fucking
mute like God, it changes your
whole state of consciousness. Yeah.
And it just completely
hijacks your reward system.
And what I'm thinking is that
these things, these, these, these,
these things like songs and movies and
all these brilliant things that people
create, what they're doing
is just accelerating the
need to make cooler shit even
faster. It's like, here's
your award. You want to,
you don't want to make new technology,
make new technology.
And I'll give you Bluetooth image. Oh,
so bright. You give you more reward.
Brain juice, stuff flows down.
Make you happy. Avatar. So blue,
look at skin gold. So high
resolution, more love,
more love. So for that, I need
to get the latest loved thing.
They'll ne latest lovebox Bro.
It's 90 fucking inches across each.
Amazing Three d you don't need
glasses. And it's like, wow,
they got to develop the next.
What's the next thing?
You have to kick it to another level.
We're going Hologram folks,
we're going Hologram. No more screens.
We don't need a fucking screen.
What you need to do is just shut your
lights off and I'm going to have a fucking
play.
It's going to go on in your house.
You're gonna just don't move
because you'll ruin the illusion.
You're going to see it all take place
right in front of you. Turn to the left,
turned to the right. It's all
around you all the time. You know,
they'll start off going to get right back
to theater. Yeah, they'll start it off.
It'll be almost just like a projector
on one wall and eventually it'll be
immersed in reality shows. Yeah. Returns.
Well, you know, they to keep going.
I really like what you were saying about
hijacking. What'd you say? Hi Jackie.
Reward system for love
and for honor and for,
for lost and passion and
all these different things
that are set up to make sure
that you're successful. There's like
this, I'm sure you've seen it yet because
it's fucking awesome. I fluid. If you
ever seen Ferra flew, yeah, fair fluid.
If you look it up,
it's so cool looking at ah,
this kind of magnetic fluid where if
you play certain sound frequencies that
ferrofluid forms into these
awesome shapes and patterns.
And there's a way you can do it
by putting a, I don't know what,
what the material is,
but if you put stuff on a speaker and
you have it set up just right and play
certain tones, the material we'll take
on geometric formation automatically.
And I,
I don't know the physics behind this,
but I think that with your mind,
uh,
what your mind does is,
are there certain patterns that are either
or electronic neurological interface
of your mind temporarily takes according
to external stimuli. So, for example, uh,
if you see something moved from behind
you really fast, what do you do?
You automatically turn around. You
just look, you don't think about that.
You don't think, you know what
I should look. You just look,
because that stimulus is activating
something in your brain and creating an
automatic pattern. Like if you've
ever dropped a cup or drop something,
I don't know if you've done
that and you just snatch it,
you didn't think about it. I'm like,
fuck, I'm like Spiderman. I just,
how'd I do that?
I didn't think about that at all.
That's a pattern electronic
pattern that your brain took.
So in the same way these movies and songs,
when you hear them,
they're literally causing the temporary
neurological state of your mind to take
these, these forms to take
on these forms. And um,
that's very addictive, I think. You know,
because there's certain
of those forms that you,
that are more enjoyable than others.
For example,
like the form your brain takes when
you're on a beautiful woman, like,
you know what I mean? You're,
everything shifts in your mind.
Suddenly everything changes.
The, the whatever it is,
whatever environment you're in,
you could be shitting,
you could be sitting on a giant Turd and
a beautiful woman walks in and all of a
sudden things aren't quite so bad.
It's like,
that's because your mind is the
pattern of your mind is transformed.
And it's like, that's what
these, that's what movies are
doing. And that's what, uh,
you know,
I think people have gotten really good
at understanding how that primate,
neurological geometry works
and they really get it,
activating it in certain ways,
you know, via Fox News, you know,
like you turn off Fox News and it's
like everything's trying to kill you.
Yeah. Um, well for sure.
That's one of the reasons why Fox News
is a huge problem is cause, you know,
propaganda. Even though it's funny, like
Fox News propaganda always makes me go,
well,
you have to be an idiot to believe that,
but there's a lot of idiots out
there, you know? And you know,
even though I mean look,
propaganda,
the real problem with it is if you're
not telling the truth and you're in
control, the media, that's a
giant responsibility. Sure you've,
you've done some horrible,
horrible disservice to mankind
because you're broadcasting confusion.
You're fucking things up. Even
little fuck ups. They do, like,
we've talked about this before,
where whenever a politician gets
busted for a sex crime, anything crazy,
sexual hookers, whatever, there's
always a d next to his name.
It doesn't matter if he's
a republican or not on Fox,
they put d right next to his name.
Right. And then if you ask them, oh,
it was just a slip up, but
you know, something like that,
we just assumed it was a democrat.
Yeah, it's a joke. They make a joke.
I make a joke out of it.
But meanwhile,
what they're doing is they're causing a
lot of people who may be on the fence,
you know, to go one way or
another. So whatever. I mean,
whether or not it matters,
you know?
No, I mean, it matters because the real
thing that Fox is doing, I mean, I,
it's not like fun,
I don't think.
I think part of Fox is disseminate
conservatives conservative ideals,
but really it's like you
want to understand Fox,
don't watch their reporters,
watch the commercials in
between and that'll teach
you everything about Fox News
because it's like they're selling
geriatric diapers. Maybe have seen that.
The one fucking commercial that's like,
uh,
shows like some happy old lady driving
around a moped and our living room and
they're like, you could have
one of these for free. I can't,
that's not fights.
Not Young people listening to Fox.
It's just old in geriatrics
and their living rooms on their mopeds
to two fucking steps away from death bill
O'Reilly to give them the
real deal and keep them safe.
If he's telling the truth,
he's fine. He's, I love bill
O'Reilly. Oh, poor Mitzia.
She would just,
she would fucking watch.
She would watch that and that and if we
all tried to get her to stop because was
always about helping her mental state,
but it's like, dude, I watch terrace. Ah,
they're going to get us off. I
used to watch, I watched that.
I still watch a fucking Glenn Beck,
ironically.
But if you interesting to watch every
now and then because it's sometimes I
agree with him 30% no,
sometimes he makes good points and
then he wraps him up in nonsense.
Then you know, oh, then you go,
this guy's just an actor. Yes.
He's like putting on an
act like what he's doing.
He's developed this conservative act.
He used to be on a morning zoo.
You know what I mean?
And I think maybe he believes
some of the stuff that he says,
but there's a lot of what
he's doing. That's the atrics.
Oh, that's Sarah Pailin.
Shit man.
He's a nut dude.
When he had Sarah Palin who
was interviewing her saying,
she might be the only hope for this
country. Oh, sorry. What did you just do?
We could die like people.
It's almost like he decided he was
going to make it so ridiculous.
Let's see if we can pull this off.
Like they probably had an argument,
like don't say that, man. If you say that
she's the only hope for this country,
everybody's going to know you're, you're
fucking with her. I think I can do it.
I think I'm sincere enough.
Ah, he is a God damn,
that guy snaps next.
I don't know whose or when,
but late at night guys snaps
you. Oh, you're so strange.
He works all the time too. He doesn't
just do his TV show, which he does that.
He also writes like a book
every two months and he also
goes on tour and he does
like live performances and he
was doing comedy for a while.
He was doing like the Glenn Beck like
live comedy performance thing where you
would talk about who crazy
government and he would do like,
like a live sort of a stand up thing.
But that didn't go so well.
So now he just gives like these
kind of like live speeches.
So the motherfuckers just like raking in
money. He's obsessed, he's making bank.
But if you've seen that, I don't know
when this was, it was recently released,
it was from his podcast and he's got some
kind of sickness and I don't know what
the thickness is, but he's crazy.
He broke it heart. It's crazy.
Quickly broken,
hurt.
He's telling his flock about this sickness
and it'd be so sweet of Glenn Beck
cod boats getting stuck sucked. Of
course it's going to happen. Oh,
well you know what though? He's
not a perfect guy. He admits it.
He had done drugs and drank and stuff.
Didn't he like had a problem with
booze or something like that?
Well that's the thing that televangelists
always say when they get caught with
that with getting their dick sucked.
But like that, that black televangelist,
when they're asking these logs, Keisha
did you or did, did you whatever.
And he's like, what was he saying? What
did he say? He said, um, he's like,
none of us are perfect. That
means yes, that means you, well,
there's a lot of evidence. Apparently
he's fucked Eddie Long. That guy. Yeah.
Evidence is that anytime anybody goes
to a bunch of people saying it too,
it's not just one person any long
his name as the fucking evidence.
It's not going to log. That totally got
pimples from Oakland and he would sell.
I go fucking minister. Weird Shit.
Like lick their face and oh no,
weird.
He's like,
he's like in a hotel room with some young
kid who thinks he's a messenger of God
and he's like, look, your face Giamo,
I just like licking your lips of
Moses used to the lips of sheep.
There was,
it was.
It's a Christian thing to lick the
lips of someone who loves here.
Brian ruining the whole erotic cap.
My husband etic atmosphere.
Just strange moaning.
Parliament starts playing.
He puts his Bible down.
I'm Simpson's Pan is like
the biggest travesty. Yeah,
the the the biggest like
crime against humanity.
The idea that you can take children and
pretend that you're religious and fuck
them. Yeah. That's the, that's
the, that's definitely getting,
I mean that might be one.
I mean,
but besides murder and rape and all the
other horrible things that people do.
Yeah. That's one that's really
underlooked you really ruined a life.
How the fuck you going to get
over the fact that big fat,
sweaty guy who smells like your
car just fucked you in the ass.
He smells like Dzhokhar and barbecue
sauce and it just fucked you there.
Not only that, but don't forget that
this man is a representative of Jesus.
When your mind is the greatest person
on the planet. So the, it's, it's like,
it's like someone's assistant
molesting you and you're like, Oh God,
they must be bad too.
He smells like Jerry curl juice and
communion wafers as loads smell the Viagra
on his breath.
Eight like 20 them in between ceremony.
Red Table wine is all about
fucking people's kids.
God Damn, that's crazy thing. It's
amazing that one priest could get allowed,
would be no one priest comes
out and does that. And you know,
and people should be like, well that's
just one guy's just fucked up and yeah,
it's understandable. This guy is just,
he's, you know, we didn't see it coming.
It's crazy. But if you've got like
hundreds of thousands of cases,
like all over the world,
like at what point in time does everybody
step in and start like thoroughly
investigating churches, like having
like security there at all times.
Having cops there at all times
looking for inappropriate shit.
Like this is a scene of a crime.
How many crimes had been committed here?
Who knows these,
we've got a hundred kids saying that
someone made them suck the deck.
Just to put it in context with, oh,
that's a crime scene. God dammit.
Let's imagine that Kmart for example,
now let's say Walmart, let's say Walmart,
all of a sudden word got out that all
these Walmarts all across the country,
the manager was fucking little kids.
It would be what,
one week before the government to send
it on all the Walmarts. There we go.
What is this? Well, it turns
out ladies and gentlemen,
what we had here was a pedophile
ring disguised as a business.
There was actually a Typo in
the training manual that to
for whatever it is like you wouldn't,
you wouldn't,
you would investigate that
because the Catholic church
is so powerful. Uh, no one,
no one's fucking with it. No one's
fucking with it. And that's the,
that's kind of the problem.
And the Goddamn primate hive is we are
not good at dealing with obvious truths.
We're not good at addressing things
and it just want to correct. Yeah,
establish a new viewpoint. That's,
that's one thing we don't want to do.
Once we have opinions on things,
very difficult to get someone who really
just abandoned that opinion and then
recognize the opinion as wrong and
then move on. Very hard for us to do.
And that's one of the,
one of the reasons as primates,
we get stuck in certain types of behavior
because it's comforting, you know,
instead of just being alone on your own,
not knowing whether or not you're doing
the right thing or the wrong thing in
life, you know, you're just literally
working around on guesswork instead,
you know, you have a confidence in, well,
I've always done it this way and this is
how I am and this is right and fuck the
terrorists.
Now we've got to fight them over there so
we don't fight him over here. You know,
and you know,
you,
you have these things and you don't want
to let those things go because you've
argued for those things forever.
Like,
have you ever seen the documentary on the
Sphinx where I'm doctor Robert Schoch,
he's from the Boston University, Boston
University, I think, or University of, uh,
one of the mass, either University of
Massachusetts. No, no, no. It's Boston.
I think it's boss, maybe
Boston College. Anyway, um,
very well respected geologists goes
to Egypt, looks at the Sphinx. Okay.
And notices that there's all this erosion
on the Sphinx and on the Sphinx and
closure that can only be attributed to
rainfall for thousands of years. Well,
the only problem is the last time
they had rainfall and the Nile Valley,
it was 7,000 BC. So
it's was like, you know,
that's like 9,000 years ago.
So that predates where they thought the
construction of the pyramids sat in,
buy something somewhere around 5,000
years. That's like impossible. I mean,
that's like as far away from us as you
know, like 5,000 years ago, you know,
think about 5,000 years for us.
That's ancient Egypt.
So it's as far away from them
as ancient Egypt is to us.
So he's saying we have a situation
where it's at least that old,
and it might be far older
than that because this is
thousands of years of rain.
This has been cut out and thousands of
years of rain has caused it to do this.
So it had to be older,
even still.
So there's a bunch of people
that are theorizing 10,500 BC.
There's people that want to go 34,000
BC cause you add up all the dates of the
pharaohs. So these guys,
John Anthony West, who's a,
an egyptologist who's been studying
all this shit his whole life,
he's one of the ones that's convinced
that the ancient Egyptian history is a a
rich long history.
Not of 5,000 years,
none of 2,500 BC but 34,000 years.
He says it goes back far.
You know,
you just have to recognize
it and understand it and
appreciate it and you can
show the different construction methods.
He's like,
they've got like very clear evidence.
Like this is their building
things very differently here.
And this is below what was on top of it.
So we're talking about something
that was buried in sand.
So they built on top of something that
was far older than what's right here.
And so he has all this shit
explained out and then he shows,
the geologist shows all these fissures
in the water and they explained that this
are in the,
in the walls that's only caused by
water and they explained to all these
conventional Egyptologists
like this has got to be,
we have to reconsider the age of this.
Maybe it's just a bunch of bird p.
So when the the Egyptologists look
at him, the egyptologist goes, well,
what's the evidence of this culture?
You're asking us to consider a culture
from 10,500 BC? Where's the evidence?
This culture? Like what the fuck are you
talking about? What is this? What is this?
They don't want to admit that they've
been teaching for a hundred years.
Some shit that's incorrect.
Yeah.
They want to attribute it to Khufu and
all these different guys that they can
know. Well, this guy existed
at this point in time.
It's documented and taught Moses
the third. This is the guy.
We attributed it to this.
He was around at this point in time.
They don't want to admit the possibility.
That shit goes back thousands
and thousands of years
earlier and they deny him.
He shows all this geology.
He's got over a hundred geologists from
all over the country that have signed
off on this that they have looked at
the erosion and say this is very clearly
water erosion of thousands of
years. Yeah, and they don't care.
They don't give a fuck. They don't
even want to talk about it. Yeah.
Egyptologist only want to consider it.
Well, yeah, that but in a lot of them is,
it's an because it would embarrass
them. Yeah, it wasn't exactly,
it's like they're in
charge of information.
They're in charge of
disseminating information.
You have the clearest information
you could ever have as geology.
It's fucking rocks, man. It's like, what
is this? That is slate. That's provable.
What is this? That's granted. Yeah,
it's fucking, it's rocks. Okay.
You got rocks with deep fishers
for their looks like water.
It's smooth. It goes down just like water
would do. It's not like sand erosion.
He shows this doctor Ron shock shows a
difference between Sandra Rojan and water
erosion.
It's interesting. Isn't very clear
difference what you are talking about,
how like bizarre it is that priests are
pedophiles have embedded themselves into
the priesthood,
uh,
and are doing the exact opposite of
what some pre your think of priesthood
should do or what,
why they're always protecting the priests.
So then you look at Egyptology
and it's curious. Oh look,
there's the exact same structure and
Egyptology w instead of somebody being a
true as store and being like,
wow, good work. Holy Shit,
this is going to transform everything.
That's amazing right there. Like,
you know what? That's a lot of
ink to rewrite all this history.
Let's not waste our time. Yeah, look, why
don't you go investigate that arrowhead.
Okay.
This is the dumbest thing that guy said.
Where's the evidence of this culture?
How much evidence do you think would
be there after 10,000 fucking years?
Nothing, man. It would all be eaten up,
especially houses like American houses,
like a regular house with drywall and
shit and the roof tile, that shit's gone.
Earth is going to swallow that up.
It's
fucking hard, man. Because
if you think about it,
just to empathize with that asshole
egyptologist if you think about it,
I can think of specific times I've gotten
in a fight with someone and known in
my head that I am wrong
in the midst of the fight.
I just know I'm wrong and I just
keep pushing on, pushing through,
even though
I know I'm wrong in clearly
in a, in a, in a, in my head.
And that's just some dumb little fight.
Imagine Egyptologists who stayed his
entire career on the fucking thing.
It's like,
and to epidemics saying you're wrong
about something that you mean being wrong,
being proven wrong on something that's
devastating because that just shows it
like you didn't consider everything
and you have a flaw in your thinking.
Like you had dated this and
you were clearly incorrect.
So the hieroglyphs that you read that
you attributed to all these various guys
saying this is when we built this as well.
Like the Sphinx itself,
like one of the guys I forgot,
I think it's taught Moses the third,
whoever's accredited with the, no, that's
not him. The fuck is accredited with the,
uh, building of the Sphinx. It's not
Khufu Khufu was the guy who was a cat,
made the, he was credited with
the Great Pyramid. Um, anyway,
whoever it was, the, the hieroglyph the
way it said, the way it was, uh, you know,
the,
what the reason why they attributed to
him is because he said that he was told
in a dream that if he uncovered
this, thinks that he would,
uh, get to be pharaoh.
But the problem is it's the word is
uncover. Like if, if it's uncovered,
if that's the real translation, then
you're saying that it was there. Ready.
I don't know how, how clear it is
to translate hieroglyphs though.
You know what I'm saying?
Like if you're reading something and
hieroglyphic how much of that is open to
interpretation because it's
such an alien language. I mean,
it's so different than English to put it
into English words and to put it in, in,
in the context of we're going to recognize
as me having a certain intent. I mean,
God, it's so hard, man. I just
saw this thing called, what am I,
I'm sorry.
The point is that all it says is that
he was there when the Spinks was built.
That's all you know for sure. You know
it just cause it's written somewhere.
You know, I rocked this sphinx and
you know I built La, I built a shit.
And then scientists, you know, a thousand
years to know, oh, Joe Rogan built La.
It's written right here. That
doesn't mean anything, man.
It's a fucking giant structure. Yeah. You
say you built it. Where's the drawings,
man? You don't even have
any fucking directions.
Is this pictures of you assholes with
plates on your heads with fruit and
there's no pictures of you
building the fucking parents? None.
Not a single high rigor roof represents
the construction of the pyramids.
You think,
why would you write that down?
What's really important is how do you
make bread? Oh, it's fucking crazy.
Yo a fire and we got to
fuck with some flour. Yeah.
They have all this different things that
they have written down about their life
and their culture and war and space.
Somebody sketching a pyramid on the
wall and like they're like boring.
Why are you sketching that thing?
We just built it. Forget about it.
Let's talk about 2 million,
300,000 stones connected so perfectly
like in like the king's chamber and all
these stones inside. You can't get a razor
blade in between a man. Well, I mean,
yeah, so I think that, why would you write
down how you made that? Yeah, fuck it.
Just fucking boring. It's just rocks
and stones. It's probably like,
it's a simple way we just haven't
thought of yet. Let's draw me. No,
it's probably something that's
so basic and you're like, oh Duh.
They wouldn't want to draw that
dough. No, there's no way. No,
there's no way. Just the
numbers, the numbers of stones,
they don't know whether or not the
stones were caught or whether or not they
were poured.
There's a separate argument that they
were made out of limestone and it's fairly
convincing and it's another one that's
going to fuck with Eg Egyptologists for
sure. Because the theory is that
they made those stones with like,
they made a concrete out of limestone
and they mixed it and then like set them
in place. So it wasn't that they
moved all these stones is a,
they made concrete and made
these blocks like in place.
Um,
well I think that,
well that doesn't make any sense
either, right? Because if you,
even if you make concrete blocks, then
you've got to pick them up and move him.
I mean, I don't know. Your mind gets more
detailed than mine does in these things.
These things. Did you like you try
to like figure it out? I, I, I'm,
I don't know man. I just look at it. I'm,
I think that maybe I have lazy thinking
and this says that I will just let
myself believe that. Like
I've had, uh, uh, alien crane.
It's just too much work,
right? Yeah. I don't need you.
I don't go into the number
of stones and stuff back,
but I do think whatever it is and the
way it was built is for whether it's the
most mundane,
it's just a shitload of people figured
out how to do it or whether the thing
just teleported in from some uh,
Sumerian dimension or or whatever.
I still think it's a,
it's like awe inspiring that things like
that exist and I think that there is
the tendency in science to
try to minimalize things
for some reason and remove
that, that feeling of like,
Holy Shit, what is that?
It's by the time Egyptologists get down
with everything and it's just like a
snore fast out there.
You've got this ancient insane pyramid
that appears to somehow is a, is Ivan,
and I think I've heard you say this
somehow at some time of the year
lies the summer solstice. Yeah. To visit.
There's a like shafts inside that
point to certain constellations.
There's a bunch of design where when the
sun is rising at a certain time of the
year, it goes like in the temple in
man. It goes like up the shock rose.
It's like there, it's been
crazy, incredible shed.
Like there's so much of what
they did and even the Mayans,
the Mayans had some visual effect on the
side of one of their pyramids that as
the sun would rise,
it would look like a snake was moving up
the side of their pyramid. And you know,
they read worship Wetzel Quad, Alicia's
the feathered plumed serpent. A flying,
flying snake.
Yeah, I've seen the video of the
sheets. Snake Shadow. It's okay. It's
pretty dope. But you know, you think
about these ancient ancient civilizations,
I mean,
how much room for error do you have when
you're moving 2000 fucking pound stones
and you know, you're doing it in
your barefoot with fucking, you know,
a goofy thong on pushing
these giant stones.
Maybe it was just an extinct animal
that used to love to build pyramids.
You know, dinosaurs,
irritating pyramid dinosaur,
right? I look, Eric goes, he's just
shits a mountain nakeds pyramid ever.
That's his, that's his, that's
his beehive. Yeah. Why does
he like to eat clay? So,
yeah, no, it makes a really complicated
Ann Hill. There's only one of them.
They existed and then he died
and he turned it into a pyramid.
So it looks complicated.
Sphinxes it looks complicated,
but it's just nature manifesting
itself through Dung. Well, you know,
we don't know. I mean, I think
are, I'm like, you know, when you,
what I was thinking is if you could paint,
if like you,
you are some primitive person and you
knew that whatever you painted on a wall
was going to get super scrutinized by
anthropologists who are going to look at
the thing and be like, oh, this means
that they worshiped the cow. God. Right.
Maybe you're not I to draw a
cow. Right. Well, I mean, yeah,
makes sense that they would draw cows.
I mean,
that's what they needed to
stay alive, you know? I mean,
it was very important to them. You know,
when people talk about, why did you know,
why did animals worship cattle?
Well, there's two reasons for sure,
but the Indian region doesn't make
sense. There's two reasons. One,
they did like a lot of ancient cultures.
They were embedded in cow cattle worship.
They were like, yeah. What is it called?
Choctaw? He, do you know how to say
that one? No, I just read him seconds.
That was the one that Mckenna talked
about and he shows all these images from
like all the different shit
that they were like had the,
that was in honor of the cow.
They had horns and they were showing
cows and then the idea is that the reason
why people worship cows,
his idea is that there was mushrooms,
it was growing off cow shit and they were
eating them and they were having these
psychedelic experiences,
which makes sense except they also
needed them to stay alive. You know,
you have to look at the fact that if
you're the first time that they invented
culture, the first time that
they invented civilization,
they had to figure out a way to stay put.
Right. That's what I had to do. So they,
they had to figure out a
way to corral the animals.
So wants to corral the animals like,
oh, we got 'em they, they worship on,
they put the horns up like, oh,
this is what keeps us sustaining.
This is what allows us to stay here.
This is what keeps us alive. You know,
they have a big supply of these animals
and then keep slaughtering them. I mean,
if you're a family of four and you
have a full farm just for yourself,
let me think about that man. You
got up full farm with, you know,
30 cows and you've got all these chickens.
You,
you should account and you get a side of
beef. That's all a lot of fucking food.
That shit will last you a long ass time.
Yeah.
And you've got all this corn that you're
growing and all these vegetables that
you growing, you don't need
anything else. You know, you could,
you could do it all there. You're,
you're totally self sustaining.
Yeah. And it's, yeah, it's
safer. You're, if you have to
go out hunting all the time,
you're going to get attacked
by lions and shit. It's, yeah,
but I don't think it's all
about the mushroom. I don't
think, I mean it's, yeah,
it's more, I mean, they, in
India they can, I've, I've read,
they consider a cow dung to be antiseptic.
Yeah.
Yeah. The, the,
the Indian thing I was saying that didn't
make sense is that the Indians didn't
even eat them. So if they don't eat
them, if they worshiped him as God's,
then what happened there?
Because I understand the idea that the
cattle keep you alive and that's why you
worship, but you eat them. You know, the,
the Choctaw, he, okay. I think those guys,
I think they were like at the time where
everybody ate animals. Yeah. You know,
there was no, there was no, no, like
sacred animals where he couldn't eat it.
Like you got to eat everything
that was there. You know,
you don't have that much choice.
But India people are starving,
but they won't go after the cows.
Well, yeah, they, yeah, they, there are,
they do kill some cows in India. There's
some people don't fly that way anymore.
Right. But in, you know, in the Hindu
religion, right. Our cow sacred.
Oh yeah, you, when I was in India,
you would go down the street and
just pass a cow and you can pet it.
Cows are like dogs,
they are sweet.
You are of them and they like it now
lick your hand and they're just really
sweet animals. That's the thing. It's
like, you know, we were like wow,
bowls.
Those people in China eating those dogs,
how could they do that?
Pass the stake honey. Um,
you're eating a gentle, very
sweet creature. That's, I mean,
I'm not saying it doesn't taste good.
I'm not a vegetarian. I eat them.
But you have to recognize when you're
eating that thing, it is a very,
very sweet animal. Cows, cows
are like really gentle, sweet,
not entirely dumb animals.
They, especially if you like,
I mean when you see a cow in the wild
or a cow at a slaughter house or a cow
that's being harvested now you're
seeing something that was a,
that's being treated in the most
horrific way. You know, it's,
it's not in its natural habitat and
I'm not glorifying the way cows or any
animals are treated in India. But I think
that any animal that you shall love to,
it's going to become sweet and
domesticated and seem kind of smart.
You do you understand that Joe
wants to kill tigers? It was,
we should kill tigers. Yeah.
Until everything that kills you.
That's why I'm not done for bowls roaming
the streets either. You know? Well,
I mean, yeah. It's like that's
a, that's an interesting point.
And by just done an off note,
uh,
what is more satisfying than watching
a lion tamer get chomped by align the
Russian video. Any video.
When you see somebody,
you've gotten a lion cage getting
mauled by a lion, there's all,
it's like the one time you can watch
violence without having to feel too bad
because this is a person who was enslaved
and animal that's not meant to be
enslaved or put in a cage prodding and
poking it and getting the inevitable
result. But it's disturbing,
dude. Have you seen the one that,
not the one that just happened where
the guy at, were they like, did the,
I don't know what you call it, did some
worldwide wrestling move on? I'm like,
they both grabbed him and stretched
his arms out for a second.
There are about to rip his arms
off. No, I did see that. Yeah,
it looks like they going
to tear his arms off,
but the hose kept them all got
so close to being the greatest.
I thought it was going to be.
I thought it was totally going to be deaf.
I thought it was going to be arms
come off death. That was a, yeah,
it was about to be like death for that
was amazing that he was still okay.
It was like walking around and got fucked
up. I'm sure there's blood everywhere.
There was blood all over the line.
It wasn't a blood.
There was a jacket that's blood,
but there's a lion attack video on
your website and by the way, man,
why do people on your website
keep posting these death videos?
What the fuck dude?
You get like every,
there's so many like death videos and
like I have a problem not watching
them
and it gets stuck in my head,
but there was just there on the Internet
if they're on the Internet and it's
interesting it's going to
be on my website. I know,
I know. It's not a choice.
You want to have to make
Derek need to see this. Yeah,
I'm gonna well maybe it's not that bad.
Let me see. Oh my God, it's terrible.
Stop. No more debt. Smart
video on your website of,
I think it's Russia and its Elian
finishing the job and it's like,
Geez. It's like, you know,
first the guy's got his arm in the
cage and he's in the lions kind of like
holding onto his arm a little bit and
it almost looks, it's kind of femme fun.
The lines just having a little bit of fun.
The guys got,
the guy's indicates with one arm out,
there's somebody there
kind of holding onto them.
The lions like you're not cats play
with their food and she's kind of like
chilling out looking at the guy and the
guy's like they're in the first second.
It looks like you might get out of this
and then the line for whatever reason
just pulls him into the
cage and chomps down.
I think on his neck you can't really tell
cause the lines on top of him and you
just see that thing that happens.
You know if you've ever been bitten by
a dog or a cat when it just bites in and
it's, it's in for the real
bite. It's doing that.
It's just biding deep and all of a sudden
the guy's body does this convulsive
thing,
which is kind of the last like little
like adrenaline pump before he dies and
it's just this awful seizure and then
some guy in like a military helmet or a
military hat or I don't know, police
officer comes and shoots the fucking line,
which is the saddest part of that.
The lion bellows out is it's
being shot like what the fuck?
What do you expect? What did you think
was going to happen? What can we say?
It's authentic surprise. Like, oh and
that, and that's the end of the line.
The line was doing everything
it was supposed to do.
The lion was passing the lion test.
When the fucking monkey comes and starts
poking, you are washing your cage,
you eat it.
That's how it's works.
That's how it's worked
from the beginning of time.
How long did you think he tricked
up thing and to trick them,
you have to be on them all day. Every day.
Yeah. Those guys are handled big cats.
Those motherfuckers get very intimate
with those cats because you have to, you,
you can't like tell you a couple
months off and go to Sweden.
I came back from the Alps to tell you
what to eat and to talk. I was like,
why the fuck was I listening to you
again, bitch, get over here just yeah,
crack you in the, wait a
minute. You know the fuck.
Wait a minute and here's
my dumb hippie point.
That effect of the lion handler
manipulating this powerful lion.
That is exactly what oppressive
governments do to the people.
And it's the exact same thing
where you have the clear powers,
the power of the people. They
are more powerful than, uh,
we Baka who's like, I don't care
what they say about marijuana.
I'm going to keep arresting people that
they arrest me for arresting people,
you know, so I would, he said, no, I
made that up, but he said some awesome,
awesome shit. Yeah. He got to go on Bill
O'reilly tomorrow. Yeah, he would've been,
he would've been an anchor on Fox
News the next day. But the is like
the, the, the, the people or the
lion and you event and that's the,
that's the horror of the government is
when the line starts waking up and the
people start realizing,
wait a minute,
you can't tell me I can't
fucking eat mushrooms.
You can't tell me I can't smoke pot.
You can't take 60% of my
money away from me anymore.
I don't understand why we
were in Afghanistan. And
instead of being like, well,
that's weird. What time is it?
I have time to grab a coffee.
You start fucking organizing and doing
what you can to fight against it,
which I never do, so I
should shut up. But it's,
you're saying it's just,
it's an idealistic point of view and
the only reason why it's idealistic is
cause no one's pulled it off yet. But it
doesn't mean it's not possible. Right.
Paris, have you seen what
they're doing in Paris? Yeah.
That shits not getting a lot of airplay
is, or what's happening? Tell us in a,
in Paris, uh, I believe it's in Paris,
they're like increasing the age
that you can get your pension,
uh, from 61 to 63. So I guess
it's equivalent to being a 61.
Like for all your life you've
been working or whatever,
and all of a sudden you're about to have
the big vacation before you take it.
You have to work two more years.
And not everyone's that they,
but I think there's other things involved.
They have like serious financial problems
all day. Well, yeah. Well they, you know,
a lot of people were saying the financial
problems they're experiencing, we're,
we're, again, we're about to get a
little taste of that too. But um, uh,
but what you're seeing over there is,
um,
not being carried in the mainstream
press that much because it's a,
it's a mild little revolutions
happening over there.
They caught off the fucking oil supplies.
They're cutting off oil supplies really
to the city yet. Um, and I don't know.
And I was coming off oils activists,
they're fucking blockading
like the Oil Refineries.
There's like a ship full of oil apparently
floating out there and can't come in.
Whoa.
Yeah,
there gas is running out over there from
these activists because there are six
seating there like that.
But the problem,
it's like that's the level of reaction
you have to have to oppression.
So the activists are cutting off the oil
and the reason why they're cutting off
the oil to the city is to
starve the city outside.
The city has to listen to them.
Well somebody call in and explain this
cause like this is like something all in,
we don't have right now.
I'm just
give me off the fucking Hook here.
But they are,
I know they're blockading
the fucking oil and and I,
it's not getting that much play in the
news. I haven't heard anything about this.
Oh, let's go to cnn.com
that was you. Okay.
You would have to think that's breaking
news, right? Yeah. That's breaking news.
Dems look to energize women and
unions. Yeah. Lindsay Lohan backwards.
Scotty, the stock chart. Worst Day
in two months to bullshit stories.
That's their big story. Two things
that make no sense. The stock market,
which is fake as fuck
and no one understands.
You can't even pretend you understand
that. Yeah. After that Bernie Madoff Shit,
that guy was, he even stockbrokers
got fucked by that guy, right?
No one knows what the fuck that guy
was doing. How is that possible?
Then you have a bullshit system,
right? Your system is nonsense.
Even the people that were experts didn't
understand what the fuck was happening.
Yeah. Nobody saw this fucking gigantic
collapse coming. Nobody vocal about it.
Please
shut the fuck up. And then Dems
look to energize women in unions.
What does that even mean? How is that
a story? It's a number one story.
I'd rather look at that. That's
the big one. That's the picture.
And at some haggard old check who hasn't
seen a dick in over a decade and she's
talking about running shit.
You talking about [inaudible] and shit?
Not one that was still connected to
a body talking about running shit.
You ain't running nothing, mom.
Shut the fuck up. All right.
I'm tired of these crazy old
bitches that want to run shit.
Go Meg Whitman. Neh. Donald. No.
Christine O'Donnell. Just because
your vagina doesn't work anymore,
it doesn't mean you get to be a man. You
don't get to run shit. Okay. How dare you.
You heard me? You heard and Joe? Yeah.
You are a man. I'm not talking to you.
I was looking at you,
but I wasn't talking to you.
He's talking to these crazy brides that
want to run shit, man. Stop it now.
The fucking, the, the, the,
what's her name? Um, fucking,
what's her name? Ellen did president.
You would be against Alan become? Um,
I would vote against her just based
on my talkings with Greg Fitzsimmons.
What does he say about you have
to talk to Greg for semis. Oh,
nothing goes public with that shit.
You know what?
I would fucking vote for Ellen
just for the absurdity. I would,
I would hope we would all dance like on
national flag day. Meg Whitman, ladies,
thanks that marijuana is a gateway drug
and that it should not be legal because
if it is more we'll get to our children.
Oh, we've got to protect our children.
I'm so tired of people being able to
say things like gateway drug with no
consequences. Like
that's a, that is a lie.
That is nonsense that has been
disproven by science like you can.
Alcohol is far more of a gateway drug
to bad decisions and marijuana is
marijuana in fact,
keeps a lot of people from ever trying
dangerous drugs because they get fucking
paranoid.
You know,
they think about it because of
marijuana and they get paranoid.
If you're going to start doing coke and
ecstasy and then you're going to do it
anyway. Man, it's, it's, it's out there.
If you want it, it's there. You know,
it's not hard to find pot.
It's out there.
It's not going to change the
ability of kids to get pot.
They can get pot everywhere. I mean,
just drive down the street from my house.
There is five fucking
medical marijuana stores,
five of them in a row and like two blocks.
It's pots everywhere.
You're telling me that pot is, you
know, it doesn't have a GPS chip on it.
So the 21 year old dude who bought it
can't sell it at twice the price to some
17 year old kid. Now you
know, it's fucking, anybody
can get it. It's everywhere.
Pots just out there, man. It's out there.
So you can't fucking tell me that it's
there. That there would be some sort of a,
a bad thing. You know, that that
would come with making it legal.
Making people who are responsible human
beings who want to do something to make
themselves feel.
You're treating them like criminals.
And you're saying that that
being a criminal is okay,
but it's okay for them to be a criminal
because they want to relax and have a
plant that makes you feel soothing and
it makes sex better and it makes food
better. No, you want them
to be a criminal, but yeah,
that's just dom. Let's talk.
Let's look at the gateway drug idea,
and if you think about it in a where all
drugs are lumped together,
all illegal drugs are lumped
together into one category, right?
Some teenagers smokes pot for the first
time. I was like, this is fucking awesome.
Holy Shit. Drugs are great. It's like, no,
actually drugs aren't great.
Certain drugs are great,
certain drugs are fucking awful.
Cocaine is that I, I personally hate it.
I have friends who are fans of it,
but they're annoying.
Someone on cocaine is really annoying to
be around. It's, it's, it's too expensive.
I fucking hate it. And of course the
freebase form of it is awful. Meth,
awful heroin, awful.
These are terrible drugs.
Why are you lumping them together in with
a drug that only seems to have mostly
positive effects on your life
outside of if you smoke it way, way,
way too much and you get a foggy mind
and I don't know, maybe you eat too much.
Well I think you also have to take
into consideration that everyone has a
different biological makeup.
You know,
there's some people that get addicted
to alcohol really quickly to some people
that are allergic to wheat.
You know, some people,
marijuana is not the best thing for them.
But you know what? You know what's,
this is the thing though, man.
There was this one girl,
there was a girl I dated that she smoked
we once and she took one hit and within
two minutes she stood up,
ran full speed into the bathroom,
hit the bathtub and hit her head on the
wall and she just laid in the bathtub
for like three minutes. And I was
like, what the fuck are you okay?
She said that she just got this instant
thing that she had to stand up and run
and she didn't even know where she was.
She just started running and that was
from one hit from weed. Yeah. But yeah,
but no, she wasn't dumb fucking
intelligence. That's bad.
You think one hit, one hit. How
good was the weed? Ohio brick.
We Bong. Really? Yes. Wow. We'll try
giving a skateboard to a nine year old.
If you want to talk about a dangerous,
scary, you give a kid a escapes
or they'll go get you sell like a
propaganda. They'll go slam. Yeah. Yeah.
I'd love to see you in Congress.
I'm running for office. Mr Trussell.
How do you explain all of these children
that smoke marijuana and ran into the
bathtub and hit their heads?
He man, it's like, you know,
you can get my nine year old
kid a skateboard man. Uh Huh.
Duly noted. Mr Trussell, please, please
sit down, take your seat. They'd be like,
listen to this guy. You'd be a ch huge
fuck up for the cause. You'd be like,
when they made the movie of the story,
you'd be the fucking that got it.
Steve Buscemi would play and uh,
he would get up and he'd be super stoned.
Forget what he was saying.
And he would say, hey man,
just like you can't give a nine
year old a fucking skateboard.
Well, the whole thing, I mean, the whole
thing about keeping weed away from kids,
it's like you should, I think you
should keep all things that change kids,
psychological state, that the state
of mind. I think it's all tricky.
It's a very dangerous, I think it's
up in the air. It should be done.
I have a father,
you know,
I think you should be introduced
to alcohol by your father.
You're right. Can I just say something
just to go back a little bit.
I'm not saying we should give pot to kids.
I know you're not just blow it in their,
we should make them
buy it. You shouldn't give
it away. They get that.
They get the wrong idea.
I think for a lot of kids earn it.
A lot of kids through a lot of,
a lot of kids are going through a lot
of weird shit when they're growing up.
I mean everybody is just the reality of
becoming a teenager and then, you know,
growing into manhood or womanhood, it's a
fucking freaky feeling. Like, Oh my God,
I'm going to have to take care of
myself someday and make my own money and
fucking feed myself.
And this is just too crazy.
I don't want to leave my mom's house
and his fucking schools drive me nuts.
How much am I going to have
to work once I got a job?
I'm working this hard when I'm in school.
You know,
all that shit could be overwhelming
to kids, you know, to Real,
especially young kids like 14, 15. If
you start throwing pot in the mix too,
that might send them off into the woods.
There might Corinne them off track
and really fuck with their head.
But what have you were six years old
watching sesame street and you had this
magic guy come and go, hey, uh,
would you like to look at this stoned
as a six year old PR? No, man, listen,
when you're six years old,
your brain is still developing.
I don't think it's a good
move to introduce drugs.
And to develop their minus
the mean street. I want to
talk about this magic guy,
this guy all the time.
I'm more interested in the college
guys in that pot. That's what I,
that's what I would be doing
if I was at a time machine.
I'd be going back in time giving myself,
we'd would you when I was watching sesame
seeds. So paranoid you did to try this?
Yeah. You had to go back in time into
your life and do anything differently.
What would you do differently? Uh,
probably that I was getting myself. No,
I don't know.
Uh,
is there any one instance
from your childhood that you
would redo? You take back?
Probably throwing rocks at that
cardinal threw a rock at a bird. Yeah.
Yeah.
Little baby and a baby cardinal.
That was like retarded or something
like that. But I was like six or seven.
And you know, I think I've talked about
this before. Yeah. What about you?
[inaudible]
same. I, yeah, at once when I, when
I was a kid, I like went in my,
my grandparents love birds and I had a
BB gun and my grandparents were out of
town and I like took that,
drove their golf cart because they
drove around in a golf cart with like,
like I'm on a hunting safari into the
backyard and just shot a Robin Wright,
just killed a Robin and it fell and it
like spiraled down and all the other
burden, like there's bird feeders all
over my grandmother's yard and as a staff,
you know, statue of Saints and these
birds are like dive bombing me.
They were freaking out cause I'd killed
one of them and they're freaking out and
just swirling around. And it
was like, I was mortified. Uh,
and that's definitely something
that I would go, yeah,
fish fish bombing to where used to take
him eighties and put it in fish's mouth,
you know,
like live fish and it would light them
and then throw him off the roof of the
school at people. Oh my God, you guys
are sick fucks. Which gives me his fish.
There's a pond at our elementary school
that you catch them going with Ketchum
and then we put them in a bucket and then
they'll mark God, you guys are a mess.
Fish bombing. Oh, bombing.
Yeah. That's such a fun.
It was great for fishes.
Like imagine your fish.
All of a sudden you're yanked out
of your world into an alien world.
Stare at these things. These things
are laughing. They throw you a bucket.
You're flopping around in a fucking
bucket. You're swimming around in circles.
You can't get out,
but he takes it out of that bucket.
Shoves his big giant Dick in your mouth.
You know this,
this explosive deck lights it on fire
and then you fly through the air and
explode.
That's how you leave this world.
We had also did squirrel baseball where
like the squirrels would go up and you
need to stop because it's,
you're looking at some Dexter Shit fucking
serial killer than what you would do.
Kitten crucifixion
scene in the Bible with kittens.
Have you ever strangled a frog?
Was real easy.
Just put them in your throat
and just strangle it. You know?
Look at their face and then you've killed.
No, I've never killed a frog. Skidding.
Disturbing.
That's one thing I used to love.
I used to collect frogs or inner window.
Well know you guys know what
window wells are. They're like,
we're the basement windows are and
had little sling and the neighborhood.
We had wood frogs would
get trapped in there.
And so as a kid I would take all these
frogs and put them in buckets in the
neighborhood would have like a pet show
where you bring your pet and he's like,
Ooh, first place, second place. And I
didn't have a pet because my cat ran away.
So I would take my bucket
of frogs and I did that.
I'll put like little things
for them to climb up and down.
And that was my pet never won,
but I was at frog free.
That's all I wanted to say about
frogs. I have plugged in. I was a kid.
The thing about frogs is
they've got no rights, right?
You take a frog and stomp on it and nobody
ever goes, what happened to your frog?
I Dunno. He died. Right? Was
buried that bitch in the backyard.
Nobody ever does an autopsy in your fraud.
Go Watch this frog as of a crushed skull.
The fuck is going on at frog.
CSI gives a fuck.
You can play baseball with frogs.
You could throw frogs at each other and
hit each other with fucking frogs and
the frogs die in a paralyzed.
Nobody's going to arrest.
You told us were pretty
bad ass toads were like,
throw a toad at a dude in front of
a cop and nobody would say shit.
You can pick up the toad and her alum
at a dude and he hit the dude and nobody
would be like, fuck man. Animal rights.
So a toad is a frog with herpes.
You know they used to have
those like little bumps.
If you look close and you're all just
like warts are nowhere near the waters I
would. It is. I don't that yet.
They're dry, dry licking a frog thing.
Did you ever do that? No. Did you ever? It
doesn't work that way. When I was a kid,
I did it,
but I don't think I ever trip.
Maybe I was doing DMT went
out by the way to do it.
Doesn't everybody thinks it's looked
at frog? No. You have to smoke it.
If you look at it, it's just like eating
it. It's not going to get into the,
it's just like
tea. When you, your brain
makes it. You're, if you,
if you eat any sugar has DMT in it.
DMT contains whatever,
whatever it is, uh, in your body,
your stomach breaks it down.
It's called the Amato aiming model.
Avian oxidase.
So when you're taken DMT orally,
you're,
your stomach kills it and it never
gets in your bloodstream. Wow.
So you have to smoke it.
He can't orally consume DMT and less
like the way they do it in the, uh,
in Peru and the Amazon, they, they
make this stuff called Iowasca.
You know what that is?
And with Iowasca,
what they've done is
they put in one plant,
they put one plant that has DMT in it
and another plant that has an inhibitor.
And that's why it works.
So you can't really lick a frog.
Cause if you lick a frog would just be
like eating. It wouldn't work. Right.
So what you do is you take the frog
and you put it on a glass, you know,
and you make the frog excrete his body
ages all over this glass and this body
just I guess just as certain
animals that kills him, kill sheep.
If they ate five Meo DMT kills them.
So you take any,
excrete it on the glass and then you
stick the glass in the sun and it dries it
out and then you scrape it off with
a razor blade and then you smoke it.
That's how do you think the some I
figured out how they figured out anything
that'd be figured out to eat lobsters,
you know? I mean I get that. Makes Sense.
Let's see if we can get this
thing. You're like, ah, you know,
like I wonder what this just on the back
of my fat guys, if I try and smoke it,
let me see if I stuck it up mass.
How many steps were there before he tried
smoking? He had to figure it out. Right?
I bet it's fairly recent.
I bet the smoking it off the frogs.
I bet it's probably pretty recent. There's
a bunch of different types of, uh, of,
of DMT out there too. That was one of
the things they were talking about.
Like different people have different
experiences depending on what plant they
use when they make Iowasca
cause if they use Syrian Rue,
I was listening to some guy talking
about this on the Internet and some
interesting discussion about it.
And if you use Syrian Rue,
apparently they have
all this like, um, uh,
Annunaki imagery and all this Mesopotamia
imagery. You get all this, like it's,
they all have snakes. That's one
thing they share in common, but it's,
when you get it from the Amazon,
you see black people and Jaguars,
you see like jungle themes you see like
plants and shit and like a big jump.
But when you get it in
the, uh, the Middle East,
the stuff you're getting is all
like fucking Mesopotamia Shit.
It's all like Babylonia,
all that cuneiform tablets
and that kind of imagery.
You get in the San Fernando Valley,
you see Carl's Jr's
traffic Zang, old cars
with little tires. Yeah.
Yeah. It's, uh, the, the
idea of, uh, you know,
keeping psychedelics from
people by locking them up.
It is amazing that they've been able
to do that for that long that they have
been able to keep them illegal.
And then if people try to use them,
if you want to use it for your own
edification, for your own, you know,
your own experience, it's illegal
for you yourself to do something.
Some person will come and get
you and lock you in a cage.
Where could you imagine if it was only us?
Look and there's only the three of us
were the only people left on the earth.
And um, we discovered while we were here
that there is some shit that makes you
experience like these incredible states
of consciousness and you start having
this wave of creativity in these new
ideas and it feels like an incredibly
intelligent alien lifeforms communicating
with you. And then we were like,
you can't do that dude. You
can't do that. If you do that,
we're going to kill you or lock you in
a cage and we're going to contain you.
We can't have you running around having
an experience and it just running around.
You're not doing anything to anybody else.
You're getting it and then you're doing.
And if you do it and you test positive
for it, you are, you are against the law.
Well, let's imagine that. Let's
say we just in this house,
there was a creature
in a weird outfit did,
if he caught any of us smoking pot
would come and grab us and take us to a
certain part of the house
and put us in a rape cage.
We would stop that animal. Kill
it. You kill it. You'd be like,
you know what the thing that's taking
us and putting us in the rape cage, um,
there's only one of them
and there's three of us.
So I don't want to go on that rape cage
again. Can we please make it? Can you,
can you, can we get rid of
the guy who takes us into the
rape cage? Yeah. It's like
we're trying to be enlightened
here and we keep getting raped.
Well,
yeah,
try to fucking take pay Odeon communicate
with the spirit world and someone
keeps throwing me a cage of some
big black dude. What the fuck man?
What the hell man, why does it
have to be a black dude? Why?
Because they probably would win
more often. Why the better rapers
athletes?
Oh Man.
Yeah. It's a, it's a, it's
a real confusing situation.
And whenever you a year,
you know,
leave Baka talking about how he's just
going to keep arresting people or anytime
you hear or like in Mexico and they're
like, they just found 500 yeah.
Tons of marijuana. Do you hear
about that? Yeah. Biggest,
biggest cash crop ever that they
hauled in. They busted. Yeah.
It's just, it's just, I mean, less
Mexican weed. That stuff sucks.
Your weed sucks. If you weed was good,
you want to be shooting each other. Yeah,
that's true. Mexican weeds, the
worst. No Brazilian weeds the worst.
And I was in Brazil, we got some
weight. It was a intellect. A little,
it was like almost like particle board.
It was like a little brick. Yeah.
Little Sin.
Very tightly compact brick.
And you had to break it
off and then smoke it.
AIDS tastes like shit and it smelled
like shit and you barely got hot.
It's like a cousin of high. It wasn't
like real high, nothing like we have here.
You would take God, these
people are living in the
forest, the rainforest rather.
Beautiful Tropical Paradise. You know how
easy it would be for them to grow weed.
They keep it illegal.
That's how it was in Bahamas to
same thing. Really. Bahamas shit.
Isn't that amazing? What the fuck
is that about man? You know? I mean,
how do they not rebel against that?
Prostitution is legal in Brazil.
Cage fighting's everywhere.
That's the birth of valley.
Tuto five the birth of no rules fighting
and somehow or another they keep potty
illegal.
It's an interesting,
well, yeah, I mean it's the big, it's the,
it's the elephant in the room everywhere.
It's just, yeah. That to me is the
criteria through which you can measure it.
How far a society's advanced is their
relationship with psychoactive drugs.
[inaudible] says everything because
it's like anyone who does a psychoactive
drug knows you. It's fun. It is fun.
This is the poor.
The podcast will always click off.
I was hoping you would talk about
the first UFC, which bode clear. No.
To me, it a Hippie faggot and he
wants to talk about is fucking
pro drug bullshit.
That's the only reason why we're talking
about drugs at all is because drugs are
part of life. That's the only reason.
If drugs weren't drugs, if they were,
if there was some new word,
it's a,
it's a part of life and a
fucking significant one.
Yep. That's a gateway drug.
It's all fucking gateway drugs
got damn and everything's out.
Drug milk is a gateway drug to
cookies. It's, you know it is.
Drink some milk. He's like, Oh, I'm just
going to be to have cookies and this shit.
The next thing you're eating cookies,
the milk got you. Eat Cookies.
Cookies are bad for you. Cookies of sugar
in it. You're going to get diabetes.
You're gonna fucking die young to smoke
or eat cookies whenever we want. Yeah,
that's right, bitch. There's people that
want to let mandate against fatty foods.
They want to,
I want to say that food should,
shouldn't have a certain amount of
calories or fat content or you know,
bad oils or whatever. Fuck
that man. If it tastes good,
just let me know what it's gonna do to me.
If I ate it,
I'll make my own decisions. Your
space suit, you get to Iran,
whatever fuel you want through it,
it doesn't matter what it is and if
sometimes that fuel kills you. Tough Shit.
Tough Shit. That's the way it goes.
What I say? So give me it all man.
Let it leave it all on the table.
Let's fucking sort it all out.
I don't want my kids to get hooked on it.
Neither do you write good.
So let's educate her fucking kids.
All right,
let's educate our kids and let's get rid
of the scumbags and want to push it on
kids. Get rid of people that
are, you know, don't make it.
Don't make it illegal
to sell the children.
Don't make it legal to give
them propaganda that makes
them think that drugs are
good.
But you know the whole idea behind
locking anyone up for doing anything that
they want to do.
As long as they're informed and a of age,
we can do what you want to do,
man.
If you want to start smoking
crack in 2010 he lives,
you're like a successful person who's
got a good business on a nice family.
Like I've always wanted to try
crack. I just saw, you know, I mean,
I see new Jack City. It's so
appealing. I know it sounds crazy,
but there's just like part of me. It's
been missing. Southbank Ip crack. Yeah.
I want to try and crack once.
I don't think I'm going to wind up in
a fucking crack house with no money.
I mean, come on Mike. I'm Sigma
Phi. We went to school together.
We played the costs. I'm not a crack
head. I just want to try crack.
Julie doesn't want me to do it,
but I told her, hey, don't worry.
That's on happening. No,
why not? I did it. Why not?
You did do crack, man. We talked
about this before. No, I haven't.
No, I haven't, but I did. I
did. Um, when I was, uh, why
are you saying that he didn't?
Because he acts like a crack it when I
was not that it really offended you are
ruthless where you're
cut downs Brah you know,
they come so fast and so unexpected and
they're so powerful when they land. Yeah.
It's just incredible. You really
thank God you doing comedy again
company again? No, I useless.
Ruthless Brian. I'm just kidding.
I heard him but I have, I have
bought crack. I when I was really,
when I was living in crowded one side
fucking food away, I didn't even want it.
I looked at him like, what the fuck is
this? I'm going to do crack come out.
Really guys, guys,
really? I just moved to La
and my landlord was a crack head wound.
He had a friend who would do crack
with them now. I didn't know,
I knew that he was into drugs.
I didn't know it was crack and his friend
was over and his friend said to me,
you have a copter, a rock
before. And I, I swear to God,
I didn't know what he meant, but I
wanted to seem cool. So I was like, no,
never copped the rock where I wasn't
sure what he meant. He's like,
give me a ride. So I, he's like, drive
up here, turn right. I turned right,
drive around the corner, drove around the
corner, we pull up in front of a house.
These two fucking gangsters
come running out of the house.
I don't know what it is,
but they're automatically
screaming at him. They're like,
you stupid mother fucker. You fucking
idiot. Don't just fucking pull up here.
They throw crack into the car. He gives
them money. I'm like that. And you know,
that's when I was like, Oh, you, you
more on? What do you think this was?
Drove or drove back? Well, you know,
like really, what'd you think? And um,
drove back, uh, and, and him
and my landlord proceeded
to smoke crack together.
And that's the only time I've ever seen
anyone smoke crack. So shitty smells,
smells like burning plastic. The guy's
face got all pale. And he was like,
if I have a heart attack,
call nine one one. Wow,
whoa, whoa. No, I didn't suck.
I remember the first time I
ever saw someone smoking crack,
it was like on HBO or something like that.
It's like some sort of documentary
and while the guy was smoking crack,
I was like looking at him. He's fine.
He's not even going crazy. Yeah,
I thought you smoked crack.
[inaudible]
fuck man. Does this get crazy?
Know the guy just smoking crack.
He's just sitting there and I'm like,
how high could he possibly like a speedy
high? That's all it is. It's like, Ooh,
I'm feeling speedy. You feel better
if you like, that kind of thing.
It was not my thing.
Is it like coffee? No,
it's like doing like doing cocaine pretty
much always reminds me of exactly of
doing cocaine. That's pretty much
what it was. Ugh, wow. Never done it.
Never done it. Dodge that bullet.
Don't do it. I'm not going to,
I think it might be what? The
funding research? No, I'm not.
I'm not interested in hanging out the
pilot. I'll see any cocaine advocates.
I don't see any cocaine people going,
I made it because of cocaine.
Cocaine's responsible for most of my
energetic decisions. Most of my drive,
most of my wisdom when I
innovating on a beach town,
you'll start getting in that, that
group of people that were like, no,
I prefer a cocaine when I go
out. You know, it's a nice drug.
You will have people that are
selling it to like civilized cocaine.
People always one up shooting each other.
They just get crazy cocaine,
relationships, cocaine people. They
just get to that fucking point,
that Goodfellas point.
Like when that fucking chick throws the,
the basket at Ray Liotta
that she's cooking the coke
for him and she throws the
basket as [inaudible] mad at him.
They always get to that.
I was, um, I was just telling him
about this, that I had this, one of,
one of the first girls I dated
was in Asheville, North Carolina,
and I met her and this little,
because she was sitting at,
they just done cocaine and she was
sitting next to this blonde girl and the
blonde girls like all coked up and
she's like, we're gonna run this town.
They can,
small mouth
run Asheville. It's
like 600 population. Oh,
that's hilarious. Yeah.
But that's what it does.
Asheville supposed to be really cool.
It's the coolest city ever. It really is.
And it keeps getting cooler and
cooler and cooler. I haven't know.
Every time I go back there,
it's just gotten more interesting
and more subversive and really, yeah,
it's a really cool place. We should do
comedy there. Are you and me? I'd love it.
Yeah. Yeah. There's a club up there. Okay.
Talk in trust. So we're going on the road.
All right. You got to go do it. That'd
be good. That'd be good one for you too.
You're, you're acting so fucking weird.
It'll fit right in with those hippies. Oh,
there. I mean, it's not hippies.
It's an arc is up there.
It's everybody. It's every,
it's just a way,
it's a mix of like,
I don't know how to enter
because you're talking about,
I believe there's a lot of uh,
environmental Liberation Front
type people in there, but I'm not,
I'm not positive about that. So people
who live in Azure, I don't know, easy
bags. The problem with the, you know,
the really radical organizations,
like almost all of it, even though change
does need to occur at the very top,
like if you get to the top of pita and
you find out fucking none of these guys
are. Yeah. You know, you get to the
top of any of these, like major,
like what does that Animal Liberation
Organization? Yes, it is. Well,
it's the people who wet the animals free.
There's a lot of people that don't even
think that animals should be pets that
they did all,
all animals should be free to go where
they want that you shouldn't be keeping
them locked up in cages and yeah.
Yeah, yeah. There's some, there's
some, yeah, that's great animals.
Just run her dogs running around fucking
everywhere. Oh my Chihuahua Mayor Qd.
She shouldn't be a, yeah,
that would be cool though.
You get like a new dog every day,
which is kind of dog I'm going
to hang out with today. Oh,
there's a golden retriever. Hey doggy,
come over. Yeah, fair. What stood
out here where I live,
because there's a lot of coyotes.
I see coyotes all the time,
which is a really strange thing.
It's like the cousin to a dog. Like
a dog didn't quite make it, you know,
and to the group got cast them the outside
of man and now it just follows around
and man encroaches on its territory.
So it comes in and eats cats and shit
every now and then. Dogs, cats, dogs, man.
There's a story. When I used to go
to this, a pet store near my house,
there was a guy who used to work there
that train dogs and he had this dog that
he worked as a veterinarian assistant.
This dog got brought into him, uh,
that was just covered in fucking cuts.
It was horrendous.
They had to put the dog under and
it was, it was uh, a big pit bull,
like a 90 pound pit bull. And they
were like, what did this to this dog?
Like he wants to gotten a big
dog fight with a bunch of dogs.
Like this dog is like covered with
hundreds and hundreds of wounds. Okay.
Like they then hours of stitches,
who knows how many. So they,
they take the dog and they stitch them up,
they put them in the veterinarian's
hospital and they go back to the scene of
the crime to figure out
what the fuck happened.
And they follow like a trail
of blood and like some,
they see some scuffle the woods.
So they go and figure out
what the fuck happened.
And there they find nine dead coyotes.
And what what they do is one coyote will
come out and they'll show themselves
and then the dog will see that and bark
at it and the coyote will look like he's
going to run and the dog will have
instincts to chase and the coyote will run
and a dog will chase after him.
And as he chases after him,
then they ambush him with
the rest of the pack.
So they ambushed his pit bull and
it killed nine coyotes. Christ.
Could you imagine the look on the
coyotes faces when this fucking thing is
coming? I can't tell. Are we
ever going to fuck him up?
Mikey looking can fuck them up.
This is a pitch.
You want some person who wants a coyote
and then they see this
big giant fucking fire hydrant head
muscles for crushing things built into its
fucking skull. The skull of a, a big
male, pitbull. Brian, what are you doing?
Turn the volume back up the vines
and then through the headphone vine.
What happened? I haven't changed a
thing. You just did something? No,
my volume just jacked. Oh,
you're just adjusted something.
I was turned down in the headphone
fine. Okay. All right. Point.
It didn't affect that podcast
point is that the, you know,
dog tried to kill coyotes.
Coyotes tried to kill the dog.
Man. That's, that's a, that's a
stupid fucking Kiowa. It's like,
here's what you do, Roger. You're
going to see a Chihuahua. Maybe
they just think dogs, man, they think
dogs are soft. But you know what?
Pitfalls are not regular dogs.
Those things are engineered first of all,
to fight through pain,
to not worry about their own instincts.
They were the ones that worry about their
own instincts. They don't let breed.
When the dogs quit, when the dogs give
up, they realize this other dog superior.
They never let that dog breed. And a
lot of times they kill them. You know,
it's pretty fucked up.
But what it makes at the end of the day
is this crazy fucking monster animal
that will do anything. You know the
pit bulls are like, that is the one
last dog you want. Come
on after you man. No Shit.
And like there's a guy in our neighborhood
walks his fucking pit bull off leash.
He told me about that.
It's awful.
It's like most of them are great
and people are getting, you know,
a lot of people get scared. My dogs
great. Yes, most of them are great,
but you have to recognize the
potential for destruction.
If you've got a nutty one, donate their
brains also swell. No, that's fine.
That's bullshit. Bullshit. No,
no. That's all silliness. Ah,
they're, they're fucking crazy
dogs. They are sweet though.
Anytime I've been around someone's
pitfall, it's the sweetest dog ever.
I've never, everyone always says
no. It's the sweetest dog ever.
It's not like all of them. And then it
just takes one bad day and then it's like,
okay. It's crazy. Like they're nuts, man.
I've had a bunch of them, three of them,
four of them.
One of them got this temper and the
other ones there was all fighting.
They fight, they, they get
mad at each other. And you
know, if you have, you know,
more than one,
they get together sometimes and they
just settle arguments and one of them
doesn't want to back down. Next thing
you know, you've got a dead dog.
And these dogs loved each other
and live together all the time.
He used to lick each other and
play together. We wanted to
kill each other. Huh? Yeah. It's horrible.
But this just, that's what it is, man.
It's just what it is. And now they're,
they're engineered to fight. You know,
and that's the problem.
They're,
they're engineered to not have like
normal Alpha Beta interactions where,
you know, the Beta gives up in the Alpha
dominates them and leaves them alone. No,
they fight to the death. All right?
They just go after it. You know,
sometimes I'd come home and it'd be all
bloody. So they worked it out. You know?
I'm like, well, I'm glad you're
assholes. Work this out. You know?
And I would just assume it
probably never happen again. Yeah,
of course it would rouse. Yeah.
Well, it's, you know, it's,
it's a fucking scary thing when you think
about what a dog really is because a
dog has just some fucking animal that
could kill you that you control. You know,
you got a dog like that dog that
can kill nine type nine coyotes.
What a fantastic scene that must've
been coming up on that scene.
Just oh carnage.
Just coyote guts and coyote
faces jaws half hanging off,
you know?
I mean,
think about what that thing must've done
to those coyotes and they just bite at,
I'm Taryn skin and he's not even paying
attention. He's just jacking the next one
rage of frosting. Great.
It's probably hard, man.
I had this really spooky fucking thing
happened in my neighborhood where I was
walking my dog and this Weirdo
came up to me and he's like,
you should be careful with
your tires like high, oh,
he's in his name right there and
killing animals. And it was like an eye.
You didn't need to tell me that.
Like I understand it was just this weird
gaunt guy. And I started thinking like,
was that a serial killer?
I just run into a serial killer is like,
maybe it's just a nice guy.
I want you to look out for your dog.
No, cause he said, he like
says, you know, I've got,
was he whispering this into your ear?
Yeah, he said we got a problem. Yeah.
He kind of pointed at things like,
you know,
I've got problems but our
coyote attacks lately.
And you know,
like when you're around somebody you kind
of get the sense as a bad person like
you is it, it was something that,
something else that's wrong with it.
And then I remember walking up the street
a ways and there was just like, uh,
I limb of an animal. I don't know if it
was a rabbit or what the fuck it was,
but some limb that he gotten chopped off.
So I guess he's right.
I don't know if that name,
maybe he did it. What limb? Like a dog's
limb. Yeah. It was like a foot of a dog.
Yeah. I think it was a dog.
Yeah. Do this. No joke, man.
Coyote snatch right off
leashes. Yeah, in Brentwood.
A friend of mine was living in Brentwood.
He was walking his dog and the coyote
came and took it right off his fucking
leash and ran with it.
Ah, that's just snatched.
It came by and snatched it and ran
away. Was Dog screaming and Yiping, ah,
it's out of his hands and he's running
after it and you can't do a God damn
thing about it. Instead, when my dog
was a puppy, actually was worried about,
I said there was a lot of falcons that
were just hanging out in front of my
thing and they would like come
down real close. I'm like, okay,
some hawks come inside now I think
don't even live in this country.
Do they found thousands? I don't know. To
America, what am I talking? I don't know.
I think so. Either way. Birds of prey.
Were you the one that posted
that thing of the giant Eagle?
They didn't kill the animal,
but pushes it off a cliff and
then goes down and eat. Yeah,
they grabbed goats and dragged him off
the side of the cliff and drop them.
Awesome. Too Sane Dude. Eagles
are ruthless mother fuckers, dude.
They're so scary.
The idea of made it's a flying dinosaur.
That's really what it is.
I mean,
they have the same mentality that a
dinosaur would have, right? I mean,
when they say that birds, they say that
birds are the descendants of dinosaurs,
right? Whatever survived the big
Yucatan meteor impact, asteroid impact,
whatever survived, whatever, you
know, animal dinosaur species,
they eventually evolved into birds.
That's the theory, right, isn't it? Yep.
So that's the theory. Chickens grow
things every once in awhile, right?
Chickens do. Yeah. Yeah.
And so if that's the theory,
then you got to think that
the really ruthless ones
that we have today, you know,
like eagles and shit like that.
They were probably some nasty ass fucking
flying little dinosaur reptile thing
that made it,
you know,
live through the holocaust
of some gigantic chunk of
iron and rock slamming into
the earth at 45,000 miles an hour.
These ruthless little concert
lived and became eagles.
They weren't the only ones.
What a fucked up way to kill things too.
They fly out of the sky,
they're like dragons man.
They look like Dev Dragon clause and shit.
They don't spit out fire,
but that you take away
all the feathers and shit.
If they didn't have feathers and you
looked at them for what they wore
underneath that, all that pretty, you
know, soft exterior of the feathers.
That's a nasty, scaly, you know,
gray looking lizard thing that flies.
That's what it is.
I mean we think of them as being
soft and almost be a million.
You know what I'm saying? Those are
lizard things. Those aren't like, like,
like any fucking mammal.
That's a creepy alien looking
lizard thing with dead eyes.
Those eyes don't give a fuck about you.
And they come swooping out of the sky
to snatch fish out of the water and fly
with them and pull eagles
or pull polo rather, um, uh,
goats off the side of a fucking cliff
and drop them. Just ruthless cons.
They're like a little fucking
devil's little flying demons.
I the Noble Eagle.
I take offense at you disparaging or
Ruth Colker who could shed his grace on
thee.
Just evil flying lizard,
snatches fucking shit out of sky and eats
babies.
They'd probably babies.
I bet there's definitely been a baby
that got snapped up by an eagle course.
There's a fucking cool
video in, um, Alaska.
These people are in their yard and they
have this yard that's all this grass in
it and they throw out some fish like,
you know, the, after they made filets,
I throw it like heads and all
sorts of extra fish that they have.
And these eagles come out and they're
all eating in their yard and they've
gotten like fucking,
I don't know,
2030 bald eagles eating the
salmon in their yards. Like,
Whoa,
like this is nuts man.
These crazy fucking demons with
pretty feathers. That'd be cool.
Get really stoned and watch an
eagle feast. Go on your backyard.
Would, you know, seeing any natural,
any animal in its natural habitat
must be fucking incredible. You know,
like you run into a bear if you
actually did run into a bear.
I mean I ran into a bear at Yellowstone,
but it didn't feel like it was a natural
environment because they were coming up
to cars and it was obvious
that these bears had been
coming up to college before.
So it almost like felt like the zoo,
it didn't feel real and they
would tell you not to feed them,
but people were still feeding them.
They were like open their window of crack.
This is like the seventies. I did this
when I was a little kid, you know,
and I remember thinking like,
this is just like the zoo.
Like this isn't until we went to sleep,
we were in our sleeping bag and a,
we were camping and it was me and I think
it was just me and my stepdad. No, no,
it was a whole family.
So we're camping in Yellowstone and um,
I slept through the whole thing,
but apparently they heard
some banging around and shit.
And we got up there in the morning and
the cooler had been torn open and all the
food had been eaten and there
was paw prints all over the car.
So there's bear was just feet away,
just feet away from us sleeping
and signed some little Baggie.
We're basically like a
little dinner in a Baggie.
The whole family's in this baggy,
but these bears are so conditioned to
being around wasteful humans and sloppy
humans that they just look
for food that way. Right?
They're conditioned to go look in
your cooler. That's where the food is.
It's not like let's start eating
people. But if they did, they'd be like,
Holy Shit,
this is way better though in the bag.
They can't even get out of the bag.
You just start eating them.
You just jump in and start eating. They
can't get away, you know? I mean they,
they could do that. They were right
outside our door. Rip and shit apart.
So strong they could tear apart a cooler,
rip it open.
Sto stomped all over the car. Big
Ass paw prints. That's, to me,
that's like one that really is a shitty
death is getting, I mean, I like,
it's obvious to say, but compared to
other deaths, getting killed by an animal.
Yeah. How about the guy that just got
killed by a goat? What is that? I didn't,
I saw the link, but I didn't
click on it. What is that?
Goat jabbed him in the leg
and it penetrated one of his
arteries and he bled out.
That's bad luck. Goat apparently
was super aggressive. He had,
they'd had problems with
this go before and they, uh,
had done things to try to condition
the goat, stay away from people.
So they would go near the goat and shoot
it with like a beanbag gun and shit.
And that made the go even more douchey.
Cause don't go through stubbornness.
Fuck goats. Don't learn what they
should've done a shot at with a gun.
That's what they should've done.
You've got to go. That's continued.
Wants to Jack People. Yeah. Let's just
kill this fucking goat. All right.
There's plenty of other goats. Why we?
Why are we taking chances? Job Goshen.
Go shoot the goat with a bullying.
Go bully the goat so that the goat
is scared of people. What is this?
A petting zoo. It's the mountains.
Oh, it was in the mountain? Yeah,
it's in the mountains.
So guys in the bands and goat comes
up and just fucking goes after him,
gets him in the leg,
the is fucked.
And then the goat won't let people take
away the body to go standing over him
while he's moaning. You
know, he's hasn't died yet.
So he's lying on his ground and they
can't the go to waste so they can
save the guy. Go. I know. I mean
goats aren't that small. Goats.
Goats goat though. Say
that, bro. Go fuck you up.
Hey Man,
what's a wild don't a lot of goats.
You haven't been around a wild mountain.
Mountain Mountain. Go to scary dude.
Those things are strong as fuck.
You ever see how they can
climb up the side of mountains?
They climb on mountains. I mean like
this, like this incredible pitch.
It's like a fucking 60 degree angle there.
Climbing straight up a mountain.
You're like, how the fuck are they doing
this? That's the height of absurdity.
Like if you think about as
that man was laying there,
going into shock and contemplating his
whole life situation, going from being,
you know, then like, oh look, oh
my God, Mary, look, it's a goat.
Oh eight the goats coming. Oh Jesus
fucking Christ. Oh my God, I'm bleeding.
I get in a week.
What did I just get killed by?
Go get killed by go my Dick and run.
Yeah.
That's so absurd to think about that.
That's very strange.
How long in all of human history,
how many humans had been killed by goat?
Probably like, it's probably
pretty small. It's small.
The biggest thing in this
country for farm animals, pigs,
pigs kill more people than
any other farm animal.
Have you seen Jackass Three d yet?
No,
but apparently what happens with pigs
is they'll eat anything. And if you,
if you're feeding pigs and you
fall into the the police side,
they just start jacking you. Yet there's
my, my um, my parents have a place, uh,
on this like little island off the coast
of Georgia that's got wild pigs and
those things will kill you.
Like they're dangerous.
Wild pigs especially cause they
always have babies. And if you get,
it's the same thing. If you get around
their babies, they'll, they've got tusks,
they'll bite you in. They're, they're
filthy. So the vital get infected.
Even their pigs are dangerous.
Very ruthless.
Feral pigs are scary
because feral pigs change,
you know the story that if you get
like a pink pig that's in a, you know,
in a farm and it's kept well and fed well,
they have a certain appearance to them.
Well when they get loose within three
weeks, their body starts to change.
It's a very strange phenomena.
The idea of a farm animal is like an
embryonic stage and all it has to do is
think that it has to fend for itself.
Yeah.
And then it becomes this different thing.
It's like some new chemical gets released
and it's for becomes thick and Harry
like thick and like darker and
then its tusks grow. It changed,
literally changes the animal. It's
a fascinating metamorphosis. Yeah.
And it happens within three weeks.
Within three weeks of the
animal becoming feral,
they just get loose and then they
start morphing fucking nutty shit.
That's Nutty, nutty shit.
Like what's happening there?
What's that saying about people,
you know,
are we not reaching our full potential
because we get our food from a
supermarket and you know, are we
are, you know what I'm saying?
[inaudible] we set up that way.
That's a great like weird Saifai idea,
which is like a space ship finally makes
it out of the Earth's gravitational
field and get to a certain
distance away from Earth.
And the people on the spaceship
start changing like their body
start elongating the aliens.
Oh my God.
The more they more for like the pigs.
Yeah, look, if you go into space,
that's the next stage. Yeah. That's
the next stage. It's like, uh,
the like the aquatic worm jumping
into the pawn to give spaces.
The next stage we're just like, we're
here. We're just like squashed aliens.
Like the gravity squashed his dad
when we get off the plan and you know,
there's certain salamanders that never
reached adulthood unless exert certain
environmental conditions are in place.
Like weather conditions are like
temperature, moisture, you know,
certain conditions have to be in place
otherwise they stay in the immature phase
their entire life.
How fascinating would that be if
that's what the thing with humans is,
is once you get off the earth,
once you go into space,
then the different gravity and environment
of space allows your body to knock
out of the human shell and
become this next thing. Third,
I start secreted already know that,
right?
Because the people in the
space be smart as fuck.
People that got back from the space
station will be dropping science on far
enough. People in the space station,
they're still on the gravitational what?
[inaudible] there's a lot of
what ifs. Every week, man.
I blamed the weed would
if, man, if we go to space,
we turned into a frog and then
you smoke yourself with the front,
wants to suck my Dick shot that up.
Chips seem pretty happy.
So it was on this flight to London and
Melanie Griffith was on the flight and
uh, Melanie Griffith is a very
nice lady. She seems very sweet.
Like she smiles at everybody. She's like,
she seems nice. And uh, I was thinking,
man, this is Melanie
Griffin. Like, you know,
I remember her old school
from like the 80s, you know,
some of those movies that she was in. You
know, I remember when she played, I mean,
even recently when she played. Um,
and uh, the thing about the guy who,
uh, William Randolph Hearst, what
was the movie about? Was it called?
It was about him.
It was about the constraint.
The making of Rosebud or the
making of a citizen Kane. It was,
Orson Welles was in it and it was all
about how crazy we ran our first wasn't
she played his wife. I'm like, she's
like, so it's a good actor, you know,
a an actress. So anyway, she's,
she's on this plane and
I ate a cookie like, um,
two hours before the flight.
I figured like I'll eat it in the car
over there and then right when I get on
board it'll kick in and it was
way too strong. Why would you
get that? It was so strong,
dude. It was so strong.
I was breaking down my entire life.
I was thinking about
everything I've ever done,
every every negative
thing that I've ever done,
every positive thing that I've ever done.
And then I started thinking about
the possibility of endless universes.
The possibility of every single choice
leads you into another parallel universe
that you don't even feel the distance,
you don't even feel the difference in the,
in the switch over.
I started thinking all this crazy shit
and I started thinking about mortality.
I started thinking about energy
and life and I was just couldn't,
I couldn't function. I was curled
up in the fetal position. I was so,
I was so adrift.
I was so high that I seriously
considered pissing my pants really,
because I had to go, I had to
pee, but I didn't want to get up.
So I thought I'll just pissed my pants.
I had, I thought that that was a real
consideration for a whole second,
for a whole second. I was
like, I found a solution.
I was going through my possibilities.
I wanna, I wanna pee. Okay. I don't
want to get up. What are the options?
So I'll just piss myself though
knew I had to pee. But my brain was
like, that's all that my brain was like,
that's all well and good,
but you see you can't get up.
There's no way you can get up. We need
to stay in this spot. Yeah. So I got up
and then I,
I peed.
And then I thought about like how
ridiculous it is that I even thought about
that. So I'm sitting in
this bathroom, you know,
looking out this little round window at,
you know,
it's turning dark now and I'm seeing
fucking street lights and shit and I'm
30,000 feet up and I'm fucking
flying. Dude. I'm gone.
I am a wash in a river of information
and it's flowing by so quick.
I can't grab any of it and I have to pay
attention to what I'm doing because I'm
on Whitewater rapids. And
um, if I don't pay attention,
I'm going to hit a rock of consciousness
that I might never recover from.
You know what I'm saying? Like I gotta
keep it together. That's how high I am.
So I go back to my seat and I lied down
again back in the fetal position after
I'm done. Peon. And, um,
the seats are all staggered.
Like they're not in a straight line.
You know,
it's not like everybody's
head is at the same place.
Everybody's feed her in the same place.
Well, four hours into the flight,
everybody starts to go to sleep.
I'm so high I can't do anything.
I'm just laying there just hoping this
is just gonna eventually come back to
normal.
And I don't have to think like this for
the rest of my life cause I'm not gonna
be able to enjoy anything because
I'm going to overthink everything.
And so as I'm thinking this,
I look over and I noticed that this guy
is sitting in this one seat right here
and he's this big fat guy and right where
his ass is directly across the aisle
is Melanie Griffiths
head
three feet away is three feet away
and this guy is sleeping okay.
And Melanie Griffith is sleeping.
This guy doesn't even have a
a blanket on. Okay. And I
got my headphones on. Okay.
And listen to some music.
I'm trying to writing on the
computer and this guy, oh,
his ass.
I mean opens his ass on
Melanie Griffiths head.
Her head was right across the aisle.
It was only three feet away.
He just shit in her head.
He was,
there was no blanket to
contain the blast radius.
It was just she wake up, dude, she
didn't say nothing. No one said nothing.
There's no way. She didn't know
what happened. There's no way.
I don't know if she realizes this guy
just shit in her head because she was
facing the other direction. She
just probably like, oh my God,
someone's disgusting. But she has no
idea that really she just got shat upon.
That is awesome too at this guy is not
even wearing fucking a blanket man.
He's just got his sweaty dress slacks and
it's just a poorly maintained lid to a
biological sewer that's not very
well maintained either. And this guy
probably had all kinds of
fucked up food and you know,
just burgers and shit.
He's fat man.
He's got this big fat face and
he just just fucking unloads.
It was horrible man.
It was horrible.
And you know it was him because
he's the fat guy in this.
No one gets discriminated more than fat
guys. When somebody farted, you know,
black people get blamed
when shit gets stolen.
And Chinese people when they're in
a car accident, they get blamed.
Nobody gets blamed more than if
somebody farted. And as a fat guy,
that's just immediately,
even though we all know some very skinny
people there have some horrible fucking
gas. It doesn't matter.
I'll get a fact. Yeah,
the fact guy's gotta be worse. He Shit
right in million Griffith his head.
Did she move around or when
moved? He did though. He moved.
He adjusted after he farted, he
moved into Charleston. I was like,
you motherfucker.
Like I saw him move.
So I knew he was conscious while
it all happened, but you know,
his back was turned. So he's pretending
that nothing was real. You know,
he was turned into a seat.
So he was like, you know,
facing a little wall so he could
just pretend nothing. I'm going to
open up on purpose. Dude. He opened up.
He didn't like the feeling
he farted a vengeance. No,
but it would be funny if he did.
Imagine if they set it up this way.
Imagine if it was like the guy came out
to Melanie Griffith agent. It's like,
I have $1 billion I made in the
software industry and I have,
but one wish I want to
fart on Melanie Griffith.
He had this idea and he, they were
like, well, you know, first of all,
we're going to, you know, even to bring
it to Melanie's desk, um, we're gonna,
we're gonna need to talk numbers
because guys like $5 million,
I'm willing to pay $5 billion to Fart.
And Melanie Griffiths face.
It's the role of her
lifetime and so no, no, no.
Let's say they had to figure out
how are we going to do this? Okay.
Melanie is not gonna agree to just let
you fart in your face. Man. This is just,
this is not going to work this way.
What we needed to do is get
you guys both on an airplane.
That's the only way you're going to
be about three feet from her head.
I mean you can't be fighting right on
her head but are going to be three feet
away and we'll seed it so that your ass
lines up with her face and you get to
far down there and take it from there.
Maybe hurt her agent, did the whole thing.
He's taken all the money.
He said it all up.
Maybe always for this guys wish maybe
she has a super sophisticated enemy and
that's all he's been doing her whole
life is paying guys to [inaudible]
did on an old woman at
Starbucks a couple of weeks ago.
It was one of the greatest things ever.
She was right behind.
You are totally right behind me.
It was one of those where I was
just going to do a little quick.
I thought it was going to be quiet.
Nice one, but he's just like super,
super loud and powerful. Loud. Yeah,
it was super loud and powerful and very
embarrassing and I remember looking at
her, I kind of like looked back
like like 10 seconds later,
just kind of when we did a little look
back to see what was going on and she did
not seem like mad. She looked kind of
concerned, like almost like meet with.
Was that me? No, her face look so confused
to exactly. I thought it was going.
That's awful. She thought
she shit herself. That must
be the worst feeling ever.
When you're incontinent
and just walking around,
your body doesn't contain it's bowels
anymore and your urine leaks out and like,
oh God. Yeah, it's pretty gross when
these things start melting down, man.
You know it's funny up, kids don't
give a shit if you watch him pee.
They don't feel bad about peeing and
pooping and everything like that.
It doesn't, it's not like there's
no shame in it. And so, uh,
my daughter is learning
how to potty train,
so she's getting out of the diaper stage,
but occasionally she just makes a
mistake. And so, uh, she's sitting in her,
her high chair and she has to pee.
She thinks about it while she was,
I'm just kind of just pissed.
It's just like an agreeable amount
of p is dripping off the high chair.
It's on the ground. And she's
like, what happened? She
goes, I peed. You know, like,
it's not bothering her. I go, why didn't
you tell me you have to go? She goes,
I forgot. I'm like, oh, okay.
That's the basis of Freud and psychology
is the way your parents handled you're
yourself. Exactly. So I go, okay.
I go, well, next time that happens,
maybe we should, uh, make sure before you
go into a high chair, you use the potty.
She was like, okay. Probably. She says
shit like that. That's how I saw it. Yeah,
no, yeah, yeah. And there's
a lot of maybes. Yeah.
Maybe like maybe we can get ice cream.
You know,
it was like there's a lot of like trying
to steer the conversation a certain way.
Very manipulative it too.
That's awesome.
Have you taken the a I'm sitting on my
toilet photo for her so she can use it
and in her Facebook and 15 years, no,
I'm not gonna allow her to have Facebook.
How many,
how many terabytes of photographs of
kids sitting on toilets are on Facebook?
Like two, two or three. That's such a,
that's the thing that kills single people.
I have one of you will
have babies in our mind.
I have one of me holding Glamour magazine
sitting on the toilet naked. Really?
Glamour magazine.
Is there any more overused
premise than the woman's magazine?
Do they have a story left to tell?
I mean,
is there a new sex trick to keeping your
man how to keep your ups a passion in
the bedroom?
I mean who has exhausted a
genre more than like cosmo?
Men's magazines always have a new
way to get a six pack. That's true.
Every third men's magazine or
second men every every other month.
It's like new way to day. The
six pack of a marine. Yeah.
There's something very homoerotic
about those bodybuilding magazines.
There's something very homoerotic about
the admiration of a man's physique.
You know, looking at this
guy, motherfuckers get the
best thighs or something,
but we'll get the striations in the
the ass and then the Lula back with the
Christmas tree in the lower back. The
striations are incredible. I mean,
he did still a tremendous job.
Tremendous job. And uh, you know,
and cutting the Waldo out so he
could really shoot a muscle. I mean,
it's so very beautiful,
beautiful sculpture he made his body into
why not your SCO suck his Dick Buddy.
You
know what I'm saying?
Like there's something weird about it,
but on the other hand it's like,
I recognize your,
your desire to have a insane body.
Like why not go do it if
that's what you're into and
you get oohs and ahs out of
it and people think you're special
because of it. I totally, yeah.
Was the difference between wanting to
have an insane body and then like talking
about a Christmas tree on someone's
back a term. I never heard mine.
There was a dude
who used to be a huge bodybuilding fan.
This is back when I lived in Boston.
He was one of my students when
I was teaching martial arts.
He was a huge bodybuilding fan, but
he was fat. I never understood it.
The dude was like, seriously
fat. And I was like, well,
I guess he was really fat at one point.
And then he got into bodybuilding and
then he started slowly losing weight
because you, he wanted to
have a physique like that. So,
but he never lost any weight. I
just like, was it just a fat guy?
I always talk about Bible. You see the
latest thing. And Lee Haney is incredible.
I don't know who those though. You
know, I think it was a, who was it?
The WHO's the Mr Olympia back in that day.
I really have no idea but this.
But he was, and I was like, how come? You
know, I mean, are you into bodybuilding?
Like do you body build yourself? And
he's like, well, I did, you know,
I lift a little weights, I lift. I just
tried to keep in shape, but I'm just,
I just admire what they do
and I'm like, whoa. Okay.
There's something weird about that.
Some weird about you
fixating on other dudes bias.
You're a fan of what they're
doing to their bodies,
but you don't even do
anything to your own.
Like you just like to stare at their
improvement. Our core, I'll look,
it isn't back. That is a hilarious
character. His back's incredible. Yeah,
it is hilarious character, right?
Like a guy who's not gay at all,
but he's just like super into like really,
really into men's body development.
Like you go out,
you go to his office and it's just got
like framed pictures of muscular guys and
he's just like, I respect
their work. Yeah. Come here.
Let me show you something Joe.
Look at our Christmas tree. Yeah,
that's a terrible term I've never heard.
Yeah, they call it the lower back. Yeah.
Yeah. This, this guy, this guy told
me the Christmas tree, this guy back,
one of my students was like Scott,
that Christmas tree and as low.
Yeah. Christmas tree and a
lot of presence under that.
Put a little bit of snow on that tree.
[inaudible] the snowman.
Where's that present on the ditch?
Yeah.
It always helps to go to some gay place
folks. Yeah. We are very immature. Very,
very no watches it.
I got to say,
God have a little immature with
farting met Melanie Griffith Hack.
Is that where I went wrong? Yeah. You
blame me and it really happened, man.
Nobody but shit. What I like,
what I like is it was preceded by,
it looks like you were like on the verge
of like figuring out one of the biggest
things ever and it you ended up in a
catatonic state and got to see you.
One of the funniest things of
all times. Yeah. No Shit. Right.
That's a very funny
moment to get to witness.
I mean that that may
be only happened once.
Yup.
People aren't always farting.
I'm Melanie Griffith.
His heads probably more likely that
you'd been abducted by an alien.
Then you get yourself into a position
where you could fight a Melanie Griffiths
head. Yeah. Operation. You saw
the final phase of operation.
Would you rather fart on Melanie
Griffin's head or Angela Landsbury.
I wouldn't want to fall on any
one of their heads. Angela,
all the way [inaudible] I'd make
her wear a little bit of makeup.
I put the blood on people's heads.
That's just rude. Fucked that girl.
Who was Angela Lansbury murder she wrote
here. Can you where you have a problem?
I just want to see what these pucker up.
What is it that we want to see?
Like little old ladies kicking ass.
Could you imagine if Angela Lansbury
like would beat dudes up occasionally.
Like they try to get her from calling
nine one one in the fall and she kicks him
in the balls and he carries it.
Yeah.
Like if there was like a
female seniors MMA, whoa.
That would make a lot of money. Oh
my God. Could you imagine ladies,
old ladies beating the
fuck out of each other?
And occasionally they would
die bravely in the ring.
Like she died for our
freedom and they would show
just the sound of hips breaking
ACL is just snapping like carrots.
They ensured grow wild haymaker
and their foot falls off.
Oh God,
that'd be so sad to watch.
Just concern grandchildren weeping in
this dance. Isn't there a video online?
I didn't watch it but somebody put
it up to old ladies got into a fight.
Somebody throw up on Twitter.
I know you folks know who know what it is.
It was on the rogue and board.
I'm pretty sure I didn't watch it,
but I saw the opening frame and it was
like one old lady was down and the other
old lady was up and I was like,
I don't need to see anymore.
I need to see these old ladies beating
the shit out of interesting old lady porn.
Like really old lady porn.
Yes.
I've seen some very disturbing
because that one old lady,
this one old lady I showed it looked
like she was like maybe Alzheimer's,
like they found her like she,
she didn't seem like she knew it was
Jesus. It was really bad.
There's a dark one I want.
The first one I ever watched
was Ron Jeremy. He was like
the first one to do it.
I think it was him banging this
really old lady and she was like, oh,
it's so lovely to feel so good.
I was watching it and she was just like,
just wretched old creature.
I was like,
oh my God puts these look fine.
Kind of still though.
Like they look like they don't
look as old as their faces.
I don't see that much sunlight.
Don't you think it's a
charitable thing to do though?
The face is getting lit up by
sunlight all the time, man.
You have to realize how bad that is for
people don't realize how bad it is for
you until you look at
the rest of your body.
How much is your face deteriorating like?
Well this is much more wrinkles in my
face, in any other part of my body.
You know it's because my
face is in sun all the time.
Your son's coming off your windshield,
you're out there in the sun.
The aging process is accelerated
by the sun for sure. Huh?
You know like your armpits and everything
when you aren't pits get wrinkled,
your faces jacked as fuck.
You know,
when you are pit start giving out,
you know,
and all that shit starts
to sag and wrinkle,
that means your face looks like ass son.
You know these poor old ladies man,
these poor ladies,
a dark moment for a woman.
You know,
when especially a really super
attractive woman who's kind of banked her
personal self esteem on being attractive,
that's gotta be the worst
feeling in the world, man. Yeah,
you mean the Lady Universal
Justice crushing in on you.
Do you justice as a justice?
Because anytime you are an idolater,
anytime you base your, they'll shout,
not build the house on sand. Don't,
don't, don't structure your
whole life. And it's an easy
thing to do. And you know,
I get it and I understand how easy it
would be to slip into depending on your
looks and all that stuff. But it's
like if you are really intelligent,
you would have developed some facet of
yourself that wasn't based on that. Yeah,
yeah. I know what you mean. Yeah, I
guess. But it's, that's easy to say.
Most people live their lives
without a rule book or a guide book.
And they really don't know
what the fuck they're doing.
There's a lot of good people that wind
up and shit lives cause they just never
were told how to live and they made a
series of mistakes and they fell into the
wave of the momentum, those mistakes.
And now here they are. I'll fucked,
fucked by circumstance.
Being born a fuckup neighborhood did
some fucked up parents and fucked up
friends.
I prefer to believe though that and I
think this is where we definitely differ
in opinion cause I really believe that
no matter what life situation you're in,
you can get out of that. No a better
place I can. If you go to jail, you can't.
If you do something dumb when you're
young and you want to go to jail,
I think that this areas,
even in jail,
there are ways that you cannot master
certain techniques of getting out of it.
There's there's, there's always
true, but you will not be you.
You will not be surrounded by those.
Those techniques. You will not,
you will will have to seek them out.
It's going to take a very rare effort to
really rise and eliminate yourself from
the horrible reality of your conditions,
your surroundings, violent people,
all the different shit that they're doing
in there, the gangs, all the bullshit.
We're not going to involve in there.
It's more difficult. But it's like,
I just think is it an almost
impossible man? You, it's, I mean,
people do it and they get through it
and they become better people for it and
they learn while they're in there and
they really truly reflect on their life
and you know,
reflecting their mistakes,
but much more likely to get
sucked into the system. But, um,
there's a great book by Viktor Frankl
called man's search for meaning,
which is a written by a psychologist who
was in Auschwitz and was observing the
way people were reacting with apps, having
their humanity ripped away from them,
their clothes ripped off,
being naked, covered in lice,
uh, randomly getting killed. And um,
he like founded an entire style of
therapy based on his theory of why some
people in these situations survived.
Some even flourished in these situations
as far as being kind to people around
them and why some people died. And
the essence of his theory is that, uh,
that within the human being,
if you can find something to live for,
just something, whatever it is, then
that will take you through any situation.
It'll get you to the other
side of any situation. So it's,
this book changed my life. It's one of my
favorite books. It's fucking incredible.
And one thing that he says
in there, which is really awesome,
as he talks about how he was,
uh,
being on foot on a forced work march,
and he was really weak and he was being,
he was on a forced work march and he
fell down and one of the soldiers,
because he fell down,
came and just started beating him,
beating with his fucking rifle,
get up, get up, get up. And He, um,
he had seen this soldier kill
people with his technique,
just beat him to death with
a rifle because they wouldn't
get up. And he thought,
if I don't get up, I'm going to
die. And he thought, well, you know,
why should I not die? This is, I'm
probably going to die anyway. Why should,
why not just let this be
the moment that I die?
And all of a sudden he imagined himself
giving a speech where he was talking
about this experience and
using this experience to try
to transform the world in
a positive way,
to show people that no matter how
fucking horrible the situation is,
you can find a way out of it mentally
to give you the strength and the will to
keep pushing forward.
And he got up and he survived and
he became like a very famous, um,
psychologist and an a philosopher. So it's
a good, what was that guy's name again?
Victor Franco in the book is man's search
for meaning. And it's a brutal book.
It's really fucking intense. The
description of the death camp and stuff,
but it's awesome.
And his therapy was called logos therapy.
Existential psychotherapy.
Wow.
I mean,
what is the search for meaning?
The search remaining is a search to
try to find a reason to stay alive.
And then if you do try to find a reason
to stay alive and succeed and you do
look forward to life and
put positive energy into it,
something's going to come out. But is, is
that a meaning? Is that meaning, you know,
man's search for meaning? Is that a
correct is, is there really a meaning to,
to everyone. And if we look
at the way the world is going,
look at the direction
that human beings are,
are headed into with the pollution
of the world with, you know,
this crazy nuclear arms race thing,
trying to keep Iran from developing
nukes and Israel's got him and all these
people go have you look at overpopulation.
If you look at the economic crisis,
that crisis of of government, you look
at all this crazy shit that's going on.
Like what are we, we're preserving
what, like what are we doing?
We're moving it towards what
direction, you know, like what,
what are we trying to save? What are, what
is, what is, what is good about all this?
Well, I mean, the thing is like the I,
the ego tries to create a lofty reason.
Somebody's, you know what I'm saying? Like
search for meaning. No, you live and you,
but you live and you die.
You live under these
stances of is slow toxification
of the earth and you die.
And man's search for meaning.
Okay,
well you're searching for meaning while
all this shit is happening, right?
Well, yeah, I mean, you know what I
mean? I know exactly what you're saying.
And I think he's, he's dealing
with that very issue and he, uh,
what he says, what he says that he, yeah,
he would ask his clients are the
people who came to me, he's like,
why don't you kill yourself? What's the
reason that you're not killing yourself?
Why are you deciding to stay alive
in the world? Have you explored that?
If you ever asked yourself,
what's getting me out of bed?
What's the reason behind this? And it
doesn't have to be some lofty thing.
It doesn't have to be, I'm staying
alive to cause I wanna you know,
I want to become president
and bring peace to the world.
It can be some very simple thing.
It can be your kids, it can be art.
It can be cause you like video games.
It doesn't have to be
some lofty fucking thing.
Even though to me some
of those ideas would,
it was very difficult
for me to swallow it.
But it's finding that connection
to the world, you know,
it's finding that right way.
What is that all about? What is
the meaning of all of it? I mean,
that's the thing man.
Search for meaning that there's some
sort of a meaning to everything.
And I think it's an individual. It's
like what you said when you're at these,
each individual has their
own particular meaning.
And if they don't hit that frequency
and they don't find that path,
then they won't
be happy. Well, think of it man. Like,
you know, like the Times that I've,
this sounds really stupid, so go ahead
and make fun of me for it. But like, uh,
um, I have, uh, uh, a really,
uh, amazing girlfriend.
I have a really fucking cool shower.
I fucking love those entities right now.
There have been times in my life where I
haven't had things like that. You know,
we're having those connections,
right?
And I've noticed I tend to be more self
destructive in those states. Right.
You know what I mean? Like I
agree. It's like we are, uh,
Louis C CK has this really funny joke
about how like if you don't have a kid,
you know, he's like, I can't die.
There are people I have to feed.
They're things that I have to take care
of. You know, they're like, I like,
it adds this whole other d.
So it's like finding that
thing in your life, you know?
And it doesn't have to be an interpersonal
relationship. It can be other things,
but it's like the idea is find that thing
and that thing will be the thing that
steers your ship through this
turbulent, the inevitable. But
take it a step further. What, what
is this purpose? What is this,
this reason to stay alive,
this reason to find this thing,
this reason to do your job and stake your
position here and have your influence
here. What is it, what is it about
choosing the correct frequency to you?
Whatever it is for you,
whether it's pursuing a a career as a
professional bowler or a carpenter or a
doctor or a writer or whatever
the fuck it is for you.
What is it about that pole like
what, what do you, what is,
what is really happening is fulfilling
your own personal desires and interests?
Is that really just a part of a gigantic
equation and then everybody is working
and everybody has a certain part
and it's, it's, it's not stated.
It's not written in stone.
There's some room,
some wiggle room to go this way and that
way, but in order to truly be happy,
your, your instincts, your emotions,
all these things are guiding you towards
a certain direction and that certainly
Rick direction might be a part of
some huge that is impossible to see.
You'd have to get so far
high above the human race.
You have to separate yourself from your
history and your ideas about humans to
in order to see it all together and all
the see all the fucking different things
that are happening all over the world,
all together simultaneously and consider
the impact of the human race as a whole.
It seems like that that's
why there's trashman.
That's why there's like these jobs.
You'd be like a wire people actually
doing that. That's crazy. You know?
It seems like that is makes
complete sense that way.
We don't like to think that it makes
sense because we'd like to think that we
all have our own personal choice.
We all have our own identity and we all
have our own path that we can choose
through this life and you can change
when you can become a different person.
And I agree with all that I,
I'm not saying that it's 100%
everything that you do is set in stone,
but it seems to me that there is,
without a doubt there's a push towards
a certain direction and it might not be
very exact. It might not be. Everyone
gets pushed towards a certain direction.
But if you're, you're instincts are to
breed, to settle down, to procreate,
to possess the coolest
material possessions to shy
show off for the Jones is to
be successful at what you do. What
are all those things doing? Well,
all those things.
They're all pushing innovation.
They're all pushing the
creation of new technology.
They're all pushing the invention of
new crazy fucking super things. Yep.
It's almost like we don't even
realize we are infected by a parasite.
The parasite is technology.
We're slowly giving birth to it over a
period of a couple of decades until it
gets to a point where it
can take care of itself.
And what we're doing is we're carrying it
inside of our bodies. We're leaving it,
you know, in, in our houses. Everywhere
we look we're connected to it.
And it is a life form.
It is a life for, yeah.
We just don't recognize it as a life
form because we're looking for something
like us.
We are looking for something that has
cells and give blood and it has blood
pumping through it.
But if you look at like my old Shitty,
I have an old shitty Mac laptop. It's
big and fat, like a fucking like a Bible,
you know, and it cranks open. It's
like it's all rickety and shit.
The screen looks like dog shit.
It's only a few years old man.
It's like 10 years old. You know.
That's, that's, that's insane. You know,
in 10 years this thing is evolved.
Like,
like it's like comparing a
monkey and comparing a person.
But that shit took millions of years.
This laptop into a macbook pro that
only took 10 that's a 10 years.
His big fat, stupid brick and now
this thing's awesome. What is that?
It's 15 years. 16 years.
That's some crazy shit. And,
and the thing that it evolved
into is using itself as a,
as tip make make itself smaller like that
you're using each subsequent evolution
is accelerating the next phase. Yeah.
It's, it's really cool man. Yeah,
it's fascinating man. It might
be a life form, like literally,
literally technology.
It might be something that we just,
we don't consider it a life for him
cause we need to consider life forms as
being similar to us in some way. You can
kill it. It bleeds, it eats a chits. We,
that's the only way we see it.
We don't, we don't see this
thing that we're making.
We're literally creating its brain young.
But if you are watching from
a far, you'd be like, Oh yeah,
those creatures are innovating.
Some sort of, I don't know. Sure.
If you were an alien intelligence
without a doubt. Right?
That's immediately what you
would say a Terence Mckenna.
That what he says is we are
extruding psychic objects
into the material universe.
That's what human beings do. And if
you look at the, you know, the cities,
it's like coral extrusions of matter
coming from our minds like coral reefs and
this is all being,
this is all moving towards the
invention of some super tool.
Yes.
Yeah.
This is moving towards the invention
of some new connection to the universe.
Some new,
you know,
we might be giving birth to some
organism of some technological organisms.
Something that can replicate something
that is sentiment, it's aware of itself,
and that can make decisions and alters
its environment and chooses to replicate
itself in a more advanced way.
And then that one chooses to replicate
And like literally within a year they
could go through 10,000 years of fucking
evolution. I mean, they can, they can
produce incredible results. You know,
if you really get to the point of view,
see how quickly took technology and
computers have evolved as compared to
biology,
if they're both life forms,
it's not even close as to
which one's gonna win. Yeah,
the technology ones going,
they're getting to,
they're going to develop wormholes and
portals and we'll just be growing webbed
feet because we live near water.
You know what I mean?
That shit will take a million years
before people can hold their breath past
five minutes.
Right.
There's one tribe in New Zealand that
can hold their breath for seven minutes.
This is an evolutionary advantage.
You know,
when they talk about like Eskimos have
an evolutionary advantage where they
could be outside in freezing weather and
their hands don't get cold like ours do.
Well, your, your hands
would get frostbite,
you'd be fucked and you might even lose
your fingers. They can actually be fine.
You know, it's because their body
has adapted to that environment.
But that shit takes generations. Yeah.
You know when that started. Okay.
They didn't even have writing. Okay.
And the way that that happens, Joe is,
is by according to like hardcore
evolution as it's random mutation.
It's not even as though the necessity
caused, the thing that happened is though,
like you through the will of necessity
that you need to survive in the cold
longer, suddenly you get
that it's a mutation that
happens to some lucky Eskimo.
And because he has that mutation,
he's a little bit more advanced than he
reproduces more on passes that mutation
on. And that's how it gets into the
gene line, not from an intentionality.
So it's even more random than
necessity. It's just, you know,
when the moth accidentally mutates
into the same color of the tree,
that math is gonna survive more. The
birds can't see it. And that math,
is it accidental though? That's,
that's the big question. The question.
Random mutations being accidental is
a very controversial subject. Yes.
It's a very controversial theater.
Very cause a lot of people believe that
things just like Mckenna had this idea
that everything. Brian,
why do you keep doing that?
Because we have three minutes till
we have to split up. Apartment has
codes. You're going seven, five please.
I'm just letting you know because he
will have to split this into two podcasts
just so it doesn't matter.
I don't give a fuck.
I don't give a fuck about two podcasts.
Right. What were we talking about?
We're talking about whether evolution is
some random mutation or whether through
the need of the organism itself.
Somehow this begins to itch in Munich.
Well, the idea that, thanks did,
Mckenna had this idea that everything
naturally moves towards uh,
infinite complex con. Let comp the
idea. What was the exact wording?
Um, his idea was that everything
moves towards complexity.
Let like everything from the Big Bang
till today from single celled organisms to
multi celled organisms,
from everything that exists in the
whole universe has like an ethic.
It has like a rule and that rule moves
towards more and more complex things.
And that,
you know,
what it is is that these animals
recognize that they're being spotted and
somehow or another by them getting
jacked over and over again,
the universal consciousness
recognizes this is unfair.
This is kind of a tricky situation. These
things are stupid and they stand out.
We have to figure out a way to hide them,
to keep them in the situation.
And so what they do is they impart some
sort of an ability to blend in with
their environment. Like chameleons
are like octopus can, you know,
that it's just some sort of a universal
intelligence that recognizes there's an
imbalance. You know, we need this octopus,
but they're too easy to eat. We did.
They're getting Jack left and right.
Let's figure out a way to keep
them around a little bit more.
And so they adjust their superpowers.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
And,
and I find that so I mean
that other alternative that
just at some point on our,
it's like, wait a minute, I can
turn any color in the world.
Well, and even the idea of
random mutation and you know,
maybe that is how it goes and maybe the
whole thing is programmed by radiation
and maybe random mutations are
really what causes evolution.
But maybe that's the tool that it uses
in order to move towards complexity.
It's still the, it's moving
towards the same thing every time.
So to call it just random mutations.
It's not like,
it seems to be these random
mutations are always good. Yeah.
They're always an advanced version.
They're not that, that they don't,
they don't succeed. Yes. They don't
succeed. So even though it is, yes,
it's very simple. They are random
mutations. But look where it's going.
It's always going towards more
and more complex things. You know,
it's fascinating shit man. When you
really think about the idea that we're,
we're moving towards something and
no one's recognizing it and it's all
happening all the time.
And everything you do every day in your
life is really just pushing this thing
along in a program towards
some predetermined goal,
right? Yeah. The thing that you
consider to be whatever that, that,
whatever it is,
it really is part of a bigger picture.
And that's a very optimistic
way to look at it.
And I liked that way of looking at it
because the alternative is as them,
Ooh, well that's it folks. That's the end.
That's the mind. Fuck. That's the mind
fuck of life. Is this all just a pattern?
Are there patterns upon,
are there
infinite possibilities for these patterns?
Is every single second a choice that
you make that pushes you into a parallel
universe of a very close
distinction, but, but different,
was it evolution that farted on her,
Ellen Griffin said,
was the evolution or a random mutation?
We want to thank, uh, the podcast.
We want to thank the fleshlight
for sponsoring the podcast.
If you go to Joe rogan.net of the, uh,
put some, put some of that [inaudible]
word on cause there's some new shit.
What is this? That's like
Duran Duran. Talk to the guy,
the guy that did the song at the
opening at the podcasts singing.
Now it's just another song.
Who's singing there? Freelance.
Yeah. Throws tosome Deann
word on you got any in there?
Check gut put. I don't need
you. Do you got that one?
I was listening. I didn't really like it.
Well I'm not asking you if you like it.
Yes please. The lavender, our lavender,
our dotcom was in our podcast.
And where do you get it?
I, it's on iTunes. It's on
iTunes. It's on lavender out.
And uh, his Twitter is Duncan
Trussell, t r U S. S e l l.
And M. Brian's Twitter is red band, r.
E. D. B. A. N. Thank you very
much for tuning into the podcast.
Thanks to the fleshlight. And
again, if you go to Joe rogan.net,
you can get 15% off and you can fuck
it and it's awesome. There you go.
It's right there. And it's blue, but
it's not avatar. That's an alien.
Thanks everybody. And we'll probably
be doing another one this week. Um,
I'm trying to figure out who going to
do it. It might be Brian Cowen, but, uh,
thanks very much for all the love.
Thank you everybody in England.
I had a great fucking time.
I'll be at the galaxy theater this Friday
night at 8:00 PM with Joey Diaz. It's,
no, it's not Anaheim and Santa Ana. Yeah.
Did I say that already? Or wind is born.
What's that? Where wind is born.
Where wind is born. Santa Ana winds.
That's where they start.
Yup. There you go.
Knowledge Vegas at the palms this weekend
when Natasha Sheriff from last Comic
Standing Vegas out of the
palms, the palms, what is this?
This is dot Harris the Ding Dong show,
October 25th.