Okay.
Experience
Rain Soak jungle of the Pacific northwest.
We're hippies flourish. Chris
Ryan, dude, they're out there, man.
It's like they're like monkeys in the
jungle. They're like bugs in the forest.
Yeah. Flowers in the
garden. Yeah. That too.
You could look at it in a positive
way. Yeah. It's a good place for them.
It's an interesting place.
You're going to be there this weekend.
I'm very excited. I love Portland. I fuck
with them about being hippie infested,
but better that than fucking psychos.
You know? That's true. That's true.
It's an interesting place that it's got
such a strong culture for such a small
city. Yeah. You know what I mean?
There are huge cities three times that
size where like you don't even know
you're there. Right. Based on how people
dress, food, you know, attitude, whatever.
Portland is so specific and sort
of micro cultural. Yeah. Yeah.
I was talking to a friend who grew up
there the other day and I asked him what's
the biggest change from 20 years ago?
And it was interesting and he said, uh,
not eccentricity. It was really eccentric.
Then it's the same now. You know,
that sort of became the
calling card of Portland.
He said the big difference is there
was no smugness 20 years ago. Oh,
now people are smug now.
Yeah.
Because I think people who sort of
choose that identity then go to Portland.
You know what I mean? Like hippies
who are actually kind of Nazis. Yeah.
There's a lot of those, right? Yeah.
Like really judgmental hippies,
like super ultra left wing people who
are really just mean and they just find a
target and the target is a right wing.
So they go after them with or whomever
or they often go after each other.
It's like,
and so there's like a a fascist mentality
that just happens to have chosen a
hippie outfit off the rack.
Exactly.
I had an ex girlfriend who was really
into fashion and I remember one time her
saying, we lived in San Francisco for a
while and I remember her saying, yeah,
I want to, I want to go for a hippy look.
You know what I'm going to like buy the,
the fringe.
I just remember thinking like that is
so antithetical to what a hippie is.
You know,
like to go buy expensive hippie outfit.
Isn't that perfect though
that it's America. It's like,
it's like spraying body odor deodorant.
So you'll smell like a dirty hippy,
you know, I saw this commercial, not a
commercial, like a website rather online.
That cells use genes,
right?
They sell jeans that people
wore and they have like,
I mean they have like stains on them.
Some of them have patches and they
were $270 for a used pair of jeans.
Good gig though. Be a Jean wearer.
Good Gig to be selling these genes.
You could probably buy from
goodwill for really cheap,
and I forget the name of the
company, but they're, their hook is,
they're trying to make you look like,
you know, you're worn these man, right?
I don't care about what I
looked like, man, you're,
you're buying $270 use clothes.
Like you're instead of wearing
them and turning them into that,
you were immediately trying
to like adopt that persona.
I'm a comfortable pair of
jeans flicking me with my,
like when you see like fake rips,
those fake rips and people love it.
They're crazy.
Like what are you doing?
You're buying torn clothes and you think
it gives you a look down home. I'm,
the knees are just all worn out and these
pants, man, I'm waiting for, you know,
it works with clothes. I'm waiting for
it to work with the body, you know,
because I just turned 53 recently and
I'm like when it is old and fat going to
be in,
because it's a time when
genetic engineering kicks
in and everybody looks like
Doctor Manhattan.
Then like old ugly fat will be wow.
Interesting new. Yeah. It's
something different bag. It's like,
like a lot of white guys who are into
Asian women will go to Asian countries
like China for instance, cause there's
no white men. They're not as many rather.
Yeah. And so they become an oddity.
It's like how I've experienced that.
I remember the,
I can remember the first night,
I can remember the minute I
experienced that thinking like what,
you know first everyone's looking at me,
okay I'm a foreigner. Whatever's were,
but these women are smiling and Flirtin
and what that, what's going on? And,
and you know, eventually someone
explained to me like, dude, you're white.
They love,
and I've always had,
the one thing about my body that
I would complain about is my skin.
I've never liked my skin.
Like all I've got as much
melanin is anyone else,
but it's all in my teeth.
So I've got yellow teeth and
super pale skin, you know.
Um, do you get burnt real
easy? Completely. You know,
what is your bank minutes?
Irish? Yeah. Yeah. I don't remember
red head, which is like, you know,
one tweak away from albino red head.
I used to be gone gray and now do
you prefer the gray or the red? Well,
the Guy Kinda could thing going on and
go a blondish right. For an accident.
That's it. When you mix red with gray, you
get blonde. Right. But no, when I was a,
you know, until I was in my thirties
or forties probably, um, you know,
I had sort of orange, red hair.
Whoa. Yeah, it was dark orange.
It was like copper wire kind of
color. Um, so it wasn't Bozo.
That's very close.
People are prejudice against that in men.
Yeah. Sexy man. It's deep.
Geeky. How does that happen?
Well, maybe because of the
novelty and also there's a,
there's a reputation among redheads
for being sort of temperamental and
everybody knows a temperamental
woman's a lot of fun in bed. Right.
Maybe that's it.
And temperamental men are just
dangerous drunks except assholes.
Fires you hassles. That's funny.
Raquel Welch was a red head,
although she was Mexican,
so I'm not sure how that happened.
Everything I've seen from Raquel
Welsh, it was so old. I can't remember.
Or it was black and white. Yeah,
she was a redhead. Like a dark red.
I think she dyed it. Yeah, but just
like Auburn, reddish kind of bloody.
You think di was like back then,
what would they just grind up some leaves
and fucking rub them in their hair?
Well, they apparently had, um, what's
that stuff they use in Pakistan? Uh,
uh, Hannah. Oh, you know Hannah's goes
way back. Yeah, that's, that's tough.
Is Strong Shit too, right?
People get those fake Henna
Tattoos. They last for days,
came to scrub them off. The dudes
in Pakistan, Henna dye their beards.
That's look, oh, that's funny. So
like when, when they start going gray,
that's their version of just for
men. Exactly. That's funny man.
Yeah. Yeah. No one wants to be gray.
That's the one thing like
universally people like, Ooh,
that's a fucking tricky one man.
Did they think so I'm not
happy about my gray hairs.
I just grew in a little chin beard
here and it's completely white.
And I had one five,
six years ago when I was
traveling and it was still red.
So we don't know what happened between
then and now. I got old man. Oh,
so you weren't shaving, you were
shaving it completely. Yeah.
So it was like a snapshot. I,
there was no gradual process.
I still have mostly like say
be like 80% black in my beard,
but like the sides of my hair, like where
if I have any, this is all going white.
Now all this is gray on the sides.
So you think the grades more
traumatic than the balding?
Cause I've gone through both.
Both of them are rough. Um,
the gray is probably less traumatic cause
I know dudes who are totally gray who
dye their hair and they look fine
or they look fine with the gray.
Which gentleman kind of thing?
I know both. Yeah. It just,
while it just represents
reality represents the
finite nature of the body and
usually going through a process and also
like I was talking about how I'm hoping
that like old and fat comes in
now that I'm almost there or,
or they're dependent
arguably, uh, you, your,
your sort of balding experience happened
at a really good time. Historically,
I've got lucky sorta,
but I fought it for the longest time.
I had hair transplants,
Propecia and I put Rogaine in there,
which is very ironic.
And your name is Rogan.
You're going bald and you're
buying rover shake sponsorship.
Especially when you had to go to the
counter. Like now you can just buy it,
but you just have to go up
to the fucking pharmacist.
He said prescription for that Shit.
Yeah.
I've bought a lot of Rogaine in my day
because my ex father in law in Spain had
me bring it back from the states.
Every time I came to visit he
couldn't get it over there.
I think it was like he thought it
was stronger or better in some way.
So it was like the only thing that kept
my relationship with him, partly civil.
I so wished that I shaved my head way,
way,
way back in the day when I first
started worrying about it and way better
because I love being bald. Like I really,
I don't, if I could grow here back now,
I would still shave it.
It's the easiest thing in the world.
I don't have to go to. I had
a great barber and she was
hilarious. A hairstylist,
my friend Gabrielle. Oh she, she worked
on news radio with me. She was my,
she cut my hair forever,
you know?
But at a certain point in
time she was cutting it.
It just looked like dog shit after she
was just like get thinner and thinner.
And then once I quit taking the Propecia,
then it was like a serious
downhill slide. Oh really? Yeah.
Shit was just dying left and right.
It was horrible. I agree with you.
I think that all young men like in their
mid twenties should shave their heads.
Yeah. It's just so you don't worry about
it. If you're going bald, for sure.
Shave your head. I say people don't
want to shake my head. Believe me.
Take control.
Yeah.
It's better than whatever the fuck is
gonna happen if you don't shave your head.
I wanted to shave my head. I
wouldn't, we were in India,
I was with my wife Caselden
in India, in Goa. For months.
We were in Asia for like over a year
and I thought this is a perfect time to
shave my head because if I've got a weird
shaped head or I look like a Dork or
whatever, who gives a fuck? Right. Nobody
knows me. Um, and I came to her one day,
we rented this House on
the beach. I was like, hey,
cut my hair and I want to shave my head.
And she said, oh, please don't do that,
please. So why? Why? Well,
it's not just because she's used to
me looking like a Dork, but it was,
my father had just had a liver transplant
and she said in India you shaved your
head when your father dies and like,
and she's very suspicious and she's
got all these beliefs and she's like,
you know, to understand your
father's and rocky shape,
you don't want to be shaving your
head. You know, that's different. Yeah,
I could see that. Oh, I miss
my, I miss my chance. Yeah.
I missed my chance when
I was on news radio.
That's when I got my hair transplant.
My first one, I got three of them.
When I got my first one, I was on
news radio and I was like, God damn,
this shit is going man. I just like,
it was seeing it fallen out and uh,
I was like, I'm thinking about shaving
my head. They were like, don't do it.
Don't do it. I'm like, my hair
is starting to look like shit.
And they talked me out of it.
Well because it will fuck because of
your character. Right? You like, it goes,
you'd look like a psycho. I'm like,
all right. So I didn't, you know,
people get used to whatever the
fuck you look. Right. Exactly.
Like I have a picture of Joey Diaz,
um, back when he was like 210 pounds.
It's crazy. It's on my wall in my
office. I stole it from the comedy store,
was a head shot that he had up. And
um, he, I don't even think it was up.
I think I stole it from the office.
I don't think they had put it up.
So I snacked it. Um, but it's, um,
it's Joey like Finn and like,
but if I saw it,
if he'd walked in today looking like that,
I'd be like, what the fuck is going on?
You sick? Yeah. But I see him the
way he is now. I give him a big hug.
And that's Joey, you got used to, you
get used to the change. Definitely.
And I mean, just thinking about
the, I turned 53 last week, right?
So thinking about time and all that,
and I'm here in la visiting my
parents who are in their seventies.
So there's all that, you know, there are
a lot of cues for these things. And, um,
there's this famous poem by
Dylan Thomas where he says,
rage against the dying of the light. You
know, and I often think like, I dunno,
I don't know, maybe embrace the
darkness, you know, like the light,
like people fight, he lost the fight
against pancreatic cancer. Well, you know,
maybe that's not a fight worth
waging, you know? Well, no,
I know a guy who's got pancreatic cancer
whose fighting it and they gave him a
very short window to live and
he's pushed way that, and you
know,
and everybody's completely shocked,
but he has this amazing attitude
and he's positive and enjoying life.
And I think his point of view is not,
instead of rage against
the dying of the light,
enjoy the moment and live your life.
And I think because of that,
and he's actually living longer, there
was a guy, his name was bill boiler, uh,
who I became friends with
from the Internet. From my,
my own message board. And um,
he was a young kid who got pancreatic
cancer and he lived for years and,
uh, we became friends from online,
you know, he, he would have a,
he had a screen name,
we would call it a,
I think it's queen name was called Pan
can fight or a pan can like pancreatic
cancer for, I believe that
was a screen name. And um,
I would get them tickets to the UFC
and get them tickets to a comedy show.
And one time it came to visit me in
Florida and um, he came to the show,
I got them tickets to this show and then,
you know,
he told him he was going to go
sleep in his car and I was like,
you drove all the way down here, you're
gonna Sleep in your car? He goes, yeah,
I just wanted to see the show.
So I got him a hotel room and you know,
like this guy's got cancer
and sleep in his fucking car.
Like your immune system is like super
important when you have cancers.
Sleep is super important
for the immune system.
But he was always so
thankful and never weird.
And like for a kid,
a young kid who was facing this horrible
disease that almost nobody escapes
from, it's like the percentage of people
that survived one of the worst, very,
very bad.
But his attitude was always like,
I'm going to fucking fight
this and I'm gonna end it.
Would post these tweets on the messages
on the message board. Like, uh,
three years later I'm still alive,
motherfucker. Like that kind of shit.
And you know, he had tubes in his
stomach when I saw him. Once we saw him,
Eddie Bravo and I became
friends with this kid.
We saw maybe six or seven times
over the years. And uh, you know,
one time we saw him, his head, he's lost
all his hair, his eyebrows were gone.
He had tubes coming out of
his stomach because you know,
some surgery that he had and he was still
alive and he still had a good attitude.
It was amazing what an attitude he had.
And I think that that attitude is probably
what allowed him to live for so long.
But he eventually did die recently
and as we all do, right. Yeah. Yeah.
It's funny, I saw the, the guy from 60
minutes who was in a car crash last week.
Did you see that? Um, I
forget his name, but he's 73,
he was 73 years old and the headline said,
this gentleman, his name, I can't
remember, lost his life in a car crash.
And I thought, you know, when you're
73, you're not losing your life.
You've already banked 73 years.
You're losing a couple of years.
You're losing whatever was left
at 11. Yeah. Me. Yeah. Yeah.
Actuarial tables or something. Yeah.
Right. Um, that's not losing your life.
You've spent that money that's like,
you know,
somebody robs you and they got everything.
Well,
they didn't get everything and they didn't
get what I already spent. Right, right.
It's not like they spent, they
robbed your whole life savings. Well,
it really saved my whole life.
I've never saved a couple of weeks.
Yeah.
Really look at this picture
of Vince Mcmahon from the WWE.
69 years old. Seriously?
Yeah. This is insane.
And that's not shop that I'm going to, uh,
I'll, I'll, should I forward this to you,
Jamie? What's that? Okay.
He's on the cover of muscle and fitness.
Tony Hinchcliffe sent this to me.
Tony Hinchcliffe is a fucking WWE fanatic
and he's in love with Vince Mcmahon,
but nobody in human history has ever
looked like that at 69 years old. Yeah.
Testosterone is a motherfucker.
Yeah.
So if you want to rage against the dying
of the light, that's the way to go.
Get all pumped up testosterone
replacement therapy. Go to a doctor.
They bring it to the same level. So we
look at that picture. That's ridiculous.
It's up. Oh, sorry. It's behind you. Yeah,
he goes, now that other one, that's okay.
It doesn't have to be on, but
it's just ridiculous. Like,
who the fuck is ever looked like that
at 69 is it good or is it bad? You know,
I don't think it would be too terrible.
People could live to be a thousand years
if I knew that we had the resources to
support it because I would think like,
man, what kind of amazing philosophy,
insight would you get from a thousand
year old woman who's lived hundreds and
hundreds and hundreds
of years and you know,
and seeing culture shift and change and
remembers as much as she could and tells
you about life in a way that only a
person has lived a thousand years and we
were are a little blips. You talked
to a guy that lived a hundred years,
you're going to be fascinated
if he has his faculties.
But someone who's lived a
thousand, my God, I mean it would,
holidays would be a bitch. So you imagine
the great, great, great, great grandkids.
She has to buy shit for.
Imagine the candles on his fucking
pain do with Dai blown them out.
Isn't it ironic, don't you think? Um,
I think that we're going to see a great
advance in our lifetime of, of lifespans.
But the real issue is do we
have the resources for that?
Because one of the things that is going
on with our world as everybody knows,
is that there's a lot more people today
than there's ever been in recorded human
history by a giant number.
And when you see places like
India that are in dire poverty,
it's one third of the
size of the United States.
It has three times as many
people. Plus it's like, wow,
I mean how that,
you're dealing with a lot of poverty
and a lot of suffering and you know,
maybe it's a perspective issue and
maybe what I considered poverty,
they consider life and
that if I lived that life,
I would be accustomed to it
and it would be normalized.
But I've got to think that most
people don't want to sleep on dirt.
And most people don't want to
eat food that's bad. Or you know,
the struggle to survive in any way and
do your only with rampid diseases and
that you're dealing with an
impoverished nations, you know,
when they don't have enough medicine to
take care of people. I don't know, it's,
but if we did have the resources men,
it would be amazing to talk to a thousand
year old person who knew everything
about the the mean.
If you could keep your faculties,
how grumpy when they get these fucking
kids today in their electronic hologram
music. Pull your hands out.
When I was a kid, we had drums.
We met at an animal scannings
fucking kill those animals.
We chop those trees down. We
hauled him out, striked the
skins, made the palm palm,
boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
But seriously, I mean, if
you think about, you know,
just how much things have changed
since you and I were kids. You know,
if you're talking to the guys 500 years
old, it's like, holy shit man. Well, yeah.
The other thing is thousand
years from now, I mean,
if we really could live to be a thousand
years old, a thousand years from now,
people might not be necessary. I mean, we,
we might have evolved past this state
in some sort of a gigantic technological
leap. I really believe that when you're
looking at the iconic image of an alien,
you know the big heads,
the big eyes and no genitals.
I think we're looking at what holds us
back as organisms and what the things
that if you look at our wars and our
greed and does all the crazy fucking
larceny and crazy shit that people do,
it's all attached to the primate body.
You know,
it's all attached to sex and breeding and
greed and guilt and fear and the worry
about being mortal.
If we can move past that and some
genetic engineering leap or if it goes
Kurzweil on us and they developed some
insane artificial body that you transfer
your consciousness into that
it's just way more preferable.
You know that you got all the
buttons you can push for orgasm,
all the busing buttons you
can push for adventure.
All those exist inside your head and
they can access them at any moment,
but you're looking at the world
and some crazy three d, you know,
minority report fashion
where everything you see,
you're interacting with the
world in a very different way.
You might get a bunch of people to jump
ship and the models might get better and
then the next model
might be so pleasurable,
so much better than being a human being
that had just fucking people just start
jumping ship. Especially
English racing, you know,
we're fucking polluting the ocean.
Guess what?
How about you live off photosynthesis?
We were going to cure the whole thing.
All right. You gotta stay the Allergen,
Kim? No, you live off the sun.
Incorporate somehow into the genome
or something. But somehow, and look,
there was a,
um,
a snail that I read about recently or a
slug that shifts between photosynthesis
and actually eating things and it eats
a certain algae and then through eating
that algae can actually absorb life exist
off photosynthesis and this is a new
fine. So it's like colonized.
It's food and it's still alive.
Yeah. Yeah. That's it.
It's somehow or another taking
disability from its food.
Do you know how sea slugs have
sex? No. No, this is great.
Since you mentioned slugs, I wasn't
planning to talk about slugs today, Joe,
but since you brought it up,
a sea slugs are so interesting.
They're there on the bottom of the
ocean and they're just sort of wandering
around blind right on the bottom
of the ocean. What are those?
Can they see what those things? They're
like motion detectors, you know,
whatever antenna. Um, but
the, when to sea slugs.
Now Sea slugs contained both male and
female reproductive organs right inside
their bodies.
So they've got sperm and eggs and
when to sea slugs meet each other,
they sort of
rear up and, and with those horn,
these horns come out of there,
their heads and they start slamming
each other with these horns,
like a couple of, you know,
mountain goats or something.
And eventually one of them will break
through the skin of the other with his
horn.
And at that point he injects
sperm into the other and he,
and so the other becomes female.
Well,
because now the eggs have been
fertilized and that one's a male. Wow.
So it's like when the,
they're like fighting to see
who's male and who's female,
which you know,
maybe reminiscent of that's
cravat school or summer camp.
Boy Scouts. Who's the boy? Just retreats.
Yeah, man, that's fascinating.
That's fascinating.
It's amazing when you see all
the different varieties of life,
when you see all the different forms
that it can take and then you stopped to
consider that. That's just in our,
you know, our Earth's environment.
Imagine like what they're going to find
if they could chip through your Ropa and
get to those oceans.
It's very possible there's something
alive under there that's being fueled from
the heat of the volcanic vents.
Most likely nothing.
We've never seen anything in the
ocean other than like, you know,
we see like hermit crabs, they'll use
other people's, you know, in Shell. Yeah.
Who've never seen anything like
build a structure. Other than that,
I don't think like nothing because
nothing you could consider like, look,
there's a house, you know, like a beaver.
Beaver has a beaver den, you know,
even it's crude as fuck, but damn,
they're building their own little house.
I was kind of crazy and we
obviously have insects in,
in the the world above ground that build
incredible structures and termites,
a cross section of a termite
mound. Insane. They're like
the vents for key thing.
Temperature leaf cutter ants.
Is that the one where they
filled it up with cement?
Uh, and they, they bring the
leaves back and then they have a,
a fungus that grows on the leaves and
that's what they eat where the termites
probably do something similar.
The termite thing I'm thinking of,
I saw some BBC special recently and I
think it was termite mounds in Africa.
And what they do is like where they
have all the eggs has to be an exact
temperature and humidity and this
is in the Kalahari desert, right?
Which is dry and the
temperature changes a lot.
And I today and so they build these things
and they've got this chamber and then
below the Chamber are cooling fins that
that hang down perfectly spaced and the
air circulates through them so that it
keeps the temperature exactly the same
all the time. Wow. It's like, how does,
I mean there are things in
evolution that are not understood,
right? Like there are things where
it's like, well, there's no, um,
a gradual way to get from
point a to point B here.
How do termites know to do
that? Right? You know, that,
how do you encode that in DNA?
That doesn't seem possible
based on what we know of DNA,
especially since it's
an isolated incidence,
right? It's happening all over the
termite world. Yeah. It's crazy. Yeah.
They don't communicate in a way that we
understand. Right? So the, yeah, it's,
it's very mysterious. I
think there's a, you know,
you're talking about like quantum
leaps and thinking and stuff.
I feel like in a strange way,
and I'm even hesitant to say
this publicly because of, it's a,
an example of what I'm talking about.
Like it's really hard to talk about the,
the areas where Darwinian notions of
evolution don't quite make it because you
immediately get lumped in with the
religious lunatics, you know what I mean?
So it's sort of woo woo people or,
yeah.
So it's sort of shut down an
important conversation. You know,
much like the Nazis,
I mean the Nazis were doing all this
interesting science that you can't talk
about, you know, or you can't
talk about eugenics like,
well that's a legitimate
thing to talk about.
Sure.
Everything is legitimate to talk about,
including when you're talking
about Nazi history, right?
Why is that legitimate to talk about?
But eugenics as a concept,
not saying as an actual practice,
right?
I don't think you should take people's
lives because they're dumber than you,
but you could, you could encourage
some people not to reproduce. Like,
like people who have a
genetic, a propensity to a
certain illness, like, hey,
you know, maybe you should
adopt and here's a massive
tax credit if you do. Right.
I agree with that.
But man,
I don't think you should be able to tell
anybody that they can or can't breed.
I think education is,
is important with all aspects of breeding,
but we all know that people make terrible
decisions when it comes to breeding
because didn't want to get dead Knutsen
and, and then they're like, oh no,
I met a person. All right, now I've got
to deal with it. You know what I mean?
I don't think we should take it
got away from people just because they
have diseases or forced them to get an
abortion or if,
you know,
the also one valid point that
people have illnesses say is, um,
I don't want anyone else
to have the illness that I
have, but I'm alive and I'm,
I'm okay. And I have, you know,
cerebral palsy and I have,
you know, whatever I have,
you know, and I can still enjoy
life. It might not be perfect,
but you're telling me
that this experience,
my experience in life because I have
cerebral palsy or because I have something
else is not valid. And I'm saying that's
wrong. I'm hampered, I'm hindered.
I've certainly can't move the way a
regular person moves. Right? However,
my experience is my experience and I
can make the most of it and I enjoy it.
And I'm not necessarily
trying to give a child,
but I'm not trying to invalid
argument for that. Okay.
Right. But okay, but let's look
at the counter argument, right?
Because the assumption there is you're,
as you said,
you're invalidating my experience
but looked at from another way.
Well what are we comparing that
experience to where we're experienced?
We're comparing it to nothing. We're
not, we're not comparing it to,
you know, you should die. You should
be, you know what we're saying?
Nothing right now.
How do you compare it to nothing.
A kid who isn't born isn't suffering.
Right.
So I mean, I think that the, the
assumption, I've got a cousin,
this really smart kid,
he's like
five or something. And the other
day he was talking about how he, uh,
before he was born,
he was saying that all
fetuses should have um, uh,
iPads but, but no password. Right.
Cause cause they wouldn't understand it.
It's like five I think. And it's cause
it's boring, you know, being a veto.
Right. And I was like, well, my aunt was
talking to him and, and uh, he said, uh,
she said, well, where were you
when you were a fetus? He said, uh,
I was a sleepy dead. And he
like sleepy dead. He, yeah,
it's not like dead when you die.
It's,
it's dead before you're born and you're
kind of sleepy, so sleepy, dead, whoa.
And like, okay, yeah, this
is, it's kind of a genius kid.
What does that kid actually know?
Something what if you remember some shit
that we forgot? I'll tell you. I mean,
this is gonna sound crazy,
but I remembered when I was a kid,
I remembered you remembered
what I remembered the,
the feeling of where I came
from before I was born.
And what happened was,
and this is a weird thing,
I was just talking to [inaudible]
about this recently. Um,
I remembered it as it general,
uh, how can I say this?
Like, what I remember is
as I got older, as a kid,
I remember thinking,
I'm losing this memory.
I'm losing contact with something.
I know.
And as my consciousness was getting
more sort of aware as a, uh,
as a person, right. Uh,
I realized that that was a really
valuable thing that I was losing.
And so as I was like
12, 13, 14, I was like,
I have to remember this. I, I knew,
I wouldn't remember it as a memory.
So I was creating like a,
a record of it that I would remember,
if that makes any sense to, you know
what I mean? Like, I know, you know,
it's like people who have,
um, I forget what it's called,
where they don't recognize faces,
like, uh, that all Oliver sacks,
the neurologist has that and he describes
it and one of his books and he's like,
they've got this face blindness.
So what they'll do is if they're having
a conversation with you and they're
going to go to the bathroom and they
know they're going to come back,
they'll be like,
okay,
the guy with the blue shirt and the
thing and the tattoos is Joe, you know,
just to create a record in his head
and then we'll go to the bathroom.
So when he comes back, he'll
remember your Joe. Wow. Yeah. It's a,
it's a really interesting
neurological thing.
I would like to see that guy
draw a picture of a face. Yeah.
I wonder if they would want to, how
that works. Do you know Oliver Sacks?
He would be an amazing guest. Know don't
know. I don't know who he is. Yeah,
I've heard of him actually described that.
I forgot what show was listening to,
but he was actually describing
that issue. Yeah. Not,
not knowing what people's
faces necessarily look
like. Yeah. I think I just,
it's hard to imagine it is,
right because it's something
that's so automatic to us.
He also wrote a book about
Hallucinogens Hallucinations,
which was very interesting
because it was the first, this came
out maybe five years ago and it was,
it struck me as the
first like main stream,
a sort of non apologetic discussion
of the use of hallucinogens by a very
mainstream doctor who's written all these
bestsellers and he talks about when he
lived in Topanga in the 60s and he
took some acid. Of course he did.
You have to get in there exactly what
to go to the farmers and the gate.
That place is ridiculous.
I was looking at a house that once and
he's fucking hippies talked me out of
even looking any further.
They were like, uh,
like the house had a tax court behind
it. They're like, if you buy the house,
you're going to let the community use
a tennis court. Right. I go, what?
That's right under my bed. Like
get the fuck Outta here. No,
I'm not going to let you carry you.
Fucking people are too much.
Imagine all these dirty hippies
showing up Sunday morning.
You're trying to sleep in here.
Boop, boop, boop. Hey man,
that was inbound. It's new.
It wasn't man. You should share
the score, you know. Fuck you.
It was good. You said like the
California and the Saturday night live.
That's them doing. I know. It's so true.
I want to go back to what you were saying
though. Like your, your memory of, um,
of B before you were born. You know, I was
listening to this, a radio lab podcast.
I know that I've said that about a million
times. If you're playing the podcast,
drinking games,
time to have a shot,
because I listen to that
podcast all the time,
but they were talking about memories
and how poor people's memories truly are
and how many people believe that they
have an idea in their head that's carved
in stone. This is what
happened. But if you, if you
look at the, the actual events,
the provable actual events in comparison
to their idea, what happened, right?
Oftentimes they're way off, you know,
courts or Tara. Horrible. Yeah, yeah.
La often people see that when they go
back to where they grew up, you know,
and you go back to your home
and your house looks smaller,
everything looks different.
It's just like, wow. It's
like, oh, it's like someone,
he made a replica of where you grew up
but did a shitty job because they didn't
have all the data. Did you
ever feel betrayed when you
had that experience? No. No,
no. I, the opposite for me, when I went
back to where I grew up, it was amazing.
I took my, uh, my wife and my kids and
we walked through the neighborhood.
There wasn't even a neighborhood.
I lived across the street from the Charles
River and this is big park like area
and uh, I would go fishing, um, down the
river. There was like this pond. It was,
I would catch bass at and I took them on
these walks that I used to take through
the woods and I was like,
this is a crazy spot to grow up.
I didn't realize how weird it was. I grew
up near this place called echo bridge.
And Echo Bridge is in a place
called Newton upper falls.
And I had a waterfall across the
street from my house and I never,
never realized like how cool this was
until I took the kids there and walked
around. I was like, wow,
this is a wild place to be.
Like all the places where I used to hang
out with my friends and just, you know,
it's nice and it wasn't all built up. It
was still there. Still like that. Yeah.
I mean it's the hemlock gorge reservation.
That's the area.
I think it's preserved.
That sounds
nice.
I always imagine you like inner city
cause I remember you talking about rough
neighborhoods and stuff.
I lived in Newton from the time I was 14
to the time I was 17 or a toilet time.
I was a, well that was
high school, you know,
14 to 17 and then like a year and a half,
two years after that I stayed there.
But before that I lived in a place called
Jamaica Plain. Jamaica plain was rough,
but we only lived there for about a year
and a half, maybe two years at the most.
But I went to high school or Grammar
School in this, uh, I think it was curly.
I think that was the name of the
grammar school. But it was bad man.
It was real bad. It was Jamaica
plain is become more gentrified now.
But when I lived there in 1979,
1980,
I guess it was somewhere around then.
I think my first year of high school
was 81 it was a, it was really bad.
There was a lot of like
bad shit going down.
There was 17 year old kids that
were in the seventh grade, you know,
they would like never graduated
and like you'd be, you know,
I was like a little kid and I was going
to class and it was just fucking full
grown adults that are in my class.
You know,
there's guys and girls making out in
the back of the class was all these like
inner city kids like they were.
So I come from Florida where I lived
before that in a college community in
Gainesville,
Florida.
And we moved to like the only place in
Boston that my parents could afford and
it was this Jamaica plain place and
they worked really hard to get us out of
there and moved us to Newton and
Newton was like way more urban,
way more relaxed but Jamaica plain
was fucking scooter. It was sketchy.
There's a lot of crime like w there's
breaking and enterings in our,
in our neighborhood all the time.
You know,
like we got a dog just to bark to let
us know if someone is trying to get into
the house.
It was very weird.
It was a weird place to live and then
Newton was a total different planets.
Cool. That's something you and I
have in common. Moving as kids.
I moved a lot as a kid.
I went to call my three high schools.
It's real common with people that
are interesting for whatever reason.
Yeah.
I mean I have a younger sister and
she and I sort of dealt with it in
diametrically opposed ways.
Like she um,
had developed a real need
to be part of the community.
So as soon as we moved to it,
we then Jacksonville for example,
as soon as we were in Jacksonville, she
developed the local accent within a week.
You know, I never developed
any accent. I sort of,
I became the pedantic arrogant asshole
who doesn't need friends. You know?
That's how I dealt with
it. Right. You know? Okay.
I mean I got used to eating alone
in the lunch room, you know,
like reading a book. Like I got my book,
I'll ignore the rest of you fuckers.
I mean, I made friends, but the,
the point was that I didn't, like,
I wasn't reaching out, you
know, I was trying to be,
and then that worked great in the,
you know, the rest of my life.
Traveling all the time, living overseas,
all that. I don't have a home. And you're,
you're like this too. Right? You
move enough. It's like, well, okay,
I lived here for a couple of years.
But when people say don't you
miss your home, all your friends,
the people you grew up with. I don't
know the people I grew with, you know,
there was stages.
I'm still friends with a couple guys
from high school. Really? Yeah. Yeah,
me too. Yeah. One guy from high
school, actually I have two,
two buddies from high school that we
talk. One that I'm pretty close with. Uh,
I saw him last when I was
in Boston and, um, you know,
we've known each other since we were
like 14, so it's, it's weird, you know.
[inaudible] now he has grown kids and
we went to dinner with him and his kids,
his daughters like in her twenties.
I'm like, this is crazy, man.
You gotta you know, I've known his wife
forever too. It's uh, it's interesting to,
to see, uh, he, he grew up in that
neighborhood. He lived there and you know,
we became friends when I moved
into the neighborhood. But, um,
almost all my friends like Joey,
Ari,
like all these guys moved all over the
place. You know, Dunkin, um, you know,
Brian Collins the worst, not
the worst, I shouldn't say,
but the most experienced because he
lived in Saudi Arabia, his family,
his family was involved in international
finance and so he lived in all these
crazy Middle Eastern countries.
He lived in Afghanistan.
I believe that's a whole different level.
Oh, he lived everywhere, man. Yeah. And,
but he's one of the most interesting
people I know because of that.
It's just like he,
there's pros and cons I think definitely
there's like a definitely like a more
calming confidence of growing up in a
neighborhood where you know all the people
and you can, but there's also like
a limiting aspect to that too,
especially if it goes wrong.
You know, like if she gets
on the neighborhood right,
and I assure you the bad neighborhood or
if you get labeled as like a person in
the neighborhood with the cancer ostracize
or they get mad at you for something,
right? Yeah. It's like you redefine
yourself when you move to new places.
That's what the new girl,
she's a new girl. Where's she
from? She's from Portland.
Oh, did she smell like feet?
You know, like you see her,
she's wearing the grand dress.
She's got a truly honor. Thank dude.
She's got oh good. I got assigned
a guy. You're the fucking,
I'm the Lloyd Guy. I mean, everyone
always likes, I like Petrouli.
I like prune juice. I mean, I
know it's a joke, but it's like,
it tastes good for your body to get,
makes you shit or not shit.
I don't even know. I know what
affect shit somehow, but I mean,
I just like the flavor and
put truly smells good to me.
It's not the worst smell.
I like incense. That's a very hippie
thing. People get angry at you.
You don't like the smell of incense?
Not if they're anything but
nug Champa I like the nug.
Champa some stuff laying around
here somewhere right there tonight.
This one smells good. Yeah,
I'm sure it'll be fine. Yeah.
Hey, shout out to Dunkin. I feel shouting
out. White people shouting out. Well,
you mentioned Dunkin and,
and you know when I,
I tweeted that I was going to be on
the show. Everyone's like, oh you,
you and Joe and Duncan. Oh
yeah. Dot. Can couldn't make it.
He's in big Sur live in the time. It was
like, fucker. He likes it up there. Oh,
he loved it. Good. He's trying to
talk me into buying a house. Dude.
I'll watch your house. What a favor. He,
he'd be doing you. Yeah, I would do
that too. I would totally trust him.
It's pretty cool up there.
I mean that's,
it's a very unusual place because
you can't really support a large
population.
It's like you can only live in or out.
You're kind of butted up against the
mountain. Yeah. The water's right there.
It's like this is all you got.
You spend time at Esselyn ever
talking about hippies? No, I did. Um,
I was invited to do a workshop there.
How's that smell? Is that okay?
I don't even smell it yet. He'll
smell that's going that way. Damn.
What's wrong with you?
Around what you know, son,
you should smell the fuck out of
that. Oh, there it is. How's that?
It's nice sunny show. Don't lie
to me, man. I'll put it right out.
I haven't really noticed that. I tell you.
I mean, I don't, it must be the coke. Oh,
sorry. How dare you? That's a bad drug.
Don't understand it. That's a
drug I had access. I mean you're,
you're in this position all the
time, I'm sure. But you know,
having access to like the
best of the best of something.
I knew a guy in college who was the
son of an oil minister from a country,
I won't name, just to keep me out
of trouble. He had a private jet,
he used to fly to Columbia.
He had a diplomatic bag so he could
bring anything into the country.
He bring this shit into the country
and he was like in this frat and I knew
someone who was in the Frat and
I was never a frat boy at all.
But they would invite me and like,
he's like yellow rocks of coke,
you know, and like, and it was the,
I mean I went to this dumb ass
college where everybody was rich.
So the drug scene there was off the
charts and like I've done the best coke
there is. Right. I mean, I know the guy
who invented them, Dma, I, you know,
it's like I've got,
I had these really good connections for
drugs and coke sucks the best coke in
the war. Shit, don't get it. Wow.
I mean, my, my sense is that it,
it affects a certain personality structure
in a really pleasant way and I don't
have that structure. So for
me hallucinogens are like
boom, that's pushing my,
my button, right. Coke, it just made
me fucking nervous and drink too much.
Well you're a self
deprecating guy and you joke around about
a lot and you also introspective and I
think that one of the things that people
don't like about people that are coked
up is that they want to
talk about themselves.
They want to tell you how fucking
bad ass they are. They want to brag,
they want to,
they want to talk about like making money.
We're going to buy this forest, we're
going to fucking, you know, like,
you know what I mean?
Like Mike Young used to always talk about
how people in on coke always want to
start a business with you
because it's really kind of true.
It's like they always have these awesome,
yeah,
they have these crazy
grand plans and it just, I,
I've never been interested in it. I
got lucky and I ducked it. I was a kid,
I've told the story a hundred times,
but I had a friend,
my friend that I'm still
friends with in high school,
his cousin used to sell
it and he turned his life,
went down the toilet and
I watched him wither away.
Lost like a shitload of
weight became weird, you know,
just always on coke and when it warrants,
it wasn't on coke,
he was just exhausted, you know,
it's just like Jesus that looks like,
like no one is someone who got
bit a vampire. Like, oh my God.
Like you got you get
that bug that got you.
Yeah.
It's like you're taking all the energy
from party or life and concentrating it
in the few hours after
you do the coke and like,
well what are you gonna do with all
that energy except irritate people.
But I knew a girl and she was a
great girl. She wasn't a mean person.
She wasn't nasty materialistic.
She's beautiful.
She's really nice and sweet and kind.
But fuck, she loved coke. God Damn.
And she would feel bad about it.
She got fucking love it.
I love doing coke and be like really?
Like what?
I was not curious enough to want to
do it but listening to her, you know,
she knew it was bad news. She shouldn't
do it, didn't want to do it anymore,
but she'd tell you God damn and
I'm doing it. I love doing coke.
In my experience,
the people who tend to get really
hooked on coke are people who have um,
issues with uh,
they feel bad about themselves.
They feel they've got a lack of
self esteem. They feel like they,
they're not good enough.
They're not whatever.
There's shame and all that because
the coke takes that away for awhile.
That totally makes sense in
this case because this woman,
her mother was like really overbearing
and her mother was like Super Alpha
successful, right? Her mother was
a single mom and was like, like,
no man is going to fucking run me
and show she was a lawyer and she is,
she ran successful business.
She had a law firm and she was like super
like intense with her daughter about
achievement, about pursuing things, about,
you know, don't eat the wrong foods. And,
you know,
and he just,
it was like really like overbearing and
gave her a hard time about her weight.
Like, you're too fat, you're never
going to be a model and like, Ooh.
And so I guess the coke was like, ah,
free. You don't have to think about it.
Give her like, maybe she had a deficit
created by her mom's constant, you know,
I just never letting her just be
herself then. You ever, you know,
Gabo motto is no, he's a bore Montana.
Yeah, I know. It didn't know the name.
I've only seen it written.
Yeah, he's, he's a cool guy. And if
you ever want to have him on the show,
let me know. He's, he's a friend of
mine. He's a very interesting guy.
He's a doctor who works with addicts
and he's been working with addicts in
Vancouver and like the slum part
of Vancouver for a long time.
A lot of like real down and out people.
Um,
and he also is very interested
in alternative approaches
to addiction. And Eh,
you know, he's written about Iowasca
as a way of dealing with addiction,
treating addicts and all
that. Um, but anyway, he, uh,
his theory is that all addiction
is due to trauma. It's not,
it has nothing to do with the
substance or the activity. It's,
that's just how it manifests, right?
But it's all about psychological trauma.
It's all trying to alleviate
suffering of some point of some kind.
And um, it's interesting,
his research, uh,
sort of meshes very well with this
experiment that was done also in British
Columbia. I can't remember. Williamson
I think was the scientist's name.
You know those famous studies
where they give rats like a,
they've got a water bottle,
it's just water.
And then another one that's got coke in
it and the rats will just keep doing the
coke and they'll forget to eat. And
then the, the, you know, like die,
like these people you're talking about
lost all this weight and then just like
completely focused.
This guy looked at that and he,
he was a professor scientist. He looked
at that and he's like, okay, well that,
that's the sort of main study that
everybody cites that shows that coke is
addictive and it's coke that causes
the problem and it's the substance.
And molecular problems.
But what if we took those
rats a same kind of rats,
but instead of just being in a
cage where there's nothing to do,
put them in a really interesting
environment where there are lots of other
options.
There are lots of other rats they're tubes
to go through and things to climb and
things to hide under and lots of
stimulation, right? And then let's try it.
They try it.
What happens?
The rats do the coke once or twice and
then walk away from it. Never go back.
Right.
So there's an argument to be made that
a strong argument that it's not about
substances. It's like I was saying,
it's about the way this substance,
inner sex with whatever your
particular suffering is,
right?
So these rats in a cage are obviously
suffering because they're not in a natural
environment or in a fucking cage.
There's nothing to do except
like get high so they get high.
That's a very good point
that I never considered. That
is a very, very good point.
It's called rat park. If anyone wants
to Google it, just Google rat park.
Cause that's what he called this,
you know,
like sort of enclosure
that he made for them.
Imagine being a rat,
being stuck in a fucking fluorescent
lighting room and fucking metal cage and a
little water bottle. You got
suck on big too. I mean, look,
the fucking life they live is dog
shit. Yeah. You're in a prison.
So imagine you got, you got to prison,
the guy in solitary confinement, right.
And you're offering them to get high.
Of course it's going to get high and
you're being surrounded by giants
everywhere you go.
This is enormous creatures who can easily
reach in and just snuff your life out
of my squeezing. Ridiculous. And
by nature you're terrified, right.
Cause you're a prey animal.
You're, you know, yeah.
You should be running from everything
and all of a sudden you can't run.
You can't hide. Right. Change.
And they just reach in and grab you
and they fucking give you a coke. Yeah.
Which makes it even
more pair fucking shit.
God Damn Pita might have a point.
I interviewed this guy recently
talking about animal stuff. He, uh,
he was doing his phd in,
uh,
University of Pennsylvania and
he was working in psychology,
but there were chimps involved in
his research and so they, like,
they would come in to these cages,
but they had this big area outside
back behind the cages. Right.
We're so like at night they would go hang
out and there were trees and stuff and
whatever. And so this is in the,
I guess, 60s or 70s. And, uh,
so he would hang out until everybody
went home and he was alone.
And then he'd sneak back into
the area where the chimps where,
where he wasn't allowed.
Nobody was allowed or I like
walking around with chimps,
but he was like, fuck it. If they kill
me, I think they'll kill me. No problem.
So he was a Hippie, right. Um,
actually he's the guy who now owns this
chain of Paleo restaurants in Portland.
Really cool guy. Richard.
Um, figures. Yeah.
He opened the first mountain
bike shop in the country.
He's a very good businessman.
Then he opened like he went to Portland
because you wanted to be in a place
where you could get all your
supplies for a restaurant,
all the food within a hundred mile radius.
And he studied all over the country
and he said, Portland supplies,
everything can be grown
within a hundred miles.
He sort of was ahead of the mountain
biking craze that he was ahead of the sort
of farm to table thing.
And he opened a chain called,
I'm laughing planet, which there
were like 15 or 20 of these uh, uh,
like vegetarian burrito shops
in Portland sold that, uh,
cause he had quintuple bypass surgery
and he thought he was going to die,
sold that, bought this
beautiful farm where he grows
stuff now it's just amazing.
Quintuple bypass surgery and he's a Vegan
mountain biker. He was a vegetarian,
not Vegan, but he was a vegetarian.
And so that's what he said. He's like,
I work out, I'm eating vegetarian
for 20 years. What the fuck?
And he started reading about like,
wait a minute,
this idea of low fat is bullshit,
wasn't taking healthy fats.
He didn't know, you know. So now he's
shifted to Paleo and now he's opened like,
you know, he's got this expanding
business of Paleo restaurants anyway,
what am I talking?
Oh,
so he would go back with these chimps
and he told this hilarious story where
he's with his champion. He'd let
go back there and, and you know,
smoke a joint at the end of the day
and the chimps are wondering. Right.
And one day this Jim comes over and
sits down next to him and he's smoking a
joint and the chimp reached,
no,
he has not get this champion.
The joke to the gym. No,
it just hits it.
It gives it
back to, oh my God, that would be
the greatest video ever on youtube.
But Dude, get this is one of a chimp
fucking a frog. Have you ever seen,
I have seen that. It's kind of
sad. Yeah. Not for the chimp but,
but one of a chimp smoking a joint with
a dude, especially a hippie. Right.
Will be the ultimate. Don't
bug or don't bog. Right it man.
And if he did Bogart or what
are you going to do? You know,
like give the chimp that
joint shut the fuck. Exactly.
Rips your arms off. Exactly.
And a high, what's a high chimp light?
You know, probably pretty mellow.
It's like a, it's like a paranoid,
right? Like how do you know?
Well that's another thing.
We were talking about rats being in cages.
I got super high ones and I wrote a,
a a piece way back a long time ago.
My blog before my 2009 special,
before I started podcasting,
I used to write a lot and put it up in
blog form and one of the things I wrote
about is it,
it's called animal prison and became like
the foundation for a lot of jokes that
I want to use and some of my specials,
but it was about getting high.
I got really high once and I went to the
zoo and I was super depressed. Yeah. Not,
you know,
me personally in my personal life.
But being at the zoo stoned made me
like really like, especially edibles,
you know,
I had eaten a pot something or another
cookie or something like that and I was
like really fucked up about this. I'm
like, this is just not fair. It's not,
it doesn't,
it's like it's cruel,
it's cruel and it's cruel in a way were
insensitive to, and the joke was like,
hey man, you know, I watched the
chimps, they were playing with the tire,
swinging around, lifted, they're
having a good time. And I'm like, yeah,
well you can go to prison,
you'll see dudes playing basketball and
it doesn't mean it's awesome. You know,
like people do what they have to do
and they're in prison to have fun,
but they don't want to be there.
And that's the same thing that these
animals that didn't like the idea that
somehow or another their sit being saved.
I guess we're supposed to accept that
they're doing conservation work for sure.
And that's,
some of these animals can only exist in
captivity in this day and age or, or,
or at least we have to have
some of them in captivity.
To ensure their survival because humans
are pushing in on their area where they
live. But fuck man, that's,
especially with intelligent animals.
That's depressing as shit.
Yeah. I've got a friend, I just did
a podcast with him the other day.
He's a sort of been hired
by the whole marine mammal,
the consortium to try to help them deal
with their image problem from black fish
and blah blah blah.
Right.
So we were talking about this and he's
been working a lot in this place in
Florida where the dolphins are
used for therapeutic, you know,
with like,
um,
vets with PTSD and the kids
who are autistic and stuff.
And the Dolphin seem to
have a real sensitivity and
there's an interaction and a
lot of them were born in captivity.
If you let him loose,
they'd be dead within hours, you know,
they don't know how to survive and stuff.
Um, but anyway, we were talking about this
and you know, I said like, okay, you know,
what are you going to do about the,
I understand he has good arguments about
the dolphins and the smaller animals,
but like what are you going to do
about the Orca is man, you know, how,
how do you fix that? And he's like,
he said, there's no way to fix that.
Like they just should not be there because
you can't build an enclosure that is
even arguably big enough and interesting
enough for them and they leave their
social so you can't just have one. You
got to have like 15 of them, you know,
they're very community based animals.
So license isn't it
possible that they could
take an area in a bay,
like a very large area and take all the
worlds captive orcas and transport them
to this large bay,
like take a large area and a part of
the world that we don't go but it's
habitable and habitable for
them. And then, you know, fence,
something off underwater,
spend a lot of money to fix this issue
and then slowly but surely reintroduced
them to the wild.
Give them a steady source of food,
like provide them with food
and then provide them with
food that's you'd have to
catch like give them more and more food.
That's like you're going to let
it to go or whatever it is. Yeah,
habituate them and make it a project.
I don't buy idea that it's impossible to
take them and let them live in the wild.
You can take a 40 year old man and teach
them how to go forage through the woods.
I mean look at survivor man,
that fucking guy,
he taught himself how to do that shit.
He can exist for months at a time during
the wilderness and there's a lot of
people that do that. They have survival
skills. I guess what we call it.
We used to call hunting and
gathering is now survival skills.
It's not just existing as
a person foraging for food
like people used to do for
fucking untold thousands of years.
I think you could teach orchids,
but it would have to take a long time.
Been a huge cost, a lot of money,
but you owe that to the fucking orcas.
Man.
Agree. I agree. But you know,
we're not, we're not. Yeah.
We get into what we owe to
other, you know, being sure
to say never ending. I mean,
Peter Singer, you know him.
No, he wrote animal liberation,
which sort of started the whole animal
rights frenzy and the 70s whenever it was
really interesting. Philosopher
teaches at Princeton now I think. Um,
and he made a really interesting arctic
argument about using primates in drug
testing. And because, you
know, the argument there is,
well, they're close to humans,
so their responses to
pharmaceuticals and things is,
is as close as we're going to
get for our own testing. And, uh,
what he said,
he's one of these guys who just thinks
really clearly wherever it goes,
and he doesn't give a shit. And
so his argument was, um, okay,
uh,
chimpanzee has the intelligence and sort
of a demonstrable awareness of a three
or four year old kid. So
they're, they're beings.
They're thinking they're experiencing,
they've got emotions,
they've got relationships. There's
no question. Right. They're not fish.
They're not, you know. Um,
and every year thousands of babies
are born with no brain with,
I forget the technical, the
medical term for it, but they just,
their brain never developed in the fetus
and they're born and housing. Really?
Yeah. Maybe it's hundreds.
I don't know. But a lot. Um,
and his point was these babies are
all going to die. They are born,
they put him on these machines,
keep them going there.
You're feeding tubes and whatever. Um,
but the, they're never going to survive.
They feel no pain because
they have no brains.
So why aren't we testing pharmaceuticals
on them? Wow. Cause they're human.
That's some dark shit.
Well, it is. You're right.
But it makes sense. It certainly
makes sense. Logically, the emotional,
instead we're torturing, you
know, these living thinking,
you know, aware of beings.
Yeah. Um, the idea
being, of course, I mean,
the argument against that is
that if it saves one human being,
who cares about the champ?
That's, that's the, the idea wife.
If your wife has saved your,
the person you love more than anyone
else in this world is saved because they
tortured some chimp. It's not a
beautiful thing. You know, it's, it's,
it's very dark. But you'd be happy
that that chimp gave up his life.
Right? But I think that's
why have government's right
to think beyond that personal level.
Cause you know, that's what war is, right?
Where is innocent people are dying
so that, you know, and, and you know,
there is no good choice,
right? It's like, okay,
a thousand innocent people die there, or
100,000 innocent people die here. Well,
a government exists to kill those
thousand innocent people essentially.
Isn't that the real problem?
Like what makes someone uniquely qualified
to be the person that makes it very
difficult choice and really no one
deserves to be the person who decides this
great group of people dies.
So this group of people lives or that
this lunch he gets, uh, you know, uh,
battery cable attached to his Dick,
right?
That's why psychopaths do so well
because they're not worried about the
consequences there. They're able to
make those decisions or sociopaths.
I've never really understood
the difference between the two,
to be honest with you.
I think sociopaths don't feel empathy
and psychopaths like are prone to more
violent behavior,
if that makes any sense.
Like I think sociopaths from
what has been explained to me,
and I might be butchering this,
probably should look, but uh,
I think that the idea being that
they're not seeing feeling empathy,
like the rest of us are,
like if they,
by their actions they get ahead with Sony
else suffers, it doesn't bother them.
Whereas for you, you would do something
that would hurt someone's feelings.
You'd be like, man, I just
can't fucking sleeves. It's
so freaking me out. You know,
they don't have that,
that sense of empathy.
I have a friend who wrote a book called
the psychopath test. Oh, I read that.
You Know Jon Ronson? Yeah, yeah. I
started reading it, I should say.
I think I bailed on it. I got bored. Yeah.
Well you get the idea pretty quickly.
I'm all add on that shit
like that, man. I can,
I'm really good with like a
documentary and stuff like that,
but like getting deep into the dry
issues of psychopaths and sociopaths and
what's his take on it? Uh, you
know, essentially that, uh,
psychopaths are very prominent
in fields like Wall Street,
military, you know, high.
They do really well in areas where you
have to make decisions that you know,
hurt people and you don't give a shit.
Here's an article in psychology today
that explains it in a way many forensic
psychologists,
psychiatrist and criminologists use
the terms sociopathy and psychopathy
interchangeably.
A leading experts disagree on whether
there are meaningful differences between
the two conditions.
Uh,
I contend that there are
clear and significant
distinctions. [inaudible] okay.
Sociopath and psychopaths share.
This is what they share.
A disregard for the laws and social norms,
a disregard for the rights of others,
a failure to feel remorse or guilt,
a tendency to display violent behavior.
Uh,
in addition to their commonality.
Sociopaths and psychopaths also have their
own unique behavioral characteristics
as well. Sociopaths tend to be
nervous and easily agitated.
They are volatile and prone to emotional
outbursts including fits of rage, blah,
blah, blah. Psychopaths.
Psychopaths on the other hand,
are unable to form emotional attachments
or feel real empathy with others,
although they often have,
or even charming
personalities. Interesting. That's
what I would think of as sociopaths.
Psychopaths are very manipulative
and can easily gain people's trust.
They learned to mimic emotions.
Now I've met,
I've met people that do that despite
their inability to actually feel them and
will appeal normal to unsuspecting
people. I, I've seen that.
I've seen that where I've
had conversations with
people and I realized that
they're like mimicking emotions like,
oh yeah man,
it's horrible that that happened to him.
Like you don't care at all when you're
feeling like, no, you know there's a,
there's like certain feelings that
people have what you feel you, you, you,
you see it in them that they feel remorse
or they feel sad or they feel empathy.
And then there's other people that are
like fake in that where it's like they're
doing a bad acting on a soap bar in La.
Dude.
And I was on a TV show here
two weeks ago or something.
And it struck me how this sort of their
concentric circles of bullshit that get
more intense. The closer you
get to the cameras, you know,
just like you check into the hotel
and they're like, hey Dr. Ryan,
kind of light but friendly, but
they don't give a fuck. Right.
And then you've got the driver who's
like, hey Yo, yeah, is everything good?
Can I help you with that sir?
You know,
then you get the assistant producer
who greets you at the door. Oh,
we're so thrilled you're here,
Dr. Ryan. Uh, you know, it's just,
and then you're actually on stage in
front of the cameras and the shit is just
like up to your fucking neck.
It's unbelievable. Yeah.
Like all the fake emotions.
What kind of a show was it? Well, I'm
legally, uh, can't talk about it. No,
I can't name it, but it was like
a, like a talk show, you know,
kind of like where I was talking about
monogamy and you know, hey, you know,
and the, the, like the
segment before me went long.
It was about dirty underwear and you know,
so I'm like,
that's important too. That's important to
discuss their issues. Is there bacteria?
Can people die? What about vaccinations?
They protect you against dirty underwear.
And I'm not saying it's a PR. I
don't, I've never seen the show,
so I don't know if it's a good
show or a bad show, but it's just,
I've experienced this in lots of
shows, not this show. All right,
but lots of shows where
like your TV particularly,
why am I talking to you about TV?
But in my experience,
at least the way I interact with TV,
it's just such bullshit.
Yeah, it can be. Certainly can be,
but there's some shows that
you do that aren't bullshit.
Like they're like the Jimmy Kimmel show.
For instance, you talked to Jimmy Kimmel,
he's like totally there. He seems like a
real guy. He's a real guy. He's totally,
why I often wonder about,
I was talking to his buddy that
doing the dolphin stuff, his,
he dated a woman who was on a rebound
from George Clooney talking about a tough
Gig, right? Like you're the
rebound from George Clooney.
I would take that over the rock.
I'll take George Clooney all day.
I Day Day,
I dated a woman who,
who told me I was even
better than Fabio in bed. Uh,
you should never know that a chick.
Fuck Fabio. Fabio, sloppy seconds.
Good Lord.
Good Lord. She didn't tell me until it
was too late to sort of change course,
but it's one of the most
dubious compliments I've
ever received. Interesting.
Even better than Fabio.
So Jimmy Kimmel was dating a girl who was
on the rebound from George [inaudible],
not to him. He came home,
my buddy. But anyway,
that got us talking about about famous
people who seem cool like George Clooney.
To me, George Committee seems
like if you hung out with him,
he would actually be a cool guy. Yeah. I
would imagine he'd be pretty cool. Yeah.
And so like how hard is that a,
for a guy like that who's probably a
thousand times more famous than like my
level of fame,
he's probably like legitimately like
a thousand times more famous than me.
That's pretty intense fame. He can't go
anywhere. When George Clooney shows up,
like helicopters will start circling the
restaurant that he's at and people just
jump out of buses with cameras
and tried to touch him.
And it relates to what we
were just talking about.
Like that fake emotion thing.
Right. How much true input is
he getting from human beings?
Well he goes to other countries. That's
one of the things that I think benefits.
You forgot like that. I think he's got
like a fucking villa in France, France.
Notice how I said France because
I didn't say France.
Okay. I'm not like that. He uh, he's
got, he's got mad cash. That's cool.
Cause it insulates them from a
lot of the bullshit, but yeah,
but it also attracts the
bullshit. Well, I was gonna say,
my buddy is friends with
Johnny Depp and his,
and he spent some time with Johnny Depp
in England and he said it was the most
ridiculous scene you've
ever seen in your life.
The guy can't go anywhere
everywhere he goes.
There's people with earpieces in and
suits and they follow him everywhere.
They're like their peripheral
and you tried to go outside.
He was like going outside to have
a cigarette and they swarm on,
get your ride somewhere. Do you need
something? Like you're always cater to.
And so he lives in this
weird insulated world.
We like runs from restaurant to restaurant
and had chefs come over his house and
cook. You can't go to their
stores everywhere he goes.
He's being swarmed upon.
And for him, apparently it happened, uh,
after the pirates of the Caribbean movie
sound like took things to this critical
nuclear place where it's at right now
where he's just like, he's a story.
He's an an object of
attention everywhere he goes.
There's got to be really hard to keep
your shit together when you're like that,
because your version of
reality. So fuck. Yeah. I mean,
you're not getting the sort of,
the feedback that you need just to like,
know what's real. You know, it's,
it's interesting the character
that put him over, you know,
into that world of strangeness
was based on a Keith Richards,
right? Yeah. Who I, yesterday I was
talking to my friend towel who, um,
he's an Italian prince talking
about European, you know,
he was married to Olivia Wilde for seven
years, you know, so he sort of like,
he's like in this world,
a strange world. And uh,
he was talking,
his father was this crazy Italian prince
who hung out with Fellini and Brigitte
Bardot and Salvador Dali and he sort of
started the dolce Vita in Italy and the
50s and squander this huge family fortune
you like in his lifetime on women and
boats and parties and all that
shit. You know, I love him. Yeah,
really interesting cat.
Anyway,
Tau is a great a Flamenco guitarist.
And we were talking about like,
how do you get into, you know, how, when
did you start playing guitar? And he said,
well, when I was 13, um,
the rolling stones came to like
Rome or wherever they were playing.
And my dad is an old friend of Keith
Richards and he took me to the hotel where
the stones were standing and Keith had
like a whole floor to himself, right.
And we went in and there are all these
people and all this scene and actually
Keith Richard's father was there,
he mentioned and um,
and my dad had mentioned to Keith
like, Hey, towels, learning guitar.
And Keith had a Flamenco guitar there
and he picked it up and he did a few like
riffs and he said to him,
if you want to learn to play guitar,
learn Flamenco because if you can
play Flamenco you can play anything.
And towel now is a fucking great
flamenco guitarist. And he was like, man,
if Keith Richards, I tells you
what to do. Like, you know,
that's what you do, you know, and
he fucking went with it. It's great.
That makes sense.
Cause that Flamenco is very fast finger
movements to be like you would have to
develop some incredible
coordination or your fingers. Yeah.
Like doing a stone's riff
after that. Yeah. It's a,
I've always loved music but have
never had any inclination to learn an
instrument. Yeah, I love it.
Do you regret that? Nope.
There's not enough time.
You know,
I mean I have enough forms of
expression that I'm, I'm enjoying.
I think it would be cool as fuck, man.
Yeah. You watch like Jimi Hendrix Solo,
you know? Good Lord. Can you
imagine if you could just,
just the feeling of being in it that
deeply the flow, you know, it's just,
that's what I regret. You know,
I never had the discipline.
I took electric guitar lessons for two
weeks and quit and I took piano for a
week and quit and you know, I was
just too much of a fuck off as a kid.
I could never get over the hump to where
it started being enjoyable and the need
to be obsessed to get
really good at anything.
Whether it's the drums or
the guitar playing chess.
I mean it's all the same thing really.
It's like you need to just get obsessed
at that particular discipline, you know,
whatever it is that it takes
to get really good at it.
A big part of what makes
someone really good at anything.
It's like this crazy obsession.
If you don't have that obsession,
you'll just drift in and out from one
thing to the other until you find the
thing that you really are obsessed with.
Do you think the now obsession is defined,
you know,
in the psychological terms as a pathology,
right.
Obsessive compulsive disorder and,
and you know,
this is a very kind of thought,
but
it's like in our society and this relates
back to the psychopaths who attained
great success are,
I mean our most really successful people,
uh,
responding to some deep trauma, you know
what I mean? Like they say Comedians,
you know, there's some need for approval
and you know, make people laugh,
make people love you, you know,
because whatever your family structure,
I don't know as many comedians as you do,
but you know,
you always hear that right?
You don't very, you know,
cause I needed the attention.
I in an actor's like they need people
looking at them. They need to be on stage.
They're like drinking that
up because there's some need.
It nourishes them on some level.
So I wonder like is there,
you know,
like I'm thinking about people who say
like I learned to play guitar so I could
get laid, you know, cause the girls were,
I guess I didn't if I didn't think of it.
So like if you had told me I would get
like maybe if you and your friends got
together and you were like, man, we're
having a hard time getting late. Okay,
here's the form of that
and let's make a band
thank you. Probably wouldn't be as
good as if you guys were like, man,
Q man look to stones where our
age when they got together,
let's just fucking do this guys.
You know,
if you like really had this desire to
produce something that people love and
that's where you kind of have to do.
You have to,
I think to get to be a Keith Richards,
you have the,
you have to have this desire to produce
something that people are going to love.
Because like when you listen to his
guitar rifts in or any great guitar,
Stevie Rayvon anyone,
I mean they have to have this deep desire
to connect with the just the correct
sounds that's coming out of their
mind, their imagination, their,
their skill, their interpretation
of the moment. You know,
like that's why people like,
like when someone does a guitar Solo,
the idea being that this guy
is just feeling it, you know,
it's not the exact same solo every
time. Every time they're doing it. Like,
you know,
if a guy just just starts riffing and
everybody starts cheering and going along
with it, you want to see like, what's
what's in that guy right at that moment.
It expresses itself through all the
discipline or all the years that he's
practice guitar and then
the finger coordination that
it's able to achieve. And,
and you know, you, there's
some shit that's like, you
could tell that just kind of,
they're just going fast. Right.
You know, there's going fast. Yeah.
Just people that shred and it's really
cool and it's really impressive.
And then there's like some
Stevie Ray Vaughan Shit.
There's some Stevie Ray Vaughan where
you like feel like him crying through the
guitar.
Like there's like,
there's like this whole emotion that's
attached to it and then people connect to
and when you see like Stevie or Yvonne's
version of little wing. Yeah. You know,
you see a great guitarist inhabiting
and loving another great guitars.
You know, there's something
really beautiful about that.
Yeah, Dude. Fuck yeah. He's,
his version of Voodoo child is the only
version I accept other than Hendrickson.
Right. Obviously I'm a
huge Hendrix fan. Yeah.
I mean that's why I named this the Joe
Rogan experience to rebuff had a really
cute always from the time I
was little kid. I mean he just,
he has a special quality to him.
Like that Song Voodoo child to me
like that just brown box sitting.
Yeah. Where the fuck did that
come? Who did that before him?
I mean compare music before Hendrix
and after Hendrix. It's like,
I really believe that like,
especially Voodoo child,
there's something about that beginning
riff Parallon like when he really gets
into it, it's like God,
he was on some new place.
It was in some new dimension when he was
and when you string the
guitar like fuck that.
I'm not learning that I'm doing it my way.
That's it.
He's just like so unconcerned
with what came before in a way,
you know drunk. Yeah. He
was on drugs. Well that,
that's what I was going to
say and honestly the first
time it's special drugs,
not coke. Oh yeah. Right now he's
on all sorts of general. Yeah,
I mean I there,
there it is.
Hit, hit that, crank that
shit up. Listen to this.
Well you really have to think about it.
This is the late 1960s when
this guy comes out with this.
Now if you just go 10 years before that
you're dealing with like buddy Holly and
which is great music but this is just
some next level shit like listen to this
part.
This is one dude by the
way and the distortion.
That's my,
I have a few all time favorite song.
I don't have like a all time favorite
song but I listened to that motherfucker
when I'm in my car on the way to the gym.
I'll time it for like the last five
minutes before I get to the gym is Voodoo
child cause it's just just fucking blast.
Hey put my phone on airplane mode.
Fuck you and hear this
cranked always high.
That's just,
it just touches like your DNA.
You feel that guy's expression
right through the sound. I
get that with the dealer. Listen to Danny
California, the red hot chili peppers.
Is it? Oh yeah. Okay.
Yeah, there's like a tar.
There's a thing like the whole song builds
to this fucking wild guitar lead and
near the end and like if I'm
working out or running or something.
I always have that on my
playlist because I just,
there's like energy comes out of the
ether, you know? It's amazing. Yeah.
They had a cover of higher ground.
That was one of the few covers that I
actually enjoy it as much as the original,
just like Stevie Ray Vaughan,
his version of Voodoo child.
There's some covers that are better.
I that I really love that genre of music.
You know where a cover like gets the
essence of the song in a way that the
original performer may have missed.
Like there are a few, the few examples,
I mean all along the watchtower,
you know,
I think Hendrick's that better than Dylan.
Dylan and Dylan actually said that as
well. Yeah. It's just so different.
His version of it,
different song. I mean it's just
so, it's so different and you know,
here's one that people don't
talk. Suspicious minds.
Dwight Yoakam did a cover.
Yeah,
suspicious. Fine. Right? It's better
than Elvis. People get mad. Fine.
Young cannibals. That's fine. Young
cannibals did a version of it,
which isn't bad. Yeah, he did a
great version two. It's a funny song.
Suspicious minds cause bay. It's
Elvis saying, oh come on baby.
You know, I wouldn't lie to you. You get
to believe, but here your lying eyes,
especially in the context of
Elvis's guys. Dude, come on baby.
It's like JFK saying, Hey, I'm a one woman
man. Yeah, sure. You are not only that,
Elvis was probably on so many pills.
He didn't know if he was
monogamous when he was,
the drugs are drifting in and out of
consciousness all day long. I mean,
he was a guy talking about trauma
leading to great fame, right? Yeah,
yeah. Damaged soul, you know, seeking
approval from the world.
Why?
I often wonder if what we're seeing
when we see great like great resonating
forms of expression, whether it's art
or whether it's a comedy or you know,
any music.
I always wonder if what we're looking
at is a mathematical equation.
If we're looking at like a yin and a Yang,
an ebb and a pole and that the Arab,
you know, whatever it was that created
this great deficit responds the body,
the mind,
the soul,
the spirit responds with this incredible
work of art to sort of make up for all
the trauma that had experienced
when it was young. Which is why it,
it's,
it's really tough to find someone who
had this really ultra privileged life who
was accepted and loved and nurtured
and every way who becomes this really
fascinating, great artist, right? Like,
what you usually find is these people
that are in pain and torn up and yeah,
and I,
I often wonder if we're looking at it in
a cultural context and we sort of like,
oh,
that guy's an asshole,
or his life sucked or she was abused
or he was neglected. And we're,
we're, we're looking at it
in terms of like these, um,
these definitions that we've already
categorized in our mind, but in fact,
what it really is, is like math
is that with all evens out? Yeah.
We're looking at a minus and a positive.
We're looking at a Jimmy Hendricks,
this young black man in this incredibly
racist world and comes along like right
at the moment of this psychedelic
acceptance where the whole world,
especially young people are turning on
in a way that they never had before.
The Beatles come along, they do the
white album, people are freaking out,
clapped in pink, you
know, Layla, pink Floyd.
And then all of a sudden this dude
comes along who's dressed like a fucking
Indian. He's got a headband on and
he's playing music from outer space.
Chewing gum. Yeah. I mean, totally.
You know, Phil Hartman, uh,
rest his soul who's a good friend
from dues radio and he was uh,
he grew up, um, when he
was young rather, uh,
he lived in Hollywood and he worked
as like a stage hand when Jimi Hendrix
played the whiskey.
And so he was right there with Jimmy
Hendrix holding the speaker because
sometimes the speakers
would fall off the stage,
like they were on the edge of the
stage and you had to be there in case
something happened. So he was there
when Hendrix first burst on the scene.
So here's the close to Hendrickson's. You
already right in front row seat, right?
Played Guitar.
I'm Phil was a plagues on everything.
He was a true genius.
I mean he really could do anything and
he had an incredible work ethic that guy,
like we joke around about it.
We had this thing we did at
the Hollywood walk of fame.
He got a star earlier this year and
Stephen Root and candy Alexander and I or
were joking around about how Phil
had these notes like he would have,
his script would be,
he would have tabs for each scene and
they were like these different colored
tabs for every scene that he was in and
everything would be highlighted and he
would have notes and stick hymns and
everything was like super organized and we
were always like, [inaudible]
your script. You know,
like nobody can find the fucking script.
But Phil had his shit in a binder.
He would take his thing, he would punch
holes in them, stick them in a binder,
you know, he was super duper organized
and anal about that kind of shit.
But one of his greatest moments,
you know, when we were friends,
somewhere along the line,
he started smoking weed like all the
time it was before I actually smoked weed
and he did it because he had a lot of
problems. There's a lot of marital issues,
obviously that led to
his wife killing him.
But he enjoyed like after work was done,
not while I was there,
but after work was done.
He enjoy getting high.
He loved getting high and
then going on a boat and uh,
he had a boat and he would take his boat
out and he would just love painting,
high sailing.
And he was telling me one time we were
hanging out in his room. It was after,
after filming and he was high and he was
telling me that story about him working
at this club and holding the speakers
for Hendricks. And to this day,
it's like one of my favorite memories
of him, you know, because it's just,
I could see him as this young guy. It's
like he was so fascinated by everything.
He's the only guy that I've ever met
that I went to a strip club with and it
didn't feel creepy cause
he, he sat down, he was, uh,
he sat down. I can say this now because
he's dead. I couldn't, if he was alive,
I would probably not tell you the story.
But he still loved to go to this place
called Bob's classy lady and it was in
the valley. That's great. Phil
took me there. Um, and uh, he,
um, he would sit by the stage
and the girls who come out
and dance and you'd give
them money and he was like a genuine
childlike enthusiasm for their bodies.
You know, there'd be like moving her front
and be like, wow, you're beautiful. Oh,
you're Pitney was high as fuck.
Just high as fuck.
And he was watching these girls dance
and stick their genitals in his face and
he just was loving it.
He was loving in a way that wasn't creepy.
Like it was weird.
It's like he had this almost
like innocence about the
way he was appreciating
their bodies that I didn't feel weird
being near him while this was happening
because it was just me and him. Could you
feel it as well or we used to insecure.
Yeah, I was too. Uh, for whatever reason,
I've just too many preset
ideas about bodies. And I,
it also, I was like, at
the time I was singing,
I was 26 or 27 maybe 28 at the most
and I was pretty fucking crazy.
I was just a different person.
I was still operating on the momentum
of my youth and in chaos and I couldn't
even believe I was hanging out
with Phil Hartman at a strip club.
Like to me like seven years before
that I had been fighting, you know,
so it was like so recent.
It's like my competition days,
so flavored like who I was.
Cause like you know,
you're talking about the word obsessed.
What it means is a sickness.
The sickness meaning that you can get good
at something because of that sickness.
I was a hundred percent sick
when I was a kid. I was sick.
It's fuck psychotic in that way.
You know,
not in a way where like I didn't
care about other people's feelings,
but just ups. Maybe psychotics, not
the word. Now that we've researched it,
maybe it's the word is just,
just singular in my purpose and vision on,
on earth. I just wanted to do that.
And only that mono mania. Yeah.
And so it was hard for me to get out of
that headset for a long time. It was,
I would to drift back into that headset.
I don't try to fight it off and
try to like simulate and be normal,
but I'd felt like I like
almost like a drug addict too.
It stopped doing coke or heroin
or math or something like that.
I had like gone into this world where
there was no more fight or flight.
There was no more terrifying bouts of
competition followed by preparation,
followed by more competition.
Now all of a sudden I'm hanging out
with Phil Hartman and Strip club.
Did performance feel that way at all?
Like you know,
you got to taping on Friday leading up to
it. You sorta nervous you're preparing,
you know, to some extent.
Definitely not a TV show. TV shows,
especially news radio was one of the
easiest jobs I've ever had in my life in
terms of the actual performance of it. I
mean, you'd be a little nervous before,
make sure you knew your lines,
make sure you get it right.
But the cats was so fucking good that
like you were working with these people
that were so funny.
All you had to do is just do your thing.
Like if it was me and a scene with Andy
Dick, all I had to do was just go, Andy,
what are you talking about man?
What are you talking about?
And then he would do his wackiness and
then I would do whatever I had to say.
And the hard part was not laughing,
you know,
it was remembering your lines first and
then Rick, not laughing. That's amazing.
But it'd be acting about stand up.
That's a little different because you're
creating it, you know, and news radio,
they allowed us a lot of room for ad
libbing. But even if you do create it,
you're interacting with someone
else and it's, you know, you're,
you're pretending some things
are happening and either
works or doesn't work and
it doesn't work. You get together and you
take a five minute break. The writers,
all wood,
you know,
Paul and Josh and all these guys would
all huddle together and we'd try to come
up with another line.
You know,
so it's like everyone was
working together on this thing,
so it was in a way easier than standup
because standup where alone you're on
your own bitch. You know,
if you're out there bombing,
especially p people paid money to
see it, it's fucking, you know, you,
you better come. Correct. You better have
some shit to say. So stand up more so,
but still never as terrifying as the,
the in between bouts between
competition. It was terrifying. You ever,
was there ever any sort of a possibility
of you being on Saturday night live?
I never wanted to act at all. I
didn't, I didn't the sketch that, no,
I don't want to do that.
So how, how did it happen?
I mean you don't have to talk about
if this is still cover the top.
Definitely have. It's super simple.
I just got a development deal.
It did MTV half hour comedy hour.
I got a development deal.
They offered me a lot of money fixing,
you know,
I was on a Disney show of all things
for Fox. Two hilarious things.
Disney show for Fox was called
hardball. Um, when that was over,
I was totally ready to quit show.
But boy, that was a character.
I played a baseball player,
frank [inaudible] and I was terrible show.
It started off really good.
The guys who created it were
writers from the Simpsons,
Jeff Martin and Kevin Curran.
They were writers from the Simpsons.
They wrote from married with children
and they were brilliant, brilliant guys.
But they were soft spoken, you know,
writers, intellectuals got steamrolled,
got steamrolled,
they got steamrolled by half
the people who came in,
you know,
Fox didn't think there were
strong enough to run a show.
So they fucked up their pilot. They
fucked up all, all the episodes and they,
they tanked a great
idea. You know, they, uh,
they were baseball fans and they
wanted to make a hilarious Sitcom about
baseball, akin to married
with children for baseball.
Right. That was her idea. And,
um, I hated it. I hated, I
didn't hate them and I loved,
I loved being in the pilot. Jim Breuer
was actually in the pilot with me. Um,
Jim played a,
it was a onetime role for him and um,
it was just a bad scene. It was just not
fun. I didn't enjoy working with actors.
I thought some of them became friends,
but a bunch of them were like unbelievably
self centered and weird and just,
you got no training, you never did
theater and zero, no desire either,
which is infuriating to them.
But all of a sudden I was in their turf.
Who is this guy? And I played
the baseball star. I was the,
the guy who was the star of the team.
So it was based on your comedy? No,
not at all. Oh, the, the
MTV thing was in a, no,
my comedy like got me to the MTV thing,
but the Sitcom,
they had already written it. I just, they
just cast me. I met them and they said,
you could be that guy. And so boom, all
of a sudden I'm in Hollywood and um,
they're putting makeup on me. I'm was
like, when you moved out of Christ, um,
I did the pilot first. Uh,
so I came out here to visit.
I got one of those Oakwood
apartments. Right. You know,
on in Burbank that everybody automatically
goes to if they have these rented
furnished apartments and the cable.
It's beautiful.
He just moved right in sleeping some
bad that some dude before he's been fart
and jerking off and, and
um, I did that and then um,
then it became, it got picked
up. Then I got an apartment.
I signed a lease cause I figured
out this is going to stay.
I had the Oakwood for like
a couple of weeks. I'm like,
oh this show is doing well and they
thought it was going to get picked up and
then it got cancelled. So then,
uh, I got news radio, same thing.
It's just a audition.
Went in for an audition as a cattle
call was like a hundred dudes. Yeah,
I met them, went in, did an audition,
came back, did a second audition, Bam.
I'm on a show. We did some amazing
sitting there at the table.
Read with Phil Hartman, Dave Foley.
So all told being on news radio,
I had even thought about ever
acting for less than a year. And I,
this is all my second TV show. That's
fucking insane. It's totally insane.
And the second show I ever
auditioned for it, by the way,
I only auditioned for two shows
ever and I was on both of them.
It didn't make any sense.
And so you know too,
what do you attribute this lucky as
fuck that for sure. Lucky as fuck.
And the ability to perform under pressure.
That's one of the things about sitcoms,
about auditioning for them.
It's so unnatural. You're in
this room, there's a table,
there's these people that you don't know
and you're supposed to pretend that you
know, we're on a tropical island and we're
trying to find where the first aid cap
cabin is. You know, it's fake like in
a lot of times people like, oh my God,
my life depends on this.
My bills.
And some people have never had
to perform under pressure before.
But being a standup helps that
tremendously cause you're,
you're accustomed to being nervous.
And then fighting helps that tremendously
because you're accustomed to being
nervous. So those two
things, you know, I, I,
I performed under pressure more than
the average person even though I didn't
have a lot of acting experience.
Interesting.
That's very interesting way
to look at it. Yeah. I just,
I mean I'm interested in all of this.
I just watched that SNL special the
other night. Yeah. Lot of Phil Hartman,
he was amazing and a lot
of audition tapes as well.
He's one of the reasons why I
never wanted to do it though. His,
his depiction of working in
siren live was not good. No,
a lot of people hated it. He hated
it. Well Phil is a nice fucking guy.
Was a nice fucking guy. He was
not so sharp. Nice. It's uh,
it's a very ultra competitive,
mean spirited place.
And Phil had the remanence of that
almost like as a defensive shell when he
first started working on news radio.
Like you would say like things that
like were really uncharacteristic of him
later and it was really any,
we actually talked about it and he,
I don't want to name any names,
but he was talking about some mean people
that he worked with on the show. No,
I don't believe he's got that reputation.
Does a lot of people that come from
that environment do because I think it's
really hostile and they're all competing
to get their stuff in the air and
there's a lot of backstabbing,
you know,
there's people like doing favors for
writers and trying to get their stuff in
and there's a lot of, there's
a lot of greatness that
comes from that too. I mean,
we just siren live.
If you look at the overall body of work
and you just cherry pick greatness,
my God,
I mean you have this incredible bouquet
of John Belushi and Phil Hartman and
Adam Sandler and Chris rock.
I mean you,
I was greatness Eddie motherfucking
Murphy, who was genius on that show.
Him playing buckwheat. My God.
I mean it was amazing. It was a,
it was a,
but
I never had a desire to do that. I don't
want to compete with a bunch of people.
Like I don't want to be in a
hostile and vine, believe it or not.
And it doesn't make sense because
I did martial arts my whole life.
I was trying to avoid hostility. Like
I don't want to, I don't want to argue.
I don't want any conflict.
I don't want to compete.
Like the beautiful thing about standup
comedy is you're creating it yourself.
You go up there, you do
it, you're the right.
You don't have to argue with people
about it. If they don't like it,
they're not going to laugh
and then you're fucked.
You got to restructure it
and figure it out yourself.
You know how I feel about writing books?
I mean sometimes I miss like an idealized
team kind of environment because I
know how wonderful that can be.
But the reality is that generally
when you work with people,
you don't necessarily like each other
and it's a pain in the ass because of all
the weird ego shit. And so I kinda
like that. I can at least for awhile,
make a living sitting in a
room alone. You know, it's,
it's got its ups and its downs.
Of course.
There's also a positive aspect from the
reader's point of view that if I read a
Chris Ryan Book,
I know I'm getting Chris Ryan's thoughts.
They're coming unadulterated from
your mind to your typewriter, your,
your keyboard rather. Yeah. And that's
something I'm conscious of. You know,
I read this, I don't know, maybe it was
the book you recommended to me, the,
the war of art, but somewhere I read, um,
someone said always right post
humorously, Ooh, you know,
write as if you're dead because you will
be, and the book will still be there.
Wow. So like, let go, you
know, say what's true. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. That's amazing. Yeah.
That's way better than like,
if you're like a Beverly hills housewife,
you're going to write some shit
that's only based on, you know,
like what's gonna sell. Yeah. You
know? Yeah. You know what I mean?
Like they'll create these,
you know, things like, okay,
how is this going to work the best? I
mean, and I don't mean to single them out,
but I mean,
just like there's some people that write
some books where it's pretty obvious as
they're writing the book,
they're kind of bullshitting who
they are and what you're projecting.
This will connect with
that part of the audience,
but I don't want to offend that part.
So we got to, yeah, yeah. You know,
you're talking earlier about
that whole ebb and flow idea,
the mathematical sort of,
it all equals out at the end.
I've thought about that a lot. Not so
much in terms of individuals though.
It makes sense, but I thought about that
a lot in terms of a historical moments,
historical periods, you know, like
Vietnam, the, the late sixties right?
Like 65 to 71 that's when you know,
more Americans are dying in Vietnam,
right?
Then any other period earlier than
that, it'd be four. They ramped up.
It wasn't as many.
So you've got all this conflict,
all these riots in the streets.
You've got Selma and Martin Luther
King and all this agitation.
And at the same time you've got Jimmy
Hendrix, you've got the Beatles,
you've got all of his music.
We're talking about amazing literature
coming out of that fashion craziness,
tie dyes and Afros and you know,
it's like when the shit hits the fan,
it's really interesting,
you know, and interesting people rise
to the top. Whereas when things stable,
the interesting people
just, you know, they didn't,
they don't get anywhere because it's to,
the structures are rigid and controlling,
you know,
well sometimes there's a need for reform
and change that makes these interesting
things blossom.
Almost had a pressure,
almost sounded like two rocks pushing
together and they create or you know,
there's,
there's this effect that happens because
people are pushed into a certain way.
And then that sense is always been the
argument that we need a certain amount of
evil to appreciate, love to
appreciate happiness and good times.
We almost need a certain amount,
like people who,
this is a certainly no way supporting war,
but people who look at war,
uh,
like people in this country especially
as just something and they don't,
they don't think about it deeply.
They don't think about it in a way where
they comprehend the loss of lives and
the sadness and the sorrow. They just
look at it as those were our heroes.
They got to do what they gotta do over
there so we could do what we do over here
or Rod Woo. And it's like this really
surface way of looking at this thing.
But it's almost because they are
not experiencing the suffering.
It's almost because they're
not experiencing the
sorrow that they don't have
this,
this appreciate like the appreciation
that you have of not being at war
shouldn't be that someone's over there
fighting war so that you don't have to
have war. It should be that you, you,
you realize that people can get along,
that people can love each other. There
could be friendly, we can be nice.
You can go to a farmer's
market and everybody's saying
hi. You know, you could,
you know, that's a bad
example, but you know,
we can interact with each other in a in
a positive way or we could fight over an
oil whole,
you know,
we could shoot each other and kill babies
and the fucking gun down innocence and
untold numbers over an oil whole.
I mean it's almost like having
the no interaction with it,
having an,
and also having this sort of archetypal
patriotism that everyone subscribes to
that sort of like there's a
very cookie cutter vibration.
There's certain types of Patriot
type people give off where it's like,
it's really like this is
where we're going to operate.
We're going to operate in this very small
box where the soldiers are heroes and
there's no, there's no doubt they're
doing what they do over there.
So we could do what we do over here and
they'll repeat that mantra over and over
again without any consideration whatsoever
for what it means as human beings
that you're, you're, you're dealing
with groups of human beings,
fighting other groups of human beings.
For some reason that has not really been
clearly defined to me that most of the
people fighting, I have no clue what
it is. Yeah. Then most none of us do.
Very few of us did.
And I think that for someone who,
for someone who goes over there and,
and experiences that it's probably got
to be really weird to see that sort of
cookie cutter version of it. Um,
being expressed by people. Like, uh,
I have quite a few friends that have,
uh,
been overseas and been involved in
the war and you talk to them and man,
they have sorrow,
they have some horrible stories.
They have some shit they don't like
to remember. They have some, you know,
some really difficult things on there.
You know,
this Brian Williams thing that
happened in the news. Yeah.
One of the things that I took from
it especially hard was not that Brian
Williams was not telling the truth because
I think he's a fucking Hollywood guy.
He's just a show Biz guy. He's an
actor, he's an actor. He's an active,
that reads the prompter. Instead of the
script, he acts like a standard actor.
They have the tie and they w
they talk like most of them do.
I made a mistake, you know, like, come
on man, you're fucking lying. You lied.
You lied about some shit that went down.
But what would hit hit me harder was the
pilot that was involved because there
was a pilot involve that gave his version
of the story and did some interviews
and he said that,
um,
they were in a helicopter
and the helicopter took
small arms fire and that the
helicopter in front of them is
the one that got hit with the RPG.
And it wasn't the one that
Brian Williams is in. Um,
but he was telling you a story about
this and then people started questioning,
no, you weren't in the
helicopter with Brian Williams.
This guy was in the helicopter, Brian
Williams. And so the guy says, man,
you know what? I don't really
completely remember, but what I, uh,
it's hard for me to go over this.
I had put it aside,
but now that I'm being forced to remember
the nightmares are coming back and I'm
having a really hard time sleeping
really. And he was talking about, he said,
I don't really want to talk
about it anymore. I you no.
I said what I had to say is,
isn't this guy is certainly not lying.
He certainly did serve.
He certainly did get shot at.
He certainly did see some horrific things.
There's no doubt about that.
No one questions that they're
just questioning these, uh, these,
his version of events versus a couple
other people have their version of the
events and there's just so much trauma
involved in this guy's experiences over
there that he's like,
I had tried my best to forget about this
was what I can remember when people ask
me about my experience with Brian
Williams, this is what happened.
And he gave it very logical account of it.
The reason why we were an hour late,
he said it,
cause we had a drop off a payload.
We dropped off our payload
and then we went to the,
it took us about an hour and then we went
to the site where the guys landed with
and then we all had huddled down
together in a snow sandstorm and it,
it was an incredibly traumatic
event for all involved. So it,
I'm not giving Brian Williams a free pass
because he remembered this in a fucked
up way cause I do think he bullshitted it.
I think he added a bunch of shit to his
version of it and put himself in more
danger because he didn't think that
anybody would put the pieces together.
And when it came out,
look Historia as itself would have been
just as good if he said the helicopter
in front of us got hit with an RPG isn't
make you better because you almost died.
You don't definitely almost died anyway.
Like his version, the real version,
he almost died. The real version.
He still was in a convoy.
They got shot at his helicopter.
Didn't there were all forced to land
and endure a sandstorm for two days.
I mean that version is amazing.
You don't have to, but it's,
it's indicative of the kind of bullshit
artists that we have that are reading
off the news that he didn't like that
version. He wanted to jazz it up.
He wanted to make a little bit better.
My life was in danger for the news.
But it is, as we started this
conversation, talking how an unreliable
memory is, right. And Milan Kundera said,
memory is not the opposite of forgetting.
It's a way of forgetting, right?
Because we do, we remember things,
things you know, based on emotions and,
and over time it changes.
And especially a story like that.
I know a guy who's a compulsive liar.
I mean,
within 15 minutes of meeting this guy,
he told me he had trained with the seals,
he had played semi professional basketball
in Europe and he owned this amazing
apartment that we were in
that I knew he didn't know.
And His boss owned who was
this billionaire guy and
he was the private pilot of
this billionaire guy, this
friend of mine, right?
And so I knew this guy was full of shit,
but I also knew he flies a fucking
Leer jet for a living and he's like on
standby to fly this guy wherever
around the world. Like, dude,
that's a good story in itself.
You don't need to lie.
You know the guy who's working
at Starbucks, okay, you
make up some shit. Why not?
You know, it gets you through the
night, but you're fucking pilot.
Like I knew a dude who is this,
the successful comedian
and a multimillionaire and
was, would do really well,
but he would be,
he's a compulsive liar.
If you start talking to them about
something that you do uniquely,
he would also do it. You know, like if you
talked to him about, you know, whatever,
going to the jungle and researching ants,
he would tell you about
his time researching.
It was a little better than your story.
Right.
He smoked cigarettes and he would tell
me about his kickboxing experiences with
world champions.
I mean,
palsy like to get into your realm,
right? Oh, it was ridiculous or funny.
That's, that's risks. High risk.
Well, he was crazy. Completely still.
It is completely crazy. But he's really
talented too, which is interesting.
And he's a really good comic. So it's like
it's, I can't give his name away folks.
I'm so sorry. So maybe he, maybe
he likes the thrill like that.
Maybe you're going to call them
out. Nope, I don't think so.
There's no masochistic,
no,
just ego and alcohol and a bunch of
craziness, but smoking cigarettes,
telling me about how he's just sparring
eight rounds with a world champion,
which isn't totally impossible.
I had this guy in Joe Schilling recently
is one of the best kickboxers in the
world and he admitted on the podcast he
smoked cigarettes on a regular basis.
I guess I'm fucking crazy.
But he's also outside of that
very dedicated as an athlete.
It's just ridiculous that he
smoked cigarettes, endurance sport.
But he's a bad motherfucker. I mean
like bona fide legit trains all day.
This guy wasn't training guys
drinking all the time. He's like,
I know he wasn't kickboxing
like he's nuts. Like it's just,
but he almost can't help himself.
He has to just,
he starts talking and he just comes out
and he gets away. There's a weird stuff,
craziness. I, I remember meeting
a guy once at a wine tasting, uh,
who told me he was a demigod. What does
that mean? Well that's what I asked.
Like what does that mean? Well it means
I'm, I'm half human. My father was human,
my mother was from,
and he tells him like some,
some Latin word for a star
system somewhere. And uh,
and he said like again, within
15 minutes he said, uh, that, uh,
he was the highest paid artist in the
world because he had designed the,
that atlas a thing in front of
Rockefeller Center, which was the highest,
the most expensive piece of art, any
whatever, like whatever, blah, blah.
And I was fascinated it and the
guy was super good looking dude.
Like he had like a little beard and
a bit, he was big and dark, you know,
he looked like Satan Mephistopheles
kind of thing, you know.
And I thought he was bullshitting me.
I thought that my friend had like put
him up to it cause I was high and I was
just like, so he thought he was just
acting like, it was just being silly.
I thought he was goofing off,
you know?
And that after a few minutes he'd break
character and we'd all get a good laugh
out of it. And I even called my friend,
I was like, hey Dave, come over here.
I'm talking to the devil here.
He's got some great stories.
And then Cassie was there
and then she came and he,
and he got into her and he started
trying to impress her and telling her all
these stories. And she's
a psychiatrist, right?
She sees bullshit like before the rest
of us even know it's coming. You know,
it was very funny, like
the whole interaction. Wow.
Yeah. But it's a, it's a,
it's a form of insanity. You know,
like people have to scratch that Itch,
I don't know.
And they kind of keep moving.
Those people almost by nature have to
keep moving because eventually leave a
mess behind them. The lives implode,
the lies come down and cave in on them,
and then they've got to find some new
person to sucker in. And that does happen.
You know,
you see that,
you see people drifting from one group
of people to the other group of people.
And I've seen it. I've seen
it happen. Yeah, it's weird.
It's weird when you meet someone who's
just obviously full of shit and lying
through their teeth as they're talking
to. It's a very strange thing. Like,
do you know that?
I know and you're just gonna like hope
that I don't call you on it because
you've seen that too. Yeah. I wonder
about that too. Like some people,
well again, you know, my
wife's a psychiatrist, she,
she's dealt with all of this
kind of stuff and she laughs.
She just cracks up when she sees it,
she sees it immediately.
And just like her way of dealing with
insanity is laughter and is she works with
what she's worked with
all sorts of people,
but her sort of
specialization is loony Bin,
like a one flew over the cuckoo's
nest kind of scenes. Right. I,
I remember going in with her the
first time I visited her at work,
she was a running a mental hospital
with like double doors and bars over the
windows, these criminally insane people
who had killed their kids and you know,
like crazy shit.
Right.
And we went in there and
I wasn't prepared man.
We went in and it was just like lunatics
and there was this woman like must have
been in her mid fifties lying on
her back and a little nightgown,
no underwear with her, like
arms and legs, you know,
like a crab doing a crab thing and we
walk in and it's like this, you know,
pussy in the whole scene just scared
the shit out of me and just started
laughing like you crazy old lady. What
are you doing? Get off from there.
She just like last and the thing that I
didn't understand until I hung out with
her is that people who are psychotic,
no,
they're psychotic and so they kind
of know how ridiculous they are.
And as a doctor when she laughs,
she laughs in such a loving,
accepting,
I get you kind of way that it creates
this instant report and they start
laughing. Oh. So she like relieves a
little tension, right? Like it's all okay.
I know you're just another crazy person.
I deal with you all the time and come
on. It's, it's Kinda like how you know,
like a gynecologist I imagine would
have to sort of be so laid back that you
kind of, you know, okay. He seen
a million pussies, you know,
like it relaxes you in a way, you know?
And I think she does that with, uh,
with crazy people. It's normal people
who make her really uncomfortable.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
imagine if you were a gynecologist and
you were super nervous about seeing
someone's post.
Okay. I guess we're about to do that.
Hold on. I have some water on my face.
Let me have a little more wine.
Just another days off.
That's happening. All right, let's
see what you got wrong down there.
I'm looking,
going to use a mirror.
I get some fucking van buyer. It's
Medusa. You can't look at it in the eyes.
So if you had to have a job,
like a normal job,
what job would you be good at or what,
what would you want to do?
Not a gynecologist,
I imagine.
Uh, outside of comedy I would
probably be a martial arts instructor.
I enjoyed doing that. You liked
teaching? Yeah, I enjoyed teaching.
But you're good with kids.
I'll bet I enjoyed it. Yeah.
I use to teach kids class.
I taught a lot of kids.
I taught kids a up.
I taught several kids from white belt
all the way up to a higher belts.
Like I don't think a ton
anybody up to black belt,
but I got pretty close because it takes
quite a few years to achieve black belt.
So for most of them, that is very rare
that they make it to that far. Like there,
they'll learn some lessons along the way
and it'll help them, you know, in life.
But to achieve that level
of, of a fee of ability, it,
there's a lot of commitment.
So most of them didn't make it.
It's like maybe one out of a thousand
ever make it to black belt. Really.
Probably in a good school maybe.
I mean might be one out of
500 or 600 but it's whatever.
It's close to 10,000 whatever it is.
It's,
it's not 1% by any stretch
of the imagination.
It's probably a good estimate is
one 10th of 1% right. You know, so,
but yeah,
I enjoy you.
I imagine you'd be really good
in that kind of an environment.
Not just martial arts but kids in general.
Cause the,
there's like a sort of an immediate
respect. You know, like you're,
you know, you look like a bad ass. So
it's like, oh me take that guy seriously.
Well I like kids and you're amenable.
You're open to
I also, I'm a big take
in strays. SORTA. Oui.
I've always taken the stray
dogs and cats and yeah,
I've been following your Instagram. Lots
of good catch that's in there recently.
I got a new kitten. I love cats,
man. I do too. They're fun.
They're fun to have around. They don't
require your constant attention to,
they got dignity. They got their own
life man. And especially the key which,
which you obviously understand
is have multiple cats.
Don't have one cat cause then you're
going to have the neurotic freaked out cat
pissing in your bed.
But you have it.
The difference between no
cat and a cat is significant.
The difference we one cat in two
cats is negligible. Yeah. Right.
So as far as like the whole on whatever.
Yeah.
I mean so get a few cats if
you're going to get a cat.
And so they have each other when
you're not around. Yeah. Yeah.
I got three of them.
That's what we had three
plan. You know, interesting enough. Um,
teaching was one of the things that
really helped me on fear factor,
which fear factor seems like a such a
stupid show. And it was kind of dumb.
But um,
it was some people that were like really
freaked out and didn't know how to deal
with like the stress of competition.
And I was so used to it. Oh,
so you used to not just, not
just teaching, but coaching.
Like, even when I retired,
my friend Dimitri was a fighting in this
big national tournament and I was in
his corner for like,
and I pumped him up like during the,
it was like one of his
best performances ever.
Like I'm good at getting
inside of people's heads,
especially people that I know and telling
them what they need to hear to get
them to go out there and fire him the
fuck up, you know, and telling them like,
what you're really good at man,
you can do this.
And it's all about not having any doubt.
It's all about knowing how to stay
in tents and focused and, and, and,
and go out there and do
what needs to be done and,
and giving them this sort of technical
advice as well as like this emotional
pick me up like some,
some people have like a knack for that.
And I developed it by teaching kids
because kids are always freaked out, man.
I took a lot of kids to
tournaments and you know,
they'd be fighting other little kids
and most likely they wouldn't get hurt.
But you know when you got a little seven
year old in front of you and you're
putting pads on his head to protect
him from Kix and you're like, listen,
you just got to stay
focused and don't be afraid.
All you need to think
about is what you're doing.
Don't think about what happens if
it goes wrong. Never think of that.
Always think about what are you
trying to do and if things go wrong,
reset and think about it again. What is
my objective? What am I trying to do?
Stay defensive. Keep moving. Never
stand in one place at one it, you know,
never stand put. Always,
always keep fainting.
Always keep the opponent guessing and
I'd go over all the most important things
to them and then pump them
up and tell you can do this.
When you get through this,
you're going to feel so good.
I know you feel terrible now, but it's
terrible as you feel now when it's over,
you're going to feel so good. And when
they would do it and it would compete,
even if they would lose, he'd
be so relieved. I'm like, see,
now you feel good and this, this,
this experience is horrifying.
Stressful experience can give birth
to this new appreciation of peace,
right,
right.
It's the, it's the Ying Yang again,
right? You were talking about earlier,
I read a book recently, a fascinating
book called a paradise made in hell.
Uh,
Rebecca Solnit and it's about a sociology,
right? So it's studying people's
behaviors in a behavior in disasters,
right? And so it's fascinating
because the idea we have is like,
that's when people get really crazy and
they, you loot and pillage and the, Oh,
now I can rape and nobody will catch
me there. No cops. And in fact,
what happens is the opposite.
That that's when people are most generous,
most kind. They've formed
communities, they meet the neighbors,
they never said a fucking
word to for 10 years.
They're like taking care
of each other and people,
and it sort of relates to war too. You
know, people look back on it and they say,
yeah,
there was a lot of horrible shit that
people were dying and stuff was happening.
But I remembered as the best time
in my life. And the main guy,
there's this really moving passage where
this guy who sort of started the field,
who's no Hippie, he's, you know,
teachers at Nebraska or something.
He's like very straight up
scientist. But he said, he said,
the best way to think about
disasters is not as a disaster,
but as relief from the
disaster that is normal life.
Because the normal life, we're all
isolated. We're all suffering alone.
And he's like, man, when
the shit hits the fan,
that's when things get really wonderful.
What?
Well,
there's no escaping the fact that it's
finite when you're watching people die
around you, that's for sure. Yeah.
Yeah. Well, and again, it's like
you were saying about, you know,
you need the pain to enjoy the pleasure.
You need hunger to enjoy
the food you need, you know,
loneliness to enjoy companionship.
There is no light without
dark. There really isn't.
Right. And I think people, uh,
one of the things that people miss in
their lives that leads people to become
very stagnant and,
and disappointed and,
and their existence is that
there's no thrills. You know?
I think that's what leads people to um,
you know,
to get divorced or to get to become
drug addicts or to be self destructive.
It's almost like people need thrills and
when you get stuck in a really secure
job or you know, all right Chris
Ryan for the next 40 hours,
you know, you're going to be
stuck in this spot or you know,
eight hours a day for the next, you know,
seven days, five days, whatever it is.
You're going to be stuck in this spot
and you're going to be at this desk and
you're going to be dealing with all
these cases that come your way and you're
going to have to file them.
And then you're going to have to write
a report and it's going to suck and
you're going to just be lumped in to this
group of people that are all doing the
same thing. And you're going to do it
every week. And at the end of the week,
you know, when, when the day's done,
then you can go home and you can relax,
but there's going to be
no thrills. The, the,
the biggest thrill would be merging
onto the highway. Oh my God. Here we go.
Like other than that,
there's nothing.
There's no ups is all
just steady and normal.
And I think that's one of the reasons
why people have so much road rage and
stress in there. There's
no right. Oh, real
experience. There's no, they're not
flushing out. I often say in Spanish,
the word Isilon means both
to insulate and to isolate.
Mm.
So we, you know, and this gets
into this whole book I'm writing,
like civilization is largely an attempt
to insulate ourselves from a danger from
strangers, from any sort
of, uh, predators, you know,
from anything that
could be a danger to us.
We try to insulate ourselves from it and
then at the end were isolated, right?
Because we're surrounded by this margin,
this moat that protects us from what?
From farm life, right? From the thing
that makes you feel alive. Like, okay,
you want to be completely safe, you know,
get inside this coffin, you know, and uh,
you know, take some anesthetics and
you won't feel a God damn thing,
but how's that different from me dead?
It seems like we're all doing our
part in this existence and we're,
we're moving past what we used to be
from single celled organisms to higher
primates to some weird thing right now.
That's a combination of conscious
being and, and physical animal.
And someone like Dunkin sounded like
Duncan and we're moving in this sort of
advancing direction and it's not,
it's not done. You know, we're, we're,
yeah, we're a part of a great process
and what the stage that you and I are in,
but they're going to look back at us
and laugh the way we look back at Isaac
Newton. We're in a powdered wig or you
know, any of the Weirdos that you know,
figured out all sorts of
incredible things back in history,
but also believed a bunch of
stupid shit as well. Like you,
you look back at Copernicus and the
things that he discovered and it's
unbelievable and amazing,
but today it's like Duh.
Like everybody already knows that, you
know, the look at the life that you live.
Like imagine being Darwin and trying to
express these ideas that you formulated
over the course of your, your life's
work to a bunch of Christian scientists,
which is what he was dealing with.
It's hilarious if you go back
and think about it today,
like his challenges of this
idea of this monotheistic world,
that they,
that the scientist pretty much universally
existed in at that time and, and,
and tries to push forth these crazy
theories that he's coming up with uniquely
on his own. I mean, the, the, the,
the resistance that he must have
experienced to something that today is
instantaneously accepted by
everyone that's in, in academia,
in, in, in science. I mean, almost
across the board, his ideas are accepted.
So we look back at those
times and we'd go, God,
they're fucking so stupid back then.
Well, they're going to do that to us,
you know, and it's got going to
be that long. I mean with Darwin,
you're talking about a
few hundred years with us,
it's going to be a few decades and then
a few days it goes faster and faster and
faster and faster. And we're,
we're in the middle of this.
We're in the middle of this weird process
of human beings changing and becoming
more aware of all the flaws and the folly
in our civilization and our existence
and all the shit we're
fighting for it today.
All the protests like black
lives matter and you know,
people fighting for rights of, you
know, everyone across the board,
women to gaze to this,
to that.
Like what we're doing is we're trying to
patch up the holes in this crazy system
with, with agitation and anger
and loud voices and you know,
social media campaigns and
it's essentially all just
trying to make this thing
into a more coherent,
more advanced version of what it is now.
And then that in turn will find the
inherent problems in its existence and it
will move just like the monkeys from,
you know,
200,000 years ago that
became human beings.
We're fighting off all these different
creatures and realize like, yeah,
we got to make houses. This
is bullshit. Like this.
That's fucking living in trees is
bullshit. The cat's climb trees man,
my fucking tired of my
baby's getting eaten.
Like let's figure out beers
and snakes. Yeah, let's,
let's figure a way to
make a better situation.
And I think we're in the middle of
that man. No, I think we just like,
like all things you take it for granted
that you're in the middle of it.
Well if you look back on your childhood,
you know,
and today you look back and you go,
wow,
when I was 10 I was doing
this and I was doing that.
But when you were 10 you were just in
the middle of it. You know, you'll,
you'll look back at how much progress
is taking place in your own life as a
microcosm tier existence. You
know, the are all of our existence.
You are your own individual memories in
your own individual experiences. They,
you're in the middle of it.
You don't think about being
what we're as civilization.
We're in the middle of this baby hood.
We're in the middle of this adolescents,
whatever the fuck it is,
you know,
and we're moving into some
new place and it's arrogant,
but very common for people to
think we're at the end of it.
Like this is the cutting edge is the edge,
but it's not the end.
It's not perfection. It's
like, yeah, it's always,
always in process,
always in process.
But amazing to think that right now we
are at the pinnacle of human knowledge.
We are at the peak,
the tip of the spear as far as like
everything that people have learned and
figured out up until now we have this
database that we've accumulated from
hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of
years of records. And then you know,
after that it gets a little sketchy
and you'd go to a few thousand years.
So you just get real weird
and different languages.
Things get even weirder and it gets
more vague and more strange and more
difficult to decipher.
But all that data that we've accumulated
and the access to it that we have today,
unprecedented as far as we
know. And people. It's amazing.
It's amazing to be at that time.
Will you have a question?
You just like with a psychology,
psych, psych, psychopaths,
the thing we just bang,
we just Google it and we
didn't have to go to a library.
We didn't have to order a book.
We didn't have to go to a
bookstore or go to a class.
You just instantaneously get that
information and I think that that is
accelerating us in a way that we
can't even comprehend. Yeah, no doubt.
Yeah. I think we're all
experiencing it in a way that's,
it's seems so normal because
everyone has a phone, you know? Whoa.
Let me just check my,
my phone and see.
Let me just call my friend who's nowhere
near me. And you know, this affects the,
getting back to the earlier
thing about aging, right?
Like I,
this affects the experience of aging
because more has changed in our lifetimes
because it's always
accelerating that like,
I remember the first computer I
interacted with, right? It was,
I was in my late twenties working
in the diamond district in New York,
and one of my jobs was to back
up the disks in this computer.
The computer was the size of a big
refrigerator and the disks were like,
you know, double the
circumference of a, of an album.
And they were these massive things and
they were probably like 50 megabytes each
or something, you know, if that,
right. Is that right? I mean,
and I probably got a thousand times the
computing power in my pocket right now.
It's just easily insane. Maybe
even more than a thousand. Yeah.
I don't know how it works. Yeah. Hey, I
got a role. Get outta here, man. Yeah,
it's always going to see this weekend.
I'm tempted to like miss the plane.
There's just so much fun. Uh, what's that?
The planets. The rental car. Oh, okay.
They're going to rape me if I'm late.
We'll hang out this weekend and we're,
we're promising to do one with you.
Me and Duncan again.
We're going to figure it out.
And I know we've been getting tweets.
Everybody's busy folks. Shit happens.
Um, but we'll, we'll get it together.
We'll get it together. But thank you
brother. Appreciate. Pick a date.
I'll fly down for us for sure. Can you
can follow Chris on Twitter. It's a,
is it Chris Ryan? Phd? Yeah.
Or as Christopher Ryan, Chris
Ross, Ryan, Chris, Brian,
Chris, Ryan, Phd. Uh,
the one book that you can buy
that he has his sex at dawn.
Fantastic book, guaranteed to Piss
off your wife. Leave that shit around,
buddy of reading, getting these fucking
ideas out of your head. Uh, Chris Ryan,
Ladies and gentlemen. Thank
you brother. Appreciate it,
man. It's a lot of fun. Yeah.
Bye Bye.
Okay.
Hm.