Court.
Is that it? Yeah. Hello, we're back.
We're back folks. You know, we,
we ended on a very important point and
we ended on a point so important that we
had to bring it back up again.
Yeah.
The lack of manliness in this fucking
country, ladies and gentlemen,
it's me and here's his salt.
Here's something for you man.
And this is, you look at
cinema today. Cinemas,
a big thing in the United States. It
always has been. It sets trends. It sets,
you know, kind of people's
morals to a certain extent.
So let me read you this. Let
me read you this IDP. I was,
how do you say that database?
Yes. That Guy Idb oh, this man.
And he's one of my favorite dudes ever.
But I'm going to read you this list of
films he was involved with either as a
screenwriter or a writer.
Okay.
Which as a screenwriter and a rider is
a guy who comes up with the idea of the
fucking movie. So that's pretty
important. It's huge. So here we go.
Here's a list of movies for you.
Dirty Harry, Jeremiah Johnson.
Well, the life and times of
Judge Roy Bean tease Paul Newman,
magnum force apocalypse now,
Jesus,
1941 comedy with John Belushi,
Conan the barbarian,
the first one,
original 1982,
the one that made Arnold Schwarzenegger
is star and Future Governor of
California Cohen on what is best in life.
I still enemies to the living
before you and hear the lamination.
Uh, uh, and I, and to
me personally, this is,
I'm a child of the 80s, so this
is like my movie, my goto thing.
Red Dawn, he wrote the screenplay for
right. First of all, how dare you,
how dare he both of you go fuck
yourself. That movie's terrible. Fuck,
I'm not drive in a 78 Firebird any more
hoodies and I'm not living in that time
frame. Would that right back
off man? Red Dawn, the shit,
the shit. What's Red
Dragon Wolverines, mother,
whatever it is. You said red
dragons. That's it man. That's like,
that's one like overeating.
It makes me sad that you don't know
that it's a good movie or as good as
roadhouse doe. Clear and present
danger. Uh, Laurie yet Rome,
the TV series, 22 episodes. I was
a legit TV. Do you ever watch that?
Rome. What year was that?
Uh, 2005 HBO series.
Wow. I don't think I
did. It was a legit, um,
that's a must be post gladiator. They
decided to do that and yeah, probably.
Yeah. That, that thing. Patrick
Swayze. Yes. Right there, baby.
That's the, that's the original legit
red dawn. Is that the trailer? Yeah.
Peter tried to tell me Span Johnson.
Ben Johnson was a mother fucking gangster.
Swayze died from cigarettes. They
tried to say that. Did he? I,
I watched the last, uh, on
Netflix and says, Shit. The beast,
the last series that he did, yes.
And it was pretty good, but God damn,
he looked bad. It looked
terrible. I mean, it was like,
you felt so bad cause
roadhouse was a legit movie.
Religious hard to fuck with
that. Awesome. We terrible. Hey,
it's hard to fuck with that.
It's got,
Patrick Swayze is a Boucher
with Sam Elliott as his mentor.
And Ben, who's Ben Vareen is, yes,
the bad guy. The bad guy. I own,
but I don't care. Whoever the chick was
with the giant jugs. Oh, she's so pretty.
Yeah, she was. She's just fucking smart
too. I'm sure she didn't take care of you.
She was a doctor. She
was huge. Stitch you up,
send you back out into the battlefield.
Basically.
The perfect woman accepts you as you go.
It looks like a rubber blowup doll.
It's been left out in
the sun for 20 years.
You could take a picture of her right now.
I don't want to take a picture of it and
I want to go back in time back in 19 I
don't want to smell her vagina when
it smelled like paradise wrote about.
Uh, well, I don't want to bring
that up. We don't want to get,
you don't want to stir up too much shit,
but I was going to say
at that point in time,
that was like the Steven Seagal era.
That's when Steven Seagal like roadhouse
was that Steven Seagal was like right
about there because Steven Seagal started
with above the law. That was legit.
That was like 90 91 right around that era.
89 maybe that's when roadhouse
was roadhouse was 89 and
it was awesome and it's
still awesome.
Oh,
it's got some of the best lines
ever until it's time to not be nice.
Yeah. How do we know when that is?
I'll let you know. Pain don't hurt.
Oh, that's, that was great stuff,
dude. He looks at say, well Sam,
it's been a gangster forever,
but actually above the law cane before
roadhouse. It was a eight, eight,
four 88.
That was just first movie.
Like he's doing Kung Fu and he was hanging
out with that dude who was, uh, Jeff.
Uh, the guy was, the guy was
blind and grape scenarios. Yes.
Great Blues Guy. Yeah. Kelly
Lynch. That's her name. Right.
So pretty.
You're so fucking hot.
I don't even want to know
what she looks like now.
She will forever look like she
looked at in my eyes. Oh, this,
that's the monster truck days.
Got Girls got entirely too many brains
to have an ass like that. No, it's fine.
That's fine. That's a quote from
Sam Elliott. It's ridiculous.
Sam Elliott was incorrect. It's just
a matter of being able to handle it.
Look at the little chicken chest.
I'm Patrick Swayze. He's so lucky.
There's no black man in that movie.
So lucky because there was a black
man that got injured. They did.
They did the fucked up graphic.
That was the,
they didn't have the original graphic.
Oh Wow.
That's probably a post
that was failing three.
I bet that was an early trailer Mip,
but did they have a lot of trailers
back then? Yeah, the early,
if you look at trailers, like a lot of
like big films, they were all dog shit.
Now with the trailer is better than the
fucking movie that I have a real problem
or trailers. Now I wait for a bus on the
movie and I try not to see the trailer.
If I could see a trail on my computer,
I'll literally turn away,
but I heard the Godzilla trailer was
nothing. It was just like there was a,
someone said it was amazing trailer and
it's actually a like a proof of concept.
It's a concept.
Okay.
It's not that they just started
filming in recently on a Wahoo.
According to Twitter. Have you seen a
move on source? I'm trying to think about,
I haven't seen movie.
The last movie that really made me like,
you know what,
like that's a bad ass. Like that's a one
for the ages. I'm trying to think of it.
And the closest I can come is it departed.
The department was really good,
but Avatar does it for me. Really.
I hadn't dealt with stupid. I know it
was dumb. I know. It requires suspension.
It's a bunch of hippy bullshit. It's
nothing more than one. It's, it's a,
it's like a bunch of fucking, uh, it's
revisionist American Indian history.
You're right. You're right. You're right.
If it was an original thought, you got me.
I respect the technical aspects of the
filmmaking cause it's fucking amazing
what they did.
But the story is straight up.
Fucking put truly bull. You can follow
up with Julie. You're totally right.
You're totally right. However,
I feel it's my feeling that,
um,
a movie like that is a comic book movie
and it's basically a vehicle for just
showing you pretty things and getting
you carried away in a story. And, uh, I,
I see your argument,
but I also see the argument
and making it completely.
James Cameron is a fucking genius.
He's a wicked motherfucker.
He's a fucking genius dude. Went down to
the farthest reaches of the ocean south.
Yes, Matt. I mean south,
I think he's a stud and I,
and I respect what he does and I wish
more people had the balls and ability to
do what he does.
I think you,
you've got to have a giant fucking ego
to do what he does. But you know what?
You get that ego by making movies that
make hundreds and hundreds of millions of
dollars. That's so true. You
know, I was talking to um, uh,
people on my message board about, uh,
there was, someone was talking about,
there's a, a situation recently
where there was a, a, a billionaire,
a very famous cat who denounce Steve
Jobs and sold all his apple stock.
His name is Jay Robertson.
He dumped all his apple shares.
And the reason why I did, he said
Steve Jobs is a really awful person.
Like that's his quote.
And there was like this big debate on
my message board and, and you know,
I started reading it and you know what,
what makes the guy an awful
person and what doesn't? And My,
my take on it was that it's like anybody
running a company like that where
you're running like
an insanely innovative pressure filled
company that's trying to be at the very,
the very front of the line of the most
competitive form of technology available
consumer technology in the phone business
should, I mean they, they're, they're,
they're so like attached to people's
like that mean people fight over android
versus apple or you know,
I'm, I've got a windows phone,
I'm a fucking contrarian and it's a weird,
very competitive Uber Geek Environment.
And Steve Jobs was the
master of that Shit.
The phones master of the home computer.
He was the master.
He made exclusivity. He made the, he,
he came up with the very best stuff.
And for him it was like, it was
everything. It was his whole existence.
And for the people that work for him,
it was a job man.
Just like you talking about working at
the auto [inaudible] I'm working for, for,
yeah, it's just a job. If you
had to work for Steve Jobs,
you would have fucking nightmare stories
about that con. Yeah. He'd be like,
that guy's a douche bag.
It goes.
That's one of the things about,
another thing I'm fascinated by
is with modern media, new media,
um, Facebook, Twitter, everything,
just the way everything is.
It's this thing that if you don't agree
100% with what an entity as a company
does or with,
if you think a person is an asshole,
then all of a sudden that
means whatever they make,
whatever they do is not cool
or not acceptable anymore.
And to me that's false.
I see. It's positive. I see a,
it represents this unique need for
accountability across the board.
I understand accountability,
but here's the thing, man. If,
if you're in charge of getting something
done, I don't give a fuck who you are.
If you're in charge of making something
and putting product out the door,
somewhere along the line someone's
going to say, you're a fucking asshole.
Sounds going to get butthurt. Yeah.
It's impossible not to that true.
So that's true. But I show now
and it's the fact that, okay,
and I'm, maybe I'm guilty
of it in certain instances,
but at the same time it's like,
why not let the person's work speak
for themselves, you know? I mean, okay,
perfect example music. Uh, I try
not to get, I, I'm guilty of this.
I try not to get worked up because
I'm a conservative, pretty much. Dude.
You know, if any, like
I said, I feel like,
and this is a problem that I run into
with most left leaning or whatever you
want to call it,
is I'm perfectly willing to let
anybody do whatever the fuck they want.
The flip side of that is, let me
do what the fuck I want. Right.
And that you be a man.
Yeah.
And that's the problem that most people
fucking run into say, no, no, no, no.
You'd have to fall within
these parameters. How dare
you want to do x, Y, z.
You can't do that. We need to
control this. Yeah. So my point
is if any of these guys,
you know,
I don't give a fuck if you're a prick.
I don't care if you're an asshole.
I don't care if you got in a fight with
the guy over here or are you getting a
lawsuit over some bullshit if your product
does what it says it will you treat
me right as a customer?
Why am,
why would I ever be an asshole and not
buy your shit because someone else says
they don't like you. Well, I
think it's based on empirical
evidence and what, what,
what, what, what? Now, that's
not to say if a guy's a
legitimate fucking prick. Look,
I've heard conversations that other
people have had about me. Right?
Someone has said that I was
a head. I was like, Oh man,
let me tell you what
that guy actually did.
I walked in and said this to my
friend, like right away, Zack,
of course I was a dick to him, right?
He's got me the creepy eyes, you know?
He's saying that, I think I'm too
good. Whatever the fuck it is,
there's two sides to the story.
Exactly.
And that's the problem
with the way shit is now,
is that all of a sudden
through an onslaught.
Now imagine if you're just a fucking guy,
just a dude that doesn't have a big
media presence and somebody decides to,
you know, you, you, you run into some
asshole out here and they go, hey, look,
you know,
for whatever reason,
something goes down and all of a sudden
they want to make you the asshole.
Now that's, I mean, is it right?
Is it wrong? Not so much. Well,
they're trying to reshape reality and
they're trying to influence other people's
opinions to justify their own opinion.
Not only that,
but there is a fucking mob mentality
of let's jump on board and you know,
we're going to fuck this guy. And I know
for a fact you've been a victim of it.
Me. Yeah, absolutely. Perfect example. I
mean, you're outspoken on certain shit.
Perfect example was with the, uh,
uh, the, the, the transsexual thing.
I mean you got your fucking nuts kicked
in and certain circles over that it's
happened before. I mean, so
that was, it was all important.
You know, that was a, that
was a good thing. That was a,
that was important for dialogue.
Yeah.
Like it's important for those people to
express themselves and be angry at me.
You can't hurt my feelings.
That's all right. I understand.
If you have a version of
reality to difference,
and here's when it comes to describing,
here's what tilt me is when people want
to start fucking with your income. Yeah.
People start going, they don't go to you
what they want to be reacted to know.
They want to go, hey look, you know, fuck
this. We're boycotting the UFC. You know,
they're calling your boss,
or not your boss, but your
employer, Dana white saying,
hey look, you know, you need to fire this
guy because he's a fucking asshole. And,
and to me that's just like,
you know,
that's the biggest pussy move on the
planet because they can't argue what you
were saying, that they're not
willing to have a dialogue and say,
I disagree with you because of this.
Let me try it.
Let me try to swing you to my way
of working. They want to say no,
I disagree with what you're
saying. I'm a pussy, so fuck you.
I'm going to try and take your money.
Not only that, there's also something
that's going on with people that disagree
with certain people's opinions is that
they are absolutely convinced that
they are right and that you are wrong.
So because of that,
they're willing to do almost anything
to express the idea that you are wrong,
whether it's distort reality,
whether it's to give their
opinion a very biased way,
excluding certain aspects of the facts,
whatever it is,
there's an ego battle along
with the ideology battle.
My problem is when that ego battle is
so glaringly obvious and you're not
willing to admit that that's exactly
what the fuck is going on. You know,
like we said about the transsexual thing,
like I'm happy to get the transactional
conversation out there because I think
ultimately once the dust settles,
I think people should realize
that it doesn't matter. You know,
it doesn't matter if someone wants to be
a woman or if someone wants to be a man
or if you want to live your life
doesn't matter. It doesn't matter.
What matters is how do you treat people
well at the same time, this is kind
of been my issue with, uh, I dunno,
alternative lifestyles, whatever the
hell you want to call it. But it's,
there's a difference between acceptance
and it's like, okay, here, look,
I accept the way someone wants to live
their life. No problem. That's on you,
but don't expect me to cheerlead you.
Well, you know what I think that's from,
you know, don't expect me
to be. It's like, you know,
I will accept however you
want to live your life,
but accept the fact that it's possible.
There are people out there
that are willing to accept
it and say you're, you're,
you're, you know, that's, you're right.
100% but that doesn't mean
they have to agree with it.
And if they don't agree with it,
it doesn't make them a bigot.
Right? Well, people don't have
to agree with anything, you know,
as long as you treat people fairly
and kindly and it doesn't matter.
That's what I really look for.
And to me that's a sign of someone
that I will respect is someone that is
willing to understand and they
can argue vigorously. You know,
that I do not agree with
what you're saying, but,
but I respect your right and your
ability to live the way you want to live.
And I will not degrade you
and I will not hinder you,
but I do not agree with you.
Yeah.
I think it's a really important point to
know that there's a bunch of different
ways of looking at the world and you
might not agree with my way of looking at
the world.
It doesn't mean that you're right,
that doesn't mean that you're
wrong either. It means a,
your, the, the, the fucking,
the spectrum of thinking is so broad.
There's a lot of variabilities.
What's important,
I think as a culture and as a community
that anything that we agreed to,
we agreed to on the basis.
Does it cause less harm than it does?
You know, does it co, does it cause
more good than it does harm? Right.
And as long as we act in
that way, we would let allow
anything. Right. Basically,
as long as it doesn't victimize people,
man,
that's the way I look at it is,
is I mean I could write up a
bill rights and it would be about
eight sentences and it would
be maybe not even that.
Basically it's your rights
end where mine begin.
You don't get to touch children
and you know, that's it.
I mean basically just do whatever
the hell you want to do, man.
Let your freak flag fly. But at
the end of the day, you know what?
You've got to pay your taxes.
You got to go to work.
Let your fleet, your freak flag fly. Yeah.
Jimi Hendrix baby. That's it.
That's his line. You know, I mean,
do whatever you gotta do. I don't give
a shit. But at the end of the day,
you're still a member of a community.
So most important thing to say ever,
and I fucked it up. Let
your freak flag fly. Yeah,
let it free party 2014 starting a
new political party. I saw that.
I'm down with that.
It's a hunter.S Thompson had freak
power and the 1970s I'm going what?
The Freak Party for 2013
out of respect for HST.
You know what's funny is in other
countries with parliamentary systems,
um, it's designed towards
not a two party deal. Well,
my point is you can do,
I mean no party and now the countries,
I mean you could legitimately no bullshit.
Probably put together a freak party
and maybe get one or two house,
you know, house members and they would
have, you know, but I mean that's,
that's what's crazy.
I think the way the system was designed,
that was what was in mind. It was
never designed to be two parties. No,
they hijack that. Yeah. And I think
that I could be president of Canada.
If you're willing to move to Vancouver,
we can make some shit happen. I mean,
Edmonton and I can't tell you
for, I mean that's, I love Canada.
You know what I love about Canadians?
They're the nicest people in the world.
So Nice. They have beautiful women,
so hot, but fuck, they're communist.
They're communists. Listen, only
when it comes to healthcare,
the only his communist is the
people that you interact with.
If you choose to interact with the people
that are all social Isti and they're
trying to fucking make it the NERF,
the world and provide [inaudible].
I got two topics for us.
Number one.
Tell me what the fuck you would have done
in New York City if it would have been
your wife and your two kids
and an SUV and that SUV thing.
Here's my take on that and I'm
sure you've talked about before,
but I haven't really, it's the SUV, um,
motorcycle biker thing.
I don't know how that guy was driving.
I don't know what happened.
I don't know if anyone was aggressive.
I don't know if anyone was clueless.
I literally don't know what I looked at
when I saw the end where that guy drove
over those people and uh,
drove over those bikes.
I saw a guy who looked like he was
panicking and it looked like he was
surrounded.
But without the information of hearing
what these guys were saying to him or
what had happened before that I don't,
you know, I saw the one guy slow down.
It's like brake check them,
brake
checked him and,
but apparently something had occurred
before that where the guy had like maybe
bumped into a bike or
gotten too close to a bike,
but apparently something had occurred
before that where they were involved in
all [inaudible] with another automobile.
And there's a video of that and there's
a mob mentality sort of an argument to
be taken to I think unless you're there.
And you know,
there was like three cops, they're
undercover. I think it was five,
six x six is the last I heard was
three in and they arrested one. Well,
you know, cops are people.
There's a problem for sure. Um,
I don't know what the fuck happened,
man. I really don't know who got beat up.
New Video, the new video shows
a guy got beat up apparently.
I don't know who caused what.
I Dunno who deserve what.
I do know that I've been around some
dudes and bikes and act like fucking cock
suckers,
but I've do know that I've been around
people in cars around bikes and act like
fucking cock suckers.
I do know that people tend to act like
fucking cock suckers when they're in
groups especially.
Yeah,
and I don't know if it's the guy in the
truck didn't know what the fuck he was
doing or the gun. The bike didn't.
I don't know what happened, man.
I mean, I dunno. I fedec. From what
I've watched and from what I've seen,
one of the best forum posts I've seen
yet that described it was I seriously
doubt that that guy in the
SUV woke up that morning,
put his wife and kid in the truck and
said, let's go fuck with some bikers.
But I'm willing to bet at least a few
of those fucking bikers woke up in the
morning, got on their motorcycle and said,
let's go fuck with some of these guys.
Maybe. And it might be, they're just,
they all got together and felt
the power in numbers. That's fine.
The same time, you know, the
brake check thing, I mean,
I've read different accounts and I've
seen some different videos and then you
look at history.
Past performance is an indicator.
It really is.
You know what people do in the past,
but to me it just looks like,
I don't know.
The biggest thing that flipped my mind,
those motherfuckers chased him
like 50 blocks in Manhattan. Yeah.
You've been in New York?
Yeah.
How the fuck do you do 2030 more recycles
40 motorcycles chasing a guy through
Manhattan.
What a fucking cops.
Yeah. Where are the cops were
to cops? I don't know. I mean,
I don't know if he called the cops.
I don't know if he had a flat.
I think you might have
had a flat tire to that.
I don't give a fuck 50 blocks a minute.
You can't drive 50 blocks in van.
You can't.
I mean for fuck sake.
Well, you know who knows
what? What's going to come
out about the undercover cops?
How much information? My question is if
one of those guys were calling them off.
Yeah, it could be. I mean, could be, is
that possible? I don't know. You know,
like I said, both sides
are gross. It's gross.
If the guy was disrespecting
the motorcycles or it's gross.
If the guy was panicking and putting
people in jeopardy. It's also growing.
But here's the thing. Here's the way I
look at the guys stopped the guy brake
checks them. If you just
started that video, dude,
brake checks them. Number one,
if you're on a motorcycle and you brake,
check an SUV,
you're a fucking moron cause you're
gonna lose. Yeah, that sounded good.
That's number one. You're a
dick. Even if you're 100% right,
even if this guy almost ran you off
the fucking road, okay, you got me,
you're on the right.
But if you can in front of them and brake,
check them and he runs you the fuck over.
Whose fault is that?
Even if you were right to be mad.
So right there,
one wrong.
And so the guy gets on the brakes and
then the next thing he stopped and he's
surrounded by these bikes.
Now if you're a guy, and,
and he was the thing, it goes back
to what we started about before.
The whole thing about fucking people not
being a man. You know, here's this guy,
probably never been in a fight
in his fucking life. You know,
never had to protect himself,
never had to protect his family and he's
surrounded by these fucking assholes.
So what's he do?
Panic. Exactly. Yes. Right. Yeah.
Well it's a scary fucking scenario,
man. If it would have been
me and that position and I was,
well I dunno,
all I gotta say is it would
have been like, I dunno,
you see death race 2000 like
microfilm or like every which way,
but loose the remake.
I have been around both.
I've been around very
respectful bikers who do,
they ride down the road like you know,
a hundred strong and you know,
waving to people and share and there's
no problems. And I've also seen assholes.
I've seen assholes cut people off and
get in front of people. And there's a,
there's a thing when you
have ultimate strength,
when most of your life you don't have
ultimate strength most of your life.
You have a shitty job. We have
to respond to your boss, right?
You have a bunch of rules
you have to live by.
And then all of a sudden you're
in this fucking scenario.
There's the guy tears the cop. The
guy on the right is a cow. Wow.
The guy who did that,
I ran the duty,
the bike with the,
either that or he,
one of them because at least in the
newspaper I saw the dude had the cut right
there. That a guy with the cut on with
the three three piece patch. Yeah.
He's a cop.
Why did he do anything?
Well, the whole, who knows who exactly,
who knows what the fuck happened.
And he's one of the cop, he's a cop that
got arrested and charged two felonies.
You know,
I think that if you're a fucking biker
and you're with a bunch of bikers, right.
This shit,
it's your responsibility to not get
close to SUV is if you can avoid it. No,
but like what just happened right there,
no matter what that guy did,
you don't do that well that was a
gap to the guy ruin it. Ran over.
Yeah. But I mean, if
that guy does that too,
I dunno the wrong person with a gun in
his car. Well, no, no. If it was me.
Okay.
And I'm disparity of force.
Any state in the United States,
that is a legal reason for excessive,
right? I don't care if you're,
especially for police officers,
if you're a police officer
and three guys come at you,
even if they don't have
any weapons in their hands,
you are justified to use deadly force.
Because this disparity of force,
no man is, no one person
is expected. You know,
there's nothing in the law that says
you've got to take an ass whipping. Yeah,
I mean even if this is one on one, if the
guy's a bad motherfucker know yes. If,
if you're a woman, if you're a
female, say you're 120 pound a year.
A man either that if you're 120 pound man,
what have your hundred and 80 and the
guys won 60 and he's got a good punch.
Shoot that motherfucker now.
And the will note now that that is,
that can be argued that if you have
a guy that's, you know, if you know,
if you're a guy that weighs the same as,
I dunno,
pick a fighter and then a fighter of
the same stature who was documented as
being a fighter, tries to beat this guy
up and he pulls a weapon and kills him.
He has a legit defense that
don't mean he's going to win.
But here's the one thing,
if you're talking about multiple odds,
disparity of force is almost every state
that I've looked at is a legitimate
cause for the use of
escalation to deadly force.
So that means if three or
four people come at you,
even if they don't have
guns and you do have a gun,
you don't have to take an ass whooping.
We don't have to let four people kick
your fucking head in just because they
don't have a gun or a weapon.
Disparity of force should be one person.
If you're not a candy person,
can be someone who knows how
to fight once to kick your ass.
You don't know how to fight your.man,
you're gonna get knocked unconscious and
the guy's going to stomp you to death
while you're on the ground. And
that's the thing that is that. And,
and in most states,
that's the reason why is because
once you get knocked out,
you're dead.
Yeah.
If a guy wants to kill you and the more
you're on Worldstar hip hop, right?
Oh, there's a great video that, uh,
unfortunately it's not available
for free, but it's a, it's,
it's a mindset video that I think
a lot of people should watch it.
It's by a guy named Paul how Paul How's
a Delta force operator who was on the
ground for Mogadishu, uh, for
the Black Hawk down scenario.
And he made a video and he's a,
he's a law enforcement trainer now
mainly also does civilian classes.
But he has a class about mindset and
what the mines and his mindset video is.
This is that.
And I think it's really important in this
day and age is because in this day and
age, kids, men, women, everyone is taught,
if you're, if you're encountered
with force or if you're
encountered with an APP,
you know, aggression, you give up retreat,
know if somebody tries to Mug
you, give me a wallet. You know,
if somebody tries to break
into your house, you know,
cower and he proves through some videos,
he shows examples, but he's
Trump. His point is this,
is that if your mat with
a situation like this,
and it's so rare and people
like you and I, our lives,
but that makes it even more important
is because if it ever does happen,
you must be prepared. Yeah. And his
point is this is like if you give up,
if you don't fight,
you forfeit all your rights to life.
And then he shows some videos
for assumption. I'm sure
you've seen most of them.
You know, the videos of the guys, uh,
in Mexico getting their fucking
heads chopped off, you know,
and he shows videos of the Columbine
massacre where they're walking through,
uh, you know, the cafeteria.
And people are cowering under the tables.
What else are they going to do?
You know, I mean, that was, that's,
that's an argument situation.
There's not much a guy could do,
right. But the point is, this is it.
You're still there. They're
still helpless. You know,
you, you can do nothing,
right?
If you don't fight,
the only thing you can hope for
is that they don't kill you.
They kill somebody else.
And that mindset of never give up,
you know, if you're going
to die, die a good death.
I think there's a point of view
from a lot of people that, um, have,
they don't have violent tendencies and
they're intimidated by violent tendencies.
There's a point of view where they want
to eliminate all the strength in the
world. They want to take away all the
benefits of being armed. All the, the,
you know, there's, there's a bunch of
people that discourage martial arts. I've,
I've, I've, I've actually
had that argument.
I had that argument with my family when
I started doing martial arts because I
was kind of a fucked up
kid. And, uh, my, uh,
my father was really worried that I was
going to become a much more efficient,
dangerous person. Right.
You know, that I was a,
a kind of a sketchy kid and then now I've
become a sketchy kid who knows how it
was dismantled people. Right.
And it was a real issue. Um,
like with me when I was 14 years old.
And I think that there's a lot of people
that are not inclined to physicality,
not inclined to violence,
not inclined to aggression that would
like to silence those things in other
people instead of deal with the inevitable
reality that those things exist.
And whenever someone tells me, you know,
they started talking about like, you know,
a, you know, if this guy said that I
would beat his ass or that I, you know,
there's a certain amount of that that
it'll tolerate until I get to a certain
point. Like, do you really,
do you know what you would do?
Do you really know what you would do?
Have you ever been in a
violent confrontation? Have,
do you know how to fight,
do not to fight when it's important? Do
you know how to fight? If someone said,
are you ready? Are you ready? Go. What'd
you be able to keep your shit together?
Right? Most likely not. If you've
never kept your shit together before,
if you never had that experience and
whether or not you've proven your, your,
your strength of character,
I'm going to be honest with you.
You're going to shit your pants.
You're going to Piss your pants right.
You're going to fall apart.
As soon as the guy gets a hold of you,
you're going to be breathing so hard.
You're not going to able
to control your heart rate.
You're not going to be able to do it.
You just,
unless you've really thought about this,
this is not some sort of like
easily manageable situation.
Real violence is incredibly
scary and incredibly scary.
And if you don't address that as a,
as a reality of life and the of life
that existed from fucking 4 billion years
ago when the first shitty little single
celled organism crawled out of the ocean
to what happens today in, in
2013 in Los Angeles, there's,
there's a reality to biological
life that you are a fucking part of.
And just by painting this Utopian picture
of reality doesn't make the dangerous
aspects of reality go away and
your a want to control nature.
It's like, it's an idealistic
sort of a point of view,
this Utopian view of the world, but
no one's violent. No one's, you know,
have the best achieve that strength
uniformly across the board.
And that's, that's a hard thing for
people to describe for people to swallow.
But the,
the,
the most safe environments I've ever
been in when I've been around trained
killers, right? The least amount of
street fights that have ever been at.
Where at the UFC,
when I'm at the USC and I'm backstage,
I've seen one or two scuffles
ever amongst the biggest,
most insane killers. The planners ever
known. It comes to hand to hand combat.
Right. Seemed like a few arguments seem
to huge dudes. Slap dudes, you know,
over hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of thousands of fights. Even
when you get egos. I mean,
yeah, he goes, well, yeah,
but even guys who do that,
their ego is checked. Yes.
Because they know that
as good as they are,
at some point they got
clipped or even that,
it's one of those things to where it goes
back to there's Jeff Cooper is what's
Jeff Colonel Jeff Cooper is considered
the father of the modern pistol
technique. No, hear me
out. Most of the things,
it sounds kind of silly or
gay. No, it doesn't at all.
But most of the talking about pistols.
Yeah, but, but we'll hear, hear me out.
Martial arts or martial arts. Oh
yeah, I agree. They really are.
Whether you're fighting with your
hands or this swords, guns, knives.
It really is.
You're talking about fighting.
And the difference is when
you're talking about, uh,
fighting with guns and knives,
the differences,
there's a force vector there and
there's a great James Edwards,
I can't think of his name, but he
made a great point. And that's this.
If you and I are fighting, I can block
your punch. Okay? I can take a block.
Or if I miss and you hit me,
chances are maybe I can take a punch.
You know, maybe you might not nec,
knock me out if you hit me with a punch.
But when you start talking about
fighting with weapons from steel up into
bullets, those are force vectors. Now,
if we're fighting with knives or
we're fighting even with sticks,
and I swing, this is a vector, okay? This,
this plane is a force vector.
If you're in that plane and I
have a knife, you're fucked.
Bodies cannot take that. If
you, if you throw your arm up,
even if I haven't got a knife this long,
I will cut through both your bones.
I'll cut your fucking hand off. Yeah.
Now if we're talking about guns,
even more fucked.
Yeah.
So it's forced vectors and it's a
different way of looking at fighting.
You know when you're talking about hand
to hand martial arts, you can take a hit,
you can block,
you can use that block to Perry,
you can use that block
to pull into an attack.
But when you start talking
about fighting with weapons,
the only way you can survive is to not
be there. Yeah. So not get hit. Right.
Not Get cut. Exactly. And so it's just,
it's that whole thing of the mindset
of being able to accept your on a fight
except the conditions
you're in and deal with it.
And the people who can do that generally
are because they understand the fact
that they're not fucking invincible.
Nobody's a bad ass.
Everybody can get hit, knocked
out, shot, stabbed, whatever.
No matter what your level of training.
So when you talk about being backstage
with a bunch of guys who spend their
lives, understanding that
no matter how good you are,
no matter how good your ego is, you
know, you have to keep that in check.
Everybody gets checked her.
Holly,
nobody starts out the
baddest motherfucker ever.
You get a few guys like John Jones that
come in with exceptional athleticism and
they do really, really good
right away. But even then,
like you look at the Gustafson fight,
even he meets a guy one day that handsome,
you know,
a a handful.
And that's also the training
that a god goes through.
It softens the Ego.
It changes the ego's impact on,
on your consciousness where you ego will
fucking lying to you if you don't get
any tests right.
If you don't get any real tests in life,
your ego will have you
all sorts of pumped up,
all sorts of confused
about your abilities.
I've had conversations with people that,
you know,
I'm the fucking kicked this fucking
dude's ass and you know, you,
you just want to just, you want to
stop time and pull them aside and say,
do you understand what you're even saying?
Because you don't really just kick a
guy's ass. Cause if you kicked my ass,
I'm coming back tomorrow with a bat.
Okay.
Or a gun or my friends and
we're gonna fuck you up.
I'm not just taking an ass kicking
from some pieces of that. That's
the difference between when you're
talking about sport, you know,
UFC blah, blah blah, or this or that.
And on the street in real life is,
it's, it's funny, I had a, uh,
a friend of mine who was a
marine and he was an auto worker.
The guy had done like
six years in the marines.
He wanted to be an auto worker and we
were drinking the bar all the time.
But he said something to me probably 10,
maybe 10 years ago,
it's always stuck with me. He said,
you know what? Nobody's a bad ass.
It's just comes down to a
question of will you know what?
Because if Brock Lesnar
whip my motherfucking ass,
which he would every day,
twice on Sunday,
but if I had the will to do whatever the
fuck that was required to do something
evil to him,
if I was willing to go to prison,
if I was willing to give up my life,
you know what some bad,
what happened to him. Right?
And it's how you stay alive. Yes,
exactly. If I lived, if I survive now,
but here's the point,
the point is
it goes back to will most people,
most normal human being people you know,
don't think like that.
But here's, but here,
if you look at every fucked up story
in this country when it comes to,
Oh my God, this guy did
something terrible, or Oh my God,
look at how fucked up this is.
You know, when it comes down to,
it comes down to somebody saying,
I don't give a fuck.
Well, somebody recognizing
what the situation actually
is and then acting. Yeah,
well, no, I mean like every panicking,
every gangster like criminal
motherfucker who's got 40 bodies on them,
you know? I mean, if you've watched,
what's the movie down in Miami,
cocaine cowboys and to dos
two was pretty amazing.
Well, you talking about
Zelda is still alive. Well,
she got smoked and Columbia in 2012 yeah,
2012 but then I just got out of
jail before, so, no, no. Yeah,
she know she was Zelda fucker.
Zelda.
She's a fucking,
oh,
but the guy that I was
impressed by was the,
the other dude that hit me now guy and
present. And it was, it was his thing was,
you know what, Eh, he's not a
tough guy. He's a fucking killer.
No, he's not trying to fight
you. You know, he, he, he'll
wait for you to go home,
fall asleep in your bed. They
don't come in your house, you know,
anyone in your fucking
house. Well, you know,
another example of the
distorted perception of people's
in vulnerability is the
iceman cook. Kuklinski yeah. That guy.
I'm still kind of curious as to how much
of his shit was real. Really. Thank you.
Bullshit it a lot. I think you had
a lot of bullshit or anything that,
that was at least my, that was the
feeling I got by his interviews.
Let's Google iceman bullshit. Nice. And
we hope we don't get any chocolate, Dale.
But no, I mean, watching Kansas
interviews. I, that was the feeling I got.
I got the feeling he was
a braggart. Really? Yeah.
Interesting. Um, nothing
on the first page. That's fair.
Ice Man. I mean, Hey, I'm,
maybe I'll completely fuck
all of bullshit. Let's
try. It's full of bullshit.
Richard Kuklinski, he's
100% full of shit. Oh,
that's the wrong eye span. That's that
guy from, uh, the gay guy who got fat.
He's not gay. I'll tell you what
though, man. You got to admit, I mean,
he some legit roles.
Okay. This is one of the guys
saying hard to beat tombstone.
He's saying Kuklinski is
dangerous and has killed,
but not to the extent that he claimed
he did not murder Gullah Gullah,
Dante Costello or de Mayo.
He claimed to have worked with de Mayo.
But apparently it's bullshit.
I don't know if apparently he
exaggerated some things might.
He's probably at fuck crazy guy.
I mean,
no, I mean, that's, yeah, I mean, I
absolutely, I don't deny that, but I,
I do get the feeling that,
and I think that happens with
a lot. Um, there are some,
if you'd go to the FBI,
I think it's fbi.gov on youtube channel.
It's like youtube, slash, FBI, whatever.
They have a series of interviews with
this asshole who was a serial killer.
Right. And, uh, he, he, they
caught him in Alaska I think,
but he killed over 10 or 10 or 15 years,
like eight or nine people,
something like that.
He ended up killing himself,
hanging himself in a jail cell and the,
but they had,
they put on Youtube,
the FBI did the fucking interviews
with him sitting in the thing.
And what's crazy to things that are
crazy is one is they're sitting here and
they're talking to this guy and they're
explaining to him why these other police
departments are being assholes about
jurisdiction and this and that and why
they're holding up certain things.
It sounds like he's buying a house and
the fucking realtors trying to explain to
him, you know, why it's taken longer
because they haven't got their clearances.
But anyway,
but this dude is,
it kind of looks like him not
being an asshole, but he's Stan,
you know, kind of long air. No,
good luck. Good looking cat.
You know, someone's going,
no. Does that him? Yes.
While it does have it you Jamie,
right.
Told you dog how each do 2012 Jamie
wasn't working for me and Joan had to tell
them, well, you're in Alaska Bro.
Did you hang yourself and go,
I've watched some. Uh, but here's what's
so freaky about this motherfucker.
He didn't know his
victims didn't stock them.
He had a murder kit hidden
and he was on the west coast.
He had property from when he was
a kid or something like that.
And a New York did his family left him
or whatever he stashed or murder kit in
New York and the murder
kit had like a tape,
a fucking gloves, uh, rope,
all this other kind of shit.
He was living on the west
coast the whole fucking time.
He flew back to New York and evidently
he had seen or or or seen some kind of
house or whatever, but he flies
back to New York, kills two people,
man in her life,
dispose of their body just mysteriously.
I then flies back. They didn't catch
him until like 10 or 15 years later.
So he did this several times.
Yes.
So his is Emma was that he
did not know that. Yeah.
He would just pick random as victims.
Had nothing
in common. How they catch him? Uh,
he, I think a chick got away from him.
Yeah,
it Alaska,
well there was one guy and I don't know
if it's the same guy in the last kid
that would a fly women out. It would
tell them that he was going to fly them,
like pay like prostitutes,
fly them out to a place where they're
going to get your freak on and a,
and then he would tell them like,
listen,
you have one hour and in one hour I'm
going to come find you and I'm going to
shoot you and kill you. Stop it.
Yeah. So good luck. Take care.
You got one hour ready go or
whatever it was the whole,
the amount of time was and he would go
hunting for women and he killed several.
Yeah. La, I'll pull it up.
What did you kill the ones that he was
like or just like random ones or what'd
he kill? The ones I keep was at after.
Oh, the ones who was after he would,
he was up on the left there. If somebody
said that to me, I would be like,
where's the nearest
fucking police station,
because you won't get me out of there.
His name is Robert Hanson and, uh,
he's an American serial killer,
is born in 1939 and he killed between
17 and 21 women near Anchorage,
Alaska.
He was convicted in 1983 and is currently
serving 461 years and spring creek
correctional centers alive
and Seward. Alaska. Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. And a 1983, 17 year old,
Cindy Paulson escaped from him while he
was trying to load her into his Piper
Super Club, which is apparently his
airplane type of jet that lands. And, uh,
he was, uh, loading her into this,
uh, airplane and she escaped. But did,
did, did. And, uh,
she told police that she had been
offered $200 to perform oral sex,
but when she got into the car dollars
in Alaska and Navia like eight beavers,
he pulled a gun on her and drove
her to his home town of Mole Dune.
And there he took her captive,
a torturing, raping and
sexually assaulting her.
He mentioned that she mentioned that
after a he chained her by the neck to a
post in the houses basement.
He took a nap on a nearby
couch and when he awoke,
he put her in his car and took her to
the Merrill Field Airport where he told
her that he intended to
take her out to his cabin,
which was a meet Shaq on the Nic River
area of a Matt to new Tsca valley
accessible only by boat or Bush plane.
That's the gangster move, right,
because they can't get out.
They can't go anywhere.
And crouched to the backseat of the car
with her risks cuffed behind her body.
She waited until Hanson was busy loading
the airplane's cockpit to make a run
for it. And while Hanson's back was
turned, she crawled out of the back seat,
opened up the driver's side door and
took off running near Sixth Avenue,
a nearby sixth avenue.
She told police that she had left her
blue sneakers on the passenger side floor.
This is a dance back seat as evidence that
she had been in the car. So, um, they,
they pulled them over and
they found it. They found her,
her, uh, her, her, you know,
they, they, uh,
pulled over the truck and found her
sneakers and knew that she was telling the
truth.
Do you know what's fucked up? If
you go back and you look, I mean,
there's a ton of stories like that,
man, I've never heard of that one.
And I generally, I mean, I'm not like
a serial killer freak or anything,
but I mean,
I pay attention to like certain things,
but I've never heard that story.
And I guarantee if you look back,
you could probably find a hundred
more like it, different things.
Maybe not that many people, but
three or four, one or two, whatever.
But it goes back to my opinion that,
you know what,
there are fucking monsters
out there, bro. Yeah.
Well this guy was an hunting champion.
I mean there,
there are fucking people out there.
They're legit monsters.
This guy was a monster. He was a monster.
He loved to kill things. He was a world.
He was a Hyundai champion.
He hits established, uh,
several documented records in the pope
and young book of world hunting records.
So this guy was like,
he was a legit hunter,
but it was not exciting enough to him.
So he had decided that, you know what?
He was in payments. Hunting women.
Yeah. He's, it's a scary, scary,
scary thing. And you look at them on
the fucker. His name is Robert Hanson.
Google it on a Wiki.
That's crazy. Cause Robert Hanson
is the same guy who was a spy for a,
so the FBI wasn't, yeah,
Robert Hansen was a spy for,
I want to say FBI counterterrorist
same. Same Dude. No good.
No. Google. Robert Hanson.
FBI. That's not the same guy.
Robert Hansen, that's the A,
I'm sure that's the FBI guy.
Robert Hanson on
Wikipedia. H a. N. S. E. N.
That's him. Creepy fuck
killed. 21 women at least.
At least 21 if they clicked them
for 21 you know it's more, yeah,
between 17 and 21 is the number
that they're there. But that's,
that's true. But then sometimes,
sometimes they lead others.
Yeah.
Right.
Because they do the shit where they
write off every unsolved on earthing,
chalk it up to them.
And we,
which a serial killer or did you ever
see that documentary? Not Documentary.
It was a docu drama. It was a, I don't
do docu dramas. I hate that shit.
It was based on the Henry Lee Lucas.
Is this a weird drifter that randomly
killed people and confess to a shitload of
crime they never got, was
it the Green River killer?
They never got Zodiac killer.
So the actually they never, we never
got the Zodiac guy. Yeah. Yeah.
They have a lot of different theories
on who that guy was from a mathematician
to, you know, various
high intellect people.
That's some creepy shit.
I mean,
what do you think the guy went to
prison when you think he's, yeah,
I don't know. They don't quit
right now. Most of them don't quit.
But who knows what makes
someone start ready go.
And who knows whether or not
they can ready stop. You know,
some people can stop
drinking and some people,
they don't need alcoholics anonymous.
Some people quit heroin. You know?
I don't know. Maybe. So I've always wanted
real killer. I've always wondered that
if you were going to do,
and it's been a fucking plot
on a million television shows,
but it's the idea that, okay, if you're
going to off somebody for whatever reason,
if you make them fourth
in a series of six, yeah.
All of a sudden now it's
not an assassination. Right.
It's a serial killing. Well,
the other thing they say
is that if it's random,
if you just pick random people who just
pull into a gas station, you know, go up,
hey, can I get a pack of gum? Boom.
There's that where it's
almost impossible to solve.
It's crazy. Like if you look at unsolved
and like certain cities like Chicago,
DC,
other things,
it's like 70% unsolved homicides.
Yeah,
because dude, I tell you
what, there's a fun Mas.
It's a phenomenal book.
You ought to read.
Did you ever watch the movie or you've
seen the wire television show? The why?
I've only seen actually the first couple
of episodes. I never kept watching it.
I know I failed culturally. Dude,
I'm telling you I'm not and I don't,
I'm not saying that to be
a breaking bad hipster.
I'm not a breaking bad type
prick. Who Back to Madison? No,
I watched the first season. Fuck off.
You didn't like it. The wires. The wire,
it gives it the six. Both
of you can suck. Suck Dick.
Because I think that game of Thrones
can conquer all of them. What?
How hard is it to where everyone dies?
It doesn't matter. How hard is that?
Everyone dies.
Dragons come back next seasons we'll give
you new people to love so we can kill
them. How about zombies? Do
you like a walking dead? Not
so much area. Not so much.
Yeah, it's decent. But what, okay,
here's your question on zombies. As long
as you're doing zombies. Loved the book,
World War Z. I thought it was fucking
amazing. Love that book. Interesting.
I thought it was kind of slow.
Really. I got it out there. Yeah.
I thought the book was to
kind of slow. No Shit. Yeah.
What'd you think about the movie?
Well,
Brad Pitt is a beautiful man and a,
he's got an excellent symmetry and uh,
his wife,
I thought it was very tastefully chosen.
I thought it was interesting that
the violence was, uh, you know,
really like,
so sort of like non impactful,
you know,
it's like the coolest thing about the
whole fucking movie literally was the
Rangers at the airplane for, you
know, that was a check. No, no,
but the one no, but where the
dude was like, hey look, fuck you.
We're going to get you to the plane.
Right. I hope it's worth it. Right.
That's legit, dude. That is legit as
is the fucking pyramid of zombies.
And they tried to cry. That was
gay. Climb up the wall of drawers.
That was fucking gay.
Have you ever
read the book? Uh, it's not violent.
28 days later was on bs.
Yeah,
that slow shambling never
ending on slot then World War z.
The book. Yeah. Yeah. That's what's
so fucking terrifying. And that's,
to me that was what made the book cool.
I disagree.
I prefer the 28 days
later sprinting Zombie.
That's my kind of Zombie new age,
French fucking Greek war
z book slash you know,
walking dead. Listen, I'll
fuck those zombies up. This
bitches are never catching.
But here's the thing, they
never get tired. Yeah, that's
true. They never give up.
But you can figure out a way to
get into a house. Shut my door,
take a nine or they never give up.
And that's all that door down.
That to me was a cool,
and don't get me wrong,
I think Max Brooks is
a self-important prick.
How dare you, I'm just telling
you first of all, how dare you.
You don't even know Max. I don't
know Max. But I've watched,
I've watched a lot of interviews with him
cause he, it Dick, in my opinion. Wow.
I could be wrong.
He might be the nicest guy in the world.
Might be tired of giving
interviews, could be, but you know,
he's Mel Brooks son till he
was rich before he started.
Also tired of people asking them about
his dad being Mel Brooks and how much of
an impact that has on his career.
And it might be fine, but hey,
if the checks were all good, I'll be nice
to you. You know who Joe Hill is? No,
he's Stephen King's son,
but he changed his name to Joe Hill,
so I didn't ride on the coattails of
Stephen King, smarmy, amazing author,
great author. Really, really good stuff.
And by the way, same genre. Stephen King,
horror movies, hard books.
Great, great, great stuff.
That's cool. I didn't know that.
Yeah, he's, he's really interesting.
One of my favorite authors and he,
Stephen King's son. It's incredible.
But he's Joe Hill, you know,
and I think he's got his own
following the smart move.
You know when your back's Brooks
Brooks, Mel Brooks, Mel Brooks Son,
Jim, Mel Brooks son. Look
at you. You have grown up.
I've known you since you were
a little boy. Oh my goodness.
Mel Brooks son is here. Honey, come here.
But like every interview I've seen when
that dude, like I'm a big book TV freak,
you know, span all that bullshit. I
watch all that stuff. 28 days later.
Zombies role. Yes. Especially
when you look at the production
of that, that movie,
how they did that 20 days
later, it's sick. They run,
they gave him like fucking,
they made that movie with like $88
and a fucking credit card. Yeah.
They just shut down in London for a day
and they got their major shot and that
was it. Yeah, that's it. Everything
else was filmed on an iPhone.
I think just fucking guys are gangster.
I think 28 days later,
zombies and this carriers, the ones
that run rage virus absolute on there.
They're freaky. But at the same time,
like a, I read a book how Steve,
not Steven Pressfield, um, I
can't think of that guy's name,
but he makes a, an interesting argument
that if you look at zombies like locusts,
imagine now millions of them.
Think about this now.
If you have a life form that I can't
believe we're getting this diva in the
fucking zombies with deep and Zam. But
think about it. Okay, New York City,
perfect example. 7 million people
in New York City right now,
they all turned a zombies.
They don't die, you know,
so they gotta go somewhere and
they're going to search out food.
The one instinct they is go to food.
Where are you gonna
go?
You're gonna go north.
We're going to go south if you can
get off the fucking island. So anyway,
so now you come south,
say they come south.
Now they come through all the east coast,
Philadelphia, Virginia, all the bullshit.
They come around the Alleghenies.
Where are they gonna go?
They're going to go west. And as they
come, they keep picking people up.
Perfect examples. You look at the locus,
the great locust plagues, you know,
do the locust starved to death?
No,
because they go to the next fucking field
to keep going. So now imagine this. Yes,
you can be the biggest bad ass in the
world with all the fucking weapons you
want,
but now you're overran with millions
of something. No matter what it is.
Imagine was millions of rats.
Fuck zombies.
But I mean millions of anything. It's
just fucked. Fuck Bro. It's scary.
Scary. That was what, that was
the cool part about Max Brooks,
his book is that he got that
across was he got across that,
that feeling of humanity,
you know, even if you,
when you almost lose
because you can kill them,
but every time you lose a person,
it's a win for the enemy. Right.
It's not the fact that you lost one.
It's the fact that you lost
one and they gained one. Right.
So you do that times 100,000 that's
a 200,000 it's like gambling.
It's a 200,000 swing.
You know,
you're down a hundred they're up a
hundred right, right, right. So, but,
but that idea of that
relentless never ending,
just constant,
you know,
to me that is a different
feeling in that fiction world.
Of course then the whole rates
not be thing. Yeah. The range.
The range thing is scarier on film because
it's like motherfuckers flipping out
at you from nowhere,
but it's that shambling never ending,
you know? Okay, you want to
kill a 5,000 of us? Okay.
Eventually your rifle barrels going to
wear out before we do kills many as you
want.
I feel like the outlaw Josey Wales with
a Gatling gun from 1865 said good to de
de de, De, De, De, de, De de digit,
digit out of the back of a wagon.
Arrows wouldn't melt,
bro.
It'd be barrels wouldn't melt or you
would just go inside and take on.
Speaking of which, speaking of which, if,
if that's not one of the best
movies ever in history of life,
I'm going to send these boys
on a Missouri a boat ride.
Joey ideas is probably
seen that movie 300 times.
Fucking Judaism will call me up.
Have you ever seen the movie
Jeremiah Johnson?
Yes.
I just turned it. I just turned
our buddy Austin on in that movie.
There's something about those, the
movies from that era, you know that were,
that was my point. Amazing. That was my
original point. The God damn man. Shit.
Look at the movies we're
talking about Jeremiah Johnson,
butch Cassidy and the Sundance
kid. I mean, when they're booking,
jump off bandit son. I mean the
band is very manly, but when,
when butch Cassidy and the Sundance kid
or brought the jump off that cliff and
they're like, can you swim?
No, it doesn't matter.
The fall's going to probably
kill you anyway. Shot.
And the end of that motherfucker,
that's probably the coolest end of
any movie when those flash dance.
I'm not flashdance Guy Bro.
But I remember butch and Sundance when
they go out of that Shell girl have a,
other than showgirls,
the only thing I remember about showgirls
is when she got the guy off through
his pants. Hmm. Interesting.
I remember this.
Why are you crazy?
The fall will probably kill you.
How fucking gangsters that,
yeah.
Redford and Newman and
they're fucking prime.
Oh,
oh
yeah.
Wow. Dude, that's got nothing on Jeremiah
Johnson. I just watched it. And the end,
there was a sequence in Jeremiah Johnson,
Robert Redford in the fucking
Rockies in Utah before he bought, uh,
the Sundance Park city thing.
And the way that movie got made was
the director, uh, what's his name?
Sydney Pollack.
I think Sydney Pollack put up his fucking
house to borrow the money to make the,
to make the movie because they ran out
of money because the locations were so
expensive.
It's a great story,
but what if he found a rich guy
and sucked his dick for the money?
It wouldn't be as good as story. It could
be possible. You know what I'm saying?
Like people make sacrifices. I don't
think you'll respect certain sacrifices,
but he's like Sydney Pollack,
Sean,
this rich guy and sucked his
dick and got $100 million.
What would depend on how good the movie
is depending on how good you think about
it,
it's now think about,
think it would depend on how good a
mood [inaudible] skills are. Tariff,
he made Jeremiah Johnson,
I'll be like, hey, fuck it.
I respect that. I respect the
commitment. If you made, I dunno,
I would be like,
he's a fool.
I hope that load was weak.
I hope it was a very like the third load
of the day to where it was just like
dust. It was just a confusing
dust to where I was like,
you know, it didn't even,
it didn't even go from hard to soft.
It was just kind of me. Yeah. You know,
just halfway there. Yeah. It
was like a fucking cookie low.
There's nothing violent or as passionate
about it. And I just like, ah, fuck,
look at that picture.
The producers like God,
it and another one frozen dudes
are scary. Yeah. Hashi Jack,
that's Hatchet Jack.
The scariest shit to me is when the show
those photographs of guys who tried to
climb Everest and failed and
they find their bodies face down.
Like the first guy that airs
mother named Everest Sisters.
Motherfuckers on Everest been
there forever and we'll be there.
The first guy to climb Mount Everest
is there. There will be there. Yeah.
That was actually,
that was actually one of my,
a little fucking, uh,
what was I saying? Uh,
what's the word I'm looking
for? Goddammit. The, uh,
examples of manhood? No.
Um, niche. Like a niche.
It's a niche or niche. No, the, a
subculture goddamn culture subculture,
which is that the Himalayan
over 8,000 meter climbers,
but I mean, frozen to the ground, they
leave them up there. There's hundreds of,
yeah, but the fucked up thing
about ever since, it's basically,
it's like Disneyland. Yeah.
It's a fucking tourist park.
You could go climb Everest next
year if you want it to. I mean, you,
you pay a guy 15 grand, you roll
up there, they give you your shit,
and if you make it, you make it. And if
not, fuck it. They send you back down.
Keep your money.
The freaky shit is fucking Kaytoo.
That's worse. K Two is like the
killer just mountain in the world.
There's an article from 2012 where
they're trying to reclaim the dead,
uh, from Everest. This is,
this is pretty interesting. Uh,
if you read what's Ed
Viesturs, v I, e. S t,
U. R. S. Edvestors.
There's like seven or eight guys who
have climbed every mountain over 8,000
meters. I, there's 14 of them,
14 mountains in the world that
are higher than 14,000 meters.
There's seven or eight guys.
You've climbed them. All.
Ed Features is an American.
He's climbed them all without oxygen.
He's climbing phrases.
It's a fucking gangster.
Some Seattle area,
but a shadow area. Seattle.
Oh, did I say West Coast?
West Coast.
I was like,
is this more soldier fortunate
time to talk West Coast Seattle.
Um,
but
do you know why? Because when you live
in Seattle, it rains all the time easily.
You have a willing to risk your life
for shit. I think it was ray near,
but he's got an interesting uh,
yeah, right there. That's him.
Okay.
What's crazy is he talks about
the, I've got, I've read that book.
That's a great book.
But what he talks about is like,
there was a couple of clients he was on
where he turned back and he got like the
first time I think he was on
Everest is Everest or k two.
He was like six or 700 meters from the
top and he turned around and he said,
you know, because you know if you
don't come down alive it doesn't count.
Right. And that's part of, that's
what gets a lot of guys killed. Right?
They just need to pull it off.
Exactly.
They get within that thousand meters
and a lot of guys will set a turnaround
times to where they have,
like if it's a drop dead time,
if you're not on the summit by two o'clock
if you're one fucking foot from it,
you'd come back
because you have to build in time for
shit to go wrong. Right. And if you don't,
you die. A lot of guys die. How many guys
have jerked off on the top of Everest?
I want to
be the first you think anybody ever
has, I dunno. I'd like to be numero uno.
15 grand. You'd give it a shot, that's
all. Yeah. What I get out of it.
You think how much you can take a phone?
What would you jack off to?
You'd be like,
you have to have to fund the next round.
What are all those bodies?
That's the line of people they ever
go up. Yes. Oh, that's ridiculous.
It's okay to say now. It is.
Exactly. That's insane. It is. This,
this thing we're looking at
is like a line at Disneyland.
It is like a line of defense is different
in the fact that there's been three.
I mean there's been a lot
of years when no one's home.
Let's k two there are 200 between
200 and 233 bodies up on Everest.
Google, k to see how many, see how
many people summited k two this year.
I'm fascinated by goals like that and
the goals of climbing all the mountains,
all the over 30,000 mountain
right now I'm, I'm, I'm,
I'm absolutely fascinated by like goals,
like these big lofty goals and only
a few people have ever achieved.
One of them is a, the you, you
know what the Super Slam is?
The Super Slam is a for big game hunters.
Yeah.
Lion.
It's an elephant.
Everything in North America,
North America, the North
American gay male animals,
the Super Slam. It's a sheep, Brown
bear, black bear. Grizzly bear,
polar bear by Brown bear,
Alaska Bear Brown bear and Grizzly
bear or the same thing, right?
Same thing. Yeah. So this, this
might have been established.
It might be that their treat
they take methylate bag.
Yes. Yes. Canada, the um,
North America Brown bear and Grizzly
bear according to Steve or on the
differences,
the grizzlies inland and the brown bears
on the coast and the ground brown bears
actually grow larger, much too
popular or much to a, the what?
Most people don't. They're all
mean as fuck rounders in general.
Brown bears just get my protein.
They're getting salmon on a regular basis.
Mass Black Bears Sandman Caribou,
Moose, they get everything. The,
the massive amounts of salmon. They get
fucking tremendous. Um, grisly polar bear.
And then with cats, it's a cougar and
they might even add Jaguar. You know,
there is a real issue off American cars.
No North America,
the fuck out of the are entering
through Mexico into north
illegal fucking cats, bro. Hey,
the illegal cast blame fucking same
roads that drug dealers, a trans,
this crisis or problem.
You know what?
There probably is fucking
strapping cocaine to these jaguars,
right in their assholes,
right in their assets.
And how much you would pay for the
coastline, Jaguar of an asshole.
It would be worth so much more than
regular coke. Wait. Yeah man, it's cold.
Came through. It came from a
drug, will talk to the dude.
Stop this cocaine came out with
Jaguars asshole. This is the Jaguar.
It's caught on a trail cam duct tape
on his ass water to gram 200 grants.
I'm real.
They're starting to find them in a,
especially in New Mexico and Arizona,
they're starting to find jaguars that
have made their way from, uh, from Mexico.
Big fucking cats.
200 plus pounds.
I don't think Jaguar's got that day.
I thought Jaguars were like house like
bobcat's and go, oh no, no, no, no.
Jaguars are enormous. They're much
bigger than mount lines. 50 pounds.
I'm outlines a fucking cougar,
bro. Yeah. Jaguars a bigger shit.
If I could have any pet on earth and not
have it kill me, it would be a cougar.
Apparently pound for pound. Jaguars are
the most powerful cats. Really. Yeah,
they're really fun. They're like
drag chute up and trees. Right.
Like kill it and drag it up in the
tree. Crocodiles, get out of here.
Do you ever see a Jaguar go after Crongo
pull up Jaguars, jaguars, Black Panther,
right.
They sometimes are black but most of the
time they are blonde with black spots.
But sometimes the spots cover their
entire body and they become black.
It was just a genetic predisposition
or a, you know, a genetic choice.
Just like some dogs are black, some dogs
are white. Yeah. That's how it is. And uh,
the black ones are the
fucking scariest shit ever.
And the jungle of the Amazon called
panthers, right. They are the same thing.
So I would have Florida Panther
cancer is a Puma is a mountain lion.
A Jaguar is a larger cat.
So fucking animal. Yeah,
they're spotted there. Spotted. But the
black ones, look at this mother fucker.
That's, that's Jaguar that said,
it's not bigger than a cougar bro.
A hundred pound cat and my friend,
that's not a cougar.
It's America's much no incorrect.
That's a 200 pound Jaguar and that Jaguar,
it's going to matches up this fucking
crock of and bites it with one punch,
one punch to the back of the head.
These mother fuckers hunt
everything that lives,
everything, anything that walks in the
ground. Occasionally this Jaguar eats,
eats everything in the Amazon.
Look at this motherfucker.
I'm making a run for this thing.
Making a run for a crocodile.
What does the crocodile do? Panics. Well,
yeah. I mean what the fuck would you do?
You don't know what would happen if you
ran out of crocodile. Nothing rocket.
I would open its mouth and eat. Thank
you. The crocodile sees this Jaguar.
I was like, Oh fuck this shit
bitch. Look at this. This jag.
Drag it out of the fucking
like eating a crocodile man.
Do you understand the
significance of this?
That's a crocodile he
killed with his face.
He doesn't even fucking live in the water
cause you imagine how strong you would
have to be. The carry something that
weighs as much as you do out of the water.
Look at the look on his face.
Look how he's biting this
thing. Biting. I'm the Cha.
Tired of your shit.
He's biting it through.
It's Shit I haven't eaten since Wednesday.
Yeah,
and they also have the ability to pull
those things apart with your face.
Look at the eyes and that motherfucker.
Cats have the most murderous, evil,
soulless eyes. That's a legit murderers,
man. They're killers. Don't kill this.
And it's in the water. This
house. Yeah. I have a sweetie,
sweetie cat that I've had for 16 years.
She just killed a bird.
The other killed a million
birds. You don't know about. Just
killed one the other day. Right on a
fucking shrine underneath the couch.
Look at this. It's a bird made out of
feathers. Biting on top of his skull.
Right. Carrying around tears up. Shit.
There's a whole series of Jaguars
like get them from the bottom.
Just rips them apart. Slowly, but sure.
It's dead already now it's a matter
of just opening it up. The g,
the Jaguar is so strong with his job.
He can a stone killers.
Have you gotten any more hunting this
year? What's Word I'm going next month.
Yeah. Yeah. We're going to a
Wisconsin, I'm going to go shoot some,
some deer hollow,
and then when I come back and a late,
late a winter, I'm going to go
shoot a buffalo in Texas. Woo.
They just stand there. We ought to
go shoot hogs brought to meet runs.
I got a guy in Texas has got a ranch.
Let's do it.
She was telling me when I can hook
it up. Okay. It's done. I mean,
it's nuisance game down there,
so it's just a matter of going down them.
We've talked about it many times.
One of my favorite shows is pig man.
Pick Dan's a show in the
sportsmans channel and uh,
him and Ted Nugent shot hogs out of
a helicopter. That would be a heat.
One time they killed two 15 a day.
The next time it was more than 400,
250 more than 400. The
loud. You want to know.
It's funny now I was talking to my buddy
gets the guy who knows a guy that in
Texas, he's like, yeah man, we've
been talking about it forever.
We're going to take like 50 pounds
of Tannerite. What's Tannerite.
That sounds bad. You know, a Tannerite
is showing what tannerite is.
Google Tanner writer, check this out.
Jesus Christ. So this is the, uh,
what we were talking about. This is the
finished the Super Slam. These are the,
these are the animals, Alaskan brown bear,
black bear, grizzly bear, polar bear,
Cougar, Columbia blacktail deer.
That's like $100,000 with a hunt.
More than that. Cuzdey or mule deer, Sitka
deer, whitetail deer, rocky mountain,
elk grove, my God. Stop Chill Elk.
Way more barren ground Caribou,
central Canadian barren ground,
Caribou, mountain Caribou,
Quebec, Labrador, Caribou,
woodland Caribou, Alaska,
Yukon Moose, Canadian,
Moose and Caribou to get bison Musk ox.
A Musk ox is in north American
game. Animal style. Now
I've heard everything. Uh,
American mountain goat,
pronghorn and obvious outfitters or
making this California big sheep. Dall,
sheep desert, big horn sheep, rocky
mountain bighorn sheep. Don't cheap.
I'll Atlantic Walrus. These
are the auxiliary stop. Celia,
Larry Animals,
auxiliary auxiliary.
They get the Jaguars in there and
Pacific Walrus. That's all of them.
Know who the fuck is going to shoot a
walrus. And here's where I draw the line.
Who needs to share? Here's where
I draw a line, man. I, I'm not,
I did hunting.
That's fine.
I'm not a hunter because I don't have the
patience for it. Um, but I respect it.
I understand that hunters pay for their
whole hunters are the whole fucking
reason most of this shit. What
is this, right? Yes. Temperature.
She walks right Tanner, right? This
is like, it's in a Bacardi bottle.
Billy Express. Okay. And so I'm assuming
it's an explosive. Yes, it is. Okay.
So this guy backs way up.
Yes.
And detonates it Tannerite is a binary
explosive to where you put these two
things together and then it's detonated.
It has to be,
the only way it can be set off is by sea.
It's completely fucking legal.
You can buy it in the mail,
but it's a binary explosive. And the
fact that the only way it can be set,
you can set fire to it.
You can sell electricity to it.
You can fucking jump up and down on it.
The only way that we'll get set off is
if it's penetrated by around going almost
300 feet per second.
So you have to hit it with a rifle
round and that will set it off.
But otherwise it's completely,
absolutely,
it's illegal just because
people don't know about it.
Like there was a psychedelic,
sorta most powerful psychedelic drug
ever that was legal for the longest time.
Really missed it.
And the sweeping sites that like some
shit out of a human pituitary gland from a
fucking mail baby with
one eye. Similar, but no,
it's called five methodoxy die
methyl trip to me and five methoxy
dimethyltryptamine five meo dynamic felt
like a big stash of that Preben shit
somewhere
you to meet if you want to meet,
I can bring into Oden's chambers if
you truly want to meet him. Um, yeah,
still doing that. Oh yeah, I got one of
my basement. Yeah. Yeah. Well I'll try it.
Fuck No. That scare the shit. I be
scared. Oh, I'm telling you bro.
Now this tank's doesn't slavery.
The tank is easy to faith.
It's great on your body. Feels
good. It's relaxing. That's,
you're into this whole fucking
self, you know, I know better.
No better
have
no desire to get up in that
fucking mess. Well, um, the, uh,
the tank thing for me that's a big part
of like every day is a big part of life.
No Shit. Big Part of thinking. Yeah.
The tank is where I sorted. Right.
Sorted it all out. How often do you use
it? What's in my basement? So, well,
I've got a lot of shit in my
fucking within arms reach.
Last time I used it was two
days ago. Yeah. That's great.
How long do you use it for? A few hours.
I like to go on fat loss that time.
The time to were freaked out. If
you ever been like, fuck this. Fuck,
how do I get out? No, no, no.
Every freak out that I've ever had has
been a good one. I've learned from them.
Every freak out that I've ever had, I'd
be like, well, what was bothering me?
What was the free, why was I freaking
out? Yeah. What was the freak out about?
What weakness was, you know,
was exposed by that freak out.
What a in balance with what
thing that I don't like.
I mean were you're able to do
that in the tank or, yeah. Yeah.
You got a little carried away
and then you backed off or what?
It's all about breathing and perspective.
It's all about keeping your breathing
under control. Don't let panic breaths.
Like the big thing about psychedelic
trips that happened with a lot of people,
whether they're naturally occurring
psychedelic trips, like a tank, meditation
or drugs.
The big thing is you trying to control
what's happening and when you try to
control what's happening, it's just
you can't control a bitch. Good luck.
It's like going down a river, you
know, like some crazy fucking,
what is that airplane? Is that an
airplane vacuum? Why this awhile?
What do they vacuum? I think
it's an airplane with a
vacuum on it and I say, Bro,
you're, if you're going down a
river and you know your, your,
your body's flailing and flailing around
like, and you try to like control it,
you can't control it.
You know,
if you're bouncing off rocks and shit
and you're completely out of control in
the white waters,
you can't control it.
The difference between that
and a psychedelic trip is
it the psychedelic trip is
actually not going to kill you.
Whereas the the out of control feeling
that you have in a river, there's,
it's inevitable. Like you, you,
you may get lucky and grab
a branch on the way down,
but you may also go off the
waterfall and die. Sure.
The difference between that and
the psychedelic experiences,
there's nothing to worry about
and the psychedelic experience,
but it's just as much out of your control
so you have to be able to let go and
it's very, very, very, very,
very hard for people to do because you
have to let go of all your perceptions
about who you are,
how you interface with the world,
what your environment means to you.
The, the, the, the, the, the,
the, the circle. I mean, you know,
all this shit going in though,
right?
I learned all this shit going in
and I still don't know I could,
I could freak out. Well, what happened
if you just stuck someone in there
like you stuck someone in there.
It depends entirely on who that person,
if they weren't prepared,
if they just,
it's like if you fucking
threw a hood on them. Yeah,
if you just threw a fucking hold on him,
snatched him off the street and they
woke up in the tank, the tank is,
well that would be weird.
That'd be like torture.
Well no, it wouldn't be tortured
cause you would move around.
You would feel the water. You, you can't,
it's not like your body doesn't move.
The beautiful thing about this,
the
tank is basically, you've got
your own Guantanamo Bay in
your basement. No, no, no.
That's way nicer than that.
It's, there's no music blaring.
No fucking dogs.
Crazy ass holes.
And trying to fucking get you to talk
about your time as a student in Pakistan.
There's none of that. The, the,
the tank zero, dark 30. Yes. Yeah,
I know you didn't like it because you're,
you know,
you're up on what all the hell that shit
you're fucked up by this suspension of
disbelief, you know. But I gotta tell Ya,
the dude who was doing the
questioning was freaky. He was scary.
He was scary because he was so
calm. Yeah. Well that's really,
look how those guys get.
They get very clinical.
It was I looking at you lie
to me, I'm going to hurt
you. Yeah. And then with the,
with the fucking,
something else I heard that I had never
heard before was they were sticking them.
My thing, dude, bugs, bugs.
Even worse fucking spiders.
Yeah. I mean, you know,
I'll fight Ya. Okay, fine.
But you put a fucking big
ass spider right here.
I'll scream like a bitch or I'll flip
this fucking table trying to kill it.
One or the other. But fucking
spiders. I hate spiders.
But that was one of the things,
I guess they played on the phobia as a
motherfuckers was they would stick them
in these fucking boxes filled with all
kinds of bugs and fear factor. Yeah,
exactly. Exactly. That was one of the
reasons why I never watched fear factor.
Seriously. The bugs and the spiders
and the bullshit. And I always thought,
you know, like eating, you know, donkey
balls and all that bullshit. I was like,
I never could understand it because
it's like, what did they win 50 grand?
If they win, you have to make
it to the final. So sweet.
I looked back then and then they play
and then they play fucking taxes on it.
So they make what? 33 34
yeah, 34 thousands. Um,
fuck you.
But that's not even fair brow.
Some people did it and they did it as
nice in fair. Let me tell you something.
I guess I'm watching that. I eat one
of those for free. Stop it. Yeah,
me and Michael. Yo, there was
a TV show. It was one of those,
what was that like that? Well, Michael
Yoh was one that was a, um, uh,
African cave dwelling spider and he,
me and Michael,
we were doing a promo for the new series
of fear factor when it came back. And,
uh, we both, uh, ate them. It
was nothing. I ate it, it was
nothing. It was just chewy.
It was nothing.
Believe me,
if you gave me the option between that
and a ton of other shit that I've done in
my life,
I would take that all day.
I need to have right in front of you right
now. It's nothing. It's like a logical,
it is psychologic and that's what's crazy.
It's just like it's all psychological.
Yeah, totally. I agree. I
don't give a fuck though. The
well, that's like the tank.
What's scary about the idea of
the tank is only psychological.
There's no tigers in there.
There's a Jaguar tank.
Doesn't seem like it would
freak me the fuck out. Well,
you just said it would. No,
no,
I was saying it.
It could like if you took somebody and
through the metal know personally me. No,
I don't think it would. It's great.
You would love it. Personally,
I don't think it would. I
mean for one thing it's like
I like being by myself. No,
no, don't get me wrong. But I like,
I spend a lot of time reading.
I'm not one of those people that,
you know,
if I don't have inner social interaction
every hour, I flipped the fuck out.
You know, I mean me and Michael Yo where
eating these k kicked willing spiders.
Michael. Yeah. Michael. Yeah, he's uh,
he's like an entertainment journalist
and he was actually on fear factor back
way back in the day. Like episode one,
the first shows I just pick it up,
pick it up and then might
in some blue cheese.
That's the thing I got so used to
like people eating bugs and I got cha,
I eat a bunch of shit. I eat a fucking
Matt just on the set and you're like,
just saw a roach and you were like, no,
no, like an Asian girl. Just pick it up.
I'm not stupid. They had catering.
They had really no need to do it.
But it wasn't that it was something
I wanted to do, but it's easy to do.
It's really not that big a deal. So I
give it to him. I'm holding onto too.
I hand him one and he had the hardest
time grabbing it, man. He was,
I don't know if he was
playing it up for the camera,
but he really seemed to have
a heart. Very, very nice guy.
But you know what the thing is though, I
was so desensitized. I was so used to it.
Yeah. This doesn't even
interest me. Jesus.
Yeah,
I would telling him do it.
Can, oh, spiders bite. Oh yeah. Get the
fuck Outta here. What does this nun,
who the fuck's filming this on us? Camera
phones. I don't know. Some of the phone.
I told him if we lived in caveman times,
just that's being,
I'm, I'm going to say I hope I would. I
would hope I'm not that big of a bitch.
I would hope I would reach out. Crush
your hand, kill the spider and walk away.
It's nothing. You would just take it.
You just take it. You, you'd have,
it would have to be minimum.
We'd have to be talking new car. Money
for free. Well that's cause you're crazy.
No, I'm not looking at you. He evidently
didn't enjoy it. I just eaten it.
That's him. That's him. I'm sorry.
He's freaking out while Joe's over there
like popcorn, like apps more. My bad.
Yeah. I'm like, well no. For
me to do some shit like that.
We're talking minimum 30 Jesus had
a diet coke waiting on standby.
Minimum Minimum 30,000 you
the fucking spiders. Nothing.
It's not even worth 100 bucks. Yeah. Whoa.
Easy to just what I'm saying. I mean,
you know,
my price is my price,
but I'm just saying that it's all based
on personal. Sure. Absolutely. You know,
if you ever had someone choke you
choke you like almost unconscious.
We have to tap out. No, that's way worse.
I believe I have that happen all the time.
I've done that to people but never got
me a bug is it ain't shit. You know?
Oh, a young gal give you enthusiastic
but yet horrible blowjob. Yes.
That's no fun. It's way better to
eat a bug. Disagree. Check out these.
He's can't grow. Jobs are like
pizza. You know there's bad pizza,
but need to get someone to suck your Dick.
That really has malice in their mind.
Share these Kangaroos.
Beating the fuck out of each other.
This is a video that someone sent me.
Apparently this ends with a
rear naked choke people. Yeah.
People didn't send it to me all
day on Twitter. So out of respect,
I got to throw it up there.
But sweat how these fucking things fight.
They go back on their tail,
they use their tail to hold themselves
up to kick kick with their back legs and
they fucking do get out for like 10
minutes. Man. Do they take round breaks?
No, they just keep fucking
each other up. Look at that.
That's like a fucking 120 pound rat.
Yeah.
Well they get really big apparently.
Apparently it's two
different types of Kangaroos.
I think there's a gray
kangaroo and a red kangaroo.
Our Buddy Eddie if spends a lot of time
and arch Barker's team spends all the
time as well in Australia and
some of them are really big,
like six feet plus. Well
there's another, uh,
I guess donkeys in Australia are feral.
Like pigs are here.
I guess I have a lot of trouble with,
at least they did at time with
donkeys and Kangaroos. Wow.
So there's a guy, his name's Jd
Jones. This is a gun thing, but um,
he's known for a handgun hunter.
He's one of the bigger handgun hunters.
He made a bunch of custom calibers
and all kinds of shit. But anyway,
he used to organize what's called
a Australia environment hunt.
Look at this fucking scramble and these
guys would go down and Doris please this,
this one. Kangaroos on top. Keeps
winning. Go Guard. Pull guard,
pull guard, Bro. It's the blonde,
the bonds of bitch. Oh Shit.
He's got this book and he's got the
hugs. The chuck. No hooks. He's gone.
Marcella Garcia style
concentrated firesides. I joke.
Well Marcello concentrates
in Thailand and shit.
He doesn't even worry about the hooks
is like, dude, I'll watch my UFC shows.
Incredible. This is
incredible. This is a battle.
Okay,
stop. This is crazy, right?
It's got a good grip.
It looks like he's got a gable
grip. Wow. He put them to sleep.
Tapped him. Fuck you. He just tapped him.
He let him go and he's just like hovering
with his balls over that Kangaroos
face. Wake up and go buy me a
Starbucks is asleep. He choked up.
Motherfucker to sleep. Correct.
Not a choked him to death.
Wake up and wants me to fuck your wife.
Let's see if he wakes up.
He doesn't have a wife fitting.
Get married, Kangaroos, whatever.
The kangaroos on the bottom,
licking his balls. See,
they looked up and he saw his balls.
Kangaroo still pass the fuck out.
Look over on the left. Well he,
he just laying there. He's uh,
he's submissive and this one's walking
away nice and slowly on his tail.
He's hurt. That tail is legit. Yeah.
Well I think they duked
it out for a long part of,
for a long period of time before he
eventually got the rear naked choke.
So the big ones, um, that are
the red kangaroos and the,
the Red Kangaroos is the
largest of all kangaroos.
The largest mammal to live in Australia
and the largest angle marsupial.
And it's found in mainland
Australia avoiding only the
more fertile areas in the
south east coast and the northern
rain forest. They're like, fuck you.
We don't want your water. We don't want
your fertility. The biggest they get, um,
head to body length is 5.2 feet and
then the tail and the legs and all that
jazz.
So would win the apparently getting
toward chimpanzees or a kangaroo in one
champ would kill everything. One
chimp. Yeah, they're ruthless.
Chimps are so God damn strong.
I mean I'm sure Kangaroos are strong too,
but I'm sure at shampoo just fucking
grab its neck and tearing shit apart.
Rip Its belly open.
Shims can do shit with their bodies
where they grab a branch and then launch
themselves into the why.
Bang on that kind of strength is really
hard for us to even wrap our fucking
stupid heads around. Right. You know, how
many chips can you think you can do? Me?
Yeah.
I probably couldn't do one for $1 million.
A guy who's a really good chin up guy.
Gangster 50 what is,
yeah,
50 is just the crazy mother be like,
I got to believe like,
or there's like some,
you know,
ripped up crossfit chicks on there and
it does it every day before breakfast and
a good kid. World Record
Chin ups. Let's find out.
I'm guessing.
I'm guessing it's 70 5:00 AM I the
only one that thinks crossfits a cult.
It is a call. You're
not the only one. It is,
and there's good things and bad
things about cults. All right.
A world record list. What is
the world record? Two. Two,
two, two, two. What is that?
A raccoon. Oh Shit.
Okay. The fuck is that?
Yeah, it's erection. Okay. Here's the
here. They're circling this motherfucker.
You're dead world records.
He's punching it like,
fuck you. Fuck you. Take that Jab. Is that
a champion or a raccoon? I don't. Yeah.
That's not even a big chance yet.
Look at it.
I saw you fuck all my car last night. What
happened? That raccoon got into the uh,
yeah. Oh look. That's a miss dude and
coons are tough, man. Raccoons are tough.
Champs or fucking or not like, oh,
he's throwing, throw thought. Oh Shit.
They're ruthless.
They threw it off the top of a cluck.
You let me throw you off this mountain.
Yeah, they're ruthless. All right,
here's the, they have most
chin ups in a minute. Okay.
Here's the world records
for Chin ups the most, uh,
the record holder is a guy from the Czech
Republic. Of course, ready for this,
or you're going to freak out.
232 pullups in 36 minutes.
That's insane.
In 2010.
Okay.
And the Czech Republic,
Jesus fucking Christ.
Have you ever seen kipping
pull ups but whatever.
Have you ever seen the bartenders shit?
The guys who do the Barre workouts look,
yeah, I have seen that. It's always black
guys. Look at that. Look at the Chin ups.
Motherfuckers up though.
This isn't say kipping Chin ups pull ups.
What does it pull it? Chin up is
when your palms are facing forward.
It's none of those count. Jesus Christ.
Those are insane. None of those kinds.
This guy's still going.
None of those kind of look,
he doesn't even barely break his elbows.
Well this is called his fucking head.
Barely touch the bars.
The bar crazy.
He's you're kipping chin
ups or kipping pull ups.
I guess it's a pull up comments. Which
ones a chin up and which one's a pull up?
Pull up is like this, right pull
is your palms forward, Chin ups.
Is your palms outward, is that right?
Is that it was one or the other.
What's the difference between true
Wikipedia son? What's the difference?
That difference.
Okay,
I'm going to guess. Chin ups are
probably the curl motion. Right. And uh,
and pull up and pull ups are
probably palms out. Okay.
We're going to find out really quickly.
I don't know because I do all,
all look at this shit. I do all of them
cause I'm sexy as fuck. I would love,
I would love to be able to do this.
That's a sane, just be fucking fat.
Just to see the look on people's faces.
I when millions,
he's doing sideways ups on a bar where
his body is sticking out like a flag.
He's rushing. That's insane. Okay.
Pullups means a proteinated overhand grip.
So pull ups,
his palms out, Chin ups, his palms,
which is a soup unaided or
underhanded grip. That's crazy.
I've never seen it before.
That's very interesting.
Was this guy's going to do 62 in
a minute and he's 50, he's 50. Oh,
dairy. Who is this fucking
animal? You don't have low t.
His wife doesn't want to fuck them.
That's all that is.
It's trying to like a truck. He's got
a string of 19 year olds. Two, three,
four, five, six those are legit. Yeah,
those are wide grip.
10 1112 okay.
We can keep counting and the people at
home listening on iTunes or [inaudible],
you're going to count to 100 you fuckhead.
You're not even describing
what's happening from 50
to 63 skip them pretty is.
It is pretty amazing. 63 that's
incredible. Who's The guy?
What's his story in a minute? He likes
palsy. Can't get any world records.
Chin ups. Just say who it is. Does it say
Stan apps that cough. Spell it. A p.
S. E. L. O. F. F. I guarantee.
I guarantee you he has Ohio.
That just goes to show you
man, Ohio. Ohio is legit. Yeah.
I always liked the Philippines
of the United States.
Is it really what way and pool?
That was nasty.
He's all of that was always nasty things.
Said Ohio is the Philippines
of the United States.
If they're from Ohio and they've
got it on a white tee shirt,
they will gamble with you.
What is it about that?
The Midwest,
I have so many gangster pool players
because there's nothing else to do.
Seriously. You don't got to work.
What are you going to surf? Right.
You know you gonna play volleyball,
right? I mean fuck half the year's winner.
So good luck trying to get
lights on. Right? Exactly.
So you go to the pool room,
you play pool and there's
the Midwest is full of them.
There's gangsters throughout Kansas City,
Missouri, Saint Louis, Shit like that.
Fucking players. Why did they
pick? Could take bar table though.
Cause that's all they got. What's
that about? That's a lot of it fixed.
Well that's one of the tournaments are,
but you could take some of those guys.
Like I could go down through that part
of the Midwest and take some people and
run them up through New York City and
just robbed the fucking northeast. Yes.
When I say rob, it would be hard because
you can't sneak up on anyone anymore.
Right?
You can't outrun the Internet.
I mean camera phones or
camera phones ruin the road.
Isn't that an interesting will the,
the websites they'll like ac billiards
did to a certain extent to too.
It's not, but even before that, it's
just, I guarantee you could show,
you can take me to a pool room here in
la today and there could be somebody in
there and if it's a legitimate player,
I could, if I don't know who they are,
I could take their picture,
send it to two or three
people and probably take it
everything there is to know
about that within 10 minutes.
And that's without going to the Internet.
That's just within that network and
having the ability to take a photo and
connect and tell them,
here's what this guy looks like.
This is a game he wants to play. What
do you know about them? And you know,
it's just,
it's such a small world.
It would be like you showing like a
fighter that you knew was like a legit
fighter. Well, just like when I,
when I did that celebrity pool
thing for Bravo and they were like,
you know, hey, you know,
we're going to put together a
celebrity tournament and uh,
we'll see, you know, like who can beat
who out of the world of celebrities?
Like good luck. You're all playing for
second place. Sure. Absolutely. I'm like,
I know you're all playing for second
place. And they were like laughing at me.
Like, how do you think you're going to
win? I'm like, I'm gonna win. I'm like,
not only going to win, it's going to
be easy. I'm going to show up high,
I'm going to be highest two cookies.
I'm like,
there's no way they put in the
time of effort that I put in.
He just know very few celebrities.
If they were as fucked up as I am,
I would know about them.
No, no. I wasn't here.
The only people I've ever heard Paul
Sorvino, which I think he's dead now.
Jerry Orbach Sorvino or past
right or bucket Jerry Orbach.
Paul Sorvino, uh, David, uh,
Brennan. What's his name?
David Brenner. Brenner. Was he a
player or was he just an investor?
He's an investor.
This is me running out like a
fucking world champion right here,
ladies and gentlemen with Max.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That was, yeah,
me and Max.
I believe when I was taking us,
I took a lot of lessons from Max Everly.
Powerful Max. Yeah. Max Happily went,
that was back in his Vegan. I was
responsible for getting them off that.
See me now? Yeah. He eats
everything now. Beautiful.
He started eating fish. He started
off with Sushi. How it starts. Yeah.
It's how we all start.
But Max changed my fundamentals and
people think that pool was like a stupid
game and it is kind of a
stupid came. It's, it's, it's,
I'm, I'm telling you stupid.
If you're not a, uh, if you're not
a player, I mean, if you're not,
and I tell people this, it's like
I do it for a living man. I mean,
that's what I sell for a living is pool.
But if you're not into it,
if you don't understand it, you know,
it's like me trying to watch golf.
I don't play golf is a video
of you and me plan? Yes.
Somebody who ran the fuck out.
You ran out. Yeah, there's a,
yeah, I think it's just the best
video is you do on the Earl though.
Me laughing like a fucking
retard over top of you.
I was nervous when I met him that
he was going to be mad at me,
but he wasn't mad at me at all. He
was a, he was. That was easy. Yeah.
I mean arose.
I was a fan.
Mosconi Cup is in Vegas this year.
When is they make it? When is it?
It's the first weekend in December.
Let me see right now. Hold on a second.
Are you broadcasting? No,
we're doing well. Actually
I can't spill any beans yet.
We're trying. We're trying to,
we're trying to do something
before Moscone starts.
I'm open that week, man. Maybe we
should do something. It starts moaning.
Mosconi Cup starts Monday. That'll be fun.
Yeah. I would like to be there for that.
I think that'd be fun. It's fun if you've
never been to one. They are a blast.
I mean we could do something because it's
because it's like big money production.
Yeah.
It's like the only legit real
television production in pool.
We could do something with pool man.
We can pull needs something.
It needs something right now. Needs
a little, a little juice, you know,
I'll no ship. If you and
I got behind something, we
could do something right now.
We can make something fun.
I think the only thing that has any shot
to get mainstream acceptance of pool
naked girls is that,
or some kind of reality show or just a
character study to where you like you
picked the most fucked up.
Follow around for six months.
People would watch. I would watch
that. Yeah. Well Earl is you,
like you said earlier, seven miles in the
morning, seven o'clock in the afternoon.
14 miles a day.
He's a maniac.
He probably stabbed you in the eye times
before the filming is over, but Nah,
he wouldn't ever stop me.
Me and her would get along
would be awesome if you could.
If you could do something to where like
you and Earl went on the road. Yeah.
Oh my God.
I mean row like when we were hanging
out together talking like there was,
even though I'd made fun of him,
I know he got bummed out that I made fun
of them, but I only made fun of them.
I do an impression because I'm a huge fan.
Right.
Email could you add impression was
if you didn't know him, right? Yeah.
So he knew that like when
I started talking to him
that I wasn't an asshole and
then I, you know, I really said, I go,
you're one of my favorite players
of all time and that's a 100% legit.
He w he and I wouldn't have a problem. He
would be crazy. But I'm pretty easy man.
You know? I know crazy. It's
if someone was like, if like
you a guy like you, yeah.
All of a sudden became crazy. Sure.
I'd be bummed out. I'd be like, damn,
what the fuck happened him?
Why do you go to stupid? Yeah.
But if it's just a crazy dude being crazy,
that's like asking water and not be
wet, you know, it's like water is wet.
It is, it is. What it is. Oh, here it is.
Are going to play pool if
you're not properly equipped.
Where's your 80% people
quotes all the time.
Everywhere I go,
what are you doing?
It might be it my grace impression of
all time and it's super obscure this.
Most people don't know
where else strict on jump.
Tusaro jump to jump with a fucking junkie.
That ain't what the fuck is nice.
He's got a tiny little shoes.
Y'all pleased as punch.
He's got a big smile on your face like
you just did something. Get the fuck dad.
Jump with a full table with a Meucci.
Don't understand.
After this,
after this you have to Google
Earl Strickland ranch. Oh really?
Sounds like when the marijuana,
I said a lot of my plans was marijuana.
Earl got all paranoid. How's you
know I do marijuana even said that.
How's he know training?
He was saying marijuana.
Did you tell him I smoke marijuana?
Well you guys talking about marijuana.
Is it commonly known?
Earl smokes all the weed. Well, Mad Max,
I believe,
told me and rob cy as told me,
you know that the of their adventures
together, the Earl Strip. Well look,
a guy who's that good at pool.
Why would he not fuck with marijuana?
Marijuana makes if people who don't know,
I know you don't like rock with it.
It makes you very sensitive to movement.
But the thing is he,
that's probably the only thing he can
do to keep his mind and this fucking
atmosphere. Yeah, there's
a little bit, man,
he's Earl is people genius.
He's,
he says you cannot subpool genius.
You can't take it away from him.
He's a pool genius and like many people
that are genius at something, the,
as we said before,
that genius comes out of a,
a bit of madness and look at him.
He's all pissed off.
Well the Mosconi Cup is really interesting
because it's like the UK or Europe
versus the United States. All
this is, that still blows up.
I'll look at it as she's
pretty, yeah, she is cool.
An Earl gets crazy.
Can I box out of everybody?
He also puts weird shit on, like look at
it, look at the eyes, look at the eyes.
They're all laughing.
He's so serious. He's like a character
and character. He's a man. That shit man.
He's like a comedian. But I mean he's
serious about it. Yeah. It's like,
that's one of the things I was talking
to Jason Shaw about when he came down for
our last match. Uh, you
know, he said it amazed him.
He stayed with her at all and he goes,
Earl woke up in the morning talking
about pool and when he went to sleep at
night, he was still talking about pool.
Yeah, he's Legit, you know. I mean,
think about it. I mean, you don't,
whenever we hang out it's like
you don't talk about it. Yeah.
You don't talk about UFC from the time
we started at the time we end. No,
you won't talk about comedy from the
time we start to tell them we in. Yeah.
You know, it's every hang out
like a normal fucking person.
Well that's the thing about pool though.
Pool requires that of you.
Pool is like the craziest needy.
His girlfriend in the history of the
universe at a high level, it's sick.
The bitch wants to see you all day every
day you go to bed and then when you
wake up, where are you?
Right here, right me,
wake up right and pool might wake you
up in the middle of the night with a new
move. Pull my weight. You
don't have to get out that way.
You know you play it like this.
Then you play for the fourth ball.
You're playing for the third row. If you
play for the ankle on the fourth ball,
then the,
if you look the fifth balls on the rail,
if the fifth Paul's on the round, you
know, it depends on what I've seen.
I've seen her.
I'll do that after matches.
He'll come in the next day and set it
up and talk and talk about his shot.
That was in like the seventh game and
it's like, yeah, it's like you go here.
If I remember it was meaningless.
Yeah.
It would be like a football player
talking about a fucking play that got two
yards and the second quarter with
20 minutes to go. I mean it's,
it's like something that means nothing
and he talks about it like as a
disastrous date that he just got home
from right. Yeah. It's, I dunno man,
those guys.
And what's funny is
most the players in the world
have played for us on our,
on our matches.
Um,
you can't name a pool player
that's hasn't played for us.
It's not top of the world.
Top 10,
20 players in the world have all played
in our matches at one time or another.
And for the most part,
the Americans are the craziest in general,
like most mental about shit.
Um,
the Filipinos are the most laid back,
which is funny because they play
like the Filipinos literally,
if they win $1,000 here,
it's like five or six grand back home.
It's a huge amount of money.
And maybe that's why they are laid back
is because of whatever score they make
here they is bigger back home.
Whereas here,
if an American player wins
three or four grand, you know,
if you tell any normal human being on
earth that works for 15 or $20 an hour,
you can make $3,000 in a weekend. There
would be like fuck that's good money.
But you know for someone who
is at the top of their game,
yeah it sucks and you would
think they would make more.
It sucks for a pro athlete and I split
at the same time it comes and this is
like, this is one of the battles I'm
fighting is I tell people like, look man,
if I could pay you guys 10 grand I would
cause it makes everybody better but I
can only pay you what people will pay.
You know,
cause I eat what I kill.
I mean the way I do it is I've,
there's no sponsors.
There was nobody here giving me
five or $10,000 to do a match.
It doesn't work like that.
It's Manny Pacquiao.
What I take in on fucking paper view
is what pays for all the freight. Dude.
That's the big pay per view.
Me Versus Manny Pacquiao.
That would be sick. Come on.
So I think you'd be rob. I'd be
robbed. He would rob me. Damn.
From what I understand, I have to
get in stroke. I have to get crazy.
And you just have to outbox him. Yeah.
Well according to Max Aberly Max,
everybody says he plays it very good.
Yeah.
Max Planning to race a 10
and he only beat him like,
I think he beat him six
or seven to 10 right.
Which if you know how good Max plays
Max's mother fucking world class.
But Amy's got a great reputation as
a solid player. Yeah. He said, man,
he gets out and being
from the Philippines,
it's like it plays all those killers
every day. They call him the cow.
Oh look at Max with the
long hair and and go, wow,
this is a Manny Pacquiao.
If for first shot is not listening
or listening and not watching,
rather this is Manny Pacquiao,
shooting some kind of crazy trick shot,
which I don't know how to do one
single looking at many packer.
I was a lefty too. That's interesting.
That's worth a ball right there. Yeah.
There's something about lefties,
man, there's fucking shot.
Dang man. He made it.
I made all those balls.
There's something about lefthanded people.
This is an athletically lefthanded
athletically. I believe that.
I've seen pictures, quarterbacks. It's
crazy. Yeah. I don't know what it is.
I think it's a nonconformity thing.
I think that lefthanded people have to
figure things out for themselves and it
makes you smarter because
everybody else is going one way.
You have everything else in the world is
fucking opposite and from striking from
a standpoint of striking,
a lot of people have a hard time with
people that fight in the south pole
position with his right hand
forward instead of left.
Isn't that a big thing in boxing though?
People who go, you switch. The good guys,
the greatest ever at switching
is Marvin Hagler. Marvelous.
Marvin Hagler was like,
he would fuck guys up because you expect
them to come out south and he would
come out Orthodox and just put a beat on
you because he could fight Orthodox as
good as he could. Fight
southpaw cause that very rare
to, hey, very rare. So do you,
what's the deal?
Do you still think boxing is viable sport
or is it just so fucking corrupt and
fucked up that no,
it's viable.
Viable because there's awesome guys
there that are excellent at it.
You know there's like a lot of people
like think that I don't like boxing
because I got in an argument with some
asshole on ESPN who was a boxing promoter
and you know, I shouldn't call him an
asshole. He's just defending his turf.
And the whole reason why we even had this
thing is cause ESPN was trying to set
up this dispute between boxing and MMA.
Which one's better?
And I was cool with it all
until he was calling MMA like,
like human cock fighting.
Like they have this attitude that it's
like some barbaric sport and I'm like,
look, you're being stupid. Like you
don't think it was 15 years ago.
Well it's not only that,
it's like boxing is a part of MMA.
It's a key aspect of MMA. You don't have
good boxing, you can't have them in that.
It's like, but MMA, if you like,
you get a boxer who's a really good
boxer and that's all he trains his boxing
and he gets in there with a guy who
was an MMA fighter. He's fucked up.
He's going to get his legs kicked.
It's going to get kneed in
the body and the clinch,
he's going to get taken down a mountain.
He's going to get smashed as strangled.
That's just a fact.
It doesn't mean that boxing is an
exciting and that I don't lock box,
that I don't like boxing.
I would've never said what I said.
If that guy was in a deck,
if that guy got on that ESPN
interview with me and if he said that,
I think mixed martial arts is a
very exciting sport for some folks.
They though they prefer just striking.
I would've said absolutely. You know,
there's something for everybody,
some people for, for soccer.
So I'm guys like baseball. You know,
I, I, I'm a huge fan of striking.
Striking is what I started out with.
But boxing striking is even like
if I was going to watch any fight,
legit straight striking fight. I want to
watch more Thai. Have you seen a glory?
Glory is a, it's, it's debuting
on a spike actually tomorrow,
tonight or tomorrow. What's that?
The 11th I think it's tomorrow.
Whatever the fuck it is.
Glory is this new high level kickboxing
event where they're taking the best
kickboxers in the world. Most of them
are European because like in Holland,
kickboxing got fucking gigantic.
It's huge.
And his great fighters came from Han
like Ramon Dekkers above Ernesto hoost.
Rob came in like some of the
greatest kickboxers of all time,
all came from Holland
for some strange reason.
And then there's also this great guys
that fight in all sorts of Delhi.
Romania has a lot of great
fighters like Daniel Gita.
There's a lot of great and there's a lot
of great American kickboxers that are
coming up right now too. But when it
comes to like pound for pound excitement,
kickboxing is way more exciting
than regular boxing to me. Sure has.
His leg kicks and knees and head kicks.
There's a lot of craziness.
Now you're talking about because you
were a traditional martial arts guy,
so taekwondo when I first started,
when you first started, but um,
so now are those like tournaments,
those sports obsolete,
are they hurting for talent because
everyone's going to MMA is money?
Well they also, they're going the,
the big thing about martial arts,
when I was a kid,
when I was first starting out and
I had to choose a martial art,
it was always a very difficult to figure
out what was the best martial art.
And you had to kind of
decide for yourself.
You got to watch people
and decide for yourself.
And it was really hard to quantify.
It was really hard to figure
out what was the best.
Then the ultimate fighting championship
came along and now there's no question,
now we know what you need in an all out
fight and a mixed martial arts fight
where essentially there's
a limited set of rules.
We know what you need to learn how to
do and it's not taekwondo and it's not
Moitai and it's not wrestling and
it's not Jujitsu. It's all of them.
And if you don't know how
to do any of those aspects,
if you're a really good wrestler,
but the guy you're fighting knows how
to defend the takedown and he could fuck
you upstanding,
you got a real problem.
And that's what a lot of
wrestlers are dealing with today.
They don't know how to strike and they
face a guy who develops like Mirko Cro,
cop and pride days had really good take
down stuff and take down and then you
walked with head kicks and there's nothing
you can do about it and you get hit
by that shit. You're going
night night. So there's that.
Then there's also these wrestlers
that figuring out Jujitsu,
they can take you down.
It's strangle you,
you've gotta be able to stuff that take
down. If you can't stop that take down,
they're gonna take you down every
time. If you can, stuff that take down,
but they can't stand up,
you're going to fuck them up every time.
There's a lot of variables
and that's what we know now.
We didn't know that when I was
starting out, when I was starting out,
it was no one knew what was the right
way to do, whether it was it was boxing,
but there was wrestling, whether it was
taekwondo or karate or morning time.
No one knew. Do you think he meant may
guys are wanting to like the second,
third generation?
I don't know how many generations.
I don't know if there's a need to,
to numerically ordered them.
But I would say that today we have a
much better sense of what is ultimately
effective in martial arts
than we did even a year ago.
Just in the last couple of years,
we've seen an increase in the number
of traditional martial arts techniques.
Front kick to the face and
Anderson Silva landed on v tour.
The wheel kicks that had been landed
v toward landed a wheel kick. Um, uh,
junior dos Santos knocked out
Mark Hunt with a wheel kick.
Edson Barboza knocked out Terry Adam,
there's all these wheel kicks
now that we haven't seen before.
And those were always viable techniques
in taekwondo and in a kickboxing
Kyokushin,
but we haven't seen them in MMA because
the guys who are really good at them
didn't fight MMA. They fought kyokah
should and they fought taekwondo,
but now we're seeing these
MMA guys realize, hey,
this is a really tricky weapon
that I can add to my arsenal.
So the arsenal instead of being a
hundred moves deep is now 200 moves.
T there's not two 50 moves deep.
There's a lot of new shit that
people learning how to do that.
This is the old techniques that
everybody thought didn't work like you're
starting to see acts kicks again. Guys
are throwing it off shifts and Emma, yeah,
rich Clemente through one the other day
and Bella toward John Jones through one
in the UFC,
but they're still not at the level of
the ax kicks of like a guy like Jersey
long who was a Canadian MMA champion
who was, it had this nasty ax kick.
It was like getting hit in the
head with a fucking baseball bat.
This mother fucker would just full split
wing up and slam that heel down in your
face and you would go to sleep.
He knocked out a friend of mine out cold
with an ax kick in a tournament that's
his due date,
Jersey long and it was so nasty.
It was like getting hit by a sniper,
the way the dude.
And it made me change
my whole ax kick game.
I put way more credence into ax kicks.
I didn't think that aks kicks
could knock guys unconscious.
I just thought it kick. It was like
a flashy technique that you use.
But I never saw anybody go to sleep
till this guy named Jersey long fun.
It was like 1980,
probably two or something like that.
And he fought my friend and acts,
kicked him in the head and knocked
him out cold. It was brutal.
The way he did it too is so fast.
We just not,
we're not seeing that speed of execution,
that fluidity of motion,
that economy of,
of movement that a guy who's a
really high level taekwondo guy has,
uh, in that, in that, um, in MMA
there's a guy named herb Perez.
I saw him a knock out this dude I
think the Tuesday and was not seem,
I forgot the guy's last name,
but the guy was a high level guy as well
and herb knocked him out with the ax
kick to the head right in front of me.
I was like my first national tournament.
Um, I had lost, I lost
my first fight and uh,
it was probably, I was probably like 18
or 19, and I remember watching this guy,
her Perez knock this dude out with
a fucking ax kicked of the head.
Like as far as a way as you are
standing on the sideline and I saw this,
he'll land on this dude's head
and I re that was one of the,
one of the main moments in my
life where I realized, Oh shit,
like national champions can also
get knocked the fuck out. Right?
Everybody can get knocked out.
If you miss something. Yeah.
If you zig when you should have zagged
and someone kicks you in your face,
you're going to go to sleep.
And that's a technique like we haven't
seen yet really effectively in MMA.
Andy Hook used it in k one he used that.
There was a, there's a few other guys,
there's a couple of guys I've,
I saw a Russian dude who throws a
mean ass kickers fighting MMA in a,
a small organization,
but we haven't seen it in the UFC yet.
Wasn't any going to do a fight
with one of the guys? Yeah, yeah.
They're going to do a grappling match.
A rematch of the fight they had in 2000.
What's the name of that series?
Cause I'll watch on metamorris
watch some of that on Youtube.
Metamorris is a huge,
huge grappling organization.
They're putting together this really,
like they had Hixon son Kron for
[inaudible] who's a famous MMA fighter.
Very good grappler from uh, Japan
and uh, chronic guillotine dumb.
And that was a really exciting match.
And they've had some like real high
level MMA fighters and Brazilian Jujitsu
fighters. It's submission
artists, California,
one of the bigger communities
for Brazilian Jujitsu,
one of the biggest of the world,
one of the biggest in the world.
And there's so many Brazilian Jujitsu
schools in southern California.
It's almost like beyond recognition
or beyond a comprehension. There's,
there's a massive amount. There's so many
high level guys here. Hickson's hear it.
Well, his son Crohn is here now. Um, uh,
John Jacques Machado is like one
of the all time greats is here.
If I here for doom is here and
there's a lot of great MMA fighters.
Would also teach you to how Natto
Baba Lou. So brawls here, you know,
there's a million Alberto cranes
here. This is, it goes on on a hoist.
Grace, he's here. Henner grace.
Who's he? He, Ron Gracie's here. Hell
yeah. Horian uh, you know, is here
that there's so many guys here.
They just,
they came from Brazil and they're like,
there's those little kind of crazy,
and there's a beach here too.
Let's just fucking, let's just
stop here in southern California.
And then of course when
Emma May start to explode,
this was like the glamor
market, right? You know,
and there's a lot of money here and
there's a lot of people here is a lot of
people who want to learn Jujitsu.
It's a good place to open up a school.
But the biggest school in the country
is a apparently Henzel Gracie school in
Manhattan has a giant school,
but people love that guy so much.
Henzel Gracie was like one of the best
personalities and mixed martial arts and
a two period, just amazing, amazing guy.
Like a really a fun guy to be around.
Great sense of humor, great ego,
great perspective.
And because of that,
he has like this fiercely loyal
following and he's a huge, huge fucking,
I could see that going completely crazy
in a place like Manhattan. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. He's got a giant studio. I think
he has hundreds of students in Manhattan,
but Manhattan is stupid expensive.
That's what I mean. Could you imagine
what a studio cost, but, but then again,
I mean all your students would
probably fucking millionaires.
So what's the difference?
Well, I can't ask how many
millionaires in Manhattan.
There's a fuck load of
A lot of people in Manhattan also that
it just like barely getting by like
credit card and paying their
rent. Yeah. Feeding themselves.
But I mean Manhattan, that's one
thing. Like I you, we were there,
we were to Amsterdam. Yeah.
You know, you've got to
Amsterdam billiards and it's,
that's why I love, that's probably one of
my favorite pool rooms on earth. Me Too,
because it's just a legit,
I mean it's a beautiful place.
It's ran well. They take care of
it. Clean, organized the, yeah.
Nice little waiters and waitresses,
you know, courteous to you and,
but it, it's one of the few,
you know, it's hard to explain,
but you know,
you go in there and you don't have
the feeling a lot of pool rooms,
especially in the Midwest,
you walk in and you can almost
taste the fucking desperation.
You know what I'm talking about? I mean,
it's like, it's just like the sign,
the cigarette covered sign on the
wall that says pool $2 for five hours.
Yeah. I mean, it's just
like, oh, Jesus, you know?
But to me like a room in Amsterdam
that caters to executive plying to yes.
And the people, it's somebody,
like if I, if I had a date,
I would take her to Amsterdam.
Yeah.
There's maybe two or three pool rooms
in the country I would take a date to.
Yeah.
I love hard time outside of that,
but I wouldn't take a date to
hard times now. Sacramento or, uh,
or Bellflower. I mean, a hard
times. I love hard times for
the history. Yeah. I mean,
the history,
if you know what the f you know,
that's gotta be like
probably Yankee Stadium,
old Yankee stadium or Fenway park is
to a baseball guy and it's still there.
If you go there at any Sunday. Yes. If
you know the history of it, it's, it's,
um, it's cool. Yeah. I mean,
you can go in there and you can look
at that table and know that, you know,
it saves him morale is probably played
on that table in 1986 or whenever the
fuck he came there,
which that's the name for.
And Reyes who Efrin Ray was
just considered in my opinion,
the best player of all time.
He's still alive. Still Plan. Um,
and most humble,
professional,
nicest dude in the world.
Who's done more things on a
pool table than anyone else?
I think we'll probably ever do
you just use the backs? Well,
what's amazing about a
place like hard times,
there's a guy like me could
enter into a tournament and play.
Like last time I played in a hard time
tournament I played or necessarily demand
gas.
Right?
Anessa Domingo's is as a high
level pro guy for 20 years.
Been a great player.
Great Guy Too.
And his son Oscar Domingez
a also high level pro.
You could play against professionals
like a regular guy on the weekend.
That's a good thing and that's also
a terrible thing in my opinion.
What's a terrible aspect of it?
Because there was no one's going to pay
to watch if they can go pay $10 and play
with them. Is that true though?
Yes. I don't know if that's true.
I think the real issue with watching
the real issue was watching this,
this is not enough people participating
if I think this is true. Yeah,
I agree with that.
That I think there was an element of both,
I think pools in art form that the
only people that could appreciate it,
that people that can do it.
Sure what,
but that's a lot of things and that's
kind of where I've made my peace with the
whole thing is like there's a lot of
people in the industry that seem to think
that there's this magic bullet.
You can shoot at it and mainstream
approval will come and all of a sudden
there'll be millions and millions of
dollars flowing into the industry.
I don't believe that because I can't
think of anything else where that's ever
happened. People always want
to compare pool to poker,
but it's completely not
even the same thing.
It's really thing about poker is they
came out with that fucking camera that
allows you to see what the
person's hand was. Yes.
So that person at home has an inside view
and they get to see the drama of feel
like God because you know,
if you know,
nobody else knows and you get to
be smarter than the plas instantly.
And here's the other thing about
poker, and this is, you know,
the reason of so many,
if there was 5%,
the amount of dead money suckers
and pool is there is in poker,
we'd all, I mean, I'd be
driving a new car. Well,
the biggest suckers in pool are people
came over from poker who don't have any
appreciation for money because he used
to gambling big money, but, and poker,
you've got a built in reason for losing
because you can make the dumbest,
stupidest plays in the world and still
feel okay because it wasn't your fault.
You got sucked out on. Why did that?
How, how's that donkey call my bet? Yup.
You know, I've got, I mean you, if you
listen to poker players talk, it's crazy.
Yeah. No one else on earth can play poker
except for that particular person. Well,
there's sometimes you hear that from
pool players that go, yeah, he got lucky.
He ran for you seven to the eight. It
bumps into the nine if you didn't bump it.
And I a lot of crying from pool
players, but nothing like poker. Right.
And the other thing is,
the biggest thing with poker
is Pittsburgh for example,
I will never, ever, no matter what I do,
no matter how much effort I put into it,
ever when the u s open
nine ball championship,
I could play 15 hours a day for the
rest of my life. I'll never win it.
It would be like me saying,
I'm going to win the heavyweight
championship of the UFC.
It's fucking impossible.
It's not going to happen.
But you could win the
world series of poker. Yes,
I have a legitimate shot just snapped.
And I mean, I mean, I'm not saying,
I'm not saying a legitimate shot. I'm
saying it could happen. It's possible.
It is possible. It's fucking
impossible. You might as well say,
I can win the UFC lightweight champion.
You know, it's fucking impossible.
Goal should be the wind, the women's
world championship. We should put,
that's your television show. That's your
television dress. That's yourself. Okay.
Would hate me though.
They get mad at me.
Joe Rogan takes on the world
of women of low.dot, dot.
In Pool Dot, dot, dot.
It'd be rude. No, I,
I, I eventually want to do something
with pool, some sort of a show.
Figure out some sort.
You know what I would really like to see
you do if for no other reason than just
pure self satisfaction is some kind
of really cool documentary. Yeah,
that'd be fun. Because one reason
and it's not, and once again, man,
I'm to the point,
I'm just not a believer that pool
is a crossover to mainstream,
but as, but I don't think
it has to, but it has twice,
twice and two times because of the
media will tossler color mine. But now,
okay,
I agree with you 100%.
So look at those two instances.
Yeah.
Two Academy Award winning movies.
Both those movies won Academy Awards.
Pretty crazy. Yes. So
both of those movies that,
so basically in order to
get mainstream acceptance,
you have to have an academy award.
Winning movie, Jesus Christ.
Wrap your head around that one.
But here's my point is the
fact that you know what,
it doesn't take that to improve
things for pool and everything else.
I mean if you just get, you know,
100,000 more people playing,
which sounds like a lot, but that's
shit. That's 200 people in every state.
Yeah, we just need an ambassador. Yeah,
I'll take the reins. You could do that.
I'll handle this pitch.
You could do it by checking on women.
Now they just got to divide us people off.
It's weird too. Also, it's a,
it's an interesting argument
about the differences,
differences between men and women that
besides the cultural aspect of pool being
more acceptable for men to play,
there's actually a difference in the way
men and women see three d geometry the
way that may, the way men and women see a
spacial distance and their, their, their,
their, their understanding
of space. It's different.
It's really interesting because a women
can get fantastic at pool. You know,
there's gene Valukas who competed against
men and jasmine ocean plays basically
like, you know, Allison Fisher. Please.
I don't understand why.
I mean if you look at it on paper,
especially a game like straight pool,
right,
where it doesn't require the big break,
there is no reason on
earth that I can think of.
I mean physically, mentally you can
go into all that if you want to,
but physically there's no reason at all
that a man should be better than a woman.
That's true.
But it also,
it highlights the differences between
the way men and women look at three d
space.
Okay.
We apparently have a different
need. There's, there's,
there's different requirements
for survival that a man
had of developing to this
point in 2013 from, you know, many,
many thousands of years of
evolution and women have,
they've had a different need
for fast twitch, muscle fiber,
a different need for reaction time.
It's one of the arguments
against a male transvestite,
a transsexual who used to be a male who
became a woman fighting females is the
reaction time. There's a weird reaction
time difference for men and women.
It's really significant.
It's about 10% Oh shit. Yeah.
It's pretty much across the board.
So that's funny because yeah,
shooting,
which you wouldn't think,
I mean there's really no strength issue,
right?
But the women aren't,
don't come close to the men.
Yeah.
Well Northern Cheyenne Pool,
what was the last time a woman won a
world championship and pull the u s open
and he knows that they don't win them.
They don't win them.
And there's an amazing,
amazing, amazing women.
But what they are is so incredibly
exceptional that they stand out,
but they still can't beat the best man.
They still can't be changed.
They still can't beat Bustamonte.
No, there isn't. There isn't
different.
And that's one of the things I like about
what I do with the people I do it with
is it's interesting and
enjoyable to me to show,
uh, the levels because they're, you know,
like we've done matches to where guys
play and you're sitting there and you're
going, you know what, if this
guy was playing Alex or shame,
he'd get beat 160. Right? Maybe. Right?
But at the same time, the
guys playing great, right?
Yo guys playing great runout pool.
You'll not making mistakes,
but it's like it makes it bad decision
here or he does something to get out of
line there and unless you really know
what the hell you're just going on,
it's hard to miss. But you know
when you see, I don't know,
it goes back to the excellence
thing I was talking about,
but like one of the things
that I'm really happy,
you know when what I do is said and done,
whatever that is, 25 years
from now, somewhere on youtube,
someone will be able to flip on one
of these videos and watch and see.
You know,
people always talk about how good and
Keith McCready was on a bar table in 1984
you know what?
Well people will be able to see how good
chain was on a nine foot 10 ball table
and 2006
or 2008 and 13 yeah. Right, exactly. Yeah.
That's unfortunate aspect to some of the
past players when they talk about it,
like there's like some
urban crane footage.
We see him playing straight pool
and you try to like put it together.
Moscone there's a lot of footage
in Moscone when he was really old,
unfortunately. You know, like those, uh,
those ABC wild world of
sports events that they had,
they used to play pool on
ABC wide world cool ports.
But there was four channels
on television. Yeah. But it,
this is even more impressive. That pool
made it down to four channels. Well,
because of the story and I really think
that if pool has any shot at mainstream
television, it is a reality show type.
Totally didn't show you and May, dude,
we're the last of the Mohicans.
You could absolutely.
I think you
could do something. Yeah.
You know what I could do?
I could play really high level
women and the action report match,
you know what you could do is you
could just could just make you into
like the ultimate asshole.
No, you do it. It's just,
I mean we could just make you the bad
guy. I don't want to do that. Yeah,
that'd be better than the
other way as I was nice.
I just play really good women kicked
her ass, cause I can't be in there, man.
You can't.
You
can't be to any really good women.
None of them.
I'm going to tell you five really
good one and you got no shot to beat.
Give me a year. Can't beat
Allison. You can't be serious big.
Can I get crazy guy young?
You can't be all comedy knows.
Y'All are saying just fucking nine
ball and jasmine. None of them.
I'm to bring somebody in.
That can be all the rest of things.
All the rest of them.
A lot of how much of a drop off is there?
Who I want to see you play? Who? Sarah
rousy. She's a really good player.
He's a very good plan. Okay,
let's do it. Let's make it happen.
I think Sarah would straight rob.
You straight rob me.
Someone's got to crush straight rod.
Someone's got a crush her as much,
so there's my buddy. If I
start firing, man, we were in
nom together, but no Sarah,
she hasn't played pool and like for you
to perfect. That's what I'm looking for.
Duck. Yeah. Listen man. I have gears and
on my highest gear, I surprised myself,
but at my lowest gear, I'm not very
good at all. That's my real problem.
You know, like remember what time you and
I were in Vegas from playing Eric? Yeah.
I couldn't miss the ball.
She's running out packages over and
over and over again, but that's rare.
And then I have to get into the groove by
playing like six. Okay, six, seven hours.
I know exactly what the
hell are you talking about.
What do you think causes it?
Uh, you get loose, you
understand exam. For me,
it's a matter of pool is all,
I mean I understand how the
stroke the ball correctly.
I understand how Stan correctly,
I understand how to aim correctly,
but unless I'm playing consistently and
I have constant feedback loop between
qtip hitting the cue ball,
Cuba hitting the object ball and it goes
into my calculator of what's going to
happen,
I can fuck up and I can over juice
shots and I can have too much English.
It's a matter of a massive
amount of information coming
at me over a long period
of time.
Six,
seven hours of just playing pool know
us eating pizza and fucking drinking
coffee and then right back to the table.
And when I do that,
then especially that homeboys
place where that intense pasta,
what's that fucking best billiards in
Vegas and amazing food that motherfucker
has. I heard the kitchen closed
down. It's not true for the herd.
I haven't been there since
last time we were there.
How dare he closed down the kitchen.
But when you do that for
a long period of time,
then I then I'm working with a massive
amount of information and when I'm
working with a massive
amount of information about
touch and feel and movement
and I get a sense of what's going
to happen, then I can get into it.
And once I get in,
does it anything like his
Jujitsu and very sad for you.
Very, very, very, very, very similar.
It's all just a matter
of feel and movement and,
and knowing what the feedback loop is.
Like if you've never punched somebody in
the, your punch someone and you're like,
whoa, this is crazy. But
then if you punch him a meal,
if you've used to punching people,
it just comes out. It's just,
it just feels normal when
you're hitting someone.
And I think with pool balls is the same
thing. The more you stroke that ball,
the more you understand the
movement and the more it it,
it's in my head exactly how much effort
I have to exert to get exactly the same
result on one ball and have balls
twist and turn and move. And that's,
that's the big thing.
And for me also,
I'm so busy that I don't get
a chance to play that much.
So when I do get a chance,
like when you and I are in Vegas
with Eric and we get like seven,
eight hours and we're playing
in a 24 hour pool hall,
I'm an enthusiastic as fuck. So
like five, six hours into this,
I haven't lost any enthusiasm. Sure.
I'm the loving the shit out of this,
but I'm also getting excited and then
they start seeing Eric fall apart.
When I started there, I shot it and
like predatory instinct kicks in.
And then I'm a sneaky feeling.
You feel him with his cue.
It's like you get any nuts shot in with
your own cues sign. That's not good.
It's right. I see you over
there. No wobbling, wobbling
in the back of the herd.
I don't know man.
There's very few things in life that
I've had as much of an attachment with
where I really like got a lot of
satisfaction out of like pool.
So for me it's just a,
it's just fun. It's uh,
and I'm not playing the person either.
I'm just playing those balls.
I'm just trying to do my best.
I'm trying to do my best to making my
way around the table so I'm not upset if
someone wins. You know,
when I was a young man,
if I was playing a game
when I was an idiot,
I would get upset if someone else one.
And then I've realized somewhere along
the line that doesn't help me in any way.
And in fact it hurts me. But it's also
got nothing to do with you. Exactly.
Especially with pool pools.
One of the rare games where like
there's a famous match between Francisco
boosted and Johnny Archer.
They were playing a race at 10 for
some incredible amount of money.
Johnny Archer broken ran 10 racks
in a row on him, which is insanity.
And then at the end,
Francisco Bustamonte want to double
the bet and keep it going. Right.
That's how crazy it is a fucking game
is that a guy can do that with 10 games
you don't even get a chance to shoot.
It's like the old joke about a guy,
he makes a game with the guy,
they're going to gamble and uh,
the guy breaks and runs out the set.
The other guy never gets the play and
he comes up to him, he goes, hey man,
you're going to have to spot
me something cause spice.
I kind of spot you something
I haven't seen you play yet.
You know, so it's, well there's a thing
about pool and this is the big one.
Ended up with this. The thing about
pool that separates us from video game,
not necessarily video games,
but really from poker is
execution exactly as they occur.
You have to make a decision pool,
you have to make a decision and you have
to execute it and you have to keep your
nerves together.
You know,
if you've ever played in a
tournament or you ever gambled,
you know how hard it is to really shoot
straight when your heart's pounding your
chest and a bunch of people are
watching you. Yeah. You know,
which is why you see a guy like Shane
or a guy like Alex or you know Earl when
they're playing their very best against
high level competition and then it ever
fucking surrounded by people
who know how to play pool. Yeah.
Real pool players.
Like I could run out a rack and get
out and the average person is like,
that's incredible.
But you know someone like you is like,
why don't you go that way on the
sixth right. And like I fucked up man.
I just got lucky.
I pumped the eight and I got got clear.
You will know that I fucked up.
You will know that I got lucky and I got
out still. That happens all the time.
Whereas a guy like
she's fucking see that if
he misses that five ball,
he doesn't even get out if he doesn't
clip the fire ball with his cue ball.
He was playing luck. Pool playing wish
pool. We wish. Wish you add a shot. Huh?
There was a dude named
Tom, uh, um, uh, Mt.
Vernon and Tommy and while we were at a
time, it was like a, a top player, uh,
back at executive billiards where
I played in white plains, New York.
And he would get mad at people
when they play wishbone.
Wishful.
He's over here playing some old wish pool,
some old wish pool.
You wish you got positioned?
I learned a lot, man. Hanging out in
pool halls. I learned a lot of it.
I learned a lot about life. I really did.
There's some extreme human beings. Yeah.
And I'll tell you what
it will, uh, you know,
I've made my living in
that world for the last,
since 2007 and probably one of the
you guys outside of pool players
that actually can make a good living.
It's not good. Yeah. You got
to keep your place. I tell,
I tell people, you know, it's like,
I feel like from just the
technical things I do,
I could go make more money
doing other things, but it's,
I'm pretty confident in it.
But one of the things that,
and I tell players this and
players have told me this, is that
it's, it's, it's,
it really means a lot to be able to
control your own destiny kind of.
And that,
you know,
if I wake up in the morning
and I want to go do Xyz,
I can do that with the knowledge that
I also have to have this done by this
time. It's like a lot of people who, who
do their own freelance type of stuff.
I mean, there's a lot of people out there
who do that, but, uh, you know, you,
you give up security for
freedom and once you make that,
I mean, dude, you are a fucking
standup comic for how many years,
if anyone on earth understands that
it's you. Yeah. You know, I mean,
before you got your break, what
were you making a night? You know,
it wasn't very much. Right.
But I mean it's, yeah,
and there's,
but that's the thing too is,
you know,
if you want to go work a nine to five job,
you'll have a little more security.
Not much in this day and age,
who was even more drastic
than comedy because, well,
you can't go make money with
comedy. At least, you know,
if you go show up, you're probably going
to get paid. Even if you suck with pool,
you can go and you have to pay to go and
pool. Yeah, no, you have to be a room.
You have to pay for your tournament entry.
And if you don't perform,
you don't get fucking paid.
So pool is double tough for
players. It's very, very, very good.
Listen man, after this podcast
is over, it's basically over.
Now let's wrap this bitch up. Let's
figure something out, man. Let's,
you and me do something. Let's do
something. We'll do it on the internet.
We'll do it somewhere.
It doesn't make something happen.
See if we can see if we could
do something. Just get a
little fun in it. Maybe, uh,
you know, maybe it's me
playing, maybe it's me.
Maybe it's you and I go into Derby
city and doing a a documentary.
I would love to do that.
I would love to do something.
We'll do something for sure. I just
podcast had no beginning, no end.
It has no end is a no point. But
that's life. Ladies and gentlemen, uh,
if you want to get ahold of Justin,
you can get ahold of him, uh,
at the action report on Twitter.
Uh,
the actual report.com is the website
where you could see the absolute,
very best players in the world.
Duke it out, uh, in long races.
And if you're a fan of pool, go check
that out. And if you're not a fan of pool,
play a little pool and then go
fuck yourself. Go Fuck Yourself.
You'll understand how, uh, how amazing it
is. Dude, this is the fun epic podcast.
I enjoyed it, man. Thank you very much
for having me. As long as podcasts,
I think we've ever done ever.
Jesus. That's impressive.
We made a record today. Yep.
All right. All Right, ladies and
gentlemen, that's it for this week.
We'll be back next week. We've got a lot
of shit going on next week. Next week.
Uh, I got, uh, Greg Proops
powerful Greg Proops.
Um, Steven Pressfield. Yeah, that's right.
Even press office to write the author,
he's a shit is legit.
Next Tuesday rather the 15th.
Yeah, he's amazing. So, uh,
Greg Proops and Pressfield next week,
lots of good shit coming up yet. Fucks.
And uh, then the week after
that, uh, well the week after,
the week after that I got
Sam Harris coming in. I got,
I got a lot of shit calling on you
fuckers. Uh, and thanks for uh,
all the tweets that you guys send me.
I am more informed because of you guys
sending me tweets and sending me really
interesting links and sending me really
cool websites and stories and I'm,
I'm more informed because of
that than anything. And I, um,
I absolutely do feel the,
uh,
the responsibility to retweet
as many cool shit. Uh,
cool things is you guys send me and,
and tweet as much cool
shit as I find online.
So I just wanted to thank you guys
for that and tell you that this is not
something that I take for granted
in any stretch by any stretch of the
imagination. I appreciate
it very much. Um,
next Gig is next weekend,
the 18th.
I met the by you music center in Houston,
Texas with the one and only Tommy
motherfucking Segora. And then the 25th,
I'm at the dance house, uh,
for two shows in Manchester,
England, by the way. Sold out, suck it,
and then Irvine Improv November
4th, second and third. All right,
you for, that's it. The end of the
show has come. It is a eight 34.
It's time to go get some steak,
talk some shit.
And we'll see you guys next week.
Love the fuck out of yet because.