The joe rogan experience.
I was influenced by a tell a massively,
yeah.
Drinking too that that oh no,
I was being thing.
No,
I was fine.
I told you I came in,
explained that because
this is a crazy story.
You didn't say this on the podcast.
I have when I was in 1997,
Rollingstone magazine wrote a six and
a half page article about me calling me
the number one party
animal in the country.
It's actually gets a little weirder.
What are you doing?
Standup act,
just partying.
I had a notorious reputation of
Florida state for being like funny,
but being a wild party animal.
Like what kind of Shit were you doing?
Just Fun Shit.
Like uh,
like fun.
I think Wa loudest guy in the room.
Shit.
You know like I remember we,
I used to climb up on this telephone pole
outside the bars on Tennessee street.
There'll be 500 people out
there and I just stand up my go.
Everyone shut the fuck up and listen.
If you want to smoke weed,
go to my house and the
cops are all sitting there.
I have tons of weed enough for everybody
and we're all gonna have a blast and
get eye.
If you know where I live.
You're invited.
If you don't ask someone,
just no one tell the fucking cops and
you'd have literally 500 people just
giggling at the idea that someone was
offering them weed in front of the cops
face.
And what are the cops
saying when you did this?
They would laugh too.
Like one time for an election,
uh,
gotten naked for this election and just
shit on a pizza box and won the election
election.
For what?
For my fraternity.
I just got up naked and shit on a pizza
box and then everyone who won and then I
won.
Did you wipe?
Not just shit.
I just,
Shit.
I learned one very important
lesson when you go number two,
you also go one,
cause I pissed all over the feet on
everyone that was sitting in can't stop it
when you go one,
two.
And so I won the election.
So like all these stories came out and
then rolling stones like let's do a
fucking,
let's do an article on him.
Oh my God,
it gets crazier.
Ready?
Sorry for the you already for the
part that you go that you go bullshit.
I will never say bull shit.
I've heard enough of your stories.
I'm not so lost.
So uh,
so Oliver stone option the rights to
my life and then from the article.
So then I try to stand up and I moved
to New York to start to stand ups.
I did it once and to in a townhouse,
you know we went amazing.
I got offer my own morning
show in Tallahassee.
Really?
Yeah.
Oliver Stone Officer.
The rights of my life,
like I start doing stand up five minutes
later will Smith sees me to stand up
and I get a deal development deal
with him like right out the gate.
It's like bill burr style,
like been doing standup for no time at
all development deal based on the article
and that the fact that I could competently
do standup somewhat and then the
development deal falls
apart with Oliver Stone.
All the guys that have submitted their
scripts for Oliver Stone's movie about my
life then get their
intellectual property back.
One of the guy takes his movie changes,
my name sells at the National Lampoon
and it becomes a movie Van Wilder.
So theoretically,
and I say this theoretically loosely,
I'll never be able to sue.
I'm never would sue,
I never would sue.
But I went into national lampoon and did,
do you remember Kevin Couch?
He used to have a show on
national lampoon XM radio.
And I told him,
I said,
bring some exact sin.
I've always wanted to
find out if this is true.
So then he brought some execs in and I
start telling the story just like I am
you one of the guys fucking locks up.
Like hold on,
stop right now.
What do you want?
What's going on here
is just like an ambush.
And I was like,
no,
I just want to be able to
tell it on radio and no,
I'm not lying.
That's all I care about.
All I care about is the
story being like true.
Right.
And,
and he was like,
what do you want?
Like your own radio show.
I'm like,
fine.
And then he's like,
we'll do a show parting
with the original band.
While are you happy?
And I was like,
yeah.
And so then he was like,
pretty much,
I was like,
so I can say it's true.
But you were worried you
were going to sue them.
They were worried I was going to sue
them cause we put it must mean you have a
case.
Right?
Why don't you just go
fucking sue those cunts?
Barry Katz said to me one,
they papa,
you can be one of two guys.
You can be the guy that's
Susan doesn't work.
Or you can be the guy
that doesn't soon works.
Which millimolar?
Yes.
[inaudible]
okay.
I never knew,
I never knew how to start.
I don't hear anything.
Brian.