Do.
Oh No.
Yeah,
Vamos.
See,
okay.
We'd lie.
That's all I know.
Spanish.
Don't expect more.
Ladies and gentlemen,
elite camp.
This is what I want to do,
buddy Lee camp.
Alex Jones.
Anger at me.
Let's go drink it.
We can all be friends.
We're going to pass around a joint.
We're going to agree to be friendly
while I'll just go to dinner somewhere.
Have a good old time.
Throw back some beers.
I think we would all get along famously.
I know nothing about Alex Jones off the
mic.
I can't even imagine what goes on.
I love him.
I don't care what anybody says about him
being crazy.
Alex Jones is my friend and I love that
guy.
He's a big sweet teddy bear.
He's a super nice guy.
Does he get humor all?
Oh yeah.
He comes to comedy shows all the time.
It's a fucking big comedy fan because I
saw Doug,
Stan Ho,
Doug.
Doug's been friends with them too and I
said I've gone with him once and it just
seemed like he dug was being hilarious.
It just seemed like he didn't get it.
What was happening?
Have you ever seen him with Joey Diaz is
one of the funniest moments in the
history of radio.
They're like bizarro version.
He told Joey Diaz that um,
it was on the Internet.
That's where he fucked up because there
was one part that we're dealing.
We're in Austin and we're in studio and
one part we were doing was on the radio,
radio,
radio.
You can't swear.
He's like,
well,
this next part is going to be on the
Internet,
but uh,
you know,
you can swear.
Many of you shouldn't swear,
shouldn't put it,
but if you do,
it's no big deal.
No one's going to go to jail.
So all of a sudden Joey Diaz realized as
the flood gates are open.
So he just,
I mean,
Joe,
he's the funniest guy.
He's like,
Oh joke,
he's not the funniest guy that's ever
lived.
He's in the top two or three.
So he is amazing.
Just goes off.
And I'm just sitting there red faced and
crying and laughing.
I'm laughing so hard.
I can't breathe.
And he just had alex to do with it.
They know what to do with it.
He was trying to juggle it.
You won't player Jimmy to this part of
it.
Yeah,
but just don't move.
And he was dancing and singing and
Mexico.
He's done oxygen.
No,
not a junkie is a junkie.
The junkie is a junkie.
Everyday.
He doesn't wake up singing dance and
then he has oxygen tanks at night.
Something's not right.
Michael Jackson case.
You're worth more dead than what you are
alive.
You understand me?
He and now they got a new record coming
out that no more.
He's doing a tour next year with the
people from Vegas that jump up and down
the blue band group,
but he's worth more now than he's ever
been.
Michael Jackson was up to me.
What?
I know.
I smoke a little joint.
I'll break it down,
break it down,
because he bought the music from Paul
Mccartney back and all of a sudden they.
They put Paul Mccartney,
the soup bowl.
They tried to build up the Beatles to
get to Jackson.
By the way,
we're so high right now so high.
Like we got barbecue
before this thing.
Obama is a strategy,
keep going know what to
do you,
but what to do,
never be on the air,
so most of this is on the regular radio
until joey finds out that the radio,
see if he could find where it goes off
because he only goes off for like five
minutes,
but he's screaming and yelling about
going to the TSA with a bag of weed
under his balls and Alex just try to
bring it back to Hillary Clinton,
a knee elites.
I would never want to try and compete
with Joey Diaz.
Will you just got to let him go.
Let him go.
I'm telling you,
joey loves Alex to Joey and Alex.
they went to
stinking,
stinking up a storm.
Not to mention my balls.
I'm sweating now because I'm going to go
to jail.
Shook my hand.
I'm like,
my tax payers are work a politician.
Nice talking to you.
Like a Christian.
Someone already edited.
Oh,
this is someone else's edit obviously,
because that's where he goes.
You get take a taxi.
When?
What does he yell out?
Oh yeah,
a pig.
Dixon gas is bad for your health state.
Black and then he leaves this to black.
That's the most important thing.
I mean he just.
He knows when to exit the room.
No,
that's.
Go Fuck Yourself.
You can hold on.
Hold on one second.
Don't take the shuttle.
Joey Diaz.
Facebook.
Check yourself before you wreck
yourself.
Big Dixon.
Yes.
This is the.
I'm drawing
a blank because that's the most
important.
The only way to deal with,
but I'm telling you Alex,
a good guy.
Nice guy.
He just.
He's just balls deep in that world.
He's balls deep in the.
You got to get dried food.
You need gold.
He believes half the half of the shit he
say and I think he just knows he gets
hits.
We've got hypnotic brain pills at the
CIA.
Found in a basement.
Charlton Heston uncover this years ago
and was silenced for it.
The crane pills.
You've got to get silver and your veins
and they drink that silver water.
I had a buddy of mine,
he used to do that.
He used to have a like a rod that you
would electrify.
You would like.
It would have like wires on it and you
would dip it in water.
I'm like,
what are you doing?
And he's like,
you're making some sort of a silver
drink and if you have a cold,
you drink that.
You're good.
I,
yeah.
If you spend,
if you spend your whole hour telling
people that they need to fear for their
lives and then go and then go buy the
survival garden,
it's like,
yeah,
you just us,
we need the survival
garden.
Set it up.
He sells some good fucking survival food
though.
If you want some solid survival food.
Jesus Christ.
There was a video that Duncan sent me
yesterday.
Um,
this dude put together of Jim Baker,
the Jim Baker.
Do you know Jim Baker's back?
And when trump won,
I mean they were like,
it was like Jesus came home.
You got to put in.
Watch this video because I put it,
see how much of it we can watch.
How much of it can we watch without
getting kicked off?
We just put a little bit of it in the
background,
but it's the actual Jim Baker show,
Jim Baker as an actual show now,
and he.
He sells food.
He sells dried food,
like survival food that you.
They're advertising it as furniture.
You stack it around your dinner table
table on showing it and I sell it.
Somebody had that furniture to to run
for your lives up on the stage.
He has a whole setup on the state.
Pretty sure we can't play this.
Okay.
Does this the one that was on my twitter
feed?
Look at this guy.
Yeah.
This is it.
This is who put this together.
What is the guy's named?
Super Deluxe.
What's that number?
Twitter.
Super Deluxe,
but that's it.
Just super deluxe.
Yeah.
Fucking.
Oh,
youtube.
Super Deluxe.
Whoever you are.
You've asked man,
this is God damn genius.
This is
the survival food.
Genocide.
No,
I love that because that was the number
one problem with survival food is what
do you do with it all?
So you've got to make it furniture
fracture and people's houses.
I mean,
he's doing all this shit with this with
a straight face.
This guy's a maniac.
That's crazy.
And he's making cash.
I almost want to like.
I would almost like to get that guy high
and get him on the podcast.
How bizarre would it be done in a boy
and a little hat like that baby?
Like if you could just talk him into
going camping with you and slip them a
couple of edibles.
You know,
Derek,
it would wake all these.
What would Alex Jones be like?
I got to settle down.
I got to relax.
I'm just setting.
The elites are just got me so fucking
riled up.
I just want to start.
Did you.
Did you see Eric Andre when he kind of
crashed Alex Jones things at the agency.
I just ran into him at the airport.
Yeah,
he's hilarious.
Alex Jones thinks he's with the daily
show so that Eric Andre is in the crowd.
He's like,
he's like,
let's get to the daily show up here.
Bring him up and bring him up here.
She'll come up here and come over and he
goes,
this guy's a Pentagon shuttle for the
daily show,
and Eric Andre is like,
I'm not with the daily show.
And then he got my own show and then he
goes,
I want to sleep with your wife Alex.
oh no.
I was just like,
what are you talking about?
He's like,
no,
I really.
I want to sleep with you,
or no,
I want you to sit with my wife.
I'll give you the room cave.
You sleep with my wife,
and I was just like,
I don't know what's going on.
He's a.
he's susceptible to manipulation.
Say that he can be trolled.
He's a good dude though.
I swear to God.
He is.
I've known Alex forever.
I've known him since [inaudible] 99.
Really?
Yeah.
We did a video together a long time ago
with me and him dressed up like George
Bush running around the capitol.
We went into the bathroom and smoke
bongs.
No,
it was hilarious because I offered them
a hit of the Bong and he goes,
uh,
I don't do that shit.
Makes me paranoid.
Does he
do that?
Makes him very though it was an inside
joke.
That was fun.
Uh,
and did he have the same stake then?
Look Dude,
he was doing that long
for.
I'm Adam.
He would like fucking like Herbert
Walker.
Bush would be somewhere and he would,
you know,
meet there and call him a war criminal
and yell out and get arrested.
And there was actually,
it was like Gw when he was running for
president.
I thanks.
Alex got arrested.
He got arrested a gang at times,
you know.
And the thing is Alex had some,
he was right about a lot of shit
and this is where it gets wet in a war.
Criminals fine.
It was right about the NSA stuff.
He was saying from a long time ago.
I mean years before the Edward Snowden
Shit came out.
He was like,
I guarantee you there is a place right
now where they are dumping all of your
information.
They collect data.
They have the capability that,
that was like,
come on man,
who's,
who's copying all the emails?
And that's the thing.
Could you imagine 15 years ago you said
they're watching everything.
They know your emails that you.
Anyone said that you were like,
all right,
let's get the fuck away from this guy
right now.
Everyone's like,
oh yeah,
sure.
They're like,
how quickly they changed so quick.
It's like you just assume we're still
NSA.
Nsa and privacy were mentioned in the
three presidential bates,
one vice president Dennis was a zero.
It never came up in all the best.
This is the largest surveillance
infrastructure ever created,
not mentioned in the presidential
debates.
Never discussed.
Fucking insane.
Right?
That's like,
that's almost like the agreement,
like you guys conduct shit about each
other.
All you want started talking about the
NSA,
we're going to have a real fucking
problem.
I mean,
that's the number one way that they
honestly like mainstream media and all
this shit lies to us.
It's just ignoring stuff.
It's not.
It's not usually flat out lies.
It's just we're not going to talk about
it.
I'll tell you what,
man.
There was a really impressive moment
where I was like,
I was really impressed with Obama as a
person where he was at this,
they were doing this campaign speech and
this guy that trump supporter was in the
crowd and this guy was a throwing a flag
up there is a trump flag and waving and
he's an older guy and he had like some
sort of military outfit on and he's
yelling out,
you know,
trump and he's kind of sign up and all
these people are billing and Obama stops
him and he goes and he goes,
first of all,
he goes,
this is a gentleman,
he's an older gentleman.
We should respect our elders,
so let's think about that.
And he goes,
and it looks like he's done some
military service,
has got a military so we should respect
our veterans.
And then he got it,
got to the singles.
He goes,
don't boo vote,
don't vote videos.
We respect freedom
speech like don't boo this map.
Yeah,
I
liked that,
but the whole respect,
the veterans thing,
when you don't fucking fund their
medical care,
when they get home,
we treat them like shit and then they
go,
oh,
respect them though.
Like you're totally right.
You're totally right.
It drives me nuts
more in a leadership role or as a
respect someone for like the way to
handle a delicate situation like that.
Yeah,
I agree with that because I think,
I mean ultimately you do have to be
concerned and we've been talking about
this with the whole trump thing.
You don't have to be concerned as much
about what trump's going to be able to
do as you do about people that see trump
in office and they getting bold and to
be assholes because I really think that
there's some people that are on the
fucking fence to asshole fence go one
way or another.
Oh yeah.
Then they might go full asshole,
full asshole doors open.
It's not trump's fault.
It's not trump's fault,
but it's a reality of being the person
who's setting the tone for the way the
country thinks of itself.
Right?
Oh absolutely.
And here's part of the,
the maybe the positive of having someone
like trump in the presidency is this
country,
like,
you know,
racism being an ass hole,
treating people like shit that's been
part of this country,
that is as long as we didn't have a
leader that you didn't think represented
that people were like,
oh,
okay,
we'll just keep going at this rate.
Whereas now people like are looking at
it.
Maybe we needed this ugly orange face as
the face of things to really be like,
Hey,
what is going on with the,
with the xenophobia and the racism and
what is,
what is the deal,
man,
we needed that face.
Well,
it definitely it.
It highlights the fact that it's a giant
issue still.
People that don't think it's an issue
because they don't see it in front of
their face that you're forced to look at
it now it doesn't,
you know,
this is something that Alonzo Bowden
said during the young Turks,
a coverage of the election that was so
on.
He goes,
he goes,
not all trump supporters are racist,
but all racists are trump supporters.
That he nailed it.
Is there,
they're not racist,
but he has a number one with racists
racists or voted for Hillary.
She get in that boat.
You know,
it's funny,
man.
It's funny.
It's a great point.
It's dead on.
It's you.
GotTa worry about the tone.
I mean,
it sounds ridiculous to someone who's
like got sovereignty,
someone with personal sovereignty,
somebody who knows who they are and
isn't so easily swayed and like,
that's not gonna.
Make me an asshole.
It probably won't make you an asshole.
Right.
But there's,
there's a guy.
Yeah,
that guy.
There's a bunch of those guys.
There's a lot of disenfranchised men out
there and this is where
I really put it on on,
you know,
the mainstream media is they legitimize
some of the shit that trump says or
whatever trump supporters say that is
just crackpot nuts.
Like when CNN had the Kyron that said
are Jews people?
And it's like,
oh you didn't hear about this.
And it went kind of viral.
They were,
they were saying,
hey,
this crazy white supremacists,
or maybe there's someone in Toronto
having something to do with trump said
has in past question
whether Jews or people or something,
so then they run with the chirons says
are Jews people?
It's like,
well now this is a legitimate
discussion.
You just made this a legitimate
Instead of just ignoring it.
Instead they're like,
hey,
let's have a panel to discuss.
Dude,
you smell funny.
It's a human.
Legitimize this shit.
If Jews are people,
there you go,
so fucking stupid.
That sounds like if someone gave the
news to people in the 15 hundreds and
said,
listen,
it's time.
This is a new technology.
If you imagine if he gave it to people
are just people.
I'm not sure
that's something we should discuss.
Let's sit down.
Talk about this.
What kind of people discuss where
they're not?
Usually people are like,
what else is Santa Claus Real?
Is that next?
What about Rudolph?
Was he a real character or is that a
mythical creature?
Is he an analogy as enl allegory?
What is he?
They gave $5,
million dollars of free coverage to
trump twice as much as hillary in the
primaries,
23 times as much as Bernie,
and they wonder how trump got elected.
It's like help themselves.
He was a master at manipulating them in
that regard.
Say controversial things,
whether it was on purpose or not.
Wow.
Jesus Christ,
fully.
God dammit.
People could die.
You're.
You're the first guest to do that.
I'm a fuck load of time.
Shit.
I've wrecked at least two laptops on the
show live.
We're good,
dude.
It.
I just did it.
Oh my God.
What a cluster fuck here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
at least she knows.
That's a good host is you wanted to make
me feel better about.
I'm just a slob.
Clumsy Dork,
but we're good.
Nothing got zapped.
We're good.
We were just talking about
country.
Trump and media.
The endless media coverage
can awesome job,
but you know what?
There's the possibility,
like I would like to think that we
watched some genius chess play by a
master of the media,
which he most certainly is,
right?
I had a guy absolutely television
forever,
but
I really wonder,
do you,
I mean,
do you have thoughts on who he,
what he genuinely believes?
That's the question.
No idea.
I thought that was my question.
I was going to say,
do you think that.
Did we watch a master manipulator or did
he just get lucky that his personality
like totally works right now?
Now like that,
everything is lined up for you to be the
guy that says,
you know,
you should grab chips by the pussy and
everything goes.
That's locker room talk.
I think so.
I think it's a little bit of both.
I think it's the perfect time for him
combined with a great manipulation.
Here's the thing,
if you didn't have people struggling so
hard,
if you didn't have this quote unquote
recovery all going to the top one
percent,
people wouldn't have gotten behind this.
You needed a populace that is furious
and struggling and miserable to get
behind this.
Isn't that weird?
A populace that is furious and
struggling and miserable wants to get
behind a dude who's a billionaire is
probably
get there.
I mean the whole thing is like,
I mean,
how much tooth Fang
and claw competition in businesses,
that guy had been involved in probably a
fuck load.
Right.
It sounds like every deal he's ever
signed,
he reneges on like half of it.
Like it's hilarious.
Like when,
when they were talking to him,
but during the debate when Hillary to
brought up the taxes and not pay any
taxes because I'm smart.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well,
but he got away with it,
but you know why he gets away with it?
Cause he goes,
yeah,
those laws shouldn't be there.
But since they are,
I'm not going to not use them.
Of course I'm going to use them.
He goes,
but let's take them out.
Let's take those logs out.
People wanted someone who just said,
fuck the system,
which,
which it's hilarious that you then get
behind a billionaire is the guy who's
gonna say fuck the system.
No,
but he's also a populist.
That's what's weird.
Like,
he likes to be popular,
you know,
and you have a unique opportunity with a
guy like him or I don't think he's gonna
be as influenced by other people as
we've had presidents before.
You know,
we've had presidents before they get
into the office and I'm like,
Oh my God,
this guy's not doing anything.
He said,
all right,
let me know.
Say who they are,
right?
Obama,
all of them.
Right.
All right,
but this is the first time a guy has
gotten in that like the,
the,
the party itself doesn't even want them
in there when they were trying to force
them out,
like everybody didn't want them in.
Everybody was saying,
there's no way we can lift this guy.
You know?
Basically the Republicans tried to rig
their primary to beat trump and failed
the democrats rigged to their primary
and succeeded.
That was the only difference.
Yeah.
It's fascinating,
isn't it?
Like they fucked over that Bernie
Sanders guy.
Oh man,
on every level we,
I covered this unredacted and I like
endlessly.
I just couldn't get enough of it.
It was like,
it was like on every was like voter
suppression,
closing polling places,
you know,
x opposed aren't matching up just at
media manipulation 23 times as much
coverage as I was saying for trump and
and like 10 times as much coverage for
Hillary as Bernie Sanders.
It was just like an every level they
tried to force through their candidate.
He would have been great.
Yeah,
I think Bernie would have been really
interesting.
I think Bernie running against trump
would have been way less vulnerable.
He was a,
he had way less skeletons in the closet.
Yeah.
He was pretty much an open book.
He also didn't,
he,
he had immense like compared to hillary
immense unfavorability numbers.
Whereas Hillary just had crazy
unfavorability.
Well he was,
he represented character to us.
Thirty years of saying the 30,
40 years of saying the same stuff.
Whereas Hillary from week to week,
you didn't know what she stood for.
Yeah.
And even the way looks,
you know,
like he represents character.
He represents this,
this,
you know,
disheveled,
really smart guy with his glasses and
his jacket and he's not trying to look
good at all.
He didn't have any orange makeup on.
He's like,
really?
The polar opposite of trump.
I would love a guy that cares more about
getting shit done than his hair.
I would love that.
Also seems to care about people whether
you agree with them or not.
I think that guy,
he genuinely cares about people.
Hopefully I'm not getting bullshitted,
you know,
because he is a politician.
Here's how you know a little something
is you don't spend 30 years in
government and not
get rich unless you've got other goals.
It's like everybody has been in Congress
that long is a multimillionaire.
Hinton.
He's not
waste from Vermont,
right?
Yeah.
They're all hippies up there.
They're all hippies and farmers in
Vermont is weird.
I had been going on a bunch of Ben and
Jerry's Vermont to too.
It's so weird.
It's great.
Don't get me wrong.
It is a great place like Burlington.
That place is amazing.
I did a gig up there once.
I was like,
wow,
this is like a little frozen paradise up
here,
like this little small town of like
hippie people and they always go against
whatever's going on around them.
How do you get like a group?
Is that.
It has to be a university town.
It's the only way you get like a group
of liberals in a mountain.
Right?
Well they uh,
yeah,
and then into,
I mean guesses universities there too,
but in some of these southern towns it's
just like they all fleet to one city.
It's like Asheville,
North Carolina,
just like we got to get together.
But that's the university too.
That's where Duncan went to school.
Asheville's amazing.
It's amazing.
It's such a great little town the best
and now like the people are so cool.
It's like you guys are like,
if you took like 30,000 of the best
people from Austin and brought them in
North Carolina,
that's what Asheville is.
It's like,
what are you guys doing here?
Like this is weird,
really cool bars.
Everybody walks around.
Okay.
But played there like six months ago and
I told them,
I was like,
you guys should build a wall around the
city.
It's great here.
Yeah.
That's the.
The area outside of it.
It's very strange.
There's still parts of this country that
haven't recovered from the civil war.
Really?
Yeah.
No,
I know.
there's parts of this country we were
driving through and we'll.
You'll run into small towns that still
have like the vague echoes of the city.
Dude.
I grew up in Richmond,
Virginia.
I'm named after Robert e Dot Lee.
Oh my God.
I went.
Really?
Yeah.
My high school,
my high school was the confederate
rebels.
Whole Mascot.
Did you got to have a rebel flag?
Rebel flag.
We had a rebel flag the first year I was
there.
Then they finally decided that it was a
offensive.
So they took away the flag but kept the
rebel soldiers the fast.
Oh my God.
Wow.
Dad Drinking whiskey.
What is that?
It's just water.
It's water and like a flask.
Yep.
What do they do?
And I try and get crafty.
Getting crap.
So.
So
it's Fred.
My name is Fred drink.
My water came off my breast.
Fresh water.
That's water.
That's how you advertise it during.
You just change the shape of the bottle.
Yeah,
he made it.
He made me talk about it.
Why is his name on the front of the
bottle?
Isn't that water?
She didn't just say water.
You fuck.
Say Fred.
Fred is in giant letters and underneath
it in tiny letters it says water.
Look at that.
That's ridiculous for it.
But here I am.
I'm talking to him about he won.
Were you surprised when they pulled the,
uh,
the confederate flag off the generally
you'd have freak you out?
Say Generally?
Yeah,
dude,
I had that.
I had the Dukes of hazzard bedsheets.
I think I had the poster,
the poster when they pulled the,
uh,
off TV land.
I was like,
Whoa,
dude.
Is it different history growing up in
Richmond,
Virginia,
it was,
I was 12 before anyone mentioned we lost
the civil war.
That was like,
wait,
we didn't win.
So you knew there was a civil war,
but you didn't know that the south lost?
No,
I just,
yeah,
because it's because it's talked about
like uh,
like almost like a victory because they
talk about it like all the grand old
times of civil war and stuff like that.
Do they really?
Yeah.
And,
and I was like,
I was like,
wait,
we lost what
all the monument avenue in Richmond,
Virginia is basically all civil war,
quote unquote heroes meaning the losers.
Wow.
It's crazy that,
that was so recent that 18,
65 was so recent 100 years ago.
There was like slavery pretty much.
Pretty close in 1916.
I mean there's probably,
well,
there's slavery now.
It's been that long.
Well yeah,
they're asleep.
That's the craziest thing.
Well,
there's not slavery now necessarily in
America,
but there's more slaves in the world now
because there's more people also.
There are,
there are more black people in prison
right now than the were slaves during
the civil war.
We imprison so many people and those
people are largely,
a lot of them are forced to labor for
like,
you know,
a nickel an hour or whatever.
So we,
because we have a,
we have a stipulation in the
constitution that you can have slavery
as long as they're in prison.
We've been talking about that a lot.
There's apparently there's a documentary
about that on Netflix.
Thirteenth.
Did you see it?
How is it?
It's great.
I keep hearing it.
I get real close to and I go,
God damn.
I haven't caught up on narcos.
Yeah,
I it,
but I got like one episode left and no
need to be entertained.
I want to watch westworld.
Sorry.
It's not looking good for Escobar.
It's not looking good man.
I'm worried what's going to have to.
But he is the star of the show.
How are you going to have another
season?
Just seems like he's digging a hole for
himself and he's just not going to come
out.
He should start treating people better.
I mean,
you keep killing people.
Eventually someone's going to kill you.
That's just what I think.
Uh,
he just said thank you a little more
please.
And thank you.
It is absolutely insane that you can
have a minimum wage except when you've
trapped someone for a crime.
Then not only do they have to pay for
that crime by being incarcerated,
but then they have to work and make
pennies to it.
It is such a.
it's such a game like that.
Another great book by T v is the divide
talks about this.
It's like it's like Matt,
Matt,
Matt Taibbi.
Then the cops just running.
They'll run around,
look for mostly black people standing on
the corner sometimes in front of their
own apartment,
charge them for loitering or something
and then and then they take a plea deal
because they're told like,
Hey,
do you want months of a trial where you
could spend a year in jail or do you
want to take this plea deal and just
have a tiny charge until they all take
the collegial.
So now they're in the system and it's
just designed as this railroading so
crazy.
It's so crazy that people have made an
industry off of like there's money to be
made from keeping people locked up.
It's just the way that we have allowed
that to happen.
It's so shameful because it's sort of
just everybody sort of woke up as adults
and was like,
what?
How many,
how many private prisons are that we
make?
How many people are in jail?
We didn't even know what percentage of
who or what.
We're five percent of the world's
population.
Twenty five percent of the world's
prisoners.
We have way more prisoners than any
country and it's all like it's going on
without us looking,
you know?
I mean,
they're not obviously for violent
crimes,
but let's just talk about the nonviolent
ones.
Yeah.
It isn't that like 50 percent.
Yeah,
it's a huge.
Most people in prison are nonviolent,
so 50 percent of them are locked up in
jail for something nonviolent.
And then what percentage those are
drugs,
I don't know,
but it's.
Yeah,
it's a lot.
A lot of this has to do with a lot of
this has to do with the drug wars.
Yeah,
I mean
I think like deft and obviously all the
violent crimes,
but all those things that they sort of
rationalizes you need some sort of
punishment,
but has anybody ever even proven the
prison is effective?
No,
that's not at all.
It could be because here's the thing is
that it destroys most people's lives.
They can't get a job when they get out,
their family's been broken up,
their community's been broken up.
So it's like you get out and then how do
you put things together?
So it,
it doesn't help people.
It doesn't help them get to a regular,
you know,
upstanding citizen level.
It's a lot of people.
It institutionalizes.
Yeah.
So,
but here's the thing,
the big question is like,
what,
what could be done that's better?
What does that say,
Jamie?
Would you putting up?
Well,
first of all,
if it's a nonviolent,
you know,
I think you shouldn't,
you shouldn't be in jail.
You got that one,
stick it out.
What do you think it is?
Um,
with a different offenses.
Oh,
that's,
is that drugs,
drug charges on the giant.
When's a drug charges?
Oh my God.
See,
that's crazy.
Six percent.
Oh my God.
That's crazy.
Look at those numbers.
The only.
The only thing.
Scroll down a little more.
Yeah.
The only thing,
even above 10 percent is drugs.
Okay.
And weapons.
Here's the thing.
You're not stopping people from selling
drugs,
obviously.
Plus there's a bunch of other drugs that
are available legally with
prescriptions.
You need to stop this illegal drug
thing.
You need to stop telling grown adults
what they can or can't do.
Keep it away from children.
Make strict laws about the age
restrictions.
Put a lot of money into education and
stop putting people in cages for doing
things.
They want to do like coke,
so when he wants to do coke,
let them go do coke.
What do you give a fuck?
They can go drink whiskey and die and
everybody's fine with that,
and then people go,
oh,
well they.
They do coke and they commit crimes.
Well then arrest them for the crimes.
You don't arrest them for the coke.
Alcohol is a huge factor in.
In crimes.
Yeah.
How many people have committed horrible
crimes because they'd been drunk?
Yeah,
it's and fights and beating the shit out
of people.
That's all alcohol.
I was running a gang of drunk people
last night.
Stone sober.
It's not.
Not a good time.
And people are.
They get fucking crazy.
Especially.
I would hate to be a woman at a bar.
Yeah,
fucking
sleazeballs and is the thing.
I love drinking.
I love my whiskey.
I'm fucking big fan,
but if you can't handle it,
want to drink right now.
Now I got to drive.
Drive somewhere.
I was little drinky poos.
Just one little slip,
but the good stuff.
We're going to little Daniel.
Oh yeah,
man.
Booze is a sketchy drug because I enjoy
it.
I like it.
But is it for everybody?
It's like there's a lot of things like
that though.
Try.
How about how come you can just go to a
Chevrolet dealership and buy a corvette?
Do you know how to drive that thing?
You know how to drive.
I know you know how to hit your blinker.
You don't have to handle a 600
horsepower fucking demon ride.
You could just buy that these cars
today,
because of the horsepower wars,
every year,
they're ramping up their speed,
their ramping up,
their handling,
the ramp it up to the breaking,
like the distance between like zero to
60 breaking or $60,
zero the day.
Those things are super cars now and any
regular kid,
if you have enough money to like what?
What's the corvette like?
50,000 or $60,000.
If you can,
you can get that money together somehow
and get that loan.
You can have something that's insane,
right?
You could just drive right into people
and kill people.
Like the responsibility having a big
giant truck.
The responsibility of driving that
thing,
like all those things are dangerous
and we allow people to do it
and so yeah,
I mean,
yeah,
we accept that there is a certain level
of harm or death for things that we want
as freedoms and that should be.
That should go through a lot of things.
It should go through with drugs.
It's like there's a certain level of pl
harm or death people might do to
themselves and they start doing it to
others.
We arrest them for that.
One of the things I was thinking about
when I brought up the,
uh,
the car thing,
so I wanted to ask you how you feel
about this oncoming onset of autonomous
cars.
So that's happening now.
So here I talked about this last night
in my,
in my standup.
So Uber is now put self driving cars in
Pittsburgh.
They're trying it out and this is gonna.
This is a massive employer in our
country is transportation.
That's huge.
And those are going away.
Those jobs are going to go away soon and
I think that's fine because what that
should do if we were fucking rational
beings,
is that should though that time of that
time and money savings should go to
people,
it should go to all of us.
We should all be,
if we hate our job,
which we work in less because the
technology can handle it now instead,
everybody's just working that goddamn
asses off at jobs they hate because all
of that time and savings is going to
the,
you know,
the elites that run these corporations.
It's not going to the people we are.
We are.
People are working themselves to death
to feed a family.
It's completely nonsense,
but how does that have to do with the
Uber thing though?
What is it?
Transportation is a major employment.
Isn't it like 40 something percent of
all white men over a certain age work in
some sort of an industry where they
drive a vehicle?
I'm not sure,
but I'm going up.
I'll use values to say I'm a according
to Joe Rogan
and people will go,
oh,
and they just raise their eyebrows.
Oh,
fear factor.
Guys got opinions on driving,
but no,
I think self driving cars should be
great.
They're gonna get better and better and
then the light bulb that when you say
like that,
the money is going away because it's not
really right because someone has to make
those cars.
Someone has to maintain those cars.
Someone has to run the uber software.
It's just the driver aspect of it is
going away.
The human labor part is going right,
right,
but all we're making all those cars to
begin with,
but if it's way safer and people's lives
are saved over people having jobs that
are not like a lot of fun anyway,
like shouldn't that person like for
technological progress,
when you look at the future of our
culture,
as much as I love automobiles,
I love them.
I love engineering.
I'm a giant fan of auto engineering,
but they're going to go away.
You're going to have autonomous
vehicles.
It's going to happen just like everybody
has a cell phone.
It's almost,
you can't find it.
The hard thing is going to be getting a
license to drive a car on your own
without any sort of that electronic to
be sad.
I didn't even think of that.
That's what's going to happen,
man.
You gonna have to have a.
like if you have an old corvette or
something like that,
you're going to have to have a license
to drive that old corvette with your
shitty has drum brakes and skillset
fucked up tires.
And people like to think,
oh no,
the autonomous thing won't happen
because you know,
on a telesummit,
autonomous car,
autonomous car will kill someone and
then it's like,
well,
yeah,
but they don't need to be better.
They don't need to be the best ever.
They just need to be better than humans.
Humans quickly.
Yeah.
Like they're going to be instantly
better than humans.
And by the way,
with all those sensors that they could
put on those things,
if you ever seen how they respond that
they're really good at responding to
like cars swerving at them,
they hit the brakes and if they're all
doing that,
as long as the code is good and the
machinery is good and nothing gets
fucked up,
but that's the big thing.
If it gets fucked up,
will it have enough checkpoints like to
be able to do an assessment of itself
and know whether or not should be
driving.
Although here's the,
here's the big question is it'll take
it'll inch,
it'll eventually get to a point where
it's taken away our freedom and a lot of
ways because these things are going to
drive the speed limit and you're gonna.
It's gonna drive a fucking nuts.
That's true.
You'd be sitting there and it's going to
become illegal to go above the speed
limit because it's driving.
Cars will go the speed limit.
You're going to have to follow.
The rules can be awful.
We'll just have to find some Russian
dude who knows a guy with a chip hot rod
out your shit.
I got one of those second one of the
bots that breaks the law,
one of the criminal butts.
I mean,
but if if we're going to progress and go
from here to some new state of
technological excellence,
which undoubtedly will if we stay alive,
right?
I mean every civilization,
every culture in this country as far as
we've been measuring,
it just keeps getting better and better
and better at figuring things out more
and more efficient.
Although we're polluting more and
damaging the earth more than what our
capabilities keep getting more and more
powerful.
There's.
There's gonna come a point in time I
think where it was inevitable that
people had stopped powering
machines with their hands.
Like we should probably get out of that
as quick as we can and concentrating
using our brains like and like the idea
that the person who drives the car could
only drive the car.
That's kind of crazy because I used to
drive cars.
Did you ever drive cars before?
I drove limos,
so I just drive and deliver newspapers.
So I've been in driving jobs.
Right.
And I can do other stuff like other can
do other stuff.
People can do other stuff.
You can find another thing that you'd
like to do.
It's not like this guy lost his job.
The only way feeds his family.
Okay.
I feel terrible that you lost your job.
I'll feel terrible.
Then anybody loses their job and they
have a hard time feeding their family.
But when you're talking about a job,
I know it's hard to get jobs,
but people lose and gain jobs all the
time.
It does happen.
Yeah,
but I got to find one that's better than
this one,
right?
I.
I mean,
I agree,
but.
But for one thing,
not everyone is smart enough to get a
headset and really intelligent jobs.
There's a lot of families.
There's a lot of dummy fix that will the
Alex Jones Britt genius pills from the
CIA,
basement.
Luther Vandross hold of these 1984 and
there was a period of six months where
he didn't sing because they had him
locked up in the basement.
The Dungeon and Virginia colloidal
silver will fix you.
You ever see that dude who drank too
much?
Cool little silver?
He turned blue.
Oh yeah,
I did see the blue guy.
He died when he died,
but he was old.
He died.
He didn't die from being below blue.
I don't think so.
We might have.
I don't think.
Maybe I'm wrong.
I think he just died.
I'm waiting for one day for Alex Jones
and go,
guys,
I need to tell you.
I don't have the papers,
I don't have the documents.
I've been lying.
I've been lying the whole time,
but right here I don't have.
I lost the documents.
I lost.
I had them.
I spilled coffee on him,
but he had some documents.
That's the fucking problem.
Did you ever see he had a documentary
that one of them.
No.
Really opened my eyes.
It was nine one,
one a road to tyranny and there's was
another typical ouch Jones to touch on.
You know it.
He's talking about the demise of
civilization and all these different
things,
but then he goes into the WTO,
the WTO protests,
and this is where it got really crazy.
Ninety nine.
Yeah,
and he showed that all of these
anarchists came in.
There's all these peaceful protesters
and then all these anarchists came in
with ski masks on and government issued
boots and started smashing everything.
They're literally wearing military issue
boots.
They start knocking over newspaper
dispensers and smashing car windows and
storefronts and stuff like that to move
in to.
The cops have to move in,
so then these guys get wrapped up into
some building.
They get like quartered in some
building.
They negotiate their release and then
they're released without charges.
Oh yeah.
The provocateur thing that.
That shit happens all the time.
Where I mean at the end of occupy,
it's like half of those camps were
infiltrated cops.
Like we're just plain cops.
Well,
here's what they did with,
with Seattle.
Was it Seattle?
The WTF?
They made people take off.
They had badges.
Like,
like if someone had like a pin that
you're wearing that hat a WTO with a red
line through it.
They said this is a no protest zone.
You can't get through this zone with any
form of protest.
So even a pin that says WTO with a red
line through it.
They were telling people,
you can't get to your job with that.
You know,
you gotta you gotta be in the freedom of
speech zone.
We've fenced off four feet.
That's the freedom of speech zone.
Dude.
That's what's happening in standing rock
right now.
Have you talked about Sandra and.
I haven't.
We have.
We've talked about it very briefly
because I've been trying to pay
attention to it.
It's getting crazier from all sides.
You know,
this,
this group,
standing rock,
the standing rock Sioux.
They don't want an oil pipeline through
the fucking water supply.
That's a,
it should be the right and instead it's
this corporation,
it's just plowing through their sacred
land and you know,
the,
the cops.
I,
a girl had her arm nearly blown off.
They didn't quite have to amputate with
a concussion grenade by the cop.
I heard that.
And then the conspiracy theory online
was that it wasn't a concussion grenade
that it was something that they had
launched and then it went bad because
there was more than one propane tank
grenade or some shit.
See if you could find out,
get to the bottom of it,
Jamie.
But uh,
yeah,
I saw them spraying water on the
protesters.
It was like 40 degrees out there hosing
these people.
It was 23 degrees though subfreezing
temperatures wasn't really.
And they're hosing them in water and now
this is the best part.
On top of that,
the governor signed a mandatory eviction
thing for,
for all of them saying it's because of
cold temperatures and we're worried
about your safety.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
I wasn't real worried about,
we're going to hit you with concussion
grenades because we're worried about
your safety.
People are getting jacked by those
rubber bullets to rubber bullets can
take an eye out.
Folks.
Those things are no joke.
I can hurt you.
Bad to know a girl who lost an eye to a,
a face shot,
a tear gas canister that hit her,
hit her in the eye.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
No.
These,
these less than lethal rounds can
fucking do some damage.
Yes.
He can't.
He can't just,
that's,
that's like really weak assault.
That's like going up to someone.
You say you didn't start a fight,
but you start spitting out him and
slapping him.
You know,
like you're not trying to kill them,
but you definitely hurting them.
Like,
what do you do?
What the fuck are you doing,
nick?
Going after reporters.
This girl,
Erin Schrode,
she's been on ABC as a,
as a commentator and stuff.
She was down there.
There's video of her,
a viral video of her where she's
interviewing a guy as she's
interviewing,
she gets shot by a sniper with a rubber
bullet for doing nothing for just
interviewing her.
I've seen that.
Yeah.
Jamie,
have you seen that does.
It's incredible.
She just sitting there talking to
somebody and she gets shot.
They just fucking.
They just take pot shots at you.
Yeah man.
It's and it also creates this us versus
them environment where these guys who
are hired to be the cops that get rid of
the protesters are just regular people
and they've been given orders to get rid
of these protestors and in the protest
has become the enemy and then it becomes
an US versus them scenario,
which we're so accustomed to
and a lot of them are coming.
You are.
They coming back from Iraq and
Afghanistan and they're used to war
zones and they shouldn't be a war zone.
This a peaceful protest twos,
which it is.
Exactly.
You know,
I don't know what the answer is to
something like that.
I don't know how you stop what's already
been done and I don't know how he ever
got permission to go through somebody's
land if the land is public.
Okay.
That's one thing.
If you want to have a debate on whether
or not we can do what we can do with our
own national public lands.
I'm,
uh,
I'm against that.
I'm against.
I think we fucked up so much of this
country as it is.
Let's stop.
Let's not do anymore of that.
But if that's private land,
if it's privately with they own the
land.
Do they have a treaty land?
Yeah.
It's a rancher on the land to right?
If they're like,
no.
Yeah,
yeah.
The rancher who are ranchers lands.
There's another woman in Iowa St
pipeline though.
Dakota access.
Cindy Coppola.
She's a farmer.
She,
she's not native Americans.
He's a white woman farmer in Iowa.
They're coming through her own farm.
They arrested her for getting in their
way.
Yeah.
They said that they had to have access.
And so they made some sort of an
easement,
right?
They just,
yeah,
they just started.
They just,
they go into the city council and they
get something passed and the eminent
domain and they just take the land.
See,
that's what the problem is,
folks.
This is a company,
this is not the United States government
safety commission that needs this oil to
protect us from impending invaders.
There's nothing like in your best
interest about this.
This is all money that they're not going
to give you free oil because they got
that oil.
Most of it shipped overseas don't even
go to us.
It's billions of dollars in profit.
That's the darkness of this is that
they're going through land that's not
theirs and they think they just can
because they want oil.
Like I've seen people argue that,
you know,
oh,
this is exaggerated or that's
exaggerated,
but here's the cold faculty can't
ignore.
They're going through somebody else's
land against their will.
So either it's their land or it's not
their land.
It's their land.
Did you,
do they have a treaty?
Yes.
Does this guy have a ranch?
Does he own it?
Yes.
Stop.
You're the government,
right?
You know what that means?
Your people.
People can't go through other people's
fucking ground because they think they
want to.
You can't just do that.
The,
the,
the idea.
The hypothetical idea is that we elected
these people to do our bidding,
not to do the corporations bidding.
Whatever the fuck they want to make
profit.
Yeah.
Whether you left wing or right wing,
that's the most insane proposition is
giving the government that kind of power
to just go through private land and and
pumping oil pipeline under a fucking
river and that's where what
and that's where mostly the left and
right come together.
It's like Libertarians,
the left and nobody.
Nobody wants to just be like,
oh yeah,
you can just plow through someone's land
where they want it or not.
And it's convenient for people to poopoo
because it's not your land.
But if it was your land,
what if you had this bitch and stream in
your backyard?
And he used to like catch in it and
you're like,
God dammit baby.
We found the perfect spot to build a
house and you set up and everything's
good and then one day you go out and the
fish are fucking belly up and the
water's rainbow hued because it's filled
with oil and you're like,
oh no,
the pipelines leaking that pipe under
your house that they forced you to have
gang.
They're going through the Missouri River
and it's a drinking water for 18 million
people and that's what they're fighting.
I know a guy who had bone cancer and his
entire neighborhood had cancer because
they live next to a golf course and the
golf course,
the water from all the.
Well,
the pesticides,
it was getting into the groundwater and
drinking out a well.
Water is as these people got Jack.
Yeah,
that's.
That's.
That's what you really see it as when
like a whole neighborhood.
There was a whole neighborhood in
greenpoint,
Brooklyn that had brain tumors or stuff
because the oil spill underneath the
streets.
Oh,
it's crazy.
Jesus.
Jamie just did it.
Two,
three,
three and one,
two,
threes.
What have you done?
What have you done to Jamie?
Did you come in here with a spell?
Was there some sort of magic you have?
Lee Camp,
some sort of lefty magic,
dump water all over control panels,
man.
It's just.
It just makes me sad.
Oh,
here we go.
P police brain blame will lansky's
injury on protestors.
While we could not reach law
enforcement.
A Morton County sheriff's department
have released a statement on facebook on
the 23rd of November,
2016,
saying the injury was caused by an
exploding propane canister that
protesters were handling.
They later removed the post,
but Wayne Wilansky Willinsky Lansky told
us the statement is false if he had no
burns on her and while making a major
portion,
while major portion of her lower arm was
blown out.
Oh my God,
her hand was still attached by the own.
The bone making a claim that she was a
victim of a fire explosion seem
unlikely.
He said she was totally lucid after
being injured and recounted being struck
by a grenade like object and exploded on
contact with her arm.
So it's a flash grenade.
It's a flash grenade.
Okay.
So the other thing was the Ra.
Well,
when crazy things like this happen,
there's always a lot of stories floating
around.
It's hard to figure out what is it?
Oh,
there's some viral posts that everyone's
sending me of a woman,
a native American woman saying they're
dumping chemicals on the protesters.
And yet if you talk to anybody else,
it's not true or,
or it doesn't seem verified and yet
every,
it's so viral.
Everybody's emailing me this post of
them dumping chemicals on protesting.
Yeah.
Well that's what people do.
Um,
did you see the,
I think it was,
um,
I forget what one of the online
magazines caught up with a guy who
creates fake news stories and they asked
him why he did it.
And it's really interesting.
It was not dig the other day.
Well,
not just that,
it was also a,
he is,
um,
he's actually a democrat.
The guy who did it,
who they interviewed and they said that
he was trying to expose how vulnerable
the right is in particular to really
obviously fake stories.
So He'd make these really obviously fake
stories that anybody could like a
seconds
about the pope endorsing trump went
viral in the right.
What was one of them about a paid
protestor?
How much protesters getting these
protests are getting $300 an hour or
something like just ridiculous shit.
And then they.
These fucking people ran with it.
George Soros is paying those prototypes.
All these arrows just given free hand
jobs to every protest.
Dude.
I was in New York for the protests.
It was fascinating.
It was really like a lot of protests
right after trump won.
Oh,
it seemed like so much weird energy.
Someone's like,
chaotic.
We're lost energy.
Like to see the streets filled with
people.
I was like,
wow,
this has been Nana's like this is like
they close down streets.
He closed that entire streets was
hundreds of thousands of people.
Millions just walking down the street
screaming out slogans.
I made my.
My point is yeah,
they have.
They should be furious,
but they should have been furious five
years ago.
Like,
why wait until this?
Because we have bills,
bro.
Shit to think about it.
Got Problems.
My bowling games down,
dude.
Westworld is good.
It was good.
My kids keep flunking school.
People have all sorts of things,
so they got.
They got shit to do with them.
They got shit to do.
That's why I think just even the idea of
a person being president is fucking
ridiculous.
Like how's this guy gonna run the way he
does.
He have a life.
He has an actual life.
He has family does.
It doesn't even play golf.
Doesn't have like things you like to do.
Does he read?
How the fuck is this guy?
Good time to do all that stuff.
Hey Bush.
Had time to take more vacation days than
anyone had ever.
Probably a good move.
It's really good.
I mean we all knew that Dick Cheney,
who was running the show anyway,
I know we think we think we know we've
given increasing power to the president
when the president was supposed to be
one of three factors going on and now we
just keep feeding more and more power to
the president and that's the thing.
People that like Obama,
it's like he did not give away any power
that no president gives away any power
they've gotten.
So they just keep gaining and gaining
power.
Yeah.
Well that was the big question.
When the NDA was proposed it they said,
what happens if Obama was very
reasonable guy?
Most likely he won't use indefinite
detention.
Right?
But what if you get some new president?
That's crazy.
And then liquid happened.
Here,
let me,
let me give you a dictator's toolkit.
The largest surveillance infrastructure
ever.
Let me give you a the right to lock up
journalist without a trial or charges.
Let me give you the right to drone bomb.
Americans and American was.
It was a executed in drone bombings.
And as long as it's not an over here,
as long as it's not in our patch of
dirt,
we're cool with you killing Americans.
Flying Robots.
No trial,
no trial.
What was he,
what was he in?
Al Qaeda guy was the isis.
He joined isis or something.
And here's the thing is,
and I don't want to say the names
because I'll get them wrong,
but,
but his,
uh,
his father was preaching terrorism,
so they executed him and then executed
16 year old son.
Nowhere near him.
They just took out the sun.
They just decided the sun was too risky.
They are like,
AH,
why not?
Whoa.
That's some game of thrones shit,
isn't it?
That is right.
That's some game of thrones type shit.
You got to kill the sign.
And literally when they,
when they were finally answered as to
why they had executed the sun go,
one of them,
one of the press secretary's,
someone goes,
well,
you know,
he shouldn't have had a father like
that.
Can you imagine if everyone were
responsible for what their father did?
Jesus,
imagine if every father was responsible
for their kid.
Did exactly.
My argument has always been,
how come if your dog bites someone,
you can get sued.
If your kid shoots up a post office,
you're not liable.
You know,
like up to a certain age.
You should be liable for your kids like
23.
And you want to go that far?
Twenty three?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
You'll really work hard at doing a good
job.
Make sure you don't unleash that little
monster in the world.
So we have to deal with it.
Listen,
you dropped him 12 times and fed him Mac
and cheese all his life.
So what you have done,
if he fucked him now,
I mean how many people were out there?
Fucking their kids.
It happens.
A lot of monsters out there.
People need hotter pets and then they'd
leave the kids alone and hotter.
Pets.
Kidding.
These reality joke.
What the fuck?
I've gone off the rail.
I was going to say something.
I totally derailed.
That will fry your brain right there.
Yeah,
I'm not that.
I really think that people should be
responsible for the kids.
It's just,
it's odd what we are and aren't
responsible.
It's just amazing how easy it is to just
have a kid and they just do a shitty job
raising it.
Like you don't have a license to pump
out these fleshy idiots into the world.
Well,
it's not that you want to stop anybody
from doing it because who are you to
tell?
I mean somebody might want to tell you
that lead camp and all this bullshit
about the elite.
You think that fucking asshole should
have a kid?
Yeah.
He's going to have the kid.
That little lefty fucking
argue about some shit that I know is
wrong.
I mean they're going to decide that you
shouldn't have a kid.
So who the fuck?
You know,
there's a lot of people wait fucking
smarter than me and it became an
argument between who gets to breed.
Me or them they're going to win,
but I like having kids.
So what the fuck?
Great.
How many kids?
I have three.
I had to think about it for a second.
I thought you said I like having kids.
I thought we were going to hear like
seven or something.
Now I think about it because we were
talking to John Jones yesterday.
He's got four.
I left.
I was like,
God damn.
I got four kids already.
He's trying for a boy.
But my point being,
it's an uber complicated experience to
just hand off to everybody and the
outcome is a developed human being.
So we're counting on everybody to do a
good job developing us.
It lists at the beginning of idiocracy
is the truest thing that's ever been
created.
Do you remember that movie?
I never saw it.
Never saw it.
I have a bit.
Apparently that's extremely similar to
the premise of it.
Oh,
really came out before the movie on
showtime,
Luckily.
So it's documented and that movie was so
in
the fucking knew what was gonna happen
at the very,
very beginning of the movie is just,
it's just too.
They just show a split screen of a
really dumb idiot couple,
you know,
uh,
maybe rednecks,
but just like,
they're,
they're fucking morons.
They clearly don't know what the fuck's
going on and they're just pumping out
kids.
They just fucking dust into kids and
then they answer these,
you know,
little liberal elite couple living in a
brownstone in New York deciding whether
to have a child.
And each year goes by and they're like,
no,
we decided not yet.
We will do it soon and,
and they never have the kid,
meanwhile the rednecks and pumped out 42
kids and it's like,
well that's your world.
That is what happens.
People that are career oriented,
especially if the,
you know,
the husband and the wife can't decide
who's going to stay home with the kid if
they,
they're both career oriented.
It becomes a thing like,
hey,
let's wait until we're 36.
Hey,
let's wait until we're 42.
let's freeze my eggs,
you know,
hey,
let's,
you know,
and then next thing you know,
you adopt,
I think you should be allowed to freeze
a kid.
At least,
you know,
up to five.
Adopting you know,
is a great idea and it's,
it's awesome that a lot of people do it,
but people want their own kids.
You know.
That's the other weird thing about it,
about DNA is like,
you want your own DNA DNA pumped into my
boy.
That's my boy John.
You came right out of my own body.
I'll teach you the way,
the way of the Mayan.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
it's a very odd thing that we do it so
often though,
you know,
like even me,
I'm guilty.
I told you I've got three of them,
but I look around,
there's 7 billion people on this planet.
I'm like,
man,
maybe got,
we got too many people.
Sit down the kids and talk to them.
Hey guys,
let's do this guys.
I think all of us hang together.
You don't need your own kids.
Come on,
I had you get a get a dog,
get a nice dog,
snuck a nice little dog.
Has a shitload
paypal.
We,
that's the thing is America as we're way
out numbered.
Oh yeah.
Way Out numbered here.
The world,
you know,
India.
Well that's a cool thing about America
when you fly over,
like if the shit gets really bad,
we have so many places to expand.
We have so many new subdivisions we
could open up in the middle of nowhere.
Like when you're flying over and you see
nothing but like empty space,
like,
oh,
we could fucking live here.
Yeah,
yeah.
Lots of rooms play a space.
We just uh,
just kinda settled down.
Breeding.
You think about that when you're sitting
in la traffic,
you're like,
you know,
pays there is out there.
Why are we all in four feet in la?
Traffic is no hang right worldwide.
I've been to Mexico City,
Mexico City like stoplights aren't even
the suggestion.
They're just bullshit.
Nobody's paying attention to anything.
It's a perpetual traffic jam and people
just weaseling left and right and like
in trying to merge into the stream of
perpetual gridlock,
they just go for it,
go for it,
and all of a sudden they're in the
middle and they go for it.
No one's letting anybody in.
You got to catch people that are
sleeping in or you just got to be really
rude about it.
And do you think people are people that
people in Mexico City was just like that
initially or do you think that came from
like,
no cop wants to pull someone over
because they don't want to get shot?
I think it's the population.
It's too high.
It's just too high.
Mexico City has an incredible
population.
I think it's the number one city in the
world is Mexico City.
Number one,
Tokyo is number was $35 million into
really 35 dude in Tokyo.
They have.
They have people whose job it is to cram
people onto the subway.
I've seen just the elbow.
The people in the subways.
Yeah.
How about that?
Thirty 5 million people in the ground
moves every couple of years.
Good luck.
Have Fun.
Stay.
Stay together.
Keep it together people.
But that's interesting.
Thirty 7 million.
Oh my God.
800,000 in Tokyo.
Holy Shit.
So that's number one and I haven't even.
Mexico City.
I'll probably not nearly as many as
that.
I want to say it's.
I want to say 30,
21.
We'll go with.
Let's go with.
Let's go with the better.
When I said 30.
Either way it's a totally congested
city.
It's completely jammed up with people,
but
la is on the way to that.
It's on its way.
It's not going to get there tomorrow.
We'll get there in 20 years.
Yeah,
it's.
I don't know.
We should all go live out in the middle
of nowhere.
Well,
problem is.
This is a really good spot.
You know what else,
speaking of how open the country is,
people fucking are buying up all the
land,
like the scientologists own all the land
and who was it?
Ted Turner,
a seed guy who created CNN.
He owns enough land in America that it's
equivalent to the size of Delaware.
Whoa.
He's balling out of control people,
but he got rid of Jane Fonda because she
came Christian.
Is that true?
Yeah.
No,
definitely.
Probably other factors.
I mean,
I'm just saying it because it's a good
soundbite and that's what I read online.
She was great and knew who the fuck
knows.
I mean maybe they just stopped liking
each other.
Maybe what do I know?
What do I give a fuck?
But I just thought it was fascinating
that she became a Christian,
like really late in life and he was
like,
check.
Yeah,
no,
I'd be the same way.
You can't show up Christian and my door.
Come on,
but if you're dating a girl and she was
like super cool,
but she got into yoga and then she got
an idea cities.
Then she got his writings of Christ.
He came home one day and she's reading
the Bible,
what are you doing?
That's just an interesting book.
Yeah.
Well,
I picked up this novel and I said,
I'm going to live my life by head Turner
Ranch Ted Turner's Weird Faq.
I keep saying Mr Turner,
Mr Turner,
that you say frequently asked questions.
How large or Mr Turner's landholdings.
Mr Turner is the second largest
individual land owner in the united in
North America with the POC summit.
Oh my God.
Approximately 2 million acres of
personal and ranch land and the 12 us
states and Argentina.
Wow.
Argentina.
So now look up how many million acres of
Delaware and we'll see whether I'm
making shit up,
whether there's something weird about
like owning a ranch in Argentina.
What's going on,
Bro?
You have a branch here.
You have 2 million acres here and you've
got a ranch in Argentina.
Are you going to live forever?
What's happening,
sir?
Well,
yeah.
Well that you get to the brain in the
jar.
Him and the Koch are going to have their
brains in jars running the big almost
twice the size of Delaware.
Wow.
That's incredible.
He's got more property than Delaware
Bowling.
Probably more entertaining.
The Delaware balling out of control.
He's got a girlfriend.
Just ships in Russians probably when you
get to that much money,
you just have Russian orgy,
so I think.
Yeah,
they just show up,
dude.
Have you heard the sumner redstone tapes
during the trial?
What's that?
He's like,
so he had this big trial and he's like
98 or whatever it is,
96 or something and the tapes that they
played to show that he was with it were
him arranging and worksheet.
Oh my God,
he's,
he's in his nineties.
He's like,
you know,
then you'll suck me off.
And on this guy sumner redstone,
he's one of the biggest media owners in
the world or whatever.
And how they filled him doing this.
It was a tape,
I don't know how it was recorded,
but it was a taped phone call that they
submitted to show that he was mentally
with lucid,
but he was lucid because they were
trying to take his company from him.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
So he submitted that.
What does it,
Ted Turner,
the 73 year old billionaire,
founder of CNN,
has revealed that he has for
girlfriends,
each of which whom he spends one week
with a month.
Wow.
I love the idea of having four
girlfriends,
but they've got you nailed down per
week.
I love him.
Jane Fonda's probably screaming when
she's reading this.
Just looking at our screen
that says
she went to standing rock though Jane
Fonda went to standing rock and fed the
protesters.
They let her off the hook after that.
Hanoi Jane stuff that thinks she's
finally gotten past that poor girl.
Don't get in the tank down.
Get getting the tank when you're like,
how old was she at the time?
I have no idea.
Twenties.
Yeah,
and when you're that young,
hey look,
ma involved and well being in the tank
wasn't right,
but most people would agree she was
probably right.
That Vietnam shouldn't have been
happening.
We shouldn't have been bombing hundred
percent.
One hundred percent.
Right.
It's just that message was so confusing
to people because it was the first war
that we shouldn't have done.
Like all the sudden we're the bad guy,
whereas when we're killing native
Americans might have some qualms with
first we shouldn't have done,
but uh,
but you know what I mean,
it was the first native American was
more of a genocide that he was a war,
but I mean the battles,
but I mean like,
uh,
an army shipping off to do battle with
opposing army.
This is the first time like,
Whoa,
we're,
we're wrong here.
And on TV you're seeing the body's.
Yeah.
So there was a lot of people that were
trying to protest it.
And then when you're 20 or in your
twenties,
you're so clumsy as it is you.
So it's so likely you're going to get
the message out wrong.
Yeah.
She,
that was the wrong way to do it.
She fucked up.
But I know it Jane,
man,
that stuck with her forever,
for decades.
Many of twitter was around back then.
Shit.
Oh God.
Oh my God.
You'd be tarred
and feathered so quickly.
Yeah.
Like if she did a reddit ask me anything
in the seventies,
I'm in a tank and asked me anything.
Oh my God.
Oh,
whoops.
Do you.
What are your thoughts on like the,
the public shaming,
the mob just get out of hand sometimes.
Too Fun for people.
That's the problem is it becomes too fun
to fun to attack
and they love to see people that got you
going
fall 100 percent.
Yeah.
People love that.
It's unfortunate.
It's unfortunate because it's new power
that people have and we're yielding and
against each other sometimes for the
wrong reasons.
Sometimes for the right reasons.
I mean,
I think um,
I think certain people who've done
terrible shit.
I mean I couldn't think of any offhand I
could think of like a lot of those
football players,
like the one guy knocked his girlfriend
out and in,
in the elevator like that.
That guy deserved all that shame.
You know,
like what the fuck man,
you just,
you punched her in the face,
like you can't restrain her.
She's trying to hit you.
So you left hooked her.
Can you grab a hold of her man?
You're a giant,
big,
giant super athlete and you killed your
wife.
That's fucked up.
Right.
I think a lot of us had that sort of
feeling and so when a guy like that gets
all this blow back for something like
that,
it,
you know,
it's deserved.
But there's been some people that have
been attacked for some shit that didn't
make any sense.
Oh,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
Some.
Yeah.
I mean hell,
there's that new documentary out on
Amanda Knox.
Like what do you think about that?
She's totally innocent if you watch the
watch the document.
I.
So here's the thing,
I went little fill out the story for
people in Italy,
right?
I went in with kind of a blank mind
because I didn't pay attention to almost
any of it.
Uh,
when it was happening,
she was,
she was dumb and I just mean like young
dumb.
I don't mean young.
I just being young,
dumb a exchange student or whatever.
And she's in Italy and she's,
when she's in a housing unit with a girl
she's kind of friendly with,
she goes and stays at her boyfriend's
place,
comes back the next day the door's
locked and I can't get it open,
but they see some blood on the car.
But they call the cops,
they opened the door,
the girls,
dad,
there's blood everywhere.
She's been raped and stabbed and beaten
and then they,
they found the guy that did it,
but they were so keen on going after
Amanda Knox.
It was just like,
it's gotta be her.
And then honestly I think what indicted
or is she seems to be a little off.
She seemed that maybe have some
asperger's or something so she wasn't
behaving emotionally.
Like people are used to someone behaving
and that's all it was.
It's like she had for sure,
I think pretty for sure.
Yeah.
And,
and so they convicted her,
then they,
then they found her not guilty and then
they ultimately found her not guilty
again.
So.
And she,
they,
they tried to bring her back to the
country.
Right.
They tried to bring her back for the
supreme court trial,
but they went along with it anyway.
She didn't come back and.
But she was found not guilty again
because the DNA evidence was bullshit.
It was so contaminated.
It was.
And if someone does get pronounced not
guilty and they've been put through that
Har for all those years,
did they get any compensation for that?
No.
Nothing.
Nothing you can do.
That's scary.
Occasionally when you've got a guy like
in theu ,
s has been in jail for 30 years.
They'll give them like a million dollars
or something,
but it doesn't.
It doesn't bring their life back.
That's scary.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
No,
she.
I mean her life and her boyfriend's life
were just destroyed and she spent.
Do you remember that fucking guy who got
accused of being the Olympic Village
bomber and he was a security guard and
they smeared his name.
What was his name?
Richard.
Richard Jewel.
I'm pretty dude.
They put that guy on TV.
They said he was the bomber and he was
just a regular old security guard.
Didn't do anything wrong.
I was.
I was a kid at that Olympics and we were
deciding whether to go to the next day
after the bombing bomb blew up.
Did he kill anybody?
Killed one person won't bleed.
He died of a heart attack.
I believe I was there that night.
It wasn't there when a bomb went off,
but I was going to be like,
we were going to go to a basketball
game.
There was like the US Dream Team was
playing and we went to the one sculptor,
woodlands buy tickets,
so he left,
but on our way home that happened like
we were on the subway going out to a
suburb.
My mom was calling everyone around us
thinking like we got caught in it.
I have video of the park,
the park and whoever was on stage that
day,
but we met.
I'm not like a really cool because I
wasn't in the bomb,
but like it was there that
Callan was in New York City and I'm
Gotham comedy club.
When the most recent bomb went off,
he was six blocks away from me.
He will that.
What was it?
What was the pressure cooker bomb?
It hurt a lot of people.
It didn't kill anybody,
but it hurt a lot of people.
It was an unknown.
One of those remote controlled pressure
cooker jammies or they set it and he
just walked away from it.
Say this God,
the fact that someone could just do that
just indiscriminately blow up a bunch of
people and blow shrapnel into their
body,
but that guy got accused that jewel,
Richard Jewel guy.
The guy got accused publicly.
The news ran with it.
They didn't have any evidence.
It was all wrong.
He didn't do anything and everybody was
like,
oh,
they found him.
They found him.
They put his picture on the fucking
newspaper cover.
Oh,
oh,
that guy after the Boston bombing,
another pressure cooker after the Boston
bombing,
they put those guys on the front of the
New York Post or whatever it was,
stone remember,
and it wasn't.
Well,
no,
that was a real guy.
These are the innocent guys that they
did.
They did put them on.
They were like,
FBI is looking for this guy,
and it was like his life was torn apart
and he's like on facebook,
like I didn't bomb.
Anyway.
What do you have those?
See if he could find that photo.
Jamie,
I freaked out about that until you just
brought that up.
Within the first day,
one day his life was destroyed because
you're walking down the street.
People think they're looking at the
Boston monomer.
That's so ridiculous.
And that's,
that's the fucking running
with information we don't have yet.
Well,
that's why people that have that sort of
responsibility,
like you're,
you're,
you're the media.
The,
the official stamped media.
That's why,
you know,
rolling stone took so much heat when
they had that cute bomber on the cover
of Hanson Hanson.
Bummer.
It's like that guy could have got so
much tail.
Was he on?
Was he on the fucking cover of rolling
stone to being a bomber?
He shouldn't be out there.
Getting chicks does seem like if these
guys got laid a little more,
they wouldn't have done this shit back
and seek these two pictures at Boston
marathon.
Meanwhile,
they're just fucking dudes and that kind
of blue.
Like next day he's walking down the
street being called a bomber.
God dammit.
Yeah.
Those,
those big mistakes.
There it is.
Sorry.
Dewey Beats Truman.
They get that guy in Dallas shooting
too.
That was walking around with a gun that
it thought it was him because people saw
a picture of him with a gun walking
around the street,
but he had actually turned in the gun to
police officer.
Remember that?
I'm talking about.
I do remember that,
but vaguely.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
In Dallas.
Yeah.
Uh,
go ahead.
I'm sorry.
Please go ahead.
Well,
no,
I was going to say,
Oh,
you know what I wish people were still
talking about with the Boston bombing is
there was a third guy who wasn't there.
They said he was friends with the
bombers,
so they wanted to interview him.
The FBI goes down to what?
Florida,
Georgia,
somewhere interviews and four times the
fourth time.
And they admit he was unarmed.
They shoot him seven times.
Once in the back of the head.
Yeah.
Abraham to have just executed the guy.
The FBI did.
And then they came out and said,
oh,
he had a gun.
Oh,
he had a knife,
A.
Oh,
nevermind.
He had a stick.
Oh,
well we,
he didn't have any weapons,
but we feared for our lives and it's
like you're the fourth interview with
the guy.
You just execute him.
It's crazy.
Wow.
But what better way to get the cute boy
on the rolling stone cover to talk to
the pump?
Seven bullets into your friend,
his friend.
I mean,
that's how you get to do the talk and
here's a picture of your friend.
Yeah.
I just shot him in the fucking head.
I'm going to shoot you to tell me.
Tell me who told you to do this.
You have to do this.
Fuck fuckface here's a video on my
phone.
Just so you know that I really shot your
friend.
But that's.
But that's our media.
How is that not a story basically.
Basically never mentioned in the
meeting.
Like really briefly mentioned.
So,
so briefly that I forgot about it until
you just brought it up.
I had totally forgotten about that.
I'm like,
Oh yeah,
the Jack Back Guy,
you know,
but we're like fucking guy's a bad guy.
Friends.
He was friends with fucked up,
fucked up shit.
Been hanging around.
Thought about who his father was,
she thought about those friends were too
God damn.
It's people that have that kind of
power.
Like that's an enormous responsibility.
You have a gun,
you're job is part of your job is to
shoot people when they fuck up.
Like,
whoa.
Yeah,
and you're at the highest level,
right?
You're the FBI,
you're there to protect national
security,
Federal Bureau of Information.
I feel like they're not taught how to
deescalate shit.
They're only taught how to ask you.
I'm sure they're taught how to
deescalate.
I'm absolutely sure that they don't
stick with that training.
Let's just say that there are people.
There's a real problem with giving
people power,
you know,
giving anyone power over other people.
It's like that's a,
it's a very intoxicating position.
Especially like the kind of life or
death power someone with a gun has and
people don't want to listen to you.
You know?
And the other thing is like how many
people could handle that kind of
pressure day in,
day out for 10 years or 20 years.
I totally agree.
Those guys,
a shitload of pressure,
but that still means we're doing
something wrong.
If they're executing people,
oh,
this,
oh look,
it's 100 percent wrong.
It's 100 percent wrong,
but the whole stew is wrong from
everything we've discussed from people,
anybody being able to have a person,
which I don't have any solution for.
I'm not a eugenics guy.
I'm not saying I'm not offering up any
sort of crazy solution.
All I'm saying is we all agree that part
of the problem is people get raised by
horrible,
awful people who abused them and beat
them and rape them and they're subjected
to all sorts of horrible shit as are
growing up and they develop all fucked
up and we all know people like that.
They're just all fucked up and those
people would just cast out into the
world.
And this is,
this is what our world is made up.
Our world is made out of people.
I mean our civilization at least.
Well,
this is why I think,
and maybe people will get behind me on
this there,
so the numbers are.
It's rough,
but they think in a sociopath test about
pet test,
about one out of every hundred people is
a sociopath and those people usually do
really well in business.
They get to the top of corporations,
they become president of United States
and it's like we should have a sociopath
test for high ranking of it.
You'd have to completely define it as
someone who really doesn't have feelings
for other people.
Right.
You'd have to be able to really nail
that down,
but feelings are so emotions and
emotional connections and empathy.
It's such a poorly defined thing because
someone who watches a lot of movies and
reads a lot of books,
you can say the right words.
If you're a manipulator.
I without actually feeling it,
you could say all the right words,
you know?
Yup.
It happens to people all the time in
relationships.
Like,
you know,
girl me to guy,
he's charming and he tells her he loves
her and I mean really just as like he's
doing stuff that he saw in a movie and
then,
you know,
maybe four or five months in she
realizes,
oh my God,
he's a total psychopath.
And like he's just saying things not to
say anything.
He just knew how to say the right things
were the right Cologne,
whatever it was,
say the right things at the right time
because he's had a lot of practice and
at the end of it,
and there's a person who's like
literally barely a person,
like some sort of a robot reciting
things,
you know what I mean?
That was,
did you ever read,
um,
was the Bret Easton Ellis book?
They turned into a movie.
Bradley Cooper.
What?
American psycho.
Yeah.
Right.
Psycho.
But that's a Christian Bale.
Yeah.
Bret Easton Ellis.
This book,
the book is terrifying.
It's way more terrifying than the movie.
I didn't,
I didn't read the book.
The book is awful.
I remember like people not awful like a
bad book,
like it's really well written,
but it's awful like holy
shit and by the way,
how much did the trump kids look like?
American psycho.
It's like they're trying,
well,
how do you look if your dad's a
billionaire?
He probably can't look any other way.
I have two options.
You go all in with pops and you join the
family business or you become like that
surfer dude who like a band.
When we really got into drugs and we
brought in into counseling,
fell far from the tree.
You can be like in the Malibu,
Rehab,
perfect.
Permanently with flip flops on you feet
up and they keep you sober,
but you know,
you just like to surf.
Your Dad just pays for your treatment.
I mean they have like a special kind of
hair gel for like the kids of
billionaires.
I don't know how they slick it back like
that.
Well,
it's liberal tears.
They just scoop amount of buckets of
Hillary Clinton rallies.
They just kick liberals in the balls,
collect the tears.
They just went around that night.
We all,
the people were crying when Hillary
lost.
They just gathered them up,
gathered up those tears and nice slick
their hair back.
Yeah,
I think that's it.
It's going to be interesting.
You know,
we're gonna.
Find out how much power the president
actually has to.
Because like that,
this trump election,
let us know,
hey,
the system actually does work.
Like someone can come in that's not
being represented by their party.
The party didn't want him in.
Someone can come in and still win,
but sadly,
so far Bernie Sanders got closed.
But right now,
only if you have a billion dollars.
Right?
But I think
that's going to change.
First of all,
no one liked Bernie ever existed before
Bernie.
Right?
Agreed.
So all of a sudden,
Bernie comes in.
Now here's the thing.
If trump's policies start working out,
that's when everyone's
fucked.
If he,
if all of a sudden we realize,
oh,
well,
here were the log jams.
He's right,
like Holy Shit,
we're prospering is holy shit.
Look,
all this good stuff that's happening
does have massive infrastructure
projects that put people to work so that
he can have his name trump across the
bullets to the trump train,
the trump,
this,
trump that.
Even if he just does that,
that could make people pretty happy.
People very happy.
Yeah.
It's interesting.
It's interesting because he's a total
outsider who has paid off the insiders
for a long time.
If now he's in.
If he follows through,
here's the scary thing is,
is in a way,
if he follows through with just
bringing us back from bombing every
country,
it's like that alone could be a big step
and it's like,
oh,
we needed a fucking crazy motherfucker
to do that.
To finally say,
why are we in all these other countries
and start to say this for me.
He was already basic.
Well,
okay.
Protestors and him stopped the TPP,
the transpacific partnership,
the fucking largest corporate coo that's
ever been devised and basically,
you know,
he said he wasn't going to sign it.
Now here's the thing,
he's not.
He's going to create a new trade deals,
so it's going to be awful.
He's going to put that forward so it's
not like he's done creating havoc in
that way,
but the fact that the TPP is over is a
huge
step.
It is.
It's an interesting step and what I was
saying earlier that one of the things
that a lot of people said that I agree
with is that I think him being a
populist and him being really interested
in public's opinion and what people
think about him is actually a good thing
because when certain things he says like
you off the cuff says shit off the cuff,
and then he finds out that is really a
stupid thing to say.
He amends like what he says and I think
that's kind of interesting because like
if he starts to talk about some specific
set of regulations or rules and then the
public starts freaking out about it,
it's very likely he might reconsider if
it makes sense.
Well,
this is how he's kind of like a standup
comic because he was going from speech
to speech.
Basically.
He would weed out the stuff that wasn't
getting a huge reaction.
Keep the stuff that got a big reaction
and it was just a greatest hits.
He was just playing the hits,
just doing a set.
You have a strong set and yeah,
but dude,
by the end of the election,
like after all the grab the pussy stuff
and after the last debate he was doing a
run of these speeches and I tuned into
one of them and I was like,
the guy sounds pretty reasonable right
now.
Like right now in this moment,
if you could like take this snippet
instead of the other snippets when he's
gone to the wall,
just got 10 feet higher.
Instead of that take this snippet and
you go with this guy.
Very reasonable.
He's talking about corruption.
He's talking about deep suited,
the deep seated red tape.
It's almost impossible to remove because
it's an ecosystem and all these people,
they had been feeding off of each other
and the bureaucracy roots run deep and
you just got to pull it out.
You've got to drain the swamp.
I totally agree with all that.
The problem is now you look at his
cabinet,
he's grabbing the same swan things.
Putting them,
well billionaire,
but he's putting the swamp things baggy.
No,
he's talking about Patraeus.
It's like,
and all these,
all these assholes.
It was,
it.
Uh,
I can't,
I don't know who he ended up going with
for treasury secretary,
but he was talking about Jamie diamond
for awhile.
The fucking head of Citibank.
I mean,
sorry jp Morgan Chase that was behind
the collabs bind what created.
Occupied.
Like he's putting the swamp things back
in the swamp he's drained at and now
he's putting.
What was he trying to portray us in for?
Had a defense.
Right.
That's an interesting choice.
I don't know.
You might want to verify that trace
thing is fascinating because portrays,
didn't do anything that was really that
awful.
He had an affair.
He leaked information.
Right.
But what did he do?
He leaked information to this girlfriend
that he was dating.
She will follow up with it.
How heavy was it?
Like what was the information?
I don't know what the information.
Was it top secret?
I don't know.
A secretary of state supporters he was
looking for.
Yeah.
Well,
he's um,
he's an interesting case because he's a
case of the FBI and the CIA don't like
each other that much.
That's where this came from.
This is what's so fascinating about it.
Patraeus was running the CIA,
the FBI does an investigation on the CIA
because portray us is banging this chick
and she's crazy and she likes to send
crazy emails to people.
He was,
he was banging some nutty abroad and uh,
and so that's what sunk this,
this crazy lady was making some noise
threatening people.
She was threatening certain people and
then they want who's,
what's going on here?
And it turns out there collect kinda
swinger type characters or something.
Petraeus was hitting it hollow and next
thing you know this and then portray has
had an affair with this other woman
who's writing an autobiography on,
that's what it was.
Now I'm remembering the autobiography
woman and the other lady got into it and
then I didn't follow any of those.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And so the CIA was like a what?
And then the FBI was like,
fuck's going on over here?
And then that's how we wound up getting
in trouble.
That's where it all went down.
That's why he got stripped.
I covered him when he.
So he got into fracking.
He was the front of a corporation that
was pushing fracking around the US,
post his.
I'm removed from the army after that and
uh,
he had a year or two doing this and they
said they fly him out to North Dakota
where all the fracking is going on.
And he's introduced by the one of the
higher ups in North Dakota government.
I can't remember if it was a,
I can't remember what her job was,
but you know,
lieutenant governor or something and she
introduces him and she's clearly not
very bright and she introduces him.
She goes,
it was such a privilege to have David
Petraeus here.
He's here,
he's talking about fracking so that we
never have to go overseas to get the oil
we need like we did in Iraq.
And it was like,
that's,
you're not supposed to admit that we
went to get the oil.
That's part of it.
That's part of the secret.
Right.
And so,
and he goes up and he's just like,
thank you for that lovely introduction.
And I'm like,
she just said that
went to war for oil.
That is not supposed to be what you're
admitting.
Like you,
you're supposed to say,
hey,
we went to war for freedom.
Right.
We're given an Iraqi freedom whenever
they go,
wow works.
But he's not responsible for her.
He's probably just being polite.
I didn't want to have to correct her
ma'am.
We actually went to war for freedom.
For Freedom.
Yes.
This is a,
this is incorrect.
I can continue.
Yeah,
he was,
he was teaching at City College.
And do you ever see those protests where
he'd walk to his car and they'd be
screaming criminal war commodore and
it's great war criminals.
I think that these kids need to face
that shit.
They should see people in their driveway
yelling at him.
Yeah.
It's um,
it's real interesting that you could get
taken down like him just because you
were having an affair.
Like he,
they got him out because of that,
like a because of adultery and because
the,
the top secret clearance stuff.
Right.
Well,
I think the adults or anything but just
to make him look bad,
but it was really the leaking leg to his
girlfriend who was writing books.
Right?
Yeah.
That's crazy.
Isn't it funny that like the,
the most powerful military people are
still just vulnerable to the.
Well,
yeah.
But here's the thing.
He could have been at the Deq pillowtalk
Ya.
He could have been having an affair is
all over the place.
No one would have tried to stop him
because he's top of the military.
But once you started leaking the
information and things change.
Hey,
what was your opinion of that journalist
that wound up allegedly committing
suicide by driving his car head on into
a tree?
Remember Michael Hastings.
Hastings.
Yeah.
What did you think about it?
I think that I think that there's a lot
of evidence that he was probably taken
out
because it's got the right doing this 19
late Harvey Oswald acted alone.
And,
and it is.
Here's the thing.
So we know he emailed and by the way,
it's,
it's fucking sad and horrific weather
whether he was taken out or not taken
out.
It's fucking horrific.
Uh,
because he was such an amazing reporter
and amazing ability did wrote the story
for Rolling Stones for rolling stone
about Petraeus and about some of those
guys was another,
it was actually another general two and
he,
there was something that the general,
it's said like in some way mocking the
president [inaudible] and he printed
that.
Yeah.
And it set off this whole chain of
events that guy went up stepping down
and people were furious at him for
making this guy stepped down when he was
embedded,
was embedded for an extended period of
time because he was only supposed to be
there for a shorter amount of time.
And then he stayed for a longer time
because something had happened.
They couldn't get them out of that.
He did the right thing,
which is you're not supposed to become
best buddies with these guys.
She was supposed to keep being a
legitimate reporter.
And most people,
most people embedded,
don't they?
They become friends with them.
And,
but uh,
here's the thing a lot of people don't
know is he sent an email to buzz feed.
That's where he was working at the time,
right.
Saying,
Hey,
I'm onto something pig.
I'm not going to.
Might not hear from me for awhile if the
FBI shows up to the offices,
uh,
tell them you need a lawyer and don't
talk to them.
So that email goes out like it's like 24
hours or something before his car
explodes in a fiery mass here in la.
And uh,
it,
it seems like they definitely could have
been hacking of the,
you know,
who's going 100 miles an hour now.
I've also heard some people saying he
was,
he was into some wild stuff and while
driving,
but I don't know,
will they,
um,
they definitely found methodist system
allegedly according to the coroner who
was absolutely not paid off,
he asked.
But if you read,
if you read the full coroner's report,
it says not at a level that would have
impaired driving.
It's like a trace of some stuff of math.
Yeah.
But what I was going to say was that,
um,
I think,
correct me if I'm wrong,
I think if you take adderall,
he took a lot of adderall in particular.
I think that has almost exact same
chemicals as math.
Right.
Wouldn't you test positive for meth if
you were taking a lot of adderall?
I,
that's a good question.
I have no idea.
Please look that up.
Jamie,
do you think,
what do you think?
Let's just guess.
Let's play
test positive for meth.
If you're taken adderall,
I think that you could test positive for
meth if there's probably certain certain
other chemicals in your system.
The unrelated to math,
what the urinalysis test for any and all
amphetamines and methamphetamines is
just one derivative.
Similarly,
adderall is a combination drug comprise
of two amphetamine salts,
Dextro,
amphetamine,
and level amphetamine.
Any of the three will show positive for
amphetamines in a urine drug test,
so they all get on well done.
Wow.
Joe Rogan,
everybody adderalls math,
so he could have been just taken
adderall,
which is super common amongst writers.
When you have a deadline you have to
bang out something.
You're exhausted.
I mean it is almost mandatory amongst a
lot of writers.
Yeah.
But so,
I mean,
and even so it's like trace amounts
wouldn't have impaired driving and he's
going 100 miles an hour and these cars
are,
the car he was in was,
had a hackable computer.
Oh yeah.
Well they can do it now for sure.
I mean that's what we're talking about
previously.
All these autonomous cars,
there's a lot of cars now like the Tesla
where you can get on the road and you
could press a button and take your
fucking hands off the wheel.
And the navigation system drives the car
100 percent.
My buddy texted me from his fucking car.
He's like sitting there texting me while
he's driving.
So this is a car right now today that
can do that.
So if you,
if there is no requirement that you keep
looking at the road,
well you're supposed to actually have
your hands on the wheel,
but you don't have to.
The BMW seven series apparently has a
very similar technology,
but you have to hold onto the wheel.
Like it'll do all the driving.
It'll do all the breaking.
There's a lot of acceleration,
but it wants your hands on the wheel
just in case some shit goes down like
please pay attention as much as
possible.
We're gonna make it as safe as possible.
We're going to do all the work,
but right here at 10 and two,
10 to buddy.
I wonder who do.
Does the human or the computer when,
if like you were accelerating into a
tree with the computer stuff or would it
just be like,
oh,
it's a very good question.
I don't know.
He's a very good question.
Humans got it covered.
Yeah,
that's a very good question.
Yeah.
This guy's trying to commit a homicide.
There isn't a question,
but what happened if there's like people
crossing the street with the car hit the
people are safe.
The people in the car,
which is almost a better question.
That's a very good question.
A moral judgment calls like,
what do you do if an animal runs in
front of your car?
What does the car do?
Because the car looking at these trees
to the right trees,
to the left and an animal runs in front
of the car.
What do you do?
Well and if it slams on the brakes,
the guy behind you could plow into you.
Maybe if it's like maybe there's a size
limit,
like if it's a rat you just kill it.
But if it's a dog slam on the brakes,
maybe don't want anybody to lose their
dog.
Has a cuteness test.
Yes.
Or the animal.
Yeah.
Like if it's a rat you kill it.
But if it's a squirrel you tried to
swerve,
you're really sad.
If you hit a button,
right?
If it's a deer,
fuck it.
But if it's a bunny,
obviously that one word guy hits a bear
was going like 60 miles an hour.
That one,
the really recent one.
This guy is driving and he's talking.
I think he's talking about getting baked
too,
which is really funny and this fucking
bear just jumps out of nowhere.
I really think he was talking about
getting high while it happened.
So this guy's drive and he's
accelerating and as he's driving down
the road,
this bear just jumps in front of his
car.
He slams into the bear and the bear
literally goes launching the air.
And then the bear gets up and runs off
into the woods.
So there was fine dude that probably
not,
probably had massive internal injuries.
Watch this.
Here it goes.
Ah,
hold on.
Let me give me the full volume.
Do it from the beginning.
Jesus,
listen,
I want to go home and smoke a fucking
huge fucking.
So he's talking about getting baked shit
out of a fucking bear.
And he just slammed into this bear dude.
The bears.
No,
no,
no.
That Paris dead
hobbled off,
but it's going to die.
I'm pretty sure it's going to die.
That the impact.
Watching one more time because I enjoy
these things.
One more time.
Why should more volume?
Please
do that as not a financial.
There's no way that animals find bears
are pretty tough.
Pretty tough.
I would imagine that thing's dead.
I would imagine you're dealing with
massive internal hemorrhages.
He just slammed into that thing and went
flat.
I mean,
how many feet do you think it went?
Let's see.
The impact.
One more time.
Please do it.
It's just really roll one more time.
It's amazing that I can walk.
It hits the ground.
It gets up and starts hobbling off into
the woods.
You're going to make this your ringtone
or you know,
let's go champ.
Let's go chat.
Inspiring toe.
Man.
That's crazy.
I'm going to go home and smoke it.
But that is obviously in the animal that
your car would stop for so big ass
animals and does it.
So the coach just assumes there's no Mac
truck behind you.
That's just gonna drive over to.
Very good question.
It's a very good question.
Yeah,
I mean that doesn't make judgment calls
and you could make the wrong one and
maybe its calculations will be more
accurate than yours,
but maybe it'll just be going slower in
the first place so that it won't be as
much of an issue.
So it,
if these cars are going the speed limit,
I'm going to lose my shit.
Like if that guy was going exactly.
I was driving down the road and he was
going 10 miles an hour slower.
He might've been able to slam on the
brakes and avoid that.
They're showing you yesterday.
But uh,
well I thought it was going around
because it was new.
But this Tesla slams into the back of
this van.
Oh No.
See at the last second.
Because that car.
Oh well I guess there's some verbiage in
that autonomous driving that it may not
see parked vehicles on highways or
something.
Oh my God.
So like if you're going 60 miles an
hour.
So it was the computers were watching
the moving car and ignored the stuffed
time to see it or recognize.
So there's a bunch of them,
but you know what?
That's to be expected with some new
technology.
There's no way it's going to come out of
the bat and it's going to be out of the
bat,
Bat,
bat out of the barn with this Goddamn
hyperloop.
I got questions.
Elon Musk.
I know nothing about the hyperloop.
He's putting a Goddamn.
It goes as fast as a jet,
but it's on the ground.
Just put putting the Goddamn ground jet
and jet to ground isn't around yet,
but he's living in his goddamn yet
putting it in our sacred land.
Why is there not a bullet train across
to us though?
Because that to me,
because people can just decide.
She just wants them to jump in front of
the bullet train and that's like having
a.
If you were at a plane,
okay.
If how,
how much more dangerous would air flight
be if any asshole at any point in time
could instantly put a telephone pole up
right in front of the plane
when I'm traveling or a bear plane.
Travel or
travel would be so much more fucking
dangerous.
Right.
If anybody could just randomly decided
we.
Most people wouldn't ask,
but if they decided to trains out of the
cow catchers and knock the cows out of
the way.
Yeah,
but does that always work?
I mean,
there's a lot of shit you could put on
the track.
The train couldn't just knock out of the
way.
You can move some boulders in place.
He could put some explosives and some
boulders,
boulders.
Fuck La Cena guy.
He puts the dynamite in the hale and he
times it.
Right?
I mean,
Dave [inaudible] for sure can stick
something in front of that train.
That sucks if you hit it,
you know,
some sort of a bomb type situation.
I mean,
it's essentially what are you going do
you have TSA agents every 50 feet across
the United States to damn Amtrak goes
along.
Nobody's trying to stop them.
Rosary in their hand,
glassy eyed Zombie look leaps off the
top,
boom.
It hits the window and you can get them
on all sides.
They could just jump in.
Still I.
It's worth it.
So it works for a month and then you
plaster a couple of guys and it works
for another month before you put it all
into ground and starts earthquakes
quicker than fracking.
That's the other thing.
They we're going to do one up to San
Francisco.
How about that?
Going 700 miles an hour on the ground
and the fucking earth moves.
Yeah.
How about that?
I Dunno.
I Dunno how La has a metro.
I don't really get how it works.
What didn't that thing gonna collapse in
the moment.
There's nothing really well built,
but San Francisco goes one better.
They have the bart system which goes
under the funk and old.
Was it?
That's it goes onto the bay.
Is this know how I found out I was high
as fuck and I was hanging out with the
crew at fear factor and we decided to
go.
We're filming in Oakland.
We decided to go for dinner in San
Francisco.
So we all got together.
We got on this train and I'm like,
why my ears popping and they go
[inaudible] we're underneath the bay.
Uh,
I was like,
Shit.
Underneath Alcatraz.
I was already super paranoid.
That was already super duper high on
edibles.
I mean it was like the worst time to
underestimate the power of vegetables.
And I was under the water.
That's feeling my ears pop
was a real moment where I came
downstairs.
This is,
I came downstairs from my hotel room and
I met all my friends in the lobby and I
was just so beyond barbecued that I had
this illusion,
this a hallucination of people being
this two dimensional,
like cut out,
like say like,
like those a preview things that you see
at the movies we see like a,
a two dimensional cutout of an action
figure.
That's what people were.
And then behind that I would see peeking
out their true self.
Like,
Oh shit.
It was like poking out from behind
there.
I would sleep.
The problem is you don't know which one
to punch.
Which one do you punch where all my
friends just want to punch.
It was just like,
are you really taking me or am I ears
popping?
That thing moves.
The ground moves there and they're under
the goddamn ocean.
San Francisco is.
It's built unlike mud.
It's filled with sharks,
surrounded by sharks and the ground
moves.
It's trying to kill you.
Sharks are walking down the street,
but it doesn't matter.
It's trying to kill you.
A lot of mountain lions up there too.
Yeah,
they eat.
Dogs are dogs and cats.
They.
They catch what?
Good for them.
I say,
listen,
some of nature needs to fucking be
winning.
Some of nature needs three.
Winning.
I think it's great.
Not on my watch.
I think it should eat a bunch of
poodles.
Yeah.
But occasionally we'll get your
girlfriend.
Oh,
that's not good.
Yeah.
Joggers,
they like to go off to joggers.
Buyers.
I remember it was hiking once and I saw
a sign would be where of mountain lions
and the the advice on the sign was throw
sticks and rocks at it,
but not if you have to bend down to get
them.
I was like,
what are you walking around with?
Bundles of sticks and rocks.
Fuck.
He talking about.
Yeah,
you got to be careful because you,
you,
you want to be scary,
but you don't want to be challenging.
It's a very tricky fucking dance.
He was like,
if it attacks fight back.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
There was a.
I saw signed recently when I was up in
San Francisco.
I put it up on my instagram that that
was the very,
the very advice that if you see a
mountain lion,
a mountain lion attacks,
you fight back like,
Oh God,
do you have.
Can you show me an instructional dude?
Give me like,
what are the number one,
how much you'd get laid if you won that
fight though?
There's student candidate killed him
with the knife.
He was in his sixties.
Mountain lion jumped him and he's like,
Fuck,
because fucking jab today's.
That guy's been waiting his whole life
for that moment.
Maybe it was just a man.
It's the man with a knife,
maybe other giant ass fucking crocodile
dundee knife,
and it was
just the idea that we're supposed to
just let those things run around.
There's a big protest.
Nature shouldn't be winning in some ways
of eating some eating.
Some dogs you.
They dogs,
dogs out here,
so they do occasionally.
Yeah,
they definitely little dogs,
but it's interesting.
There's been reading this book forever.
I swear I'll get it done soon.
Folks is a Dan Flores book called a
Coyote America.
It's actually about a history of the
coyotes.
He,
he,
he's arguing or he's saying that most of
what goes on when coyotes kill cats and
dogs,
they're cute.
They're killing competing predators.
That's how they look at it.
Like they're going to eat the cat,
the dog,
but really what's going on as they.
They're killing the competitor not doing
food.
Well,
cats kill an exorbitant amount of
animals.
You probably know about that,
right?
Tons of number one killer of birds.
I think his cats in America.
Yeah,
feral cats are.
They just don't kill just a little.
They kill billions of mammals and B I
and people like there's no way.
Yeah.
There was a whole article about how
these scientists did this longterm study
and it blew them away.
They had literally had no one.
Once they start doing the calculations,
like how many cats there are,
how many animals have cat is capable of
killing the cats outside.
How many animals will encounter.
Well,
and that's why it's bullshit.
When you know,
anti environmentalists are like,
oh,
the solar panel system is frying birds,
fries.
A minimal number of birds compared to
the number of cats are taken out.
Jack and everything.
Man.
Cats are just monsters.
There really are.
I also read that if you die in your
apartment dogs,
we'll leave you alone because they your
face,
they start with your lips,
but dogs are dogs.
Olivia.
Yeah,
that's cat's.
I thin again,
I love cats.
I think they're cool as fuck,
but they just designed by nature.
There's a whole system and cats are at
the top of the system.
The biggest ones are like you ever seen
that video of the crocodile coming out
of the water with its mouth open and the
lion goes in the water and stairs it
down and the crocodiles like,
fuck this.
A crocodile backed off from alliance.
There's another video of a regular cat
getting a crocodile or alligator to back
down,
just like a regular ass kept being like,
oh,
it's a bear.
They're seeing the cat swat.
The bare metal comes to look at the cat,
the cat hisses and slaps the bear in the
nose.
And the parents are like,
all right,
all right.
All right,
chill out.
If I could each Jesus don't want to
fight,
just trying to eat and just relax a
little
big cats in our neighborhood.
There's one in Malibu that they're gonna
kill now because,
uh,
it's in the mountains of malleable and
they just got the.
It's really controversial.
I've been getting all these tweets about
it.
People are so upset.
We got to say this mountain lion,
but it's specific one.
Yeah.
They have a radio collar on this fucker.
Know where he's been and he's
slaughtering things up there because
there's an Alpaca farm and flossing his
teeth.
The dog collars hold up the killed dogs
too.
He's killed a lot of shit,
but he's killed a lot of shit recently.
Like 12 animals or something crazy like
that.
Say,
listen,
don't hate the player.
Hate the game.
Mountain and mountain lion in Malibu.
Killed.
Here it goes.
Pee Forty five suspected of killing 11.
ALPAC is in a goat cheese.
He just,
and he's not doing it is in two days.
in two days he's done this.
Listen,
he's a monster.
Have hobbies.
He's out there,
Jack and shit.
That's what he does.
Just put them in a zoo and let them
keep,
you know,
I would rather kill them and put them in
a zoo.
Uh,
not that I want to kill them either.
I just think he should probably be moved
to somewhere.
We could have a more fruitful life.
Take them to Africa and put them out on
the Savannah is just not good when he's
living around people and he's choosing
to kill their pets and livestock.
Either you're going to kill them or are
you going to move on,
but we chose to be in his way.
He has 10 days.
The permit allows the rancher,
it's called a depredation permit.
They allow the ranch or 10 days to
search for p 45 within a 10 mile range
of the ranch.
The ranch may also hire a hunter under
the terms of the depredation order.
See,
that's what they do.
They hire hunter and the hunter comes
with dogs and the dogs find the mountain
lion.
Because guess what bitch?
You're not finding them outline.
If the mountain lion doesn't want you to
find them,
you're not finding them.
Most people that live up to it,
even with a tracking device,
no,
you're not going to find them.
You're going to know where he is,
but you won't be able to get near him.
Uh,
he's going to know where you are unless
you figured out a way to circle the area
where he is and have like a large number
of people,
you know,
like an army and the old timey days and
then come at each other with spears.
And then just start moving in,
but you would have to have so many
fucking people.
You'd circle an enormous area because
he's going to be what?
He's going to smell you from a mile
away,
like literally a mile away.
They'll run.
When they smell you,
he could see you way better than you
could see.
I appreciate that.
Let them go.
It's pretty dope.
But it's not.
I don't appreciate it in a,
in a zoo.
I think in a zoo,
I think that's the,
that's the worst thing.
You could do it a lot of,
one minute to do,
but I also don't want them good.
But why is he,
isn't it more dead to be in a zoo then
to give your life to the organisms in
the ground,
like nature intended that was put out
there in the wild.
I mean if you have that Alpaca killing
monster,
that goat slaying monster just gets
shot.
The coyotes.
Itam.
Everybody eats them.
Everybody gets off.
We're fine.
And we're models or you know,
maybe he'll put them in the zoo and
eventually he'll escaping.
Grab a kid there too.
Did you see that one?
The zoo that killed a Koala,
the La Zoo.
Critical.
No.
Climbed a fucking barbwire fence.
Got into the Koala cage,
killed the Koala.
Those must look so appetizing after
you've been in your cage for a year.
Like I am this.
There's snacks living next door,
but he's not in a cage though.
He's outside.
He's a legit wild mountain and he saw
this thing.
It was a qual.
Was it a qualler Panda Koala?
Yeah.
He saw the things like,
I can fucking definitely that too.
And he realized he's like,
there's a whole pin of snacks right
there so I don't get in there.
It was so baffled like how did he get
over the barbed wire?
He figured out a way to get over the
bar.
You got to the rafters,
figured out how to open door handles.
Dude.
Amazing creation.
It's just.
It's so cool that nature has all these
varieties of amazing things that you
could kind of pay attention to if you
really want to really spend a day
looking at all the wide variety of
bizarre animals were playing a video the
other day of a road runner that kills
and eats rattlesnake.
Did you know that road runners eat
rattlesnakes now,
dude.
So crazy like it to death with.
Does rabbit by the head and then smash
his head on rocks.
That's playful.
Playful.
He need to see this.
You see this?
I couldn't believe it.
I saw it.
I was like,
this,
this can't be real.
Did you see the one with the.
Was it a road runner was on.
It was chasing like bikers on by on
bicycles and it's just like going with
them for like miles.
Yeah,
he is.
Look at this bad motherfucker.
A little more of the video there.
I guess they were in a fight before he
got ahold of him.
They go at it for awhile and pull them
so he gets them by the top of the head
and not why.
Look how he does doesn't mean here,
man,
smash bleed is fucking dinosaur,
man.
Bang,
getting bitten because he's got a hold
of him.
He's got a hold of his job.
Look what he did to his jaw.
He figured out a way to bite his top jaw
and then smash his head on the rocks.
Just killed it.
And then he starts eating it.
Which Watch,
watch.
When he eats it,
it's even more bizarre because it's so
big.
That's an amazing creation.
Look at it.
He's eating this snake.
She's down in one bite.
This is insane.
What a crazy dinosaur.
Like tiny animal.
Have you ever heard of terror birds?
No terror birds were like,
um,
uh,
like a road runner type bird,
but nine feet
tall,
nice flightless birds that lived,
uh,
in a thing in the Jurassic or the select
pterodactyls.
But yeah,
no,
it wasn't.
No,
it wasn't the Jurassic.
I think it was like somewhere around
like 15,
16,000 years ago.
Maybe.
I'm,
I wrong about that.
When,
when did terror birds go extinct?
Might have been a lot longer.
It might have been like 100,000 years
ago,
but it wasn't so long ago that there
weren't people.
There were people alive when these
things were alive and they were these
giant nine foot predatory birds
that look well because dinosaurs are
closely related to birds.
Basically.
Burdens.
Yeah.
Jesus.
Jesus Lee Camp Jesus.
Here's the thing.
You were talking a half million years
ago.
Yeah.
Oh,
so before,
before people am I talking about,
but who gives me the mic?
But they should.
They should have been here that we
should bring them back.
We can do it now.
I'm probably.
Look what they looked like.
Clone them.
Okay.
Those should be walking around and then
you have fewer people than those two and
a half million years ago.
So what was a two and a half million
years ago when we like a Australia
[inaudible]?
Is that what we were back then?
Wow.
Look at that bird and the reign of
terror.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
Gorging on a smorgasbord of planet.
Any mammals until the scary birds
disappeared.
About two point 5 billion years ago.
So if you had to guess what?
We're humans two point $5 million years
ago.
Like hairy ape things will make things
sound good.
I bet they were scared of that fucking
thing.
Fuck yeah.
That's probably why we were scary.
A little eight things.
Maybe once that thing died off we came
out of the cave and getting our shit
together down from the trees.
It's weird that that's our logo to write
an eagle.
That's our mascot.
A flying tera Byrd.
Yeah.
Boot camps and how you feel about life
right now.
Yeah,
but you were talking about too many
people telling you,
you bring back a couple terror birds.
You let them lose fewer people.
Um,
that's not the way to handle it.
Lee Camp,
because they're going to get you to.
And they're going to get me through out
the target parking lot.
See,
this is the problem.
You have kids,
so you're worried that mountain lions
going to get them.
I'm worried about my kids,
but I'm definitely worried about me too.
What about you man?
Listen,
my kids might not run.
You better know how to choke out a
mountain lions right to work.
It's not going to work.
Do you think,
honestly,
do you think there's too many people?
Do you think it's possible that we could
balance it out?
I think we could balance it out.
I think if we use technology
appropriately,
I mean we throw away 40 percent of our
food,
so it's like we really.
Yeah,
but if we give that 40 percent away,
maybe they'll just keep fucking and
having more babies more doing.
Eventually we'll get there too.
Who's they?
Those other people.
The other is what were you pulling up
over there?
Jamie doesn't know.
Yeah,
it's a.
It is a weird thing when you look at
someplace like India that has one third
of the landmass.
We could live in a sustainable way,
but we're not doing it at all and the
planet is collapsing under the weight.
But how would you decide like when it
comes to overpopulation,
without doing the China thing,
the one baby thing,
which really didn't work at all,
like kind of fucked up everything.
What a disaster.
People throwing babies and over bridges.
Not only that,
they had like 70 percent men.
Yeah.
They had some bizarre thing because they
wanted more men than women.
Yeah.
Cool.
Well,
because everyone,
the way their culture works is the,
you know,
the man inherits all the.
Yeah.
They wanted a boy.
That's not a good thing.
Seventy percent men.
No.
That's a mess.
That's a lot of sad men.
How many different continents right now
have more than a billion people on them.
There's India have no idea if you had a
gas,
so quiz.
Well,
it depends on what.
It depends on what you're considering a
continent because you've got Eurasia,
you've got,
you know,
we're talking landmasses.
That's true,
right?
Yes.
A lot of hugging people,
countries.
It might only be China and India that
have over a billion.
It's a lot of fucking people.
It's amazing.
When you look back just a couple of
hundred years ago with the numbers of
people that were alive in an will,
populations go on like this.
Yeah.
It's shooting through the roof.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
Yeah.
I think it was the 19 seventies.
The world population was in like $2,
billion range and now it's what?
Seven,
7 billion?
Yeah.
It's not good.
Well,
the problem is we've wiped out all the
diseases.
Do you need some real good diseases
running to really to clear out the
underbrush,
you know,
I don't think you should say that
I'm making you uncomfortable.
We went to the CDC wants me and Duncan
Trussell for this show I was doing and
we talked to all these disease guys.
You know,
what's really interesting,
they're terrified.
The people that run the CDC,
they are legitimately terrified of
pandemics.
Like legitimately they're like,
we're not worried about.
I'm like,
will you guys worried about weaponized
w,
you know,
diseases and anthrax on the,
like we are worried about regular
diseases that just go a muck that just
go Spanish flu on people just start
slaughtering massive amounts.
People.
Yeah.
Uh,
and I think a large reason that they
fear that is because the overuse of
antibiotics.
And a lot of that is in factory farming
is.
Yeah.
So with these most antibiotics pump they
are,
it's like 70 percent of antibiotics or
more than that is used in factory farms.
They pump these animals full of it
because they're these animals that are
living on top of each other and each
other's shit and the only way to have
them survive is to pump them full of
antibiotics and so then that immunity to
antibiotics and spreads to us.
Yeah.
That's where the next pandemic will come
from.
Factory farming.
I was watching this video online
yesterday of this girl who is a.
she's like a Vegan activist who had this
video about why do we Turkey on
Thanksgiving?
It's really well done video.
She's very.
It's very smartly
edited and very smartly narrated and she
starts talking about the Turkey
industry,
but she sets it up really well.
Like what did we just sort of do it,
like why do we turn?
And then she takes you to this Mike Rowe
episode where they show how they get
Turkey come and then all these turkeys
are so they're so overbred and fucked up
and they're so big so quick.
You literally can't physically have sex
and then I can't walk yet.
So these artificial insemination and so
this guy has to literally talks to talk
sweet to them.
Yeah,
you gotta start sweet to them.
They have this Turkey's legs clamp down
on this machine and then he's like
touching it's prostate and with a tube
and it's like Whoa,
because it has one hole and sucking it
in,
sucking it out with a straw.
Turkey's got to be like,
what the fuck is going on?
Exactly.
He's getting settled.
He's coming.
This guy has a tube.
He's sucking the come out of this
Turkey's whole,
you know,
because they have like that one sort of
universal whole for everything.
Yeah.
And as he's sucking to come out of it,
he has a glass of bottle water with them
because sometimes it gets in his mouth
so he has to clean it out like kind of a
fucking job.
But this is the only way you can get
this done.
Turkey rape should be illegal.
Totally illegal,
but it's amazing that nobody talks about
that.
But everybody talks about like force
feeding ducks to get fog was like,
how'd you guys missed that one?
Yeah,
what could they do into that?
Turkey's
how come you guys everybody's fucking
sick and,
and you know,
like you're talking about.
Then they pump them full of these
hormones to make them too big.
It's like pigs in factory farming are
made so big that they can hardly move
and then when they have them,
like they take them out to the killing
floor or whatever.
They've never really walked very far.
Some of them collapse under the stress
of like walking 10 feet.
It's six system is weird too because
pigs are smart.
Yeah,
emotionally really smart.
There was a documentary once called my
brother's keeper.
It was about these mentally challenged
guys that were being put up for murder.
Did you ever see it so long time ago,
but I remember when I watched it,
there was a scene because they were
rural farmers and they were being
charged with murder and apparently they
were just really mentally slow and
incapable of sort of understanding the
charges that are being levied against
them,
but when they were running this farm,
it was one scene where they had to
execute a pig and the guy pulls out the
gun and he starts going towards the pig
and the pig recognizes the gun and just
fucking panics like the pig who had been
around him all the time.
It never worried at all.
Saw that gun and freak the fuck out and
just started running and running around
and he's chasing it and then he shoots
it in the head and I remember thinking,
Whoa,
that pig new.
Yeah,
like that.
Peg knew what the gun was.
That's,
that's a level of intelligence.
It's super uncomfortable and they're
fucking smart.
But the problem with pigs is they go
wild.
I thought you were gonna say the problem
is the delicious.
No,
I was gonna say the real problem with
pigs is what do you do with them all?
Like pigs.
Pigs are like super prolific breeders.
Yeah.
He received wild pigs.
No,
we can't.
I know that the too much right now.
I know that exists.
Yeah,
they were um,
all over Texas.
Texas is so crazy with them and it's not
nice to call the people at Texas wild
pig.
And that's what I meant,
but it's too much.
Just that's what I'm saying.
How's Ted Cruz keep getting elected?
Tell me about that.
You're,
you're,
you understand politics.
What the fuck's going on there?
Because he's in the middle of fucking,
you know,
but how,
how do they not even look at him?
Like people should be looking at Jim
Baker with his fucking furniture made
out of survival.
How they should be looking at him the
same exact way.
Like,
man,
they absolutely should.
They do.
And anybody who's ever been in a room
with Ted,
because you just see them,
they're like,
oh,
that guy,
even his own daughter,
you were that video of his daughter
being like,
Oh,
do you know the story about his
highschool?
Or rather his college roommate who's
like his number one troll now,
his college roommate brutalizes him on
twitter.
His college roommate is really smart.
And uh,
I think he's a screenwriter and he mocks
Ted Cruz so openly on twitter.
And he said that in order to think like
Ted Cruz,
you have to.
And He abbreviates it out.
I'm like,
I should be present.
So you should have I s,
b p before everything Ted Cruz says or
does,
because in his mind he should be
president.
So before you look at anything that he
says,
just put in his mind the thought I
should be president first.
And then he says these things like,
oh my God,
that's so good.
It's so good.
His twitter pages,
marvelous,
marvelous.
Uh,
and how sad that people are like,
damn,
if only Ted Cruz had won fully,
he'd beat book.
Be Trump.
We had a real god feeling Christian and
the lighthouse instead of Tsar and
Fella.
He was a spooky
dude,
man.
Yeah.
Here's the guys name.
Freshman Year College Craig Mazin and
it's a.
What is it?
What is his,
um,
his cl maison c l,
m,
a,
Z.
I n will cut him on twitter.
He's fucking hilarious.
Do you saw that?
I'm sure
you saw the mothering Ted Cruz in his
sleep in 1988.
Getting emails blaming me for not
smothering Ted Cruz in his sleep in
1988.
What kind of a monster you think?
I am a really prescient one.
The kind knew by freshman year college
roommate.
Ted Cruz is going to be elected senator
in case I hadn't made it clear.
He's also a huge asshole.
Things people don't have a right to
stimulate their genitals.
This would be a new belief of his.
I was his college roommate should be a
new believer of it.
It's a funny dude.
He's.
He doesn't really funny,
but it's like Ted Cruz,
when they had that video that came out
where they were all making that family
like a,
you know,
it was supposed to be sort of a candid
moment with the families all sitting
around talking and they just keep
redoing it.
Redoing.
Did you ever see that?
You never lie.
No.
It's wonderful.
It's wonderful because they couldn't
look like a real family,
like his well all fake.
He says to his mom,
one of the things he says is my mother
will pray about me oftentimes for hours
a day and the mom go look
and they have like this awkward hug
moment where they have to Redo it.
It's like,
so gross here plays out with this.
I'm just thinking for a second.
Who released the unedited.
Okay.
We're still rolling.
Why don't you say something to get him
going?
He sees in people what they may not see
in themselves.
That's his son.
Dude.
He hates his dad.
Leaves more guarantee.
That kid listens to this podcast.
Holla.
Holla at me
when my dad was a scared teenage boy.
Listen,
listen.
When,
when my dad,
was it
gift in the way of
was his son,
his son's thinking science thing in the
round into the chamber.
Right.
Are you okay with a.
with a way that was uncertain?
What do you mean to America?
What would it mean to America as a
president in Espanol.
Heritage.
I admire Sonia.
That's hilarious.
I'm proud of you.
Very proud.
My thea Sonia fought against Castro in
Cuba.
Fuck
how diddy and elected?
Well,
this is a lot of people out there.
We're all you have to do.
Lee Camp is put on the right uniform.
I like how you and the.
You have the right
kind of hair.
You have liberal Tier Hair Gel.
You're doing all the right.
Do you have an American flag on your old
pal?
You do.
You have an American flag pin on your
lapel.
Everyone else's.
It's.
Well,
it's,
it's distinctive to distinct it flat,
so I have to.
I have the right say the right things.
You did appeal to the right people.
He was involved in some sort of a,
a,
a law against or the enforcing of a
logins dildos at one point.
So that you never saw that.
Oh wait,
wouldn't that mean he can't be senator
does I forget the specifics of the,
of the law?
Not,
don't want people enjoying their sex
lives.
Well,
there was a lie,
there was some sort of a law in place
about like sexual novelty devices,
like dildos and stuff and he was
involved in,
I think it was like a crazy law too.
Like you go to jail for two years or
something like that.
Yeah.
Ted Cruz defended a band on delay.
Still did enough.
I like the look in his face like,
like King Kong is coming in his face.
That's what it looks like right there.
And on Dildo.
Yeah.
This was from 2003 to 2008 when he was a
solicitor general.
So what do they do with,
what do they do with Zucchinis and
things?
Do they ban deldot shaped fruit?
Yeah,
I know,
right?
Can you say anything?
If you're a girl,
they're so lucky.
The case.
The case is an important battle
concerning privacy of free speech rights
in 2004.
The companies that owned Austin stores
are selling sex toys,
uh,
and the retail distributor of such
products challenged the Texas law,
outlawing the sale and promotion of
supposedly obscene devices under the
law.
A person who violated the statute could,
you could go to jail for up to two
years.
At the time.
Only three states,
Mississippi,
Alabama,
and Virginia had similar laws,
blah,
blah.
Okay.
This is what happened.
Uh,
Texas mother,
who was a sales rep for passion parties,
was arrested by two undercover cops for
selling vibrators and other sex related
goods at a gathering,
a kin to a tupperware party for sex,
toys,
you,
you fucking monster.
God had to be women by the way.
Guys will be getting their dick sucked.
The ability to look.
Let's just cut the shit.
I got
no doubt this had worried business
businesses peddling such.
Where's the plaintiffs in this sex
device?
Case contended this state law violated
the law,
the right to privacy under the 14th
amendment.
They argued that many people in Texas,
you sexual devices as an aspect of their
sexual experiences and they claimed that
in some instances,
one partner,
a couple of my up,
up,
up.
Ah,
okay.
I get it.
So anyway,
Ted Cruz's team,
scroll down.
So we find what he did.
You would just,
there you go.
And 2007 Ted Cruz legal team working on
behalf of the then Attorney General Greg
Abbott.
Um,
file the 76 page brief calling on the US
Court of Appeals
for the fifth circuit to uphold the
lower court's decision and permit a lot
of stand.
The penal code inhibits the
advertisement and sale of Dildos,
artificial vaginas and other obscene
devices.
Oh my God.
But does not forbid the private use of
such devices.
That's hilarious.
So they wanted to uphold the law.
That was a 76 page brief.
Listen,
I feel the same way about this as I do
about drugs.
Whatever you want to put in your body.
This is an even more innocuous.
This,
this doesn't even get you drunk.
You know,
you stick a Dildo in you,
you pull it out,
you're sober.
I would imagine.
Listen,
you don't remember about the Dildo
massacre of 76.
How could you file it?
People should go to.
This.
Should go to jail.
All of them for fraud.
First of all,
it took you 76 pages to figure out
whether or not someone should be able to
sell dildos.
I mean it's.
Yeah,
they should go to jail for going against
the constitution.
What should it be?
Four words.
Who gives a fuck?
That's it.
Next case to what you want with your
plastic devices.
Dude.
What's it like working for rt?
That's fine.
Is it cool?
Do you like it?
Yeah,
I mean,
here's the thing.
It's like all this shit I say I can't
say on like any other network,
right?
They,
I,
you know,
I was on,
I was on some of these networks,
one guest appearance and then I was at
like,
what show was that?
Wow.
You last time you played me on Fox News,
the laptop box.
It was awesome.
I was on MSNBC.
You Dylan rat again.
The only time they've ever had me on,
I was on a Keith Olbermann only time
that ever happened.
So it's like what happened when you and
Keith Olbermann while I was a guest
house.
It wasn't him,
but,
uh,
Schuster,
but uh,
there's nothing went wrong.
It's just the stuff I'm saying is not,
it's not good for corporations.
I feel like you're a very reasonable
guy.
I feel that way.
I don't think you're saying anything too
crazy.
So when you work for rt,
they pretty much let you.
I mean,
what kind of a editorial control they
have over your content?
Well,
I mean technically they have editorial
control,
but I'm not told to say anything I say.
And that's amazing.
And yeah,
no,
it's huge freedom.
And you know,
I think you have,
you have our news which says on their
website we are the Russian perspective
of the world.
And then you have red opinion,
which is me,
Larry King,
Jesse Ventura,
Chris Hedges Hedges,
Chris Hedges.
Oh,
uh,
Abby Martin used to be there obviously.
And so it's like great voices that it's
just like,
it's,
we're doing our opinion thing.
We're doing the same thing we've been
doing for years.
They try to ship Abby Martin off to
fucking Siberia.
That was hilarious.
That was.
That was such a catastrophe.
Not not just for them but it,
but it was like CNN had her on.
I went with her to piers Morgan
interview because they.
Because they thought she was going to
give their side of things.
They thought she was,
oh,
she's on our team now,
and it was like,
no,
Abby Martin knows what the fuck's going
on.
And she said things.
They were.
They were like,
wait,
she's going off script.
This is not what CNN thought.
She'd say,
yeah.
Then they wanted to bring her to fucking
Ukraine.
All other people think that she got
fired from because of that.
She was there for another year and then
left on her own accord.
It is kind of crazy that they were
thinking of.
They could just make her go there
though.
Well,
they had an.
That was funny.
She woke up that morning and they had
announced she was going to go toward
Crimea without telling her and she was
like,
what?
She's like the fuck I am the fuck I am
hilarious.
Could you imagine if you got up and you
had heard that the,
the government of Russia had determined
that you're going to visit a warzone
wow.
Wow.
And I don't know that.
I don't know whether it was a PR person
thought it'd be a good move.
I have no idea what happened.
I bet it came from the top.
I don't think Putin spends his time,
but he was in the middle of a botox
session.
He was like,
he's like his mouth,
his nominees yelling out.
It's getting botox.
Somebody needs to tell him to stop that
because he has to stoop fucking rugged
for Botox.
So let it go,
dude.
I was thinking a lot of the latest Brad
Pitt thing.
I was wondering if there was some botox,
Brad Pitt,
Brad Pitt was hanging out with Putin.
Is that what you're saying?
No,
no,
this is.
I saw a allied.
It's actually a great movie.
Oh,
his new movie.
You'll see some botox and Brad.
He just.
The wrinkles aren't there.
Something's going on.
Something fishy going on and be Angelina
Jolie's just got it.
That good
gives to you.
Stay young.
They used that CGI stuff for a lot of
people.
Now when they're doing Hollywood movies,
do they use it throughout the whole
movie?
Yeah,
and in lots of cases thought it might
look like that.
Well maybe that's what it is,
is.
Well,
they did that for sure.
With Westworld,
with Anthony Hopkins.
Spoiler alert.
There's one scene where the show Anthony
Hopkins back in the day and they stay,
have him as you know,
maybe a man in his fifties instead of in
his sixties and they do a really subtle
job of CGI and it looks great.
It's amazing how far away from just like
dad actors being in movies.
Oh,
100 percent to is touring.
You know?
That's true.
The hologram tour.
Yeah.
I think um,
they're going to have almost an look at
that.
That's amazing.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
How do you make them skinnier too?
Well,
they had them not just at this stage
either,
by the way.
They had them in more than one stage.
They had them in a slightly older stage
as well.
It's just a.
and do you think the acting,
the scenes,
the,
the body,
did they get a different actor?
Vaccines?
That's a good question.
Do they pretty sure.
Yeah.
It'd be a different actor and they just
put a different face on.
Yeah.
You remember when they did that with the
soprano's and it was terrible.
No,
the mom died and then they did one last
scene with the mom and you're like,
what in the fuck led you to think that
we would accept this
was so bad.
It was so bad.
And they only had her in there for a
moment.
But what?
Somebody else's body or head was moving
weird and just like,
look,
here it goes.
Watch it,
play it,
play it.
Give us some volume.
So how's it going?
What are you out of sight out of mind.
Butch.
Some books on tape,
but since you say you can't concentrate
to read,
I wish the Lord would take me
now.
Was it just using clips from?
Yeah,
that's about all I know,
man.
I thought there was A.
I'm confused.
No,
maybe this is the same scene,
I think.
Yeah,
those were just clips they had.
that's not.
That's not the same scene.
Why don't you google,
what was the mom's name?
Fake Cgi mom in the soprano.
Maybe I'm wrong.
This is what came up.
It says it happened.
Maybe I'm wrong,
but this is just the clip that pops up,
man.
When I saw it,
I could have swore they had somebody
else.
Six insane attempts to make movies
starting dead movie stars that the next
thing during the sprint is the death of
Olivia Soprano is the last time you see
whatever with poor CGI.
This foot.
That didn't look that bad though.
Maybe a bit later.
And maybe it's just because we're
looking at,
um,
maybe it's later in the Clinton
era there were showing her originally
whatever we lost Gandolfini,
bro.
That's rough.
That's rough loss.
Okay.
Let's just let it go.
So I'm here that as the cops,
we've called them on.
You decided you a little too divisive
for trump's man.
They're speaking to the cop.
There is a story going on right now.
You guys might be interested in that.
Remember the shoe,
I think it's the shooting of Walter
Scott was his name where the gun was
planted on the ground by the Cop after
they got to pee.
Pee.
Okay.
Nabil,
right?
No ears.
The cases going on right now,
and I guess they almost have a hung
jury,
like a,
it's the judge is telling them to go
back and deliberate and figure out how
they can handle it,
but they're there.
They're trying to get out of it.
So this is the one where the guy shot
the guys who was running away and then
through a gun on the ground and you
could see it clearly in 55 witnesses
gave testimony in the case.
And
what is there to deliberate on?
We'll find out shortly.
They fucking shot the guy in the back.
We watched it on video and not only
that,
planted a gun and then drop the gun.
Scary.
This is,
that's the thing is like if the cubs
want us to respect them,
they've got to go after bad cops.
They never fucking do all these guys get
off.
Yeah.
They have this,
um,
well,
I mean some cops that go after,
like that one woman who shot that guy
who remember that he got tasered.
Then she shot him on the highway.
He was a,
he turned around.
He wasn't listening to them.
He went and got back into his car.
They said he was on PCP.
Remember that what I had heard from
someone is in the tactical community was
that she made the gigantic error of
keeping our finger on the trigger and
that she wasn't doing anything.
She was,
you're supposed to have total finger
finger off the trigger because when the
guy got tasered by the other gentleman,
the other cop,
she like reacted to it and pulled the
trigger.
This guy in the tactical community said,
it happens all the time.
That's why you have to have trigger
control because you don't even realize
you're doing it because you're reacting
to a violent moments.
Your muscles,
whole lot.
You have your finger on the trigger and
then something violent happens and you
just do that and you shoot them.
And that's what happened according to
him.
I don't know if that's true,
but I could totally see that I to fuck
that job.
Lee Camp,
right?
I did there.
I think they're told that they had guns.
Are that,
that pulling out the gun is going to
solve the situation usually and it's
fucking,
it makes it worse half the time.
Half the time.
But it was the other time.
It's perfect.
Fucking.
Yeah,
shoot away,
Bang,
Bang.
You leave it up to them to decide when's
when,
when you do your show,
I'm on our team.
Do they have guidelines for you?
How much control you have over,
like what kind of stuff you do have to
work with?
Uh,
no we have,
we have a meeting with the news director
but uh,
once a week.
But uh,
I write all my own stuff and it's
really,
it's really pretty cool.
That's crazy man.
What other network or give you that kind
of freedom.
And here's the thing though,
is is,
you know,
I just figured like the one thing I
actually do just kind of avoid
intentionally is saying nice things
about Russia because I know everyone's
going to think I was put up to it,
right?
And I haven't been.
But I just know that's what people would
accuse me of.
So do you,
do you find it amazing when you look
around in 2016,
there is a country like Korea where
you're completely divided and one side
is kind of American,
like you know,
one side South Korea.
And then the other side is an insane
dictatorship and they live right next
door and they look alike and they were
once one country.
And this is how it could go bad and this
how can go good?
I think it's,
I think it's a fucking major problem in
the way we discuss these things,
the way we talk to each other,
the way we view the world,
that we start to think of people as
their leader.
Like people thought all Americans.
Where George Bush,
people think all Russians are Putin.
It's like this.
The leaders that are fucking crazy,
it's like if you go fucking chat with a
Russian guy,
you're gonna,
you're gonna love the dude.
Like probably like,
it was like,
it's like everybody around the world,
we're not our leaders,
we're not,
you know,
the,
the Brits aren't,
they're crazy leader and the vus
trillions aren't,
they're crazy leader and it's like
people are their own people.
Yeah.
That's one of the reasons why having a
president in the first place is kinda
ridiculous.
Having one alpha person.
Yeah.
Male or female running the whole show is
kind of a figurehead.
Kind of preposterous.
Yeah.
Bizarre that we still do it,
but it's,
it's even more bizarre that someone can
still pull off a dictatorship,
you know,
in Korea.
Like how does Korea and that's the big
one.
Like how does North Korea and how does
that,
how does that ever resolve itself?
I have no idea.
They're so deep in 2016,
so locked in.
Yeah.
Just people don't want to think that I
could ever happen here
and it might not.
It absolutely could happen.
And the other thing is,
you know,
in a certain way it's,
it's the best kind of slavery is you
don't know you're a slave.
So if you spend your whole life trying
to work off student debt and jobs you
hate,
it's like that's kind of slave.
You don't know.
Your sleeve.
Cut to headline says Lee camp says Korea
is better than.
No,
I'm not saying that Korea is fucking
awful.
Jesus though he can't points to
different type of slavery that makes
America worse than everywhere.
No,
it's.
But it's.
Oh God,
the worst.
Well,
Russia is a little spooky.
Putin's a little spooky.
Jack and
Jack and people
gangster.
I mean allegedly were blowing people up.
Yeah,
we're doing that too.
I don't know.
I don't know either.
I just know you can't talk about a
proper right now.
I made you uncomfortable talking about
something better.
China.
China's fuck drop,
right bro.
What's that?
I said China's fucked up,
bro.
I don't know much about him either.
I don't either.
That's the problem.
It's a.
it's just amazing how I couldn't even
tell you this is.
I shouldn't admit this.
I couldn't even tell you China's leader
right now.
They have a leader.
China's president.
What do you think it would be president
or would it be an emperor?
No
president,
but I don't know his name.
Well,
what does Canada have again?
They have a uh,
well they have prime minister say that's
so fucking high and Tati Trudeau.
Yeah.
That's the dude trying to president.
Is that how you say z?
Z?
Jin Ping.
It looks trustworthy.
I like him like we're doing a good job.
They're doing a good job over there.
Imagine running a billion people.
Fuck.
That's a crazy country,
man.
Have you seen this?
No,
I have not.
Have you seen the cities that they
recreate in China?
Well,
the ghost cities that just recreate
that.
It's,
yeah.
These are two separate things,
but yeah,
they'll recreate where it's just like
Paris,
right?
Yeah.
People just go there for our honeymoon
and everything's empty.
It's nuts.
They recreate the old city.
And the part of the reason they do that
is because they have these ghost cities
and it's because GDP measures production
partially.
And so to keep their GDP up,
they just build ghost cities.
Like fucking no one lives there.
That's so crazy.
It's nuts.
Vice did a thing on it.
Now as a comic who also has a show and
you know,
you're this sort of observer of the
world.
Do you have to look at the world more
than you would like?
Do I have to look at the world?
Well,
like all the crazy chaos that you have
to kind of focus on or you just show and
doing standup.
I,
I view my life because I'm,
I've always focused on America just
simply because I'm an American in
America talking about American issues
and I don't honestly not educated well
on world issues.
Like I said,
I couldn't tell you certain leaders of
countries and so to me it,
it comes from a place of ignorance.
It's like I don't know if I want to rant
and rave about something I don't know
the truth about.
And so,
so I definitely stick to the American
issues,
but in terms of having to focus on the
chaos,
do they can get depressing to focus on
all the chaos,
to focus on the fucking protesters being
brutalized in standing rock.
It gets exhausting.
Do you throw in the occasional cute
kitten story?
Make things better?
Oh yeah.
What can you throw in kittens?
It's not a weird thing about the news
though.
I did one where I literally wish I just
showed puppy dogs over my shoulder as I
talked about it just to like show people
how do you feel a responsibility to show
people all of a sudden this become an
interview.
Try not to do those.
But I am curious about like what's like
to put together a show the jurors?
Yeah.
Every week.
Do you feel like any sort of
responsibility to like for your content?
Like you have a platform and I feel
responsibility to not be too depressing
but not per story.
So like,
I'll,
I'll cover fucking depressing shit,
but I,
I do feel a responsibility,
like in the sense of I don't think
people are going to keep watching,
nor will they feel active to create
change if they're just like,
ah,
it's all fucked.
Fuck it.
Like,
so I,
I do try not to get too much on that
side of things.
That's all
logical but super depressing perspective
that it's all fucked.
Fuck it.
That's logic.
I get it.
I know why you would think that way.
But God,
Oh,
I think there's a lot of people to think
that way.
Sure.
That give up and
they just decided not voting.
There's a guy that I really respect is
get this psychedelic salon podcast.
Uh,
same as Lorenzo.
He's been on this podcast before.
Really interesting guy and he runs this
amazing podcast that has all these
psychedelic speakers like Terence
Mckenna and Alan Watts was like really
interesting people.
Audio recordings of them giving lectures
and stuff.
I'm Timothy leary and uh,
you know,
he went on this rant.
He's like,
I don't,
I don't buy an any of it anymore and I'm
tired of it.
I'm not doing it.
He's like,
I'm tired of being disappointed.
I just,
I'm going to,
you know,
live my life and I'm not voting anymore,
and part of the party,
he goes,
Oh man,
you're putting the boom boom,
you know,
party goes,
hey man,
that's your right.
Like I get it.
Like you just want to live this wild
idea.
And especially with people like you said
earlier that they're,
you know,
working three jobs trying to feed the
fucking family.
It's like,
of course they don't have time to give a
shit about five states over.
These people are being brutalized.
Like yeah,
it's too hard.
It's too hard to think about those
people in North Dakota,
you don't know them,
but.
But we have,
we have also created a culture that is
distinctly like good at getting people
to ignore what really matters.
Just like we're just under a swamp of
bullshit to actually pay attention to,
to important stories.
You think that that is by design or do
you think that that is just what we were
paying attention to it?
Like we pay attention to nonsense,
celebrity gossip,
stuff like Brad Pitt and getting
divorced
and I think it's good
combination of bydesign and just what
gets ratings.
You're going to get more ratings by
covering trump,
let's say,
or his twitter war.
Then you are going to get with like the
details of how these people are having a
really hard time because they were
kicked out of their home by the bank or
whatever.
So part of it is ratings,
but part of it is by design.
I mean the fact that occupied got very
little mainstream media coverage was by
design.
It was like if we cover this as an
important thing,
it's going to grow bigger and we're
going to fuel it.
Yeah.
No shit man.
It's,
it's interesting because the things that
we do get obsessed with that are
ridiculous,
that take up so much of our time that
really mean nothing.
You know,
when you look at all the stuff that we
do ignore,
you don't like the guy that got iced
that was under FBI care,
like that never,
never,
never gets talked about whether or not
you agree with that.
Whether it should have shot him or not,
you're allowed to execute people now
because that was going on,
right?
That that might be a big issue.
We should probably discuss it.
Right?
That's just one,
right?
There's a million different stories.
It's amazing that the standing rock
stories become as big as it is really
because they'll all that and Bernie
Sanders and all that.
Like any black lives matter.
It's like the only reason,
and you know,
I'm not saying everyone's gotTa love
Bernie or agree with all that shit,
but I'm saying I'm saying the fact that
those guys as big as they are,
it's all because of citizen journalism
and and social media and all that stuff.
The Internet,
the ability to make your own new site.
I mean new sites or.
No,
this is all you need is a website.
The gatekeepers are gone.
Not only the gone,
but like the amount of people that pay
attention to certain alternative media
sources far exceeds what you get an a
daily episode of the bill o'reilly show,
like how many millions of people do
think listening to bill o'reilly
cheeses.
I don't even want to know.
I would like to know like what do you
think
he might.
I might've been off it.
Does he get 2 million viewers or show?
Do you think he gets 2 million views to
show Jamie?
Yeah.
Let's see.
I say yes.
I say it gets more than 2 million to
show.
That's what I.
that's kind of confidence I have in how
much are we going to point to how much
we betting?
I'll bet you five American dollars.
Did you hear about the Vegan?
$5 thing and in England they came out
with a new bank note and it's using
animal fat.
Vegans are freaking out and demanding a
Vegan note.
You know what?
I got it.
They got a good point.
I talked about this in my standup unless
dry.
A lot of dryer sheets of animals.
So if you're a Vegan,
that's funny.
Oh my God,
not dryer sheets.
Those fucking clean free ones that make
you smell so good.
Naugles is a psychopath.
That's crazy.
It's got rendered up beings inside of
it.
What did we find out on?
Bill O'reilly?
A article from earlier this year says
you averaged about 3 million.
Thank you.
Oh,
thank.
Thank
you that a bunch of scared old people.
Mexicans just yelling at the screen.
What about the age of the people that
watch your show is?
Yeah.
No,
it's like 50.
It's like,
yeah,
okay,
let's.
Let's get really crazy.
What's the percentage of them are white?
You think?
Whatever you think they're going to tell
us that all of them.
One hundred percent.
They go through the entire United States
is not a single black guy like we heard
about a guy in Virginia.
Quick.
Let's go before he shuts it off.
They fucking one.
Not a Ben Carson out there.
They said bad guy.
You're right.
This is a black duck hunter
out there.
Fucking out there.
You're so right,
dude.
Clarence Thomas hates black people think
so.
Eight.
So wow.
That's a big statement.
Sorry,
I had no one.
No one rules in ways that are going to
harm black people more than Clarence
Thomas does.
He really hates him and his and his wife
is a.
He never said he hates his wife is a.
she's one of the heads or head speakers
of the tea party.
Like there's still a tea party.
Tea Board is sort of fizzled out.
When Sarah Palin joined up.
Shit,
I think that's like having an open party
in that crazy drunk down the street.
Comes in with a gun,
like
a home party.
When is that furniture made out of
survival food.
I gotta go.
I gotta go
pick her survival food.
Oh,
I'd love to see the first time he
presented that.
Listen,
things get bad.
We started eating the furniture.
I'd like to see like how they decided to
sell it that way.
They say,
well,
what are people going to do with the
gym?
They've got these big player.
Where are they going to do with these
barrel weight?
They'll just put it on the table.
Where are your feet going to go?
Jail.
You're going to eat from a fucking
distance away from the table.
You got damn con man.
Jessica,
where are people going to get planks of
wood to go on top?
It's such a size six.
King Arthur's round table of survival
food.
Are you a fan of the Gloria standup days
in 19 eighties.
Kinison era too.
And I'm sad I went.
When did you start center?
80 eight.
I'm sad I missed it.
I missed,
I missed.
I mean I was coming open.
Mike in the eighties.
I missed it for the most part,
but it was a fan,
but that was back when Jim Baker had
that gigantic scandal because he was
this big online minister guy.
And he's banging his secretary.
Yeah.
Playboy playboy revealed it.
And Gang Kennison started banging her.
What?
Yes,
after she left,
she got,
she knew him from his pastor days.
I do not think so.
I think he just zoomed in,
less attracted to this.
He knew those nutty Christian swinger
type.
She's like,
I know him.
I've been around
them.
So he,
uh,
that was a bad candidate pressure by.
And so he started banging her.
She got fake boobies.
She posed for one of them Penn House or
something.
One of the magazines.
Playboy
days.
Yeah.
It's just amazing to see Jim beggars
still out there rocking it.
Kennison long gone,
but fuck Baker furniture mixed together.
Eight your couch.
We'll be right back.
Praising Jesus failure couch cushion
with stakes in is.
There's a scene in that video where he
has.
This girl was like,
you got some Mexican blood in you
telling me about these enchiladas.
We're not kidding.
She's eating this enchilada.
It looks like it looks like a tampon
from a zoo animal.
That's what it looks like.
He's about to cut into this fucking
thing.
It doesn't look anything.
Survival Enchilada,
and he's talking to her.
It's like you got some Mexican blood,
don't you?
Oh God.
That's super deluxe guy who put that
video together.
He's a.
he's a beauty.
He's a,
but he's a gift.
A gift to all of us here on this planet.
It's a fucking hilarious video because
he just found the most preposterous
scenes and edited them and amazing way
where he closes in on his face when he
says Mike.
Really nutty shit
guys.
Still rocking it,
man,
so I've got people in the audience
stuck up people the same dad.
One I bigger than the other.
Not even just watching at home.
There's people that are their wall.
Make it out to the studio.
Jim's going to give the sermon today.
Do you think that survival furniture do?
Please tell me that studio has a warmup
comic.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're going to need you to really give
it up here.
Have you ever seen one of those guys
that does
Christian,
like church comedy?
Ever seen that?
Oh No,
but I've heard about it.
A big thing.
Number Watch.
They do enormous venues,
enormous 25,000 seat venue and they do
church comedy.
I'm not kidding.
They have standup comics that do clean
Christian comedy and the only perform
with these church gatherings kill
yourself.
Well,
it's a totally different sort of a vibe.
It's like this agreed upon note that
you're going to hit.
It's like if you were an opera singer,
it's like,
well,
we can't play rap.
No,
no,
we do opera are right,
but that's what they're doing.
They're doing like a form of opera.
Like,
I understand that for you or for me,
that would be a horrific proposition,
but for someone who enjoys that tone,
right?
Like they hit that fucking Amos and
Andy,
you know Andy Griffith?
Hey,
there's someone that enjoys scooping up
the shit behind the elephants at the
circus.
It's a job for everybody.
This guy is doing Jesus comedy.
Wait,
this is the.
Oh,
that's the guy with the TV show the
Brown.
Oh,
that's the guy who has the big hot dog
rolls in the back of his head,
the back of his neck because like hot
dog rolls.
That's a pastor that.
Yeah,
that's Mr Brown.
Uh,
I
always wondered where that family Sitcom
thing came from.
That does look like.
Stand out.
Let me hear some of this.
Let me hear the sounds like,
stand up on the.
What is this?
Yeah,
he's doing standup and I know y'all pass
the don't do this,
but sometime my pastor starts preaching
and I can't understand what he's saying.
Get the preaching of his
stand up.
He's.
So he's doing standup 100 percent
people laughing.
You need to spit.
Oh my goodness.
No,
he did not,
and there bobbing up and down,
forward and back.
It's just,
that's another thing,
like it's agreed upon.
Agreed upon sort of quincy.
No.
Yeah.
You got to hit in these certain notes
and you know,
we all agree that we're,
we're going to,
you know.
Yeah.
I mean that's the whole thing about
being a gentleman,
right?
Not Curse.
Yup.
Yeah.
When you're wearing a tie and a suit and
a nice clothes like that,
I expect you to understand a certain
etiquette.
You're not a rag a bond.
You're not a savage.
That's some sort of hooligan.
Right.
You know,
you're not some dude with fucking high
top converse on and ripped jeans and
fucking dirty shirt.
No.
You're dressed in a way that I could
predict your behavior.
Well,
when we do the same with a sleeve of
tattoos,
right?
Yeah,
for sure.
A lot of people think they can predict
you or a pocket watch.
I have a buck one,
but with the chain from a vest while I
have right now,
I have it hanging on my lunch.
I was talking the other day about
everyone with a pocket watch is an
asshole and I have to amend that.
I like you.
I'm going to ask you.
Come on.
You're not an asshole.
You're a nice guy.
Let me see your pocket wash.
Because we were,
we were,
we looked up one that cost like how many
millions of dollars.
Oh No.
This is like,
this is $35,
but it was from like the 70 [inaudible].
This is dope.
Alright,
I changed it.
I'm getting a pocket on the other way.
I'm not married to my thoughts folks.
Okay.
You shouldn't be either key.
Didn't even stick to his beliefs on
pocket watch.
This is dope.
I love it.
And that's really cool.
And I mean obviously I just for fun
because habit.
It's fucking cool.
It's not right at all.
Now you got to keep you because you got
to keep wanting to again.
Oh that's weird.
And I forget to wind up how often you
have to wind it.
No.
Are you like several hours?
Once every few hours or.
That's so stupid.
Why'd you buy a cheap one?
Why don't you buy one that actually
works?
Do you want people to know?
Look Man,
I'm at it works.
I'm a Mumford and sons video walking
around.
I'm
walking,
living,
breathing,
Mumford and sons,
and the key is you can only have one of
these things.
Like if I had the curly mustache too,
then you can't.
You can't have the biowatch and the
curly mustache.
I couldn't have this pocket watch and
your hat right now.
Right?
Right.
That was fast.
Yeah.
I know.
I'm talking shit about wearing a build
versus a little rascals hat and I have a
fanny pack that's a real legit little
rascals heads.
I'm a little upset at apple that I had
to buy
this new little thing that allows me to
charge my,
my phone and play music with an actual
set of fucking headphones instead of the
bullshit.
Proprietary crap.
Now I got it.
I got it.
Setup.
So that's your fanny packs filled with
those devices and weed and fear factor.
Money
filled with fear factor.
Carry around.
Not to comfort me.
Yeah,
I'd get it,
but luck.
Fuck.
Shut up.
You would have done it to how much are
you doing that show?
It was fun.
Wow.
Was high every episode.
So there's always fun things every day.
And I worked with people that I really
loved.
They were really nice people.
You're having a good time.
I had a great time because the people
that I work with,
like all the guys behind the scenes,
super super nice guys and I'm still
friends with to this day.
So there was a lot of fun involved but
it wasn't what I wanted to do.
It was just money.
So there was,
it was moments where it was hilarious
and there's moments where I was really
touched like I cried once when this mom
and daughter team one,
like they were,
there was a son and father team versus a
mother daughter team and the southern
father team kind of Douchey and the
mother and daughter team.
We're kind of sweet.
And then you looked at them and this was
a physical stunt and the father was kind
of in shape and the kid looks like he's
kind of shaped me.
Like God damn it,
these girls,
the mom.
And the daughter are going to lose
and they really needed the money and the
sun was kind of insulting,
you know,
people play the game.
It's part of it.
They're encouraged,
encouraged to be insulting,
but he fucked up.
And then the mom and daughter one.
Wow.
And when they won,
like
the whole crew was crying camera.
People were crying.
It actually got real.
Oh yeah.
They were crying now because like,
oh my God,
we want all this fucking money.
We did it and was against the odds.
And that's cool.
Yeah.
So I'll tell you,
years ago doing stand up,
it was probably when fear factory to
come back the second time or something.
Two thousand 11.
Yeah.
And I.
and I just stopped by comedies too.
I was watching.
It was fucking hilarious because he
tainted a bit unlike,
hey listen,
I know I,
I,
if you'd said to me,
would you,
would you be on TV?
Get Darren someone to eat a bowl penis.
I would've said,
no,
I have no idea what you're talking
about.
Yeah.
I wasn't even possible that I'm not.
The joke was that I'm on TV and I'm in
someone's eating an animal deck and I'm
like,
Hey,
you can do more.
You can get more in there,
and and the people running the show or
like,
good job.
That was great.
The
more dictate the better.
Really.
I mean we really did serve people.
Animal Dicks.
We served them elk,
Dick bold deck,
a couple of different types of dicks.
Who was the intern in charge of
collecting was.
It wasn't an intern.
It was a beast on guy.
There was a couple different ones,
but Josh Silverman was one of the guys
who did it towards the end and he was
awesome at it.
He knew his fucking craft,
like I knew how to get the most
disgusting stuff.
They all have a twisted sense of humor
too.
They all have this very bizarre like
realization of what they're doing,
how preposterous it is
making people amazing.
Bob for a cow hearts in a vat of blood.
I think that was one of them.
These people that had bob,
so they go into like a writer's room and
they're like,
what's the grossest thing we can come up
with?
Some of the stuff was insane.
That's nuts.
We went to a slaughterhouse once.
That was the one of the first times I
ever believed.
Like when we went to the slaughterhouse
I was like,
I really do believe that places hold a
feeling [inaudible],
you know,
like I'd never been to a place where
like who knows how many thousands of
animals have died if not maybe a million
or maybe even more.
I don't know how long had it been around
for,
but it was a like a legit big time
slaughterhouse.
Was there a slaughtering going on?
Not what that we saw but very recently
because we had to do the scene with
blood and when you have blood you have
to keep it very cold and you can only
keep it that way for a short amount of
time because it could get go bad.
You can get sick from it because these
people have to dunk their head into this
stuff so they have goggles on and they
have to dunk their headed.
They're bobbing in this freezing cold
blood so you don't.
Your body doesn't want to do it because
it's so goddamn cold.
Imagine the number of lawyers involved
too.
It's while this is going on,
there's a guy who's about to do the show
and he's outside and he's talking to
himself in the side mirror of a truck.
He's got like one of those side mirrors.
That truck is not his truck,
but he's a competitor so he's like,
you found a mirror and he's like,
you are a winner.
You are not a loser.
You will succeed.
You will follow through.
You will get it done and he's like doing
all this stuff and he just like,
he's doing like little sprints.
The same thing Ted Cruz's kids say to
themselves before they talked to him
probably will follow through.
You can talk to.
You will talk to Dad,
dad,
I'm gay.
Anything else?
We can't do anything to add now.
That's amazing.
I heard something about a,
a this American life went into a
slaughter house,
like a pig slaughter house,
but it was Waldo.
It was while it was going on and like
two of them left mid segment and went
and vomited outside and then like it's
madness.
Well that's one of those things like
many things in our culture,
it's like,
like prisons that we were talking about
before,
like how did it get to this point
because we kind of realized it was at
this point as adults.
I mean,
do you remember the day that you became
aware of factory farming?
You were probably a grown adult.
Right?
And we,
we habituate to these things.
We get used to them.
We're just accustomed to like,
it's like it's slowly,
we're accustomed to so many people being
in prison and just slowly grows and we
slowly accept it and we sold the except
the invasion of privacy.
It used to be without anyone watching
your email,
we people would talk about they were
upset.
Now it's like everyone assumes and the
same thing can be said about factory
farming.
I mean the immediate answer as well.
Offering up a solution.
There's no solutions were.
What about the,
we need the numbers.
We need the numbers of Burgers,
so we need the numbers of chicken.
Wow.
You know,
we,
we've really painted ourselves into a
strange corner here.
Well,
there's no reason that you know,
hamburger.
Mcdonald's will be cheaper than like a
thing of Broccoli at the store.
It's like we're just subsidizing this
massive meat intake.
Yeah.
And the corn industry too.
That's another dark one.
Three out of every four products in the
grocery store.
I have corn in them.
Jesus grew are basically does 90 percent
quarter.
Now I saw the documentary king corn.
Have you seen that when they test their
DNA?
Yeah.
They,
they test the carbon in their DNA.
The carbon in their fucking very virtual
being and it's like predominantly corn.
These guys are there.
We're doing this documentary and they
start growing their own corner.
It's really fast.
It's corn,
corn,
corn with hats on the a little bit.
Dude,
that's sugar corn syrup stuff that's in
everything.
Corn Protein.
Yeah,
but meanwhile corn on the cob,
wonderful suicide.
One of those things still.
It's just a good thing can be bad if
there's too much of it.
Right?
Everything in moderation except for
moderation.
You just try and get all of that.
You can leancamp ladies.
Gentlemen is here all week.
So often it dropping.
The bombs were.
Where are you?
Where are you,
uh,
doing standup where someone could come
and see you.
Oh,
um,
I don't know.
I'm touring the country,
but we do have a live audience were
redacted tonight in DC.
So beautiful theses.
You're flying out.
You're a fucking animal dude.
There's no not tonight because he be
lying to people.
And I didn't say it to any politician
tonight.
You did say tonight.
I'll redact it tonight.
His name is.
Oh,
we thought you were saying redacted to
hawes tonight.
Now every week.
Except for this one loophole.
The Guy got away on a loophole.
That slippery politician.
We have a live audience and people can
come.
They just sweat email,
redacted ticks.
So you do everything in our t is in,
is in dc because that's where our
America's big studios are.
And say,
yeah,
what does DC like these days?
So to a weird environment,
that must be a hell hole.
It was free weed though.
It's legal,
right?
Well it's legal,
but you can't like be just publicly
smoking.
It's like when you have to do.
Maybe I was talking,
I was like,
what are the rules in the the.
They were like,
oh,
you got to go around the corner.
The law is you got to go around the
corner.
What does that mean?
You just can't be out on the sidewalk.
If you had to guess how long before
state like countrywide legalization.
Ten years.
Maybe less.
I think so,
yeah.
What makes you think that?
Well,
the states that have legalized,
they're doing fine.
They're doing better than fiber and so
it's like people realize it's not the.
You just had to get past this propaganda
of it's like destroys lives.
It's scary.
And once you get past that,
what do you think about that jeff
sessions guy though that,
that trump brought in?
That guy is a old school.
Antioch.
He used the.
One of my favorite ones.
Good people don't smoke marijuana.
I'd love to know the list of drugs that
Donald trump has done over the salt.
Coke,
coke,
adderall.
Coco,
coke.
Do you think he does drugs?
He doesn't drink.
Not Anymore.
Remember when they were accusing him on
CNN of doing coke?
It was potentially doing coke lot.
Yeah.
I mean that was just his like,
you know,
buffalo brain.
Just
bowl.
Got Her with that Zinger.
You'd be in jail.
Yeah.
That was,
that was the singer of the campaign,
wasn't it?
It's pretty good.
Did you enjoy the whole festivities?
Did you enjoy the,
of the nonsense of it or were you upset
by it?
No,
I don't know.
I just kind of.
It's all.
I did one segment where I took,
honestly,
it was like three minutes of the two of
them talking to another debate and just
every half sentence I would stop it and
go,
that's not true.
That's not true.
That's,
that's bullshit.
Like every,
it's like everything,
every word that comes out,
he's somehow manipulation and it was
just like,
it's,
it's both sides on both sides.
And,
and I just,
I was like,
this is,
I tried to cover it as little as I
could.
I mean it's still covered it a lot,
but I tried to avoid it as much as I
could because it's just a fucking
sideshow.
My most frustrating thing of the
campaign wasn't just that because I was
aware that there was a lot of things
that were being said that weren't true
was that there was very few people doing
what you just said while you recovering
and on both sides.
Saying that's not true.
That's not true.
Yeah.
Like if you go back and forth from a
right wing show to a left wing show,
it's hard to pay attention.
It's hard to know what the hell is
really going on,
right?
Student for realities.
And no one was doing like what you just
said.
You didn't go with the whole thing like,
hey,
this is all crazy.
Yeah,
because people are lying.
They're wrong.
They're lying.
Now I want Lee camp.
What do we do?
Do we energize Bernie?
We got to get them on hormone
replacement therapy and keep them alive
longer.
I think you should go get him on a
training regimen.
I want to get them doing deadlifts.
Yeah.
Got To get them to fix that posture to
this shit.
You can't.
Nobody wants it.
I'll just take it.
I want you to put it under your chin on
up.
Every day when you woke up one,
just sit up straight.
This is very important.
Bernie.
You can't be doing this.
Listen,
this comes.
This comes from the 30 years of trying
to change the government.
That just.
It just wastes time.
It just shrinks you into a diamond plus
snow shoveling in Vermont.
I think what he should do is he should
run in four years,
but he should say,
I'm only going to serve for four years.
Nobody wants that could make a
difference in the stamina to go eight,
and then trump's going to come in.
I don't have insurance.
I've got a winning attitude and he's
going to win again.
Trump's like overweight.
He doesn't need that looks great though.
It doesn't look whatever cocktail he's
on his fucking carrying them through
like a champ.
I'm telling you.
Look,
you could say about his appearance all
you want.
Now you.
You'd be absolutely correct,
but
he never showed any signs of physical
deterioration.
No,
I think he's okay,
but he is.
He is relatively overweight.
He's not a healthy man.
Definitely not.
Yeah.
No.
If I was his friend,
I would definitely get them on some sort
of an excellent diet.
I'd be like,
there's a way to do this better.
You know,
you allow even more energy and you're a
god dynamo as it is.
That was a real concern to the Hillary
Clinton health concern and when you
would bring it up,
people would say you're an asshole for
discussing and that you're a sexist or
you're enabling and some sort of a way.
Like,
no,
these,
these are legitimate concerns.
She had a stroke.
Yeah,
I mean,
and I,
I don't,
I don't honestly,
a lot of it,
I don't know,
tradition.
Say she had a stroke.
She had,
excuse me,
she,
she fainted,
she blacked out.
She had a seizure,
fell and cracked her head.
That's been,
that's been confirmed and then she had
another seizure apparently in 2015 that
was discussed
during the week and then what was the
one where where Bill Clinton in an
interview.
He was like.
He was like,
Oh yeah,
she has these spells every once in
awhile and anyway,
the point is like,
I don't know what the,
what the truth of every last detail that
is,
but it was like it was like they're not.
They're not talking about that in a
legitimate way.
They're not talking about the fact that
Donald Trump won't release his medical
records.
He had one doctor write a five minute
thing and said,
oh,
it's the healthiest guy that's ever
lived.
What the fuck is that Dick?
Not Orange pay regular color.
That'd be weird that you cannot be
addicted to of color from the face.
He got it.
If you're going to go on and you got to
go all orange all the way down on his
toes,
his orange,
except like a little strip down as
butthole,
like when people like Tan spray tanning
thing and then do porno.
That'd be amazing.
If he had just a really tiny bikini
line,
well you know,
people like if you.
Do you remember what it be like if
people would sit in a tanning bed like
tanning beds have kind of gotten out of
favor,
but one of the things about tanning
beds,
they would leave weird sort of semi
white spots on your butt because your
cheeks kind of compress and so like your
cheeks touch each other when you're
lying flat on that thing,
so in between your butt cheeks gets
Pale,
like unless you're making a real
concerted effort to spread your asshole
out and sort of hover over.
That opened that Suntan booth for a good
solid 20 minutes or how long it takes
you.
I'm sure Donald Trump has people spread
his cheeks for it.
Probably in the tanner.
They just smooth it all out.
Let's get my cheeks spreaders.
Get them in here in.
Yeah.
I don't think he's using.
I think it's,
it's probably a spray tanning type
thing.
It wasn't just drinks out of character
so and were just being assholes.
There's no way.
Maybe there's some kind of excuse to do
that.
Spray Foam.
I've seen people do that with so much
carrot juice and orange.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He was drinking so much carrot juice
that his fingers started getting.
He was talking about it.
It's apparently super common when people
do that,
they drink a tremendous amount of
characters.
It literally will change the color of
your skin.
We didn't look too weird until he
brought it up and you're like,
oh wow.
Wasn't like,
dude,
you got you,
you going orange on us.
It's cutting corners,
not blue.
It'll be blue.
That's a good thing.
How do you have time to do your show and
do standup?
Is that difficult to do?
Yeah,
it is.
I only,
I've only been doing stand up,
uh,
when I go out to cities and I do,
like,
I'll play a theater or something,
but I haven't been getting up as much as
I would like it.
So you basically just do your show and
like does a lot of the subject matter
just bleed out in your standup because
of working on this stuff?
You must find some pretty observed
subjects.
Most of my standup,
uh,
it comes from stuff from the shell
because it's just like I can't fucking,
I basically have two,
I have two TV shows,
one of them and luckily as an interview
show so it doesn't fill up as much in my
writing time,
but,
but I've got the right to a whole other
show every week and so I just don't have
time to write new standup.
So the standup usually becomes a stuff
that was in the show.
Are you planning on doing a special
anything anytime soon?
Um,
well we just filmed this a redacted
tonight live.
We called it or whatever and laugh
factory and we're going to a or portions
of that at the end of December on our
youtube channel.
So that'll be a bit of a special.
Oh,
so you did it like as standup.
He did it like.
Yeah,
stand up.
Okay,
cool.
Yeah.
Well accept passed by the laugh factor.
I put it up on my instagram the other
day I passed by the laughter.
I wouldn't look at camps.
Does that feel weird?
Driving down,
seeing your face?
It's weird,
but here's the thing,
as you will know all it means that
someone had some money to do.
That doesn't really mean anything.
I'm your friend.
Took a picture of it,
man.
Thank you.
You've never from one of your new
albums,
you've never done the laugh factory
billboard?
No,
I've never had the laugh factory before.
You coulda.
Well,
I
tell people what's the best way to get
ahold of you?
What's the best way to see your stuff?
What's the website?
You should check out the show at
youtube.com/redacted tonight,
but everything else is pretty much Lee
camp.net and at Camp on twitter and your
shows on our rte and on Youtube.
The same exact show.
Yeah,
we put it all.
Yeah.
So unlike,
unlike daily show or something,
we put it all on youtube.
Oh,
that's nice.
That's very cool.
So you don't have to have our tea to get
it.
Nope.
These crazy kids that are untethered,
untethered from the free as a bird and
don't give a fuck.
Crazy barrier out there.
A bit torrent and then.
All right,
well,
um,
that's how you get all your stuff out,
Lee camp and when done that,
when we camped on it and when can people
see again when,
when is your next tour date?
Where you at?
Anywhere
next door to it?
Yes.
I'm playing like a Cleveland and
Pittsburgh in the new year and I have
Chapel Hill in DC coming up.
Uh,
December ninth and 10th.
Very funny guy.
Go Out,
see him please gentlemen.
Thank you joe.
I love you as well folks.
We're done for the week.
Not yet.
Pitches tomorrow.
Fight Companion,
full onslaught.
Brian,
Eddie,
Bravo,
Brendan.
Shop plus alcohol and marijuana
pizzagate.
Hashtag pizza gate.