This episode of the Joe Rogan
Experience podcast is a bonus episode.
We had no idea we were even going
to be able to do this as recently as
yesterday.
You fucks.
Okay.
We're making it happen.
So the only sponsor is
[inaudible] dot com it's o,
n,
n.
I.
T.
Use the code name Brogan.
Save yourself 10% off
any and all supplements.
Shortest commercial ever.
Cue The music.
Justin,
the Viking Ren is in the house to
tell us about some amazing adventures.
It's going to be educational
and enriching for the soul.
Yeah.
Justin wren.
First of all,
thanks for doing this.
I'm so glad we could fit you in.
I was,
I was a little worried we were going to
be able to get you before you got back
to the Congo because you're on
this kind of a whirlwind thing.
You know you have your back at La.
Have for only like a few days,
right?
Actually,
I head out to Vegas after this and
then I'm driving there and I fly out
tomorrow.
For those who don't know.
Justin was a contestant on the ultimate
fighter is a mixed martial arts fighter
in the heavyweight division for the UFC.
And then I started reading some stuff.
I think the first thing I read
about it was a on the underground,
uh,
which has mixed martial arts.com.
It's this great website
that we both belong to.
It's probably the best,
uh,
mixed martial arts message
board in the country,
in the world really.
And uh,
there was a,
uh,
a thread where it was talking about you
going over there and helping people in
the Congo and working with these pygmies
and this would become something you
were really,
really devoted to.
And I was like,
wow.
Like who saw that common?
Like check this guy out.
I saw a picture of you before that with
a pig that you had killed with a knife
over your shoulder.
You know this,
I'm like,
this guy's a fucking savage.
He's got a pig over his shoulder.
Yeah.
There's a picture of you with this,
uh,
with this wild hog over your shoulder.
I'm like,
I want to party with Justin wren.
And the next thing you know,
you go from there and you're,
uh,
your mixed martial arts fighter,
hog killer,
pygmy saver.
I mean you're,
you're over there helping all
these people in the Congo.
How did it all this get started man,
I just heard about how much
they were suffering and uh,
I,
I had no clue.
Like I fighting,
I wanted to fight against people,
you know,
and I wanted my dreams,
my everything.
And then when I heard about the pygmies,
I just heard the suffering
that they were going through.
I heard that they felt forgotten her,
that they were enslaved.
I heard that the four out of 10 is the
small stack that you can find four out of
10 of their children die before age five.
And so for me,
I was just like,
man,
that's brutal.
And I knew that they were not given
citizenship in their own country and so I
just went there to just learn and
see and sit with live with them,
sit
around the campfire.
That's where I've learned most
whenever the slave masters on,
around whenever,
uh,
whenever those guys are asleep,
then they'll really open up and tell
you what everything is happening.
Um,
and so it was just a ton of suffering
and that's how I went over there.
I just went with a burden to
find out what was going on.
Could you put that a
little closer to yeah,
absolutely.
How did you find out about it at first?
What was the,
uh,
what,
what mean?
What led you to this?
Uh,
I had a buddy that was having a plan to
go to the Congo and he was going all by
himself and I mean just completely,
utterly alone.
And it was like the worst
conflict zone on the planet.
And,
uh,
heard about what he was doing,
heard about,
uh,
what was happening with the
pygmies and heard his wife,
uh,
was a little worried that he was going.
And,
uh,
I just was looking for something with
purpose and passion and I felt like I
could be passionate about
fighting for people.
And so I went with them and uh,
heard all the terrible stuff that was
going on and we went there to see what we
could do to help.
Wow,
that's so inspiring.
And for folks who haven't seen it,
there's a video that Justin did that's
gone viral and this has really brought a
lot of attention to your cause and,
and what,
what you're doing.
There's a video of you with
these young pygmy children then,
or is this the first time
they're seeing a white man to,
to preface the video?
This is actually not the pygmies.
The video.
It's actually the band too.
And the band to are the tribe that's
actually enslaving the pygmies.
Oh my God.
So it was,
yeah,
it was uh,
around some of the pygmies,
but this was the least remote location.
Like you'll see that there wasn't many
trees where I went was 85 kilometers deep
in the jungle where you couldn't even see
the sky because the canopy of the rain
forest is so tall.
And so this was the band.
Two people in the band too.
People are ones that enslave them.
He was actually a gift because I don't,
that video to me is a real gift.
It,
it shows me,
uh,
even though I hated their parents,
um,
uh,
you know,
you can't even see that in the video
that I actually just had a hatred in my
heart towards it,
the parents of these kids.
Um,
but yeah,
so that was brutal because I,
on the Ugi also,
I posted a video.
Um,
we're actually a thread about how I,
I buried a,
uh,
a one and a half year old in the
Congo and his name was Andy Bo.
And so this video that's
playing right now,
you can't even tell that they were,
uh,
that,
that their parents are responsible
for the grave that I dug,
I think two days before that video.
So these are the boon to people's Bam,
to the a n t u and the band two
people are in slaving the pygmies.
And this has been going on for how long?
Uh,
it's actually rather recent.
I mean,
there's been types of it
for hundreds of years,
but,
uh,
they have different kinds of
slavery within the pygmies.
There's ones that
they're held to gunpoint.
Uh,
there's by the rebels and the
gold and Colton at diamond mines.
Uh,
and then there's other ones where they're,
they're in shackles,
but then the ones that we've actually,
I didn't get to say that yet,
but we've actually set some slaves free.
Some pygmy slaves that
were from the band too.
And we negotiated with the band to
people who go up and they buy up the land
from underneath the pygmies.
Pygmies don't have a way
to make any monetary gain.
They don't get paid anything and money.
They get paid sometimes corn,
sometimes bags of salt,
sometimes bars of soap,
like a bar of soap for two days of work
they might get a bar soap to bathe with.
Um,
and so yeah,
the Bantu people are the ones that
are enslaving them that we're actually
negotiating with them to,
to free him.
Wow.
Yeah.
What a crazy environment that must be.
The Congo itself,
not being able to see the sky and
having all this insane conflict going on
underneath the canopy of these trees.
Also primitive dealing with things
like slavery and forcing people.
What's really crazy is forcing people
to work in the minds to create the very
things that we need to power our most
technologically advanced pieces of
electronics.
Like these laptops,
that Cold Tan,
right?
Yeah.
Colton,
I think 80 to 90% of it
is found in the Congo.
So it's only found in
two places in the world.
80 to 90% of it's the Congo.
100% of its rebel owned.
There's not a legit mine.
And so that's insane.
Most of it's pygmy slave mind.
100% of it is rebel from the Congo.
Yes.
The Democratic Republic of Congo,
all of it is rebel owned.
So there is no Karma free cell phones,
electronics,
smartphones,
not max,
not flat screen TVs.
So I mean I support it even I have the,
the apple products,
iPad,
iPhone,
everything.
What a bizarre,
fascinating sort of a
statement on humanity that is.
Yeah.
It's actually pretty crazy man,
because I had um,
some pygmies come one time and give me
some Colton and I didn't know what it was
though at the time.
Uh,
I didn't know.
I knew that there's golden diamond
mines there and that they were slaves in
those,
but I had no clue what Colton was
a and that was after my first trip.
But they actually put some Colton in my
hands and I was holding it and they were
really excited to give it to me,
you know,
this is why their slaves and,
and and so they thought I'd be a static
and so I'm having to ask my translator
like what?
Like what is this stuff
they're handing me?
I didn't know if it was like a rough
diamonds or if deep inside there there was
gold or what it was,
but it was Colton.
What does it look like?
It's like this black dark mineral.
It's almost,
some of it almost looks like a crystal
or I don't know if you can throw up a
picture.
Almost like coal.
Yeah,
almost like goal.
Um,
it's,
it's long and Jaggedy it's kind of a,
I dunno,
you know,
those like crystals that you can use to
be able to buy like that are long like
that there'd be a black
one of those almost.
And sometimes it has more of a coal,
like charcoal kind of
feature to it and it's,
it's heavy.
Uh,
but it's,
it's a great conduit for electricity
and that's why we're using it in all our
smartphones and everything.
And that's why they're slaves.
But I wasn't excited about it and
I didn't know what it was and I,
but for them,
you know,
think how,
think how crazy that is.
That's why they're slaves and
I don't even know what it is.
And they're just a
static to give it to me.
And while it's a huge source,
I mean,
you need it all over the world.
Yeah.
And most people are completely
ignorant as to what it is and a set,
especially where it comes from.
Right?
Yeah.
It's very bizarre.
Like I had explained that to someone when
they were talking about,
um,
uh,
how much better it is
to have an electric car.
And I'm like,
do you understand that that car
is filled with conflict minerals?
Like it's not that simple.
It's not as simple as like,
you're good.
And the guy with the gas guzzlers bad.
Like,
no,
there's a lot of fuck Uri
in creation of your car.
Batteries like lithium ion.
That's another reason
why we're in Afghanistan.
This is a lithium stores is
trillions of dollars of lithium and,
and Afghanistan.
And that's what you need
for lithium ion batteries.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's insane.
I,
I can't even,
I don't,
I mean,
I know we have two hours,
but I don't even know if I
could get into some of the,
the stuff.
I know that Shane from vice has been on
here and then someone was saying someone
else from your end tomorrow.
Is He really?
Oh Man.
I wish I could meet that dude.
Uh,
each has a cool guy.
You want to meet him?
If he could stay til tomorrow,
you can meet him.
All right.
We'll have to see about my plane
back or something like that.
He'd be happy to meet you,
man.
He's a big,
crazy,
coolest motherfucker on her.
I think he's awesome.
Yeah,
he's a great guy.
You see super easy to talk to,
to just really like down to earth.
And he goes to some of
the craziest places.
Oh yeah.
Oh yeah,
he's returning back and forth.
You know,
I wonder what he thinks about
me going for a full year.
Just,
I know that he said it was a
crazy time going there and uh,
and I just would want to pick his brain.
What party you went to.
Is that what you're doing now?
You're about to go for a year?
For a full year?
Yeah.
I'm going to go for a full year and I'm
partnering with the Oldest University in
the Congo and they have been working on
this project for seven years and we kind
of just linked up together to where,
uh,
our visions just are kind of the same.
We want to free these people and
give them a sustainable ways of life.
So,
um,
one of my best friends now was
born and raised in the Congo,
was educated,
got his doctorates in Australia,
but then he came back to the Congo and
he's the dean of the School of community
development.
So we teach you some
different ways of agriculture,
water,
wills,
all these kinds of things.
So he's actually setting them free.
And that's what we did in September.
We saw 60 slaves be set free,
put on 30 acres of land and get a water.
Well now it's doubled.
Now since I've been back here,
it's been 120 slaves that free men,
women and children put
on 60 acres of land.
And then now,
uh,
you know,
we were wanting to find a way,
we think that me going there for a year,
and if we were able to fund raise $50,000
so we could find a thousand people at
50 bucks,
thousand people,
50 Bucks,
that's a thousand slaves freedom.
And it would,
it's,
it's a nuts,
um,
amount of stuff that that would do.
How many people are
slaves right now there?
Well,
the pygmies in the
Democratic Republic of Congo,
there's a few different,
it's hard for them to do a census,
you know,
I mean,
these are hunters and gatherers and
nomads and slaves and then in dangerous
areas and then really remote area.
So there's a few different senses and,
uh,
that they've tried to do.
The lowest I've seen is 300,000
pygmies and then another,
I've seen a 600,000.
And pygmy actually literally
translated means elbow height.
So I mean they're smaller
than everybody else.
It's almost like they're just a,
the worst bullying victims,
uh,
that I've ever been.
So the average men's
height is four foot seven.
So are,
are they in any way like a,
have you ever seen any of that stuff on?
Um,
uh,
the,
the Hobbit,
people from,
uh,
this,
island of,
um,
the remains they found now.
Yeah.
They found remains of people that lived,
you know,
tens of thousands of years ago with,
with humans and they were the real tiny,
like almost people like things.
It's,
it really interesting when you see like
some of them like the pygmies where you
have like a whole race of them that
are like really tiny like that.
It makes you wonder like,
how did that,
how did that separate
strain branch off way,
way,
way back in the day.
And the evolutionary chain of these,
these people being developed.
It's really odd.
I mean,
it actually,
one of the,
one of the problems that they,
uh,
they have is that,
um,
they're called half man,
half animal.
Uh,
by the surrounding tribes.
And so that's one reason
why I've met people,
uh,
that have been,
that their families,
members of their families have
been victim of cannibalism.
Uh,
and so yeah,
I've,
I've pictures that Santa
Buzz of cannibalism,
they actually,
the surrounding tribes believe that if
you can consume the flesh of a pygmy,
uh,
that you can gain super human strength.
I mean,
from taking the genitals off of small
bullies and putting them under businesses,
uh,
it will bring you wealth
from eating their flesh.
Yeah.
The rebels believe that if you
eat their flesh that you can,
uh,
what does it,
it makes you not bulletproof,
but what does it,
whenever a bullet can just
fly right through you.
So basically not invisible pervious.
So it just,
they,
that's what they believe you that you
take children's genitals and they put them
under a business.
That's what they'll do to them.
And then we'll,
uh,
think that that brings him many blessings.
It,
that some of the witch doctors
have done that and Uganda,
but they do it in Congo.
Ah,
the part of the Congo that I'm going
to is it borders Rwanda and Uganda.
And so I'm right over the border
and then in the jungle kind of,
um,
Booney as where Shalom university is.
And then 85 kilometers from there,
there's a part of the
Congo called commander.
Um,
they say it differently than that,
but then we go from there deep
into the jungle and where that is,
there's some different
rebel groups that have,
that have done just brutal stuff there.
And,
uh,
that's some of their beliefs.
Wow.
Yeah,
I was pretty crazy.
There's one place gets so messed up that
[inaudible] crazy man as they should
be.
The richest country on the
entire face of this planet.
They have every element
on the periodic table,
every single one.
And uh,
and they have the most fertile soil.
They have gold diamonds.
Now Colton,
with all this taken off,
they should really be the
richest country there is.
And then all the corruption
and everything just ruins it.
It's,
it's so,
it's so crazy.
The corruption is so nuts.
The warlords and the whole system that,
uh,
that they've got going on down there.
It's so,
it's so bizarre to look at the United
States of America here in 2013 how
everything is and then realize there's
another part of the world that exists in
the same time that is essentially living
the way people live thousands of years
ago with guns though.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And that's what's so crazy is the pygmies.
I actually have my grandpa's,
I've been accepted as
family there now and um,
I,
my grandpa [inaudible] is his name
[inaudible] and he gave me his bow.
So it's pygmy bow and arrow that he's
had for 30 40 years old in your hands.
It's actually pretty tiny man.
It's pretty tiny but,
but in it,
it has all these things that are almost
like a pygmy tally mark and it's all up
and down at the top of the bow
and the bottom of the bone inside.
And it's all the kills that he
has of certain types of antelope.
And he gave me the,
I think I have like 10 arrows,
five with like the metal on it.
And then for that are just straight would
that are sharpened and they have this
like circular thing around the tip of it.
And I thought the ones that are metal
would be the ones for the antelope because
they look like they would do more damage.
But it's actually the ones that
don't have the metal on it,
uh,
that are just carved a out of the wood
that are the ones that go after the
antelope because they dip
the tips of them in poison.
And so it's poisoned arrows.
And those are the ones that go
after with the biggest ones in the,
the metal ones are more for like monkeys
and small little pigs and things like
that.
Wow.
So you're going to go there and live
with these people in like a tent made out
of leaves?
Yeah.
It's a,
a twig,
a Twiggly fuck man.
You shouldn't pull the
people see the picture.
Do you have it on your
website or anything?
When did you send me those pictures?
Yeah,
I,
some of the pictures over.
Um,
yeah,
it's a twig leaf hut and they,
they rebuild them basically every night.
Every night.
Well,
it depends on if it was raining,
the rain forest.
And then if it's a,
if the wind is blowing,
uh,
actually have pictures of,
I think like the widows and orphans that
lived in one hut together were just in
the middle of the night.
It didn't even rain that night,
but the wind blew in.
Their whole roof came off.
And so they have to go get the leafs again
and place them over banana leaves and
different,
like those big elephant looking here,
leafs.
And so they just get
those and they cover up,
um,
in nine different villages I went to last
time I was there for a month and nine
different villages don't we do not
one of them ever owned a blanket,
so they're just sleeping
straight on the dirt,
man.
That's it.
And no blankets?
No,
no,
just sleeping straight on the dirt.
Wow.
First Time I went to one of those tribes
was I saw the chief and I was putting
up my tent and they about lost
it and had a little air mattress,
you know,
and I had a sleeping bag and I mean
to them that was the Ritz Carlton.
So I let the chief habit and I said,
yeah,
so I let him have that and I
slept in his hut and uh wow.
Yeah.
And then site.
Yeah,
he was man and they all passed around the
air mattress and that they're actually
like holding it up above them.
Almost like a crowd surfing,
like crowd surfing at a concert.
But they're doing that with Eric
mattress so everyone could feel it.
Wow.
Yeah.
So they've never had mattresses.
I mean this isn't like
a new thing to them.
They've slept on dirt forever.
Yeah.
I haven't come across one pygmy in the
remote locations that had been to the
other ever.
Pygmies and other locations that have
cities or anything like that or no,
no,
they're,
they're actually basically if
they come to a city at all.
So yeah,
there we go.
That would be home sweet home for,
uh,
for a full year.
That's the kind of villages
that I'm staying in.
And if you look in there,
I think on top of one of those huts
there's like a few clothes and if they,
if a pygmies had close,
they've been a slave.
So there's basically the
only pygmies that are there.
Yeah.
So some of the clothes,
so obviously these ones were have been
slaves and most of the ones I've ever
been to have been slaves.
We've only been like one village I've
been to where they were so remote that
they still weren't enslaved and
they can be hunters and gatherers.
But the deforestation with
the trees falling that you
could drive to Mack trucks
through a,
those are scaring all the animals away
to where they basically can no longer
live like hunters and gatherers because
the animals just flee from all the trees
falling.
So the,
there isn't loggers,
is that what it is?
It's loggers,
but it's also the guys that are,
uh,
like the Bantu,
the slave masters,
they can get the pygmies,
they're slaves to go
cut these trees down in,
into pygmies.
Trees are wholly,
uh,
they believe that the ancestors of their,
um,
yeah,
their ancestors live inside.
The trees become trees and uh,
they bury their dead inside
holes inside of trees.
They find an opening in it.
They'll put,
put their dead there.
Um,
and so they're having to cut down what
they've lived in for thousands of years.
And then the rain forest preservationist
and wildlife conservationist,
they,
they push them out.
They'll buy up the land and they'll
say pygmies aren't good for this.
And they'll kick them off the land and
they'll buy up thousands and thousands of
acres.
Actually thousands of square cushions.
Yeah.
They'll kick the pygmies off.
So they're more interested in the
trees and the are the pygmies.
Absolutely.
Wow.
Yeah.
I,
I've,
I've heard from my family members in
the pig pygmy tribe and when I say this,
like literally I have pygmy family that
are more family to me than some of my
family here in the u s and so on.
Crazy cousin who gets
drunk and grabbed it there.
We're sure.
Yeah,
there's some piggies I just
love man that I love and uh,
and you speak their language.
I must speak the language.
I speak some of it,
man.
But,
but not a lot.
And during that year there
for my birthday coming up,
I'm going to get Rosetta stone,
I think in a,
that's what I'm asking.
How could you not?
You're going to live there for a year.
You say you love these people.
What do they have been talking shit about
you the whole time and you gotta learn
pygmy and find out?
Well,
they don't have,
they don't have a Rosetta stone.
That'd be funny though.
I'm the crazy uncle.
What is the language that they have?
Like what is it called?
It's like a,
it's not the clicking is,
but it's close.
It's actually a tonal
language or a polyphonic.
Actually there's,
there's some sweet videos,
I don't know if you guys
want to pull any out,
but on youtube there's a,
they do a thing that I love called,
uh,
the water drum.
And that actually isn't
gonna be on my youtube thing,
but you could look up pygmies water drum
and on youtube and there's some sweet
songs.
They'll have like seven to eight women,
uh,
inside the river.
And then they,
they each have a part to play and um,
wow.
Uh,
and they just slapped the water and it's,
it comes out the beautiful songs.
Or they also have something called
polyphonic singing where they each have a,
uh,
a tone that they do and they actually,
some people would call it the language
of song that's trying to think of that,
but their language,
sometimes they're joking around with
each other getting into it and it sounds
like they're kind of
singing to one another.
Wow.
So that's the ones that are in
the more Romaine remote locations.
The ones that had been slaves
for years and years and years.
They've started to learn to speak Swahili.
Yeah,
there it is.
And you're not in it for just the boobs,
right?
No,
sorry,
the Sag after awhile.
Is there a drum
to that as well or is
that all just the water.
Bottled water.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
This is just three.
Whenever they get like
eight to 10 in there,
they get some intense songs.
This is hilarious.
Take a pause.
Wipe your eyes.
Wow.
They also have something
called the tree drum.
They'll,
they'll uh,
hollow out at tree and they'll get some
harder sticks and they'll just beat the
side of a tree.
And it's,
it's odd man.
It's sweet.
So what are you doing for food out there?
Uh,
the last month I went,
I took about 40 to 50,
uh,
power bars with me.
Man,
my bag was so heavy because I had took a,
I took a supplement shop with me and,
uh,
but I mean,
they,
caterpillars I've eaten,
like I normally don't ask
the different parts of it,
but,
um,
uh,
like whenever they do goat,
which actually pygmies don't eat goat,
they believe that it has
a evil spirits inside it.
So even though goats are
really easy to raise,
they won't eat it.
Goat,
the hunter say that a goat
makes you weak in the knees.
And then the women just
don't like the flavor of it.
And they all think that it,
they've seen it.
Evil spirits come inside of them.
And so they don't eat goat's
did they see drag me to hell?
Is that what it is?
The Gate becomes the goal becomes evil.
Remember that?
I never saw it,
but yeah.
And so they,
they eat,
they'll eat chicken,
whatever their slaves for.
I have a picture I think of,
uh,
of my buddy Harry and,
um,
he,
we call him Harry because he's the only
pygmy I've ever seen with facial hair.
Ah,
that's why that video is so unique about
me because I went over there and it
wasn't just like some guy,
uh,
from America that went there.
Giant,
White,
hairy dude.
What the fuck is all this?
That's why my buddy started calling
me the great white Sasquatch.
What do you think about your tattoos?
Oh yeah.
That,
that is a crazy,
not to the pygmies.
The pygmies actually tattooed
their faces sometimes.
Um,
the women,
uh,
I've come across a few of them that
are more like traditional or remote.
Those women still carve their teeth.
I don't know if you can Google that.
They actually carve their teeth and
it makes them almost look more like a,
a Pirana to me it's not attractive,
but to the pygmy men,
it's attractive.
Yeah.
They,
they,
uh,
hate below jobs.
I hate to,
I don't even want to
be tagged those teeth.
Good.
Perfect.
You read my girl.
I don't know if you guys
can find a picture of that,
but,
uh,
it's,
pretty,
pretty crazy looking whenever a smile,
there's a lot of,
um,
strange things that,
wow,
oh my God.
That African people do
to customize their body.
The neck rings.
That's very strange.
The stretching of the lower lip.
Serie a women do the,
they put a plate in their lower lip.
Yeah.
Well the,
the Masi they do,
they're a big gauges in their ears and
whenever they get so big that they start
flopping around,
I've actually been brought into that.
So the pygmy tribe
brought me in his family.
Uh,
the Masai tribe had a ceremony and made
me a warrior and they painted me red
head to toe.
Um,
they gave me a spear
that killed two lions.
Whoa.
She's seen the main of the line
that it killed the head warrior,
you know,
gave me my name,
which is Mizzou.
Simba Maasais Milan.
And that means though the white lion,
Masai warrior.
So I'm a part of the warrior class,
the Masa.
And whenever the wind blows with
them and there was big gauges,
um,
they'll just twist their ear loads and
then wrap them around the top of their
ear.
So it looks really funny.
But uh,
but that's just on a windy day.
So they killed lions with spears.
Is it because the lions are attacking
them or just they just got to be gangster?
A little,
a little bit of both.
Really.
I think the younger guys go
out there to impress the girls,
but,
uh,
to kill a fucking line with the speed,
their waiting,
just show your deck.
The,
the,
uh,
what is it?
The guys,
um,
oh,
the,
they there.
Those are shepherds.
So the pygmies are hunter and gatherers,
but the Masa or shepherds.
And so they take care of
different cattle and goats.
And so whenever they're doing that,
they have to protect,
uh,
their herd.
And that's against lions and Jaguars,
cheetahs and leopards.
And so my spear,
they actually showed me the skin of the
leopard that it killed the main of the
lion that had killed.
Um,
and he also said it killed a man.
So I guess I have a murder weapon,
but a holy shit.
Yeah.
He,
but he was protecting their cattle.
A thief came in there
and a actually came with,
uh,
a room Goo,
which is a club.
Um,
and so it was a room Guo versus a spear.
And it was a warrior.
So anyways,
it's pretty,
pretty crazy.
Wow.
What is it like,
what kind of a head does this thing,
the spearhead,
the spearheads about this long.
And it's heavy because I mean at all?
Uh,
yeah,
actually they have this,
uh,
the wood part of it in the middle of a
Maasai warrior spirit from like an olive
tree of some sort,
and then they put it through
the fire and make it really,
really strong.
It's a hardwood anyway.
Yeah,
that's a hard way.
And they,
they,
they know how to treat it through
the fire and make it like rock solid.
And then one end is almost like,
it looks like a javelin.
And so that's the end that they use for
either target practice or just sticking
it in the ground whenever they're
walking around and the other,
and they only use for whenever
they come across the line.
Wow.
So one end,
they throw it just to
like to just to practice.
Yep.
And,
uh,
we took some balloons over there
to see if the kids would like it.
And to be honest,
uh,
the,
the warriors liked the balloons better
than anything because we blow up those
balloons and just tie them,
throw them on the ground,
and then,
uh,
they would,
the different warriors would stock
the balloons almost on every time.
Almost the first throw,
every single time they nailed it.
How far away?
Uh,
I mean not too far because
the wind's blowing in there.
They're stocking it and whenever
they're going after a lion,
they normally wait until they're
close because if they miss,
they,
they wait until it's close.
And so,
I mean,
probably here to the door,
me and only like 20 feet.
Oh,
well,
I guess some of them did it farther where
some were getting it from all the way
to the,
to the window.
So some of them could actually
throw him pretty good and for,
sometimes they get jacked when
they go after these lines.
Oh yeah.
The,
the,
the spear that I have,
um,
the guy that's the warrior
that gave it to me,
it seems almost like it's
like most is his name.
It's like most and the other warrior
mean I'm slipping on his name.
Uh,
but I took a picture of both of
them in the one guy that I met,
he had this,
these teeth marks out of his,
uh,
his knee.
He's kneecap.
He,
he had a big room Goo,
which is a club,
but it was,
it was like a walking stick for him.
And,
uh,
his knee was really swollen and
it had these chunks out of it.
And then,
um,
we,
uh,
I asked him what happened to his
knee and then he pulled over.
They always wear red because that way
if they're ever wounded in battle or
anything hits them,
they,
you don't know that they're bleeding.
And so he pulled down his,
uh,
his Shuka,
which is like a robe of
sort for the warrior class.
And he pulled it down and down his
shoulder blade and the back of his like
shoulder.
He had claw marks,
I mean,
just wicked claw marks.
And so the,
the lion had attached onto a shoulder
on to his thigh and then bid into his
knee.
They showed me the scars
and the w the head warrior is the one
that saved the other warrior and that's
the spear that I have
hanging up at my house.
Wow.
So as the line was biting him,
homeboy jacked him with the spirit that
came after this one that wasn't even on
a lion hunt.
This was just,
they were going after,
uh,
or they were tending the fields,
tending the flock and aligned
came after the guy to fuck cats.
That's all I have to say.
And I'm more of a dog guy.
Yeah.
I'm way more of a dog guy.
I,
uh,
I have chickens right now.
It just got a little baby chicks.
That's awesome.
My little girl,
they wanted to get chicken,
so we decided to get like a little
chicken coop sort of a situation.
Um,
but the fucking cat,
I have two cats and my one cat,
this motherfucker just paces in front
of that door and laughed and Ryan,
and it doesn't matter if he's trained,
it doesn't matter if he's sweet nippers
he can't wait to murder one of those
birds.
He just can't get it out of his head.
Like in his head.
He's got to get in there and fit.
He hears them.
He sits out in front of the dorm,
the owls and you know,
it's,
it's almost like you want to kick his ass.
He like,
come on man,
why don't you fucking leave them alone?
They're little chicks,
but in his DNA there was
just no stopping that.
That's what he wants to do.
Yep.
Have you ever seen a live?
Uh,
yeah,
I,
I've just seen,
I've seen a two different times.
I've seen two and a one time
they were sitting over a,
it was either Cape Buffalo or a,
what is it,
a water buffalo water buffalo.
I think it was a water buffalo and uh,
it was still chomping down on that and
so it wasn't paying attention to us.
I had my spear though and I did,
but I wasn't going to test it out.
Like some guys are
trying to go over there,
have practiced with it.
I have practice with it,
but I'm not going to use it man.
Like,
I'm not,
I'm not what they already gave me,
uh,
the ceremony and gave me the spear,
made me a warrior.
In fact,
the other ones,
they can't be a warrior
until they kill a lion.
So they come back with the
female tail a waving it in.
If it's a male,
they come back with a law.
The main wrapped around them.
Yeah.
You got to be a w two w you have
to be Elian killer to be a warrior.
Yeah.
Oh my goodness.
Until then,
you're kind of a lesser class.
A male should bring a blue
state policies in this country.
Yeah.
So I thought I was a warrior.
That's what I tried to connect with them,
you know.
Hey,
I fought.
We,
they wrestle.
They just do take downs though.
They don't do any like ground
fight and you show them some moves.
I did.
I wrestled two at the same
time and picked them both up.
Uh,
so they thought that's how they thought
I was a warrior because they were like,
oh wow.
As wrestling,
like we can't dot.
You had a line of them.
Did you submit anybody?
Uh,
you try to teach them at a tap man?
No.
Uh,
for me,
I would just pick them up
and put him over my shoulder.
I did that with both of
them at the same time.
Wants to do what you got to remember.
They're,
they're skinny skinny dudes.
I did start to put one
in a guillotine choke,
but then I started thinking,
man,
this guy killed a lion.
He's not going to tap.
Right.
You know,
so I'm like,
I'm not going to hurt this guy.
I'm just going to play around with them.
So is he trying to wrestle with you?
Oh yeah.
They have figured out your sprawl.
Yeah.
Get doubled under hooks.
You're like,
what is he doing?
And they trying a couple of different
kinds of like colored ties and trips and
then they do like a double,
almost like a Thai clinch real.
Uh,
and so they do that and
they just kind of like,
um,
circle each other and they just
do that amongst the warrior class.
Just a,
almost like a ranking system of sorts.
So,
uh,
but you should be able to go in there
and school those dudes and why when it
came to wrestle,
create a whole elite team.
Yeah.
Masai warriors,
Kenyan wrestling team.
That'd be pretty crazy.
It's like you could be like
your own Sandra Bullock movie.
A white guy goes over there,
teaches them how to wrestle,
brings him into the state championship.
They got leaves for shoes,
teach him.
And Cy had a fucking tap people,
they probably don't understand this,
like probably so many different
techniques you can use.
I don't,
they don't see comment.
Right?
Yeah.
But the craziest thing is,
is that they have all these cactuses
and briar bushes all around.
So inside the village,
the wrestling was,
was okay,
but it was just,
it would happen anywhere.
And anytime.
I remember I had those,
a five finger shoes on and I stepped
right on a briar Bush and it went straight
through the soul of it and into my toe.
And,
uh,
I mean,
just,
I'm like,
come on guys,
let's at least were you,
uh,
you know,
so you just said it like,
where do you used to?
The mats were used to the,
to the sissy stuff.
And so those guys are just,
they're worried be barefoot too,
right?
Yeah,
they're barefoot.
I got shoes on,
I got,
I got hiking boots on.
I have,
I have everything.
So when they step on a briar
Bush and they're barefoot,
they just walk it off.
I don't know.
I didn't,
I guess I'm the only one,
even while we're wrestling,
I'm not aware enough to know there's a
briar Bush around or herself ridiculously
tough feet too,
especially with the pygmies,
the Masi too.
But a lot of the,
I now are getting a
sandals made out of tires,
so like tires at blowout,
they'll uh,
they'll make it out of the,
the rubber from the tire.
But the pygmies,
they don't have access to stuff like that,
especially because they don't have
anything to bargain or barter with.
They don't have goats,
they don't have cows and their slaves.
So they are mostly barefoot all the time
in the running through the jungle and
stuff like that.
And so they're the soles of their feet
actually almost like the soles of shoes
almost.
I mean,
not,
they don't have the,
the gripping and stuff and,
but uh,
but they're thick.
They're really thick.
Have you ever seen that studies
show where there's two dudes,
I think they call it dual survivor
or something like dual survivor?
I don't remember the Cody.
Cody a Landon or Landauer's,
I dunno.
Whatever homeboy's name is pig tails.
Yeah.
He's got pigtails,
big gorilla looking dude
doesn't cold weather snow,
I mean berries and stuff everywhere.
I saw the one and because I'm trying
to learn from those guys some survival
stuff,
which the pygmies no more than anybody,
but um,
while I'm here,
you know,
learning from that show and they did
like the swamps of Louisiana or something
and there's all these water moccasins
and all this stuff and he's barefoot and
there he,
he's walking through and poisons fighters.
And first time I saw
him scared like he was,
he was terrified walking through that.
Yeah.
One bite from one of those crazy fucking
animals that live down there and you're
done.
You got a lot of that
in the Congo as well.
I've watched some documentaries in the
Congo and then there's the only place in
the world when they have
spiders that move in packs.
No.
Yeah,
yeah.
And then,
uh,
their aunts manner,
pretty crazy.
My buddy I took with me,
um,
he went to take a dump
behind a tree and he put his,
he put his back against the tree and he
had these ants crawl up and just start
biting them.
Uh,
like these ants though,
make you bleed.
They're,
they're chompers on him.
Like literally,
um,
what's,
what's the most brutal part is they
tried to find the softest spot to bite or
something,
they,
with their sensors.
And so whenever they came up my,
my leg,
uh,
I didn't notice them
because how fast they are.
Uh,
I didn't notice them until
two were on my left nipple.
And I was like pulling this thing off.
And I mean,
I'm having to pull the aunt out.
And whenever I finally got it off,
I literally was bleeding.
Um,
like just from a fucking aunt.
Yeah.
And they travel in these things,
like I'm talking about.
They like roads.
So sometimes the,
the path that you're walking on,
if it's a pygmy path,
they're small.
Really,
really small.
Sometimes the,
the,
it's wider than the path of ants.
Like a,
I mean like a road,
a road of ants like this thick.
And I mean the,
the answer when like this,
this long and about an inch long.
Yeah.
But there's millions of them that
they make these roads that are wide.
They answered goddamn terrifying.
Yeah.
And even really are Brian Callum,
a good buddy of mine was working,
I think in Borneo.
I think you said it was,
I forget where it was.
It was in some jungle,
but he said they would
have to pose it in Congo.
No,
no.
But they had to put Turpentine
over the posts of the,
they had a suspended tents put turpentine
over the posts of the aunts didn't
climb up them.
He said,
well,
when you were lying in bed at night,
you would hear the ants
walking through the forest.
Yeah,
absolutely.
We can to them.
You can hear him.
Yeah.
I mean that's the part,
see,
that's,
that's why I know I'm passionate about
this and that I really feel like this is
my life's purpose because I don't,
I don't like creepy crawlies.
I don't like stuff like that man.
And,
uh,
I think I sent a picture of a black Mamba.
I almost stepped on a,
and luckily the pygmies killed it.
It was an angel.
And uh,
and it was,
it was pretty crazy because
all of a sudden I heard,
I heard the hut next to me,
which at this tribe was a chief and,
uh,
I heard his wife going nuts
and I would sleep with a,
I would actually sleep with the,
Yep.
There it is.
That's the Black Mamba and um,
that almost got you.
Yeah.
It was like five or
six feet long probably.
Did you guys eat that thing?
See,
I thought about it and they,
they,
they see,
they believe,
they believe trees and
snakes are their ancestors.
And so even though they killed the snake,
if it's a python,
they won't kill it.
They'll,
they won't kill a python.
They'll drag it to where it's safe.
The only python I've heard of them killing
was whenever they had gone fishing.
And then they had it almost
on like a stringer of sorts.
And then a big python came
by and took their fish.
And then the guy was so
mad he killed that python.
Um,
but the pygmies were mad at
him for killing a python,
uh,
because they aren't poisonous.
But the black Mambas,
they know how dangerous they are.
I think it's like 20,
30 minutes and you're gone.
And those things can get up
to like eight or 10 feet long.
And then the fastest snake in the world,
one of the most venomous,
so fastest,
most aggressive,
one of the longest.
And uh,
so it just seems like Congo man,
like everything,
there's some of the most
beautiful places in the world.
I mean,
the mountains covered on
the equator covered with,
I mean,
the most gorgeous trees.
A silver back gorilla is,
I mean,
just some beautiful stuff there.
But there were some gorillas in the wild.
No,
I haven't.
I haven't,
I think they said,
I've heard we've heard them and
we've heard definitely monkeys,
but I haven't seen the guerrillas.
Have you seen monkeys?
Oh yeah.
A lot.
Like,
yeah,
it's the Mohs cy,
not the pygmies,
but the Masa.
I actually will target
practice with their room.
Goos their clubs.
They'll throw those at the monkeys.
And so poor monkeys,
the monkeys get no fucking slack.
It's just like the pygmies,
pygmies,
the monkeys,
the little guys get picked on.
Yeah.
And I actually,
that,
uh,
Black Mamba that was up there,
I heard them going nuts.
And so whenever I got up
and I crawl out of my hut,
so,
which I mean,
those things for me to get inside,
sometimes I have to be on my elbows.
And so I start getting
out of it and I'm like,
what's going on?
And I had a video of it and uh,
I should cut it off right
before I asked the question,
but I didn't know what
kind of snake it was.
I thought Black Mambas were black,
like just black.
But it's actually their mouths
when they open their mouths.
It's like pitch black inside their mouth,
even.
They're like,
teeth are black.
And so,
um,
that's how they got their
name Black Mambas and so,
uh,
but they're,
they're gray on top and
then white on their belly.
And so I didn't think it
was a black Mamba at all.
And so I was,
uh,
I,
yeah,
I was getting out of my hut and then I
got slapped in the belly a and stopped
and I didn't know what was going on until
I got my phone on because it's pitch
black.
Yeah,
man,
that's the thing I almost stepped on and
it's like 20 or 30 minutes and you're
dead.
Oh,
what a creepy look in alien,
like creature.
They had only hit it in the back of
the tail and so it was still slithering
around.
Actually,
I'll pull up.
Wow.
I don't think I uploaded it to anywhere,
but maybe my phone.
So they won't eat these even though
it's a source of protein hungry?
Nope,
not at all edible though.
Black Mama.
I don't know about bike mama's.
I know that the pythons are,
uh,
rattlesnakes are actually pretty tasty.
Yeah,
I think,
I think if you cut it off far enough,
far enough down from its head,
then I bet it wouldn't be poisoned us,
but they weren't going to eat it all,
huh?
Yeah.
And then I,
I asked on the right before this video,
uh,
cuts off.
I ask if,
uh,
if it's poisonous and so,
yeah.
I don't know if I can,
if I can email the sows or Pete.
Pretty much everybody there must know
somebody who's been killed by something
natural in that area.
Oh yeah.
Whether it's a crocodile or whether
it's a lion or whether it's whatever the
hell else is out there.
Yeah.
The,
the rivers close to the pygmies
are full of crocodiles and hippos.
So crocodiles and hippos
live in the same thing.
Oh,
pumps too,
man.
That's another problem,
right.
Only hippos kill more people
leaving than crocodiles.
Yeah.
A lot more.
I got a video of a hippos and crocodiles
all in the same water hole and the
hippos,
we'll like swimming right next to the
crocodiles and they don't give a fuck
about the crocodiles and
they remotely concerned.
I don't think,
I don't think hippos are
concerned about anything.
And I don't know if you know that,
but they do like a bark.
I mean it literally sounds
like they're barking.
Um,
like a softer bark.
Not so like,
like doggish,
but it sounds like a bark and that's
how hippos like communicate and stuff.
And so like in the morning
and in the afternoon,
like towards like the
sunsetting and sun coming up,
the hippos are barking.
And so you hear that and
hear a little leave house.
Yeah.
And you hear these murderous giant pigs.
They're like thinking like a pig or
cousin to a pig or some shit like that.
Probably.
Yeah,
I think,
and I think there's
even like pygmy hippos.
So,
uh,
like pygmy hippos picked me crocodiles,
pygmy monkeys,
which are like the size of your finger.
Um,
like my,
like actual monkeys that are like
donkeys and size of your finger.
Are you anywhere near
that area of the Congo?
A,
I think it's called [inaudible].
Do you know where that is?
Bili Bi Loi.
Benny is really close be in,
I know that Zoe,
I don't have if ever heard of a that
chimpanzee that they found there.
Oh,
the one that's supposed to be massive.
Uh,
the,
I've heard stories from the
pygmies talking about a,
uh,
a like human type monk and not human type.
They weren't talking about like big foot.
And if they were,
I guess they were talking about me,
but no,
they,
they talk about,
uh,
different kinds of animals and,
but they all start about this scene,
spirits and stuff like that.
Right.
But I mean,
I've asked him about,
I forget what they call it.
There's like an actual,
like,
Swahili name that they call that,
uh,
that potential dinosaur of sorts.
It's friend David Choe actually went out
there looking for a long time ago for
vice,
it went for vice.com and he went to look
in the Congo for like a brontosaurus.
Wow.
Well,
it's so crazy.
It's like there's a saying,
the Congo was called the
heart of darkness and uh,
on the dark continent and the like,
the pygmies I think are the ones
that have the saying that it's,
I can't really say it
eloquent like they do,
but it's called a,
it's,
they say like,
it's basically hard for a fish to
navigate through the rivers because of how
thick everything is.
Um,
and it's just hiking
and everything is just,
it's actually,
I guess better to be a pygmy because it's,
it's hard to move around,
especially whenever you have like
an 80 pound pack on your back.
I'm trying to figure out how,
how I'm going to go.
I haven't sent this picture in,
but that's a,
that's part of the ways that we get
through like 85 kilometers hiking and
styles.
So it's just so thick.
Yeah.
People tried some European,
um,
a nobleman tried to live there.
They tried to settle into the Congo
because there's such a vast amount of
resources.
They just figured,
look,
we'll just carve out a little
place and then make a house.
And the forest just swallowed it all up.
They just couldn't keep off.
Yeah.
I think in the 18,
late 18 hundreds,
early 19 hundreds,
that was whenever they went there for
all the rubber and really slaughtered a
lot of the Congolese.
And then,
um,
since then they came in for the golden
diamonds and now they're there for the
Colton.
And you can go through
whole colonial like,
uh,
like settlements that are from like,
the,
from Belgium and other places
that have settled there.
And it's from like the early 19 hundreds,
and it's just,
uh,
almost like ghost towns.
Um,
but they're like the Belgian colonization
stuff and nobody lives there.
Like trees are growing up
through them and everything,
but they're brick buildings and the
Congolese don't live in brick buildings.
A lot of them don't unless
you're more towards the city.
Wow.
So,
um,
these pygmies that you talked to,
had they seen that big giant chimpanzee
at any of them?
I don't know.
I,
whenever I,
I heard lots of different
stuff and normally they open
up around the campfire at
night.
I would have to pretend
sometimes to go to sleep,
um,
for the band to slave
masters or the kids to leave.
And so Shalom University calls it Campfire
University for the pygmies because
they'll open up and there'll
be real around the campfire.
And,
uh,
they'll actually,
cause if I ask him in front of,
I had a chief,
uh,
of the band to come to me and welcome me.
It will.
First he was like,
what do you want with my people?
What do you want with my property?
Uh,
and then he,
and then I told him I
was just there to learn.
Um,
I was with the university
where they're learning,
doing research and just here to,
to help and benefit.
And then he gave me an egg.
Um,
he told me he had a gift for me.
And,
uh,
so he gave me just one single egg.
Uh,
it wasn't until,
and I was so grateful
and thankful because,
you know,
he gave me a gift and I was gonna be
able to eat it and everything else.
And as I'm cooking it,
uh,
and,
and the pygmies are helping me cook it,
uh,
and after I eat it,
um,
they finally tell me around the campfire
after I had pretended to go to sleep
and then got up to come back around the
campfire to talk for hours until we fall
asleep around the campfire.
They finally told me that the egg
they gave me wasn't the Bantu chiefs.
It was the pygmy chiefs and the pygmy
chief had saved that to give to me because
he heard that a visitor was coming.
And so the Bantu chief like just,
you know,
took his gift,
completely,
stole it and acted like it was his,
uh,
and really it was the pygmy chief and he
was giving me everything that he had to
give me because that's food for them,
like foods,
foods,
their livelihood.
Um,
and that was a clean source of food.
And,
uh,
so yeah,
it's just,
it's pretty messed up how they treat them.
Wow.
That's,
so,
that's gotta be so strange for
you to be around both of them,
to be around the band to people.
And do you,
do you try to communicate that there's,
there's something wrong with this?
Yeah,
absolutely man.
And uh,
so in six of the places I went to,
they referred to them as,
these are my slaves,
these are my people.
These are my property,
kind of of sorts.
Three of the places I went that
were even deeper in the jungle,
they said,
what do you want with my animals?
Because they believe them to
be so low class like that.
I see a man,
the,
the tribes that surround me,
it's,
it,
most of it spanned too.
Sometimes it's rebel.
Sometimes it's other tribes.
Uh,
but they,
they treat them worse than
they treat their cattle.
Then they treat their,
well,
they don't have cattle,
but they have goats.
And I don't know if that
falls into cattle category,
but,
uh,
but they treat their goats
better than they treat pygmies.
That's insane.
And they've always done this.
This is just,
well the pygmies used to never
have to depend on the band too.
So this is why,
I mean on the Ugi some
people have really been,
uh,
they're really interested and they'd
been trying to find out what kind of
slavery there is and the slaves
that we've been able to set free.
They weren't in shackles and
they weren't held at gunpoint.
Like,
I don't know how to do
that with the rebels yet.
Maybe in the year I'm there.
Um,
I can befriend them.
Like I had to befriend the slave masters,
so they would want to learn and stuff.
Um,
and so with the band to people,
we just had to sit there and say like,
Hey,
you know,
these are people.
Like I'm an educated guy
from the United States.
I'm not really that educated.
But uh,
but the Shalom university guys,
those four guys I'm with to have
masters degrees and to have doctorates.
So they're really educated and they're
the ones leading the university.
So I'm like,
these guys are,
are,
are knowledgeable and,
and,
and I came from us.
These are actually people
like fully human beings.
And the band two eyes
would get big like what?
And then they'll see us
treating them like humans,
treating them like they have
value treating them like,
you know,
they're,
they're like,
like they should be treated.
Right.
Um,
and so it starts to,
to change some of the things in,
in the pygmies are more slave to
the band through circumstance.
They used to not depend on them.
They used to be hunters and gatherers
and not have to worry about it.
But whenever I can see the sun at times,
and it sounds like this earth quaking
thunder going on all throughout the day,
thunder going on,
but I see the sun,
it's not raining on me.
I'm like,
why is there thunder?
And then we finally get close enough to
where we see some of the deforestation
going on.
And these are,
these are trees that you could
drive to Mack trucks through,
you know,
and,
and they're cutting these trees down.
And whenever those things fall,
it sounds like thunder.
And so the animals just flee.
I mean,
and,
and I think,
I think last I heard and I
don't know that it's scientific,
maybe someone can find it,
but uh,
but I think they said that the
deforestation in the Congo,
the second largest rain
forest in the world,
um,
is up to the size of Texas or
over Texas and the last like 15,
20 years less 1520 years,
man,
they've divorced,
did the size of Texas and I've seen it,
I've gone to places where it's just big,
lush,
awesome forest and then you go to this
place and it's just like wrecked and it
goes from like looking like
the rain forest and now
it's looking like this might
turn into like deserty kind of
stuff because like they've just,
it's barren and no one does any or makes
any attempt to replenish the forest.
No,
not all.
And see that is why the rain
forest conservationists,
the wildlife preservationist are getting
involved in ways that they're trying to
buy up that lane and protect it.
And I agree with that.
That's why I feel like what,
what Shalom is wanting to do and what
I'm wanting to partner with them.
It's a,
it's a all encompassing thing where
it's like human slave liberation.
It's a rain forest preservation
and wildlife conservation.
It's,
it's,
it's attractive to all those people.
There must be a tremendous amount of
money that they're making from those trees
though.
No.
Oh,
massive amounts.
I mean,
some of those are very rare woods.
Uh,
other things that they're using it for is,
uh,
his charcoal that seeing the Congo,
since they don't have like electric
electric plants and things like that,
they have to cook for them to cook.
If they burn up wood,
it's not as long lasting
or as hot as charcoal.
So I have a picture of a woman
that was a slave for charcoal and,
um,
she had to,
her slave master put this bag
of maybe 120 pounds minimum.
I mean,
the bag of charcoal was
taller than she was.
I mean,
a pygmy woman is,
is small.
Um,
I don't know if you can pull
up the one chai booze Sicu,
the picture that says [inaudible].
Um,
but I mean these are small people and
they're carrying bags of charcoal where
two slave masters put it on their back,
tie a rope around their head and this
woman having to walk four or five
kilometers on these little paths carrying
this charcoal and they'll cut down the
trees to make charcoal.
They'll cut them down and
they'll start a fire and,
but they'll put like dirt over
the fire and it smolders and it,
I don't know if it's a week long
process or a few day long process,
but it makes it just a long burning.
And so that's how most people cook in the,
and in Rwanda and in Uganda and in Burundi
and those places we'll get charcoal
from the Congo jungle
cause there's so much wood,
they don't even think about it.
Wow.
Yeah.
What a fucking trip.
So these,
these poor people that are,
are just recently slaved.
Hmm.
These,
uh,
these poor people,
these poor pig beans.
Before that they,
they were,
they were able to hunt and gather the,
able to do everything where
they treat it as people.
Then,
uh,
I would say there are
treated a lot better,
but still they've never
been believed to be,
um,
fully human.
They've always thought
of them as Subhuman,
part monkey,
part,
um,
part man.
And uh,
the thing is that with the Bantu,
uh,
the relationship,
the band too and pygmies used
to have is they would trade,
the pygmies were master
hunters and they still are a,
if there was more wildlife,
this was a specialty,
but they would go hunt bushmeat and
then they would come to the band.
What's bushmeat emotionally like?
Uh,
some monkeys,
um,
uh,
also antelope and uh,
just anything wild game inside of,
so that's try CQ that you just put up.
That's my mom and the tribe.
Oh,
it sounds so grown woman.
Yeah,
she's in her mid forties.
She's probably as old as my mom is 46.
So that's taboo seeker and she's awesome.
She,
that was her first
picture ever taken of her.
So I have some other
ones where she smiling,
but that,
that's the one that shows her,
uh,
her size.
So that's how they got their name p pygmy,
which is elbow height.
So they really are just like
the bullied people of the world.
Yeah.
And he's bullied people the world.
I mean there was times that I've gotten
sick to my stomach hearing the stories
that have happened to them.
And that's what I was saying,
that they would go hunt and then they
would come to the edge of the forest where
the band to are and the band to grow corn,
grow,
grow beans.
And they would basically want some
side dishes to go with their meat.
And so they would trade
sometimes like the,
the,
the wild plants that they would
gather and they would come and trade.
They're either bushmeat or they're hunted
animals and they're different kinds of
like mushrooms and stuff.
And they'd trade it with
the band to peoples for some
corn or beans or rice or a
cassava leafs,
which I can make a Ugalde out of.
Um,
it's like kind of paste like thing
that takes on the flavor of the meat.
And they would do it had
a trading relationship.
Sometimes band two would go find the
pygmies because they wanted some meat and
they weren't the best shepherds.
And so they could grow the corn and beans,
but they wanted to meet.
And so that's how the
relationship started.
And then they started to get exploited
whenever they could no longer hunt.
Like they,
they,
they really can.
Um,
the animals started fleeing,
uh,
in the wildlife conservationist
and rainforest preservationists.
Preservationists are trying
to push them towards the road.
They made a bunch of promises.
Uh,
I mean a lot of these NGOs that had
their special interest would promise the
pygmies,
if you go off the deep forest,
if you let us have this,
um,
we'll take care of you whenever
you're closer to the road.
We'll make sure you you're taking care of.
And then they just never took care of him.
Uh,
and then the band to buy up the land from
underneath them and then in slave and
say,
you're on our land,
you work at.
And so it's just kind of a whole crazy,
how does people feel about you
taking off going to America to,
to let everybody know about
them and then flying back again?
Mean he's this,
uh,
this must be so bizarre for them.
Yeah.
Well,
that's what's crazy at first,
every,
all the night,
well,
I've been to more than nine,
but the last time I went I went to
nine different tribes and of pygmies,
a little nine villages,
each one of them.
I'd never seen a white dude before.
Uh,
so that scares them.
I mean,
there'd be times that
it would take an hour,
maybe even sometimes a little over
an hour before someone in that tribe.
Most of the time it was
always women or children,
uh,
that would finally come up to me and touch
me to make sure they don't go through
me like I was a spirit
or a ghost of some sort.
Um,
and then once one person felt me and I'd
play a game with them or something like
that,
then more would,
I mean literally come out
from hiding behind trees,
come out from,
uh,
from the forest.
Whenever I come in,
sometimes they would flee,
run,
cry kids like flailing on the ground,
like just freaked out by me.
Um,
but whenever I'd make friends with them,
uh,
then they would ask me one thing,
every place that I went
and all nine tribes,
they asked me will I
help them have a voice?
That was the thing.
They were like,
we have no voice here.
They're the only tribe not
allowed to have their citizenship,
um,
in Congo and like,
so they have zero voice.
Wow.
What a strange turn your life has taken.
That this is a,
you've gone from being on the
house and the ultimate fighter,
you know,
competing in the heavyweight version of
the show to now live in a grass hut in
the Congo.
What a,
that's a string or a leaf,
hod rather strange journey you're on,
man.
Yeah,
to be honest,
I wouldn't change it.
I mean with,
especially with this video
going viral and with a,
yesterday,
um,
US talking about a book deal and,
and today I went out to,
uh,
to lunch with a publicist that will
really worked on the blind side and the
movie invincible.
And,
uh,
I forget some other big time
blockbusters that he worked on.
But,
uh,
I mean people are saying that this is a
kind of crazy story and the whole thing
is the Sandra Bullock movie,
man.
There we go.
I'm going to have her,
I'm gonna have her play me
my is Justin a chick?
Yeah.
Well we pulled it and uh,
he was more likely to believe that
it will more vulnerable situations.
You get this giant MMA
fighter go into the Congo,
kicking people's asses then ain't right.
Yeah.
No,
me and I just,
the,
the wild turn is man,
I just feel like it's,
it's something that I can be fully,
wholeheartedly passionate about and I'm,
I'm fulfilled doing it.
And uh,
and when I say they're my family,
I mean it seemed very,
very sincere.
How old are you,
Justin?
25.
So this is a good time.
You don't have kids,
you don't have responsibilities.
You can,
you can go and just follow your,
your desire and your passion and your,
your,
your interest here as the
only thing that really,
I mean,
I have a future wife and uh,
got to find her.
What's that?
You got to find her.
I have her in Dallas Fort Worth,
right.
She's in Dallas and you're going
to the fucking Congo for a year.
So how does she think about that at first?
Well,
at first she was pumped.
Then,
uh,
she,
she's done like some different trips
around the world and has gone and helped a
orphanages and Mexico and she kind of
has a heart to maybe one day started an
orphanage.
Um,
and so she's got a great heart man.
She's awesome.
She's gorgeous.
Um,
but,
uh,
the s the first time I went,
um,
I went one time before we started
dating and then the second time I went,
uh,
it was,
it was hard.
It was hard for her because she
started doing some research,
started finding out that,
uh,
the Congo leaves,
people call it the African Holocaust,
that's what they call it.
Um,
because depending on
what stats you look at,
they say it surpasses,
uh,
the death of death toll of
the Jews and the Holocaust,
which is pretty crazy.
But some stats say 6.8 million
Congolese and the last 10 years,
some say over 5 million,
but it's between 5 million.
And 7 million men.
Um,
and so it,
it really is like one of the,
if not the,
it is the worst conflict zone last year
in 2012 because then she was saying,
maybe I'll go with you.
And I was like,
yeah,
and then,
uh,
maybe,
we'll,
uh,
we'll talk about that.
And uh,
but the staff for 2012 was that over
400,000 women were raped in the Congo.
It's 58 women every 60 minutes.
So,
uh,
you can't bring your woman to the Connoco,
especially not kind of,
it was the most dangerous
Walmart parking lot in the world.
Uh,
and so it's,
uh,
it's,
it's been a crazy journey.
It's made us both grow a
lot in a relationship to,
um,
me being gone for that
month there and her,
you know,
sitting there and thinking about,
am I okay?
Cause I know contact.
Um,
so all this different stuff.
We,
we've really been on a journey and we
were talking about even getting married
before I went,
and then now we're,
we're talking about waiting
until I get back from the year.
But it's just something
I know I got to do.
Are you going to come back
at all during that year?
So far,
no.
I mean like spring.
Greg stirred,
actually my girlfriend's
sister's getting married and a,
I might want to come back for that.
But uh,
but so far,
no.
And it depends on my visa.
Luckily with Shalom university I might
be able to get like a student visa.
Uh,
I might be able to do something with
a school to get a year long visa,
but if I can't get to
your long be something,
I'd have to come back.
And you have no income
while you're doing all that?
No,
man,
I have the last year and a half,
man.
I've honestly felt like I was just a nut.
Like,
well not enough.
I knew it was right,
but I felt like a lone nut.
Like everybody,
people be like,
oh,
that's really good,
but why don't you go back to fighting?
Uh,
I mean,
I've worn my last three fights and then
I took some time off to go see the world
and see what people I could fight for.
And I couldn't find anyone
better to fight for them,
the pygmies because they're the
worst off people group on the planet.
And,
uh,
but yeah,
man,
it's,
it's been a crazy journey,
you know,
from people,
a family,
from close friends all see.
And I'm an idiot for given up fighting
and I could actually do it well and,
um,
at grudge training center,
going from,
from being invited thereafter,
the ultimate fighter to then being kicked
off of it when I was a drug addict to
then being invited back onto it.
Uh,
and then,
um,
me saying,
you know,
I'm going to,
I'm going to leave and go,
go here.
And then they'll be like,
what are you doing?
You know,
uh,
my coach Trevor Whitman,
he's awesome.
I love that dude,
Bro.
He's one of the best guys
I know as a person too.
He's just incredible.
Him and his wife,
a big giving hearts.
And we,
uh,
we set up three different
hospital visits for the,
for grudge fight team.
I was,
uh,
official volunteer at the
Denver Children's hospital.
So we went there three
different times as official,
like whole team.
Um,
and so that was great.
That was how I started showing them,
Hey,
I've really made a life change here.
I'm no longer the drug addict
that was coming in here.
And,
uh,
and I mean we're actually a
depressed drunk drug addict.
Tried to take my own life,
all this different stuff.
And what were you,
what were you addicted to?
Was addicted to a bunch of pills,
a bunch of pain pills.
I had three different doctors that would,
that would give me scripts.
And,
uh,
I had one doctor that would give me a
hundred at a time and I could go to all
three of a hundred at a time.
No joke.
Which pills?
Uh,
well,
hydrocodone a lot.
But then also,
um,
I even gotten into like
harder stuff like on,
is that Vikatin?
Yeah.
And then,
and then,
uh,
and then oxy and oxy is the hardest,
right?
Yeah,
Bro.
I don't,
I don't remember two to two
and a half months of my life.
Like just,
there's no memories except for there's
one hazy memory and was from my best
friend at the time and we're,
we're building that relationship back.
But,
uh,
my best friend at the time,
the guy that got me into fighting and
then my first fight was because he was in
the hospital and,
uh,
and he couldn't make it to the fight.
He had a staph infection where they
almost thought he was going to lose his,
that his leg.
It was that bad in a lot of guys get that.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
And he got,
he got,
he got put to the side,
like they literally thought
we might have to take his leg.
It was deep and do as like,
oh,
they thought it might've
been in his femur bone.
So he's laid up man.
And uh,
and then I went to the,
to the promoter,
told him he's out.
Then the guy started talking trash.
He just ended up in the hospital one day
early and the promoter had watched me
wrestle.
It was an Oklahoma.
And so he knew my high school wrestling
coaches who are both two Olympic gold
medalist,
both wrestled Oklahoma state
were national champions there.
Kenny Monday and Kendall Cross and uh,
Kenny money fund MMA for a while.
Yeah.
He was one of my training partners to
whenever I was in coaches whenever I was
fighting.
Um,
he's been a coach of mine
since I was 15 years old.
Uh,
and then,
yeah.
Anyways,
the guy,
uh,
his name's Justin McCorkle,
I think he's like a foreign one,
pro MMA heavyweight.
And um,
yeah,
I missed his wedding,
not just being there,
but being the best man.
And I remember I had an eight minute
voicemail and meet at like 10 seconds
through because it said something like,
you missed my wedding.
And then I'm like,
oh,
freak,
you know,
and then it paused and he goes,
you miss being my best man.
Uh,
and then I just remember
hanging up because,
and going straight back to the drugs.
And so I'm a medical marijuana
license for three years,
which I'm cool with people having that.
But I went with,
I would always piggyback everything.
Like I would,
the reason grudge voted me off the team
was I started waking up and fixing my
steel cut oats,
fixing my egg whites,
getting my berries,
putting in the steel cut oats,
um,
fixing all that.
But then,
uh,
starting on my vaporizer before
practice and then hitting a,
the pain pills and then starting with
a washing it down with hard liquor man.
And so then I go train and they knew it.
They knew I sweated out love out
of my poor was coming liquor.
Um,
they knew that.
I mean,
how would you bro,
I don't know.
I mean I was going through a literal,
when I say depression,
I mean like the darkest,
deepest,
um,
most desperate time of my life.
And what was that being caused by?
Um,
selfishness.
I don't know,
man.
A lot of different things that,
that didn't,
uh,
it didn't make sense to me.
I grew up at 13 years old.
I was,
I was heavily bullied.
That's when I found the UFC.
Uh,
13,
I sat at the lunch table by myself,
had people throw stuff at me.
I,
uh,
I was invited to my middle school
crushes like a birthday party and,
uh,
and it was a costume party.
I got the invitation.
I'm like,
no ways costume party wins a prize.
And I remember her dad
worked for Dr Pepper and,
um,
she loved transformer.
So I came to the party as
a Dr Pepper transformer,
like with the Dr Pepper Cardboard and
made out of a made out of duct tape and Dr
Pepper boxes.
And,
uh,
I got there and I was 30 minutes late.
Everyone's pointing,
laughing,
calling me an idiot.
And that was whenever I was probably,
I guess maybe in the
first fight of my life,
uh,
was suicidal thoughts
cause they were like,
you're so worthless.
You should just kill yourself.
Um,
13 old.
Oh yeah.
I mean I left there.
Oh,
I there no cell phones.
So I walked and I got to dairy queen.
I lived in the country,
so we like that.
They call that the Texas stop sign,
dairy queen.
And,
uh,
and so,
I went to dairy queen and,
uh,
I,
I think I remember one of the,
uh,
employees,
I'm coming out to throw away trash and
I'm like sitting there behind the dairy
queen right in between
kind of the dumpster.
And then they're like,
what's going on?
And I was just sobbing.
And then I went inside and called my mom.
She wasn't there for a little
bit and had to sit in there.
They asked what was going on anyways,
so that was this big left turn.
But that's when I found the UFC.
And I thought maybe a
few weeks after that,
and I thought,
these guys don't get bullied.
Uh,
these guys are like modern day gladiators.
Um,
I,
and I was,
I mean,
I was mesmerized by the sport of it
because I loved sports and I always played
sports growing up.
Um,
but this was multiple sports putting one.
And I'm like,
man,
if I could just become one of those guys,
I'll have all the passion,
the purpose,
the significance,
the,
I'll never be this dude
that I am right now.
And,
uh,
I'll,
I'll be the exact opposite.
And so I set out for
that and started at 15.
So wrestling under two
Olympic gold medalist,
17 won my first national championship.
18 was living back and forth
with the Olympic training center.
19 started fighting professionally.
21 I was on the ultimate fighter 22,
um,
fight in 23.
It was main event at the hard
rock and another promotion.
And I think every time I got my hand
raised and it got worse as this drug
problem got on.
But,
uh,
I stopped looking forward to even the
victories of fighting and start looking
forward to the parties after the fight.
And then I started thinking like,
uh,
I don't know,
every time I get my hand raised,
uh,
if you can find a picture of me or
a video of me smiling after a fight,
that would be the first for me because I
don't think I smiled after any of them.
Wow.
I was always looking towards the next one.
You know,
most guys jumping up,
smile and screaming.
When was your issue with,
with drugs?
Was it after the ultimate fighter?
But it was,
it was before and after.
It got really bad after and
I mean it got brutal after I,
uh,
actually the,
the week of my job,
I don't know if I've ever,
I told Loretta hunting this,
I'm a couple of days,
I did an interview for
sports illustrated and uh,
um,
the week of my John Madsen fight I was
taking handfuls of pills and I was uh,
in,
in some guys can function,
um,
and,
and fight and everything.
Me Though,
I would piggy back everything if I got,
if I got high,
I needed,
I needed the pills or I needed a drinker.
I never did one thing that was my,
that was a huge problem of mine.
I always piggyback that I had to have
something else and so I was doing that the
week of my John Madsen
fight for the finale.
And while you were there,
how was high that week and the pain pills
like lots of pain pills like the day
before?
I didn't the night,
the day of how did you not test positive?
They didn't,
they didn't test me on that one.
They tested me when I
fought at the hard rock.
But at that one they didn't task,
they only tested the main events.
I think that was the time
that there was a commission.
Yeah.
Or even the,
I think the commission hit a time where
they didn't test everybody on the card.
They were only gonna do like the main
event fights or something like that.
And then I was kind of in that window.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's crazy,
man.
What,
what would happen if they did test you?
Oh,
I would've failed big time,
which is like a lot of the other guys do.
But I mean,
not a lot of the biggest,
so you knew you weren't
going to be tested.
Is that why you were
kept taking the pills?
I honestly,
yeah,
I would have taken him anyway.
I didn't care.
I never did any sort of steroids.
Never.
I already,
I already felt empty enough,
I guess with some of the victories.
And I think whenever we got real bad
was after that Roy Nelson fight on the
ultimate fighter and Dana and rampage
and Rashad and coach t and basically
everybody except Roy.
Um,
was telling me that it should have,
well that I won or that it should have
gone to a third round at least because I
think one judge thought
want to thought he won.
It was a split and we
only went two rounds.
And for me this was my dream.
And uh,
and so whenever that was taken from me
and I felt like it was taken in a wrong
way,
then what really got bad
was after the Mattson fight,
um,
I lost a split decision again.
So two back to back.
I just,
I lost it and I went straight.
I mean,
I don't even remember that we can Vegas.
What started you off on
pills in the first place?
Well,
it was it an injury this right here.
Um,
so do you know how many times I've
heard that man will guy gets injured?
Is doctor puts them on pills?
Carl [inaudible] same story.
Went off the deep end.
How goddamn addicted or the addictive or
these pills and it just got handed them
out to,
I remember,
uh,
a bit about my mom would confirm it,
but,
uh,
whenever this happened,
I was 18 and I was living at the
Olympic training center and I wrestled a
against the world champion.
I didn't give up a point.
It was kind of like I could
have given up a point,
it would have been similar to,
could have tapped or let it snap,
but I just didn't want to give up a point.
So I let him and snap and uh,
anyways,
I probably took at least a month worth
of the oxycodone and a week after that I
went back.
Probably took three weeks worth.
What happened next with arm?
What position was it in?
It was just wrestling,
Greco Roman wrestling.
So,
uh,
have you ever seen a gut wrench like
short Recko how they go to turn somebody?
Um,
so I was fighting it,
the post explaining to people
who don't know anything.
I was,
I was a on my belly.
A guy who maybe took me down and,
and once he's on your back,
he goes to do a gut wrench.
She wraps around your ribs and he starts
to crank down with his shoulder on the
back of your shoulder blades.
You're trying to fight it so
your back doesn't break 90,
it breaks 90 degrees and in your
back angles towards the Mat,
the guy gets two points or
maybe you one point sometimes.
Uh,
but I didn't want to have my,
uh,
backbreaking 90 to
where he get any points.
So just let it keep fighting,
fighting,
fighting.
And I tried to to do this hot thing
and whenever I went to do the hop hit,
that's whenever all his
weight came down on it.
Super Experience Guy.
He's like 33,
34 and I was 18 at the Olympic training
center where he was world champion and
Olympic bronze or silver medalist and it
just snapped it whenever it snapped and
went completely behind my back.
One of my buddies at the Olympic
training center puked because of it.
And uh,
so I was laying on it
completely behind my back.
Like if I was on the bet,
the mat right now is
completely behind my back,
except it was this way.
So it was show part of this
whole part of my heart is wicked.
This whole part of my
arm was under my back,
so it broke it,
it dislocated it and it tore the
old Neri collateral ligament.
Um,
so they did a nerve transposition.
So I have no more funny bone.
Uh,
they moved it to where it's right here.
So if I talk on the phone too long,
these three nerves go numb or I'm sorry,
these three fingers go numb.
Uh,
and then they took a,
they were going to do,
is it a cadaver?
Cadaver?
Cadaver.
So they were going to use a
cadaver nerves that Zombie show?
No,
no.
For the torn ligament,
the UCL,
the ordinary collateral.
But then instead they use the,
uh,
there's like three tendons in your
hamstring that are kind of like this.
And he took the center one out and
they said a tendon is stronger than the
ligament.
And like,
we want to put some strong in there.
If you're wanting to be an
Olympic caliber athlete,
um,
and they said that that was actually
maybe a harder chance for it to,
to take,
um,
but it was the best chance
to take instead of a cadaver,
which might be weaker,
smaller person than your
body could reject it.
Right.
Dominick Cruz nine brutal blows it out,
has to do it all over again.
Yup.
And so they,
they wanted to use that
tending cause of stronger,
and he said,
and it's going to be from your leg.
And he goes,
and you want to fight Sunday?
And I go,
yeah.
And he said,
well,
this will be like you're kicking
someone in the face then.
And I'm like,
okay,
that sounds pretty sweet.
Uh,
but yeah,
so that's whenever the drug
problem probably started.
I remember I was,
I was piggy back and even then,
um,
kind of started going into
depression because I thought,
man,
did I just lose my Olympic
dreams and my MMA dreams?
Uh,
so,
and I was doing all the oxycodone.
The how old were you at this
time when you hurt yourself?
18.
Yeah.
So you're 18 years old.
No drug problem before.
No,
get on the pills.
And I had smoked some
weed before and I drank,
but not as never,
no nothing where I had to have anything.
People in my family that
have had the same issue,
guy got injured and all of a sudden taking
pills for his back and he's a fucking
loser now.
I mean,
he's just gone.
It was a normal guy and now he's a loser.
And I've met so many people that know
somebody that has that same story or that
have that same story and then like
you pulled themselves out of it.
It's so terrifying.
It's so terrifying how they're just
handing out some of the most addictive
medication that the world has ever known.
That that really is what it is.
It's brutal,
man.
I,
I owe and it's heroin.
Yeah.
And I know drive on it.
I would a man I,
and I know that's,
hey,
you should have that reaction.
I,
I have that reaction to me now
looking back at my life and,
and,
and just,
I mean,
I dunno,
thank God that I didn't,
I didn't kill somebody or a family or,
but I remember the time that
I really wanted to end it.
I just took a handful of the hydrocarbons.
Um,
I was taking Adderall to,
uh,
I,
and then I was,
uh,
drinking straight.
I'm actually,
I didn't drink it straight,
but I had it,
uh,
in a Sonic Cup,
but it was ever clear,
like a strawberry slushy up,
brutal and knows how to party.
I told you about the,
he's got a dead pig on his shoulder.
I got to hang out with.
And then I was,
I had my tinctures.
Tinctures are,
yeah.
And so I had those and um,
and so I just took it all and
driving and I blacked out.
Oh yeah.
What a confusion.
Your mind,
you had a civil war
going on in your brain?
I did.
And I blacked out driving and,
uh,
I do what?
I've been so low that have woke up in
a drug house up in kind of a outside on
the outskirts of summit county.
Um,
and uh,
it will,
you still usually live in boulder?
Yeah.
So you know where summit county is then
with like Breckenridge and keystone.
So we'll go up on me and I loved it.
Yeah.
I wish,
uh,
yeah,
I'm in Texas right now,
so Congo is going to be beautiful too,
but I miss scholar is another level.
Yeah.
It goes a different level of life.
It's like so vibrant and green,
rainy and everything that,
I don't know if you know this,
this is a completely different subject.
But in Uganda,
right on the border of where I'm at,
there's,
it's on the equator is the jungle.
Um,
but there's mountains that
are so high that there,
I think the only,
uh,
glaciers that you can find on the equator.
So there's like actual glaciers in Uganda,
in Africa on the equation,
the equator right outside the jungle.
That,
so there's glaciers.
That's insane.
Yeah.
So anyways,
that's completely random.
What made you straighten up?
What made you sober up?
I knew I was going to die.
Well,
that was one thing.
Uh,
how did you do and you clean up?
for me personally,
um,
I had this guy that that
was just brutal man.
He a brutal in a way.
Like he was relentless.
He was just coming after me,
man,
saying that I had a purpose to live for,
um,
saying that,
you know,
uh,
he told me this and I remember,
I'll always remember this is
my buddy named Jeff Donkey.
He'll probably be watching this.
He's an awesome dude.
Man has a great family,
great wife,
great kids.
Um,
and he told me,
Justin,
you're in the battle for your life.
Like if you,
this life is a battle ground,
not a playground.
If you treat it like a playground,
you will lose the battle.
And then he started talking like,
what's your game plan for victory here?
And I'm like,
man,
I got a perfect game plan,
right?
Like,
I mean,
thank God that guy didn't find Brian.
You'd be like,
well,
I'm no,
no,
I'm not.
No,
no battle.
I'm here to play.
Fuck.
What am I going to lose?
That eating too much pussy.
And so he told,
he told you that you have
to find your purpose.
Yeah,
he said I had to find a purpose
and that I had a purpose.
What does this gentleman do?
Um,
he's a Roofer,
so he's a childhood friend and uh,
not,
uh,
actually he's even older.
Like I had some family friends in a debt,
a guy that was like a second dad to me
and his kids are some of my best friends.
And um,
and Jeff was kind of in that,
that core group,
but he had heard through the grapevine,
uh,
that my mom had come and checked on me
and that like two and a half period.
And I think my,
my dad might've came,
but,
uh,
but she had broken into my house
that was in color and not broken in,
but she just was able to
get through the back door,
saw the drug,
saw the pills,
saw how has living,
and it looked like hoarders
or just just filthy.
Um,
and so she knew that he might be one guy
that could get to me and get through to
me.
And so he called me every
single day for two months.
I mean called me,
left me a voicemail,
text me and email me
and was pissing me off.
Man.
I was getting livid with them.
And then whenever I got
kicked off a grudge,
I got up to my phone and
it got out to my car.
I was like an angry tears.
I didn't know what to do.
Um,
because like I was living my dream,
but it was a nightmare
and my dream was reality.
But it was literally a nightmare.
Right?
You're living your dream as
a competitive MMA fighter,
but you're also a drug.
I had,
I had transform successfully,
I guess we can go back that I transformed
successfully from that 13 year old
loser that was invited to the parties.
And now I was that maybe quote
unquote modern day gladiator,
ultimate fighter,
mixed martial artist and uh,
and somehow I wasn't fulfilled.
Somehow I was a depressed
drug addict and um,
and whenever I got to my car,
I had a text message,
voicemail,
all this other stuff then
want to hear from him.
But the text message said
this was when your iPhone,
it didn't just say text message on it,
it would say like the actual message and
on the actual message on the screen it
said check her email,
checked my email.
The very first thing said
a game plan for victory.
Um,
and then whenever I opened it up it said
the best thing you'll ever do in your
life.
Uh,
and it was a trip that was paid for and
I thought it was maybe like a a detox
detox kind of thing or a
rehab or something like that.
So I was interested in,
I just got kicked off of grudge.
I think Trevor was the only guy,
maybe Brendan?
No,
I think there was like
30 guys or something.
They got there early to vote on the day
of sparring to vote if I stay a part of
the team because some of the
guys that had it with me and Ti,
coach t brought me into
his office and he said,
Bro,
like we can't have our name
attached to you anymore.
Like,
I'm the only guy that
once you still a party,
I could veto it.
Maybe I'm the head coach,
but I'm not going to go
against the guys and grudges.
Unique man,
because grudges,
it's a family.
I mean,
then what I mean like it's,
it's like the,
I think for Elliot Marshall,
we threw a surprise baby shower for him.
I mean,
in fighters throwing a
baby shower for a fighter,
you know,
like that's just not normal.
And a lot of fight gyms are there.
A bunch of gym hoppers and a bunch of
selfish dudes and they're never going to
give the coach to the money
or they're never gonna.
They're gonna try to knock
out their training partners.
Like we,
we just worked like a
head cookouts together,
all this different stuff.
But I was the one guy that was a,
that was the problem.
And uh,
they voted me off and
so me and I was just,
I was empty.
I felt like,
man,
now my dream or my nightmare,
but my dream now that's
even ripped away from me.
So now I had nothing,
you know?
I know that you've gone
through some growth as a human,
as a man,
some spiritual development and
character building and all that.
But I can't help but be terrified at
how smart you are and how to gather and
passionate you are.
But yet you still got hooked
by these fucking pills.
Those goddamn things
scare the shit out of me.
And I know you were a younger
man at the time and you didn't,
you didn't have the life
experiences that you have now,
but you're not a loser.
So the fact that you got just
sucked up into it like that,
it's,
it's so terrifying to me.
Yeah.
I mean,
they're,
they're dangerous man.
I think they should.
I don't know how they could,
they could,
uh,
watch it better.
You know?
I mean,
I,
I shouldn't be able to go to three
different doctors and have one given me a
hundred at a time.
I mean,
you know what I mean,
hundred,
this is going to Colorado.
Yeah.
At least they have.
I mean,
I literally just go to
three different pharmacies,
three different doctors,
three different doctors to be,
that was the whole topic of a vanguard
show called the oxycontin express.
Oh,
I was on it.
I was off the board at the man.
I was taking the train.
It's about Florida.
It's Florida.
Had these things calls up pain management
centers where you would go to a doctor
and the doctor would say,
what's wrong?
I hurt my back.
What?
You need a prescription for pain pills.
So the doctor writes it in the
same facility right next to that,
you leave the doctor's door.
The next door is the pharmacy
that only sells oxycontin.
You go in there and you buy pain
pills and they have these fucking pain
management centers and
they're all over the place.
So you essentially have these
oxycontin addicts waiting in line it,
all these parking lots
to get into these places.
And the places was filled.
They were filled with poor people that
were just hooked on these goddamn pills.
And I think,
I think for me,
uh,
mean I appreciate you saying like,
you know,
you're not a loser.
Smart guy or whatever.
I think it's true.
I mean,
I'm listening to you talk,
you're,
you're obviously a smart guy.
Well,
I appreciate that.
I think that worked in my
advantage for my problem.
Uh,
I,
if that makes sense.
Like,
it,
it fed it.
I was able to justify it,
justify owning also,
but to the doctors even
like articulate it,
I wasn't the same kind of guy they would
classify as we got to watch this guy.
He's a professional fighter.
He does have a bum elbow.
He's got a back problem.
He,
uh,
yeah,
we can trust this guy.
What was your back problem?
I actually,
in my last fight,
I a herniated one disk
and I bulged another.
And so I have a,
I have an x ray that
they have a messed up,
uh,
actually a bunch from the,
mainly it was the thoracic,
the thoracic,
and then one or two of the lumbar.
But,
um,
I have a x ray of,
from those pain management places.
I think I had six different
disk where they put these,
uh,
injections into my spine of Cortisone,
kind of like cortisone.
I'm trying to think of some sort of
steroid a little time for absolutely.
That was brutal because I was supposed
to be in a twilight kind of sleep and I
woke up during it because he hit
something and I just remembered just ah,
uh,
and then they put some
more in me and I was out.
But yeah,
I had a boss and in
here yesterday and his,
his right arm,
it's like shriveled away because of a
neck injuries cause the disc injuries.
I used to get stingers all
the time from wrestling.
So it's so amazing how many guy you have
a bulging disc now and my neck and uh,
it's amazing talking to how
many guys talking to people,
asking how many guys also have the same
injury or a similar injuries were in
their lower back or in the middle backer.
It's fucking everybody.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
Yeah.
And I mean,
it's easy if you want to get,
if you want to get it,
uh,
you know,
fund your or whatever,
find your addiction and you want to
find a way to feed that and you can,
if you want to find something
to take a pill for it,
they'll,
they'll get you.
Absolutely.
Even one of my doctors was an Iowa,
so two,
we're in Colorado.
One was an Iowa.
We won't go there,
man.
That's a,
that's terrifying shit.
But it's a,
for a lot of people out there that might
be struggling with that very problem
right now listening to this,
you know,
hearing you that you were able
to pull yourself out of it,
I guarantee you,
you can inspire people to do the same
when they can realize they listen to you
and go,
I want to be that guy.
I don't want to be this guy that I'm now
a slave to his bottle of pills that I
have to figure out how to get every week.
You know?
I feel like that's one of the reasons
I have that connection to the pygmies.
Like,
I wasn't a slave to a band too,
but I've bet I've definitely
been a slave to something.
Uh,
and,
and so yeah,
if there is somebody that's watching me
and that you can get out of it because,
um,
there's definitely hope.
How did you,
how did you do it?
Did you go cold Turkey?
Yeah.
I actually,
I went,
I ended up going on that,
uh,
that kind of retreat of sorts with
my buddy and he just loved on me,
man,
in a way that,
uh,
it was genuine.
It was authentic.
Where was the retreat?
What did you guys do?
Have you ever heard of the
hallmark family or hallmark cards?
Sure.
I know they're big in Texas.
I don't know if they're not sure,
but it was actually their
house or their ranch.
Um,
and it was,
they kind of donated this ranch
to be for all walks of life,
um,
kind of all beliefs and
for people to come there.
And,
uh,
it was a vision of this one guy that,
that wants to just have a place where
people's lives can be changed and stuff.
Man,
there's these,
there's like 20,
30 guys that said that
they are not that said,
but they literally went
to war for me in my,
in my life and told me
how to life worth living.
And it was,
it was awkward,
kind of,
not awkward,
but just right.
At first I was like,
what's up here?
This is crazy.
Um,
but for me,
I had a,
I had a radical change,
man.
It wasn't a,
it wasn't a,
it wasn't a slow process.
It was like I finally realized
I have a life worth living,
um,
in my life can be for a
bigger purpose than myself.
Then getting what I want when I want it.
Um,
I can make a contribution to this planet,
to this world,
to people.
Um,
I can not just fight against people.
I can fight for people.
And that's what it was demonstrated
in front of me at this retreat.
Um,
and I'm,
I'm not man.
I have my own personal beliefs.
Everyone does,
man.
Uh,
but this was a,
it was a Christian retreat
and for me it changed my life,
man.
Because,
uh,
these men weren't like,
because Bro,
if you want to go into some
jacked up religious background,
I got it.
I've got a jacked up religious background.
Um,
I have family that says if,
I mean just crazy stuff like you
have instruments in your music,
you go to hell if you have tattoos,
you got to have them only
tattooed guy and my family.
Um,
and I have a whole back piece and,
and,
and all this stuff.
And I had another one where,
so they're super like legalistic
and this rules and this other one,
when I'm 13 years old,
I left up a church camp.
When we church camp,
I ever went to,
I left the church camp,
have bruises on my neck because
they tried to cast demons out of me.
Um,
and then,
yeah,
yeah.
And then I went to Catholic
school and had a background where,
you know,
the,
the parents were throwing keg parties
for us and then only there in this place
and this retreat.
And I told the guy,
Bro,
I don't need anything Christian,
Bro.
I don't need it.
I don't want it.
Uh,
I know your type,
like if I sit around the campfire and
hold hands with a bunch of sissies punks
and sissies and sing Kumbaya,
what does that,
what is that going to do for me?
I need a real answer.
I need some like real hope and me and
the guy gave me an answer where it was
like,
you know,
a real people with real problems
could really use a real god.
Um,
and for me that just
kind of struck a chord.
He told me that if you,
and this is again,
this is my beliefs and stuff,
so I'm not throwing anything
out there on anybody,
but he told me,
um,
and it made sense to me.
You've experienced the counterfeit
and for counterfeit to me,
anything,
there's gotta be an authentic.
And he told me,
you know,
if there's going to be a full
ex a watch made a fake Rolex,
there's gotta be a Rolex and
you've been around the fake stuff,
you've been around the full Lexis,
you felt the weight of
them and they broke on you.
You,
you've seen it and you,
you sometimes gotta get close
enough to where it ticks,
where it has a smooth transition.
Other Times you got to actually hold it
because there's that smooth transition
on the Rolex instead of ticking.
Other ones are so tricky.
You actually got to feel the weight.
What,
what you're making an analogy
too is the fake religious people,
the people that know the people that,
that,
that abused me.
And there's a lot of religious people
that abused people that judge people that
all this stuff,
man.
And,
and for me,
and what this guy shared with me and
what he did was he didn't look at the
problems I was going through
except for to help me out of him.
He didn't come down on
me about any of them.
He didn't judge me.
He didn't say you're wrong.
He didn't say God hates you.
He didn't.
He said,
God loves you bro.
And you got problems and that's okay.
And Love God,
love people.
If you can do that thing,
it would solve all the problems.
If you could love God and love people
that and then that would change things.
And so that's what changed
my life was like wow.
And the Wa what had to happen first was
to see if God could actually love me.
And then I felt it me and my own
personal experience and encounter.
Like I felt like,
man,
God,
God doesn't hate me.
He might love me.
And then I feel like he does love me and
then he wants me to love him back and
love people.
And if I can do those two things for me,
that would change.
It has changed my life and I believe
it will change others lives if I can do
that.
I think for a lot of
people who are atheists,
they hear this kind of talk,
one of them,
one of the things that comes to
mind is they're going to like,
where's is God?
You're talking about?
Where's this evidence?
Um,
to,
to put it into it,
the way I kind of look at it,
like a lot of people,
uh,
have thought for whatever reason that,
that I don't believe in God
or that I'm anti God or,
or that I'm an atheist.
I'm,
I would,
I would not classify myself in any way,
shape or form.
Uh,
I definitely don't think that
I am an atheist because I,
I don't not believe in God.
But what I think
is that when someone can tune into the
genuine intentions of the best aspects of
any religion,
whether it's Christianity,
whether it's Hinduism,
whether it's what it really boils
down to is love and generosity and,
and,
and fellowship and,
and moving towards good and bringing
people together with happiness rather than
moving towards bad.
And what you've done in your life,
you can call it God,
you can call it anything,
but what you've done in your life is
recognize the worst possible aspects to
chemical addiction,
the depression,
the sadness,
the failure,
all the self sabotage.
And then realize there's
another way to do this.
I've hit the worst possible frequency.
And I've also kind of barely been able
to tune into this great frequency,
well,
what is this?
Knowing the lows and the lowest lows,
sometimes you can really sort
of extrapolate that there's a,
there's a counter to that.
There's 180 degrees to that.
Just like your friend was talking
about the full lux and the Rolex,
you know,
you call,
for a lot of people that have
a problem with the word God.
You know,
I had this Guy Alex Grey on
who's this visionary artists,
really fascinating,
fascinating guy,
and he's also this a
psychedelic adventure.
And he throws around the word
God all the time and he's like,
you know,
we kind of have to take that word back
because the word God sort of has this bad
heebie jeebies yeah,
yeah.
Like,
Oh,
you're talking about nonsense.
But no,
you're not necessarily talking
about nonsense and you're,
you know,
just because you can't prove it.
And just because you know,
the,
the Bible was written
thousands of years ago,
it doesn't mean it's all bullshit.
And the,
the,
the true frequency of love,
the true frequency of
fellowship is really what,
what leads to happiness.
If you're experiencing that yourself.
Oh Man,
I am.
And that's what this,
this vision is for me with
the pygmies in the Congo,
like a lot of people have misinterpreted
it to where they've thought,
oh,
you're just going there to
make a bunch of converts.
You should take him a sandwich
instead of a bunch of converts.
Like if,
if people,
if,
if you actually looked at what I'm doing,
like I'm actually doing slave liberation,
rainforest conservation
and wildlife preservation,
all wrapped into one
sustainable ways of life.
This and that.
It does not hinge around,
uh,
it does not really hinge around
if they become a Christian or not.
If they don't and they
don't want to and they will,
they want to worship their god,
do witchcraft,
do all that fine.
I'm going to love you the same way I feel
like God has put on my heart a desire
to love them and to love them well and
to love them regardless of their choices
that they make.
Just because my choices are to love
them and it doesn't hinge around if,
if they do what I want them to do or not.
Like they're my family.
And so I want to see them be,
be self sustainable and
all that other stuff.
So it's not about,
it's not about like are they
going to converts or anything
like that at all.
It's about,
I'm going to love you guys and see
you guys go from being slaves to being
liberated,
to being free to being
put on your own land,
to being able to farm,
uh,
to being able to produce
your own corn and beans.
Crops which are getting ready
for their second harvest,
first time in history.
They're gonna have their own school.
You're gonna be educated.
Once they're educated,
they can represent
themselves at the capitol.
They can be citizens of
the country after that.
I mean,
it's just,
it goes on and on and on
and it's like anybody,
I don't think anybody who's reasonable
who listens to you would think that
you're just trying to convert people
because you're a religious zealot.
It doesn't sound like that at all.
It sounds like you're doing everything
absolutely perfect with the best
intentions possible.
And thank you.
It's beautiful story,
man.
It really is.
And it's one of the reasons why I wanted
to have you in here and talk to you
about it and it's become more
beautiful the more I hear about it,
man.
It's,
it's really cool.
And uh,
please come back again
when you're back in town,
when you're back a year from now.
Yeah.
Again,
you got my number.
Get in touch with me and let's do
this again and tell me more things.
What's the end game?
Are you going to stay there forever?
Man,
I honestly don't know.
We're talking about that
with my future wife because,
uh,
she,
I don't think we could live there forever.
There's no,
there's no,
but I do want to go back often in this
one years is my way of committing to
them.
And this is what's crazy man.
Like I'm trying to find a way to turn
this huge publicity or they're going
viral.
It was on Jimmy Kimmel and TMC and the
today show and now there's going to be a
book and I'm trying to find a way to
go from 800,000 views to $50,000 or,
or even maybe even 200 to 250
which I know that sounds like,
oh,
he started Kickstarter.
Yeah,
we're on Indiegogo right now.
And what does now that goes,
it's a,
it was before Kickstarter.
It's a crowdfunding site.
So it's indiegogo.com/projects/fight
hyphen for,
it's for the fight for the forgotten,
but hyphens in between it.
So indiegogo.com/projects/fight
for the forgotten,
but there's hyphens in between
fight hyphen for difficult
as fuck for someone to
give you some money.
I know,
but where you can go to fight for the
forgotten.com and then you hit donate and
then it would take you the Indiegogo page,
fight for the forgotten.com go there,
please go there.
And uh,
and and donate some cash.
That sounds,
that sounds amazing,
man.
If we can help you,
if we can help publicize things,
we can tweak things for you,
just let me know you're going to have
any access to the Internet while you're
out there.
Actually my buddy that
I brought in with me,
the film maker,
he's got a buddy that,
uh,
is developing this military technology
that's been picked up by him,
but uh,
they can fly like drones and stuff like
that from a briefcase and you'd take
this briefcase and uh,
you can take it to remote places of the
world and you set up these four squares
or something like that.
And inside of that you have perfect Wifi,
high speed stuff.
So they're trying,
they're trying to see if they could get
that to me cause I've had zero contact
while I've been there.
So I'd love to be able
to Skype with people,
talk to people from the
jungle of the Congo.
All I needed was some power
that would definitely help.
And when you do do that,
please let us know and we'll
tweet it and we'll get,
we'll get it out there to
as many people as we can.
Yeah,
that's great.
They'll hold the whole main
goal is getting potentially,
oh,
well that's,
that's actually what I would love to do
is if we could get Shalom university and
it's,
it's the shares that the Indiegogo page,
if we could get them a
research center on the land,
uh,
and I'm talking about 1200 acres of land,
if we could get them a research center,
then that would mean they have year round
students on the pygmy land and they'd
be able to develop them in different
self sustainable ways of life,
crops,
waterwheels all this stuff.
College students,
we get credit to uh,
develop the pygmies and
sustainable ways of life.
And uh,
so the,
the big goal would be 200 to 250,000.
I think it's right there.
And it says what it does and it's,
it's some crazy stuff where,
uh,
where,
I mean,
I'll,
I'll read it real quick and uh,
but it's,
yeah,
so for 200 to 250,000,
and this is with the university,
this isn't something that made up,
this is what they've been able to say.
It would,
it would literally have three to 5,000
slaves put on five square kilometers of
perfect rain forests,
five square kilometers of land for under,
for the $200,000 price.
But then after that it would uh,
preserve the culture of the pygmies.
It would get water wells,
it would get nutritious crops growing.
So not just,
uh,
not just corn and beans,
but like,
like good crops.
It would have a tilapia upon that stocked
so the corn would feed the chickens.
It would also feed the Tilapia and it
would feed the pygmies and it just is a
self sustainable way of life.
It could have like a earth
bag home technology where,
have you ever seen those?
The earth back homes or the ECO domes?
Those things are going crazy today.
One of my buddies was over there having
a meeting with them and they might want
to support this project were four
in the u s three to five men.
It would only take them three to five
days to build a three to five room home.
And it's under $300 in the
u s all it is is sandbags,
sandbags.
You fill it with dirt and he make this
like Adobe that you put on the outside of
it.
And so we're trying to get
that technology over there too.
I'm Shalom University is like
all on board wanting to do that.
And so really,
and then it would have that,
uh,
could have that university research
center there where they get,
and that's the thing,
I don't want this,
this project,
I don't want the pygmies
to be dependent on me.
Like if I'm only there a year and I
can only do a year's worth of stuff,
I want this thing to be a well oiled
machine that it lasts long after I'm gone.
Um,
so that way I don't know.
I want this thing to outlive me,
if that makes sense.
I wanted to keep going on.
It does make sense.
It's a very noble idea,
man.
And it,
listen,
you've done an amazing
thing so far and uh,
we're going to try to help you.
So fight for the forgotten.com.
Go there and give some money to the,
what does it Indego,
what does indeed Gogo Dunkin
on indiegogo.com find it folks.
You can find that your smartphone
forgot for the forgotten dicot man,
you could fall Justin.
He is a on Twitter.
It's a Justin the Viking on Twitter,
right?
Yes sir.
All right dude.
Thank you very much [inaudible] guys,
this is one of the coolest things.
Thanks.
One of the coolest things for
us to thank you very much ma'am.
Uh,
all right folks,
we'll be back most likely
tomorrow with a Shane Smith.
We got to work out the uh,
the dates and time,
but tomorrow night we do have a show at
the Ice House comedy club and that is at
10:00 PM with Ian Edwards and Ari Shaffir.
Thanks to hover.com go to
hover.com forward slash
Rogen and you'll will get 10%
off your domain name.
Registrations are very cool company
and they help support this podcast.
Thanks also to audible.com if you
go to audible.com forward slash Joe,
you will get free 30 days service from
audible.com and a free audio book.
And A,
we would recommend a nocturnal
from our buddy Scott Sigler,
who was just in here today.
Really cool guy.
Uh,
so audible.com forward
slash Joe Thursday night,
this Thursday night at the American
comedy company in San Diego,
California,
where they just got their liquor.
So if you want to fuck your life up and
go down the hard path that Justin wren
just recovered from gut out of San Diego
and take shots of Jack Daniels with
Mexican narcotics because
they're right across the border.
And Sandy,
I'm not telling you you should do this,
but if you're gonna do that,
that's the place to be.
San Diego American Comedy Company,
and,
uh,
lots of funny comics and
it's this Thursday night.
All right,
my friends,
uh,
listen,
the,
the message of this podcast could not
have been better served by Justin wren
today.
You are,
you're,
you,
you stand for everything
that is good in this world,
my friend.
And what you're doing I
think is a beautiful thing.
And it's a,
I'm honored to have you on this
podcast to tell the world about this.
I appreciate you so much.
I'm going to have you on again,
my friend.
All right.
[inaudible] we got to
send slaves three free.
We're going to put people on Mars.
You telepathy.
We're gonna find the big foots and uh,
or more,
and then some,
and then we're going to go to God.
All right folks.
We love the Shit Outta Ya
and we'll see you tomorrow.
Thanks Mike.
Appreciate it.
Yeah.