The Joe Rogan experience,
my family and I and my family,
I inherited flat Butts Syndrome.
It's embarrassing.
Have your butt hurt because you have no
padding when you sit and have no pants
fall, have your pants fall because there's
nothing in the back to hold them up.
After week I def notice something
extra in the back. I'll keep using.
That's the people that you want to buy
your butt cream cause they're morons.
That's like people that give money to
preachers that fly in private jets.
Yeah. I think and as crazy
that don't work, but I,
I'm telling you government bottle work,
Joe, I'm telling you, let's look at this.
Who would have known it works faster
on your breasts and on your button,
but it's work. [inaudible] this is
not real. It is real looking at me.
I can't see shit.
I'm telling you God.
But listen, these fucking the people
that are writing these reviews,
not only does it works, that's
it works. Not only does it works,
it increased my breast size.
They probably should change the name
to breasts and button hansman butter.
I know it for the, but I know it for
the but so I figured, let me see,
will it do anything for my breast
since it's in quotes, all natural.
So I did so with,
within a week,
my breasts was fuller.
Last time I seen them this size was
right before it was time to breastfeed.
My baby is now nine years old.
Oh. So I imagine that what
we was doing in the ghetto,
I'm telling you at thick
as butter does work.
It I watch, I made it people who knows
what I'm talking about from the south.
Say Joe, we did that
and it worked out well.
You should have done it on one titty.
Did it just to see no,
John wanted nothing to be here.
I know there's only one way to find out
that actually works. One cheek, one tick.
You bounce it out left cheek,
right Tim?
I'm going to find that but butter
and rub it on my crack baby.
One of her titties and see if they grow
in their head and just don't even tell
them what you're doing. Just
put it on one today. I okay.
I'm gonna have to get her to do it.
I don't think I feel appropriate.
How old is she now? She's
nice. Too late. No, no.
She's well known for you can do it.
You have a five year. I can test it,
but she already got a big ass booty.
Oh yeah. Then what? I'm going,
I'm going to get some of that and see
if it works. My husband would kill me.
I don't know if it's true, but I don't
think it is. It doesn't make sense.
But then again, I'm not a
scientist. I'm telling you.
It's like that peanut butter that they
used to send to the ghetto to choke.
Nick rolls out
and you realize, oh, the bubble
machine. You got a machine for 13,
13.
Yeah.
Whenever we're talking about,
let's keep it rolling.
The um, yeah, the uh, so you don't
get caught up and popping them though.
I know. That's a problem of getting
too high. You're like, I'm talking,
what do we do? Let's just pop bubbles.
The bubbles fly marquee races.
It's like for them to really like take
in the basic wisdom they got from the
mythological creature.
They needed a mythological creature.
The mythological creature said
something to them along the lines of,
you need to love yourself more.
You need to give more to your community,
whatever the message is.
But if your Uber driver said that to you,
it wouldn't get through because it
wasn't like phosphorescent it didn't have
multiple heads.
So similarly with these religions,
what happens is you do get
some real transcendent wisdom
that's sort of timeless
mixed in with it. And then the people,
because they realize like, oh my God,
it was kind of a fairy tale. They also
reject the good stuff inside of it.
And that to me is the big tragedy of
any kind of fundamentalist literalist
interpretation that's being forced
on people is because within that is
inevitably something great or it wouldn't
be so viral like Christianity wouldn't
be here right now if there wasn't a
core thread in it that had a beautiful
message in it. It makes me, yeah,
well,
nicer people.
I actually have a really big conversation
this weekend with a very good friend
about it,
about another very good friend who's
very religious and we were saying like,
I think for some people it's an amazing
framework and a guide to live your life.
I really do believe that.
I have several friends who are
very devout Christians. Yeah,
it's beautiful. And they,
they're the nicest people I
know. And Mormons, by the way,
I have friends that are
Mormons still to this day.
I have several friends that are Mormons
and there are some of the nicest people
and I don't care if they believe something
that I don't believe in. That's okay.
It's okay. It is okay. But I mean,
the idea that everyone is supposed to
buy into stuff without questioning it is
the reason why we are 51 year old,
16 year old
dude.
I agree.
And then there's the deeper symbolic shit.
It seems to be encoded in Christianity,
whether from people projecting their own
understanding on a pretty wild symbol
sat or maybe it was intentional.
Either way. There is like a quilt,
like you know the uh,
if we talked about this,
like if you take a cube and unfolded,
it makes a cruise effects and like the
cube represents pre big bang conditions
and the crucifix represents past,
present,
and future intersecting with Aternity.
So if you have a a square. Oh,
I get it. So the the length,
the height is twice the
width. Yes. Oh, okay.
Maybe it unfolds into a crucifix for
people that are annoyed with that sound.
It sounds like a pencil sharpening over
and over and over again. We're sorry.
Sorry about that
y'all. But bubbles don't come free.
You need machine. Got To have,
we got to hire somebody. Hire
some dude. Just blow bubbles.
What did you do?
I blow bubbles on the jre Bro.
I'm like fucking manly wrestler Dude,
man.
Definitely do that.
Have different people come in and blow
bubbles and then occasionally they chime
in. Hey, I'm going to be on the
Jerry next week. What are you doing?
I'm blowing bubbles. Oh, cool. You're
the bubble blower for the week.
It wasn't real animal at one point
in time. I don't think it exists now.
I think it existed. It's just a primate
in the fucking woods. Yeah. Oh, okay.
You don't think it exists?
You believe that exists now?
I did up to a certain point,
but I was like in this era with all
of the cameras and everything else,
somebody would've caught one. Okay.
Right. Good. Yeah, I was a little worried.
I was like, yeah, I don't believe in it
now. I believe it existed at some point,
but I don't believe it exists.
Let me tell you something.
Charlemagne has this amazing
power to manifest shit. Okay,
so I see how it could lend itself.
When you believe something so much,
it becomes real. Right, right.
I could see how it manifests
itself into things like big foot,
like you believe in things.
I mean Sasquatches wasn't,
it's not a far fetched idea. It's
literally just a primate in the woods.
I'm just saying. When you were young and
you believed that you were a teen wolf.
Yeah. That was like he, no, no, no.
Third Grade.
He believed that his ears actually
changed shape. No, they did.
I was sitting at the
lunch table telling everybody I was
going to turn into this Werewolf at
lunchtime and I was saying this for like
a week straight and we was all sitting
at the table and I was just sitting
there like this going to happen.
It's happening.
And my ears actually come around
to points into like two seconds.
All the kids at the table
saw it and jumped up and ran.
So they fucked up my concentration.
So if I had kept that concentration going,
I probably would've turned full
fledge werewolf in that moment.
Maybe levitated possibly. I've done
that before. Really? Oh yeah. I used to,
I grew up Jehovah witness,
so I used to leave the kingdom hall and
I would walk outside of the kingdom hall
and I would like jump in the air and be
looking down at the kingdom hall and not
to stay up there for awhile and then I
would come down. But here's the thing,
he's not, he's not doing bits
right. He really believes this shit.
I'm just telling you
what happened in my life.
I don't know if you believe what you
believe it, if you don't, you don't.
Memories of strange thing.
Um,
it's a very ominous feeling because it's,
there are no f, first of
all, everything is one color.
It's like a dark pewter color and
there are no right angles anywhere.
It's as if somebody took a,
I've said this before,
somebody took a model out of in fashion
did out of wax and then he did it just
for a short time. So everything melted.
Everything looks like it's fused together.
Everything has a radius of
curvature or to, uh, items.
It's a, it's a really weird
looking thing. But, um,
uh,
there was almost nothing other than
a small foldable hatchway that,
um, that looked recognizable.
Everything was, uh,
was really unworldly to pick on it.
A way to describe it.
So you,
you get inside this thing and it's
designed for something that's much smaller
than a human being.
Yeah.
You can't really stand up till you get
to the very center of. And how tall you?
I'm five. 10. And what do you
think this was designed for?
I'd say something close to half my eye.
Wow.
So these little three foot
tall ish creatures. Yeah.
And that the seats were small too. I
mean obviously it was made, you know,
for something something small,
but there is no, like there's,
there's nothing else in there.
There's just seats,
the reactor and some of the
sub components. There's no,
there's no control panels.
There's no bathroom. There's
no, no decorative, uh,
components or artwork or anything that
you would recognize or trim. I mean,
it's just a very bare bones thing.
You're not seeing any screens.
Well,
there are archways around.
It adds that are part of
the superstructure and that
one of the archways can
become a transparent,
when I was in there,
there was another group working on one
of the archways and you could call that a
screen more or less.
So through that archway it would be,
it would maintain the
solidity, the, the solid,
whatever metal it was. Yeah. But you could
say it just became transparent. Yeah.
I saw that happen once
or twice before I left.
Did you ask any questions
about what the no,
there's no asking because
no asking questions,
but when you watch something
become transparent and you
realize it's still there,
but you can now see through it. Yeah, I
may not now that's not that impressive.
We do have some liquid crystal
materials that are like that.
You know they had seen in smart
glass. Yeah, they call it smart glass.
So this is just a, and I don't know
if the craft is made of, you know,
an advanced metal or a ceramic.
It was cold to the touch. So, um,
you know, I would lean more
towards a metal. You're not
allowed to ask questions?
No,
the only,
they work on the buddy system so I can
only exchange ideas and talk to Barry.
Now this really interferes with science
because science is based on free
discussion and ideally you get a bunch
of guys together, exchange ideas,
work on problems and that's
how things move forward.
But they're still over the
top concerned about security.
They split everything off and
everybody becomes stagnant.
It, it, it, it,
it just destroys any of the progress
you can make or at least makes it go so
slow. Um, they, I think they wound
up shooting themselves in the foot,
which is probably why they arrived at
this bottleneck that they needed to get
this madman with a jet powered Honda
come in and see what he could do.
I think that was an act of desperation.
I think they wanted someone that
thinks out of the box and let's,
let's just give this guy a try
here because they weren't in,
and they might have done this four
more times since, uh, you know,
up until the point in time today, assuming
they're still working on this thing.