And Creole.
They would say Dubai
ladies and gentle man.
Darren.
I was wanting to do that
to do it man,
man.
And he brought,
look your friend Nathan [inaudible].
Both of you guys escape the winter of
Wisconsin,
which I'm representing right now.
Hunting and my teaching and Yannis
Portelos.
This is their company and my tank sent
me a code for people.
If you want to use this,
if you go to hunt to eat.com and I think
it's the code word is just Joe Rogan all
in one word.
I'm going to find it one second.
And if you do that I think you get 10%
off.
Hold on one second.
I'll find that real quick dude.
Do A,
yeah.
Joe Rogan all caps,
10% off hunting and it's what is,
some of them are licensed plates.
This one's the Wisconsin one.
It's just a,
a circle shows the state,
a little deer in it.
Friends,
their company and um,
great guys,
man.
The best people,
they worked for Steve Rinella,
meat eater and uh,
we know the well.
Doug [inaudible] of course is my friend
from Wisconsin and he brought his friend
Nathan and yeah,
and we're gonna talk about some stuff
and we'll just,
good to see.
Anyway,
but,
uh,
we're going to talk about this one thing
that came out today that I tweeted that,
uh,
they found that there's a huge
difference,
not just a little difference because
people have always wondered like,
does it matter if you buy grass fed
food?
Does it matter if you bought,
I mean,
what if it does it really matter?
Well,
it apparently it does.
There's a new study that found clear
differences between organic and non
organic meat and milk.
And this is the largest study of its
kind.
An international team of experts led by
new castle university in the UK is shown
that both organic milk and organic meat
contains around 50% more beneficial
omega three fatty acids than
conventionally pro,
uh,
produce products.
Which is pretty fascinating because a
lot of people have speculated that it's
all bs,
that you go and you buy grass fed this
or grass fed,
that it doesn't mean anything,
but it means a lot.
Well,
you know what's interesting to me about
it is so much of it for me is intuitive.
Uh,
I grew up with cattle and it makes sense
that a,
a ruminant,
a cow,
uh,
it eats grass,
you know,
that's what it eats.
And you start putting all this other
stuff into it.
For instance,
corn,
soybeans and that sort of thing.
That's not what they were made to eat.
Um,
and so then you take that a step further
and have it be,
I think they're referring in this
organic that they're talking about
grasping.
Yes.
And so they're,
they're eating what they're supposed to
eat,
not what we somehow along the way
decided,
well,
this is what they're going to eat,
corn or soybeans because I'll put on
that fat that we all liked so much
speeds up the process.
Yeah,
it does.
It speeds up the maturing process of the
animal.
Uh,
but not who the good way.
Yeah.
So,
so many bad things.
Yeah.
It makes so much sense to me that,
uh,
from it just from a common sense level
that this is going to be the best thing
for the animal.
And then down in the way,
it's going to be the best thing for us.
We're not forcing stuff on that animal
that,
um,
uh,
they wouldn't,
you know,
normally normally be eating and they are
going to eat it by choice.
But I will tell you if I,
uh,
the cows,
they're not the ones that I had when you
were out there.
But if I go out with the cattle that I
have now that I bought a about a year
ago,
I bang two buckets together and they
come running because they know the
food's coming well because they used to
be fed corn.
Oh,
so these are animals that you purchased?
Yeah,
but we're already at maturity.
Uh,
yeah,
they were bred cows.
So I was looking to get,
uh,
those,
those cattle that I had when you were
there that we had when you were there.
I sold,
we had a drought year and he prices went
through the roof and I had a,
uh,
had a barn and shed full of Hay,
which was pretty valuable and the cattle
were still pretty valuable,
so I,
salt was able to sell those.
And then take the winter off and spent
some time in Mexico and what not.
Cause if they might be a few cattle,
but uh,
and then,
uh,
decided to get back into the game.
So now I've got her to Herford so that I
bought last year.
I heard of what Herford what's a
herferd.
Her ferg is a,
it's a breed that I think originated in
Britain,
um,
and wait face red animal.
So a lot of the ones that we had when
you were there the last time,
we're actually a herferd cross.
Um,
so they were Herford originally or their
original brood cows were her fridge.
And if we bred them to like a black
anchor,
sir readying cause crossbred um,
to get some hybrid vigor out of him and
that sort of thing.
Or wait,
what is the difference?
What's the difference of between
different styles of cows are different
breeds of cows.
Wow.
Um,
everything from the,
how they put on weight to how they look
to,
um,
uh,
in the nation.
See Holly,
I'll put weight on,
um,
uh,
if they're dairy cattle,
um,
some of the like guernseys and jerseys.
And that sort of thing.
Uh,
they won't produce as much milk,
but it'll have a real high butter fat
content that's fascinating with the same
food.
So at the same feeding them the same
thing.
Different cows produce different butter
fats.
Yeah.
Uh,
so holsteins which is the,
the,
the sort of the traditional dairy cow,
big black and white thing.
You know,
you've seen him on everything.
Uh,
they're a big animal,
big boned,
you know,
a really tall,
big animal.
Um,
and they sort of have the ability to
kind of eat.
They're not as picky eater.
They produce a lot of milk,
but it will have a lower butterfat.
I can't believe I'm talking about dairy.
I mean,
I've been out of the dairy business
since 1988,
but,
uh,
what's fascinating stuff you'll have no,
I had no
idea.
The different cows will produce a
different level of dairy fat.
Oh,
no,
that's exactly right.
And then butterfat is what a farmers is
paid on.
So a hundred pounds,
which is,
who is about eight pounds to the gallon.
Um,
and,
and in milk,
you're paid by the pound.
I'm 100 pounds of 3.5%.
Butterfat for instance,
is not worth as much as a 100 pounds of
4.5% butter fat.
So there's this whole calibration system
they used to do that.
So,
you know,
milk's being tested all the time,
both,
uh,
organic grass fed,
manage,
pasture raised and you know,
more modern if you will.
Um,
the uh,
confined animal
facilities where they're,
you know,
milk,
I don't know,
a thousand cows in a real small area,
are very confining them to a very small
area where,
uh,
nate and I both grew up,
and use our farm,
a lot of pasture fields,
that sort of thing.
So the catalog kind of walking around
doing their thing out on pasture,
they come in at,
in the evening,
you,
you'd feed them,
uh,
sort of a supplement of it might be
great or it might be,
hey,
you know,
it might be these various things.
And it kind of depended.
That all evolved over time.
Um,
and in my lifetime,
and you were always sort of aiming to
get the most out of each one of those
animals.
And depending on how you looked at the
science,
um,
you know,
people spent their whole life studying
how to get the most out of a cow.
Um,
depending on how you looked at that
science,
um,
you made decisions about that.
Well,
when I was a kid it was a lot more of,
and I mean a kid like in the 60s and the
early sixties,
there were a lot more common sense
involved.
Um,
and now it's much more like in those big
milking operations,
that sort of thing.
It's more science.
It's like,
Hey,
here's how we can get the most out of
them.
So you remember this shift between what
was like normal farming,
normal dairy farming,
normal meat,
cow farming to this thing that we're
seeing now that most people have a real
big problem with this factory farming
installations where you have these cows
jammed into these warehouses and
chickens and the same thing with pigs
and the thing,
those are the things that people have a
real issue with when they see them on
television and they see youtube videos.
You,
do you remember this shift?
Oh God.
Yeah.
Um,
so I was 57 years old.
I was born in 1959 by the time I was old
enough to drive tractor,
which was when you're about four years
old where I'm from,
you're driving to check their full out.
You're sitting there steering it anyway,
and you know,
going through the field and they're
popping in Wisconsin.
I was sick.
I was six when I,
when I jumped out.
You remember this?
Oh yeah.
And so when I was a kid,
um,
do you remember where we shot when we
had that shooting range set up by my
house,
that little kind of a,
it was an old foundation there that was
a chicken coop.
We had chickens there.
There was a greenery in between the
little building that we finally call the
keepout shed now because it's the
security,
there's just says keep out on the door.
Um,
that was,
uh,
a facility where we raised pigs and that
we had a rolling herd of about 40 milk
cows and they were holsteins.
And so it was a diverse farm was a
diversity ecosystem,
if you will.
And I dunno,
uh,
during the Nixon administration,
Earl Butz who was the secretary of
agriculture then came out and said,
get big or get out.
And that was really the beginning of the
end of the small
family farm.
What do you mean?
Like he said,
he said this like,
was it a statement on them?
It was the halogen or what?
How did this go down?
Uh,
okay.
Well I'm sure it can be found somewhere,
but,
uh,
get bigger get,
and that's just the,
uh,
it was like part of it.
Yeah,
it was a r a press conference or
something to that effect
that was going to be the move and
agriculture,
you know,
and it was a long process.
I mean,
I remember,
um,
our exit,
if you will,
from the,
the dairy sector.
Um,
ours came in the late nineties,
so there was a big shift,
you know,
if just for example,
my grandfather was running the farm in
1977 and then the milk price was like 14
or $15 per hundred weight when my dad
was forced to sell in,
I think it was 98 or 99,
it was like nine bucks,
you know,
so you're trying to raise a family and
continue a legacy and you're getting
paid dirt,
you know?
So what caused that shift?
Big Agriculture,
systematic,
you know,
as a systematic shift to the corporate
and there's some sense,
yeah,
I want to say there's some sense in it,
but that's probably not a completely,
I mean,
you understand that efficient getting,
you know,
it's,
it's the American way.
You get bigger,
you get A,
there's efficiencies in the in scale.
Hold on.
I'm trying to understand like what was
the motivation?
Was it that populations were booming
because there's a lot more people today?
Yeah.
I mean,
I think we looked at it up the other
day.
I think in the night in 1970 there was
something like 150 million people in
this country.
Now there's 300 million.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's not that long ago.
I mean that's in my lifetime and that's
crazy.
That's crazy that the population has
doubled and the demand for food
obviously doubled as well.
You know,
something that's really interesting if
you look at that area where you came out
and visited,
exact opposite has happened in
population there.
There's half as many people.
Well,
in our areas they were as there were
farm area and it's a farm area.
Um,
so the small farm,
the family farm is what's really
suffering because they,
it's so hard to make ends meet with
these gigantic operations that are just,
yeah.
Is that,
well they can,
you know,
I mean it makes sense,
on a,
on a business you
can afford to sell a product cheaper if
you're doing it bigger,
but the things you lose there are the
quality and the,
the sustainability and environmental
impact of the process.
You know,
you've got these big farms.
We're basically,
they have,
they got make more product.
But they also make more shit,
you know,
and that's a water issue.
Um,
well that was a big part of that
documentary cowspiracy where they were
trying to talk about the methane that's
produced by cows,
the methane and just the,
just getting rid of the actual cow shit
itself,
like you're talking about massive,
massive quantities.
Well,
and when I was,
when I was younger,
and even now the manure that's producing
on our farm,
like now in the winter where I'm feeding
hay and they're confined would be kind
of a strong word.
They stay around where the Hay is,
you know,
and we've got fresh water,
therefore him and it's spring water and
I can talk about that later,
but they stay in that area.
Um,
and so that's where also where they're,
you know,
Shit.
And,
and uh,
and so I ended up piling that stuff up
and I pile it up and I composted and I
put it on everything from a community
garden nearby to our fields to,
um,
people want to come by and say,
hey man,
can I go and I look,
get a load of shit.
And I'm and sure as heck I,
you know,
I give it to him.
Whereas for them,
for a big facility,
it's where do we get rid of this shit?
Right,
right.
Yeah.
What I'm one of the reasons why I wanted
to talk to you about this is because I
think that,
um,
most of us that live,
when I say us,
like people that live in cities have
almost no idea of how all this stuff
works and when,
when people examine it or where they
tried to watch a documentary on it or
try to figure out like,
uh,
how,
how cows are raised.
W one of the things we get confused
about is stop playing with that same
answer we get confused about is how did
it happen?
Like how did these things become these
gigantic sort of operations where it
seems so,
so inhumane?
Well,
it's,
it,
you know,
it is,
it's a business model.
This business model,
like corporations,
banks like everything,
it's the same.
It's the same idea,
interestingly to me in our area and,
and,
and neat.
And some of the folks that he knows her
example.
I know and I am to a lesser extent,
um,
because it's just a little bit different
on our farm.
It's not something where I'm trying to
make a living at it,
you know,
um,
that it's starting to go the other,
it very much has gone the other way.
Things like community supported
agriculture and those sort of things are
happening that people want to know their
farmer,
right?
So there's like a,
uh,
a blowback.
So people are realizing that there's
something kind of crazy about these
factory farming setups.
And so now they're trying to get their
meat more form organic farms.
But how much more expensive is it say
like one of your farms?
I sell bulk.
Any,
I consider bulk anything over 50 pounds
for six 50
upon.
So like a family could come to you and
by directly Oh yeah,
absolutely.
And do you,
do you sell most of your stuff directly
or do you sell it to like a wholesaler
or how does that work?
What I try to do is,
and my whole goal with my meat
production,
I mean we do a lot of other things we'll
maybe get into later,
but um,
the meat production,
I try to take care of a certain amount
of families,
you know,
and when they need meet I have it.
I'm not really,
I don't market it.
I mean it's all,
I have customers and they come to me
when they want meat.
So it's like a word of mouth type thing.
And some people buy a quarter you don't,
which is like a hundred to 150 pounds
sometimes.
And some people will come up by 20
pounds when they need it.
You know,
I have a buddy who is a fireman who does
that.
He has like a,
a deal with a local rancher and he buys
like the,
him and a couple of the families that
he's friends with,
they'll go in on like a side of beef.
They'll go in on like a whole half of
the cow.
And you know,
they,
they save money that way and then they
know they're getting like real organic
grass fed cows.
Like would that nice yellow fat.
Yeah.
I have to tell you this story.
Um,
some years ago when we were raising
beef,
uh,
one of the things that I did for my,
my ex wife and I did for my brother and
sister in law was gave them a,
a quarter of a beef for Christmas.
And I thought it was being real clever.
You know,
the steers at that time kind of all had
the same name,
the Heifer calves,
the female calves.
I give them different names for
different numbers and everything cause
we keep them around.
But the steers all had the same name and
that was dinner
and a steer for people don't know cow
that has its balls removed,
the male male trial.
So unique and yeah.
Uh,
and there's a lot of,
there's a lot of good reasons for doing
that.
Um,
and just so nobody says,
so you're knocking this thing down and
cutting,
it's nuts.
Off,
well,
yeah,
this is what we're doing.
But when we knock it down,
we actually sedated.
It goes to sleep,
it wakes up and it's singing soprano.
I mean,
that's how that,
how that works.
Jerk a little bit though when you went
well,
yeah.
Were to imagine,
I don't care what you're sedated or not,
but,
um,
but uh,
and so yeah,
that is what is serious.
So I'm sorry,
the story was that,
uh,
so we gave a Sarah anarchies this
quarter of beef and um,
we're making a presentation of it and
they had,
uh,
the,
the neighbors over.
Uh,
and so everybody's sitting around the
table and there's a couple of girls,
young women maybe tend to,
and 14,
something like that.
I don't remember their exact ages,
but I had this polaroid picture of,
of that steer and said,
you know,
and I had it in quotations dinner and
made a presentation of,
well,
we gave you this meat and here's this
wonderful steak that we're having and
everything.
And here's the before and here's the
after.
Apparently I turned one of those girls
into a vegetarian.
All right.
And I felt
horrible about it.
Well,
you're,
you've been there from the beginning,
from the time you were really young.
You've been there from the,
I mean,
it's a part of your life,
right?
You,
you've always been around cows.
You always been around cattle.
It seems totally normal to you.
But to somebody that just is used to go
to the supermarket and buying a steak
that comes neatly wrapped in Saran wrap
on a nice little foam tray,
Eh,
you're kind of freaking them out with
reality.
And I learned something that day about
it.
But some of the folks that buy meat for
me,
they come out and they take a look at
the place and you know,
I mean,
you've been there,
you've been there not maybe the nicest
time of the year because it was cold
and,
and all of that.
And the cattle were not in a pasture.
We had them confined in the barn yard.
Um,
and they're not walking around.
They're laying on the hillside there,
chewing their cud.
Man.
It's just,
they're just happy as they can be in.
And they're looking at me and they're
looking at the Catalan,
so I'm going to have some of that meat.
And it's just like,
there's that connection,
you know,
know,
if I don't get anything else across here
getting this conversation,
and I encourage people to know what
their farmer,
no,
the guy who's raised in that,
uh,
whatever it is,
because that's the bowls or meat or
whatever for him.
Well,
it's very difficult for someone who is
not used to the idea of an animal being
alive and then being dead and then cut
up and then portioned into steaks and
then cooking it.
People that are,
that are used to going to the
supermarket and buying it already done.
For them to be sort of a forced to look
at that whole process as an adult is,
it's a little disconcerting for a lot of
people because we're,
we're faced with is very convenient
world where we're completely detached
from any of this stuff now as a guy
who's been around it your whole life,
that's gotta be kind of frustrating when
you see the hypocrisy of people who eat
the meat,
but really kind of don't want to know
where it came from.
Yeah.
Hypocrisy is the only sin,
you know,
in my world.
It's kind of the way I feel about it.
Um,
but I don't know the other sets
necessarily.
That's the hypocrisy.
Hypocrisy as much as it's just ignorance
and,
um,
and I,
you know,
I also want to say I don't take it
lightly at all.
We load up a cow or a steer or whatever.
I put him on there,
man.
It's just like when we shoot wildlife,
you know,
we kill wildlife.
Something like that is we did a thing,
or you're doing a,
this is a big thing.
There's a reverence.
Reverence.
There is a river,
that's exactly the right word there a
reverence to it that you have in these
smaller situations.
I mean,
I could see where if I had 500 steers
and I'm raising the 1,250 pounds,
they might not have the same reverence
to those animals.
But they're giving me something and I,
you know,
I'm taking it from him,
but that's my deal.
You know?
Well,
that's similar.
There's similar argument when you're
talking about large populations of
people that there's sort of this,
it's a fusion of responsibility that
comes with interacting with 20 million
people versus 20 people.
When you're around 20 people,
you have a town of 20 people,
you know,
and the relationships are kind of
important,
whereas 20 million people you'd give the
finger to somebody on the road was the
idea.
You're,
you're never gonna see them again.
Yeah,
no.
Right,
right.
But if you're in Cazenovia and you see
that dickhead down the street from me
and it leaves the nasty voicemail
messages,
you'll never forget the fucking guys
crazy.
You played that for us because that was
seared into our head.
But you know that you are forced into a
relationship with that person and you
have to manage that relationship when
you have,
you know,
how many cows you have now.
Uh,
well I have 20 head run it.
Yeah.
So if you have 20 cows,
like what?
When you have to,
and even,
you know,
when you do the deed,
you're not,
you're,
you're really not saying I have to kill
this Catholic,
but you're saying when we load went up,
when we do the deed,
you know,
there's all these euphemisms for what
you're doing.
You're going to kill this cow.
It's like it's a,
maybe that's because of the fact that
there's so many of them or there,
but the rather,
there's so few of them that you have
this,
you know,
this is like a,
it's a big moment.
It is a big moment.
You know,
I sold a,
a cow this fall that I'm through no
fault of her own.
They had a prolapsed cervix.
And if you want to know what that is,
essentially her cervix pushed out.
And no matter how many times you push it
back in and sew things up,
she's going to continue to push.
So she's not going to be productive.
Um,
and her productivity is to have calves.
and I felt terrible about it.
Didn't mean I didn't do it.
I mean,
I know,
I knew.
Do it mean killer?
Well,
I didn't kill her,
but yeah,
I mean,
that's what the adults do it well.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And,
and,
um,
and I'm not,
uh,
I'm not
passing that responsibility off to
somebody else from the standpoint of,
well,
I don't want to do it.
So I have somebody else do it.
I'll do it when it needs to be done.
But when were neat and I both are
selling,
you're selling meat to people.
There's regulations that go along with
it.
I mean,
I can't just like drop a cow in the,
in the barn,
you know,
in the,
in the driveway of the barn,
hang her up,
cut her up and start selling.
Joe Rogan meet.
Um,
there's USDA inspection and all that.
So we both send our animals to very
small,
uh,
family run.
Uh,
slaughterhouses butcher shops and they,
so you don't necessarily kill them
yourself?
No,
no,
no.
Never.
Oh,
you know,
if something,
if you were doing one for yourself.
Yup,
Yup.
Um,
and have,
so if you want to sell it then you have
to go through these and it has to be
yup.
And it has the stamp.
Yup.
Um,
yeah.
And,
and there's a,
you know,
a standard to that.
Now,
I would confidently never sell you any
of my beef if I butchered it myself,
but I would confidently give it to you
and say this,
it says,
I mean,
you've seen how we do it out there.
Basically it just government regulations
you have to fall.
Yeah.
But
I mean there's a standardization.
I'm all,
I'm done with that.
There's,
there's a pretty cool movement going on.
The place I go to is called driftless
meets and [inaudible] and it's a,
it's a really,
like when they bring in a cow,
like one of the big problems with these
slaughterhouses,
Joe,
is,
you know,
a lot of them,
you bring your cow in the night before
and there's,
who knows how many cows jammed into a
pen and they're stressed out.
They're running around bumping each
other.
These guys up there,
I think the Max they take in on a
slaughter day is four.
And so these cows got their own pen
there.
You know,
it's very stress free.
It's very relaxed,
you know,
so the process and then that's what's so
important about all of this and the
sustainability and environmental impact.
It's all about the process.
You know,
it's fortunately there's a really strong
movement in that sector of the,
the processing is going on,
you know,
conscious carnivores is a place near us,
a facility near us.
And I just,
I think that's a very important way of
putting it.
Um,
you know,
the guys from a cowspiracy,
there was a lot I read wept with those
guys too.
Yeah,
that's
unfortunate.
About the exaggerations of some,
some of their claims.
Because I think that if they just stuck
with what's absolute and reality,
it's very disturbing that this
sustainability doesn't look good,
you know?
But what's,
what's interesting is here's some things
that you disagree with strongly.
It's one of the reasons why we got into
this conversation.
One thing,
the amount of acreage that it takes to
grow a cow.
I just raise a cow.
I did,
uh,
I,
I've been in looking at my own,
uh,
cattle one,
but and also spending some time with our
udw extension.
It's the egg people at the end through a
university,
you know,
Land Grant University 1.4,
1.4 to 14,
depending on how,
that's a big difference.
And that's a huge difference.
Well,
1.4 to 58.
Yeah,
no one agrees with that places.
It probably is though going to have to
be like desert,
but wasn't that guy.
And why we raised was from Wisconsin was
from South Dakota.
Didn't you tell me?
Yeah,
there was that.
He made a reference on this and you
know,
I'm not gonna,
I don't want to pick all their numbers
apart or,
and if not ranchers.
So I think what happens is someone told
him that that sounds great.
They went with it.
Yeah,
yeah.
You know,
and this is like,
look,
they made a great documentary,
but when you make a documentary,
you also have a great responsibility.
Like they have an agenda.
It's very clear,
their agenda is the promote veganism.
It's because they feel very strongly
about it.
Whether you agree with it or why you
don't agree with it,
that's their point of view.
That's what they're trying to get
through in this documentary is that if
you grow,
just grow vegetables and you live off
vegetables,
you don't need as many acres,
you could feed more people and it's a
healthier way to do it.
That's just their,
their perspective and their point of
view.
So they sort of,
they,
they lean towards that in a very strong
way while highlighting some irrefutable
facts that are very disturbing.
And that's,
that's the shame of it is because you
know,
they're environmentalist too.
You know,
that's,
that's obvious,
but you know,
it kind of put off the vibe that,
you know,
people like Doug and I aren't,
and that's the problem is as you look at
the big,
the big corporations that are,
you know,
feeding off of all this misinformation
really.
And the,
what do you mean by the big corporations
that are going well?
You talk about the,
you know,
the big farms you can talk about in any
industry,
you know,
um,
it's kind of a disjointed effort.
You know,
you've got these guys talking about
this,
this.
We're all concerned about the
environment,
you know,
but some of this stuff came off as an
attack on,
you know,
beef production,
cattle,
livestock production.
But we all agree on certain things.
I think if you really want to focus and
you want to make a change in the world,
find a way to work together.
Yeah,
but they're there.
Change is,
don't eat animals.
Oh,
I know.
Don't kill.
So we've got to compromise,
but they don't want to come.
They're not in the proper less problem.
There's there,
there's very strong connections between
veganism and religion and if you look at
a lot of their ideologies,
they're very similar and a lot of ways
to religious zealots,
like they have these ideas,
they want to promote them.
That and only that,
and this is,
this is the way they want to go about
it.
And you know some,
some of them say crazy shit.
Like I've had these conversations with
people on twitter who this guy was
saying that human beings are not meant
to eat meat.
We're,
we're herbivores.
I'm like,
well that's just not fucking true.
Showing her teeth dog.
Well not only,
but forget about the canine teeth.
That's absolutely true.
But how about the fact that scientists
have done very clear studies on ancient
humans and the reason why we became
human in the first place is the
consumption of meat.
It literally changed the amount of brain
tissue we have.
And then hunting changed how crafty
people had to be.
It changed the innovation of,
of these lower primates,
these lower hominids.
They had to innovate,
they had to figure out tools.
He had to figure out weapons,
not just to defend themselves from
humans,
but in order to hunt animals.
This is a,
this is an irrefutable facts,
essential part of evolution.
It is.
It's so there.
I think if I could speak for them,
if I would play the devil's advocate,
their point of view is now we have
evolved to a point where we don't need
to do this anymore.
We don't need meat anymore.
We're very intelligent.
We are also aware,
we're also faced with this overwhelming
amount of evidence,
this over whelming amount of information
that we have now because of the
Internet,
because of her access to it,
but we've never had before.
So you can look at some of the
statistics and some of the things they
brought up and you could say,
well,
this is their argument for promoting a
Vegan lifestyle.
I see.
I can go with that.
It's what,
what the problem is that a lot of these
guys,
they,
they say things like,
human beings can't process meet.
Or we had this guy that robb wolf was
arguing on twitter who said,
uh,
animal fat is toxic.
Well,
what the fuck are you talking about?
How To inuits live?
Yeah.
How would the how they've been around
forever.
They just eat nothing but fat.
These fucking people and if you look at
their diet,
you look at what their,
their,
their diseases.
The only fucking inuits that are getting
cancer.
The ones that are smoking cigarettes.
That's true.
Nasty fucking western habit that we
passed up to these poor people.
That's how they're getting cancer.
And you're getting cancer in in higher
numbers than they ever have before
because they weren't getting it before
at all.
Right.
Cause people were eating blubber and fat
and seals and whatever fish they could
get and I can't grow a goddamn single
vegetable and they weren't getting
cancer.
The cancer thing,
that's a,
that's a great issue because recently,
I don't know if you've caught the whole
red meat and cancer thing and they,
they came out and they said,
you know definitely your smoked meats
and you're cured meats.
Like our meats aren't cured.
You know what you mean by cured?
Let's say you're talking about,
we talking about like sodium nitrite.
Yeah.
When you make bacon,
like if you took a package of my bacon
and looked at the label,
I think there's three or four
ingredients in mind.
You look at,
uh,
what it like,
what are those ingredients?
Water,
pork,
you know,
uh,
and uh,
it's like celery,
salt,
you know,
which is how it should be.
Yeah.
So problem is your bacon.
If you sat on a shelf,
Nascar,
Oscar Meyer Bacon,
if you put them both on the same shelf
and sat for a week,
Oscar Meyer will look the same.
Years would start to fall apart.
Mine would need to be frozen.
Yeah.
You know,
that's the only thing fucking normal,
right?
Like why do we think it's just going to
sit around
and not fall apart at 39 degrees or
whatever your refrigerator is.
It's not going to,
that's not how it goes.
Then the,
so the cancer thing and that,
and I get done,
you know,
I mean,
that stuff was probably is linked to
cancer,
but they've pulled back on the red meat
in general.
They're not sure about it.
But the thing is,
and I think the study is skewed because
you talk about cancer and Ph.
Okay.
You know,
grass fed beef has a neutral Ph,
corn fed,
grain fed beef,
that Ph goes up and,
and we know that cancer thrives in an
acidic environment environment.
You know,
and you know,
there's other things that the cows that
have a high acid guts basically is what
it is.
They're more prone to acidosis,
which,
which needs more medication.
You need antibiotics.
Um,
and it's also a prime harbor for e coli.
The,
uh,
I'll,
I'll find a stat for you,
but the Ecole I,
it's,
I think it was 6 million,
300,000,
um,
milligrams per,
I'll look that up.
I'll,
I'll try back here and you guys talk.
I,
that's an important,
yeah,
yeah.
Go ahead and look that up.
But that's a very important point I
think you're making about,
um,
about how these animals that are
unhealthy,
it's kind of unhealthy to eat an
unhealthy animal.
That seems logical.
That is one of the points that I found
really interesting about about the,
the documentary was how these guys spoke
about,
um,
cattle aren't intended to eat and I
couldn't agree with Martin and corn.
It's corn and soybeans can agree with
the more.
That's why mine eat grass right now.
They're eating here's taste very
different.
By the way,
you know,
you gave me a couple of rib eyes last
time I took it home.
They were damn delicious and lean and a
nice dark red meat.
And that's how account supposed to be
when you get these cows that when you
get beef from a store,
you're getting this really light red
meat.
It's very light,
almost like a pinkish meat.
And you compare that to like,
like someone,
one of the elk steaks,
I haven't back those elk steaks or like
a red like got dark,
almost like a purple,
you know,
it's just fucking overflowing with
testosterone and,
and you know,
and an outcome or whatever the hell they
got in about us.
I mean,
that's a healthy animal.
That's exactly right.
And that animal is choosing to eat.
Uh,
an elk is choosing,
well,
it's obviously a product of his
environment,
so it's eating what's available.
Just like a white tail deer is,
I remember when,
uh,
when you and Brian were out and,
I think Brian held up one of the back
straps and he goes,
oh my God,
this is like Shashimi grade.
Oh my God.
And we cook that on your kitchen.
We just butter salt and garlic and we,
we,
we grilled up some of those and we were
all eating them going good Lord.
And it was from an animal that you shot
what,
three hours ago?
Yeah.
I mean,
he's incredible.
Yeah.
To talk about fresh.
Oh my God.
I do have that counter.
It is.
Um,
remember he's my numbers
brought Nathan here to know the flight
information.
What's the hotel room?
What Time's the podcast?
You know,
this is fun dog,
but come on,
I've got a family bag.
Oh yeah.
Ah,
so this is,
now we're talking cells per gram of
meat.
Okay.
So in your grain fed the count of
eco-line,
the grain fed in the count of e coli,
6 million,
300,000 cells per gram and the grass fed
20,000 holy Shit.
Holy Shit.
And it's all about the environment that
you're creating by what you're putting
into this thing.
It's unnatural.
That is unnatural.
That is crazy.
Crazy numbers.
Oh Wow.
And so
these guys and I,
you know what?
I'd love to have them come to the farm
and talk to me
and just,
I don't think they want to be around
your house of murder.
Decker jog during house of murder.
Oh,
well tell him,
take him out around thanksgiving.
Right around that one day.
And they could hear the fucking war
zone.
We grow veggies too where Doug lives
opening day.
You like in the morning when we were out
in there,
we were out in the the
blind and is soon as the sun starts
peeking up over the horizon,
you hear boom,
boom.
Here it off in the distance.
I'm like,
dude,
are we at war?
Why is there a picture of me that's
gross?
I got to sleep.
I don't know,
man.
I kinda like it.
Thank you very much.
Um,
I'm sharing a room with this guy.
Yeah.
The,
um,
that's,
that was a weird experience.
It was the first time I'd ever been a
place where like when I had
gone hunting before it,
before that time,
it had only been in the wild in Missouri
in the breaks where there's no people
when we were in your area in Cazenovia,
it's like everybody is so geared up for
it.
When we stopped at that sporting good
store and got tags and got,
got some equipment,
like everybody was rip rare,
raw and ready to go.
Like tomorrow is like the opening day of
a race.
It's weird.
A deer per second opening day in
Wisconsin is shot cheese here.
Curse sex.
Well that's a testament to how many
there are.
Well,
yeah.
We,
we read a statistic in about Minnesota
about how many car accidents or in
Minnesota was a Michigan,
Michigan,
Michigan has 100,000 car accidents a
year.
It's from people hitting deer.
Just stop for a second,
ladies and gentlemen.
And you tell me you don't think they
need to kill some fucking deer.
There's 100,000 a year.
I'm pretty sure that's the number I
should probably like be careful if I
keep repeating it over and over a lot.
So there's always a lot
a year.
It was the number 50,000 I was so close.
80% of these crashes occur on two lane
roads between dusk and dawn,
50,000 what is the amount of uh,
animals that kill people?
Okay,
here the states,
2 million deer,
2 million deer in one fucking state.
How many people are in Michigan?
Maybe a million,
but not a whole lot more.
And I think in Wisconsin,
cattle out and other folks are dropping
by the day with them.
1.9 million.
Holy Shit.
That's insane.
So there are 20% dear.
So what that means is,
here's the reality.
You literally could feed that entire
state of the deer population.
That's real because one deer,
you fucking eat a deer from months and
one deer is going to make more than one
deer.
I think that is
a really interesting point and it kind
of goes along with it.
Some of my agreement with these guys,
uh,
we're not,
we're subsidizing the dollar meal or
whatever,
you know,
the dollar hamburger and,
and uh,
and that kind of like quick meet you
drive through,
you get the Burger and off you go.
Um,
I'm not,
but I would advocate for is that I'm
okay with eating less meat.
Uh,
they had Michael Paul and he talked
about eating less meat based on the
numbers that they were using,
which I think was like,
it was,
I think it was 0.6 something I think is
what they said on the movie.
It's like a half a half a pound of meat
a day.
Well,
it was more than I was 0.6 something.
I don't know.
That's what,
that's what the average American eats
ever done.
Way more net balance that shit out.
You bring the average up.
Well,
you got to think about the guys.
You know,
we've
all seen these guys,
you know,
Charlie chicken fingers and slobber
mcgee,
you know,
eating fast food.
Everything is,
you've seen these guys eat right?
You're going to eat your finger dude.
One slow down
food,
man.
That's what we're,
that's what we're dealing with because
the real sickness isn't the,
that we're raising meat.
It's the demand,
you know,
so farmers are rising to meet that
demand and people aren't demanding good
meat.
They're demanding Shitty,
cheap meat that they can buy for 99
cents.
You know,
one of the things that these folks were
addressing in that documentary that w w
w w I think didn't get to the heart of
it all,
but the heart of it all really is the
amount of human beings.
The only reason why,
like if there was only,
if,
if Cazenovia was the world,
you wouldn't need a fucking factory
farm.
Sure it wasn't.
You wouldn't need it.
Cazenovia is essentially a sustainable
environment.
All you need is some solar power,
some windmills for electricity.
You got your own spring,
you got your water,
you can get from a,
well,
you got your cattle to graze that you
have more than enough food for you.
You could grow your own vegetables,
you can don't have in the winter,
you know,
or we don't.
You know what you want to last through
the winter and you're good,
but we have too many God damn people,
right?
Isn't that often comes down to people.
Keep fucking then that's fine.
I'm a fan of it.
Well I have three kids
so I should shut the fuck up because
I'm,
I'm obviously making more people than I
am.
Oh boys are,
they're all boys.
All girls.
Man.
My best friend Gatlin,
he's got five boys.
If five,
it's one thing to have five kids,
but to have them all be boys.
That's like you're talking to,
they're just going to shoot just all the
land and make more boys.
But the cool thing is in Doug and I were
talking about this and he mentioned
earlier,
like we're sitting here talking about
this really interesting stuff because we
don't want to come off on this podcast
is a bunch of,
you know,
knuckle dragging,
multiple bruiser [inaudible] not,
you're definitely not,
but we're,
we're talking about this,
be careful.
We're talking about all this stuff in
the middle of la where he got guy
dressed like spiderman and all these,
these women wearing,
you know,
well,
by the way,
that's why we're way out here in the
suburbs.
You know,
I don't want to be around that,
but sounded good.
Thank you for putting us down there and
go.
Yeah,
no,
no.
Yeah,
no,
that's perfect.
Well,
it's a good place to,
you know,
just to come here people watch.
But one thing we've been,
we've been talking about a lot of,
lot of awesome people and really digging
deeper into this,
but there's guys like doug can expand on
this more because he's read more of the
book.
But this guy,
Mark Sheppard and other guys,
I mean,
people contend that that we can raise
enough food sustainably.
But part of that equation is,
you know,
and that's what maybe we could unify
with these guys like guys from
conspiracy is,
you know,
let's not talk about ending meet.
That's an unachievable goal.
That's never going to happen.
Let's talk about educating people.
Say,
hey,
let's not eat quite so much so we can
sustain.
Just to play devil's advocate,
because a lot of these guys are there.
They love of animals,
they love animals or animal lovers.
They,
they,
it's almost like that.
But they did,
they do it in a way where they don't
want animals to die.
They want those animals to dive all the
age only.
Um,
the,
the problem,
I think there's,
this is an ideology attached to veganism
where once they stop eating meat,
they want everybody else to stop to,
well,
you're talking about 95% of the world
that he to meet.
It's 95%.
Something crazy like that.
Please always check my numbers
off by 100% the day off to those guys.
Yeah.
But you know that why if,
if these guys,
this is to play devil's advocate,
if these guys can stop eating meat and
become vegans,
why can't the world,
and I think that's what a lot of people
were saying.
Well other things I would agree with
with them.
I have a garden.
Yes.
Grow some food on your balcony in the
city.
We have a couple of mutual friends who
are growing stuff on their balcony.
That's different.
Yeah.
Well I don't know.
One thing I noticed
was dudes hydroponic system on the roof.
Tile was empty robotic system or
homeless
picked up on.
It's kind of fucked up,
you know,
and we're not here to throw punches.
Right.
It could have started it and they set it
up by some plants and put them in there
for him.
It's one of my favorite stories is this
former FBI agents who were retired and
they were arrested because they were
growing hydroponic plants and vegetables
in their basement.
And you know,
the dea passes by houses and they scan
these people bought hydroponic
equipment.
When you buy hydroponic equipment,
they flag you and they follow you.
It's so fucking insane that growing
vegetables has become a crime because so
many people grow pot.
They assume that if you're growing a
plant with some sort of a plant system,
that you must be going an illegal drug.
So with no evidence whatsoever to
fucking former FBI agents,
they break down their door,
guns a blazing,
and they arrest these people and then
find out their fucking grown tomatoes.
Yeah,
that's kind of a hot button deal going
on in Reedsburg right now were my home
town.
My Buddy Gatlin,
I already mentioned him,
but he's got a he on a whim.
I mean this dude is a,
he's in a successful appraiser,
real estate appraiser,
but he's always looking for that home
run,
you know,
so he's making a living,
but he's taken his cuts and so now his
latest venture,
he took his whole tax return and just
turned,
is this,
this building that he couldn't lease
into a hydroponic wonderland and we'd
know,
well,
when it comes legal,
he's going to be ready to rock and roll
and he wants to do a cbd oil extraction.
I mean,
you know,
he's,
the government's going to have to that
now.
Right.
So,
but you get these people walking by and
we got these purple lights and people
are,
what are they growing in there?
You know,
and everybody's,
and everybody thinks we're growing weed.
And it's like if we were growing weed,
the cops are at the door kicked down two
weeks ago.
Just put a sign,
we're not
grown weed.
Right.
Fox,
get a sign off,
sign it.
And it's called that.
It's called girl lucky.
You can google it does,
I think it's grow lucky.
greens.com it's all pretty new.
But I would definitely assume that kind
of under the Wheaton Rocky Greens.
Yeah.
How lucky can I get
for an ounce of,
you're lucky shit.
Let's talk about this downstairs.
Come to this special room,
the of,
uh,
of growing in a garden and people taking
responsibility for their food.
Um,
you know,
it's such a big deal in those,
uh,
the fellows that you had in here.
Um,
that's,
you know where I'm,
I'm joined at the hip with them.
Yeah.
I think we're all,
we're all in agreement with that.
And there's a guy named Ron Finley that
I had on before who was awesome and he's
a proponent of urban gardening.
And what he does is he takes medians,
like you know that you just see grass
and the bullshit in an la genius.
He grows plants in them,
he grows vegetables and foods and he
does it in a abandoned lots.
He'll,
he'll set up gardens and abandoned lots
and he does it all throughout south
central.
And he has people that live in these
communities growing their own food.
And he had this amazing point that I
never considered before.
He's like,
you drive down this street and you see
bushes,
you see trees,
you see all these plants and you can't
eat none of it.
He goes,
we're wasting water on shit.
We can't even eat.
He goes,
you could have food growing in the same
places.
You have all of these trees.
Why don't we do that?
And I was sitting there going,
why don't we do that?
I can talk about laws two longs.
Fuck yeah,
right.
An orange tree looks great.
Well,
that's exactly right.
That's exactly right.
Aesthetically pleasing on top of it all
this said you to get him some of these
pictures.
This Guy Mark Sheppard,
who's from our area and he doesn't know
me from the man in the moon,
but this is his book,
rest restoration,
agriculture.
A real world per permaculture for
uh,
aerial photographs of his farm art and
it looks exactly,
it looks like a landscape architect was
involved.
Um,
layering of plants starting with the
tallest trees down to annual.
So eventually,
um,
at the same time he's pastoring through
there,
um,
three and four different kinds of
animals.
Um,
they're cleaning up the,
the uh,
they're cleaning up the nuts that,
uh,
they didn't,
they didn't hard,
which is good enough.
Clean.
You're nuts.
That's bar none.
Molson pub.
Unless you're in a weird shit.
Some people like dirty things.
Three get minerals.
All right.
I'm not buddy.
What was this is done.
So check that out.
That's amazing.
Cool.
That's gorgeous.
And so this is a,
it says new forest farm Mark Sheppard
permit culture.
What does it say the words abbreviated
there?
Permacultural a pup pup.
Hipaa apprenticeship program.
I think he does his classes and stuff.
Oh,
that's cool.
And the amount of food he can pull off
that Joe.
And that's,
and,
and they graze that then.
So,
and he talks about what you mean.
Cows graze that V and pigs and chickens.
Um,
and Ras in,
he says
any,
and maybe doug can find this,
but I've got it.
The amount of food he can grow on there.
And he talks about just how many
vegetables he's like,
but if you're only growing vegetables,
you're gonna have to mold this stuff.
So it makes sense to it's,
and that's the whole thing.
You've got to complete the loop.
You've got to complete the cycle.
You got to close that loop and,
and find that he ecological harmony.
That's the,
that's the whole thing.
Two photos that go jamie,
don't go through those real quick right
there.
Bam.
Make that bigger.
Whoa.
What's,
he's got a little ponds in there too.
Yeah.
And so the cattle graze in the grass
area and then in between the grass,
he's got trees that grow food.
Wow,
that's beautiful too.
And then he brings the pigs chickens
through and this is near you.
Yeah,
viola or broke the real quick and go to
it.
Now it's a big fucking ice skating rink.
Frozen Tundra.
Yeah,
let's go.
Let's go and change his point
being that when we grow one crop on a
farm,
field,
corn,
soybeans,
organic or otherwise,
or uh,
vegetables,
that sort of thing,
that in our area in the winter,
then that's a desert.
I mean,
once the corner wants the beans come
off,
that's what it is.
I mean,
you saw it,
the deer come out into the field and
need a little bit of this stuff and you
know,
and all that.
And guys,
we'll pasture out on that.
But it really does become a,
you know,
sort of that one trick pony,
which to a certain degree vegetable
gardening we'll be as well,
although you can rotate crops through.
Um,
but like on my place,
we're growing livestock,
we're enriching the soil.
We're,
um,
we're,
our pastor is getting better all the
time because we're not over pasturing in
any particular place.
Um,
there's carbon sequestering going on.
What's that mean?
The carbon sequestering,
the carbon in the soil.
So like I'm with composting and things
on those lines.
Yeah,
there's,
there's people can see on two out of the
APP contend that that cattle and proper
management in the pasture rotation that
they can start to turn back the,
the climate change,
you know,
by sequestering the carbon starting to
pull it,
pull it out.
And we're,
when we till and you know,
the constant tillage is that's,
that's one of the,
you know,
that's a no,
no,
you know,
a lot of no tilling,
lot of rotational grazing.
That's,
that's up and up.
I mean,
that's where we need to be
multiple benefits from one action.
So I'm pastoring and you saw some of the
pastures,
some of the places where you hunted,
it was pasturing or there's wildlife in
there and we've got good clean water.
When we,
uh,
went to a point on our farm where we
weren't over pasturing and it was just
something that we,
you know,
we sort of learned the stream's real
wide.
Um,
when we were over pasturing,
they were,
they were really wide.
Uh,
the water was shallow and it was warm.
No trout.
As time has gone by and we weren't over
pasturing anymore of those streams
narrow up because it's running water
that's going to cut that and those,
it starts to fill in.
The grass starts to grow.
Now you stepped across a creek that used
to have to walk [inaudible].
Um,
so there's strout in there now.
the catalog going in there,
they're eating a certain amount of the
grass.
Um,
we keep them,
we keep moving them through a certain
amount of the grass or keeping some of
the invasive species down.
A deer are still living in,
their songbirds are still living there
at game.
Birds are still living in there.
All of those things are happening and
the uh,
plants themselves are pulling the CEO
to,
you know,
the whole photosynthetic process.
Pulling that out and putting it back
into the ground where it belongs
to counteract some of that.
So Gee,
I think I'm getting like three or four
different positive results from having a
pasture know hickory orchard with some
bigger trees and that sort of thing.
This dude with permaculture starts to
add multiple other things,
layers of,
so if you think about an acre of land,
like this table,
and if you're growing one crop on it,
one vegetable crop,
you've got an acre of land,
43,000,
560 square feet of that particular
vegetable or that was groups of
vegetables.
But with the idea of permaculture,
you have your upper layers,
trees,
big trees,
big oak trees and uh,
uh,
you know,
you might make of Hickory for hickory
nuts and that sort of thing.
So short things and uh,
well to begin with,
with the upper level,
so on that same chunk of ground,
you've got this large tree,
it's producing wood,
which is,
looks like a good oak table here that
we're leaning on.
You know,
it's the same sort of thing.
The next layer is the smaller trees like
app,
you know,
fruit trees and that sort of thing,
below that,
below that or are shrubs that are going
to be,
uh,
you know,
service Berry,
um,
chokeberry Rania,
some of the,
uh,
antioxidant producing fruits.
Um,
and then you go down to the next layer,
which is going to be things like
asparagus and rhubarb and keep coming
down.
So now instead of just that one plane
of,
of plants growing,
you've got it on that same acre,
you've just grown multiple acres of food
and that is just something that needs to
be thought about in the bigger thing.
He's then rotating through four
different kinds of animals,
running beef through it.
Um,
and they're not in there all the time
because,
so it takes management after beef,
he's run and it's called a leader
follower grazing system.
Um,
after beef,
he's running pigs through it because
pigs are great cleanup animal.
Um,
after that comes turkeys in Turkeys or
cleaning up the grubs and whatnot in the
shit from the,
from the cows and the pigs.
He run sheep in it.
And last might be chickens.
So the intensity,
the intensity of,
of management is incredible.
And the amount of,
uh,
layers of food that are coming off of
that.
And then layers of acreage will suddenly
we're getting,
you know,
and his scenario,
I'm getting three or four benefits out
of it.
He's still getting all that carbon
sequestering and all that.
Um,
but now he's built that up to 10 or 12
different positive results from the same
thing.
And one of them is from a wildlife
perspective,
which is one of the things that gets
talked about all the time.
You grow up,
you have your garden at home,
I garden at home.
What's the one thing that every garden
that has wildlife around it has a fence.
If you're going to grow vegetables for a
profit or for fun and put your effort
into it,
you can put a half,
you didn't put a fence around it,
you're going to exclude wildlife from
that.
Exactly.
Well,
and that's one of the main contingents
we had when we sat down and were like,
okay,
there's going to be tough.
These guys put forth a really good
narrative and had some really
irrefutable facts.
But then one of the things we talked
about,
the water talked about the acreage,
but the wildlife thing,
one thing that they said was,
and where these livestock or are living
that is,
that is area of void of wildlife.
I mean I look at my pasture from the
soil microbes and worms to the bugs and
butterflies to the,
you know,
field mice and moles and we've got hawks
and we've,
I mean we'd see a badger and a Fox.
I mean that's wildlife,
you know,
it's a,
it had a very
realistic point of view.
They didn't understand the wolves,
they didn't understand the management
roles.
They didn't understand that the reason
why they're starting to open up hunting
seasons on,
well they also didn't know that Idaho is
one of the most wildlife rich places in
the country where people go and hunt elk
and mule deer.
I mean,
Idaho is fucking filled with animals.
And they thought that Idaho is like,
you know,
it's all farms now.
It's devoid of,
they just,
it's an idealized sort of Hippie vegan
approach,
which,
you know,
they're just leaning towards that.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't mean they don't have great
points.
Absolutely.
No,
that's what we're saying.
It was a tough,
it was a tough,
tough thing to do to come out and,
and be a counterpoint for something that
you agree with a lot of
what their main bone.
And I think a lot of people,
I mean it's,
it's the factory farming thing.
Well,
we're talking about here.
I don't think it's sustainable for the
population of Los Angeles.
And we'll,
you're talking about here with this kind
of a farm man,
you would need a giant fucking farm like
that to feed Los Angeles.
Are a lot of them.
A lot of small,
yeah,
a lot of small,
low.
But you would mean so many of them.
I don't know how much they produce in,
if you compared in comparison to one of
these gigantic factory farms.
Well,
and you know,
and I'm not,
I don't know,
my number guy isn't going to have those
numbers.
Well,
no one is,
I mean,
and this is the thing,
you know,
we can keep going deeper and deeper with
this because people can say,
well,
hey,
you know,
it's sustainable and Cazenovia.
Okay,
well,
is this sustainable in Wisconsin?
Yes.
This is the sustainable on the entire
eastern side of the country.
Not really.
Okay,
well what about,
what if we can get the United States of
standable,
we'll still got India.
Well,
we're,
we're fucked.
You know,
I mean,
you've got a billion people living in a
place,
a third the size of the United States.
What do you do then?
Those numbers be wrong.
The big thing here is in the bigger
conversation,
I think is,
is,
and,
and that's something that,
gosh,
people that care should really,
you know,
she'll veganism and,
and you know,
meeting,
eating aside and just,
let's say,
how do we,
how do we make this work?
You know,
I think it's education.
I think people need to,
to understand that you can't just go
around eating,
eating meat.
You know,
my Mama,
you know,
Charlie's chicken fingers.
You can't be doing that.
And you got to have a balanced diet and
you can't be eating pounds of me today
off,
you know,
you,
you probably shouldn't overeat with.
And we all agree if you've read
anything,
but this is um,
this is a different subject I think
we're talking about,
we're talking about sustainability and
we're talking about feeding gigantic
swaths of people.
Yeah.
And that's what these factory farms have
set up.
I mean,
through the method of collecting
nitrogen from the oxygen,
I mean,
what,
what from the air that the hopper method
that they invented in like the early 19
hundreds.
That's how they figured out how to
extract nitrogen.
And because of that,
a gigantic population boom and sued.
That's the reason why there's so many
people in the world today.
This is widely accredited with the
hopper method of collecting nitrogen
because before that it was really
difficult to fertilize soil.
Once they figured out how to extract
nitrogen from the actual Ehr itself,
things got a little easier to grow food
and the population boomed.
And that's part of what we're dealing
with here.
What we're dealing with here is kind of,
um,
in,
you know,
what we talk about wildlife,
we were talking about the 50,000 car
accidents that are in Michigan every
year alone because of the over abundance
of deer.
This is sort of what we're talking about
with human beings.
We have an over abundance of human
beings.
Now,
obviously I'm not suggesting we have
massive hunts on humans,
so turning to herd the herd,
but we would,
if we were some sort of an alien and we
looked at,
okay look,
let's put it this way.
If chimpanzees were overrunning Chicago,
like somehow or another chimpanzees like
figured out how to get Chicago,
uh,
they fucking swinging from tree to tree
and they moved in and started,
it starts setting up shop and overriding
the place apart where people are getting
in car accidents with chimps and uh,
would we kill them?
That would be very tricky.
I don't think we would because chimps
are way fucking smarter than beer and we
liked smart shit.
So we wouldn't kill champs away.
We would kill deer.
So people obviously are smarter than
most people are smarter than chimp.
I know some people that probably aren't
smarter than chimps,
but when it gets too intelligent
animals,
that's when we get weird.
Like nobody gives a fuck if you kill a
bug,
okay?
If mosquitoes contained Zika virus and
malaria and all this different shit,
you can kill mosquitoes all God damn day
long and for whatever reason,
nobody gives a fuck about mosquitoes
because we've all agreed that mosquitoes
are the enemy,
right?
Mosquitoes contain malaria.
Malaria has killed.
This is a number.
I know it was real.
Malaria has killed 50% of all the people
that have died ever.
How that,
wow.
So you've had again,
50% of all the human beings that have
died ever in the history of people have
died from malaria.
How about them?
Map
Real Shit is,
I've been fascinated with malaria for
years.
So I've,
I've read a lot of Shit on malaria and
I've had two friends that got malaria,
including justin wren,
our friend who was in here recently who
fights this weekend.
I'm Bella door.
Good luck to my friend Justin.
He's the best.
This guy is fucking him.
You want to talk about an amazing human
being.
This guy,
uh,
he gave up like years of his life to go
to the Congo and dig wells for these
people.
These pygmies in the Congo,
he's just the salt of the earth,
like the nicest guy ever.
But he got malaria to is doing that and
almost died.
Um,
so nobody gives a fuck if you kill a
mosquito,
which is my point,
you know,
you could swap flies of vegans will swat
a fucking mosquito,
right?
You know,
you look who please no mass day in jail.
My blood.
It's the blood of a carried eater.
No,
you fucking,
he slapped that fucker down.
But there's,
there's a certain level like,
okay,
if a up an aunt is on your food,
a lot of times a Vegan will kill that
ant.
And what do you do with the body?
You throw it to the ground,
you'd ignore it cause it's little,
but don't you don't,
you just fucking killed an aunt in my
house.
And if you went like that and brushed it
off,
I wouldn't say a word.
I'd be like,
Doug's doing some acceptable behavior.
He killed an aunt that's on his pants.
He dropped it on the ground.
But if a mouse ran across my kitchen,
you stomped it and then ignored it.
I be like,
Hey,
what is this fucking job hair you've
left?
Right.
There's a weird hierarchy of living
things and the lion is clearly,
I mean,
one of the lines is fellow mammals.
Yup.
Um,
and you know,
I don't even know what to say about
about that,
but uh,
but not rats.
Fuck rats,
rats of the black plague and all kinds
of,
nobody gives a shit.
If you fucking kill a rat and your
garage,
if you,
if you're so hardcore,
you're not into killing rats.
I've got a great rad story.
And your hairdresser,
I was living in the hills and uh,
I rented this house and I had a real rat
problem to the point where I'd hear him
banging around inside the rafters.
There are big man like the hills around
Los Angeles.
Los Angeles is a very strange place
because you have this city and then you
have just outside the city,
pretty abundant wildlife,
including coyotes,
a lot of hawks.
And a lot of crazy shit,
but this a place that I lived had a rat
problem.
So I set out a rat trap and,
uh,
I killed this fucking big ass rat,
like as big as my laptop.
It was huge,
man.
It was no bullshit.
Like body big fucker.
We gotta be real careful when you said
it.
Definitely break one.
Right?
Um,
I set it out and I,
and I heard it in my kitchen.
I'll,
you know,
I'm like,
Oh shit.
I got one.
And I went out there and I looked and
it's this big fucking like fat boy rat.
I was like,
oh Geez,
look at the size of that thing.
So I said,
okay,
in the morning I'll get up and don't
kill,
put that thing in the garbage and
whenever and deal with it.
I went to sleep.
I got up in the morning,
that fucker was gone.
They ate him down to almost nothing.
All that was left is the tail.
So rats apparently don't even like rat
tail,
but they had most of his body.
The rats had cannibalized most of his
body.
That's why we say fuck rats.
Yeah.
And if you see one red,
you got a dozen.
Oh,
it'll eat.
My house was overrun with them.
It was really bad.
Yeah,
it was real bad,
man.
He's like one of the first places I
lived when I lived out here and I was
like,
what the fuck is going on?
Cause I,
I had before that I lived in New York
and in new Rochelle and um,
my area,
although New York City has a huge rat
problem,
New York City's rat problem is crazy.
I parked my car once,
it's back in the days of phones,
payphones.
I didn't have a cell phone.
I parked my car at this gas station.
I was getting some gas and I walked over
to the pay phone and as I'm on the phone
I saw three rats jump up in my wheel
wells climb up over my tires.
Three big fat rats.
Like this place was overrun with rats.
They were looking to move or something.
They say you see one ret,
I don't know,
maybe check the numbers,
but if you see one,
I don't know if it's a hundred or a
hundred or a thousand or something like
that.
Let's get you see one.
There's 50 million
pizza rat.
Have you seen this New York City pizza
rat?
He's a rat.
Take it home for you.
This word.
Yeah,
this is,
this is cool.
But here's something that a lot of
people don't know.
Rats are hunters.
Um,
why don't you Jamie pullup rack kills
pigeon because there's not just one
video of these.
There's many videos of rats in New York
City attacking and killing pigeons.
Iphone videos.
It's this fucking bizarre.
I had no idea.
I had no idea they were pregnant.
Did you?
Well,
wow.
Look at this fucking rat is jack in this
pigeon and the pigeon gets away and like
almost almost gets free.
What's going on here?
It's like their little lane prey.
So this rat has this pigeon by the neck.
So this is a different one that I saw.
The one I saw,
the pigeon gets away.
It's like near stairs and Oh yeah,
here it is.
The pigeon tries to get away and the rat
chases it down.
Look at this cause he's already winged
him.
Yeah,
but look at this.
The rat chases a living pigeon.
Well look at the camera guy doesn't want
it.
He's like not getting through clothes.
Okay.
Walking around with his iphone.
I know what I'm going to do to this.
Oh,
why wouldn't you go?
photos are going to do,
but I had no idea.
Did you know that rats were predators?
No.
I,
you know,
uh,
Tunis.
Maybe even
an animal.
Yeah,
no.
Always a problem with,
you know,
when you had green around,
look how strong he is.
He just jumped that fucking curb with
that thing and its mouth.
Like it was nothing.
There was one point he stood up on his
hind legs.
Fucking monsters.
Yeah.
We're so lucky.
Their little image of a rat was the size
of a deer.
Oh,
okay.
Oh liquid.
There it goes.
It,
you still tries to get away and he's on
it.
He's got it back.
That's great.
Techniques in was that good technique.
That's a very good look at the back
legs.
He was controlling very good technique.
Oh God.
Jujitsu,
Jujitsu.
I got to mention something like that
because the only way my grandpa knows
who I'm talking to is the fight guy.
That's how I explained to my grandpa.
Your grandpa likes watching,
loves it.
Loves the UFC.
Like I said,
he's the only guy in the nursing home.
They'll watch.
Wow.
[inaudible] 93 going on 94 freaking out
all the other people.
Yeah.
So it looks like that's it.
Rats are creeps seat.
Now if you kept caught that rat in a
trap,
nobody would get mad at.
Yeah.
But if you,
uh,
you shoot a bear,
the fucking protest.
I have a different story for you.
Uh,
uh,
had a house up in,
in door county and old farmhouse and no
one lived in it for a long time and we
had rats in that house.
But the other thing that we had in that
house were snakes.
And,
uh,
my,
my daughter's,
my daughter's mother didn't like snakes
at all.
She opened up the back door,
the place one time.
And it was,
I don't know,
I guess it was a fox in it cause it's a
big ass snake and it's like,
like knocking on the door,
trying to get you,
there was a spot where they could get
in.
When we started to remodel the place
taken with,
you know,
we put some beams up and we were taking
some interior walls down snake skins.
Oh,
I would,
she's just pro if she's listening to
this,
she's hearing that for the first time,
man.
She was like,
oh wow.
Like three feet long,
you know,
where they molted or whatever the word
is.
Oh man,
those aren't predators.
Right.
I mean those are your presence on the
license and they're probably there for
the rats.
It's probably good.
Yeah.
Have him.
Well that's the thing about life.
Like in my,
in my neighborhood,
I see hawks all the time and they're the
ones that keep the population of rodents
down.
Yeah.
See Him all the time,
man.
They're fucking beautiful.
As do in our area is the thing that I
struggle with a little bit is coyotes.
Wko people do guy coyote hunting around
me.
And,
um,
he,
we were talking about wolves before and,
uh,
I mean,
I'm not physically,
you know,
I'm not worried about coyotes like
taking us down or anything like that.
And I have this at fact talked to
[inaudible] tell us about it and he,
his response to me talking about
allowing Chi Coyote hunting on our place
once he goes,
Oh man,
I just think they're trying to make a
living too.
And you know,
they eat a lot of rodents.
They clean up a lot of,
uh,
the weekend,
the,
and the old deer and that sort of thing.
But,
um,
my buddy,
uh,
Greg,
who you may or a great cue for who you
meet,
her man,
a big dude,
Steve Talks about him all the time.
Recently had a deer run into his yard by
a pack of coyotes when he took it down
and it in his yard.
Whoa.
It was a deer.
It had been wounded during the gun while
we assumed the gun season,
they'd had a big scar in the back of it
and knock,
I suppose it could have been up.
You don't want Arrow that had cut it or
something like that.
So it was weak or whatever.
And uh,
yeah,
in the middle of the night,
this went down in the middle of the
night.
You went outside cause I couldn't
believe it.
Never seen anything.
How many coyotes?
Well,
based on he didn't see how many,
but it was,
you know,
they,
they work in groups of two or three or
four or five.
Um,
so they were right.
They had me right.
You know,
I have a chicken coop in my yard and uh,
I went out in the middle of the night to
shut the coop because I let the chickens
out and they wander around and I closed
the coop.
And uh,
when I closed the coop,
I was just outside enjoying the piece,
looking up at the stars.
And I heard these deer running,
like running full clip.
And then something was chasing after
them,
full clip,
but it was dark and my eyes hadn't
adjusted.
So I was trying to figure out what the
fuck was happening.
But these deer were running and this is
something was chasing them.
And I saw,
I don't think so.
I'm pretty sure it was a coyote,
but it could have been an outline.
But I saw,
uh,
I saw what looked like the silhouette of
a coyote on the top of this hill.
And I was like,
this is so wild.
Like,
here's a house here and this fucking
asshole over here is watching the
Bachelorette.
And like,
you know,
this guy pulls in,
it was driveways and Mercedes.
He's smoking his e-cigarette and some
fucking two thing claw shit is going on
right there.
These coyotes are chasing down these
deer because there's a,
there's a series of oak trees down the
street from my house where these deer
tend to bed.
I see them there all the time and it's
like,
probably like five or six of them.
And,
but uh,
you know,
you'll see coyotes especially come
spring,
you know,
like when the phones are being born,
you see these fuckers hanging around
just looking for an easy meal.
You know guys who raise cattle around
me,
we'll talk about,
and I don't know Nathan if you know
anything about this,
but I,
to my knowledge,
I've never had a calf taken by a cop by
coyotes or anything like that.
I have had a calf that was born and
died.
It was stillborn or something that
wasn't there the next day.
So Coyote's took it.
But yeah,
call abandon it too.
The one thing that you do not want to
mess with,
it was a 1,450 pound Herford cow.
We just had a calf.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I would imagine is not going to let you,
you're that guy get kicked by a cow.
Oh,
I've only had pigs and chickens tagging
and that's the only one.
The dogs like we forget and leave the
dogs in for the night.
A pig lit or an actual whole piglet.
Piglet.
A full grown pig would probably,
especially if there's more than one,
I'm sure they take care of themselves.
They're vicious.
I got her to one of my pig's ears.
I mean if I were to fall down and my pig
pen,
you'd be fucked.
And if I couldn't get up there,
my wife would come home and there'd be
nothing left to me.
Three,
four pigs would have to be done.
Yeah,
that's real.
That's real.
That's the number one.
Here's more statistic.
That's it's your number.
The number 1% of people that have died
is another one.
Number one animal that kills people on
farms.
Really?
Pigs.
Yeah.
People fall like sometimes like an old
farmer will have a heart attack and fall
into the pigsty and they just gobble
them up.
I for the first time I actually saw it
in my pigs,
eat a chicken,
please google it.
I want,
I couldn't save the chicken and time.
And so I was like,
what am I going to do?
I don't want to save a half mangled
chicken,
you know,
so I let him finish it,
but they systematically cornered the
thing and I'm running over and try it.
And then it was over.
It was too many coyote take a chicken
from my yarn or watching a hop the
fence,
but it's in its mouth.
It was crazy.
And I was going to kill the fucker.
But then I realized it was a female and
then it had,
it had cubs like a lot of the typing and
hollering that you hear like,
like people think there's a lot of
misconceptions about coyotes and one of
them is that when you ever hear that
that there's like some sort of a,
a party,
a lot of it is a mother,
uh,
communicating with her young.
Yeah.
And uh,
I was pretty sure that this was hat what
happened because my dog had let this
female near the chickens,
like the dog had like it was sort of
like aided and abetted this coyote
killing this,
um,
this chicken.
And then I realized like,
Oh,
this is a female that has babies.
And so that's where your soft spot.
I'm a pussy.
When you hear that sound though,
I mean when my wife first moved to our
farm,
I mean it sounds like there are a pack
of children being murdered and it was
still night,
like all where we are and it just
resonates.
That's good.
That's weird.
I have a relatively new friend out in
Washington who has actually been
emailing me and asking me for advice
about a coyotes trapping coyotes.
You knew when you think about trapping
cocktail Rinella,
he rep recommend sub sonic 22 is when I
trapping wildlife colleges.
I know in Wisconsin,
uh,
when people would start to talk to them,
talk to them about,
you know,
I'm trying to get rid of the sea animal
or whatever happened to make a woodchuck
or something like that,
he would always recommend a small piece
of land at a very high velocity.
Yeah,
well that's what a buddy of mine does.
He sets out cat food,
he puts cat food.
He leaves these coyotes that we're
targeting is dogs.
So we would set out plates of cat food
and sit on his balcony and just wait and
call him into yeah,
you can call with Predator calls,
but that you might call them some other
shit too.
Man,
we were talking about this yesterday
that they,
um,
they just did this study of all these
different mountain mines that they've
killed.
Here's some more numbers.
I think they killed like a hundred
mountain lions in the San Francisco
area,
in northern California area.
And,
uh,
out of these mountain lions that they
killed,
most of them had cats and dogs in their
body.
That's a finding out that this is what
these things are eating.
Only 5% of them had deer in their body.
Well,
it's easier,
but it's bizarre.
I mean they're,
they're,
they're targeting people's pets.
I mean,
that's,
that's their food cause fucking weird
man.
Madison,
Wisconsin where I live on the edges of
town.
Uh,
that's it.
And we actually live near to parks.
We have coyotes and,
okay.
Yeah.
There was a certain group of folks who
are like,
well,
you know,
they're just out there trying to make
live in two until,
you know what?
I'm kittens mittens and Fifi he got up
and then we've got this situation we
have to deal with.
Yeah.
It makes a story for the kids at that
bizarre thing to see your cat in the
jaws of a coyote as it's running away.
You know,
there's a,
uh,
the La Museum of national history has
this really cool exhibit on North
American animals and their exhibit,
I pulled,
I had a picture of it on my instagram,
Jamie of the coyote there,
exhibit of the Coyote in Los Angeles is
a coyote with a fucking cat and its
mouth that's in the Museum of natural
history in Los Angeles.
The actual,
you know,
they have stuffed animals,
they have buffalo,
they show Moose and they have these,
you know,
so you can get a see,
oh,
that's what that one of those looks
like.
Yeah.
Well they have these displays,
the stuffed animals.
So the coyote has a fucking cat and its
mouth and it's on someone's porch.
We're going to at home.
Look at this.
That's a national history.
That's the museum.
Fucking dead cat.
And my kids will like this.
Yeah.
Like I'm Daddy.
Well honey,
the only fucking animal,
it's killing something.
And the entire museum,
this is the animal that's killing me.
I thought that was the notes from the,
the,
the uh,
museum.
And then I realized that that was it.
You had written that.
Yeah.
See if they're really,
they're saying,
fucker,
no,
but look what these people are saying.
Look at this guy.
My cat was just killed by one of these
fuckers.
You know,
I'll shoot a coyote for no reason other
than it's a coyote fuck a coyote.
Yeah.
And they were right,
man.
Those are a little,
little creepers,
little creepers.
Look at this.
Uh,
what does it say?
Swine likely kill fewer people than
cattle do,
but there's no reliable data.
Hmm.
20 people a year killed by cattle.
It said,
whoa.
Um,
find out how many people killed by pigs.
Couldn't find any but one story
recently.
Mm hmm.
One guy in Oregon.
I would guess that that number is a
little bit higher.
I mean,
personally,
I know,
uh,
okay.
Two people have been killed by bowls or
bowls is especially solitary bulls.
Um,
you know,
the old expression is you fuck with the
bull,
you get the horn.
I would imagine that was,
I was milking for a farmer one time and
uh,
you know,
one of the things with dairy farming and
I grew up dairy farming,
but,
uh,
if a cow has a stepdown teat that's,
you know,
we usually say tit,
but you know,
we're on the,
I guess it doesn't matter.
No,
but they have stepped on time to clean
it up or they get mastitis,
which is a sort of infection.
Um,
it's,
it's very sore obviously.
Um,
so you gotta you gotta,
you know,
strap up the milker and not put it on
that one.
And I was in a hurry.
I was late for my other job,
so I'm trying to hurry and I forgot
about this one column.
This guy's cows didn't go in the right
stall,
so my head wasn't where it needed to be.
Anyway,
I put the,
I put the milker on the bad tit and she
kicked me so hard.
She kicked me in the face and then I
flew back into the metal post.
I mean,
I was out for good 20 minutes,
you know,
when you wake up in a daze.
I mean,
so that's one example of how somebody
could
easily be killed by a car or you were so
big,
you know what I mean?
I'll do is fall and once dumps you and
that's it.
Well,
again,
it goes back to the calving thing.
Um,
our neighbor,
the guy who I used to,
while he still does some farming for,
uh,
for us to cuts and rakes and bales or
hay,
it was almost killed by a,
um,
uh,
a car would just fresh and just had a
calf.
And he went in there to deal with the
calf and she got him into a corner and
beat the snot out of him.
Eventually he was able to crawl out and
get under a gate.
And,
and this isn't normally a very nice
animal,
you know?
Um,
uh,
so it's funny to tell that story when
I've been sending you all this shit
about how nice my cows aren't.
I
so,
well,
we were talking about that because I
said that when we were around your cows,
they fucking panic.
Then they ran off.
But you brought up an important point.
We were shooting squirrels.
They're shooting pigeons.
So what,
we had shot anything yet.
Is there a lot of you though too?
There's a lot of you guys,
a few fewer guys,
four guys.
Brian Count might have been singing
loud.
He was singing and you guys smelled
different.
I mean I definitely don't let strangers
in with mine,
you know,
I wouldn't want that.
Yeah.
What happened that day is what it,
a couple of different things that
happened.
Cause you know,
factually you were correct.
What happened was is you went into their
pasture,
well they weren't out in pasture.
We had them in a,
in a corral barn yard because we'd been
hunting and I didn't want him out on the
pasture where they would be and that
sort of thing.
Um,
there is that video of that and you see
as you guys are walking in,
and I never even thought about this.
Then Joe was like,
I should probably go out there.
The cattle would be a little calmer if
I'm with them.
But you know,
I was afraid that Brian was going to
fall through the floor.
It's shown email,
here's where you can buy it.
And I wanted to throw rocks too.
But,
um,
as you're walking out there,
there,
they all turn and look at you as you're
walking in because that's on that,
that outtake.
And then when you start shooting,
they're all down in the corner.
Being very in a defensive position.
And the analogy I think I use to you is
imagine you're at home having dinner and
four dudes walk into your house with
cameras and guns talking loud,
doing their whole thing and,
and then they start shooting.
Guessing you're going to probably go to
a corner of the house.
Yeah,
no defensive position at once.
The shooting started happening.
Um,
Jamie,
I just pulled this up.
There was more people were killed by
pigs in 2014 than were killed by sharks.
Sharks get a bad rap last year.
Uh,
it says there were 12 fatal pig attacks
worldwide versus 10 shark fatalities.
So.
Huh.
Different stats,
I guess different websites on Pharma
specific by that might've been,
yeah,
I think they're talking about wild pigs
actually,
which I didn't know.
Wow.
Well that many people,
they're fucking creepers though.
Have you ever been around wild pigs?
I actually have not,
man.
I was in home ranch with Rinella and we
were walking down this road and we're
pig hunting and we got close to these
pigs and they didn't know we were there
because it's really thick brush and
grasses.
And we heard them fighting and they were
less than 20 yards away and they're
going to war.
And I'm like,
these are demons,
man.
They fucking demons.
They sound like monsters.
This sound like something from the Lord
of the rings
and they're attacking each other for
whatever reason.
Like right there.
I'm like,
God,
there's fucking creepy things when
they're giant tusks and they're black
hair and that they look like demons,
you know?
And they sound crazy to hear one.
You'd go,
oh,
okay.
You know,
that's how the king and the game of
thrones died.
Remember?
Do you ever watch that show?
How dare you?
How dare you say no?
Um,
he was killed by a boar.
Wild boar.
Spoiler.
Well,
it
doesn't matter.
You don't have to doug,
he dies quick.
He does early in the show.
But,
um,
but he was killed by a wild boar.
And that's,
that's not uncommon.
You know,
they're big animals,
man.
They get real big.
Fair enough.
You know,
you're going out to,
we're not going to feel well that's
there had very different animal.
I mean,
deer have killed people.
It has happened,
not just car accidents,
but they have gord people.
It has happened.
It is possible.
It's very rare,
obviously.
It usually they just want to get the
fuck away from him.
But uh,
you know,
they're wild.
They're animals.
They don't play by our rules.
And I think we have a real problem in
this world with our idea of what an
animal is.
You know,
we anthropomorphize these things.
We think of,
I'm the same way we think about our
pets.
When you have a dog and you think of
your dog the same way you think of a
wild bear.
Like,
boy,
they're playing on some fucking
completely different fields.
They have completely different rule
book,
you know,
and we'd like to think that we're not
animals.
And that kind of connects us,
that that's where the disengagement and
the disconnection with our,
our food supply comes from.
Yeah.
We're so,
you know,
we're above it.
Yeah.
That's our psyche.
When we were also,
we're just not used to being around
them.
Most people are not around wild animals
ever,
ever.
The great majority of people that live
in cities are virtually never run
anything other than pigeons and
squirrels.
They're just not around them.
So our ideas of wild animals,
I like these beautiful things that you
rarely see.
Why would you want to kill one?
Yeah.
An interesting point about squirrels,
urban squirrels versus a woods.
Squirrels.
Uh,
we shot a couple more episodes,
immediate or that'll be coming out here
in the next couple of weeks.
And A,
we took Helen and,
and,
and Brittany,
a squirrel hunting.
And their experience mostly with
squirrels was urban.
And Helen had this,
wow.
They're way different than,
oh,
they know what squirrels,
they're like not coming down.
And of course Brittany was talking about
like rubbing acorns on her body and
maybe they'll come out and stuff like
that.
But a completely different wild animals.
They're out there making the living,
they're out there surviving that,
that whole thing.
They aren't going to react the same way
to,
to human beings walking into the woods.
Animals are pliable.
They're,
they're flexible just like people are.
And if you start feeding wild animals,
they kind of become domesticated.
There's a park right down here in north
Hollywood.
He could sit down in the park and if you
bring a bag of peanuts,
the squirrels will literally come and
take them from your hands like a little
baby.
And it's cool,
you know?
I mean those are different animals,
you know,
like,
like the deer in my yard.
Like a,
my buddy came over one day and there was
this deer standing there just standing
and he's like,
dude,
I didn't even think that was a real
deer.
I thought you were fucking with me cause
uh,
he came over my house and we're going to
work out and there's this deer stand
there.
Look at that.
I think it goes,
what the fuck is that?
I go,
it's a deer.
He was like,
this is a real deer.
Cause he's a,
he's a buck.
And just stand there looking at us and
uh,
and he goes,
okay,
would you shoot that buck?
I go,
fuck no,
that's a depth thing.
Might as well be a pet about starving.
I'd shoot it.
But that thing is not worried about me
at all.
It has never been attacked by a person.
It doesn't associate people with danger.
They're just standing there staring at
me.
You can't your hostess.
Yeah,
you can't kill them.
That's fucked up.
That's why you can,
if you have to survive.
But that's not a game animal.
We have a,
a rule.
Um,
I don't think that you were up by my
cabin,
but Brian was,
and my wife said,
you know,
can you not kill him right here by the
cabin?
You have a rule rule,
but you had a beaver that you guys
killed right there,
right.
Uh,
oh.
That beaver that we ate.
Oh,
that was,
that was up on a crick.
Not,
not far from there,
but that's okay.
She allows the beavers to die.
Well,
yeah,
she loves the Muskrats to die to burrow
into the dam and you know,
cause all kinds of damage.
I want them to die.
Yeah,
you got it.
We get rid of him because they're
causing their,
you know,
the issues by the way,
how good is that?
God Damn beaver taste absolutely.
Bar none.
Best wild meat I've ever eaten.
It's fantastic.
Well the waiver Nela cooked it.
Yep.
Braised it and then slow cooked it like
a stew.
And I'm telling you man,
it was like the best beef stew you've
ever had in your life.
Like in Guam,
rich and flavorful.
And again,
just like we're talking about with um,
organic beef versus regular,
you know,
corn fed.
This is a wild animal with a wild
natural diet and a real healthy big fat
beaver.
Yeah.
So,
so texture wise,
I mean it's,
I've eight rack cooling.
Oh,
slow down.
Koons.
A whole nother ball game.
But it's a raccoon.
It's a wild game thing.
Bear,
I mean people seriously,
one of the worst thing in Wisconsin,
I'm taking the shirt off.
I notice there was not a beaver in the
middle of the grail.
Sustainable beaver.
When did you eat a raccoon man game
feeds,
you know,
they do it.
They,
we have bare feeds,
like,
you know,
packers,
bears weekend,
they'll have a bare feet at the local
tavern.
And you know,
people bring in all their stuff to wild
game.
Hold
the fuck on.
First of all,
let me just explain to people that are
only listening.
I asked,
I asked nate,
I go,
where did he eat?
No raccoon.
And Doug throws his hands up.
Like,
I'm like,
what have you had French fries?
I get to fucking raccoon,
man.
It's been a long time.
A long time.
That's so what is it that you have a
bear?
What?
Every once in a while when they're,
it's packers,
bears,
you know,
they'll have a,
at a local tavern,
they'll have like Newman's barn grill.
We'll plug,
those guys don't,
and he'll point,
you know,
they're,
they've had bear bear feeds,
you know,
for the pack or bears game,
there's a connection and they'll,
uh,
you know,
people bring other stuff.
There's buyer game feeds,
rattlesnake a fee,
but you're calling it a feed.
You don't like a steak feed or uh,
you know,
it's just,
uh,
you feed a bunch of people and they sit
down and get drunk.
Well,
how much chuck and how they cook in the
bear,
what are they doing?
Probably roasting it,
you know,
I mean the big barrel clothes on.
Yeah.
That's it just have a gigantic banner to
me that's part of it up and you know,
that sort of thing.
It's good.
Well,
bears a real tricky,
right?
You got to make sure that you clear the
role that temperature is constant as
well.
Oh yeah.
It's everywhere is,
Yep.
Kenosis is a concern.
Yeah.
So yeah,
it's sort of a Wisconsin tradition.
I saw your
game fee
be and it could be bare,
it could be back in the day when there
was more,
uh,
when,
the raccoon heights we're in,
uh,
we're more valuable and that's,
there's an ebb and flow to that market.
Of course.
Well,
you've got all these hides and what he'd
do with the carcasses and so a certain
amount of them are,
are being eaten.
Um,
what does it taste like?
Any Greasy?
Yeah,
he's really greasy.
Yeah.
Was it a good grease?
Is it?
Yeah.
Good.
Good for you.
It's,
it's one of those things,
there's a little gaming as to it,
you know,
it's one of the things you've got to get
used to it,
you know,
and I don't eat enough,
bear me to get used to it,
but no,
I've had,
they're talking about raccoon,
the raccoon,
raccoon all,
I'm sorry.
You're talking about Pat Baer.
Raccoon.
Oh,
I,
I way prefer beer.
Yeah.
Super Gaming.
It's kind of nutty in a weird way.
Did bear was greasy at all?
Bare to me.
Tasted like a,
almost like a beef.
Where did you,
uh,
Alberta?
Yeah.
So what's that e in Wisconsin?
In the midwest where there's hunting
going on.
They're doing a lot of baiting of them
with,
you know,
like old donuts and stuff like that.
Um,
and I remember Steve Talking about,
um,
I've never,
I've never bear hunted anywhere.
Um,
how he doesn't like taking,
like,
does it spring bears or because they're
eating?
Behold the timing is of sound.
Sandburs he loves the blueberry bears,
but not the cause.
It,
their meat tastes like what the eight
right.
Hey Holy.
And that's what we're talking about
crazy though.
That you know Rinella show.
Have you ever seen that show where he
shot happens?
I haven't the show watch much TV
at all.
Well he uh,
he shot a bear in Alaska and the fall
and it had been just feasting on
blueberries and he was saying that this
is the best meat bar.
None in the world are known.
And he was saying that you opened this
bear up and you smell blueberries and
it's like a sweet tasting meat and then
you,
and then it just really,
I mean you eat a burger,
you don't think about it.
You drink a soda,
you don't think about it,
but that is your cells.
You were literally supplying nutrients
to yourselves,
to your food and when you eat,
like I used to work with this dude,
he's string a lot of carrot juice and
his fucking hands turned orange.
Like his skin tarts started turn orange
cause he was eating like three or four
glasses of carrot juice a day.
Orange.
Are we talking orange is fuck like weird
like Spray Tan,
like Jersey shore Cheetos,
orange or no,
like an orange,
like a carrot.
You know he made a jerk off motion.
I don't know why.
You know why that was shirking off with
cheese.
That's a joke.
Do you know that?
Okay.
It is,
but I don't want to say cheetos and
jerking off like we mean it's,
it's kind of one of those things,
you know,
it's like a bare feet.
Like you got to bring those concepts to
understand.
Yes,
she knows I give you a pass times
renting now.
I don't know man.
There's some stuff about this guy I
didn't know before,
so,
oh
well cheetos forgot cios.
If you're eating cheetos all day or
potato chips or whatever the fuck it is,
that is literally supplying yourselves
and we don't think about it that way.
We just think about this tastes good.
I am me.
I am Doug.
Doug eats cheeseburgers cause
cheeseburger taste good,
but a cheeseburger literally supplying
your body.
You know,
I started this diet recently.
This is called the primal blueprint diet
is guy on the podcast name Mark Sisson
and he is an advocate of no grains,
no bread,
no pasta,
no rice,
no nothing,
mostly fats.
You get your fats from Avocados,
from a healthy fats,
from beef and the chicken or whatever
the fuck you eat and coconut oil,
things along those lines,
a mct oil.
And uh,
I've been on it now for two weeks and
it's pretty fascinating,
pretty fascinating.
First of all,
it took me a while to like adjust from
going on a carbohydrate based,
uh,
energy to a fat base energy getting my,
my energy from fats.
My body fat's decreased pretty
significantly.
I lost at least six pounds now and I'm
eating like normal amounts,
but I'm just eating fat and proteins and
a lot of vegetables and no sugars at
all.
None.
Zero.
I'm not eating,
I'm not eating any processed sugar.
I eat occasional piece of fruit,
blueberries and things along those
lines,
but it's mostly vegetables and meat that
I'm eating and,
and a lot of Avocados.
But my cells obviously are getting
nutrients off of this,
off of healthy fats.
And what he found is he had arthritis.
He also had irritable bowel syndrome.
Those things went away when he,
when he cut grains out of his diet and
we stopped eating processed sugar
influence things,
inflammation.
Yeah.
And that these healthy fats like healthy
fats for your body,
like coconut oil,
things along those lines is really the
best fuel for your body and your body
gets into a state of Ketosis,
which takes about two weeks where I just
started getting into it just started
getting into the state of Ketosis and
your body,
once it reaches a state of Ketosis,
gets its energy primarily from fat and
it's a more normal natural way for your
body to respond and your body can shift.
Like you know,
your body's very flexible can shift from
a glucose based carbohydrate based fuel
system to a fat based fuel system.
So this one of my body has just started
to do and I committed to this.
I was going to do a month,
but I just decided to make it two
months.
I'm committing to this for two months
and I'm gonna talk about it and see what
it's like.
But I'm sold two weeks in.
I don't like it in the fact that if I go
to a restaurant and someone's got a
spaghetti and meatballs next to me,
I'm like,
fuck the meatballs.
Fuck,
I can't eat spaghetti like I have.
I can't eat any sugar.
No desserts.
Does that seem different to you?
Uh,
and what I mean is what you smell like
a,
uh,
a carbohydrate like that.
Uh,
like a crazy,
it was all of a sudden,
whoa.
Maybe not so much before.
No,
it's the opposite.
This is what's really strange about it.
I what they've said,
what people have hypothesized and the
theories are that your gut bacteria
controls a lot of your appetite.
And this is one of the reasons why I
used to be stuffed,
like stuffed at the end of a meal and I
would still want sugar.
I'd still wants to candy or it's still,
yeah,
it's awful.
Right?
You still want some pie all bring up on
her nose.
Well,
now I don't,
it's weird because of this show.
My body taking plenty of probiotics,
uh,
drinking a lot of Kombucha,
things along those lines.
I'm taking some probiotic supplements.
You're you,
you introduce healthy bacteria into your
stomach and your gut and because of that
your shift,
it shifts like what you're hungry for.
It's very strange.
Like bread to me looks like a like why
don't you eat stuffing out of a
mattress?
Like it looks like nonsense to me.
It's very strange cause I used to see
like bread,
someone bring out like a restaurant,
nice loaf of bread and butter.
My,
Oh give me that.
Be All excited.
Slap some butter on that bitch and eat
it up.
Now I look at him like that's not even
food.
Like I said,
it doesn't register to me as a two week
period of time.
You have two weeks,
two weeks and you were such an
unhealthy.
I'm saying,
I mean I think part of it must be
psychological that I've decided that
this isn't food that I've made a shift
in my mind because I'm not eating it.
I haven't eaten it in two weeks,
but I think there's a real good argument
that it's gut bacteria.
That's a big part of it because the
sugar,
like they had like a dessert tray thing
and they brought it out at a restaurant
I was at the other day,
you know,
you know like the fancy place they bring
you like would you look dude,
this wound you would need to be
[inaudible] and none of it looked good.
It all looks like to me.
Whereas before I'd be like,
what am I going to fuck my body up?
I got to figure this out,
we're going to take home with me.
It's very interesting stuff.
And uh,
I,
I'm,
I wanted to experiment with it because
the guy was fascinating.
He's very intelligent.
And I said,
well,
well how,
what does it hurt for me to try this
out?
I thought it'd be an interesting topic
of discussion to do it first,
you know,
60 days or so and then maybe even have
him back on or have someone else on that
advocates it.
And,
and I've read people that don't advocate
a carbohydrate rich diets.
And it seems to me that your body is
pretty flexible in your body,
can exist on a bunch of different types
of fuel and people get really dogmatic
about it.
You know,
like you have to do it this way,
you have to do it that way.
And uh,
I don't think,
I think it's all,
there's also biodiversity,
right?
There's different people come from
different climates.
They come from different parts of the
world.
Originally their ancestors did and I
think their bodies have become more
acclimated to those types of foods.
And that was like the big issue with
native Americans when the European
showed up with alcohol and they
literally didn't have the genes to
process this stuff,
whereas Irish people processed shit like
that.
Yeah,
no.
Yeah.
Italians,
it's interesting that you said that
about probiotic because I've been taking
a probiotic for about 18 months now.
Uh,
all the places where I got this advice
was from my accountant and
he's a buddy.
Uh,
or is it like a,
I went over your taxes and which she
needed?
No,
it's one of her clients.
But,
um,
I had been sick and she said something
about probiotics and honest to God,
18 months,
I've been taking a probiotic every
morning and I'm not been,
and I haven't done anything else
different,
but I've been,
uh,
not necessarily healthier but less ill,
ill at all really.
There's a,
an article I read once about skin flora
and uh,
it was in regards to grappling cause a
with Jujitsu and wrestling,
a big issue is ringworm.
And even staff infection.
I've gotten both.
Really?
Yeah,
man,
it sucks that there were,
the staff was real scary because,
um,
my friend Tate Fletcher spotted it.
We were at an airport,
we were hanging out,
getting ready to go on a plane and I
just had my foot sitting up on my knee
and he's looking at the bottom of my
calf and he goes,
hey man,
what's going on with your leg?
I go,
what?
He's like,
what's going to get at least like,
what's all this?
I go,
what is it?
He like,
there's little pimples on my ligament.
I don't know.
He goes,
dude,
that looks like staff.
Like are you serious?
And he goes,
yeah,
I don't like that man.
Go get that checked out because he,
you know,
he uh,
fought,
has been grappling his whole life and he
had,
he had caught it before.
I had never caught it.
I caught ringworm before and I knew what
that looked like and so I was like,
this is fucking pimples.
Like what is it?
He's like,
I'm telling you,
I think that staff,
so I go immediately to a dermatologist,
take his advice and the guy goes,
Yup,
you can get on some fucking antibiotics.
He gives me these horse pills of death.
This stuff's awful.
These first of all antibiotics when you
have staff wrecks your entire system
because it doesn't just kill the staff.
Yeah.
It kills all the healthy flora too.
So just start over what they say to
counter that is to take probiotics once
you're done with your whole cycle,
but also to prevent it in the future.
You take healthy bacteria,
like a lot of acid off list,
different forms of probiotics and you
are essentially giving your body
soldiers to fight off infection.
And the skin flora changes when you take
high doses of healthy acidophilus and
things along those lines.
Your skin,
it's also like people that are Vegan.
There's a some different probiotics like
raw sauerkraut,
like raw sauerkraut has really good.
Kimchi is another one that's really
good,
fantastic probiotic.
You're essentially taking it live
organisms that become a part of your
body and their soldiers.
And these live organisms fight off
against shitty bacteria.
It's amazing stuff.
Well,
part of the reason I was convinced other
than I get my medical advice
cheap is,
uh,
in the other work that I do,
I build and manage athletic fields.
Um,
and there a huge movement to go towards
organic,
uh,
fertilization or cultural practices in
on athletic fields.
You know,
this one facility that I manage,
um,
before every tournament,
we'll get emails and calls from parents
who bring their eight year old and say,
well,
we're coming in from wherever and we
would like to know what's been applied
to your fields.
My son or daughter has a issue with
herbicide and tolerance or whatever.
And I take that shit really seriously.
Um,
we started using a compost from,
uh,
both a facility nearby from the county,
but also from a supplier.
And applying that as a part of our,
um,
our regime cut,
we're able to cut back on fertilizer.
And the other thing that was really
interesting is that,
um,
a lot of the pathogens that we have
issue with on,
and you see my golf courses,
they get a different kinds of fungus
that affect the grasp because you're,
it's,
you're putting water on it and you're
feeding the shit out of it.
And by putting that compost on there,
um,
and providing,
you know,
essentially the organisms that are good
for the soil,
we're feeding the soil,
not the plant,
which nitrogen that they,
you know,
synthetic nitrogen or,
or,
uh,
does.
And so what ends up happening is we're,
we're feeding that soil and so now we've
got a whole environment there that,
that,
uh,
turf grass has got an opportunity to
utilize everything that's in that soil
and it's healthier.
Um,
and,
you know,
we're kind of going the other,
we're going the other direction in,
in everything from farming to grown
grass,
for kids to play soccer on it.
Well,
I know a guy who lived near a golf
course growing up and the pesticides
that they use on the golf course fact
the water supply and he got bone cancer
and cancer throughout his neighborhood.
Everyone in his neighborhood was
affected.
Someone they knew got cancer.
It was rampant and it was just that were
drinking the water that came from this
area where the had been contaminated
because of a fucking golf course.
Yeah.
Reaching in.
And,
uh,
the one company that I work with,
has built,
uh,
been a part of a construction of a golf
course that from day one was,
and it's actually certified organic,
but it was better part of their process
all the way along and they control,
you know,
the amount of traffic on it and all of
those sort of things too.
But it's a beautiful golf course and
they haven't used any,
uh,
best sides or synthetic fertilizers on
it.
One of the things that they had brought
up in that same article about organic
meat being healthier was the
incorporation of clover and with grass
and then somehow or another clover
helps.
It helps sustain like a nitrogen balance
with the grasses.
Like it's a,
clover is a nitrogen fixing plant.
So if you,
you know,
in a pasture we,
we,
we introduced clover into our pastures
and so it fixes nitrogen into the soil
that's then available for the grasses
and uh,
white clovers and a lot of the things
that I actually plant in some of the
food plot stuff that we do for,
for deer.
Yeah.
For deer.
Um,
it's sweet.
It tastes good.
And it's also providing nitrogen to the
plants that need it.
Um,
yeah.
Nah.
And that's a big problem with things
like gigantic fields of only grain of
only corn or have only wheat that this,
it's not natural for one plant species
to be mano critter.
Yeah.
That's not normal.
Right.
That's not natural.
And it's kind of like what you were
talking about when we were talking about
these really interesting diverse
ecosystems that are created by these
organic farms.
Like this one that you were,
you were highlighting earlier.
Yeah.
And so it is,
it's a,
it's a complete ecosystem.
No Sir.
That's how it's supposed to be.
Well,
the thing that gets me is that,
you know,
this Mark Sheppard,
I mean,
I,
I've just page through it.
You know,
Doug's read more of it than I have,
but I mean,
you look at this and you read it and it
makes sense and you're like,
wow,
this guy's a genius.
But then you think about ancient
civilizations were doing things along
these lines.
Where did we lose that?
You know,
where did that go away?
We lost it with this factory farming and
we also lost it when we started putting
people in cities.
I think cities are a real big part of
our disconnect and also awesome.
I love cities.
I love to be able to go to the and
implement.
Yeah,
I like getting like highway,
like the guy you mentioned the guy you
mentioned Joel,
that girls this shit.
Yeah,
no that was,
that was um,
Ron Finley,
you know you've heard of Joel Salitan
has been on the podcast.
Yeah,
he's Aussie.
I was going to reference him.
He's amazing.
He's got some amazing books.
You know,
he's got a lot of books on a really
interesting strategy for like letting
pigs and all these different animals
graze.
And so what he does is he sets up this
perimeter fence,
this large like mildly charged fan stuff
that go to it.
It's a irritates them.
And they said they don't run over the
fence and then he moves,
it moves the fence and they graze in new
area so they don't just distraught.
Yeah.
They don't just end their living as if
they were wild.
They're essentially grazing off acorns,
things along those lines.
And it just giant areas where they roam
and forage and they eat just like a wild
pig.
And because of that,
their flesh is very different.
But that's what you got in your freezer
now dude,
well this is,
this is elk,
but I have a one kid from my free smart
home.
You got to pay.
Yeah,
we your them.
Oh,
okay.
Well that's the way to do it.
I mean it's a different kind of meat.
It looks different.
You know what I mean?
It has a deeper,
darker,
richer color.
And that's one of the things that I
noticed when we shot when Rinella and I
shot a pig at the till hone ranch.
It was thick with fat from acorns and
its texture.
The,
the meat was like a dark red and it was
delicious.
It's a different animal.
Isn't it an interesting like with beef,
um,
I still eat the occasional,
uh,
beef that,
that I might not know where it came
from,
right?
Not very often,
but are,
there's one,
uh,
one place,
one restaurant at a nearby or place that
I go to and he finishes his beef with,
uh,
with corn.
Oh.
But it's mostly,
you know,
grass fed,
but he's still sort of old school with
the marble it to yeah,
I taste the difference between,
of course she tasted his difference
between Venice soon because really
again,
I don't have this wide experience of
hunting and in,
in different areas and having meet from
different areas.
So I am excited like your elk,
but so the venison to grass fed beef to
corn fed beef.
Um,
and it's been a long time since I've had
something that I,
like I said where I didn't know where it
came from,
but I can tell you when it was,
when it was a fat cattle,
they call them.
Um,
I feel like after I get done eating a
piece of meat like that,
like I have a little prime rib or
something.
When they go out on a Saturday night,
I feel like I should take a knife and
he's like scraped that fed off of my
tongue.
It just has a completely different
tastes and that just,
I'm not interested in anymore.
And so my taste has changed that way.
Um,
so
it's very tender,
but it's also because that animals dying
animal,
you're eating a sumo wrestler,
you know,
ain't no slob.
What are the,
what's that?
Uh,
where the massage them?
Yeah.
Colby.
Or why you are the more common as I say,
why do you I don't like that stuff man.
I've had it before.
I mean it's okay,
but it's just,
it's so fucking soft and weird.
It's like why w w how the fuck is this
muscle carrying this animal around?
Gelatinous?
It's weird.
I'll take it to even more of an extreme
and,
and uh,
and that is a veal.
There was down the road from our old
friend who had the issue with us when we
were hunting and he would call and leave
me those crazy message
just before,
before he will in that place.
It was owned by another guy who raised
veal and,
and when I was younger I helped out up
once in a while.
And how you helped out was to help him
load the veal.
Those animals are in a cage where they
essentially can't turn a box where they
can barely turn around and they're being
fed,
you know,
a milk replacer powdery that you mix
with water and it's kind of a liquid.
And that's all they're getting.
And the best looking veal calves,
calves,
where the last animal I ever wanted to
eat,
I mean it smelled bad.
It,
there was nothing good about it.
Muscles aren't developed.
They're not,
they don't want them to develop,
you know,
crazy thing.
I don't,
I don't even understand that.
I don't understand how it got started
and I don't understand why people keep
eating it.
Well,
people eat lutefisk I mean,
that's weird.
Lutefisk what does that look like?
Well,
it's ludicrous.
So I was like,
what did he do wrong?
But fish in a,
what is it a lie?
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
yeah,
they took it to mean we shouldn't think
it's a survival thing.
The Vikings did it on ships and stuff,
but people still,
it's more,
it's a tradition thing,
but,
oh,
so it's literally lie,
lie.
I mean,
but in lie poisonous,
this is real.
I'm like,
fuck is this?
And it's weird.
I mean,
you want to talk gelatinous by Fred.
Learn Hanson is standing up with his
hands in the air right now.
It's an older machine.
Regions are awesome.
I just got to say that.
Oh my God,
what?
That's weird.
Eerie wines with Lutefisk.
Oh God.
It's looks like Jizz look at it.
It's like,
it's like slime,
like snail slime.
And I,
I've never had veal,
but I've had this and that,
you know,
it's gotta be what does this light,
but yeah,
but this is just a,
well it was,
it was five.
Yeah.
And it's just tradition now,
but people,
it is,
it tastes like,
I can't even describe it.
I don't,
I think I blocked it out in my mind.
Well,
see what they,
these,
these Norway and the Norwegian areas of,
of Wisconsin,
they have these dinners,
you know,
lutefisk dinners for fundraisers and
such,
but they also have,
they have other things.
So you try,
you know,
my whole thing was money out of respect.
I'll take a bite of lutefisk and then,
and then I watched that dawn with some
like,
you know,
Swedish meatballs and you know,
left.
So you know,
and just soaked in,
just get it out of your mouth.
It's one of those things like what's the
other thing you washed down with Swedish
meatballs and I have,
so it's like a little,
isn't it a potato bread type?
Almost like a Tortilla
show here you guys are eating raccoons.
Ludicrous smelt fees,
smelt feet,
little tiny fishy scoop bub and giant
and deep fry.
The fry eat the whole thing,
right?
Guts and all that much.
What is that like?
It's,
it's really good.
I mean we are wrestling club.
Oh not so good.
I like it.
I like
the favorite thing,
but I mean it's not your Friday anything
and it's pretty good,
you know,
I mean we'll fry bread and all that
jazz.
I guess I do tartar sauce.
You put the,
doesn't have the amount of Bun and
chow down and make some money for the
wrestling club.
Well you gotta do what you gotta do if
you're home beavers,
there's a TV show.
I think money from the wrestling club
from fucking,
this is how do you make this connection?
It's a fundraiser.
Yeah.
That's what we do.
That's how we make money.
We have feeds,
Ludovic speeds,
stake feeds,
bare feet,
you know,
and it's,
it's that real creative
comes to uh,
uh,
raising money,
I guess.
Although we have the,
the Cazenovia,
this is one plug.
I do want to put it,
the Cazenovia Turkey busters fishery
coming up this week.
Turkey busters fishery.
What is it?
Turkey.
Buster.
Well,
first,
well,
it's a sportsman's club.
I don't think we have a website or
anything,
so I wouldn't look it up.
But,
uh,
so it's a sportsman's club and in
Cazenovia,
which is,
you know,
250 people,
it's sort of the lion's Club,
the knights of Columbus,
the every,
you know,
the rotary,
it's everybody put together.
It's just this group of dudes who are
really into Turkey hunting and call
themselves the Turkey buster busters.
Yeah.
And,
uh,
why do we have a fishery?
Well,
I have this little,
uh,
Lake [inaudible] Lake there in
Cazenovia.
And one of the things that we do is that
with the money that we raised as a stock
it with walleyes and other,
um,
game fish.
And,
uh,
so one of the things that we do is have
this fishery which is on the ice.
So it's a,
essentially ice fishing tournament would
be the wrong word.
Um,
although there are prizes for like the
biggest blue Gill and the biggest bass
and,
and that kind of thing.
Um,
but mostly it's a thing where people
come to when you have raffles and,
um,
it's the social event of the season.
Cazenovia oh yeah.
Oh yeah.
Jesus,
don't get it.
They are lying.
But all they have,
all they have,
all they have is the phone number and
contact.
This is at Cazenovia memorial park
Chuck Keller called the Tower Online.
Whatever you do,
we've already said too much.
If they have a website,
they're getting Dick pics right now as
you speak.
Wow.
Yeah.
So those are different ways that,
and you know,
and some of the stuff that we've also
done is um,
uh,
donate it bought and donated like white
archery bows or uh,
Matthew's bows to uh,
uh,
the,
to the schools,
uh,
physical education program.
Oh,
that's cool.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
If they still do that,
that's very cool.
Yeah.
So this is a little organization of,
of a bunch of guys who get together once
her did depends on the time of the year,
once or twice a month then well,
there's certainly a benefit to having a
small community like that where
everybody really does care about the
welfare of the community and cares about
all these different things like red
wrestling team needing money for
uniforms and things along those lines.
We lose a lot
of that.
When you have big cities,
this is,
there's so much to gain in a big city,
but there's so much to lose to,
and it's like we were talking earlier
about the diffusion of responsibility
that you have when there's 20 million
people.
You see somebody with their fucking car
broken down the side of the road.
I don't even think about stopping.
Well I hope this asshole as aaa,
you know,
Brown pass by.
But if you're on some country road and
you see someone broken down,
you think one or two things,
I hope this guy,
he's not a serial killer and I should
probably try to help him.
Yeah,
exactly.
Those are the two things you think.
And the other thing out in our,
our territory when you're driving right
in our area when you're driving around
is you wave to everybody.
Yeah,
yeah.
She'd drive or not.
It might not be putting your hand up
like this or anything,
but yeah.
At least to driving on little.
Yeah.
That's nice.
You know that that is definitely missing
on the highway cause otherwise he'd be
fucking
break.
You know,
it's a saint as you
know.
It's all weird in that
it is weird.
People are weird,
but cities are especially weird because
I don't think this is a normal thing.
I don't know what,
well,
we've only had them for the last couple
hundred years in this sort of magnitude
that we have now,
like with New York and La and things
along those lines.
Just to have so many people jammed into
an area like this.
And as we started this conversation,
have a complete disconnect as to where
your food comes from and that the food
is coming from life,
whether it's plant life or whether it's
animal life,
your food comes from life.
Life eats life,
allogenic London.
Is that
what the Seawolf we were just talking
about this.
Yeah.
What'd he say?
Um,
well,
it's a,
this character,
it's this old pirate in this book called
the Sea Sea Wolf.
I knew it was going to get a pirate
fan of pirates who isn't man cards are
awesome.
I mean,
you know,
maybe not to the new age ones.
The Somalis are,
well yeah,
they're a little different.
But you know,
those are the,
not without my sympathy as well.
Everybody's got an agenda and
everybody's got a reason to fight.
You know,
they have a very,
well,
we'll get into that.
This specific pirate,
his whole,
you know,
he's a loner and his whole thing in the
conversation throughout the book is he
talks about it as a yeast,
yeast eats life.
And his whole contention is
what the fuck matters.
Life eats life.
I mean,
you could make an argument like you're
going to be dead,
you're going to be dead,
you're gonna be dead.
Who gives a fuck?
Who gives a fuck what happens?
You know?
I mean,
people's,
that's not a very nice way to look at
things,
you know?
But it is,
it's,
I mean,
it's a fact,
you know,
as a fact.
But also this moment right now is
enjoyable.
Oh,
absolutely.
I have a problem with that sort of
absolute sort of,
you know,
worrying about the end and not,
no,
absolutely.
The moment is enjoyable.
Like an l sit.
All comradery and friendship and a good
meal with friends is one of the best
things you can have in life.
Adventures and things that you enjoy,
activities that you like to participate
in.
Those are very enjoyable.
And I think that's what life is.
Life is about these friendships and
these enjoyable moments that we have
with each other.
So this is absolute ideas that people
have,
but what is the point,
man?
Yes,
but again,
it's all going to end,
man.
Well,
okay,
you could look at it that way.
It's like what's the point in playing
the game?
The is going to be over one day.
Do you not enjoy the fucking game?
Enjoy the game.
We saw sitting on the steps today.
You know,
you know,
just sitting there in Hollywood,
just poisoned Fox.
They're poisoned by the brake dust.
It's fucking flying through the air
everywhere.
Shit's terrible for you.
Hopefully different smells out here,
man.
This brake dust is terrible.
It's one of the one things that people
don't talk about,
about living in urban environments that
you don't.
You go to your car,
you know that shit.
If you have a wheel and you see that
stuff on the outside of your wheel,
you're breathing that.
You're breathing that everywhere.
Especially if you live in New York or if
you live in La and there's constant
traffic going by you.
Every time they hit the brakes,
a little bit of fucking dust gets up in
the air and that stuff,
and you're dealing with millions and
millions of cars and stuff permeates the
environment.
It's terrible for you.
People's People's vault,
the voluntary coast guard,
if Somalia,
that's what the pirates called
themselves.
The reason why they started doing
pirating in Somalia,
because they were fishermen,
they fishermen and these assholes from
Europe and Russia were dumping toxic
waste off their shores,
nuclear waste,
toxic chemical waste.
And it was killing all the fish.
So what they started doing was
kidnapping the people that were in the
boat that we're doing the dumping.
So these fishermen who were fucking
starving to death because they,
all of a sudden they're,
their waters were polluted.
They started going after these guys and
kidnapping them.
Then they realized,
hey,
we get way more fucking money from
kidnapping people than we do from
fishing.
They became pirates.
And so they also started taking this
stuff called cat.
And this is a,
it's,
it's a narcotic.
It's a stimulant that they,
uh,
they take.
It's like a plant that they chew and it
gives them like,
like it's like a fucking meth type
plant.
I don't know the exact uh,
pull,
pull that up.
I think it's k,
h,
a t,
but it's a stimulant that they chew all
the time.
It's one of the reasons why the people
are so there it is cat to be banned in
the UK.
They see like this guy's eating chewing
on these,
uh,
these leaves and it produces popup up a
website or a web description instead of
an image and we'll find out what is the
actual,
um,
go to all set of images.
It's Kinda like a big league chew on
there.
Yeah.
This is a as scene in that movie.
Captain Phillips.
Yeah.
Though this or this,
this stuff is,
it's a,
it's a drug and these people take it.
It's an alkaloid.
Yeah.
Here it is.
Catherine known or it's an amphetamine
amphetamine like stimulant,
which has said to cause excitement,
a loss of appetite and euphoria.
And so these guys take this,
they get jacked on this cat,
k,
h,
a,
t.
And.
M.
They would go out and fucking kidnap
people.
Well,
that's the thing too,
you know,
I mean,
my initial,
when I said,
except
Somali pirates,
I mean,
that's how we tell history is from
Captain Phillips side.
You know,
and that's like the Howard Zinn thing.
Howard Zinn tells it from the other
side,
you know,
so let me retract that.
I like Somali pirates a little bit too.
You know what you guys got to,
uh,
you know,
they've got a reason to fight.
They got fucked.
It's for the longest time,
they were incredibly peaceful people.
Somalians were very peaceful.
They,
you know,
they weren't out there,
Robin and trying to Jack People,
they were fishermen.
And when the Europeans started dumping
that stuff off their shores,
they had to take a new approach.
They had to just adapt,
improvise,
overcome.
Yeah.
But again,
where's that coming from?
Coming from,
you know,
large scale human beings living in these
giant civilizations,
creating waste.
They don't know what to do with some
Dick hole decides to dump it off the
coast of Africa because they don't have
any say in the matter.
You know,
they didn't want to dump it in the then
the London Bay.
Yeah.
So they decided to do that here too long
to do it all day.
Does that make loosen standards so that
companies can put more in?
That's a big deal with New York City as
well.
The Hudson River's fucking deserted
wasteland.
It was at one point in time,
they're dredging it up now and starting
to uh,
to clean it and,
and trying to uh,
really impose very strict regulations on
the amount of waste that gets in it.
But these large animal facilities,
same thing.
Yeah,
exactly.
Where we put this stuff and you see
these trucks going up into these big
tank trucks full of,
and they had the hall it really far
because they don't have enough,
they're renting land all over.
So they're hauling it as a big issue in
our areas is the weight on the roads.
And so then,
you know,
and the farmers,
they didn't want to be taxed or
anything.
So they,
I believe there's a compromise where it
wasn't a road tax,
but they made him have another axle.
So it spread the weight out and wasn't,
you know,
turn the hell out of the
roads.
Oh,
so the actual physical weight on the
road,
is that why they go to the giant tankers
doing,
I always wondered why they weighed them.
Well in our neck of the woods again,
um,
a lot of the roads were just gravel
roads and then over time they did this
thing called tarn chip.
So I grabbed the road.
It's not built in,
it doesn't have any particular engineer.
Well this was supposed to have some
engineering standards,
but fun as possible.
Yeah.
And there aren't any engineering
standards,
but gravel roads are a bitch to keep up.
So they started to Taryn chip them.
So it's,
you know,
it's a poor man's a blacktop.
So you put uh,
or asphalt,
so you put this tar down and then go
over the top of it.
And I could have pea gravel,
pea gravel stuff and it all binds
together and then over 10 people keep
driving on.
And over time it actually seals it up.
And if you're just driving over it with
cars and pickup trucks,
it's okay.
But now here comes big tanker truck or
being taker,
uh,
w you know,
behind a monster tractor and you know,
it's breaking down the sides of the
roads and it ends up being an issue for
us.
And as nate said,
they're having to haul this stuff
further for cause you can only put so
much shit on so much ground.
And the shit that they are putting out
there is,
uh,
you know,
it's,
it's liquid manure that's going into
these tanks or into these
facilities and newer liquid.
Oh,
it's nuts.
It's just found a new way to torch the
terrorist.
And there's a,
there's a double standard with it.
Um,
[inaudible] so he got this massive
model,
liquid manure.
You don't,
they,
they're not going to store it.
They're not going to compost it or
anything like that.
So like right now we've got a nice snow
pack,
12 inches,
and they're spread it on top of the
snow.
So,
and,
and just to illustrate the double
standard,
I got family that,
uh,
is in the septic business,
you know,
so if they go out,
if they spread this shit on a certain
slope,
human shit,
human shit from like holding tanks are
pumping out.
So spread it.
Yeah,
we'll see.
Here's the thing though.
It,
they spread it on the snow and if they
do it over,
have you,
if they do it over,
uh,
he said that because Jamie just pulled
up liquid I newer spreaders and tool
bars for the people that are listening
and I've added added axles,
you know,
that's a new thing.
They used to have one axle just spread
and it was just too much on the road.
But so a septic dude,
he goes out there to get rid of this
human shit.
And if he does it on a certain grade,
he'll get a giant fine from the dnr.
But a farmer goes out and does it and
it's say,
hey,
you know,
so human shit,
a farmer can dump human.
No,
no.
A farmer can go dump cow shit.
And the thing is,
you know,
in the end,
I mean shit a shit a shit.
You know what I mean
though,
right?
Because cow shit is just,
they're eating grass.
So like manure
facilities,
they're not $30 kid.
Right.
And you know,
obviously this,
when the snow melts and you know that,
that a lot of that shit is going into
the stream.
So like we're doug and I,
you know,
we really value our shit.
You know,
we keep it,
we compost it,
we turn it into something with value.
[inaudible] that's a waste.
It's going into the water and polluting
and it's a waste of money.
The drone footage,
they did it.
This pig farm,
this guy.
I've seen some,
I don't know if not a particular memory
that you would probably agree with.
I agree with.
And those,
those people in the cowspiracy
documentary certain degree with is that
there's something evil about these ag
gag laws.
Oh yeah.
Crazy shit.
Where you're not supposed to film
atrocities that are being committed in
these factory farms.
Well,
this guy got a drone and he flew it over
this pig farm and they have a goddamn a
lake of pig piss.
It is gigantic.
And it's,
they have these things where the pigs
live these cages.
And then here,
here's a guy.
Um,
he's gonna do it right here.
He's a w for people who want to spy.
Drone exposes Smithfield foods.
Say say that up.
Put that up.
Smithfield foods.
Factory farm.
So spy drones expose Smithfield foods.
Factory farms.
The lagoon is a good word because it
sounds dirty.
The lake of pig Cesspool piss and what
a,
yeah,
it's,
it's like a red color.
It's disgusting.
I look at these,
I mean,
imagine how many animals are in one of
those shots.
It's fun and they don't see sunlight.
You know,
it's
fucked.
It's fucked.
It's not.
It's not,
it's not human.
It's not humane.
It's not ethical.
It's not right.
But to bring it all home.
All right,
look at this.
The lagoon,
the color.
Does it just sit there?
Do they ever do anything with it or is
it just sit there and bubble.
Bubble.
What'd you say?
Jam.
They spray it around to the house.
That's an to try to find a picture of
the person they talked to the neighbor
Paul Ryan in the air.
Oh my God.
It gets in the air and goes into
people's houses and think some of the
neighbors are saying it gets like it
gets in their house and they can't even
breathe.
Oh fucking here's a guy.
There's a fear factor thing here.
This guy,
former pig factory on,
well let me hear this guy.
Huh?
Come on Don Webb.
Something wrong.
Yeah,
there's no sound,
but you can just see the way it's moving
within the facility there too.
Oh,
there's an issue with the computer.
Um,
strange.
Yeah man.
It's,
it's dark.
It's evil and it's when all of a sudden
these things don't get treated like a
life.
They get treated like a commodity.
And I think,
I guess there's levels right?
To people that are vegans,
they would say,
well,
any animal that you would be willing to
raise and then ship off and sell.
Like,
why are you any better than this guy
who's got these things stuffed into this
thing?
I mean,
yeah,
your animals are living a normal life,
but then eventually you're gonna kill
him anyway,
you know?
Yeah.
Whereas,
you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
You know that I have a,
uh,
a friend who's a Vegan and in fact,
one of my heifer calves is named after
her.
Um,
and she's honored by that actually.
Cause she knows that that one's never
going to be,
um,
or it probably won't be pleased where we
won't be mature,
but,
um,
unless she gets a prolapsed cervix or
something like that.
But,
um,
yeah.
So if you push these broken and you're
done for cows,
cows,
you got to be specific there,
Joe.
So to say that there's not a difference
is,
well,
there's depth,
just not paying attention,
but no,
I mean,
if that's what the argument is,
then you're not paying attention and we
can't have a conversation about it.
I just think they think that the
ultimate goal at the end is definitely
death or the ultimate result for these
animals.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
the same people don't want you to be
shooting wild animals either.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well,
even wolves,
which is why I've just read one is
hilarious because there's so much
ignorance involved in people's idea of
what a wolf is and why there's so many
folk tales and stories that involve bad
wolves killing people.
There was a two,
I just read this to,
um,
wolves,
I believe it was Idaho.
We can,
we can check it and if we're not to,
but two wolves killed 176 sheep or
something like that.
And One night I am for fun.
Well that's the thing that wolves do
what's,
and then they're having a real big
problem with this and yellowstone and,
and a lot of places that have elk is
that they don't kill.
Like a cat will kill a wolf or a cat
will kill an elk rather.
And he will eat that elk for a long
period of time.
He'll bury it,
he'll try and he'll eat it and a wolf
kills it,
eats a little bit,
and then kills another one and then
kills another one and kills another one.
And they do whatever the fuck they want.
One of these guys that I know at hoyt
was telling me about this,
this wolf,
that it killed this a cow.
And the way it did it was it attacked
the cat cow.
Elk attacked it towards guts apart and
then this thing,
and then backed off and just watched and
sat and didn't eat and watch this thing
struggle and try to walk away and tried
to walk into this river.
I tried to get away and they would go
after it again and tear it apart a
little bit more and then back off again.
They do it for fun and it's what they're
designed for.
They're killing machines and they enjoy
it and it's it.
They're beautiful.
And I'm not saying they're evil.
We should kill them all and eradicate
them from the face of war of the world.
But there's something strange about that
kind of animal.
They're not,
they're not necessarily,
they're not environmentalist.
They're not conservationists to fucking
wolves.
And wolves are dangerous.
They're,
they're,
they have an essential place in a very
diverse ecosystem.
But the top of the food chain is fucking
human beings,
period.
And when human beings decide,
you know what,
there's too many of these goddamn wolves
that are killing a hundred plus sheep in
a night.
Or my friend,
um,
Mike Hockridge who lives up in,
in BC,
his neighbor,
they're fucking cow,
got taken out at cal,
got taken out by wolves and you're in,
in BC where he lives,
there's no tag limit for wolves.
You could shoot as many as you want.
You can shoot well,
you could be your hobby.
What do you do?
I go bowling.
I shoot wolves.
Like they,
they're fucking trying to take out as
many walls as they can.
When we were talking about coyotes
before,
and personally,
I don't,
you know,
I've shot a few coyotes in my day.
How dare you.
And uh,
yeah.
Uh,
but it's not something I could go on and
pursue.
Uh,
you know,
necessarily it's more opportunistic or
whatever.
It's fucking with roadrunner and you've
got to take them out and anvil acme,
Doug's just like,
it's,
you know,
it's sort of like the deer thing.
When I was listening to various
arguments about a deer,
what,
one of the reasons we have so many deer
in Wisconsin and another agricultural
areas is because of agriculture.
And they are highly adaptive.
Yes.
And that's a really big point because
they're not even essentially wild.
They're really kind of like a farm
animal and a lot of ways.
And it was one of the,
the things that Steve brought up on the
show that we talked about,
you know,
I don't know if it ever made the air
did,
does that make the air,
we were just talking about how these
animals are essentially
a lot of ways,
they're like a livestock almost.
Well non fenced in the trail camera
pictures that I sent you have different
gear that I had,
you know,
different,
uh,
you know,
bucks.
I'm thinking,
well,
you're not going to see that out and of
course,
or guitar or whatever or maybe you do.
But,
uh,
but no,
I mean,
well,
they're very different than that.
The mule deer that we were talking about
before the show started that Rinella
killed,
uh,
that was on a show recently,
which is enormous,
beautiful,
majestic public land mule
deer that he killed a mule deer.
They've found we'll travel 150 miles,
um,
during season there.
They really migrate in
probably for a lot of the same reasons
because they have to for food.
Yeah.
Food and for whatever.
Whereas an older,
a deer gets in our area,
at least my experience has been so the
older deer gets in our area,
the less it moves.
So if you have a,
a buck that you're,
you know,
you're managing for bigger bucks and you
start seeing one that maybe has a
distinctive antler or something,
so you can tell it from other ones,
um,
you'll begin to realize,
you know,
that great big one that I shot,
I saw that dear for two years.
He lived in about a 40 acre area.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I'm just waiting for him to slip up.
And he did.
There's a lot of these hunting shows
where they named the deer's.
Yeah.
You know,
they'll,
they'll call this one,
you know,
old forkey,
whatever,
and they'll have names for these animals
and they'll target them.
We're looking for lucky.
We're trying to get lucky know they'll
have these shows.
And like this is so bizarre because it's
in a lot of ways you're like kind of
farming because they have these gigantic
pastures that they call food plots.
So what they'll do is they'll,
they'll plow the land and they'll grow a
lot of clover,
a lot of different different times,
Alfalfa,
different things that they know.
Dears,
we'll eat deers,
no.
Deers.
And so then they set up a tree stand and
a whack them out.
Yeah.
And um,
I do it too.
Part of what I do in my land management
service for people is to,
is to help their property become more
wildlife friendly.
One of the things that I try to push to
people is that when we're doing things
like timber stand improvement or
invasive species management,
or providing a wildlife food plots,
we're planting with wildlife,
food plots,
just not dear food plots.
And a lot of those guys that,
you know,
what I really want to steer well,
what's a concern at all?
Yeah.
And what's good for deer is generally
good for a whole host of wildlife.
So it's a little bit different,
but yeah,
no,
I know what you mean.
I tend to name them afterwards,
like that big one,
big one that I killed.
Uh,
you know,
we called them the standard.
Um,
and because also the standard by which
all after this we'll be judged,
you know?
And uh,
but yeah,
I mean that part of the relationship is,
is uh,
complicated man.
It is complicated,
but like all things involving life,
they'd become complicated.
There's,
it's not,
it's not as simple.
Yeah.
Can I talk about media or a little bit?
Yeah,
please.
Um,
so we did,
we shot,
uh,
starting this Thursday,
there'll be a,
there'll be three episodes in a row that
were shot on the farm.
The first ones,
actually,
steve taken apart a couple of the deer
that,
that he finally shot a couple of years
on our place.
And technically he'll say something
else,
but during our hunting killed two deer.
But he took them apart.
So it's a really informative episode
about the different kinds of cuts,
how well one,
how to just do it,
and then the different kinds of cuts in
the methods for doing this stuff.
Just really,
um,
I just watched it and I just,
just really impressed by it.
And he's amazing.
He really is.
He's so God damn important because in
my,
my mind on television,
he is the most prominent intellectual
voice for wild game management,
wild game conservation,
and for hunting.
He's,
he's a true conservationist.
Um,
he's a guy who really,
truly believes in public land hunting
and it goes way out of his way.
I mean,
he gets plenty of offers to hunt on
private land.
He prefers to hunt on public land and he
prefers to do his best to try to do
whatever he can to help keep those lands
public.
Yeah.
And to promote that.
And,
uh,
I think one of the things he likes about
hunting on my place is that he knows
that after the fact we,
you know,
like when you were there and just like
this pasture and every other year
there's a small group of people that
hunt opening weekend.
After that I start letting other folks
come in.
I mean it's our private land we're able
to do,
but it is the public's animal and yeah,
I put restrictions on folks.
You can't shoot a buck or you know,
it's got to be this big or whatever it
is.
And uh,
and he's applauded that in the past and,
Aye.
That's really important to me.
Um,
because I struggle with that a little
bit.
But um,
but the alternative isn't very good.
Where you land is just wide open to
anybody who wants to come in on an
experience that no good.
What is the problem is you can't really
count on everybody to be ethical.
You can't really count on everybody to
take care of if your land with reverence
and dignity and the way you treat it,
the liability,
you can't let every yahoo very
important.
Very important.
Like,
like the,
the animal they got winged in the neck
cause he's going by that the,
that the coyotes took up part,
you know,
who knows who shot that,
whether or not it was an ethical shot or
it's a bad shot.
Yeah.
And that's,
that's a big part of it.
Well,
so that's the first episode.
The next two are two people that I,
I hunted with us that I know and love
and we actually uh,
did a very similar thing to what you and
Brian did.
The first time Brittany and Helen,
uh,
hunted was in Montana.
That was a year ago and sort of like a
steve did with you and Brian.
Well,
very low.
The next hunt was to bring them to our
place.
So they went from hiking and working
hard and freezing and not seeing deer
very much to freezing her ass off,
sitting in a blind doing and the weather
cooperated.
It was nearly,
not nearly as cold as well
or snowy though.
Uh,
coincidentally I was in town the night
before the opening day and I was so
bummed out that I had scheduled it where
I had to be in Colorado the next day and
I barely made it out of Madison.
Oh yeah,
I was in your town,
man.
Fuck.
Well that can't happen again.
Yeah.
We were thinking about cal and I were
thinking about flying in on Sunday,
but we were schedules didn't permit.
Yeah.
Um,
I would have been that have been great.
next.
Yeah.
Good.
I'm counting on it.
Yeah,
I will.
Next year we're going to manage it.
Alan and I were,
were,
we made a commitment to it.
We were talking about it.
What can we had so much fun two years
ago.
Yeah.
I can't believe we must do what I can to
make sure the weather is not as,
we don't mind shitty weather,
you know,
people ask me,
what was it like with those guys?
They said,
you know,
as,
uh,
that's us.
Yeah.
That's shit on a stick.
Which is still,
I think it's still the number one
mediator viewed huge.
We had so much fun,
man.
It was so fun just hanging out.
Just [inaudible].
I am trying to interject.
So you know,
with conservation was the mood.
It,
it was so fun man.
So fun.
Those,
that's one of the things about these
experiences.
The comradery is almost as important as
the hunting itself.
Like just to have a bunch of guys
hanging out,
having a good time,
uh,
on your farm.
And,
and this,
you have such a beautiful piece of land
that when we're talking about earlier
that we use the term driftless.
Um,
and what that means is that this is the
area where the glaciers passed over.
They didn't go through this area.
So you have beautiful rolling hills and
people think of Wisconsin as being like
sort of a flat area,
which it is and some songs.
Yeah.
But where you guys are at,
it's amazing.
It's fucking gorgeous.
So much wildlife to Turk do.
We saw Turkeys,
we saw,
we almost hit a Turkey on her way to the
airport.
There's three of them,
big ones.
That would,
uh,
that would have messed up our day.
I mean,
I don't know if we'd have made it,
made it,
we would have made it,
I would have knocked the glass out.
We would put our goggles on.
We would have drilled,
we wouldn't be here.
Don't worry about us.
Part of the reason I got the fire in the
belly,
dude,
you said that goes on and drive all the
way.
They can't take out your windshield
though,
right?
Birds,
man.
So,
uh,
so we had such a good time with that.
And uh,
I think when Helen and Brittany,
who were a beginner hunters,
they wanted to have that experience
similar to what you and Brian had in
Montana.
Well,
you know,
we don't take it easy on us because
we're,
you know,
whatever women or whatever it happens to
be.
And I would not take it easy on either
one of those two for any reason,
because they're just there.
They're bad ass
swimming.
Helen's addicted to Jujitsu.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
She's been doing Jujitsu with Anthony,
with the Tony Bourdain.
They've been going fucking crazy.
She takes it all the time.
She's lost a ton of weight.
She looks fantastic.
Yup.
You know,
uh,
so we did a very similar thing,
although this time,
if you recall when you guys were there,
we had these blind set up.
They were like pop up lines and stuff.
So,
uh,
Steve says,
you know,
I think we have to have them do ground
blinds and you know how hard that was
when we were inside those blinds and
they didn't really offer any heat or
anything.
So it made complete sense.
Well,
we built these beautiful blinds.
I'm the one that Steve built will be
there after the
apocalypse.
You guys built them while you were
there?
Yeah.
Okay.
Do just get some plywood.
Oh No,
no,
no.
Just with what was there.
I mean of course
Steve had to take some wire and baler
twine and stuff along and Brittany and I
just went off where I was.
I,
we'll just pull stuff together and kind
of make them,
how many days did you do this for?
The blinds?
Oh,
a couple hours.
One afternoon.
Okay.
So like you say,
well what was there,
you mean like wood and yeah.
You know,
uh,
branches from trees and,
and uh,
you know,
and that sort of stuff,
stuff that was just laying around.
And what did you do with the one that I
got that I bought it yet.
Oh,
that's up on a up,
we call it shit on a stick.
Right.
So what did that area's called now?
Oh yeah.
You know,
well we named them all.
So I put for a round bales on end and
then I set,
set it up on top of it.
Actually the second day I went up there
with my camera man and sat and uh,
it didn't make the show thankfully,
but uh,
I will admit on the year that I took a
shot at a deer and just cleaned Mr and I
tell you,
I spent a couple hours at African him
cause I just couldn't believe I missed.
Well you did.
Well when we were there I fell and
fucked up my rifle scope.
Remember?
And you actually helped me cite it back
in because I didn't know that was,
um,
I had an issue with the scope being
loose and it was set in whoever said it
in.
Um,
just because we change scopes,
I had a leopold and we put a vortex on
and when we changed the scope,
unfortunately it wasn't done right.
And there's something,
so just some steps weren't taken to
secure it correctly and you float on it
real hard on it.
That hard man.
Cause I was,
that was off man.
It was off bad.
Yeah.
Like more than a foot or close to a foot
at a hundred,
you know,
a hundred yards.
Well I wish I had that excuse.
I just cleaned miss that deer.
It was,
I was a polk.
I mean,
but she was standing still many a yards,
about 400 yards.
It was a political,
but I had a long fucking shot man.
Uh,
and uh,
I just,
I cleaned,
missed it.
Now do you use one of those,
um,
ranch phone calculator apps where like
you have to like figure out like how far
it is,
the velocity of your gun,
you know,
what are you're shooting at 30 odd sex?
I actually,
I had a,
um,
a savage three windmills.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
They thought for me to,
Oh yeah.
Savage is the sponsor of the show now,
right?
Yes.
Excellent guns.
Oh,
wonderful family.
Wonderful.
So that special trigger to like,
that's like the one step two step
process.
So they have a very light trigger,
but it won't go off accidentally.
And it was,
you know,
the rifle was dead nuts and should say
these guys I know about this stuff
because of Steve and now his podcast,
it's called the mediator podcast,
which I talked him into doing and now
he's a,
now he's addicted to it too.
Yeah,
it's a great fun.
Great.
It's a great podcast.
He's so good at it.
Yeah.
You had the guys from vortex on there
talking about different things and I
learned a lot that day.
Um,
so anyway,
I cleaned mist and,
um,
I know I've talked about this before and
maybe the podcast and I've,
I said I've never regretted shot that I
didn't
take.
And Steve's like really,
um,
cause you know,
incredulous about most of the things
that I say,
but at most things everybody said,
well,
he challenges you,
that's for sure.
But I,
I took that shot and I kind of regretted
it because it was a long poker.
It was a rifle that wasn't my rifle.
I would make that shot with my own,
but right over her back and she ducked
in the whole thing and I was sure I hit
her.
I went down there,
did she jump The gun?
Like did she drop down?
Zynga Virbac
uh,
and uh,
and we watched it,
my camera man and I kept watching it on
the thing and so I went right down to
the spot where I marked exactly where
the spot was.
We had snow and everything and um,
I just cleaned,
missed and,
and it was a shot that in retrospect,
that kind of wish I wouldn't have taken,
especially with what was happening right
then deer,
we're starting to come to the field and
all that.
But anyway,
and the point was,
it was from that blind that you sent me
after that,
that hunting.
So that's where it lives is up there on
top of the lid.
It's a great spot.
You'll love it when you see it.
Um,
have you ever seen those bail blinds
that are,
they look like a bale of Hay.
You sneaky go inside them and you're
like,
Hey,
can you actually me?
And we've actually made,
I've just,
Oh,
we used to make some cozy blinds,
you know,
my old man would,
uh,
he'd take three,
four round bales and then you put a
little cover on top and you're on there.
Toasty.
I missed out on the biggest buck
opportunity in my life because my old
man let me get out of chores in the
morning.
He said,
you go out in that blind,
he's like,
me and your brother are going to kick
one out of the swamp.
10 o'clock rolls around and I'm so cozy
and I'm passed out and uh,
all sudden they're here.
My old man,
he's like,
what are you doing?
I get up.
I'm like,
what?
He's like,
don't you see that thing?
I'm like,
Oh,
I was too small and I can't remember
what he was calling.
He was,
he had a name for it and he's just like,
that was,
you know,
swampy and Oh my God.
And I've never,
never,
well I didn't sound asleep.
It was a soft trying to make an excuse.
See all my old man,
I never lived that down with my old man
cause I was such a,
and we've,
we were watching that guy,
you got to shine in at night.
You ever been shining?
No.
You need,
if you need to do that.
Sometimes it's not like moonshine and
strong light
and shine the deer that are out in the
field just to cut your monitor where
they're at and yeah.
Well isn't that,
well,
that's where what people use for
poaching,
right?
Yeah.
To do.
You don't have guns and here we can't do
it during season,
but it's legal.
Oh,
you can't do it during the rifle season
during hunting season.
No,
that's right.
It ends at a certain date.
Well,
anyway,
um,
but what we did,
because the other problem with those
blinds,
as you might remember,
is pretty damn crowded in them and they
actually sell,
uh,
blind now called shadow her blind,
which is a different other gray.
Yeah.
Um,
and so I have a few of those around.
and,
and there,
there are great,
but we couldn't,
it didn't make sense to do that.
We had too many people and you know,
the filming thing.
So we built a little blinds for four
people,
you know,
two people,
202 cameramen,
but they weren't insulated then.
Ho they sure weren't.
And the day before while you were there,
you know what happened?
It was beautiful at the end before we
were out squirrel hunting in the morning
just,
and these girls were shooting squirrels,
man.
It just wait til you see this,
uh,
that they did such a great job.
They were so much fun and they were just
so incredible squirrel,
murderers and,
and they just like you and Brian,
man,
they,
they got it and they cleaned them.
They did the whole thing,
you know,
uh,
to the point where,
I think Helen was maybe a little
regretful that she had,
uh,
well they had three deer to,
if they broke down completely by
themselves,
did they?
Um,
did everybody shoot a deer?
Was everybody's successful
buddy?
But the guy who hosted it,
you,
yeah.
Oh man,
that's crazy.
You got a big one last year,
right?
Yeah.
I got a nice one last year and I,
I,
I filled the freezer this year later on,
you know,
the season goes on.
What,
what are the,
okay,
keep going.
This,
Oh,
I'm sorry.
Well,
so we did much the same.
We set up and,
and uh,
it was really interesting way to marine
sniper trainer.
If Steve,
uh,
Noah's,
he's from actually from our area there.
He came in and talked to us about
shooting a little bit and you know,
specifically for,
for Helen and Brittany and,
uh,
I'm just so proud of those two,
you know,
they take it so seriously as,
as seriously as you and Brian did.
Okay.
You take it really seriously and Brian
always took it seriously when he needed
to take it seriously.
Um,
and uh,
very into it,
very,
uh,
respectful,
wanting to know about and all that.
And we,
I hope that,
I think it comes out in the episodes,
you know,
I'm so close to it.
I can't,
I can't necessarily say,
but we are very successful.
Well,
I don't want to spoil it for everybody,
but yeah,
there were,
we put,
we put some deer on the ground and um,
and they,
they did a terrific job.
Um,
and I think it makes for compelling,
uh,
for a compelling,
Yup.
That show's always awesome.
Um,
what I wanted to ask you is,
with all the wildlife that you have in
your area,
what,
what are the seasons?
I mean,
I know you have more than one season of
deer.
So when does the season started?
There's an archery season first.
Yeah.
Archery season starts ones.
Uh,
September 15th or the second Saturday in
September.
How many archer?
Do you have a lot of archery hunt
hunters come out there?
Yeah.
A lot
on our place.
No,
no,
but I'd be happy to have one or two.
I don't even like rifle hunting that
much anymore.
Um,
well the thing about archery hunting for
deer in our area is,
you know,
it's a very well,
but you've learned all this to hunt with
cam is it's,
they've got to be closer and I don't
care how many of them there are,
they've got to be close and they've got
to come in.
You're going to spend some time out
there and not much is going on.
But our archery season coincides with
the first part of November,
end of October,
first partner in November where the pre
rutten rod is going on.
So there's a lot of deer activity.
And so there are,
um,
you know,
you can call and you can use sense and
all that stuff and they're coming in.
As you know,
it's a completely different relationship
with the animal.
We actually have crossbow hunting.
Uh,
now you can use a crossbow,
not along Boeing personally.
That's what I use.
Um,
that's cheating.
Yeah,
whatever.
Oh,
that's not archery.
That's a shitty gun.
It doesn't fucking scope on it.
Sure does.
It sure does.
Cravings of magnification scope.
You put the crosshair on,
you pull the trigger,
you'd sit in on arrest,
you can rest it down like a candidate
that is not archery,
God it and drink beer.
While you're doing that,
you can,
you could smoke,
shoot heroin,
shoot things.
Well,
you don't have to practice with them
much at all.
And uh,
and it is certainly different than
shooting a rifle.
Um,
I'm comfortable that 50 or 60 yards with
a crossbow.
Yeah.
And I know people can shoot further in
it.
And then I just,
ethically I just,
I'm just not interested in that.
But I am interested in,
I don't have a boy of Cam was here.
He,
you know,
dragged me outside or maybe you will.
I say that that bow hunting is for
people who don't have enough to do in
that.
It's true that it takes so much time to
be an ethical bow hunter.
You're talking about gun was shot 200
arrows today.
Yeah.
I shot all day to day.
I had a weight representative come to my
house and we're,
we're shooting era.
I have a whole three d setup in my yard.
Yeah.
Shooting a rubber elk all day to day.
My arms are sore.
Yeah.
You have to be an asshole.
Well,
you have to be committed to it.
Yes.
And yes.
I,
the hardest thing for me during that
time of the year on the farm is to sit
in a tree and wait for a deer to come
by.
Um,
I've got all of these other things that
I need to be doing that during that
period of time,
not at my,
at my work and in Madison or something
like that,
but on that farm.
So I'm actually moving a little bit more
towards in,
during archery season is because I've
not had a whole lot of archery and we've
had a couple of guys over the years.
But to start the host people come home
cause I'm gonna be there anyway.
I might be partaking in it and myself.
Well that's my,
that's actually more attractive to me
then even coming on an opening day now.
How long does the uh,
archery season last until the 1st of
January.
Til the 1st of January.
So it goes straight through.
Well you can,
yeah,
you can bow hunt during the gun season.
So I could have come down and bow hunted
when those girls were shooting
squirrels.
I could have bow hunted.
Yes.
And when they were shooting deer,
you could have bow hunted.
You just had to wear orange jacket
rather than the camouflage.
But before that I could work cammo yeah.
So I could,
I could,
uh,
I could archery,
hunt and then bail and then take off
right before.
Hmm.
Oh that's,
it's end of October.
The first part,
November.
Uh,
when the,
the act of rod is going on,
that's,
that's the time.
What's,
what's the deal with a black powder?
Is that still separate?
That's after.
After everything.
After the gun season.
So then it lasted black
power.
Black power.
I'm just kidding.
[inaudible]
people know we're talking about,
we're talking
about muzzle loaders.
Yeah.
For some strange fucking reason.
It's okay to use a primitive,
stupid weapon that you should never use
in real life.
You put a ball and you pack the powder
in like you're living in the fucking 18
hundreds.
Can you shoot this stupid thing?
The,
and the thing,
here's the thing about muskets.
This is the weird thing about them.
They're real fucking accurate now.
Like real accurate to like 200 yards.
So they're basically a rifle that you
can't make a good ethical followup shot
on.
I don't like,
I get it old.
Not only that,
you shoot in this fucking giant cloud of
smoke in front of me.
I don't know what happened.
Boom.
Where's the animal?
I don't know.
Did he hit it low?
Fucking,
I dunno.
Well,
there'd be plenty of people who are
going to,
you're going to hear it from the Congo.
I know.
I listened.
It's,
it is definitely more accurate and
better than a bow,
but my point is use a fucking gun.
Like why?
If you're shooting one of those things
and it's accurate to several hundred
yards,
I know people that have shot a deer at
250 yards with a musket,
so with a muzzle loader,
when you're getting to that kind of a
distance,
like what does that really,
well,
you're got a rifle to shitty rifle.
If you're talking about a bow,
if you shot something at 200 yards,
you're basically closing your eyes and
shooting up at the sun.
You know who the fuck knows where that
Arrow is going?
You're shooting 250 yards,
both a musket or a muzzle loader.
You can put the crosshair on that thing.
You can accurately judge just like he
came with a rifle.
The problem is it takes you like 15 to
20 seconds to reload as opposed to just
going straight.
If you're,
if you want to make a followup shot with
a rifle,
you know,
or there's a lot of people now that are
hunting with semiautomatics,
whether you're going Pang,
Pang,
you can shoot a deer three times in two
seconds.
I'll think about the black potters.
You've got to have your bayonet for the
finish.
That's the civil war.
Then you're on the run.
Do you have to have a flint?
It hits the thing.
It makes us Johnny Reb,
yeah.
Everybody has their preference
thing on my or my family's farm.
You know,
I'm the captain and the captain gets to
decide what happens.
Yeah.
And um,
um,
and so,
you know,
and,
and it's like,
oh,
this is the way it's going to be.
I'm not absolute about anything.
You know,
over time things kind of ebb and flow
and change and,
and uh,
you know,
for me,
well,
I still want to,
I want to be out there in that first
part of that first part of November.
I don't have to practice everyday I k
camp where I live.
I don't have to become a,
and I readily admit it.
I,
you know,
I have an old hoyt,
um,
and uh,
I liked the bowl and I'll shoot it once
in a while,
but man,
20 yards about it where I feel like I
can make an ethical shot.
Dare you,
we need to get you a new hood.
What year?
What year or do you have
man,
I'd have to check with Shane.
That guy bought it from,
it was,
I bought it from him used cause he was
upgraded
in the 60s.
Like one of them bamboo ones.
Fucking a,
I think it's like a mid eighties,
maybe a late eighties.
Laundry wheels for fucking laundry.
Yeah.
Uh,
mid eighties for real.
mid to late eighties.
Maybe it was early nineties.
I'm sure I'll hear.
She was a slingshot.
Do you have any rocks you going bro?
Fuck.
Are you doing man
spear?
Just jump on the tree.
It's just not my,
uh,
my priority and,
and,
and I have a lot of ways,
I have a lot of respect for bow hunters
who spend the time to become that
proficient at it.
And then you end up spending a lot of
time whitetail hunting.
I are is,
there's guys who spent a lot of time
doing that.
And like I said,
I just don't,
I totally understand.
I'm totally bust your balls.
It's not something that I would add.
I don't think anybody should do it.
How about that?
I'll go hunting.
It's too much work and it's too
addictive.
It just,
and forget about bow hunting.
If I never hunt again for the rest of my
life.
Archery is massively addictive.
I love it.
I'm,
I'm shooting,
I shoot every day.
It's so much fun to me.
It's a,
it's a nice peaceful like meditation
type of a thing.
But they have like ranges out here.
Yeah,
yeah.
There's a bunch.
Yeah,
there's a bunch.
There's a,
a big one off of a,
the two 10.
So she's fucking huge long distance
range.
But I think that,
um,
it's a,
it's a nice meditation.
It's nice to do,
but when it comes to compound bows,
man is really the difference between of
both from the 1980s and a modern like
2016 hoyt defiant.
He might as well be shooting a mosque.
It versus like a modern savage arms
rifle.
It's not that much difference.
Yeah.
I mean the,
the,
the real,
the amount of power that these things
have now and the speed in which they
shoot arrows and the accuracy.
There's so much technology and
engineering going into bose,
it's really kind of amazing because it's
one of the few pieces of hunting
equipment that literally changes and
improves every year.
Couldn't sell.
We think about that when I hear these,
uh,
the bowhunting purist friends who are
just cackling right now about you giving
me shit about,
about bow hunting,
which is great.
They're going,
well this is a real purist.
The thing I'm a pussy because he,
he's a compound bows.
They recur cause they like not being
accurate at all.
They're like,
they're like fucking hoping they hit
shit.
Sorry.
I can,
they're there.
They get mad at me right now.
Full
shoot a real bowl man with you of going
make it yourself.
Get some leather.
The last animal.
Your shot.
Wrap it around your fingers.
I actually think that Steve was talking
about on this upcoming butchery one
about how he was taking,
how they used to take the silver skin
off of meat and they'd get the long
strips of it and that's what they made
their bow string trains with.
Yeah.
Sinew.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
You should dry it out and roll it and
turn it into,
I mean,
did you see his thing from um,
uh,
w when he was in the jungle?
Was it Borneo?
Where the fuck did he go?
Bolivia.
Yeah.
God Damn,
that was an amazing show.
Two part episode.
Yeah.
They went to Bolivia and the traditional
bows,
those guys use to kill animals.
They had these really heavy,
really long arrows and these stick bows
that they had made themselves
and he showed up with a hoyt carbon
spider and he's drilling.
Yeah.
There's,
there's the,
uh,
balls of these guys had,
well,
look at that errol.
Yeah.
That's what I'm talking about.
They had these really long,
really heavy arrows and notice how
there's no fledglings on the Arrow and
he's got the followup Arrow right there
in his hand.
Yeah.
Yeah,
they keep them in their hands.
And I remember on this episode how he
struggled to,
uh,
hit the fish because the,
how the water reflect the Arrow and
these guys,
you're just nailing them when after,
and it's not just that,
it's not the water deflecting.
It's the image.
It looks different.
The fish is actually,
it could be as much as six inches lower
than what you think.
Ah.
Cause the refraction in the water from
your looking down,
it almost like a lens.
So it's like distorted where the actual
fish is.
So if you shot right at the fish,
he would never hit it.
Yeah.
You have to shoot like below it.
It's real weird.
You ever,
do you ever see the,
the ones that people use in America?
The,
it's like a trident.
Yeah.
It's like a big,
you know,
they're your,
you're kind of making up for that.
You know,
you got some more,
we have all these prongs and they shoot
these arrows that like they split when
they're doing sturgeon.
The shocks.
Well,
we,
uh,
when I was a kid,
we used to shoot carp up at the end of
the lake and,
but there is the sh waters real shallow
and they'd go up there and just raise
hell and their backs,
it'd be out of the water.
So you'd be dealing with it,
right,
right.
Yeah.
I used to live near Lake Charles in
Boston and there was a area by the
waterfall with the carpet pool up and it
was incredible.
I mean,
you're looking at like these 20,
30 pound fish and there's dozens of them
just stacked together and you see him on
the surface of the water,
you know,
but it's a junk fish to us,
but a delicacy to people in the UK and
in Asia.
It's very interesting.
Like what one person?
Yeah,
one person decides it's a good fish and
then in the,
you know,
and the problem was they were an
invasive species and a lot of the North
American rivers and lakes and people
don't like them for whatever silly
reason,
but there are very good fish to eat
apparently.
If you prepare it properly,
you can say,
you know,
a lot of things.
I mean you're,
one of the things about grass fed beef
is um,
you know,
a lot of times it doesn't have the fat.
So I mean,
you got to know how to cook it.
You can't overcook it.
Right.
That's a big point.
I mean,
you can say about any kind of meat.
people fuck up a really good piece of
meat,
you know?
Well,
especially if a real lean piece of deer,
venison,
elk or something like that.
Moose,
same thing mean you what you want to
barely like singe the outside of it
almost.
And just,
and you know,
and knowing like how to prepare it as a
big part of the responsibility of
hunting.
You know,
you don't want to have this meat that
you've got from this animal and you have
so much reverence for the death of this
animal and then you just prepare it like
an asshole.
Like you have to put almost as much
thought into the cooking.
It's one of the things I really love
about Rinella show.
Yes sir.
Like the episode that I watched last
night about that mule deer that
he shot this enormous dear,
was it really focused on at the end of
it,
how we prepared it.
You know,
he showed you how to prepare it and how
to cook it properly and how you can tell
when it's done and all this different
stuff.
And Neil,
he'll go through the butchering process.
We'll go through the cooking process and
that's something,
a lot of these shows they don't even
touch man.
They get the dear luke at him.
He's a real Iowa giant and they take a
picture with this animal.
They show the antlers.
Look at his fourth son is fifth and Brow
Tine is sticking up black pass or don't
intend the tower during the tower down
in Texas.
Yeah,
well there's a lot of that,
a lot of donating,
a lot of donating and this is,
I suppose that's a good thing,
but yes,
it is a good thing.
But there's also shows where they're
pretend,
you know,
we're out here hunting and you know,
you gotta use fucking piles of corn out
there,
whether you're waiting for these animals
to come to and you're,
you know,
you just kind of shooting at these spots
where,
you know,
they're gonna be,
isn't that,
that's always an interesting part of any
discussion about hunting,
about,
you know,
where the ethical lines yes.
Because guys will say,
well,
we cause baiting is illegal by us
because of a chronic wasting disease.
Um,
when you put a pilot corn out there
exchanging saliva and that's how they,
that's how it spread.
That's interesting cause,
but you guys do have some deer farms,
which is where people think the origins
of chronic wasting disease or from,
yeah.
I heard an interesting,
uh,
discussion about that recently and one
of the things they talked about is that
there were these protein blocks being
put out and that may have been there.
They've never,
uh,
there've been a few different ideas of
where it came from.
And,
um,
one is,
uh,
from the deer farms and other is these
protein blacks that maybe got put out
and it's got an animal byproduct in it.
And maybe that's how it,
so is it like a prime thing?
Is it something that's exactly what it
is,
is a priority.
So it's similar to mad cow disease.
That's exactly right.
Oh,
so would that have come?
I don't know.
Um,
you know,
and I've even heard it said that,
um,
there are places where they were and
tried to improve the genetics of the
deer herd.
So they were bringing in,
you know,
bigger bucks and releasing him.
I don't have any proof of any of it.
So those,
that could be the case that they are,
they are very concerned with people that
release these animals from these farms
out.
But there's some fucking place,
like I got contacted by this guy,
hey man,
come hawn tent my place.
And then I looked at his instagram page
and I'm like,
that's not even a fucking cage.
Well,
it,
I don't know.
I don't want to talk shit because,
uh,
I,
you know,
I don't know this guy.
I don't know why,
but it's a high fund fence operation.
Um,
I don't even want to say what state it
is,
but these are,
they're barely deer.
There are these,
these deer that have these fucking
bushes growing out of their heads.
Yeah.
If you see what their antlers look like,
you're like,
okay,
that's not even real.
Have you get Jamie pull,
pull up this a ridiculous antlers in a
deer farm.
Oh,
they,
they're growing these animals and their
trophy trophy.
Do you call them trophies?
But essentially they're manipulating the
genetics of these animals so that they
have all these antlers.
So these are rich assholes can go and
shoot these things and like this hundred
acre fenced in area where they're
letting these animals out of their
pants,
like look,
see,
what is that?
What are we looking at here for one
reason,
which is free.
So you could put that on your wall.
I'm sure you could kill it and it would
taste just like a regular deer.
I'm sure they're delicious and they
probably,
but look at this man.
So they're growing these insane antlers
via supplemental feeding them
supplements and feeding them this shit
that makes their like antler steroids
that makes their antlers grow.
They don't look like antlers,
Matt.
It looks like two.
Yeah,
like all nut.
Like Doug said,
we were talking about this.
It's criminal.
I mean Doug's very strong opinion and
needed about that.
I mean that's what's critical here.
Be Careful
Cajun.
Oh Man.
Cajun Amanda.
And then having a three,
you know,
300 acres isn't that big.
And you've got this 300 acres cage,
you know,
that's not hunting fish in a barrel.
That's fish in a barrel.
I said earlier with that on 40 acres.
That's where that that you're true.
But you know what?
You could live that,
leave that 40 acres warning if he wants
to.
And that's a big part coming to a bait
pile or any of that stuff.
You know,
that's where it part of ethics.
Right.
And I figured him out.
Yeah.
And I guess that's where I was getting
to is you know where those lines are.
Well,
this is the hunting that I grew up with.
I never,
I've never hunted,
uh,
outside the Midwest.
I really only hunted outside of our farm
twice.
Why have a friend who hunted in Texas at
a ranch that has 10,000 acres fence?
Den.
I'm like bolts as far as I'm concerned.
Those are wild animals.
10,000 acres.
Yeah.
I mean there's not a fucking animal on
earth that's going to travel that far
other than a mule deer.
There's not,
they're not an animal on earth is going
to migrate further than that and it's
lifetime.
You essentially have this gigantic
fenced in habitat and their idea about
it is,
look,
we can manage the wildlife,
sustainable wildlife inside.
We're not feeding them anything they
live off is,
but we're just keeping people out.
We're not keeping the animals in,
keeping people out.
I'm like,
okay,
I can buy that song.
I think,
yeah.
Is that a lot in this eye line of the
song?
The put up the fence fucking music out
or all the new showroom.
Oh
God was here.
He tell it to your face.
Manage some kind of sin.
Says hippies though,
that's hippies you want to fucking get
on your land.
By the way,
I hear that the bit where they're like,
ah,
the part about the sign,
the sign said,
um,
anybody caught trespassing will be shot
on sight.
You know,
it's,
it's like a radio bit,
you know,
and then,
and then it ends.
That's the end of the song.
It's a complicated business.
It's a complicated business and these
ethical lines,
uh,
are difficult.
Uh,
it's something that you have to think
about.
It's something you have to talk about
and we'll be willing to teach your mind
sometimes to a baiting bears is a big
dog.
Baiting bears is a big one because,
uh,
there's a lot of places where the only
way,
especially in the spring,
you're ever going to kill a bears if you
bait.
So they,
to control the population
of these barriers because the bears are
killing Moose.
They're killing calves.
Uh,
they're killing Fonz from deere,
the killing all sorts of things.
And they're killing cubs.
They're killing each other.
I mean,
the bears are killing machines.
So when they have these in environments
where they have to control the
population and they allow baiting,
the reason why they allow baiting is to
make a successful hunt.
And recently I think in Maine it was,
I don't know if they passed it,
but they were trying to pass no baiting
on bears.
And the reason why they were doing it is
cause anti hunting.
People were trying to stop people from
hunting bear.
So the way they would essentially make a
hunt completely ineffective was saying
no baiting.
So cause as soon as you can't bait find
them,
yeah.
You're not gonna have any success.
You don't have,
you don't find any success.
Yeah,
no.
I have friends who live in Michigan and
they were telling me,
listen man,
you could go a fucking decade without
seeing a bear in the woods.
Meanwhile they're everywhere.
Yeah.
You just don't find them.
You go near him that you hear the,
they hear a snap and twitter.
Like this guy.
Yeah.
And they
so quiet.
It's pads.
It's one of the weirdest thing about
bear hunting is when you're out there
and you're waiting,
they walk,
you know,
like you stand by like a trail where you
know the head by,
you'll see one before you hear it.
Like they'll just be right there.
You're like,
oh shit,
he's right there.
They're just so God damn quiet.
Amazing.
That's such a big animal.
It could be so quiet and slippers on
their feet.
They have slippers.
Yeah,
I mean the pads.
Vera touched the bear's pads.
It's weird man.
And it's designed to creep up on Shit,
you know?
I mean,
that's why cats have them too.
They have those pads at the bottom of
their feet.
They,
why don't they have hooves hooves?
Be Better.
Yeah.
Well hooves back too much.
No,
you can't be jacking chant with all
that.
Nice.
So they come creeping up on you.
But they're like little ghosts,
man.
Weird cats and bears.
They're ghosts pad slipper wearing
fucking ghosts.
No.
Oh,
good stuff.
Listen,
I think,
I think we're done.
I think we should wrap this pitch up and
bring it home.
Um,
so there's a lot of fun,
man.
Thank you.
Absolutely.
I appreciate it.
I would say a little bit about,
yeah,
thank you very much.
And to steal a line from Ray Wylie
Hubbard,
the days I keep my gratitude higher than
my expectations are really good days and
today is about as good a day as you
could get.
Well I really enjoyed it.
I appreciate you guys flying out here
and doing this and I'm glad we could
have this conversation and you know,
get,
get your perspective on things because I
think a lot of people have a,
you know,
listeners continue the discussion man
can never stop learning.
That's what it's all about really.
I mean this is all about just trying to
figure out other people's perspectives
and together work together,
man.
It came man,
stay the fuck off doug's land.
You hippies.
Yeah.
Alright guys,
we'll be back tomorrow with a great
boss.
Rutan and moral Rinaldo should be a lot
of fun.
And then on Friday,
robin black,
my pal Robyn and then on a Sunday night
fight companion.
All right,
so we'll see you soon.
Much love friends.
That was cool.