Yes.
That's almost start everything from now
on.
Yes.
Like Diego Sanchez style.
Uh,
what's up folks?
How are you guys?
Good.
How are you doing?
Thank you for coming here.
Really appreciate it.
I'm doing good at it.
An answer your question.
It's one of those questions,
you know.
Hey,
what's up man?
What's up man?
Like neither one answers,
but it's acceptable for whatever reason.
We've got to change that.
We've going to change a lot of things.
Documentary freaking the fuck out.
Let's talk about it.
Cowspiracy um,
if you haven't seen it,
pause as podcasts.
Go to Netflix.
It's only on Netflix.
I tried to find on apple TV and I was
like,
what?
Only netflix.
Netflix continues to kill it.
Um,
but your,
your,
uh,
your documentary is very scary.
It's one of those documentary suite.
You can look at a lot of documentaries
and go,
well,
there's a bias in this documentary and
these guys,
you know,
they're thinking that,
uh,
the,
the negative aspects of this outweigh
the positive aspects of it.
But it's debatable when you look at your
documentary.
It's one of those things where you go
like,
I shut it off after it was over.
It was like one o'clock in the morning.
I was getting ready to go to bed,
which is not a good idea to plan the
fucking rest of your life.
Think about the future of the world,
FTC,
a documentary like yours.
Uh,
and I'm sitting there going,
well,
there's nothing.
He's not much.
You can say like when you look at the
devastation that's being done with
livestock in this country,
when you look soberly,
look at it soberly,
look at the numbers.
He's soberly look at the amount of land
they need to graze.
You soberly look at the amount of people
that we smoosh into these little areas
where we don't grow shit and we call
them cities and we have to truck
everything in.
When you soberly look at the amount of
methane that's being reduced but
produced by cow shit and cow farts,
and then the reaction that you guys got
when you tried to bring up that aspect
of it,
that was the weirdest part of your
documentary.
I expected going in that the documentary
would sort of highlight some issues that
people have already with factory farming
and show you,
you know,
what effect it had on the environment.
I didn't anticipate it would be that
much of an effect and I didn't
anticipate the,
you would get the kind of resistance
that you got from activists,
activists that are scared of that
industry.
You know,
what was it like making that documentary
that was actually more to the Mo,
more of the motivation was that these
environmental groups,
the greenpeaces reinforce section that
work,
uh,
Sierra Club that they didn't address
this issue was more of inspiration to
make the film and pissed us off to the
point of making the film more than the
actual facts themselves.
And the facts are so overwhelming when I
found them out,
but the fact that they didn't talk about
this,
I like,
I felt,
you know,
betrayed and,
and then,
then,
you know,
once I started calling them,
it became really kind of off.
This is kip Andersen talking,
by the way.
And Keegan Kuhn is the other gentlemen
to his right.
Um,
you know,
to me,
I kind of liking it a little there.
They're scared.
They're obviously scared this or they're
complicit is one of two things,
right?
Either they're scared or they're taking
money from these environmental groups
could be both.
Right.
And another one.
And also they're contributing to it and
they imagine you're the America.
That's what it meant when I said taking
money from these environmental groups.
I switched around,
I met the environmental groups are
taking money from that industry.
And also to imagine you're the American
Lung Association and you're sitting
around board of director meetings,
you all smoking cigarettes and then
you're telling somebody not smoke
cigarettes.
And that's a huge part of it.
We,
we walked in a couple organizations
groups during lunch and here they're,
you know,
they're in front of like a
slaughterhouse eating their lunch and
they're discussing how to say the rain
forest and it's like,
wait,
while we connect your connection here,
they're eating burgers and shit.
Talks about the rain forest.
Um,
you know,
another thing that really disturbed me
about your documentary was when that
gentleman who was a former cattle
rancher was talking about his,
his being sued and how the industry sued
him and he'd gotten some real deep legal
trouble,
cost him a ton of money.
But how now today with the Patriot Act,
he would have never won the case because
it doesn't matter if you're correct now.
Now if you have an action,
like you make a documentary,
you do something that adversely affects
that industry or any industry where they
can prove they're losing money by the
Patriot Act,
your league,
you're legally complicit or you legally
guilty.
Right?
Isn't that how it works?
Yeah.
Well so there is a law created call the
Animal Enterprise Terrorism Act and it
was focused on just animal rights
activists and environmental rights
activist and it,
yeah,
the law says anyone who disrupts the
business of an animal enterprise is
committing an act of terrorism.
Jesus fucking Christ.
That's scary,
right?
I mean cause then that goes,
it's so far reaching.
That's from someone who saves one
chicken from a farm or someone who does
a protest or I mean there's three
activists up in the bay who are arrested
under the law for doing passing out
leaflets and doing chalk outlines on
sidewalks.
It's just crazy.
Total violation of first amendment
that's so,
so
fucking wrong.
It's so wrong and so dangerous when you
let an industry just dictate just by
sheer money what people can and can't
protest feet deep things that people
find morally reprehensible.
There's a reason why there's these ag
gag laws.
What ag gag laws,
if you're not aware,
if you listen to this,
there's laws against taking film footage
of those pigs that are shoved into those
cages and chicken shoved into cages and
cruelty to animals.
If you've ever watched any of those
disturbing,
uh,
videos at p to puts up,
well,
they'll show like a guy like sheering
wool and kicking the shit out of the
lamb.
It's fucking,
it's hard to watch,
man.
It's,
it's weird.
Or is it a sheep or lamb?
Lamb was a young one,
right?
Is that what what it is?
Yeah.
These guys like you think,
Oh,
I'm wearing,
whoa,
it's just a,
they just give him a haircut.
Bullshit.
They beat the fuck out of those things
because those things don't want a
haircut and they're,
they bleed and cause they're not gentle
with those sheers.
Oh,
obviously I don't know if it's just one
time that they filmed this and it's just
one asshole.
But there's laws against filming those
things now.
So the only way that that ever stops,
the only way people ever go,
hey man,
I'm only gonna eat free range this or
grass fed.
That.
The only way that happens ever as you
have to know what the consequences of
not doing that are,
you have to know if you off,
you're buying this factory raised meat.
This is how it lives.
Are you cool with that?
Most people are not cool with that.
So instead of fixing it and making it
better,
they make it illegal to report all this
unethical,
fucked up dark shit they're doing the
animals that is,
that's so fucking anti-american.
It at every level.
Yeah.
But I mean that's shows how powerful
this industry is.
It literally can dictate to the
government what they want the laws to
be.
Cause Yeah.
The yag lost dump benefit consumers in
any way.
They are completely written by the
industry themselves.
Those motherfuckers need to take
mushrooms.
All those people that are involved in
those chicken farms and pig farms to the
cows just grow some please.
You do.
You don't understand.
I understand they're making a fuck load
of money.
I get it.
They don't want to stop making a fuck
load of money.
But the idea that that's all you have to
do is just have so much money coming in
that you can get away with this.
How is that any different than like
animal beastiality?
How's it any different than animal
torture?
Like animal torture is illegal.
If like Michael Vick got in trouble
because he was shooting his dogs and
killing him,
how has that really different than the
way they treat pigs?
As I say,
you know the,
at least the dogs had a chance,
you know,
these animals had no chance at all.
You know those dogs?
Yeah.
Like I guess a dogs have a chance.
I mean,
the thing about pit bulls is the real,
the ones they use for fighting,
they breed them to not have any animal
aggression.
You could beat the shit out of them.
They don't fight back then they're bred
to never sort of go after people.
It's very weird.
Anyway,
that doesn't beside the point.
The point is this,
this industry has so much fucking money
that they're able to do something that I
think pretty much everybody would
disagree with and that stop you from
letting people be aware of the
consequences of their purchase power.
They're buying.
Like if you buy,
you want to buy the cheapest meat,
you want to buy the cheapest meat
possible.
This is how it's grown.
This is,
this is how it's managed.
This is how they bring these things to
slaughter.
Are you comfortable with that thing is
too.
It's not only,
you know,
even if even if you have organic or the
free range or you know all these other
more more than anything in marketing
terms,
they don't let you,
they don't let you in these places as
well as across the board.
I have a friend,
my friend Doug during,
he lives in Wisconsin and he,
oh,
he owns a farm and he has grass fed cows
and uh,
I had one idea of what it's like to be
grass fed cow and then I visited his
farm.
So my idea of what it's like to be a
grass fed cow and he only has a few cows
and it's not a gigantic farms,
a few hundred acres.
And it's,
you know,
it's not his main business.
It's like a family thing that he does
and he grows his own beef.
Those cows are fucking terrified.
If you go in that cage though,
they fucking run.
They run and they bunch up and I,
and I was out there and went,
oh,
they know what the fuck is going on.
And it's not that much space.
I mean,
even if they have a giant pasture,
you obviously have to be able to rope
them in cause you're gonna eventually
kill him and they kind of know it
go anywhere near those fuckers.
You think of it as like those pigs in
your documentary,
those pigs that those people were
raising in northern California,
which were kind of like pets.
They came over and these little kids
were petting them and stuff.
That's not how his cows are.
Cows are fucking running for their life,
and the thing is those cows,
they know,
they know what's going on and they're
only,
they're just,
they're just babies.
You know,
they get killed at 18 months.
Imagine they can live as long as dogs.
Imagine a puppy getting killed at 18
months.
They know what's going on in 18 months
is the grass fed,
no grain fed,
right?
Grass beds even longer.
It's about 24 months because they have
to take some longer to grow.
They're just there.
They're eating their natural diet.
What did we do?
So how'd we get here?
How the fuck did human beings can get to
this position where,
I mean,
I think it's wonderful in terms of our
ability to innovate,
create technology,
educate each other.
You know what I mean?
Wow.
What a,
what a gigantic relief.
It's been to remove the daily necessity
of gathering food.
It's been a gigantic relief and it's
caused the human race to accelerate,
to technologically innovate at a before
never seen pace.
I mean,
what we've been able to do over the last
hundred years,
it's been nothing short of insane,
but the consequences seem to be not
thought out and um,
not planned for and no solution in place
to mitigate it.
Yeah.
And that's the thing is the,
when we talk about population in the
film,
you know,
and was at 19 1800 is one 1 billion,
1901.5 2000 2012,
7 billion just exploded.
And then not only that though,
the necessity to the meat consumption in
dairy consumption and just in the last
50 years.
So a lot of these people have this
notion of,
you know,
the grass fed,
that's where get into and they're
organic,
but they're living in a time where it's
50 years ago,
a hundred years ago,
we're in 2000 now.
16 that's,
it's not a reality.
It's a myth.
There's too many of us,
dammit.
But people are cool.
I like a micron is around a lot around.
It's weird,
you know,
it's,
it's a,
it's such a catch 22 like,
but there's definitely do many of us,
but fuck,
it's awesome having so many people
because having somebody be,
I find uh,
I love like going into a rural areas,
the mountains and stuff like that,
but I think living there I would miss
the amount of people that you get and
like the Los Angeles area,
you get a lot of like really cool
people.
You get the in giant groups you are,
you're more likely to find a large
number of cool people just by sheer
volume just by numbers.
But
fuck man,
that's one thing that's looked at in the
film is that yeah,
they'll,
how do you feed 7.2 billion people and
the only way you're really going to do
it is to eat as ecologically as
possible.
And that's a plant based diet or getting
as close to a plant based diet as she
can.
Yeah.
Well,
it seems like,
like what I like to do,
I grow a lot of my own vegetables and
I've been the last few years I've been
hunting in this year eating,
trying to at least exclusively stuff
that I've killed myself.
But everybody can't do that.
You know,
you can't preach that as an ethic.
You can't,
cause it's just not possible first of
all,
time wise,
not possible for most folks with
families or with jobs.
It's just they just don't have the time
to gather that much meat to feed your
whole family for a year.
If you eat meat,
you know,
three or four days a week,
even you,
you're not going to be able to do it.
And then two,
the other thing is there's just not
enough animals.
There's just not,
there's not enough white tail.
There's more white tailed deer right now
than there have ever been ever in the
history of this continent,
just by management,
by wildlife protection agencies and um,
uh,
go fish and game departments,
making sure that,
you know,
these animals have adequate habitat and
they only take a certain amount per year
and things along those lines.
So there's more whitetail deer than
there have ever been in North America,
but not enough to feed everybody,
not even close,
not even close.
We would kill them all and we would
still be starving.
That's it.
Yeah.
I mean hunting really.
Cause people have brought that up.
They say,
well what about sustainable hunting?
And the truth is that we've replaced
most of the wild animals on the planet
with our domesticated animals and we've
taken the wild animals land and we've
used it to grow feed to feed livestock
or to graze livestock.
And so yeah,
just as you said,
I mean,
we've literally replaced 90% of wildlife
with our own species.
Like what wildlife isn't there anymore?
That was besides obvious ones like
buffalo.
Yeah.
I mean there's the obvious like
megafauna.
Um,
but it's also,
I mean,
you'll have to look at timber wolves.
Eastern timberwolves were basically
wiped out primarily for fur trade and
because they preyed on cattle.
Um,
and so then you have other species that
move in and so you see an explosion of,
for example,
yeah,
whitetail deer.
But that's because we've eliminated all
the other species around them,
laminated all the predators because the
predators are a threat to the livestock.
And so once you eliminate the predators,
now you have all these deer running
around and multiplying,
and then that's where wildlife
management comes in,
which is complete bullshit because we're
true.
Wildlife management is good already
getting ready rid of the cows and
getting rid of all the other wildlife,
all the other wildlife,
wildlife doc,
getting rid of it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So basically what's happening,
just one,
just one year ago,
um,
what was the stats on how many,
oh,
I mean,
US Department of Agriculture has a
wildlife services program and they
eliminate wild animals who prey on the
livestock industry.
So they killed mountain lions.
Coyotes mean it's like 60,000 coyotes
last year were killed by the US
government because they're perceived as
a threat to this industry.
400 wolves,
500 black guys.
I'm sure you're
aware of the reintroduction of wolves,
you know about all that and like how
they reintroduce wolves to North America
from,
uh,
from actually from Canada.
Right.
Fascinating.
It's very controversial.
Oh,
for sure.
Yeah.
Because a elk population has been
decimated,
but then they've also attacked some
livestock in British Columbia.
When my friend Mike Lives,
I'm,
his neighbor's cow was taken out by a
wolf.
I think they were,
they were all sitting around from the
fucking bedroom window watching a pack
of monsters tear cal park,
like right in this little pen.
It's gotta be fucking spooky.
I mean,
but still mean wolf populations aren't
even anywhere close to what they were a
century ago.
That's true.
But in some states,
they have exceeded the number that they
intended to let them get too.
Right.
And so that's what happened.
Is that when you,
cause that's going back to these
environmental realizations.
Sierra club's got a big campaign by save
the wolves and all these organizations
save the,
we'll say the lowest,
but they're not talking about why wolves
are on the verge of collapse.
Again,
it's like we got these species off the
endangered species list and now they've
opened up out to hunting in Idaho and
you know at the states that the
population that bloomed again and it's
because of the cattle industry is not
that the wolves have exceeded that
ecological capacity,
your carrying capacity of the ecosystem.
It's the fact that they're competing
with livestock.
Well they've also reached a number that
have passed the number where the
scientists,
the biologist,
wildlife biologist deemed there would be
a healthy sustainable population and not
be a problem.
And when they get to,
you know what we call a problem,
of course it's when they interfere with
agriculture,
that's when they started eating
livestock.
Exactly.
And people's dogs and occasionally
joggers,
you know,
she didn't shit goes wrong with walls,
man.
You really,
the issue is um,
management right now.
What does that mean?
To some people it means like leave
nature alone and let nature sorted out.
But two people in indigenous areas like
um,
you know,
native Americans and people in Canada,
like a lot of them rely on moose and
deer to feed themselves.
I,
this is where they get their meat from
and they have to keep both populations
down.
If they don't keep wolf populations down
the wolf,
they,
they've already as it is,
wolves and bears kill something like 50%
of all calves and the fonts that come
out of deer and Moose.
So they do,
since there's no nothing that kills
wolves,
like you have to kill them,
otherwise they get to the point where
have you ever been to like a upstate New
York and drive through those areas where
there's so many deer you have to drive
like 20 miles an hour because at
nighttime they just darted in front of
your car like fucking rats.
They're everywhere.
It's,
it's nuts.
How many deer there are in some places.
And one of the reasons for it,
because there's no population control,
there's no predators.
And these are areas where there's just
not that many people and not that many
people hunting.
So you just get fuck load of these
fucking deer running around everywhere.
Yeah.
I mean it's,
that is that imbalance.
And that's what we've seen with ecology
around the world.
Indigenous communities have found,
I mean,
it's like a hunter gatherer.
Communities around the world have shown
that you can live in balance with
nature.
Um,
but that's not what we're living today.
Wildlife biologist,
they'll do believe that the way to
balance out as you have to keep
populations of predators down.
And that's why if you go back to
history,
all the fairy tales,
the big bad wolf,
Little Red Riding Hood,
all that stuff,
three little pigs were all wolves.
Wolves are fucking dangerous.
They're real dangerous.
And in terms of like recent history and
World War One,
the Russians and the Germans had a cease
fire because they were trying to kill
each other and wolves kept killing them.
They were getting so many soldiers
killed by wolves.
They literally had a ceasefire and just
went on a wolf killing rampage.
That's how scary wolves are.
They can stop armies from killing each
other.
So I think we all as compassionate and
people who love nature,
we have some beautiful ideas of what
nature is and some beautiful ideas of
how North American populations of
animals should be managed.
But Wildlife Biologists look at this
with a very sober I and they're,
the reason why they're opening up
hunting for wolves in Idaho and some
other areas is not just to protect
agriculture.
It's also to keep these motherfuckers
from getting out of control.
Cause there are wolves.
They're beautiful,
they're amazing.
I love them.
I love that they're here.
Even if they do jack a giant percentage
of the elk population and it's fucking
cool man.
Wolves are cool,
you know,
to be out in here and see like a fucking
pack of,
um,
there's a,
uh,
an electrical living beauty and all
that,
that if it's gone,
it's gone forever and you can never
bring it back.
And right now it's here and I think we
should enjoy it.
Be got to keep a fucking eye on that
man.
And when the wildlife biologist,
the sober ones go,
hey,
you've got too many,
you've got a problem,
you've got to open up hunting for them
because if you don't,
they just keep breeding and then what do
you do?
And we'll,
so there's this really dangerous
Predator that roams around the planet,
walks on two legs,
called him,
and I get it.
That's the most dominant species on the,
like that creditor,
no,
they're cool,
but,
but you can't advocate for those.
They've gotten out of control.
You can't eliminate them,
but she can move away from them.
I mean,
if,
if human beings,
but the wools kept human beings come in
and start jacking and killing people.
That's what's called war.
And that's why we have armies to protect
against human beings when human beings
do get out of control.
But if wolves were cool and they were
hanging around and I squirrels and they
never killed your dog and then ever
threaten your children,
yeah,
it would be a totally different
experience.
For sure.
When was the last death of a wolf and
say,
I last year we'll ask now.
Alaska.
I mean,
look,
there's not that many people are
wandering through the woods by
themselves and wolves are usually aware
then when they see human beings are
either in cars or their rifles,
but I've had friends that were stocked
by wolves.
I've had friends that were on bow
hunting expeditions where they thought
they were going to die because they were
stocked by wolves because wolves,
if they can get away with it,
they will fucking kill you.
Well,
they had bows and our hands to their
listen man,
I ain't gonna kill you.
Ain't going to kill them all.
You might get one wolf you if you're
lucky,
but a compound bow and a wolf's running
at you,
good fucking luck.
You've got to set your sight crock
correctly.
You've got to adjust it.
When the wolf's coming in,
get out,
he's speaking like say about Idaho,
you know the,
the wildlife in there is cows,
the kids,
cows and a few wolves,
you know,
and,
and the cows take up.
So right.
Take up so much space.
If you remove all those fences,
all those millions of miles and fences
and millions of acres,
and you let the wolves have that land
again,
and then you let the other predators
come back in,
then you have a balance going on.
But it's the fences and that's the,
you know,
you talk about the wildlife management,
it's,
it's bullshit because just by killing
some wolves and not addressing the cows
and the fences,
that's,
that's the problem.
Well,
there is certainly a lot of cows,
nine home,
but there's also a lot of wild game.
There's a lot of like deer hunting in
Idaho is famous,
like elk hunting in Idaho.
So we one of the best places to go in
the world.
So it's not entirely true.
There's a lot of wildlife,
Idaho,
if you've gone to other people,
they have this idea of Idaho is being
like sort of this like boring,
flat,
you know,
like the people don't go there.
They think of it as like one of those
states.
I'm never going to visit Idaho.
Spectacular.
Have you been?
Oh yeah,
that's from the fucking mountains.
It's just a spectacular place.
So there's a lot of wildlife and a lot
of sports men,
hunter people,
and a lot of Fisher people fishing.
Then that's the amazing thing.
I used to live in Alaska and you'd just
see Moose everywhere.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
Incredible.
Um,
but we still,
we don't have that perspective of that
200 years ago,
the biodiversity and they mount of
animals was that much more,
and 500 years ago was even now much
more,
I'm living in the bay and when we talk
about the indigenous people literally
didn't go more than 10 miles from where
their village was because there's so
many animals.
There's so much food.
Right.
And we've just eliminated that.
But if you want to have an apple store,
you have to do that.
But also too,
you know,
the wildlife and the Idaho that you're
talking about,
it wasn't,
there's not that much predators.
You know,
there's a lot more predators and will
the world's,
but we know they're real big populations
of wolves now the,
but it still,
it says a fraction of what action,
what it used to be.
And then you also like as far as the
West,
the bears and the cougars and the
coyotes that are just getting destroyed.
And people talk about wildlife cause
there's a bunch of Moose and a bunch of
elk and uh,
well the payers,
the bears and cougars and wolves are not
getting,
they're not getting destroyed.
Like they have very strict numbers of
how many you can kill,
whether it's cougars or whether it's
bears or whatever.
And bears are extremely hard to kill.
Like in California in particular,
they've made it so it's almost
impossible to kill bears.
You can't use bait and you can't use
dogs.
So you have to go find them.
And walls,
I mean,
bears are way smarter than then.
You give him credit for it.
They smell things a mile away.
They hear things you're never going to
hear.
And if you start coming through the
woods,
they're just kind of not be there.
It's not like there's this overwhelming
idea that we have to go out and decimate
all of the coyotes and all of the bears
and all of the wolves and all of the
cougars that's not going on.
Coyotes are the only one out of that
whole list.
You can shoot as many as you want.
Like people worry about coyotes
encroaching upon urban areas and killing
cats and dogs.
And my neighbor's dog was killed by a
coyote.
It's,
it happens all the time,
you know,
but it's not like they're out there
killing all the bears.
Like you're just fucking serious jail
time.
If you kill a bear and you don't have a
tag and you can't even kill them in
California,
uh,
cougars,
we can't even kill them.
So mountain lions in California or just
running all over the place.
Killing cattle.
Yeah.
The reason though is that we've gotten
to that place.
We've decimated this,
the populations to such a low point that
now they have to put in these mandates
and controls to try and keep the species
alive.
Yeah.
Well that's true.
The reason why they did it though.
It was like when they started killing
all these wolves back in the day when
they started poisoning them,
they did it because they were dangerous.
Like they had gotten to high numbers and
they had realized that as soon as people
start stockpiling,
um,
uh,
livestock,
this is an easy place to hit.
And so they would just keep coming back
to them.
I'm sure you've heard of the Russian
super packs of wolves that they've had
issues with in Siberia where these guys,
they're,
you know,
they can't do a damn thing about it
because there's a hundred Wolf's tearing
apart a horse and there that's,
that happens.
It does happen with wolves.
So it's,
I don't think this is something,
I see all of your points on nature and I
agree with you 100% on the factory
farming situation,
but I think we have to be real careful
when it comes to just letting wildlife
be wild.
I think there's a certain amount of
predators that you can have before
things get dangerous.
The big one,
you know,
that the film addresses is the,
is the livestock,
you know,
and that's what's gotten out of control
and that's what's literally destroying
and taking over the wildlife.
So if you really concerned about
wildlife,
if you're real wildlife person,
the last thing you do was not only
consume,
say factory farm,
but that's a whole thing about our film.
People think it's about factory farm.
We don't even talk about factory farm.
We talk about the grass fed beef,
we talk about the organic,
the organic,
a free rein,
uh,
organic grass fed milk.
And that's what's killing the wildlife.
And that's the whole point of what we,
we,
we jumped past the factory farm.
Cause ironically for wildlife,
if you care truly about wildlife and
that's what they discuss when we talk to
the animals animal agriculture alliance,
they say,
they say people think we're living in
somewhere 50 years ago,
a hundred years ago.
We're not.
We're living in a place with 7 billion
people.
The only way to efficiently feed people
who want to eat meat is to do,
put them in factory farms,
their factory farms because they're
efficient.
They only take around two acres per cow
or is the grass fed cow?
You're talking about your buddy and
Wisconsin.
The guy in our film,
he had cattle in Wisconsin.
He said 50 acres,
50 acres for one fucking cow.
One cow.
50 acres.
Think how big that is.
No other wildlife can enter that.
So that's the last thing you'd want to
eat is grass fed beef.
The last thing you wanted to be fed is
um,
would beating as these,
uh,
organic dairy farms as destroying all
our water,
water resources,
the rivers and destroying all these
predators.
And these,
uh,
you know,
the other wildlife that you're talking
about.
But the argument would be that when you
have a grass fed cow and it's eating on
50 acres,
that's where it's getting its food from.
Whereas if you have a factory raised
animal,
it's getting corn.
That corn is raising independently on
some other large area.
Two acres or two acres?
Two eight two acres to,
yeah cause you can grow a corn so much
prager and grass fed.
It needs 50 acres that no other horse,
no other bear,
no other cougar.
Know that all these animals that you're
talking about,
no other animal can live on that area.
Is that during the life of the animal?
That's,
that's just period.
That's just till slaughter.
That's constantly so mad.
You're on a 50 foot fence.
Nothing else.
What's way more than 50 foot?
50 50 50 acres.
50 acres for one.
So that's the last thing you want to be
eating is grass fed beef.
If you really care about the
environment,
if you really care about wildlife,
you,
you need to say either I fucked the cow,
screw the cow.
The cow is a miserable life.
But you know,
I care a lot about more like a,
you know about the,
the elk and the Moose and the wolves.
I care more about wildlife than I do
about this cow.
You've got to choose one or the other if
you're going to do it.
And if you could really care about
wildlife,
you got to say screw the cow.
And then Sco,
uh,
with factory farm.
And that's the whole irony of this whole
grass fed myth that's happening.
Um,
and that's what's,
that's what's kind of ironic about the
film and people don't expect that.
Shocking.
If human beings right now stopped
growing,
I can for the population in the United
States state of 300 million,
can we feed ourselves right now with how
we're doing it?
Uh,
like business as normal?
Yeah.
Not Sustainably.
Not intro to perpetuity.
Yeah.
Why is that?
Um,
right now,
half of the United States,
lower 48 land is designated to raising
animals for food,
whether growing the 50%.
It's crazy.
Yes.
No other wildlife.
Yeah.
And so,
so we've already passed that tipping
point where we're,
we're on ecological collapse so we can't
continue business as normal.
Um,
50% of it.
When you say pass that tipping point,
why isn't it sustainable?
Um,
the simple fact that we're draining the
aquifers at extreme rates and the uncle,
all aquifer large stock for North
America drops by I think six feet per
year.
50% of 55% of all water consumed in the
United States goes into animal
agriculture.
Um,
so we're pumping ground waters,
totally unsustainable in California,
you know,
massive drought,
47% of cattle
as opposed to domestic is 5%.
Every single thing you do in your home,
all everything you do in their home is
only 5%.
And why a culture?
55% and we're talking about how we're in
a drought,
it's called uh,
um,
you know,
it's clearly the food and water shortage
shortage.
I mean,
what is,
uh,
what's golf courses?
Golf course is less than 2%.
That's still a lot.
It's over just for,
sorry,
sorry.
Just for,
just for California,
for the,
for the United States,
it doesn't even register as a percent.
So in California,
5% is for humans.
Just 4% for plastic.
2% is for golf.
Yeah.
That's 50,
55% for,
let's listen.
Let's get rid of important
shit first.
Get rid of the golf,
the song.
Okay,
now we're down to 2%.
We're doing a way better.
That's your goal.
But you know,
that's,
that's a big one.
So water water's John was a big one with
a huge issue.
Alienation technology that's emerging.
Sadly that's really not a solution
either because of how much energy goes
into it.
And so the greenhouse gas emissions that
are attributed to each gallon of water.
How about nuclear son?
I would do some nuclear desalination,
put it right on a fault line.
Um,
another part of it is a top soil erosion
leading causes,
topsoil erosion is from hoofed animals
grazing on animal on land that never had
hooked animals.
Um,
it's how we tilled soils to grow corn
and soy and Alfalfa.
That's an issue,
right?
That you guys also addressed that maybe
some people aren't aware of,
is that you can't just keep pulling it
the same plant over and over again from
soil.
And when you do that,
you deplete these farmlands.
And there,
you know,
there's a guy named Dr Joel Wallach.
I don't know if you've ever heard of
him.
Controversial character,
but he had this fascinating book called
dead doctors.
Don't lie.
It's all about mineral deficiencies.
And about these farm lands in the United
States had been minerally deficient.
So it's like the 1930s and they'd been
aware of it forever.
And so they have to supplement the,
the farm,
the ground with uh,
with minerals.
But it's barely enough.
You know,
it's not good.
It's not good for your health.
You know,
it's the kind of vegetables that you get
from those places.
They're,
um,
they're not the healthiest.
That's it.
I mean,
there,
some soil scientists are saying that
we'll,
we won't have livable top soils in the
next 50 years in the United States
because how we farm and they know that's
a huge issue.
And then,
you know,
what ends up happening to all of that
top soil runs off into streams and
rivers and that's when it's flushed out
to the oceans.
We have these massive dead zones that
are completely devoid of life all from,
you know,
the primary cause it because of raising
animals that we have the greenhouse
gasses.
And then when 50% is cleared away,
imagine 50% of that land reverts back to
actual wildlife,
you know,
to actual the Fanta growing back then,
now you're talking crazy talking stop
factory farming and agriculture.
That's it.
Just forest forest and a bunch of holes
just going to be eaten.
Bark like that fucking survivor dude.
Um,
yeah,
I don't think that's going to happen,
but I don't think anybody knew that this
had happened.
I think that's part of the problem of a
documentary like this is it catches
people.
Like what,
what,
how did this happen?
You,
you get to that.
How did this happen?
Like it's one of the things that I've
realized as an adult,
I used to have a bit about this,
is there just no grownups,
there's just a bunch of people that got
older.
Like when you're a little kid,
you think that one day there's going to
be a grownup and you know,
you're,
you're gonna,
you're going to be growing up as well.
And it's gonna make sense.
Like,
oh,
one day I'll,
I'll be all grown up.
But no,
you get grown up and then you realize,
oh,
nobody knows what the fuck is going on
and we're all operating on momentum and
somehow or another,
their momentum of these greedy cunts has
created this environment where you can't
even talk about what they're doing
animals and you can't talk about how far
gone we are and we're so disconnected.
Most of us are just as long as we can go
to the store and buy some food,
we don't have shit to think about.
Dude,
okay,
fucking game of thrones is on.
I don't have time.
And because of that,
these guys have gotten away with it,
but it's like,
um,
it's like,
like a crime that you're watching.
I mean there's like crime.
It seems like it should be crying.
I mean we are,
we are literally living in the largest
mass extinction in the planet's ever
seen 65 million years ago when all the
dinosaurs died off is nothing compared
to the rate of extinction we're seeing
right now.
Are Those animals are all losers though.
All losers.
And then also I heard that 90% of
everything that's ever lived as extinct.
Yeah.
Do you want to keep animals around
forever?
Are they the perfect animal?
Can't they just go in a new thing comes
in their place?
Al's the one,
you know what I'm saying?
I mean intellectually I totally,
I'm not,
not that I'm ever,
but if I was intellectual,
I would say that ultimately,
um,
this whole thing is happening a lot.
Life is taking place and it's moving at
this very strange,
bizarre pace.
I think that ethically though,
the one of the bigger issues of the,
the PR maybe,
perhaps the biggest issue is how did we
allow,
um,
laws in place like laws where you can go
to jail for filming cruelty,
right?
That doesn't make any sense as
Americans,
as human beings,
as people that are living in the age of
information of 2016 to deny,
deny information shouldn't,
you know,
if you buy a pair of pants at that pair
of pants is made by fucking slaves.
Shouldn't,
you know,
if you went to the pair of pants factory
and you saw a guy whipping the people
that were making the pair of pants,
wouldn't you want to be aware of that?
So how is it any different?
How is it any different?
How is it any different than it's
illegal to film someone being cruel to
animals.
That's fucked up
cause people don't want to see it.
People don't want to see what they're
doing to their,
their,
you know,
they're eating three times a day.
They don't want to see it.
They don't,
I don't think that's the case.
I think the big thing is,
is that it's money.
It's,
I think it's way more money than it is.
People don't want to see it cause people
say that to all all the time.
They're like,
they see the film,
they feel really inspired.
And I'm like well what do we do?
You know,
I should write my congressman,
I should,
you know,
talk to my legislators and that's great.
If they think that's where the solutions
are going to happen,
can we just do an ice bucket challenge
type thing?
Yeah.
Right now we know,
but it really,
it was going to come down to is that as
long as this industry has money and has
the money to funnel into the government,
things are going to continue.
You know?
And so it's,
you know,
I think it's kind of,
it's undermining the baseline with that
one.
You know,
we toured around with the film and
people talk,
you know,
the politicians are,
are,
are the bad ones are the anomia culture
groups are the bad ones,
the government and it,
once again,
it goes back to those environmental
groups.
Those are the ones,
you know,
those are the ones that you need to,
they need to be held accountable.
That's why they make their billions of
dollars collectively and they're not
doing it.
And that's why they're there.
Here.
I mean that is the one that did animal
agriculture.
There's doing their business,
you know,
they're good businessmen.
They got their lobbies,
they got the government,
they got,
they own filtration now to these
environmental groups.
They're doing a good job.
So how about pure hold people
accountable to step up what they're
doing and hold themselves accountable
whilst rather than saying,
screw you,
screw you.
I'll say,
you know,
look in the mirror and what can I do?
What can I do to make a difference and
what can I do with these environmental
groups that are actually palpable and
just from the making the film to
actually now starting to address it.
So it's,
it's pretty cool they're finally doing
it.
Well,
it's interesting because if you look at
the,
uh,
the agriculture business,
if you look at factory farming business,
like I was a business,
I do look at just the raising of
livestock in this country.
There's a gigantic diffusion of
responsibility aspect to it all because
each person is one part of this enormous
industry and this industry has existed
before they came along.
So you grow up and it seems normal
because everybody's buying steak at the
butcher shop and everybody's,
you know,
getting their cows from this fucking guy
and their milk from this store.
And it seems totally normal.
But as you get older,
you become a part of that system
yourself.
You start becoming a farmer,
so you take on a job that is,
is already exists and it's acceptable.
It's a normal part of your community and
your culture.
And then you know,
you run into some problems and you need
some loans so you get alone and you
expand your business and then you get
involved with lobbyists and the
lobbyists combine and they say,
hey listen,
we've passed a new law that makes it
illegal for people to film you while
you're beating the fuck out of your
pigs.
All right,
cool.
I guess shit,
fuck,
whatever.
Long as they can't run me out of
business,
I got loans,
I got loans from the fucking government,
I've got to pay off and this is what a
lot of it,
what's going on?
You're not dealing with individuals that
are evil.
You're dealing with almost like an evil
concept.
And the evil concept is to be able to
take life and to turn it into something
that's profitable.
I have to take life and to smash it into
the small space possible.
Feed it the most fattening shit
possible.
Pump it full of whatever chemicals we
have that make it grow quicker and then
chop it up.
That's it.
It's like,
and I think it'd be in the film,
we don't demonize people who are
involved in this industry because
they're all trying to,
you know,
pay the bills,
feed their families.
My Dad was a rancher.
Yeah.
And so it's like,
this is,
again,
these aren't,
these aren't bad people.
These are people caught up in a bad
system.
Yeah.
I think that's a real good point to
make.
It's a real good point to make.
Whoever's made those laws is definitely
responsible.
Whoever let that happen.
Why whoa,
that having that put into like this one
thing,
if you have people that are fucking,
I've seen people that interrupt
restaurants and then,
you know,
you've seen videos of those people,
they get in and they just fucking start
screaming about meat is murder.
And like this is not the place for it.
It's just not.
It's like you're,
you're interrupting people's business.
You,
you're making a moral judgment and you
might be right in your eyes,
but in this person's eyes,
you're wrong and you're,
you're fucking with their space.
You know,
there's that.
Yeah,
but that's what's interesting is,
you know,
when people talk about,
that's a judgment of what other people
do.
I don't condone that at all.
But you know,
we discussed in the film is what other
people are doing with their choices.
They're saying,
you know,
say someone's like,
Oh,
you're Vegan or vegetarian.
Well,
you know,
I,
I do what I want.
You do what you would want.
Don't judge me.
It's like,
well,
you know what,
you're destroying our wildlife.
You're destroying my future generation.
I'm paying taxes for your hamburger.
Like in the film about the guy who wrote
mean denomix we're paying around on him
on a big Mac.
Was it $7 normally costs,
it costs about $3.
It's Pecans 10 it would cost $10.
Yet we are the ones paying the taxes on
this with,
through the,
um,
but do you understand that?
Saying that to people and talking to
them like that makes people think that
vegans are annoying,
which makes it baffled because
people are annoying.
There's a percentage of people that are
annoying for no,
no getting around it.
And when you ever met somebody who just
started fucking doing something like,
you know,
uh,
just started playing tennis and all they
want to do is talk about fucking tennis.
Like Jesus Christ,
man,
enough about fucking tennis.
That's how a lot of people are with
everything,
including becoming a Vegan.
You know,
I'm guilty of it with sting.
Things that I get into because when I
get into things,
that's all I want to talk about.
When when people find that moral high
ground in particular,
they tend to fucking plant the flag and
blow trumpets.
And so when you say to someone,
Hey,
you know,
it's not because I'm paying taxes on
your burger.
They're like,
oh dude,
fuck off.
You know,
this is not the way to talk to people
cause they don't want to hear it.
Even if you,
you're making sense with your facts and
your statistics.
Most people,
first of all,
if they haven't seen your documentary or
many other documentaries where it's food
inc or whether it's king corn or whether
there's a series of them you can watch
it sort of give you this complicated,
multifaceted Pete picture of what's
going on with food in this country.
And it's not,
it's not good.
It's real bad on all levels because
that's what people really love the film
is that we,
we don't say one thing to anybody.
You know,
when you watch the film,
we don't make one judgment.
We don't say anything,
not one point in pointing the entire
film.
It's just following my journey,
what I personally went through about six
years ago,
because it's all about providing
information.
Even that,
you know,
just providing information about the
taxes,
just like,
you know,
this is,
this is the truth.
It just know the information and then
make your own choices.
Well,
yeah,
you don't really have to put a spin on
it.
You know,
when you,
when you break down the actual numbers
as far as account,
what does,
the other thing that was incredible when
you show like how much,
uh,
area you need to grow plants versus how
much area you need to grow livestock to
feed the same amount of people.
You know,
it's,
it's about one 600 acre to feed a Vegan
for a year and then it's 18 times that
were so skinny.
Man,
they look tiny.
Got To have the 300 pound Vegan in here,
man.
These dudes eating pizza all the time.
When you,
when you flying over the country and
look at all the extra spot,
there's a lot of space.
They put the fuck's going on with that
space.
Like when you fly over,
it was nothing.
Nothing happened for a long time,
which is actually is kind of amazing.
It's like,
especially in the American West,
you'd drive through Nevada and you're
like,
oh,
there's all this open space.
But then you stopped cows there,
but she stopped.
Yeah.
You see,
and there's one cow every hundred acres.
And so it's,
this is land that the US has been very
efficient at utilizing this land.
What was going on with
that whole Bundy ranch thing that that
had to do with ranchers and public land
for grazing as well.
Right?
Like the one wanted to charge them more
money and so they fucking got together
with her white supremacists,
but allegedly or they rights premises.
Uh,
they're definitely the white elliot.
What is the Lgma Mormon might as well,
they're mormons with guns.
That's weird.
Guns for [inaudible].
Well,
so when he was the Mormons in the U s we
have federal lands that's managed by the
bureau of Land Management Blm.
And that land belongs to all of us.
So you can get a permit to mine on that
land.
You can hunt and fish and shoot guns and
ride atvs and all that sort of stuff
because it's just all in by all of us.
Um,
but you can also get a permit to grace
livestock.
And so ranchers get these permits,
grave livestock on federal lands.
They pay a fraction of what they would
normally pay.
So that basically subsidized by all of
us.
Um,
and so then Bundy and his cronies all
wanted to,
they say no,
you know,
they hadn't paid their,
their basically their fees.
And so blm took their cattle and said,
hey,
you haven't paid,
you know,
you're,
you're basically stealing from the u s
citizens,
you know,
by grazing animals illegally.
And so they did their whole crew and you
know,
trying to overthrow the government
lemon.
It's just,
it's nuts.
But,
so again,
this is,
and what's going on right now in Oregon
and same sort of thing is that they,
they believe that this land is for them
to use because no one else is up there.
And so they can graze their cattle.
It's like,
well right now they're,
they're cutting down fences and wildlife
refuges to graze cattle.
It's like,
I mean it's just the,
it doesn't benefit ecology and anyway,
it doesn't benefit us as people first
one to call those guys.
Y'all Qaeda something,
someone did it on the podcast allegedly.
I don't know who it was.
It sounds like something Tony would say,
but he's not really political,
so I don't,
I don't think he would be aware of the
Bundy ranch thing.
All Kinda,
yeah.
But it's been on twitter for a while and
someone attributed to someone who was a
guest on this show and I don't remember
who it was.
If it had happened,
I would like to give them credit cause
it's fucking hilarious.
So those ranchers,
they do have huge power though right now
there's wild horses in American west
that are being rounded up.
There's more wild horses in federal
captivity then there are free on the
range.
Yeah,
I saw that.
That was,
I found that to be fascinating too.
That was a part of your pot.
You're a documentary that I totally
didn't expect.
Yeah.
And that's again,
because of the cattle industry now this
federal land,
that's when you say that they get,
they get their animals can graze on it
for a fraction of the cost.
Um,
fraction of the cost of doing it on
private land.
So what you mean exactly,
but federal land is owned by all the
people,
so shouldn't it be kind of a fraction of
the cost if you do hand out permits,
like if you want to like you could that
land to go camping,
to hike,
to do cause it's all this is,
well Theodore Roosevelt,
when he was in office,
he was very controversial because one of
the things that he did is he wanted to
protect gigantic chunks of land in this
country and make them public land and
make it so that people will always have
the great outdoors.
You could always go and enjoy these.
They,
you can't overdeveloped them.
Like he had a very amazing foresight in
that,
in that regard.
He really saw the future and a lot of
ways and man,
they'd been trying to fucking sell that
shit off forever.
And as recently as,
I'm just one of those guys running for
President Ryan.
Paul Ryan said his name.
I believe he was one of the guys that
was ahead of this idea to sell that
land,
to pay off the debt that the United
States allegedly has to some fucking
invisible man.
I don't even understand the depth that
we have.
Like to who?
Like what's going on the federal bank.
Why is it called the Federal Bank?
Is it a federal thing?
No,
it's not just the name of it.
Oh,
what the fuck is going on?
We owe,
how much?
How do we owe that much?
Why are we paying them that much?
What are we paying them for?
Exactly?
They make money.
What?
We can't make our own fucking money.
What's going on here?
So you can go down a rabbit hole.
My point.
But if you do go down that rabbit hole,
like shouldn't those people like,
shouldn't you,
if you have chickens Shinny,
allow your chickens to fucking run
around on,
on,
on public land.
It's,
it's the difference is profiting off of
it.
So it's if they haven't,
you know,
they're private industry making money on
public lands,
but they do pay taxes,
right?
Uh,
yeah,
I'm actually taxes.
So it's not like they do it for free.
No,
but they're heavily subsidized.
But back to that whole big Mac thing,
you know,
it's $3 but it's really should be around
well sort of because it's all money
that's going to the government,
right?
It's like they taking money from you.
Are you really paying taxes from it or
are they paying less taxes?
You could say that you're paying taxes
for it,
but it's really that they're paying
less.
That's really what it is actually mean.
Received checks.
I mean,
so it's like they get like the oil
industry does,
you get subsidized.
So like the corn industry does to huge,
which apparently they can't survive
without that.
Like,
I'm gonna pick the hog industry in North
Carolina.
You know,
we've read a report that said they
wouldn't be able to survive here.
There wasn't people that of subsidies,
hundreds of millions a year.
So how does that happen?
Explain key.
I don't know if you can,
can you explain that to me?
I mean,
so what it is is that the US government
has policies around food.
That food has to be affordable for a
citizens.
And that's a,
it's a huge thing.
Do you want to come to the revolution
from happening?
Definitely keep people well fed.
And so we have that what it is fucking
government man keeping us fat and lazy.
Oh well you look at the,
I mean what happened in the Arab spring
that was mostly because of food prices
lease.
A lot of economists are saying that.
Yeah,
but so we want to keep food affordable
than the u s so when a industry is
struggling,
the government stepped in and said,
hey,
we'll help you out.
We'll keep food prices artificially low.
So like corn for example,
have huge,
huge subsidies to it.
70% of corn in the United States has fed
to livestock.
So that subsidy is then passed onto the
livestock industry.
You have industry,
like a hog industry has,
you know,
a porcine epidemic where all these
sounds dying.
And
so the US government bails him out and
says,
Oh,
here's,
you know,
$10 billion to get your industry out of,
out of deep water.
Uh,
and that stuff happens all the time.
But then that's to make sure that the
food supply stays adequate.
Cause I mean,
right now,
chicken in the United States is cheaper,
like astronomically cheaper than it was
50 years ago even.
And even including inflation,
I mean it's,
well,
you know,
that was one of,
I believe Roosevelt's,
um,
I think it was roosevelt with his
campaign slogans was a chicken in every
pot because chickens were like lobster
back then.
It was like really expensive.
See if that was,
I think it was Roosevelt,
but that,
you know,
that animal was a,
a wealthy person's meall,
right?
Yeah.
And it's become the standard.
And then the reason for this is it's
artificially low.
Hoover.
Yeah.
Hoover,
one of those old dead dudes.
Nothing.
Again,
that's just one aspect of it is that we,
we,
cause people will say that,
they'd be like,
well,
you know,
it's really expensive to eat plant based
foods.
And you know,
I've traveled around the world,
I've lived around the world.
Plant based foods are the cheapest foods
around the world except for in young,
extreme remote areas where they can't
grow vegetables.
Um,
we can,
the reason why you can buy a 99 cent
hamburger though is because of federal
subsidies,
you know?
Um,
so subsidies that keep food prices low.
Here's part of the problem.
I agree that it's probably a good idea
to keep food prices low because people
don't make so much money,
but then you go down that rabbit hole.
Well,
wow.
How can people who don't make so much
money?
Like why,
why is the fucking minimum wage so low?
How the hell you live on that?
You can't live on that.
You really can't.
And when we interviewed,
uh,
Lauren or Nellis from food empowerment
project,
and that's one of the things they talk
about is that,
you know,
we look at food deserts that are
happening in and around urban areas.
People can't afford food and it's
because we don't have a living wage.
It's like you want to solve food
deserts,
please?
He's a food desert.
Areas that don't have access to fresh
foods.
So it's,
you know,
you look at a community and they're only
grocery store is a liquor store that has
chips and you know,
junk food.
Oh,
I see.
So you're just talking about like
neighborhoods,
neighborhoods that have
the weirdest part about going to poor
neighborhoods is how many fucking liquor
stores,
man.
That's it.
And so,
and again,
the federal subsidies,
it's like they're not subsidizing
healthy fruits and vegetables.
It's like you're not,
you know,
the organic fruits and vegetables
industries aren't heavily subsidized.
They're not subsides even at all for a
moment.
Most of them,
uh,
they subsidizing really unhealthy foods,
high fructose corn syrup,
you know,
animal products,
foods that are actually killing us.
Well,
that was another super disturbing part
of king corn when they went over their
own bodies,
they got their bodies examined and found
out how much of the carbon in their body
had come from corn to there were made
out of fucking corn.
And then they go through the supermarket
aisle and examine all the different
products to find evidence of corn
products in them and look,
Ooh,
that's crazy.
It's a har how does happen in a hundred
years,
in a hundred years.
I mean,
you go back to 1915
and everything was normal.
People were eating normal shit,
you know,
I mean,
people were,
there were the farms where normal people
get their milk delivered to their door
in the morning,
you know,
in a glass jug that came from a farm.
It was,
it was normal.
I remember somewhere along the line.
Yeah,
well it really came from,
from War World War One and World War Two
is they started producing,
you know,
chemical nitrogen for mustard gas and
for chemical weapons and they realize,
Whoa,
you know,
you can grow plants with this stuff.
She knows the story behind that.
Yeah,
a little bit.
The hopper method,
that guy became a fucking war criminal.
The guy who invented the nitrogen that's
responsible for like 50% of the fucking
nitrogen in your body right now has come
from the hopper method where they take
it.
He's had some bizarre way of extracting
nitrogen from the air because the air is
very nitrogen rich.
So instead of using fertilizer,
they figured out how to get nitrogen out
of the fucking air.
This same guy came up with the idea of
gassing people.
He gassed the allied troops in World War
One and then created xy clon be that
fucking gas that they will,
these xy Klein a and Zyklon b.
And he came up with Zyklon a and he
figured out a way to make it so it has a
very strong smell.
So you would know it was a pesticide so
that you would know that you,
if you smelled it,
get the fuck away from it.
And then the Nazis turned into Zyklon b.
So they just took out whatever element
that gave it a horrible smell.
And he was a Jew.
And that sick dark story,
it all happened after he was,
well,
he,
it was,
most of it happened after he was dead,
like the,
uh,
the Nazis using Zyklon b.
But while he was alive,
they were,
I mean,
he,
he was like a man without a country and
the United States,
oh,
they'd given him a fucking Nobel prize.
And then they wanted to try him as a war
criminal at the same time.
It was fucking bananas.
He's,
he's one of the weirdest stories ever in
science for sure.
Yeah.
And that's basically how we got to where
we are.
It's like you can offer sudden grow corn
and places that you could never grow
foods before.
If anybody wants to hear more about
that.
I'm sorry to interrupt you,
but there's a radio lab podcast on it.
Go check it out.
I wish I could remember the name of it,
but if you google,
what does it do?
You just say something right here.
It's how you solve a problem.
It wasn't a topper,
that's what's called,
it might've been more than one,
but I think it was the bad show.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I don't know if that's the actual pot.
Either way you'll,
you'll find it folks,
but it's worth listening to if you're
in,
if you haven't heard of radio lab,
it's a fucking amazing podcast for sure.
So that's,
I mean,
that's,
he's,
he's a big reason why.
I mean we,
right now we have,
that's what a lot of population to
explode.
Um,
agriculture really is what lot of
populations to explode.
It's like once we started cultivating
plants,
populations,
you know,
we're not spending 90% of our time
hunting and gathering.
It's amazing that the pill,
the birth control pill didn't put up
fucking Denton.
Anything.
Didn't even know there was like throwing
up some cheese cloth,
try to stop a raging river.
Ah,
just didn't do Jack Shit.
They thought like,
oh,
we're going to have this down now.
All I have does take a pill.
Who,
boy,
we'll figure that out just in the nick
of time.
That's it,
man.
Magic.
There was no pill.
Probably be the same amount of people.
Probably stupid as fuck.
Yeah,
I mean the real,
the real thing.
If you want to control populations,
educate girls,
that's what it comes down to.
Doesn't work Saturdays.
Christ people do educate boys.
Doesn't matter.
You can't some,
first of all,
I definitely can't put it on girls cause
they get horny just like boys get
baffled.
But in mass,
the whole thing and said,
you look at populations whose birth the
rates are going down.
It's when they started educating girls
when you,
when they stop segregating were only
boys were going to school.
Just one correlation though.
But he also populations go down in
places that are more,
um,
more advanced and places that a or a
high population areas with more uh,
affluent people.
Populations go down.
People were there more career oriented
people,
populations go down.
Right.
But so there's a lot of different
factors in that,
right?
Totally.
But they have to be edited on chicks.
Oh No,
no,
no.
I mean it's,
it's the fact that we got it.
Yeah.
What do we have 50 kids?
Cause you're a fucking whore.
That's why,
uh,
well I mean old woman who's got an
education isn't,
isn't concerned about,
you know,
having 10 kids.
She's interested in having a career.
Some of them.
Yeah.
I mean I come from a family of eight
kids,
so it's like,
yeah,
I'll talk about human population all day
long.
People are goofing.
I don't know.
They fucking,
they make people,
it's just ridiculous.
At this point in time,
sex is the only way to make people like,
you know,
it should figure out a way better and
more obvious way to make people than do
something that your body is urging you
to do.
All the time.
I make what do we amoebas and like God
damn gets get past that.
Well we,
I mean that's one of the most important
things,
even as important as factory farming,
figuring out a way where it's completely
sober and non pleasurable to make a
person
where it's not like a desire like you
bro,
like you've been holding your breath for
an hour,
just like that's what it's like with
people and they have sex.
Just such a fucking overwhelming
feeling.
And that's how you make a person that's
pathetic to biological trick of the
highest order.
Mother Nature is a trickster and dirty
trickster.
Um,
well,
you know,
that's at least something that's
addressed and people talk about one,
the thing that I think I find the most
disturbing about all this is how few
people are aware of the reality of
factory farming.
It sorta seems like a ghost that's
whispered in the woods,
you know,
factory farming.
It's fucking terrible.
You know.
No one really thinks about it too much
because it's not really in our face
enough.
And the idea that that now is covered by
the Patriot Act,
if you do put it in people's faces that
you mean,
it's essentially like by way of creating
a law like that,
they've made it so that you'll never
make it better.
There's no need to make it better.
And as soon as there's no need to
improve the conditions that these
animals live under,
then it's just not going to get better.
If it doesn't help being businesses
don't operate that way,
it doesn't help profits.
That's not going to get back.
That's the thing though with the,
the,
you know,
again the film,
it's not just the factory farms,
it's everything.
It's with a population as big as it is.
There's just no way to feed this meat
consumption and dairy with,
uh,
you know,
the demand.
But is the,
is the ultimately is the move to make
everybody vegetables or the move to make
less people?
Can we just start killing stupid people?
Can we just like have a pole?
How old is your earth?
Usually it's more than 10.
Less than 10,000 years old.
You win a prize and we have them all
show up and just push him into a
volcano.
No.
Well,
and again,
I don't work,
but it's like who chooses that some Nazi
shit right there.
Can't do that.
I mean I had to choose.
I think it's looking at both of them.
I think you can't ignore population when
talking about sustainability.
They,
they go hand in hand.
I think having a very honest,
serious conversation about human
population is very important.
Um,
but there's no real,
you know,
ethical way to control population that I
know of right now.
And so we have to figure out,
well how do we feed people while we also
educate them?
I mean,
cause I take it serious.
I mean I actually,
I had myself sterilized on us 24 years
old could move,
Dude.
Yeah.
That's one of the best decisions I ever
made in my whole life.
Really?
Yeah.
Because,
I mean,
I just looked at the situation,
I'm care about sustainability and ma,
I don't want it to contribute to that.
I want to live as sustainably as
possible.
And then as far as feeding people,
you know,
one of the scientists on our film,
they said if everyone did just the
plants,
you know that that would happen is that
you could feed around fifth,
14 15 billion people.
It's 7 billion.
And the way we're eating right now,
we need two and a half planets.
So right now we're screwed.
But you know,
it's more than a population issue.
It's like what the population is doing,
what do people just lose weight?
People are fat as fuck.
What have everybody just stops eating so
much?
Can we just drop it drastically?
But if people ate enough to be lean and
healthy like you're supposed to,
what difference in the consumption would
that be?
I mean,
it's,
it's how many calories go into per
calorie.
So it's a unit of energy that's a big
part of it.
So that's a part of the
unsustainability.
So the unsustainable bill on
sustainability is the topsoil is eroded
to the point where,
you know,
there's just not that much that they can
do with it and at certain point in time
is going to become sterile.
So that's one part of the
unsustainability.
And the other part of the
unsustainability is that the population
is not staying the same and it's
continuing to jump up.
I think in my lifetime the United States
has gone up something like 60 million
plus people just in my lifetime I
wouldn't be as bad as it was more than
that.
It's probably,
it was more than that.
I'm probably making sure it up.
What do I know?
But I've watched a film the other day
and it was a about um,
the 19,
I guess 1960s,
early 1960s.
And they were driving around and those
old cars and there's fucking nobody on
the road,
man.
Like you look at New York City,
you could get anywhere.
You could just drive around and you
watch and you're like,
wow,
that's crazy.
Look at everyone just driving like just
no traffic jam.
Did he even know what a traffic jam was
and then you look 60 years later or
whatever it is,
it's nuts.
Like now it's just a sworn and then you
would have to extrapolate,
okay,
well what's going to happen in a hundred
years from now?
What's that going to be like?
That's it.
I mean they're,
they're expecting 9 billion people by
2050.
Um,
and those are people all,
all we're going to want to eat and
that's,
that's a big part of it.
We're going to have like apartment
buildings stacked up with cows and side
of them so that they're going to
eventually do in Japan actually there
really speed that up and they do it.
That's always fucked up when you have a
ridiculous idea that you don't think
anyone's ever going to do.
And they go,
oh,
they're already doing that Japanese one
step ahead.
And usually,
well they,
they have that wide you fucking cow
thing going on,
which I had never understand why people
want to pay all that money for a cow
that's basically like a job at the hut
cow that's like going to die like
bodies.
Just riddled with fat.
Like you,
you look at that meet and it's just like
that animal is sick.
That is a sick,
sick animal that's super unhealthy.
Oh,
it's so juicy though.
It's still delicious.
Just the best.
He's the best.
And the big thing there too though about
like the sustainability is the fact that
we're clearing forests to graze cattle.
Amazon,
you're 91% of the Amazon destruction has
been in Brazil.
It has been associated with grazing
cattle.
The um,
the assassinations too.
That was the other thing that you guys
covered when you showed that none who
got taken out by the cattle industry
allegedly down.
They're like,
Ooh,
that's it.
I mean the shot a none.
There was,
she was,
she spoke out against the cattle
industry because they killed was a good
documentary on her.
Yeah.
Dorothy standing at this thing and like
the,
the Hitman who was paid by a rancher to
kill her,
he went to prison for what?
One year?
Two years tried and then he got laid
off.
It was good documentary on him.
Over a thousand,
over a thousand forced activists have
been killed in Brazil.
And just what the past 20
years,
20 years.
And I'm this guy who,
who uh,
paid him off.
Did he get in trouble?
The guy who paid for this,
a hitman.
Oh No.
Did they name him?
Yeah.
Yeah,
that documentary.
It was a while ago.
But it's really good and just shows how
corrupt it is.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
Well Brazil,
especially when it comes to poverty,
it's a totally different situation.
Have you been well,
socks.
So you know,
this is my fee was my favorite favorite
country and then making this film,
I was like,
Eh,
I'm not going there for awhile.
It's not,
you know,
it's not everyone.
It's Brazil's awesome.
I love Brazil.
It's amazing.
Like,
uh,
I've been there probably six times.
The people are so friendly and so happy
and so proud to be Brazilian.
Like they love that you enjoy Brazil,
but whenever you have poverty,
man,
he uses a lot of haves and have nots in
Brazil.
There's a extreme poverty and extreme
wealth and there's,
it's weird when you go through
neighborhoods and you see really high
fences with barbed wire around them and
shit.
And I was like,
Whoa,
like this is a business.
It was kind of crazy.
Like these,
these like these really nice houses that
are protected,
like it's a prison,
you know?
It's unfortunate.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
But the,
the assassinations and everything,
um,
that they're having in Brazil,
it's all people that are trying to stop
the deforestation of the rain forest,
which is unbelievably devastating to the
tune of how,
what was it,
one acre?
How,
how long?
A minute.
It's up to one acre every second up to
every second.
Like a football field.
Think of a whole football field every
second.
Jesus Christ.
So right now up to,
or it varies too.
It varies depending on the year.
It went down for a few years and then
two acres a second.
And then a few years ago it went down
and then they just released the,
this law that made it go down.
Now they're backup back up again to
where it used to be.
That's literally unconceivable and
inconceivable.
And that's the thing too.
Then you look at the environmental
organizations,
you would think this would be their
forefront issue.
You know,
right now you go to any inbox or
rainforest action organization,
they're going to be talking about palm
oil and pulp in timber and dams and
fossil fuels when still today,
the leading causes of rainforest
destruction around the world life is
animal.
That's fascinating.
Um,
was anybody willing to talk to you guys
about that?
Not In the,
not Amazon much.
Amazon Watch Ya,
you know,
when it was kind of the turn of all
talking to all these groups and then
finally it was this big long drawn out
thing where she was kind of stumbling,
stumbling,
stumbling.
Finally she said,
you know what?
You're right there.
This is,
this is screwed up and this is the
reason why we're not talking about it.
And then,
you know,
these interviews are two hours long and
sometimes we go to these,
go to these screenings and you have
someone from Greenpeace or Sierra Club
and they say,
Oh,
you guys manipulated the editing of the
film.
It's like,
you know,
you watched the full edits to the film.
It's more bizarre.
It's more of a cover up.
So it was more fun.
You have that.
Who was accusing of us was accusing you
guys of manipulating the data all the
time.
When we go on tour,
some will stand up and they'll say,
they'll say the,
the edits of our interviews,
you know,
that was the most bizarre part and the
most funniest part,
they say you manipulated the edits to
make it the most funny or the most,
you know,
cover up and said,
say no.
If you see the longer edit to that,
it's worse than it appears.
Why don't you guys just put the long
edits on Youtube?
We're going to do,
we've been doing that,
but we,
uh,
we've been working on other stuff,
so,
whew.
Um,
it's just,
it's very,
uh,
very disconcerting to think that these
animal rights at are these,
um,
uh,
green peace activists and these
environmental activists and all these
different people that are involved in
this campaign to save the rain forest
are also maybe even taking money from,
you mean animal agriculture?
Is that,
is that,
I mean her to say?
Yeah,
I mean there's definitely,
there's links to shell that these,
some of these organizations do except
money straight from the industry.
And World Wildlife Fund doesn't make any
qualms about it.
They may get money from the,
uh,
beef industry.
Um,
but then you can also look at,
yeah,
who's on their board,
you know,
what's their background?
And it's,
and it's,
you know,
to be honest in all fairness is that
it's,
it's such a massive industry.
It's hard not to be associated them in
some way or another.
Um,
but you know,
Greenpeace's largest grant on record
comes from a guy who raises and
slaughters 40,000 animals for his
restaurants every year.
So it's like,
how are you going to speak at bad about
an industry when one of your huge donors
is doing that?
Now,
how do you decipher that?
Because do you say,
well,
maybe this guy who slaughters all these
animals for his restaurants that Ted
Turner.
Yup.
I knew it.
Um,
maybe he really is legit.
That's why I said Ted Turner,
because I think he legitimately does
have concerns about the environment.
It seems like a guy who really loves the
great outdoors.
He's massive ranches and it goes to them
and shit.
I mean,
I don't doubt that these organizations
really believe in what they're doing.
They,
they want to help the environment and
they do good work.
You know,
it's like the reason why we have a,
I think a big part of why we have an
environmental movement in the United
States is because of Greenpeace and
they've opened doors to be able to talk
about things and,
and I'm,
I'm so thankful for that.
But to fail to talk about,
you know,
kip has an analogy about,
the house on fire basically.
You know,
imagine a house that's burning on fire
and he's organization groups.
You know,
the Sierra Club's writing for a section
at work,
at green pieces.
They come houses on fire.
One of them comes and cleans the window
cause it's a little,
you know,
little dusty and other one dust counter
top one though those leaky faucet.
And meanwhile there's a bonfire in the
middle of the House that's burning the
house down.
That's a great analogy.
And that's essentially what's happening.
Yeah.
So I think they,
they are doing good work,
but they're failing to address the most
destructive industry.
Ted Turner's scenario.
Does he have you say he slaughters all
these animals for his restaurants?
Are they his own animals?
He has.
Does he have ranches and he grows these
cattle?
Yeah.
He said,
I think the second largest land owner in
the United States.
Um,
and so he raises really?
Yeah.
Wow.
Um,
and so therefore his restaurants,
the,
whatever they're called,
Ted's tag,
it's called teds and they aren't all
wildlife preserves,
you know,
their cow preserves.
So when he's growing these,
these cows,
like is he doing it in a sustainable way
and his property at least,
I mean he was he doing it.
He raises buffalo as well.
And,
and if you,
people are going to raise animals for
consumption,
they should be raising native species.
I mean,
I don't think people should be raising
animals is just super inefficient.
It's like 16 pounds of input to get one
pound out.
Um,
but you could at least do an indigenous
species.
And so cow nonindigenous where's it come
from?
Asia.
Really?
American cows confirmation.
Yeah.
Goddammit.
Think about that.
Texans greet and Chinese food.
I know what you think.
You think Merck and we'll sit down hill
at stake and then pure for pure
sustainability,
the most,
uh,
the most sustainable way to grow is
through factory farms.
If you're just talking,
not,
you know,
not efficiency,
nobody factory farms buffalo,
that seems like sin.
It's weird just seeing them in
supermarkets,
you know,
you can buy Bison.
So bizarre wasn't that on the only one
thing almost dead?
The ones that was most,
well,
the most bizarre thing was how many,
you know,
there's a guy named Dan Flores that
wrote a thing about bison
ecology.
It's really fascinating and I'm kind of
get him on the podcast,
but,
um,
his ascertation is that the native
Americans,
just with the introduction of firearms
and horses,
they would have probably wiped the
buffalo out.
Even like,
Gee,
you know,
without the Americans are without the
Europeans landing and becoming a part of
this.
But it wouldn't happen as quick cause
the,
the overall slaughter was fueled by
money.
You know,
the,
the hide slaughter,
I mean,
the amount of buffalo hides they were
getting,
and this is insane,
mean we've all seen the stacks of bones.
But,
uh,
he believes that the,
um,
what had happened was there had been a
massive decline in the population of
native Americans.
And during that time,
the buffalo grew to staggering
proportions that before that they had
kind of kept them in check more cause I
had eaten them.
But there was like a,
I believe there's like a 90% decline in
the populations of native Americans that
probably was linked to Europeans moving
here and giving them diseases that they
didn't have immune systems for.
Fascinating.
Fascinating subject,
obviously off of yeah,
but I mean guns,
germs and steel.
That's an awesome book.
Same similar sort of thing where it
talks about that,
that introduce technology to a
population and see what happens.
Well,
his,
um,
Flores is,
is it backs historical,
a recollections of,
um,
different people who had come before the
decline in native American populations
and they really didn't discuss bison
herds.
They didn't ever seen like these million
herds of Bison.
Like,
you know,
they described in the,
the 17 hundreds of people had gotten
there and be like,
what the fuck?
Just thunderous hills.
So that was kind of an imbalanced as
well.
So our idea of that being like,
it used to be a million buffalo,
eh,
for a very short period of time.
And that was a mistake.
And that was just a,
an imbalance that probably would have
been corrected by the introduction of
guns and horseback.
But Buffalo,
Dave,
even more grass and who require even
more land than cow do.
Right.
Yeah.
Um,
I,
you know,
I don't know if I bet efficiency like
per pound of meat they put on their
bones,
you know,
for what they consume I counts are
really efficient.
Um,
but they just eat different things too.
It's like they float too.
Yeah.
They call evolved with the grasses.
I mean there's a reason why they call it
buffalo grass is cause buffalo's
actually he never heard of buffalo
grass.
Yeah.
So that's like what the prayer is used
to be covered in was the buffalo wings,
different
tiny little buffaloes.
Miniature Buffalo.
There was a fucking episode of the
Jessica Simpson Show.
Remember she's delivered that dude
where,
uh,
she was trying to figure out how they
got wings from Buffalo,
allegedly.
She might've been playing dumb.
I Dunno.
Um,
it'd be fucking cool though.
Buffalo.
Well,
buffalo are dangerous as fuck too,
by the way,
ladies and gentlemen,
if you account or buffalo,
especially during the Rut in a yellow
stone,
get the fuck away from them.
They run you over,
they'll kill you.
They think you're going to kill them.
They're going to kill you.
They're wild animals.
Like people get fucked up by buffalo all
the time.
There's a hilarious video I saw this guy
wants to get clothes.
She's got to take a of these buffalo and
the buffalo just sees him.
Turns out,
he was like,
oh,
are you fucking kidding me?
And just charges at him to the man.
When I lived in Alaska,
you'd see tourists all the time going up
to bull Moose.
Just think they're going to get a
picture of me.
And literally they seen people walk up
to black bears just like,
oh,
like they're in a zoo.
Yeah.
People does not,
like,
people don't really understand the fact
that animals,
and that's really kind of all animals
are potentially very dangerous,
but particularly wild animals.
Well,
including people.
By the way,
you know,
we're just so used to this civil
environment where people can come up to
other people and say hi bears don't just
come up to bears and say hi.
They have to know the bear.
They have to be reasonably sure the bear
is not going to bite them in the face
and they get to know each other.
You know,
when a new bear comes into town,
it's a fucking war going on.
It's chaos.
Just like how it used to be with people.
So that's the world that a fucking moves
is living in.
You just can't walk up on that Moose
Dude that Louis is fighting off bears
all the time.
I mean,
imagine being a Moose in Alaska and you
have to deal with some potentially 10 11
foot tall,
gigantic furry monster that just eats
everything he can.
I mean,
what does a bear weigh?
A thousand fucking pounds a grizzly and
you think of that thing is just running
around looking for you.
You'd be on edge build little on edge.
So I'm fucking fat guy with a Las Vegas
visor on comes at you.
It lives iphone.
Fuck him.
They're going to trample that dude.
I think you're cute.
You're going to take a selfie with me,
bitch.
I live in a different world.
Motherfucker.
Trump.
Yeah,
they're,
they're gigantic man.
I saw my first moose couple of years ago
in Alaska.
I just couldn't believe it,
man.
I just couldn't believe how big they
were.
It's a,
yeah,
it's Saturday.
I was living in the interior about a
hundred miles from uh,
Fairbank's and he's like you some,
you see a bull moose,
you know,
mature Bull Moose.
You can feel like you'd walk right under
his stomach.
Yeah.
You probably could.
People have driven under them in car
accidents.
They made it underneath the car.
Just clip the roof on the underbelly of
the car.
Fuck.
Or an underbelly of the Moose.
Bison.
Bison in person is a faces about as tall
as you are.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
They're monstrous.
Monstrously huge and so fucking cool
looking at when you see a bison,
they seem like some star wars animal.
It really does seem like something from
star wars,
like with his crazy lion kind of main
thing going on.
You know they have the extra for in the
front and like what?
Like why did you grow so big?
Why did nature want you to be so fucking
enormous?
Just step destroyer of grasses and
either of grasses.
That's crazy.
Look at that thing.
Fuck.
I mean if that wasn't real and you saw
that in a movie,
that's a total star wars monster in
itself,
right?
Like you would see like some dude with
like black motorcycle goggles on it with
a metal helmet riding it.
It's going over the top of the hill.
And then what is the only thing he eats
his plants.
That's as crazy now it's like all the
skinny,
skinny a plant jokes,
but it's,
then you've got the gorillas and these
huge,
massive strong animal.
Sure.
Elk,
Moose,
all of them eating grasses.
Yeah.
Gorillas are real weird because they're
not just gigantic,
but they also have fangs and they're the
per pound per pound.
The strongest animal in the whole world
eaten Broccoli and shit.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
it's very strange when you see the d the
diversity of wildlife and you have to
think that all of this stuff,
if you believe that evolution bullshit,
all this stuff came from single celled
organisms and eventually,
you know,
evolved and changed and mutated and
adapted and random mutation pressure
from the environment and then they
became what they are now.
This is what a bizarre world we live in.
And I think that that's also a big part
of what's wrong with factory farming and
what's wrong with our disconnection from
our food is that we're very rarely
around animals.
And to the point where I think most
human beings think of it as like people
and animals,
but it's not,
it's life.
It's all over the place.
It was a lot of different life.
We've just cleared off most of it to
like all you see is like birds and
squirrels and you don't even think of
them cause they're around so often
though as another fucking bird shit on
my car asshole,
he drive off.
But when you're around wild life,
like if you've ever been in the woods
and seeing like,
you know,
a population of Fox walk by and you see
like the mama bear or in a couple of
cubs and you see these kinds of animals
in the wild and you realize like,
these fuckers are here.
They are.
They've been here,
they're staying,
they breed here.
This is normal.
They've been this way since Lewis and
Clark like hundreds of years ago.
They were just like this and they're
just like this right now.
We just never go into that world.
So we forget that worlds even there.
That's it.
I think we have a huge disconnect.
You know,
as you said,
from our food and from the natural
world.
It's like we live in concrete boxes and
we drive in cars and it's like we forget
that we are part of this whole system.
Um,
and that's,
I think a big part of what cowspiracy
does too,
is that remind people that you're part
of the system.
You know,
whether you want to or not.
Like you're part of the system.
You're dependent upon the atmosphere for
your air.
You're dependent upon the ground for
your water.
It's like you're presenting on the soil
for your food.
It's like this is it.
There's no way getting out of it.
Well,
this is the first time I think our
generation,
or I'm older than you guys,
I think,
um,
the generations of the last 20 years,
the people that are alive today,
let's just call it the people that are
awake and alive and paying attention
today.
This is really probably unprecedented
amount of understanding of the
consequences of the way we're living.
I don't,
I really don't think it's ever been like
this before.
We're so many people are so aware of
what has been set up and this system
that we're born into,
the system that we just,
we,
you know,
we went to school and we got to high
school and we got jobs and we became
part of it.
And we,
we,
and then as adults we start looking
around and going,
who fucking design the Democrats and the
Republicans?
That's it.
It's the only these fucking two people,
the only people and their idea,
why is this fucking wear this meat
sandwich come from?
How can I just go through this spot and
I could reach my hand out my metal box
with rubber tires and can this guy paper
and he gives me a ground meat sandwich.
I just drive off
that this cool.
The uh,
you know,
the film ends as a real inspiring ways
that people are turning on now.
You know,
so it's something just in the past
couple of years you can just kind of
feel it.
Like this transformation of just
information passes so fast.
You can't hide things from people.
Well,
do you think that,
do you worry at all that something like
that Patriot Act thing could be somehow
or another applied to people make
documentaries that expose?
We always like that.
When we made the film,
it was kind of how it went down.
You know,
when I,
we really took a step back,
we'd,
after we talked to Howard Lyman that
the,
the rancher,
he's scared,
he's scared the shit out of us.
He really did.
And we were talking once we released the
film,
should we go to Cuba for a couple of
months?
We were,
so we was,
he scared us and he says,
you know,
watch out.
You know,
this is serious shit.
And then so we realized finally,
you know,
what are we going to do if we just
stand,
stand back and do nothing,
stay silent,
we're all screwed.
You know,
the,
the fear of not doing something has to
supersede the fear of one individual
doing something.
You know,
we have to step up and all do something
because if not,
what are we going to live in a world
full of cows,
you know?
And that's in a monoculture of cows and
destruction and we're not going to be
run anyway.
So it was scary.
But now at the point it's been,
you know,
a year and a half since we released it
and we're already on door,
uh,
you know,
or new new project coming along right
now too.
So,
so you haven't had any blow back at all
when we released the film,
because we originally,
we did a crowd funding campaign,
we released the film and a week after we
premiered it,
beef magazine did a write up about the
film called [inaudible] magazine,
which apparently,
so he porn magazines,
like I think it's the other one.
Or is it a rap battle magazine?
It's a,
yeah.
So they do this write up called a why
ranchers should be concerned about the
documentary.
Cowspiracy and I saw,
hey,
this film's coming out.
It's got these stats and you should know
your numbers because this is coming down
the pipeline.
And we've had a couple other industries
say that sort of stuff.
And we get,
you know,
we get some threatening sort of messages
and facebook posts and stuff like that,
but boy,
they say,
ah,
you know,
just the same bullshit that anyone that
gets on the Internet.
Um,
but I guess a lot of people don't get
threats from the cattle industry.
Like what kind of,
I'm kind of threats are you giving?
Oh,
I mean it's,
you know,
you guys should fucking die.
Um,
you know,
I hope somebody fucking shoot you guys,
that sort of,
Whoa,
I hope somebody shoots you guys boys.
So why did they say,
I mean there's,
you were the film,
you know,
shows and exposes the atrocities of this
industry and that's a threat to a lot of
people's livelihood.
And so of course there's going to be
pushed back
saying that you should die because you
showed facts.
Yeah,
that's the thing we'd say,
nothing ourselves.
We do is interview people interview.
Well,
you,
you know,
you narrate a few of the facts and then
the numbers and statistics,
but
we're not telling anybody what to do.
Exactly.
How could someone say
that you should die because of that.
And uh,
you know,
one of the most emotional screenings we
went to Idaho because my dad's from
Idaho and um,
you know,
he's a rancher.
My grandfathers or interest,
both of them.
And so I very sympathetic to what
they're going through and what we,
what were,
you know,
there are next level of,
of switch that has to happen or we're
screwed.
You know,
what do they do?
Are they going to learn a new trade all
of a sudden,
like how to grow organic vegetables when
there's within been doing it's tough.
Well,
it's a giant issue also that a lot of
them are in debt.
A lot of them are barely getting by as
it is.
The world of being a farmer is
incredibly labor intensive and very
expensive and hard to turn a profit.
It's hard,
you know,
and we all know of farms that have gone
under him and that's why they started
those farm aid concerts and you know,
Willie Nelson was it John Mellencamp was
and a bunch of those kinds of,
I mean that was what that was all about.
Try to help the American farmer.
Yeah.
But I mean,
again,
it's about providing information.
Let people make up their own minds.
Um,
but so we had concern,
major concern about the film.
We just kind of let it go.
Um,
we just feel like,
hey,
we're protected by all the people who
back us up who supported the film.
Um,
and then Leonardo Dicaprio saw the film
and got super excited about it.
They caught in touch with us and his,
one of his producers,
Jennifer Davidson,
said,
Hey,
Leo saw your film,
loves it,
wants to be executive producer,
wants to take it to Netflix.
Actually took it to Netflix already and
they,
they're interested in taking the film
on.
Whoa.
Right away he brought it to Netflix
without asking,
not even talking to us,
which is awesome.
So gangster.
Yeah.
Um,
but so they,
you know,
of course they had major concern like,
hey,
Leonardo Dicaprio,
like a list celebrity,
biggest name.
Like he's putting his name on a super
controversial film.
And so we went through the film again
and we just scoured it for all of our
facts and back everything up.
So like on our website,
all the stats that we were throwing out
through this podcast and in the film or
on our website,
cowspiracy.com there's a fact page.
It has linked to every single study and
reference.
Um,
but so that was in major concern.
Like,
Hey,
once a huge name and this hits totally
mainstream,
went on Netflix back in September and
it's just blown up.
Um,
are we going to get even more pushback?
And so far we're,
you know,
I think the industry,
if the injury is smart,
which is questionable,
they'll continue to ignore us as best
they can because it's only going to draw
more attention if they come after us.
Is it possible that they can adapt?
Absolutely.
And that's the hall they do.
Well that's the awesome thing is that,
um,
you know,
silk soy milk was owned by one of the
largest dairy companies in the u s
because they looked at it and they said,
hey,
look,
we're losing part of our market to plant
based milks.
We should by plant based milks because
hey,
they're not really interested in hurting
animals.
They're not interested in hurting the
planet.
So I don't make money.
You want to make money.
So it's like when people switch over to
more sustainable foods,
that's where they see the money and
they're just going to follow the money.
So that's one of the real hopefuls for
me.
There was another dark part of the movie
is watching,
um,
dairy cows watching how they're
extracting the milk from and you're
like,
uhhh.
And that was,
that was the best farm.
I was like,
sure.
So the best,
kind of like when you said you visited
your buddy's farm,
we thought it was going to be nice and
like,
wow,
there's going to be kind of a weird part
of the film.
Cause you can see these beautiful cows
and that's just one of those,
they know their kids are up on the hill
face the other way and they hang out by
them.
Kind of stare at them.
And just this,
this,
you know,
thousand cows that the visceral feeling
you can feel in the air of just sadness.
It was,
that was the toughest day we went to a
slaughterhouse on fear factor once,
you know,
this,
this stunt they had to do in a
slaughterhouse.
And uh,
I remember the feeling that you got when
you were in the building.
It was like,
Whoa,
dude,
I give this is there's like a feeling in
the air here.
Like,
I don't want to be all hippie dippie woo
crystals and all that jazz.
But I really felt like you could feel
despair.
It was,
you could eat,
it was almost like a vibration that you
could detect.
Like this is very strange.
It's a very strange feeling.
And then it's like,
you know,
those animals feel that and then it goes
into adrenaline and all of these
hormones are pumping through their
system the moment that they're killed
and then you're eating that.
And um,
I was maybe that's a good point for,
so talking about fear,
uh,
addressing the animal agriculture
industry.
We were going to make an announcement on
your show.
Super stuck that we are making our new
film and it's called what the health,
that the exact same thing is happening
to the health industry,
the leading cause of diseases,
heart disease,
diabetes,
cancer is from eating animal products.
And the same thing's happening in the
American Cancer Society,
the American diabetic society.
All these organizations are not telling
the information that's coming out of all
these facts.
That's,
you know,
countless medical studies of what's
really killing us and causing diseases.
Um,
so that's coming out here soon too.
So that's exciting.
So what are the facts as far as like
what's causing cancer and how has that
been proven?
So there's been a couple of studies that
show,
I mean there's the obvious ones.
Like the World Health Organization just
announced that the processed meat is
linked to colon rectal cancer.
Okay.
So process me being meet with chemical
preservatives,
they included Bacon,
Ham,
um,
you know,
all process meet with chemical
presented.
They put it in the same category as a,
our cynic can't,
it's carcinogenics yes.
Exact same category as tobacco smoking.
And that was after thousands of studies.
And that blew people away because they
cannot believe they actually announced
that I was one of the biggest things.
And um,
and then now all these other
organizations,
they're slowly,
you know,
kind of putting in the back of their,
their website,
maybe mentioning it,
maybe not.
So we're doing the same thing in this
film is that word or interviewing these
organizations and uncovering,
and it's so crazy out.
It's like the exact same thing as
cowspiracy.
Um,
but there have also been studies linking
grassfed beef to healthy fats and that
it's actually healthy for you to eat
grass fed animals.
So I think what you're talking about is
just preservatives.
She's talking about chemically processed
animals unfortunately now.
And because like the World Health
Organization's showed that red meat
unprocessed,
just broad red meat is off,
there's type two carcinogen.
And how are they making that
distinction?
Like how,
what are they following?
People that ate a healthy diet,
healthy vegetables as long with red
meat,
they'll do these huge,
um,
like the epic health study,
which has fallen,
you know,
250,000 people,
uh,
for over the last 40 years.
And so there's these massive population
studies.
Um,
but you know,
the,
the studies and that's something we go
into in the film because there was
there,
you can look at it and be like,
Hey,
red meat causes heart disease.
And then you'll have another study.
It says,
no,
you know,
these meats are actually good for you.
And then you just look at the funding so
well who funded the studies and the
fund,
the studies who are saying that meat's
bad for you are funded by universities
and the studies are saying this stuff is
good for you.
It's funded by the industry.
I mean like literally paid for by the
American beef council.
And then,
I mean this film is crazy.
You're going to probably crazier in a
way than cal spirit.
Cause we also add in the link that we
didn't have to deal with in the first
issue.
You're talking about like fear and
stuff.
The pharmaceutical company,
how they're tied into this trinity.
You know you have the anti culture
industry of the lobby group,
you have the government,
you have the health organizations.
Then you have the,
the pharmaceutical companies that profit
off people getting sick from eating
their products.
So you have this crazy,
so you're saying the pharmaceutical
companies that profit off of people
getting sick from eating meat support
meet because they willingly are aware.
Willingfully are aware that people are
getting sick from them and they want to
make sure that they have unhealthy
people to treat.
We look,
you've got,
you have a $2 trillion stint industry,
you have,
you don't have literally trillion dollar
industries who make,
uh,
drugs and who make,
you know,
surgeries.
They don't want that to go away.
They want that to continue.
So you,
but you really think they're actively
trying to keep people unhealthy.
I mean,
you know,
again,
it's just about inflammation.
It's about suppressing information.
It's about suppressing.
It's not,
you know,
want to keep upl keeping people healthy.
It's,
again,
you look to these,
you look to these whole,
to health organizations,
that's what you look to,
to tell us the truth.
You look at the environmental groups,
they're suppressing this information of
the thousands of thousands of studies
upon studies that have this information
over and over.
Yet it's not being told to us.
Right?
But the pharmaceutical companies,
do they even have to suppress
information?
Most people willfully ignore
information.
So why would they go out of their way to
suppress information when it doesn't
seem like there's any sort of pressure
or trend so that people to get
healthier?
Absolutely.
But it's pretty interesting when you
follow,
you look at these health organizations,
you look at their donors,
they're their biggest donors are
pharmaceutical companies.
And the next second biggest donors are
meat and dairy producers.
So do you think that that's to ensure
that people stay ignorant?
I think that the,
the simple fact if you have diabetes
type two diabetes leading cause of type
two diabetes is from eating animal
proteins.
Um,
yeah.
But it was,
here's the problem with saying that the,
they're eating other things as well.
And how are you monitoring these
people's diets?
Are you making sure that you're watching
what these people put in their body?
They're not putting in processed foods,
are not putting in chemicals,
they're only eating meat and vegetables.
Okay.
Are they only eating me like what the
fuck are they eating?
How do you know this awesome thing?
There's a study,
a NIH study that looked at follow
people's diets for,
I think four years.
Huge Group of people and looked at just
that,
you know,
it's like,
Hey,
what is the role?
What is the link?
And so I or mental,
yeah,
exactly.
Been cities.
Yeah,
totally.
And so the stress levels,
all the huge,
huge,
uh,
all the different aspects.
Then they took just animal products out.
They left them have their total shitty,
you know,
die at sea and just totally processed
crappy sugar food.
They monitor these people or they let
these people report their diets and
there's a couple,
there's at least five studies that have
done similar sort of things and I think
some of them had been straight like
monitored and how many people were
talking about in these studies?
Thousands and thousands.
Thousands of people that they need aid
report their diet and then told them
they couldn't eat meat but they could
eat shitty foods.
Yeah.
They sat and they listened while,
I mean that's far as we know.
Yeah,
I know.
Totally.
I mean I think I,
high level skepticism is totally needed.
It got to a point when it's study after
study after study and there's this
corollary,
see I haven't seen study after study
after study is these things are talking
about digging deep and investigating.
You know,
people have been eating meat forever,
right?
And so it's,
it's this link between carbohydrates and
fat.
So you can eat,
you can eat a high fat diet,
right?
And low carbohydrates and you won't
necessarily develop diabetes.
Devoted genic ketogenic diet is also
prevents diabetes,
not diabetes.
Epilepsy,
right?
That's a huge issue in children when
they started giving them high fat diets,
they're finding that low carbohydrate,
high fat diets that introduce a state of
Ketosis is actually very good at
preventing symptoms of epilepsy in
children.
My partner,
she works with a younger with epilepsy
and she's on the kid.
It's amazing.
But she's actually,
she's brought Vegan too even and still
ketogenic so you can still not avocado
oil,
peanut oil.
Um,
but you know at that doesn't necessarily
protect you from heart disease,
diabetes,
right?
So when you eat a high carbohydrate,
high fat diet,
so that's when you develop.
Now what about sedentary lifestyle?
What about all the different factors
that come into play?
We're keeping about a person's body
health.
They're like our preferred that one of
the primary factors in cardiovascular
disease is sedentary lifestyle is the
fact that your body atrophies as much as
your muscles atrophy and your back
deteriorates,
your heart does as well.
And that a lot of that can be mitigated
with exercise.
And then one of the correlations that
people are ignoring when they study diet
and the Diet and in relationship to
people's health is what are they doing
with their body?
What is the,
was the physical daily activity level of
their body and how much is that factored
in?
Because you can't just factor in a
person's diet.
That's like your body is a machine,
your body is this biological diverse
machine that is a whole ecosystem inside
of it.
And if you don't stress it,
and if you don't force it to work,
it gets weak.
It just does.
If you don't demand resources,
it will
slowly deteriorate slowly.
But we explore that too.
You know how much a exercise has a role
and it's huge.
It's massive.
But you still have to clean your engine
out.
You have to clean your pipes out,
you know,
and that's what it's doing.
It's,
it's pumping the engine.
But when you have a clogged arteries,
there comes a point where it can be
dangerous.
And if,
uh,
you know,
you just do a clean diet for even,
try 30 days or something,
all that flushing out of you and when
you're sitting on the toilet for four or
five times a day,
uh,
our of 10 times a day,
it's just flushing all this shit inside
of you and even your extra hours
exercising every time a day.
That's just,
that's trying to process this food that
you're putting into it,
that it can't do just their exercise,
but there's not food.
It's like laying inside your body.
That's a myth.
There's not like caked food inside of
people's by like that whole idea that
every moon of six pounds of undigested
meet and you're dead if that's the case.
But you do have plaque building up in
your arm.
There's definitely plaque.
But again,
that speaks to a person's level of
physical activity.
There's different nutritional demands
for someone that has a rigorous physical
activity schedule and someone who does
it and when you give your body the same
amount of food is someone who like say a
fucking sprint or something like that
were a marathon runner,
someone who's,
they're constantly burning off fuel.
If you give your body,
if you have a sedentary lifestyle in
front of a computer sitting in a cubicle
all day and you give your body the same
amount of food that the person who's a
jogger consumes,
you're going to get fat and fucked up
because you're taking in too many
calories and that's a contributor,
a massive contributor to heart disease.
That has to be considered always.
Definitely.
When you're talking about what's going
on with the person's body,
then you've got bio diversity,
like where are these people from?
Like what?
What part of the world are their
ancestors from?
Because your,
your genetics have different biological
requirements.
We go into genetics,
we have a whole chapter on genetics
edge.
What does genetics was only,
I mean,
well as far as diseases,
but as far as diet too,
I mean that's,
that's another side subject that we get
into it.
So that's one of the aspects that I've
looked going to back to the lifestyle
and exercise.
There's huge study that just came out.
It's 40,000 people in Sweden and they
showed that having a,
being active versus Allah,
it's a little bit different,
but it looked at the difference between
someone who exercises all the time who's
overweight and someone who is skinny,
who sedentary.
You are less likely to die from being
sedentary and skinny than being
overweight and active.
Oh,
that makes sense.
Right,
and we'll also,
you're dealing with someone whose body
has gotten to a point where it's
deteriorated so poorly that the actual
stress of exercise can be detrimental.
Exactly.
Like there's some people that they
actually say like,
look,
before you engage in any sort of
exercise,
you're going to have to lose weight and
you're going to have to change your diet
and give your body a lot of nutrients.
Like you,
you have a really nutrient deficient
diet.
I'm going of course osteoporosis.
There's a lot of different diseases that
people get from having nutrient
deficient diets.
It's a big contributed to it.
That's why when women have to give them
calcium.
So one of the things that mitigates it.
Yeah.
Well I mean,
so this is,
this new film goes into huge depth about
it.
Similar to cowspiracy,
it's just packed full of information.
My point about this disease thing like
saying that it causes cancer and all
these things,
it's not just trying to be skeptical
just for no reason.
They said what?
What is stopping these people from
eating nutrient rich vegetables and you
know and and really
broad variety of nutrient rich foods as
well as meat.
Well,
if you did that,
would that be bad for you?
If you had a rigorous exercise schedule
and you took care of your body,
you drank a lot of water and you ate
nutrient dense foods as well as me,
what kind of cancer you getting there?
Because that's really how people are
supposed to live.
Like it's not necessarily that the only
problem is that they're eating meat,
that that may be a problem.
But it may not be.
It may be a problem just because your
body's just shit cause you're not doing
anything with it.
Yeah,
I mean it's,
it's definitely not something the film
explores.
It says the associations to these strong
associations between certain types of
foods and lifestyle.
So that's what the whole film is about.
It's what the health,
cause it's asking that question.
It's like what the hell is going on with
our health in the United States.
There's another study that came out
recently that talked about living in
urban environments takes 10 years off
your life,
like where you were breathing in brake
dust all the time and not even thinking
about it.
Everybody's worried about carbon dioxide
and the poison that comes out of,
you know,
exhaust engines from engines but brake
dust fucking terrible for you.
And it's,
it's a leading polluter of waterways and
the stuff that washes off into the
ocean.
It's like there's something to be
considered about that as well.
It's totally,
it's crazy.
There's so many stats,
which is we've been editing nonstop.
So it's like,
you know,
running on three hours of sleep that I
want to share about how just eating once
a week when you add the f cancer,
was it diabetes?
How just like once a week,
how it raised a certain percentage of
coming back again,
just one time a week.
What do you mean by eating once a week?
For example,
like eating,
if you have a woman who has had breast
cancer by eating one serving of whole
dairy a day increases her chance of
dying from breast cancer.
Okay.
You weren't being clear on,
unfortunately what you're saying,
but once a week or eating two servings
of processed meat a day increases your
chance of developing.
I mean,
yeah,
day though,
it increases your chance of dying from
colorectal cancer by 40%.
I mean,
it's just a huge,
huge correlations.
Um,
it's,
again,
it's a huge,
whole complex issue.
Just in the same way cowspiracy when we
went into doing cowspiracy,
we went in,
you know,
just looking,
looking at the information and just
presenting it all and just finding out
where,
where's the study's coming from,
what are their sources?
And then we're doing the same thing with
this film.
It's,
it's really shaping up to be,
uh,
I mean it's heavy.
It's scary.
It's got comic aspects of the same like
cowspiracy does.
Um,
super controversial.
And again,
it doesn't tell people what to do.
It's just provides the information that
allows people to make up their own
minds.
And You bring up great points
though about exercise and all of those
stuff.
And we'll also in,
in consuming nutrient rich foods,
like in saying that meat is the issue.
Well no one is always a big one.
Like the days the dairies just not
fucking good for you.
Yeah,
it tastes awesome.
Now unfortunately it's great with
cookies,
but it's just not,
it's not good for you.
It's,
it's,
it's creates a lot of phlegm and you
know,
raw milk is better than,
than homogenized,
pasteurized milk.
But you know,
it's not the best shit for you.
Right.
But my point being like,
how can you isolate that it is the
consumption of meat causes cancer and
not the lack of nutrients from nutrient
dense foods along with me.
And is it an imbalance in the diet or is
it meat causing cancer?
Well,
it's Kinda,
that's what they did.
So that's a big part of it.
There's so much correlations to the
tobacco industry that happened about 20
years ago to the meat and dairy
industry.
Kind of like how Keegan was saying.
You see these other studies that you'll
hear of,
um,
you know,
the,
the butterfat is good for you.
The cholesterol is good for the brain,
the brain,
uh,
grain brain.
And then you see who is funding.
You know,
you look deep into it.
Is that,
um,
is that where the studies come from and
what,
what the,
the,
you know,
there's a new movie out.
Have you seen merchants of doubt?
Amazing.
And that's what's happening with this
industry.
All you have to create his doubt and
people playing that movie if you want,
because people might not have seen it
and it's really an important movie,
but it basically explores,
and that's a big part of this film and
it happened.
The tobacco industry,
you don't have to prove that to,
to that cigarette smoking is going to
kill it.
You just have to just put a little bit
of doubt,
just a little bit of doubt.
And it just like,
remember when butter was on the cover of
time and then everybody,
oh my God,
butter or you know,
just recently about how let us or bacon
was,
um,
more lettuce was more sustainable than
Bacon and,
and it's like,
Oh God,
thank God.
Now I can eat a bacon.
And just that little bit of doubt.
And if that's all you have,
then boom,
you got them.
So the tobacco industry did that for
years and years.
And just like you're talking about how
do they know these studies?
Because there's thousands of studies and
then there'll be one,
two,
three of these other ones.
And there was one,
two,
three.
Oh my God,
that's the one I want to see it hired
these people to go on these shows and,
and argue against the idea that tobacco
smoke was cancerous.
And so they did it in such a voice,
Juror,
boisterous,
loud,
robust way that people started believing
that.
And now you have the,
you know,
the Paleo and the,
the butter,
you know,
the,
the fat,
the fat is good for you.
You have these very strong personalities
that top,
this isn't people though that were doing
it about the environment.
That's what was confusing and scary.
These guys that they were working for,
the tobacco companies initially then
started doing it about issues with the
environment.
And you realize that the same people and
you're like,
what in the fuck?
Like,
Whoa,
this is great.
And then you find out where they're
getting paid.
You,
you're like,
this is so transparent.
Right?
And then now it's the mean their
industry.
It's kind of like the last to fall of
these.
Um,
and then that's when it comes down to,
uh,
you know,
where a,
where it's getting funded and where that
merchant of doubt,
where were those guys working now?
Where,
where does this,
this,
uh,
industry where they're putting their of
marketing?
Well,
there's a lot.
It's going to the one of most,
if not the most powerful industry in the
entire planet mean dairy.
Well,
I think we can all agree that as human
beings,
what we need for sure is access to
information about things that affect us
when it comes to health and when it
comes to diet.
When it comes to when you,
when you find out that studies,
like I used to do this joke about,
um,
I'm sure you're aware that the
partnership for drug free America,
it was funded by alcohol and tobacco
companies and pharmaceutical companies.
That's where they got all their money
from and they would do these commercials
against pot.
And I said that's like hookers doing
commercials against strippers.
It's the most ridiculous fucking shit
ever.
But if you ever watched those proposed
postures,
commercials,
like the girl with the talking dog,
she comes home from school and her dogs
toner stop getting high,
like that's funded by pill companies.
And the idea behind that,
that that could be legal,
that you can do that and then you could
put that commercial on television and
not say,
hey the pill co partnership for drug
free America.
Like what does that mean?
Drug companies stopping other business.
That's exactly what it is.
And we need information and we needed to
be really clear.
And if you are trying to stop
information like that stupid fucking
part of the Patriot Act,
we try and stop information from getting
to people that is on American.
Okay.
That is non progressive.
That is something that we shouldn't
allow in this age of information.
You can't stop information when it
pertains to the health and the,
the,
the ethical considerations of an entire
population of a country.
You just fucking can't.
Exactly,
exactly.
And that's again what our whole mission
is just providing information.
Like people say like,
Hey,
don't tell people how to live their
lives.
I'm full on.
Don't tell people how to live it.
And you didn't.
Yeah.
The first way you get someone to put up
a wall is tell them what to do.
Like give them the information,
allow people to make their own minds.
And that's exactly what we're seeing.
We're seeing people making massive
lifestyle changes and political changes
based off of our first film.
Cowspiracy um,
and you know,
the potential again,
is there for,
for any film to do that,
just give the information unbiased.
Let people decide for themselves.
And,
and that's where I'm super excited about
the new film for that reason,
that it's,
it's another chapters,
another window into a world that we
haven't really gotten to see before.
Well,
wherever there's money,
right,
you're going to have someone who's
trying to make more of it and trying to
stop any information that gets out,
it's going to prevent them from making
more of it.
And money's just sort of fines,
holes and cracks and leaks through.
And that's a,
that's sort of like a river or
something.
And they're like,
streams of water just finds a way
through this.
That's what's so cool.
Like at the end of the film where we
show that it was so dark in the making
the food of actually making it.
And we said,
you know,
let's look if there's a glimmer of hope.
And then we saw these,
you know,
these plants,
uh,
beyond meeting the beyond egg.
And then we found out Bill Gates and
the,
uh,
the guys from twitter,
they're putting their money into these
new,
these new plant based foods because they
see this as the future.
You know,
these billionaires look five,
10 years down the road
and that's where they're putting their
money.
So now the money's going.
They're not ethically I nine for the
environment.
They're doing it because they see it's
making money.
Now this is also happening a few plants
that have a full amino acid profile,
right?
There's only a few plants that are
complete proteins.
It's like Keywan hamp and there's a few
other ones.
Well they all have a complete,
they all have all the amino acids.
It's just they haven't been different
levels.
So it's like,
you know,
you have your 23 amino acids,
there'll be high and six and low and you
know the others,
but they don't all have the same amino
acids that meat does.
Yes.
So they have all,
all of them do.
Every,
every plant that has protein,
like Broccoli has protein.
So Broccoli has all the amino acids
that,
uh,
does as far as I know.
Yeah.
And so what it is,
cause they used to be that belief that
you had to combine foods.
And so it's like,
yeah,
to eat brown rice and Broccoli.
But the truth is,
is that just eat a very diet and you get
the exact levels that you need.
Um,
the belief of in like that eating meat
is,
is the,
you know,
has the amino acids that are closest to
our own proteins.
It's,
well then that logically we should eat
human beings.
That'd be the healthiest food to eat,
but that's not really the healthiest
food for people.
Why would that be the case though?
That that's the whole basis of that like
meat,
that's where the amino acids is arguing
that.
Right.
And with what they're saying is that you
should eat what we've eaten up until
now,
like all the thousands of years of human
development we've developed specifically
for certain diets.
That's why biodiversity,
when you talk to people from different
parts of the world,
they might require different nutrients
because their genetics have adapted to
the nutrients that are in their
environment.
Right?
Right,
right.
So no one's saying that you should eat
people.
And so it's kind of disingenuous
argument,
right?
Well,
yeah,
but I mean,
but to say that we have to eat meat
because that's often the argument is
that well we have to eat these foods.
And they're saying,
I think what they're trying to,
sorry to interrupt you,
but I think they're saying to optimize,
to optimize your performance,
your health,
your vitality,
that animal based proteins are more
efficient.
And that's the part or you know,
film goes into like efficiency,
efficiency in long endurance athletes,
you know,
say you're talking about ritual are
Scott Jurek,
you know,
the,
the biggest,
longest,
the most healthiest longer south athlete
right now.
Just Scott Jurek,
he's strictly on a plant based Diet
because it's the most efficient form of,
you know,
converting,
right?
But you're talking about endurance
athletes,
you're talking about skinny guys that
run a long time.
You're not spending an hour talking
about,
look when you,
if you looked at like mixed martial
artists for example,
or boxers or explosive athletes that
have to optimize the physical capacity
of their body.
There's very,
very,
very few that have vegan diets.
And few have tried it and they felt
weak.
Uh,
John Fitch was one of them.
John Fitch who did it,
I believe for ethical reasons also
because he wanted to try to optimize his
health.
He just found himself to be much weaker
when it was on a Vegan Diet.
It's a big thing about that.
I mean there's the Mac Danzek,
he was,
you know,
Vegan.
Yes.
And again,
mack,
who's a good fighter,
never reached a championship level.
He was very smart guy,
very intelligent guy and did it for all
the right reasons and a real
environmentalist and I'm very aware of
guy and she's a real brilliant guy all
around,
but he never reached that championship
potential that some feel that you need
to eat animal based protein and it's
just an argument for that.
Yeah,
I mean it's definitely,
it's an interesting argument.
I think the big,
the big part of is that there's so few
vegan athletes right now.
I think you're right.
I think that is in a population there's
only 1% of vegans.
So you know if that person,
and what's the percent of percentage of
an elite athlete,
right 0.01 add to elite athletes.
What percentage of elite athletes are
vegans actually looking into that?
Because you know,
depending on what you're looking into,
long durrance like when Carl Lewis,
when he was at his peak,
he said he was completely vegan when
he's at his peak.
But he was also on steroids.
No,
no.
Yeah.
How does help?
Um,
I mean,
you know,
he was caught with something.
He was caught with some sort of a
stimulant.
It was at the same time that Glen
Johnson was caught or Ben Johnson
rather,
you know,
when Ben Johnson was caught with
steroids,
Carlos is caught with something too.
And Carlos had been caught with other
things before.
Like,
you know,
when I had,
I'm Victor Conte in here,
it was with the ball ball co guy.
And um,
he sort of explained all the,
uh,
the different modalities and methods at
these.
He's like every track and field athletes
dirty.
He's like,
they're all dirty.
He,
and he was saying the same thing about
Tour de France.
He's like this idea that these guys are
doing it clean bullshit.
They're all dirty.
So when you say these guys are doing
amazing,
they're on a plant based diet and epo
and testosterone and hgh and blood
doping and,
but like you said,
a lot going on everyone else's too.
Yes,
that's true.
So one thing that the strongest guy in
Germany puts a Patrick boot Patrik
strung guy in Germany,
one strong man,
his job,
one of those barrel toss and characters,
world record holder.
He's the yet has two Guinness Book of
World Records for Yolk lifts and just
super beast.
100% Vegan.
Interesting.
But you know,
I think that it's,
it's one aspect of it.
Yeah.
You're saying like we're machines and so
it's like put the right fuel in the
machine to run it.
I'm the wrong guy to have this
conversation with you guys honestly
because I just don't know enough and I
would love to have some sort of someone
who really understands human physiology.
That's why I don't want to throw out
numbers cause there's so much editing
we're still going through.
It's just blowing our mind though.
It's,
you know,
someone from the Paleo community that's
really small,
like a Rob Wolf guy would be a good guy
to talk to you guys.
And that's the other thing too,
is that we're,
I don't think we're even equipped to
make the arguments because we're not
running to doctors.
Right,
right.
I mean it's the same thing with
cowspiracy.
People want to argue with us on
statistics and say,
hey look,
we're just reporting what other people
have.
Oh boy it be,
if I wanted to get two guys together,
like a rob wolf and then a scientist
who's supporting the Vegan Diet,
who would those two?
Garth Davis,
Davis.
Just because there's a few people who
just go off on the whole Paleo Paleo
thing from,
from a physiological level to,
you know,
to every single level of what Paleo is
actually really ate and what they will
consume that sort of that,
it's just the name.
I think the problem is with the name
Paleo,
but the idea
of people eating things that are easily
digestible,
that's normal food like lettuces and
grasses and vegetables and meats and
chicken and fish.
Like that's,
that's what their ideas about.
Davis is a good one.
He's,
yeah,
he's a character too.
That would be cool.
That'd be cool.
Okay.
All right.
That guy,
Connie,
he's wanting to try to fly the wealth
that will give you a contact if you want
us.
You know,
people always complain that I have these
one sided conversations with people like
you guys and I don't bring anybody into
and then I'm stuck trying to do it
myself and I'm feel equipped.
Garth Davis,
that's the one cool thing I think about
your show is that you have,
you have super eclectic guests.
You have people from so many different
spectrums.
Like,
um,
I mean again from from one end of,
you know,
Hardcore Paleo sort of folks to,
to Yara friend retro who says hi by the
love.
That dude is awesome.
He's awesome.
Awesome Guy,
great,
great guy.
Yeah.
Plant base and durrance athletes.
So I try to have an open mind
been as,
as possible while trying to enjoy this
experience and watch what your health,
when it comes out loud,
what the health when it comes out.
And you'll get two hours of sleep when,
I'm sorry.
Um,
yeah.
Well I'll definitely watch it 100%.
I think you guys did a fantastic job
with this documentary.
I really do.
And I think,
I hope that,
uh,
you know,
as I said that I think information is
the most important thing.
And when people were trying to deny
information or restrict information
based on the worry that they're gonna
lose money because they're doing
something unethical,
that should be a fucking crime.
It shouldn't be a crime that you filmed
that,
that that shouldn't be a crime.
It shouldn't be a crime that you show
someone kicking a fucking cow,
beating over the head with a
sledgehammer.
Like we have seen.
If you watch those videos,
it shouldn't be a crime to film.
That should be a crime to do that.
And it should be a crime to support
that,
that that's,
it's fucked up.
It's,
it's against what people want in this
day and age.
And I think the analogy of like finding
out that slaves make your genes is
right.
It really is.
I mean,
it's probably worse because you're
eating it,
you know,
it's,
it's a different thing because it's
actually becoming a part of your body is
just as bad or not worse or whatever.
It's bad.
Why am I quantifying?
Um,
is there anything else you guys would
like to say?
40 ramps up.
Uh,
you know,
thanks so much for having us.
We really pleasure.
Encourage people to go to our website,
cowspiracy.com again,
it has all the stats and statistics has
a link to a weekend spots.
The film on Netflix,
we had a book that just came out that,
uh,
called the sustainability secret that
covers even more statistics and
information and behind the scenes stuff
that happened in the film.
I can get that through our website as
well and then check out our new film,
what the health,
you can find that through our website.
kasperowski.com
all right folks,
um,
anything else?
Would you like to just,
thank you very much.
My pleasure.
I appreciate you guys coming on and I
really enjoyed your documentary,
so congratulations on an awesome job.
And,
uh,
what the health,
I'll check that out too.
All right,
folks,
that's a,
that's it for this week.
We'll be back next week.
Lots of fun.
Uh,
enjoy your weekend.
See you soon.
Bye.
Okay.