Cats don't give a fuck. They don't
give a fuck. My Cat's killer.
Oh Dude. They're ruthless. Ruthless,
ruthless. Just kills everything.
Anything they can.
Yeah.
If you ever seen the numbers for how
many things cats kill in North America?
No Bill Yin's of birds.
Billions. Billions.
Billions. Billions of mammals and
billions of birds. So gangsters,
they kill them and don't even eat
them. No, they just kill him. Yeah.
Cause they like the sport.
They're monsters. Yeah.
And just brings him and drops him in
my kids' beds. Like this question,
people also ask to cats,
kill birds.
I keep leaving my birds and they're dead.
Fluffy would never do that.
He's a Sweeney.
I didn't see a feather
in his full well there.
You know Mike am I cat drops,
rodents,
all my children's hair while they sleep
in her bed.
Oh my God.
Dropped a rat and my daughter's bathroom
leak in her shower cap to mark his
territory. The rat was just
scared shitless and was rather,
we couldn't still alive.
It's like behind the toilet and
stuff and we finally got it out.
I might do the next day it goes to put
on a shower cap and it's just filled with
pee,
pee
fucking die from disgusting.
She know that you can get leprosy
from armadillos. No, of course.
I don't know that.