Okay,
three,
two.
What the fuck are you saying Joey?
I said that once you clean for 29 days
without smoking reefer.
That's it.
Why go back?
Yeah,
I like it.
No,
if I fucking stayed clean from reef for
29 days,
I go,
I'd let my lungs fucking hill from the
abuse I have inflicted on him.
The last 30 fucking edibles.
What about spring?
First of all,
I haven't had another bull since,
like I broke it in Boston September
29th.
So out of respect for Sobrato,
but I didn't do another book.
I haven't done that at booth.
Something was wrong with my stomach so I
figured out how I was a lactose
intolerant,
lactose intolerant.
I fucking eat much cheese or milk and
I'm fucking up,
you know,
it's a nightmare.
So I had to cut that out of my diet.
No much without cheese.
American cheese now know Swiss no more.
No Cuban sandwich is really fucking
crazy.
And then I had to cut out the edibles
that give me a weird feeling like he had
just gone,
just gone somewhere else and I didn't
like the hunger issue.
Oh,
the munchies,
the hunger issues after 11:00
with just monstrous.
Like here I am working hard to lose
weight.
I'd stick to it and then I go home.
I start with an apple,
another apple banana,
another banana.
Then you got to bust out the Salami
Sandwich with the fucking,
you know,
it was just a.
It was just getting bad.
I could not control it.
CanNot uncontrollable to hunger from
edibles every minute after 11:00
for me was uncontrolled.
Well you can't blitzkrieg do.
You don't just get to know and it's
totally.
It was starting early.
Two in the afternoon can pop another
tool at fucking six.
Do you like vaporizing?
No.
Just smoking.
I thought your lungs,
you don't.
Vape is at a hotel party.
Started in the morning while I'm having
coffee in my hotel room.
Writing my notes for the thoughts of the
day because I don't wake up with hunger.
She,
that was my problem.
All those years I would need to one,
if you want to be a fat fuck the only to
one when you wake up because then you
gotta make up for it.
The rest of the day,
so now I have to force myself to eat.
What do you mean?
Because how do you guys like the
intermittent fasting?
I can't live with that money mean my
shit goes up and down.
My blood pressure,
my blood sugar so I could never have
intermittent fast.
But in the old days I'd be coked up and
I'd wake up speedy still.
I wouldn't eat breakfast,
but I started eating at one or 2:00
and would not stop till fucking do in
the morning you saw me eating those pink
dots sandwiches like they will not to
meatball sandwiches the 12:00
because I wouldn't eat breakfast.
I forced to eat,
you know,
for years we was eating every six hours
as opposed to a smaller portion.
You know what I'm saying?
So yeah,
that's what people were thinking.
I got a breakfast and I got two egg
yolks,
a piece of wheat toast and fruit and I'm
good like for Sobrato,
but I gave a bacon.
I only two pieces of Bacon.
It's 45 points on weightwatchers.
That's all I'm allowed,
but at least I'm allowed two pieces of
bacon to pieces.
Megan's all you really need.
That's all you need.
Two pieces of Bacon.
Let me tell you what I was for 18.
Between you and I,
my wife,
who's on the south would make the whole
packet of Oscar Meyer Center Cut Bacon,
the whole pack every morning.
That was my breakfast.
Eat the whole package.
The whole package with three eggs,
a half a loaf of wonder,
bread and butter and a 16 ounce coke.
The boot.
A coke on top of it.
Oh yeah.
I could drink two cokes for breakfast.
Oh,
remember I grew up in the east coast and
I caught a bad habit early on after my
mother died.
I caught that and I wouldn't eat it on.
I would leave and eat at the Deli.
I went on the member one fucking cream
cheese and jelly on a.
on a roll was big.
Oh yeah.
You know what that does to your system?
Clear cheese and jelly.
For breakfast I used to.
I used to open up with cream cheese and
jelly on a poppy seed role with a 16
ounce of coke for breakfast for years
and I was in shape that that's the
thing,
you know,
you can't be with liver.
Remember that?
Nobody eats cream cheese and jelly for
breakfast on a roll.
No more cream cheese and jelly.
No,
because people know better now in Jersey
and those diners,
they got those brand muffins.
You go in there and get those bran
muffins.
They put them on the grill with butter
on them.
Good Google.
Oh my goodness.
You just chop now.
I got.
I got young.
I'm done.
It's not going to bran muffin with
raisins in it and when I know Butler and
nothing,
but they cut them in half on the east
coast.
Those east coast breakfast as well.
How long have you been doing this
weightwatchers thing now?
Since December ninth.
So almost a year.
Eleven months now.
Eleven months ish.
Thirty.
Pretty good.
Thirty pounds.
So that's nice and that's a good weight
over that amount of time because it's
gradual and I didn't.
The only week I missed my fitness goals,
I have to have 72 points of activity and
I only missed it one time I had the flu.
What's a point of activity?
How do you,
what do you get?
So if I go to a movie tie at nine,
I only really.
It's an hour class but I only put 30
minutes down.
The more we tie training,
if we do circuit training with a ball or
ropes and shit,
then I put whatever the amount.
If it's eight stations at 30 seconds of
station,
you wear a heart rate monitor or
anything or no?
No.
Listen,
I don't want to hear.
I want to see.
You know,
when I had that fucking ear infection,
I used to have to work out with ear
plugs on and I get high and go throw
kicks with Jesus.
You don't what life is when you had the
ear infection.
The earplugs kept your equilibrium and
balance.
Keep sweat going in my ear.
I don't know what life is.
When you're working out,
you can hear your heartbeat,
but yet pump pump.
That's trippy shit.
You know everlast has a ticker.
He's got an artificial valve and he put
the microphone up to his chassis here.
No,
I don't wanna hear that shit.
Fuck you tripping in there for.
What did he say?
Like 18 years I think.
Yeah.
He had a heart attack a long ass time
ago.
Yeah.
Bad Valve.
But if I was clean of off we for 29
days,
I might as well go for it for at least a
year.
Yeah.
Let's run around marijuana.
Just make a comeback just to see what
would it be like.
I'll tell you one thing that did happen
last year when we did sober October and
it took a month off when I started back
again.
I'd get nervous,
real nervous,
scared to do it,
and I'd go on stage.
I feel real strange.
Somebody once told me,
a great woman once told me that,
uh,
if you think getting high in life is
weird with you,
stop getting high and it's a different
fucking adventure and she's truly a lot
of aspects.
I called you I one October,
second one night I got home from the
comedy store.
You know when you get home from the
original room dog,
especially when you go.
It was one of those nights when I went
in there and that was rocky Balboa.
I just touched gloves and I measured and
I just started going through the body
for 15 minutes.
I remember driving up Laurel Canyon
going,
what am I going to do with myself?
And I went home.
It was like October second.
It was 1130.
I started smoking reefer,
the calm down a little bit and I went
down and I started with sign of the
times by Prince and I just left it on
auto play and they just took me into a
prince fucking cave and I ended up on
beautiful ones.
When he starts singing,
do you want him?
And I called you up.
I'm like,
this is why I can't do sober October
because I get so high and mighty.
Come down off the stage and you're going
to upstage.
You need something.
Since I don't drink,
I'm scared to come up that hill.
Drinking.
I have to smoke reefer to come down at
night and music.
That's the only thing that calms me down
at night.
Do write at night after your sets.
I write about what happened.
Yeah.
I tried to about how lucky I am that I'm
still performing at the store at 55.
I right about that.
I ate a bag of Dicks,
but I'll get them tomorrow night,
you know,
like whatever.
Whatever just is flowing through my head
while I have music on.
I'm drinking a water and I'm just going
to back and fucking Toca fucking 22 hits
off a bike and I love listening to music
at night.
That's my hobby.
It's a thing to like when you get out of
the store,
it's a thing to sit yourself down and
make yourself work and right.
You know,
because you're like,
I'm done.
I did it.
Got a good set in.
I'm good,
but that's the best time to write.
I think everything's popping while go
home and make corrections.
Maybe I said that fuck too early or
maybe I said that and I shouldn't have
said it,
but uh,
no.
I won't try to ride it and I'm gone at
night.
Might drive unless something's really.
I think my brain is shot at night
because.
Is it because you did your,
uh,
did your standup,
you've got ramped up.
Did the stand up playing with the
fucking kid,
you know,
did a podcast talk to people all day
about shit that doesn't matter by night.
I liked the,
I liked to get up.
I play with mercy.
I talked to my wife.
I'll do a protein shake,
I'll drop mercy off,
I'll go home and then I go to the coffee
shop and for 30 minutes I'll call my
peeps in jersey,
check in,
and then I'll get eggs at the coffee
shop bacon.
Once my breakfast is gun,
I write my page down for the day,
then I take my ipad up and I either
write a chapter in the book.
I try to write towards the book and
while I'm writing another book,
you're writing a book,
right?
I'm trying,
I'm trying.
How long have you been doing this?
Twenty two fucking years.
Joe Rogan.
Twenty two fucking years,
you know?
Um,
but I forced myself and with the IPAD,
you know,
this is a whole thing on,
there's a whole writing thing so I could
just turn that chapter off and go to
another document and click on the post
netflix material and then I got a thing
that we're working with immigrant
mentality.
So I think about that.
I'll go to that.
So now my,
that's all great.
I think just doing that exercise every
day is good for me.
I don't need to write comedy every day.
I'd rather just go down to the store to
throw something out there and fucking
get excited.
And like I told you,
I'm not going anywhere else no more than
Los Angeles.
I'm going back to the school,
no Improv soft spots,
especially after I shot the Netflix
special and everything.
It all came to me after they had that 10
years and especially after she died,
you know,
people you ever go to like an acting
class and people refer to Stanislavski
and all this shit.
Ten years from now people going to be
referring to the Mitzi shore technique.
There was something that every I was
talking to Duncan about.
I talked to rob about it.
I know she said something to us at one
point that we were like,
wow,
something
I remember I was telling him this on my
podcast,
that there was a time she didn't like
doing that in the cobit and wouldn't let
me do it in the main room in the
original fucking crazy is that,
that's to show you a genius in a way.
Like she was like,
Joe,
you could light yourself on fire and the
original,
I don't give a fuck,
but in the main room you can't do that
because you're killing my room.
Like the comics afterwards just could
not follow it.
Like they could just not following that
lesson right there.
That was about.
It was brilliant,
but it
think about it.
It's no good versions of that bit
anywhere.
This one version that I did that's up on
you.
It's terrible.
It's terrible version that there's no
solid versions of that pit,
but that bit was right when that guy
died.
J Howard Marshall was him getting Anna
Nicole Smith to do shit to him before he
died,
but she's trying to take your money.
I don't give a fuck.
I want to get my boss' leg,
a sunlight crazy bit.
But Mitzi didn't like it too because she
didn't like bits that were making fun of
old people because her health was
deteriorating too.
She.
There was a couple of bits of that.
She didn't fucking picture him.
He's a million years old and she's hot
as the sun and she sit on his lap,
look,
look at the smile on his face.
Dog.
Yeah.
Oh Man.
I loved him.
I loved that whole scene.
I loved what it was.
I loved that because it was so blatant,
you know?
It was just so blatant,
but she didn't like that,
but she didn't like the Hugh hefner bit
either.
She didn't like that bit.
Those when you have to hold those,
she's kissing him.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Oh,
he's in a wheelchair.
While she's married him.
I mean,
it was a damn classic that,
that,
that scene of him and her getting
married,
she's so young and so hot and he's so
old wrecked,
enriches fuck in a wheelchair.
It's such a classic scenario.
It was so good.
Good.
You called the Kentucky Fried Hookah.
Him Car Kentucky Fried it.
Like if she wanted that money shit,
doing shit to keep doing shit.
And then that's.
Yeah,
he's calling father.
He's going like,
it's time to look back.
It's time.
Oh yeah,
man.
I just loved the fact that that guy was
that wealthy and yet still.
I mean,
I guess when you're that.
Well,
was he at that time more than a billion
dollars?
He was a billionaire.
He was an oil magnate,
right?
I wasn't even.
I don't think she got the money though.
I think the kids fought her hundred
million,
but that's peanuts.
Yeah,
it got her dog
and Nicole Smith's daughter is now the
fourth richest woman in the US.
It's what?
Oh,
I know it says $37 billion though.
Koch brothers.
Oh,
I see.
He was 69th on the list.
Oh,
but fourth richest woman.
Do you know?
Out of the richest women in the world,
Google the richest women in the world,
like where they got their money from.
It's rough.
It's rough out there guys.
Then they fucking starting businesses
that mary had dummies,
divorce.
Almost all of it's divorced money.
The feminists do not want to hear this,
but there was one woman who was the
richest woman ever from a startup
company,
a Elizabeth.
What was her name from thread knows?
What was it?
What was her name?
Elizabeth something.
Not Smith.
What was it?
Something homes.
Elizabeth Holmes.
She had a ran a company called
Toronto's.
She started herself,
dropped out of college to start this
company and it was a total fraud.
It was all fraudulent.
She's going to jail forever.
She was with $34,000,000,000
at one point.
It was a blood testing company and what
it was was they just take a trickier
blood instead of taking a bunch of your
blood or you get a.
your blood drawn.
Did.
Her thing was like,
let's just be able to take a prick of
the blood.
Just a little tiny prick like you go to
a store,
get pickier blood,
and they're going to be able to do a
battery of tests on you and find out
what's going on.
Problem was it didn't fucking work and
they.
They falsified all sorts of data and
they lied to investors and all sorts of
shit.
This lady,
she used to dress like Steve Jobs.
She wore a black turtleneck and
everything and I saw her speak once
here.
Coast Elizabeth Holmes indicted on
fraud.
Oh the Gotcha.
With the fucking pop up.
Add New York to air.
She is.
She's going to jail.
She's fucked.
Oh,
but she was.
She was at one point in time,
the richest self made person in the
world.
Richest self made woman in the world.
She was worth billions of dollars to
ship.
People do.
I watched a thing.
The idea crazy.
Eddie,
do you remember Crazy Eddie?
His prices are insane.
Crazy.
I need to tell them to go crazy.
It was crazy.
It was a guy that had stores in all five
boroughs of New York wholesale outlets,
tca radios,
tvs and everything like that.
I saw.
I was watching them SNBC greed to have a
series called us.
Let me hear this motherfucker
remember we are not,
we will not be undersold and now
he's wearing a Santa Claus outfit.
He's going fucking crazy with fake snow
in the background.
He fucking like,
just like he did it out of the park.
Didn't he go to Israel?
You went to high,
but the most brilliant thing he did was
he took it.
You don't.
Don't fucking check back me on this.
He took it either his nephew,
his son in law,
somebody that was related to
blood,
put them through college so he could get
a job at the irs so they could figure
out how to rob from the irs.
This is how fucking insane this guy was.
I'm watching this diet and how they got
crazy yet.
Right.
Crazy.
Eddie fled after he started just buying
boxes.
You know how you met me years ago,
you would be driving in New York and
there was some guy selling stereos.
Speakers.
Yeah.
And then you'd take them home and it was
two bricks.
Yep.
Well he did the same thing to investors.
He took boxes,
filled them up with bricks and just
stuck them in a warehouse and then he
went public,
so he got everybody to come down and
look at all his inventory and all these
fact checkers.
They're checking boxes as a brick sort
of.
Whoa.
And he had,
I mean five fucking warehouses all
around.
They will all fake and he got all this
money.
He fled to Israel and he fled for a
while,
but they knew he was a pussy hound.
Right.
So they got them like Escobar style.
They got them like,
you know,
on the phone,
like I'm going to a store or something.
Crazy.
And what they did was they put a blonde
on the side of the road with a mini
skirt and they knew eventually he would
drive by and stopped.
No,
he stopped.
That's how they nailed them.
What is the Google the way the richest
woman in the world where they got their
money from.
He's a bad motherfucker,
paramus syosset,
Long Island.
And he had commercials.
So he was the first one that pushed to
commercial barrier,
like made fun.
I miss and him like I,
Ms Dot had the pimp with a bunch of his
hose that will go.
Did you hear with my man said this
morning.
Oh really?
Yeah,
and he had a bunch of those crazy.
Eddie had the best one.
He had Frankenstein Dracula and the wolf
man.
Peanut,
the peanut,
the men's urinal.
Miss the imus thing because I came in
like I remember I found out about
Ironman skews.
Howard stern was talking shit about him
and I was like,
who is this?
I'm Ms.
Guy.
Hi Ms Dot was around when I was a kid
was late.
He was already.
I miss was the fucking King of New York
when I was eight,
nine.
I'm Mr Kumar in the morning and talk
shit.
When I saw him he was wearing like a
turquoise,
one of those weird ties,
those Bolo ties that like cowboys went.
He had a fucking cowboy hat on and his
whole studio was done like a.
well,
like the West.
It was real weird.
Yeah,
he got weird at the end he put really?
He's wearing cowboy boots and shit.
It was like,
are you a rancher?
Am Radio show from New York City like
this got fucked up and they were paying
him.
I mean he was on for a while and he said
nappy headed hoes and they're like,
cut that sin.
He
called people nappy headed,
tried to compete with stern.
Right.
That's what it was.
There wasn't a sudden.
It was definitely some of that.
So he was,
you know,
he was trying to be outrageous.
Even before Stern,
I believe it just wasn't at the same
level.
Sterns outrageousness was nationwide.
Ims was really like an east coast thing,
like people knew about them in New York.
I had never heard about him in New York
or in Boston,
but I had heard about stern.
We all knew about stern but nobody,
nobody really knew about it.
Never made it there,
you know.
And then when I came to New York it was
at the end,
like when stern was already the king and
I'm us was just sort of like this guy
that he hated and I was like,
who is this man?
Who is this I guy?
And then he had a TV show for awhile and
then during the TV show we'd see him in
the studio and it was,
you know,
no disrespect,
but it was really fucking boring.
It was boring.
Like there was no life to them.
Like their opinions weren't that
interesting.
It was him.
And there was another guy there that
looked like it was just waiting for the
Buzzer,
the ring,
he's waiting to go home.
And then there was a woman that was with
them.
It was,
it was.
There was no life in the room.
Like can you watch the stern show?
There'd be midgets shooting bottle
rockets out of their ass halls and porn
stars riding dildos.
And it was chaos.
There was a plastic all over the
grounds.
Girls would be squirting.
It was just madness like no one had ever
done.
Not that that's good or bad,
but it was,
it was exciting.
Like you're,
you're driving to work in the morning,
you're hearing some girl freaking out
because she's riding on some fucking
that Sybian thing.
He'd make girls right on.
Like,
that was madness.
So like that,
that like you had never heard anything
like that on the radio before.
So then you would hear about ims and I'm
as a rural water.
We brought her to this warning or like
what's the hr just be at the end?
It was just,
it was in comparison.
It was so it was dead.
It was like,
it was dry and I said on stern it was
great flavor.
Flavor.
The one time on Stern.
I mean there's so many great steroids to
already was so great back already was
the best party was fucking the May.
Have you listened to an old already when
we had just gotten off the subway.
He just shot heroin.
He had sunglasses on.
Yeah.
You fall asleep.
Shit.
Fucking insane.
And he said that they encouraged him,
you know,
but man,
what are you going to do when a guy's
like that?
You're going to help them if you help.
The problem with people that are that
fucked up is the only thing that ever
helps them is themselves.
The only thing it's like they have to
hit rock bottom and then they have to
decide they're going to do something
about it,
but when you do get a lot of love for
being fucked up,
that is kind of a problem because you do
start to think,
this is my thing.
My thing is being a fucked up guy.
People love me when I'm fucked up.
This is what I do.
You know,
and you can fall into that.
Couple Belushi had the same.
The other guy got arrested,
so I had the same problem.
There's a neat you fall into.
I remember there was a pizza parlor when
I was a kid.
His name was nick,
the Greek fucking tremendous pizza.
Even though he was Greek,
like we let it slide.
He put the Sicilian by the window and it
was the flies will land on it.
It was like the airport for the flies.
They will land.
We will break his balls neck,
but I'm in my wedding gown.
Acquaint load one night fucked up to the
gills,
would vomit all over my shirt and every
time he'd see me call me fucking
Belushi.
Belushi almost died.
It was,
and he would ever,
for years he called me fucking Belushi
and there was another kid who had a
beard.
The Columbine,
I told her Khomeini,
like he had nicknames for us,
but that's a weird.
It bothered me.
After a while he would call it Belushi
and Belushi died.
It really started bothering me like my
next.
He would call me Belushi till my face
who according to his fucking Belushi,
well,
I was fucked up.
I wouldn't have done that on a quail and
open up the red pepper and threw it at
him,
but I used to sell them jewelry like I
was selling stolen.
Jimmy and nick were tight.
Nick was the pizza parlor,
50 yards from the high school and you
could run a tab with nick and nick used
to.
I used to give nick jewelry and he would
look at me and he would go speak.
How much do you think that's worth?
Because jewelry was $800 an ounce at
that time.
Gold and I would bring him jewelry.
He would look at it and then take it,
give me money and put it in.
One of his pockets from is the apron.
So two days later I'd go in and go,
nick,
let me use your bathroom,
and I go in there and stick my hand in
the apron and take the jewelry back.
And then a week later I go back to nick
how much with the ring and he looked at
me and he was racist as fuck.
Like he really the quality Belushi a
Spec to my face,
like it didn't matter.
There was a kid,
you know,
this is on Kennedy Boulevard,
this is a big boulevard and there was a
kid that would come in.
Then I'm still dear friends with that.
His family had money and he would go in
there and buy a slice of pizza,
but he would cross the street because
the ice t across the street was a dime
cheaper and more ice tea came in those
fucking cardboard and milk cardboards.
He will always cross the street.
So nick will be having a conversation
with like what's going on and also to go
west and when he went across the street
to get the ice cream,
he would fucking flip out.
He run from behind the counter,
run onto Kennedy Boulevard.
Hundreds of people be out there and he
yell at the Kid,
Tony,
you fucking jewel.
You fuck you.
Fuck.
He wasn't Jewish.
He was Italian.
He was just cheap and shit like that.
That's it.
Damn Center that you've got to be pretty
cheap to run across the street.
But it was forty five cents for the ice
tea,
but it Ashley's was thirty five cents
across the street.
Then the ashtrays,
Delhi was great because the mother was
losing their hair.
Every time you got a sandwich you get a
little piece of hair,
so get you wouldn't get here.
You'd go ms dot.
You didn't get any mail today.
Everything had a little piece of Aaron
and the macaroni salad and you hate it.
Gave a fuck.
It was tremendous.
She made the best roast beef on Rye in
the world,
but every.
No.
In fact,
the whole family to her.
And the son will losing the hat,
and I learned from her son.
Her son was losing his hair,
but he couldn't control his emotions
about it.
He went to everything.
Joe,
he did the fucking stitches.
He would spray paint his hand.
He was one of those guys,
the hat,
like he tried,
but the head just kept falling out.
He had a male pattern.
Whatever we were kids.
The mom had it to.
The mom had was something in the house.
I don't know what it was.
Nuclear tests.
The Dad had.
The brother had it and fucking
everything you got there.
Had a little piece of hair on it.
Whatever.
You got to always say if you didn't get
beat going,
ms dot hatch.
But say it to her face.
Oh,
we used to to her all the time.
We Love Mrs Hesh a dude were losing his
hair.
It's fucking devastating.
But a woman losing her hair way more
devastating.
There's something about a woman,
woman,
women losing their hair.
It kills them really hard.
So sad.
Yeah.
So I've seen women lose their hair.
It's,
it's awful.
You know,
they get alopecia.
Alopecia is.
We're like,
you could lose your eyebrows.
People lose their eyebrows.
He looks like sometimes shit just starts
falling off.
I had,
there's a singer,
there's a popular singer in a band and
he's got alopecia and I just saw it.
They bust on my 30 years later,
you didn't know that was awake even then
and I knew about him growing up and he
would just lose his hair.
You know,
from time to time,
you guys lose their eyelashes.
They lose everything.
That's fucked up.
That's crazy island and I'm getting
older,
like my hairline is receding,
but my line's getting bushy eyebrows,
eyebrows.
It's crazy.
I'm getting bushier is shit.
Sometimes I'm driving at night.
There's something my vision and I got to
go home,
but I got to fucking shop.
It's like a satellite.
I go,
I asked my wife,
don't you see this shit?
Old guys like old Scottish guys,
all the Irish guys,
Scottish guys,
fucking caterpillars grown out of there.
I was.
I got no hair on my legs.
I got minimal hair on my shoulders.
I got no hair on my back.
I'm on.
Those guys have any hair on your arms?
Nothing.
I got hair that grows out of my ears
this time.
That's typical qtip in my ear and I
could hear the head twisting in my
fucking.
You know what that's like.
My eyebrows broke at bushy is fuck.
I got to bring scissors with me on the
road to trim and you're in your mirror
at home.
You don't see this shit.
You get on the road with white in the
hotel room and you're like,
well,
do is fucking had grown out of my nose.
Did you find them about the women with
the investments?
Oh good.
Good.
From a news week in.
Okay.
What does
it say is a great here,
upper echelons of money and power,
blah,
blah.
According to Forbes worlds,
15 wealthiest people are men.
Women only make up 10 percent of the
top.
100 separate,
wealthiest woman.
The world.
Most of their money comes from their
male relatives or husbands.
Yeah.
The top 10 wealthiest men made their
fortunes themselves.
Now who will the top 10 wealthiest woman
that they're from?
Good voice.
Oh,
here,
the girl who's got to be second.
Yeah,
she's up there.
The first self made woman on the list is
wild.
I don't know how to say this woman's
name.
Z,
h o u.
that's one word.
Q,
U I n f e I zoo wouldn't fee who was
born to a poor family of China,
dropped out of school at 16.
She went on to found in an enormously
successful technology company.
Uh,
but if you put men back into the
equation,
she's only 198th richest person in the
world.
No matter how you feel about the concept
of few people hoarding enormous wealth.
The notion that women can only access
money and power through their families
or husbands seems medieval at best.
Yet we see it occur at the very top of
many professions outside of the business
world.
Most people.
Can you read the next stuff?
Yeah.
A recent high profile examples.
Hillary Clinton,
during her presidential campaign,
the first female major party nominee,
she campaigned on a ticket of
empowerment.
Yet although she is accomplished in her
own right,
she entered politics as the wife of Bill
Clinton.
And his undoubtedly benefited from his
prestige and connections.
Yeah.
Well that's true.
But also it was,
it was a lot of money.
I didn't mean for you to read that she
was a lawyer and uh,
you know,
she was a senator.
No,
oprah is up there as the world's richest
women,
period.
Like it's a weird thing because they're
saying I'm not a big fan of Hillary
Clinton.
But by saying she definitely entered
because she was,
you know,
she was married to him,
but she was a lawyer.
I mean,
she's,
she's an accomplished person.
She's,
she's educated.
Accomplish who's a senator.
I don't think that makes sense.
I hate when people say,
shit,
I ain't know what you at the right place
at the right time,
bitch.
I know you jumped in,
you jumped,
you jumped bitch.
So that's the problem.
I'm not mad at nobody.
You can't say she got into.
She may be a little help.
A push here,
a call here.
But she jumped.
There's a great book I'm reading right
now.
It's called outliers by Malcolm
Mcdowell.
It's fucking great.
And it's all about what makes people
successful and why they were successful.
And there are a lot of factors,
man.
There's a lot of factors in when you
were born,
like what?
Like a lot of it he goes on about hockey
players,
about professional hockey players that
almost all of them were born at a
certain time so that they were at the
end of the age cutoff.
Like say if
you're between 10 and 11 when you go
into what is that fifth grade?
You're,
if you're one of the oldest kids,
you have a way better chance of being
successful at hockey because your body's
more mature than whether you're one of
the youngest kids that goes into sixth
grade.
So with your fifth grade or sixth grade,
like what year you were born is a big
factor.
So the kids that were born later so that
they're older rather the kids over there
that are older,
when they enter into the fifth grade or
sixth grade,
they're like across the board
unanimously.
All the top level professionals.
We're all older kids in younger grades
so that they're planning against smaller
kids.
They get more time,
they,
they're better,
so they get more coaching,
beget more hours playing.
There's a lot of factors,
has a lot of factors in like one of the
things about Bill Gates that there was,
there's a whole great chapter on Bill
Gates and about when Bill Gates was
young,
the school that he went to had a
computer class that,
uh,
allowed him to do coding and then he got
into the University of Washington.
They would let him get into their,
their computer room from 3:00
AM to 6:00
AM.
They had this open block,
so him and his friends would sneak into
that place at 3:00
in the morning.
So all these,
all these different factors that lead to
someone being like super successful.
It's not just that you work hard,
it's sometimes you get these weird
advantages in life.
There's a bunch of things like,
for sure hard work plays a factor.
If you don't do nothing,
he just sit around and,
and,
and woe is me and cry and think the
world's fucked.
You're not going anywhere.
But the people that make it to the very
top,
that Bill Gates,
the Steve Jobs,
they have a bunch of things going for
them.
It's not just hard work.
It's also circumstance,
fortune,
where they are,
what,
you know,
who's around them,
who,
who encourages them.
This.
There's a bunch of and what time they
were born in,
what,
you know,
what age they were,
when certain things happened in the
world.
There's a bunch of factors.
But for all those chicks,
just marrying the right dude.
Divorced,
getting.
I know a lady who uh,
just got aid from a divorce and she's
just shooting shit into her face.
A bag and 20 year olds now.
It's hilarious.
She's in her late forties bag.
A 20 year old dudes.
Good.
Funny man to cut that check for the guy.
Yeah.
I've,
I've known guys I knew a guy who uh,
he cut a check for somewhere in the
neighborhood of $50,000,000.
Yeah.
Two is x 30 grand a month.
G dirty GRANDPA.
He saw a couple of guys pay that.
That was,
that was not beside half million up
front.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
House too.
Cars,
he just walked away.
I knew that guy was paying close to that
and he hasn't even seen his wife.
He's been married to a new woman,
a different woman for 14 years
at least.
Yeah,
14 years and he was only married to that
lady for 12 and he's still cutting her
checks and no kids.
He's got kids with a new woman.
The old woman,
no kids still cutting her fat checks,
tries to bring it to court,
try to reduce the amount of money.
She fights him tooth and nail.
You lose sight of.
I bet you left me.
He left her 14 fucking years ago,
man.
They were only together for 12 years.
It's like she doesn't want to work is he
fucked her so hard.
She can't work anymore.
It's crazy.
If it was a man,
if the situation was reversed and a guy
was dating a girl and they were dating
for 12 years and she was like,
I'm tired of this.
I'm gonna.
Go fuck some new dude.
And the guy took her to court,
got money from her and wanted money.
Still 14 years later.
What kind of a fucking man would that be
like,
get a job,
go do something with your life.
You're a human being.
You met another human being.
You spend some time with them.
They don't want to be with you anymore.
It's over like this.
There's no.
There's no children will told the judge
that you want your lifestyle,
the lifestyle that you were accustomed
to.
Maintain.
My lifestyle,
judge,
I'd like to buy nice person.
I like to walk my little dog.
I like to put them into little little
purse.
Now in California is different factors
also.
You have to be with that person for 10
years or something,
right?
There's a couple of ways.
There's this factors and they change,
you know,
depending upon the laws and they change
depending upon how much money you make.
And you know,
my friend was pretty wealthy.
He did well,
but the guy who I know that had to pay
$50,000,000,
he's real successful obviously that.
I mean you gotta make a lot of money to
give your wife 50 million,
but he still had to give her $50
million.
I see the list and I see the kid point
zero,
baby.
I see the.
I see the child support point.
See a little bit of help.
There's the list.
The unique one.
Oh,
Madonna's divorced from Guy Ritchie.
Estimated 76 to 92 million.
Oh,
he had.
She had to give him.
I mean she's the first woman listed
first on the damn.
She had to give him 76 million.
Wait a go Guy Ritchie.
I like to have him back here.
Now I know how you buy those suits,
motherfucker.
Now what's his name?
Pays?
Pick single from books.
This Michael Jordan's divorced from
Juanita Jordan.
One $68 million.
Mel Gibson's divorced in 2006 after 26
years.
Four hundred and $25 million.
God Damn shot scrolling.
Look at this.
Jesus Christ.
Steve winds divorced.
Two thousand 21 billion.
Oh my
goodness.
Oh my goodness.
Steve.
When one bill young Rupert Murdoch's
divorce in 1990 in 1999 after 31 years
of marriage.
One point 7 billion.
Neil diamond,
1:50
Harrison Ford,
$118 million.
Whoa.
Harrison Ford had to give up the
Cheddar.
Steven Spielberg 100 million.
I remember that one.
That that girl was an actress and she
fucking vanished.
Kevin Costner.
James Cameron limb to Halton.
50 million.
Michael Douglas.
Paul Mccarthy.
That's the chick that was missing the
leg,
right?
That's a dark one.
The dark woman was mean.
She was nasty man.
Yeah,
there's a lot of them.
Mick Jagger,
15 million.
Twenty five,
nine.
He got off light,
Bro.
Make Jack because remember he fucking
married and should make and it was like
a Puerto Rican priests on this day off.
So he knew it going in because it makes
Jag ain't giving you Dick Hall.
I think that was Jerry Hall was wife
number two.
Who's this?
That's Bianca Jagger.
The first one.
The first one?
Yeah.
He.
The first one he had to pay the secular
is like,
listen,
we're going to work around this one.
Oh yeah,
he doesn't fuck around that guy.
He before.
He wasn't under stones.
Jamie,
what's the school?
He went,
he don't make me say something wrong.
He went to the school of whales or
something.
The business,
he's all about the data for the last 15
years,
he's just been impregnating women all
over the country and cutting them a
check and saying,
you know,
London School of Economics.
No,
no.
Listen,
when it comes to bro,
when it comes to law,
this stories that you hear that you're
like,
no,
he didn't.
No,
he did not.
Do you see him?
You ever seen any of Joe Rogan machine?
It was rehearsal things.
Do you ever see any of his videos?
Do you follow him at all?
I follow him,
yeah.
You see any of the videos that he does
to him working on the afternoons?
A man like him dancing still like
Michael Jackson.
What?
That guy does not fuck around.
No,
and I still remember one particular
story where he got the bold,
they played the with the Buffalo,
with a,
with the college plays.
He walked in and he goes,
what's wrong with those seats?
And they were like,
well Mr Jagger that behind the stage
bitch,
you better get the selling because I
ain't taking the stage until those
motherfuckers are sold that I sold the
tickets behind the stage and Mick Jagger
was brutal.
They could pay for my ass,
they could pay for my ass.
Mick Jagger is brutal.
Pro.
He's brutal.
And that was back before they had those
giant screens.
There was no distance distance.
80 eighth.
They didn't have those giant screens.
This is 88,
87.
They don't give a fuck.
They didn't have those big lcds.
We could see them.
Yeah.
Like if you go
see like say drake and he's at a theater
and around and like you see is.
But you're going to see his face on
giant screens all around you.
You'll see it.
You know,
if you go to see like a real popular
person and there's a lot of people
playing in the round,
you know,
Jack is an interesting guy.
I don't think he,
he's like very tight watches.
Is this tight?
You know,
he's just like time as you have left
though.
I mean he's like 76.
No,
72 maybes.
Seventy to 75.
He's like 75.
How much time you got left?
If he keeps a lucky,
everything goes great.
You got 25 years,
but those last 25 or rough.
Not with what he's got because he could
just lay there all day.
Have young girls massage and he's Mick
Jagger.
They could just blow on his little
knapsack and sing fucking.
He's probably getting blood transfusions
every day.
I know he takes good care.
He's looking at.
He used the backbone of the organization
and just the fact that Keith Richards is
still alive and kicking and there's
people out there doing crossfit and
didn't Keith Richards write a book where
he's Kinda Shitty about Mick Jagger?
He just told a talk shit about each
other.
Right?
That's how they sell books.
Dog.
Yeah.
I know.
That's how they make probably called
them and said,
do this.
The this,
the truth.
Fuck it.
Give me 10 percent at when that.
When.
I mean when I watched those little
rehearsal tapes,
looky,
looky there,
his fingers.
Look at those fingers will.
We're looking at a Keith Richards.
Keith Richards.
Fingers is every knuckle is swollen to
the point.
It's like double the size.
He looks like he's got Megaton Diaz,
his hands.
He's like a like a Jujitsu guy.
You ever seen Megaton Diaz?
His hands.
The big fucking Kensie turns dad.
The girl who wrote the made that video.
It was Hilarious,
but her dad,
Megaton doc,
the Jujitsu legend,
all his life.
He's done.
The guys who do the gear all the time,
they develop real bad arthritis in their
hands and their joints swell up like
crazy.
See if you find megaton his hands.
That's not a good picture.
That's but there's pictures of his.
His knuckles that they're crazy.
They're all fucked up and twisted like
this.
I can tell a little bit there.
There you go.
Zoom in on his bill.
He was.
Because he'd turn his day.
Yeah,
her dad is a fucking legend.
Look,
go zooming on his hands as much as I
could go.
Oh,
that's as much as it goes.
But you see.
See how fucking flamed out.
Those Naacos.
Our guys have done this their whole life
and they're always grab it and hold onto
that game.
They get that.
Yeah,
that's okay.
We get the point,
but that.
That's what Keith Richards fingers look
like.
Like he's secretly doing Jujitsu.
Sly,
but that's 40 years of planning.
Yes,
man,
that is crazy.
That's good to hop.
Playing 40 years,
50 years.
He looks just as good as Mick Jagger.
He's doing blow everyday eating
cockroaches.
He looks as good as mcjagger.
Look,
they look great.
I don't think he looks as.
I think mcjagger looks fucking
sensational,
but he doesn't in the face.
If you look at the two of them in the
face,
get make that picture bigger.
Jeremy.
Look at them in the face.
Mick Jagger,
it looks older,
but that's just.
It's hard to tell because Keith Richards
is smiling.
We should go out.
Would love to see Mick Jagger still pull
21 year olds out of the audience.
I bet they feel so weird when he fucks
him.
It must feel so weird like you want to
do it.
Like if I was a girl,
I was 20 years old,
I would fuck Mick Jagger just for the
story,
but when he climbs on top of you and you
smelled death,
this smell it coming out of his pores.
He's not old.
He's as bad cells.
You smiled,
misfiring cells all over the place.
This 70 year old people that don't look
like that.
Seventy year old people are not going on
the road.
They weren't dancing like that.
Like that.
That's something that you have to,
and this is a new thing.
You have to take all these.
First of all,
all these bands that are going on,
I run this.
How about somebody called me a day and
they're like,
hey man,
I'm doing thinking of doing something
New Year's Eve downtown.
You know,
I hate new years eve and I hate downtown
even more fucking Ozzy Osborne just
doing the forum.
New Year's Eve,
the western forum.
The only forum I fucking know.
And La Way.
Yeah,
with Rob Zombie and Marilyn Manson,
fucking just.
And I'm sitting there going 70 years old
and he's doing New Year's Eve at the
fucking forgot to.
I forgot to.
His wife probably tells them,
fuck out of the house.
Go make money,
make money.
New Year's Eve at the forum,
Joe it.
Connect his ankles together with rubber
bands so we can't make big steps.
Ever.
See I walks.
Is that true?
If you're trying to pull a Mickey,
Mickey made fucking rocky.
Put the tire lights together is the same
problem.
Rocky had.
He told me you saw the trailer for creed
for Creek.
The first one's good.
Did you watch it?
I told you.
I called you and said watch it.
If you have an academy award winner,
man for years.
I don't know.
I don't know how I felt about so vested
stolen.
I'm a fan.
I just didn't.
Then I went to your house that time and
your wife was goofing on you and she's
like,
I think he's got.
He's in love with Sylvester stallone.
The you like.
Look at this.
Look at him.
And you had a picture of his phone when
he was 65.
He was just jacked.
Yeah,
like all that shit and stuff.
And then I was on a plane and I said,
let me watch this creed,
and I had tears in my eyes because I'm
like,
this guy has got no respect for years
and you look at them now people goof him
and shit dog.
He wrote to his whole back done.
He's wow.
Look at that.
Like in on his back.
Wow.
I didn't know he had his whole back
done.
That's crazy.
Like this guy wrote a fucking two or
three franchises.
Yeah.
This guy started like when you.
The other day they had some things about
facts about a guy like he was fucking
broke.
Had to sell his dog.
He had to do all this shit to make
rocket lawyer.
That picture right there.
Yeah.
Look at this Guy Jack.
Seventy one.
Jacked fucking jacked.
When I saw that commercial for the first
one with creed,
I was watching this shit.
And then AMC lately,
every Sunday or something,
they throw a rock here and you say,
what the fuck?
I got 10 minutes before world news
tonight.
And you start watching it and you see
the brilliance of what this man has
done.
Yeah.
It's brilliant,
it's just completely brilliant,
whether it's cheesy with dri,
when he gets beat up and Apollo creed
takes them to the ghetto and makes them
look at brothers and they teach them and
now and then create.
That kid by the way is a bad ass
motherfucker.
Michael Johnson.
Oh,
black pants and Black Panther.
Greatness.
Christ.
He's the other guy.
A fucking superb but this now and you
look at it and you're like,
like me and you at the store behind it,
like you would say to me,
really Jodie is he's going to fight the
Russian son.
I could have wrote that idea on a
fucking.
It's still huge.
It's still coming out Thanksgiving Day.
This guy is coming.
It's going to be huge.
I'll be there front and center at 1:00.
Crises,
that franchise started in the seventies,
Seventies.
He made rocky one and I remember I
watched it when I was a little kid.
I drank raw eggs and a ran around the
block.
Like I just listened to a David Goggins
fucking motivational speech.
I just,
uh,
I read about this when this first
started shooting this,
he told him to hit him for real and he
put him in Icu for nine days.
Don't flunk.
And he said to try to knock them out.
What?
Why would he do that?
I don't know.
It was a legit kill and karate champion.
Dolph Lundgren is a bad motherfucker,
like legitimate bad motherfucker like,
you know,
and he did a bunch of those crazy action
movies and he played the punisher
and all the sudden.
But that guy is a,
was a legit karate champion.
He's a bad motherfucker.
Talk longer than I would not want that
guy hit.
And what's this?
What's this one called?
London put me in the hospital during
rocky for.
Why would he let him hit him?
Well,
you know,
who else knocked him?
Antonio Tarver knocked Sylvester
stallone out when they,
when he was doing that movie where he
was still boxing.
Remember just a few years ago,
he was in his sixties and he was boxing
in one of those movies.
A font.
Antonio Tarver.
Magic man.
Tarver was a heavyweight champion.
Light heavyweight champion knocked out
Roy Jones Jr member when he stood in
front of Roy Jones,
Roy Jones,
go got excuses tonight,
Roy.
And then he knocked him out and Tonio
Tara is a bad motherfucker.
And apparently when they were doing
scenes in a movie,
he clipped him and k Odom,
here's the quick story.
He said he,
uh,
for the first 45 seconds he tried to
really knock them out.
He hit him.
So hardest chest started to serve,
his heart started to swell,
his blood pressure went up.
I had to go back on an emergency jet to
America and he was in Icu for five days.
Whoa.
And the insurance company,
now I'm intensive care for five days
with nuns walking around.
Insurance Company will not pay out of
this other footage of the incident.
Once they did,
they wrote the check,
he hit my heart so hard,
it banged against my ribs and started to
swell.
And that usually happens in car
accidents.
So I was hit by a truck that is
ridiculous when it's slow.
And also talks about why you hated
London from the get go.
They're friends now.
Oh,
probably because a big handsome fella
from fucking Norway or wherever the hell
he is from.
Where's he from?
Dolph lundgren with that name.
Sweden.
I think he's from some justice and
cousin.
His cousin or something.
Sweden.
He's a legit bad motherfucker though.
I didn't know that.
He was a cute guy.
Was a karate champion?
Yeah,
I think he was a national champion.
Cookie Shins.
No joke,
man.
Those,
those,
those fucking guys.
That's a hard style.
Very hard style isn't a GSP stone was
so.
Yeah,
I think you almost killed Christian.
I'm pretty sure they really hard hitting
motherfuckers.
It's a very hard kicks.
Lot of wheel kicks.
What they do in the tournament's.
Kilkee shouldn't tournament's they'd
punch to the body full blast,
but kick to the legs,
the head,
the body,
and they're standing right in front of
each other and beat the fuck out of each
other.
It's horrific.
It's like kind of the opposite of
taekwondo was a lot of kicks and punches
only to the body too.
But Kyoko Shin,
they,
they through leg kicks in there and
there wasn't a lot of foot work with
most of those guys.
Most of those guys stood in front of
each other and battery each other.
But a lot of killed Christian guys went
on to be really successful in
kickboxing.
In fact,
a lot of,
um,
a lot of the Holland influence in
kickboxing came from qcc shouldn't
background,
like they started out with kewill
cushion and kickboxing and then they
learned Thai Thai techniques as well.
But a lot of those guys had a,
an influence of a cube auction.
Karate is very big in Europe.
Started in martial arts.
The big thing was just sweep,
sweep,
delay.
Early seventies,
everybody swept to high kicks and even
if it was a spinning back kick your,
the third one was a sweep and that
motherfucker was gone.
I used to go to all those karate
tournament and that was my shit I throw
to high spinning back kick.
So he doesn't even want them to hit
sweeps allergenic and nobody's sweeps
anymore.
Nobody sweeper still do an MMA and more
tied to a little bit,
a little bit.
Never made,
but not as much as I'd expect.
Good sweep with a good fucking leg.
If you set them up with good old
fashioned and sweep.
I mean,
what's his name as that little sweep the
leg.
Push your back.
Uh,
you know your boy here,
Jon Jones?
No,
the other guy,
John Jones has it to all those
restaurants.
Does that show that little sweep that I
liked,
that little sweet,
but I'm talking about from the fighters
position to just coming to you with a
sweep and throw your legs out for
Monday.
It takes a bunch of fakes or I'm here
with them.
It's basically off like blah,
blah blah.
And instead of the elbow coming around,
your leg comes around and sleeps.
That guy off his feet.
He lands on his back and you went back
with your left.
There's still some,
some guys that are really good at
sweeps.
The thing about mma is just,
there's so many different things going
on,
you know,
but in Moy,
Tai sweeps are huge and more tied to a
big part of the sport.
You know,
that's why I got cast when fights in
Bellator,
he's so high level and more now he's
getting into mma and he's fucking guys
up,
not just with sweeps and spinning
elbows,
all sorts of shit.
That is,
that his level of more tie,
like,
more time involves a lot of grappling,
a lot,
a lot of weird stuff.
Listen to Kenny Florian one time and he
goes that,
uh,
you know,
more tire even as a couple of aspects
from Jujitsu in it,
I guess not Jujitsu,
but something Roman Greco Roman
mountains.
Right behind that though is clenching.
There's a lot of clench work and those
guys develop really strong cores and
knacks that grabbing her by the back of
the neck,
moving each other around,
sweeping each other all the time.
There's so much involved in framing with
your forearms and sweeping the legs out
and twisting and,
and changing angles.
It's a great one when you learn the
other aspects of wrestling,
when you learn takedowns and control and
then when you learn Jiu Jitsu and all
these other like having that background
from the clench or Moitai is so gigantic
because so many different things opened
up from their elbows open up from their
knees to the body open up from their us
in high school.
I wrestled one year in high school.
Why didn't you wrestle for?
Because I was still doing taekwondo at
the time.
I had to figure out what.
What was more,
you know,
what was more important to me?
I just.
I couldn't do both.
It's just too exhaust.
That wrestling shit,
Mr.
he used to have that fucking weight room
down 290.
They were doing the yoga before Hatha
Yoga was invented that room and it was
hotter than bestest.
Covered off the ceiling.
I was like,
what is covering these pipes?
No one's checked these pipes.
I'm like,
I don't want cancer.
What's happening in this?
The fucking best.
Those that we breathe as best as I paint
chips,
get a guide and all the water had led.
It didn't have land.
You'd be like,
what?
I went to the park yesterday,
my daughter and there was a lady next to
me and she asked me where I was from and
she goes,
her father was from Brooklyn and we
started talking and she had beautiful
two year old and a two year old got
caught on one of the monkey bars and the
father had to go over and help her and
she goes,
I remember going up to my father's
neighborhood and seeing this play art
that were nothing like these are.
I still remember coming from Cuba and
doing that,
you know,
in monkey bars,
but then you get so good that you put
your legs up and you hang by your knees
and one day Brian and hanging right.
And I landed on that concrete.
There was no rubber in those days.
It was just straight up concrete.
Half the first grade I fucking torched.
I switched the first grade.
I landed right on my fucking neck.
I never got on a monkey bar.
Got Break.
A lot of kids don't fuck around with
monkey bars at all.
Thought I broke my arm in the monkey
bar.
My daughter broke her arm in a monkey
My another kid in my daughter's class
broke her arm in a monkey body down with
a monkey bar.
Fall down.
Try to catch yourself.
Put poster arm snap.
Yeah,
you got a real common monkey bars or
fucking dangerous because you're don't
have the hand strength yet.
You're six years old,
so you grabbing ahold of bars and you're
swinging and you just don't really have
the dexterity of the hand strength and
it slips and you fall back and your post
and you got to see my daughter on that
monkey bars.
She gets it.
She does it until my hands bleed.
Dog little blisters.
The mother's got to put a bandaid on.
It's fierce.
Yeah.
I liked that about it.
She's fierce.
I take it to.
I put a lot of time into that shit.
I,
you know,
it's really weird because of the cabinet
on situation and the Harvey Weinstein
situation.
You're a dad.
I'm a dad.
It's different than how you got to raise
your daughter.
Now.
This has affected me in a way.
The capital thing was pissing me off for
a few weeks because I don't like the
idea that they could come back to you
for something you did in high school
that that's just not right in my world.
Unless I fucked you in the ass in
highschool and covered your mouth.
I didn't do nothing.
You know what I'm saying?
I think that was the thing he did do
though.
He did cover covered amount or whatever,
but who knows what really happened?
Nobody knows.
So it was 36 years ago.
I know for a fact.
I've known you for 20 and I've seen you
sweeten up over the years.
We all change.
You're not the same Joe Rogan I met 20
years ago.
I'm definitely not the same guy was in
highschool school.
Come on please.
But he was a.
He was a guy that was hanging around
with a bunch of drunk jocks and we all
remember drunk and you know,
you know,
and that,
that,
that environment that,
that sort of in the environment of being
around a bunch,
a bunch of drunk guys who are constantly
one upping each other,
I'd say that's a sketchy fucking
environment.
And that's the frat houses.
Well,
the Yale thing scared me.
That's what I thought.
You know,
those guys that rich kids,
you know,
what happened was I got a little bit of
money.
Everything's been covered up all their
lives.
Everything has been covered up all their
You know,
when I was a kid,
I knew this girl,
they used to call them Monday and Friday
nights to get in a car and they drive it
to like fucking Connecticut and those
yet to suck all the decks to get home.
God knows of that poor girl is today.
Last time I saw it was 1993 getting
coconut building in Harlem and she's
like,
you gotta save big with some guy in the
car.
He doesn't want to leave me alone.
I'm like,
listen bitch,
I'm walking to my car.
I never saw you before my life.
I swear to God.
I bumped into an cop house on 181st
street,
10 years after high school.
I'm in a fucking fourth floor with some
Dominican's.
I'm walking down the stairs and there's
mindy had and she's like,
what are you doing here?
The same thing you're fucking doing.
They obviously what's fucked up is for
some people their experiences in high
school define them.
You know,
I just watched that.
A Stephen King movie it the most recent
one with the clown.
Yeah,
pretty fucking good.
But one of the things that I was
thinking when I was watching it was like
how fucking mean kids are in school to
each other.
I guess you kind of forget about that.
And then you watch one of those movies
about people being mean to people and
you're like,
oh yeah,
I remember going around to get away from
a guy that was picking on me that was
fuck with me.
And like you would be scared of running
into him at the bus stop and scared of
seeing them after school.
And that's how I got into martial arts
in the first place.
I got tired of being scared,
scared of people's judgment.
I was still fucking kid.
Let me tell you the funniest thing about
the movie.
It was so they fuck with clowns.
So two months later,
a bunch of clowns and got together and
went on strike.
They went downtown and they had a
parade,
like a,
not a Perretta,
what do you call it when people get
together and.
And they fucking have science.
This is right after that movie was
released.
Whenever that movie was released,
a month later,
two months later,
a bunch of clowns in the California area
got together downtown and picketed
Stephen King because they will lose work
as clowns Christ.
Because they had lost a bunch of clowns
got canceled.
They lost all their clown season work or
some shit.
I read the book a long time.
Which one?
I remember I was like,
man,
how are they?
Gonna make a movie out of this.
And they made a movie out of it way back
in the day with John boy from the
waltons.
I mean the dude with the mole on his
face got a pony.
Talented.
I watched it the other night on tv,
just flipping through the channels it
was on and it was after a couple of days
after I'd seen the most recent version
of it.
It was hilariously bad.
Who is so stupid.
But it was John boy with the Waltons in.
Might've been.
How many versions of that it movie?
Did they make that?
Was it just two?
The first one was the first one with
Tim.
The guy from the rocky horror picture
show that will allow.
It was who the clown was.
Yeah.
It was so stupid.
It was like,
it wasn't scary at all.
I mean,
not,
not even remotely,
but the new one was pretty fucking
scary.
Well,
Stephen King dog is so fucking crazy
motherfucker.
We both read on writing.
Well we both did.
You see him on the songs and he ever.
No,
he went,
they contacted from like,
we want you to be on a Sunday.
And he's like,
it was the only way I'll be honest,
it's like if I could ride my motorcycle,
they had to go back and forth,
like we don't need just what I just tell
you if I go on Sunday and I had to ride
my motorcycle.
So he played a creepy guy that makes you
disappear after they kill you.
Really?
Like he comes in and measure like you
were on the floor dead and he walked in
and measure you and tell you what he
needs.
I need a rope.
I need some gasoline.
I need a club.
I also need a selection of Seventies.
Classic rock.
And then you disappeared when you come
back.
There's nothing there.
And they walk them out.
He tells you what you want.
How much?
800.
You pay on the 800.
If you only have six,
he'll look around the room.
It just take like a statue.
Just walk out of your house.
Ties a statue on the motorcycle.
He was classic Sunday Attic,
you know?
Uh,
the crazy thing about him was his battle
coming back from getting hit by that guy
in a car.
He was a walking,
I think it was in Maine,
right?
It was walking and some guy wasn't
paying attention and fucking hit him in
his car and just destroyed his body,
like just destroyed his body.
Like,
I mean he was fucked up for long.
The motorcycle and a motorcycle.
Yeah.
Shattered his.
No,
no.
He was walking.
He was just walking.
Then we got hit by a guy in a van talk.
When I read that,
I think you turned me onto it.
When I read that chapter on Carrie,
how he got written half a carry and
threw it away and his wife found him
finish it and it was about a girl with a
period or something and
like I was in shock.
Great Book.
Carrie is a great book.
Carrie and Cujo,
my favorite Stephen King books who?
Joe,
till this day I have it.
I look at it and I respected the site
cocaine.
I don't even open that book.
I just look at it and touch it from time
to time and I go,
Ooh,
I don't know if I want to get into that
thing.
No,
it's a great book that they like the
movie version of it.
It's just like,
Eh,
was pet cemetery.
Pet cemetery is a book.
Here's some things about books.
You know,
I hate the cliche that books are better.
Oh,
the book's better.
But what is interesting about books is
there certain things that you shouldn't
really see?
You should only imagine like they work
out better in,
in your,
in your imagination,
like there's something much creepier
about them in your imagination and pet
cemetery.
Think he was right about something
creepy.
Done.
Like whenever I have a hard time
sleeping or something like that,
something's going on with me.
So instead of sitting in bed and having
what's called insomnia,
I get up and I write it up.
When you read that back,
it's like when I write about something I
did as a kid,
whether it's Robin,
Freddy at Putnam field.
When I was a kid,
I used to rob this gas station every
eight weeks and you know,
like when I was in West Palm Beach,
your kids showed up.
Kid showed up in my school when I was in
West Palm Beach and he goes,
I will have something,
and he goes,
this is a map you drew of us.
We're about to rob a gas station in
1981.
He still had the map with me with stick
man grabbed this.
We would rob this gas station every six
to eight weeks.
Come in from the left,
coming from the north.
I don't even know what the fuck.
The point I'm trying to make was,
I forgot it somewhere along the line,
but right about things that you did that
were even when I write about that and
you read them,
it's different.
Iphone.
Fuck you.
Reading is fucking phenomenal.
Build imagination.
That's why when you read silence of the
lambs and you watched a movie,
you got to get everybody in that room
and give him a big hug because they kept
it honest.
They kept it real.
When you read William Blake leaves the
excesses and then the emphasis has been
on for the last two weeks on AMC and
I've been watching bits and pieces of it
and I can upload it more.
You know,
it was fucking great.
That moving the priest.
That's Jackie gleason son in law.
Is it really?
Yes.
Jason,
who's Jason?
Whatever his father,
Jason,
whatever it was that he was in sleepers
with,
uh,
with uh,
Brad Pitt Deniro.
He played the newspaper reporter.
That's his fucking father.
But Damien,
charisse plays the priest.
That's Jackie gleason,
his son in law.
He married Jackie gleason,
his daughter.
And it's funny because last week I was
in my office typing and my wife called.
She goes,
I'm gonna be home in 20 minutes with the
baby,
so I don't know what you're doing.
I go,
right.
So I want the living room.
I turned the TV on just to be out there
because unless you're going to want to
watch cartoons or whatever,
and I saw the exorcisms and I turned it
on and dog it came on when the priest
comes through the door,
which if I bump into that director,
I will take this deck out and suck it
because that's what real directing is he
scheduled without showing you anything.
When the priest comes through the door,
all you see is an image and you don't
see what his face looked like and it
scares you,
but when he walks in,
he takes this motherfucker and the guy
says to him,
can I get you something?
How was your trip?
Can I get you something?
And he goes,
do you want some coffee?
no,
let's do this.
And this guy's a psychiatrist.
You have to watch the gun.
This guy's a psychiatrist.
Not only is he a priest and he starts
dropping and psycho and the priest looks
over and goes,
knock it off.
The devil is cutting,
you know,
tack your psychological like nobody else
to not listen to him.
And he just breaks it down.
And then the guy says to him,
do you want to know the three levels of
manifestation?
And he looks at him.
He goes,
no,
there's only one st and St.
so it's just right there.
You're like,
so my daughter walks in while it's on.
The five-year-old walks in and she sits
on my lap and she's a Bible beater.
I don't know if you know this,
that mercy is a Bible beater.
She loves anything with God and you know
I got a little fucking thing she gave me
with Jesus of fish.
Yeah,
mercy.
My daughter is a Bible beater.
Even though she goes to fucking public
school,
she'll come home and they didn't talk
about God today.
So she's watching this whole
manifestation of these two priests
talking about God is powerful.
God is going to kill Satan and all of a
sudden they walk into the room and she's
sitting up and she's like,
my daughter caught it.
Took like 30 seconds to just look at me
and she just ran out of the room like
she doesn't know who Satan is,
nothing.
She just ran out of the room.
This is one of the scariest movies.
One of the finest movies.
She elevates himself.
Comes down.
What about when they say they do the
first thing they walk out and what about
when they walked back in and he's a,
he's a doctor so he's checking her heart
and she turns into the mother and the
hospital and start saying bme while you
do this to me and,
and the priest told him,
don't listen to them that the devil's
cunning,
you know,
and all of a sudden,
what about when he comes in?
He goes,
father,
I bought sparing fine science but on all
off the bar because the devil start.
I mean Bro,
you have to watch it and while all this
is going on,
you have to remember that there's a
murder going on.
Because the first night when she came
down,
before the devil came and some guy was
talking,
shit,
I'm not saying he was talking shit.
A Jewish guy was talking shit about a
Nazi or something and she comes down and
piece and says,
you're going to die,
motherfucker going to die up there to an
astronaut wasn't,
it wasn't an astronaut.
He was something downstairs.
Didn't she say something like that?
You're going to die up there.
No,
no,
he was downstairs in the living room and
they was sending like a,
didn't she?
She was talking to a guy who was an
astronaut and she said you're gonna die
and then she peed the carpet and then it
was a dinner party and then a couple
nights later they found the guy on the
bottom of the stairs,
but it couldn't have been a girl because
they twisted this neck all the way
around.
Right?
Yeah.
So it had to be a man and that's why you
have to watch that movie when the cop
comes to talk to her mother was a famous
actress last time I watched it was like
five or six years ago.
It's first one,
it's a deep moving.
That girl got fucked up doing that
movie,
you know,
listening.
How can they make a 12 year old girl
just took a crush on her pussy.
I mean,
let's talk about truth now.
She stuck across no pussy.
Took it out,
grabbed her mother by the ears,
put her,
said suck it,
eat me,
let me.
Yeah.
Alright.
And then picked her up and smacks her
and throw it across the fucking room.
She says,
your mother's sucks.
Cox in the house.
She told her one breaks.
Then you show that in the movie theater.
Shame on them.
Like if I could sue the union city
cinema today,
I was sue them because they didn't check
my id.
They didn't give a fuck.
They took my $2 and let me threw me to
the fucking walls.
But I also saw.
What was her name again?
Linda Blair Blair.
She showed up.
Twenty years later she started hanging
out with Rick James.
Oh Man.
She.
She shown up 20 years later.
Richard.
I wonder what Linda Blair is doing for
that,
but I hope they paid her a lot of money
because she never really recovered from
that.
She never really worked after that.
It's something at work after you put a
cross in your pussy.
I mean that's Ginger Lynn.
It's tough to get a commercial for
fucking bounce.
I.
Yeah.
Well it's also.
People never forget you were that
person.
Like it's very difficult for people to
have a changed perception was she walks
down the stairs backwards.
What about when a head spins around in
front of the priests?
It's just too out there for a movie.
They could never.
They think of remaking that every once
in awhile and they looked at each other.
Jesus Christ.
That was a creepy fucking movie and you
kind of realize that back then there was
nothing like this before this movie,
this movie was so extreme like there had
been horror movies before,
but it was like Frankenstein or Dracula.
They were kind of scary,
but the warm blooding though there was
nothing like this movie.
This movie was so over the top and
people,
a lot of people at the time or like
this,
the movie represented something and
representative of boundaries that
people,
these young kids,
these people today like what the fuck
are they doing?
What kind of movies or they may
category.
I remember being,
I remember being in Catholic school and
they will just piss.
They would tell them it's not to go see
it.
We weren't allowed to go see it,
bro.
That's,
I was right there when the movie got
released and I had to say it and they
tell you can't see it.
You're gonna.
See,
it blew my fucking.
That's where I saw rocky,
where everybody was on their feet
yelling for rocky.
This was different.
Everybody was young,
rocky,
and they also saw the longest year I the
original,
and this was a movie theater that was
basically Irish,
Italian and Cuban.
But they,
they,
they talked,
they yelled at the screen,
you know,
they threw things at the screen and when
the fucking longest yard,
when burt reynolds was coming back,
the whole place is on their feet.
This was a great movie data and they let
you in and they played the last movie at
1130.
I just thought,
you know how many times I saw enter the
dragon.
They man,
the late movie.
My mother let me walk up there.
It was on 48th street and my mother's
brother was on 29th street and she'd go,
go and I saw everything that fist of
fury,
the outlaw Josey Wales,
all those fucking movies.
I saw that.
And even when they played,
I just go there as a Spanish kid and
watch and learn the language and loved
it.
They had limitations,
what they could do with special effects.
And so because of that you had to
accomplish much more with even with
American Werewolf in London,
right?
The original.
What year was that made?
I want to say 81.
I'm going to guess.
Look at what year was it?
Was it 81?
I'm the special effects.
Even though they were groundbreaking for
the time,
like when he's lying on the floor and
his body stretching Isaac and he's
turned into the wolf.
Like that shit when his face is
stretching out.
I mean those are groundbreaking special
effects.
Like no,
no one had ever seen anything like that.
I enjoyed this.
I enjoyed.
It's watching a movie now and 30 percent
of it.
Forty percent of the CGI.
Yeah.
Well that's what drives me fucking
crazy.
I watched that shit drives me crazy the
other day.
Which one?
Underwater?
Kevin Costner?
No,
no,
no.
That was with the girl,
the vampire and the,
the Lichens Kate beckinsale Christ.
She's just tremendous.
She's tremendous,
tremendous.
She's so hot.
She's just tremendous.
I fell in love with him with the move
when she got caught with heroin,
with Claire Danes at the jail in
Thailand.
Oh,
that's how long I've been in love with.
It goes with,
with her and Claire Danes.
Kate beckinsale something.
They both fell in love with the same guy
and he put heroin on him and they put
them in a prison.
So I was flipping through the channels
while I was broke down palace
when uh,
oh,
there it is.
When I was doing that,
uh,
I'm doing this fucking fitness channel,
this fitness challenge with Ari and Bert
and Tom and I just watching anything I
can on TV while I'm on the elliptical
machine or the rower or whatever the
fuck I'm doing.
And I was watching one of the underworld
movies and I realized there's like 10 of
them.
I mean,
how many fucking underwear world movies.
Is there been more than that?
How many is.
She's been all of them.
She's the main star.
They're so stupid.
The fucking one that I saw,
I've been deep in.
She has a daughter now and there's five
of them.
I don't know which one I saw,
but uh,
for the first two and I think the one
that was watching a lot of control for
me that was,
I think I was watching blood wars.
It was so dumb.
But anyway,
the CGI,
the Werewolf's are so corny.
They show you too much.
It looks fake.
And the thing about an American Werewolf
in London is they showed you a little
quick snippets of the thing before we'd
kill people and it was just enough
likely that they look so stupid.
It just looks fake.
Like Cgi just does not look.
And that was something that Pat Mcgee,
the guy who made that the werewolf out
there in the lobby,
it's what he had told me.
He's like,
when you see your,
your brain can tell that's not real.
Like even if it looks really good,
your brain can tell it's not real.
He's like,
what your brain.
If your brain sees special effects like
makeup,
like that kind of stuff.
Like,
like,
uh,
a face that's been done with prosthetics
and teeth and fangs.
Your brain says,
oh,
that's a real thing.
That's the thing that's right in front
of you.
Yeah.
Look,
these worlds are so corny.
When they're running,
it looks fake.
There's shadows.
Look fake,
but pull up scene from American Werewolf
in London like,
uh,
like the actual werewolf.
They had very,
very quick scenes.
He didn't see much of the Werewolf.
It was very fast.
Like you see running through the streets
of London.
You see it snapping it.
Things like in that one that's in the
beginning when they first got jack by
the war.
Jesus.
Yeah.
Like this.
Give me some volume here.
It puts it back.
It up for a second.
Bag it up.
So.
So they're running.
You're really scared me.
You shithead going to help me up.
Why?
So you didn't see much?
Well,
here's the,
here's the corny.
It's 1981 right now.
I remember seeing Joe Rogen.
You said it best a couple of minutes
ago.
That the thing that pisses me off the
most is.
And today's the whole movie business.
I grew up on the movies.
I'm a fucking immigrant kid.
I love movies.
Remember when they have Tony Montana in
the fucking detention thing and he goes,
how'd you learn how to speak Spanish?
English?
Because I watched a movie set Gleesa
Bro.
What Cubans?
Anybody Philippe's bars have told me
that learned from watching TV by
everybody.
So you watch TV.
The problem that happened somewhere
between 85,
maybe 87 today is the disconnect of the
director and you asking me Joey,
what's the disconnected?
The director,
the imagination.
I just watched something on scarface.
I almost called you because it was so
interesting about the dilemmas they had
scarface.
When they gave it an x rating,
scarface came out.
Pachino said that at the release,
at the party,
a scarface,
he just sank.
People were getting up and leaving 20 at
a bunch.
They took Joan Collins aside and they
said,
the gentleman's Collins,
what did you think of the movie?
And she goes,
I left after I know.
She goes,
I think $100 bucks is enough flux for a
person's lifetime.
Like they it.
So.
But they showed that's enough of
persons,
not that I left,
that they counted how many fucks he said
and all this stuff.
But that's not my point.
The point is that when they,
uh,
the guy that directed that had to go in
front of a board,
it's a big difference about me showing a
chainsaw going through your arm.
Then you seeing it and then seeing your
face and you bleed.
You follow me,
the right.
That's why they had to go to that.
That was better.
That yes,
you know,
they have the x rating,
when it's a beautiful story,
this,
it's supposed to be me,
you and him.
And he's supposed to make the decision
to direct abroad violence specialist,
psychiatrist,
but thought he brought 100 witnesses.
They were there all fucking day to prove
his point.
That take it from an x rated movie to an
r rated movie.
When you watch once upon a time and the
West,
Sergio Leone,
he was the king of the directors because
he gave you the decision to decide,
are you with me?
He gave it to you when Charles Bronson
gets off the train,
the beginning of once upon a time in
America and the street dudes waiting and
the train goes by and all of a sudden it
stops and all of a sudden you hear a
harmonica and he hit Charles Bronson
going and they look up when they see
Charles Bronson,
but they're not.
They're not.
Look,
it's not focusing on Charles Bronson.
Sir.
Got All these fucking with you.
He keeps showing you this fucking thing
that keeps going like,
take me back,
Sir Joey only let me watch this
gunfight.
He gave you a imagination.
Directors gave you an imagination.
They gave you a split second to decide
whether what was going to happen.
Now I know the story before it happens.
The director was something special.
That's why Sergio Leone,
he goes,
guys don't spaghetti westerns with
genius because they gave you.
Are you with me?
You gave me a second to split the side.
Yeah.
You have to think about what's going on.
I did that scene.
I could have put it in his arm or showed
Pachino his face.
Will you remember high plains drifter?
Tremendous.
Is that the one where he's a ghost and
it was back there and paints it?
No paint time.
No,
no,
no.
It's Hypo.
Is that high plains drifter?
Am I getting the wrong name?
I mean I'm.
I'm,
I'm thinking about when it comes back as
it goes.
That's the one.
Yeah,
high plains.
Was it?
Hang 'em high?
I don't know if it was hang them high.
What's the one that we as the shield
underneath and he knows the emily shoot
for the heart and they keep shooting at
him and he falls down and they shoot him
and he falls down and shoot to them.
They fall down.
I don't remember.
Janie put Google.
Clint Eastwood comes back as it is.
High Plains drifter just isn't in the
description.
Yeah,
I'm parked ghost story part revenge West
thing about that movie is like you don't
realize.
It's like they don't spell it out for
the dummies,
that he's a ghost six cents then now
like you have to figure it out at the
end of the movie.
If I remember correctly.
It's been a long time since I saw it,
but at the end of the,
the end of the film,
they sort of lay it out in the
beginning,
the beginning,
they show,
God,
I might be wrong here.
I feel like at the beginning of the
movie is them beating him and killing
him.
They whipped him at the end of the
movie.
You kind of realize it's him coming back
towards the end of the movie,
but it's not like specifically spelled
out like it was a curse and he came back
to haunt this town and kill everyone.
It wasn't that cornball.
So if you go back to like the older
movies,
you'd go back to like,
you know,
like a Frankenstein or Dracula type
film.
They spelled things out like they
treated you like you were a dumb ass and
they spell things out and then they
eventually stopped doing that and they
put mystery and imagination and films
and then somewhere along the line,
at least with modern blockbusters.
If
I had to guess,
I would say part of the problem is
there's so much money involved in these
movies.
If you're going to make a film and you
know it's some gigantic thing with
special effects and the studio's dumping
hundreds of millions of dollars into it,
they want a return on their money.
I saw people discussing that.
I think Johnny Depp was just kind of
kicked off,
isn't the right word,
but he's not going to be in the next
pirates movie.
I guess discussing under like in the
comments section like it was the word
last one was the worst one that of the
of the lot and they spent $330,000,000
on the budget but it made $800 million
and they're like,
that's a failure.
Some people were saying like that's a
failure.
Yeah,
for them it's a failure of $100.
Million is a good.
Well,
Johnny's off the rails right now.
He shaved his head,
Johnny Depp.
He looks like he weighs 35 pounds.
He shaved his head.
He's fallen out of his jeans.
Whenever you get like two tattoos of a
woman,
the only been married to for like six
months.
These are all bad signs.
Joking.
This is a very rough town to live egos
and motherfucker.
People blowing smoke up your ass as a
motherfucker.
I mean this guy is spending a half a
million dollars a month on wind.
Yeah,
know exactly.
Don't quote me on that,
but I know that when,
when the accounts,
I read the caption that said that he was
spending $30,000
and he goes,
it was a lot more than he was joking
around about it.
It was a lot more than that.
Like these pictures of him now stay
humble or be humbled.
He's wearing a shirt.
Dude,
you're 55 years old.
Why the fuck would you wear that shirt?
Well,
who's walking on?
Meanwhile I got a Derrick Lewis.
My ball was a shirt on,
but look,
these fucking inspirational quotes you
expect to see on some strippers,
instagram page.
You're not supposed to be wearing those
when you're Johnny Depp.
Okay,
this is.
This is outrageous.
Johnny Depp.
Why are you wearing that on a shirt?
And I heard that this last movie he did
Mucho.
Mucho programas,
which a lot of a lot of problems.
What was the moving the Tupac,
but it's on shelf.
Right?
And not put it out.
Is he the shelf?
Yeah,
they're not putting it out for right
now.
It's not coming out as he to the cop
that broke a if you will.
I forget them.
That's a good book.
Yeah,
but whatever.
I forgot.
I have it at the house.
He plays the cop in there that there was
a little and the word got out.
That's it.
Well,
you know Johnny Depp at one point in
time when he had done that.
That movie dead man.
Do you remember?
Dead Man?
No.
Interesting movie.
It was a weird black and white movie
about a guy who was riding a fucking
train across the west.
He was talking in an interview about he
wants to do interesting projects.
He goes,
I'll.
I'll never be blockbuster boy.
But then he became blockbuster boy.
Oh,
but he's bad ass pirates of the
Caribbean.
Look,
he's fine.
Don't give a fuck what anybody.
Phenomenal.
Phenomenal for them.
He's really good.
Good.
I love.
He's a great actor.
They cut him loose.
He made a ton of money for them.
They did five fucking movies,
but you know he's boys with him,
Stan Hope,
right?
Essentially Johnny d,
this fucking motherfuckers with her.
Everybody thinks you're going to spend
money on their website.
Guess what?
We're not.
We're not paying to read your fucking
website.
We're not Johnny Depp.
What does it say?
And biggie Tupac movie abruptly pulled
from release.
Forrest Whitaker.
Granted it looks like.
Hmm.
Yeah.
Like a month before it supposed to come
out.
They just pulled it.
Well in my suck.
They don't pull it if it's awesome,
but the point is,
you know,
Stan helps boys with him and he's like,
he said that once he did those pirates
movies,
he couldn't go anywhere.
It was over.
He can't go to restaurants.
You can't go anywhere.
You just can't go anywhere.
He,
he hit that upper echelon of fame where
it's almost,
there's no turning back.
When you get like Michael Jackson type
frame,
you just get crazy.
You,
your,
your world is just,
it's no one can relate to you.
What will they give them?
A movie he was making like $30 million a
movie with back end of everything.
I bet he was making more than more than
that,
right?
Yeah.
That's.
He's got like 18 houses a boat.
He's got 14 houses.
You know.
I remember when I was in Colorado,
someone said he had a ranch out there.
I go,
has he ever go there?
And he goes,
no,
just as a ranch.
What about what I house sat for the guy
that don't Tgi Fridays.
She was on the board directors.
Did you?
Yeah,
when I lived on 40 4:35,
far away road and snowmass village,
Colorado.
I have sat and the guy,
the two years I was there,
he came a week and a half.
He came for three days and his daughters
came for three days.
They spent 2000 on booze.
They all got drunk and they left two
days later and I was talking to the door
and she's like,
yeah,
this is.
My Dad's got houses all over the place.
He had three in Colorado alone,
like crusty crested butte,
snowmass village,
and he had a house on the other side to
ski over there because he liked to.
Different types of powders.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ,
that world,
when people get that famous,
when they get that rich,
when they get that,
the point where they live in some sort
of weird la La land.
He had a brand new jeep delivered every
year
and part of my agreement was I had a
driver like 50 miles a month to keep
make sure because when he came to town
he didn't want no problems with none of
his houses.
So we had a different fucking house
sitter at every.
And if the background check on,
you know,
I listened to me,
I fucking grandfathered in to the house
because my buddy from had it and his
girlfriend came up to visit and he
knocked her up but the guy was difficult
to get ahold of because he was in
England and whatnot.
So my friend just said to me,
just just move and don't say Dick when
he comes in,
he'll see it to you and tell him I had
to leave and shit.
Keep my deposit.
So I stayed there for like two months
and he came and he's like,
who the fuck are you?
And I told them what had happened and
that we couldn't get ahold of him
because he was in England and he asked
me for a couple of names.
I had already lived in snowmass for
about a year.
I left and then came back.
So I had a couple of nights references
for me,
gave me the thing and then left and I
was not allowed in this home.
So part of the deal was I had an
apartment over the garage,
I could use this car and it was 18 hours
a month to be the shoveling snow or 18,
18 hours a month of work or.
So it was essentially a shoveling snow
in the winter and the along in the
summer he would give me little
assignments like paint the wall or
whatever.
I would do keep the trim up and ship.
It was zero rent.
I think he paid me $100 a month and I
got to get a day job and ski and Shit
like that.
It was found to have man,
you're a volunteer fireman because.
Alright.
So cocaine was $1,800
an ounce at the time.
And snowmass,
my buddy said,
give it to me for $800,
Jersey.
So I would go back and forth and I was
making all this dough on and the people
found that the guy that they blew up the
pipe bomb in this guy's car and they
blew him up.
His name was Steven Gray Ball.
He left a big gap in this fucking drug
place.
So I was them.
Oh yeah,
they killed.
This boy passed in Colorado and Aspen 36
days before he was to stand trial.
They could never get him for cocaine.
He was making $6 million every six
weeks.
I spoke about this a million every six
weeks in 1984,
they arrested him the first time and 83,
they brought him to Denver.
They found 9 million altogether cash
that in 84 was when he went.
Every night he'd worked out.
It was a good looking dude that kept in
shape.
He had 20 different cars and every night
he gives her the guy at the door to
start the car.
That night the guy took the night off.
He started his own car.
They put a pipe bomb in his car and blew
them up.
He lived,
he made it all the way to the hospital,
but something went so deep or possess it
just bled to death.
So left this gap.
So this guy approached him and then he
was like,
man,
these people are mad at you.
They want to do business with cotton
amount.
So I had to talk to them and they said,
listen,
for you to buy.
We never do a face to face.
So they have an aspen club and have a
place called the CEO of the Aspen Club
is through,
you know,
in those days these places were thousand
dollars a month to walk it.
And I knew a girl that used to go to the
Aspen club and she used to telling me
she used to take showers right next to
Barbie,
Barbie Barbie.
Ben had a beautiful Bush.
She would tell me every night,
bobby Benton's got a beautiful fucking
bullshits perfect.
So there's the Aspen Club in the
snowmass clubs.
No mass club as golfing,
you know,
condos around the thing.
It was like $900 a month to be a member.
I couldn't have been a member.
So the only way I could become a member
with my being a volunteer fireman,
then they'd give you admission.
And so for 90 days I had a train,
you know,
go up two flights,
this thing I'll add a carry a rope,
but basically it was putting out when
tourists come,
they don't know how to fucking turn on a
fireplace.
So they clean out the showers and they
put them in and then these people would
put them in a dumpster.
So 10,
10 or you're doing this dumpster fire,
that's all you're doing,
but you've got access to the snowmass
club.
So basically I was walking to this
moment has club give the girl a $10,000,
but I need gym clothes,
workout.
By the time he got back to your locker
was in the locker.
It was all in.
They were all.
And everybody's involved.
Everybody was involved.
So the girl that worked there,
she was getting a piece of whoever knew
we had to do this or hi,
how you doing joe?
Yeah.
Okay.
Wow.
And then later on I go into the locker,
the coke would be that I get like a
half,
eight ounces,
you know,
I was a dealer and I take it home.
But then I started getting choked up
every time there was a fire I went to
like two dumpsters and this is 16 idiots
with a fire hose.
I'm like,
is this necessary?
They even gave me like a little fire
truck,
like a little,
uh,
Toyota truck with like a bell on it to
go to the Fi's athlete.
That third fight stopped showing up for
two months.
They could.
Where are you?
Zero base?
Listen,
I'm just going to go get my dick.
You want me to go put out a fire with a
dumpster?
Go fuck these.
They came over and took the dumpster and
then I went to work for this other Dude
Dick.
There was three,
six.
The Guy I worked for,
Dick Self,
the Kelly and Dick Boone was the mayor.
So I had a buddy that used to go,
you're surrounded by dik dik,
dik,
dik.
Dik.
Kelly had one of those snow companies.
And they wanted me to go in there.
I don't know what they called.
Joe Rogan so straightened me out.
It's a high low that shovel snow.
What's a high,
low,
high,
low in their warehouse truck that pushes
snorer.
So he was another poor best that made a
mistake in hiring me that winter.
And I had to be that four in the morning
for the morning.
I'm on my second gram of blow.
He'd been in front of my house beep and
I'm gonna go fuck itself not working
tonight.
He came and took his truck.
I was on a roll up.
Their role for food tastings.
Plowed snow guys who had snow trucks
when it would snow out,
man,
that was the.
You aren't getting any sleep.
Uh,
there was a bunch of guys that I knew in
Colorado.
Boston,
Boston.
Yeah.
That's,
that's,
that's a business to business in the
wintertime.
We don't.
As soon as your business,
those people start fucking getting happy
and people would look out the window
with their coffee and making sure you're
out there with the truck up the driveway
pushing snow around my buddy Jimmy.
He had a,
that was one of his side businesses.
He was an electrician.
The side business.
He had a hit a plow on his pickup truck.
It was just fucking plow people out.
Do People's driveways.
You know,
it's,
I was,
I went home this year,
March 20th.
I went home to Jersey.
I had to do a show one night or Nyack
and me.
And Are you hooked up in the city?
We had a,
but we walked around the city and the
snow had just started the snow,
you know,
and by the time I got up the next
morning,
it's no like a foot.
I'd never seen anything like that.
Like when I was a kid in jersey,
if it snowed,
that shit was the light that should
stay.
Stay.
There is,
there was no school stacked up on the
sidewalk.
Snow Bro.
My town by the fucking ounce of snow
land.
Not An inch really bad.
Fucking tremendous that night.
The roads would clean the east coast.
I'll never forget how when I left Jersey
and 83,
like if it snowed,
like let's say if it snowed and I'd had
to take the bus up here,
I would just call you and say Joe,
which smeller you'd expect me to 11.
And you know,
everything was late whenever it snowed
in Jersey.
He is this big metropolitan area,
New York City and it snowed.
The crippled the city.
They didn't know how to handle it.
Loose papers wouldn't come.
People get pissed off the New York Post.
And I remember moving to snowmass and
getting a job at aspen electric and that
meant they had a gun on the bus and
snowmass go to the bottom of the hill,
transfer and shoot the bus to snowmass.
I did this and I remember the first time
we got woke up one day and you know in
Colorado you wake up more than this.
12 inches.
It's just another day.
Just another day.
And I remember the 1983,
they couldn't fucking clean up New York,
but I'll never forget that morning
waking up and asked him like at 6:30
in snowmass and going,
they're not going to expect me to about
10.
And I walked in there at 10 people like,
what the fuck have you met?
And I'm like,
it snowed out.
The buses are running late.
They go,
everybody don't say came on a bus and
they all got here on time.
They'd fucking busted me.
Ride out like Colorado was that far
ahead of the game while they're just so
used to it.
It was so.
But like here I was living in this big
metropolitan city that four inches
crippled,
didn't Colorado,
they throw down salt,
they throw down something.
Yes.
They throw it out on something because
then you wash your car in Colorado,
they push to
do the underwater carrots to the
prevention.
Because Russ Russ travels fast and
Colorado in Boston to that salt
assaulted puts.
It'd be you'd buy old cars and uh,
in the fenders,
you know,
in the back of the fenders,
like at the corner,
that's where the salt would pile up and
you always have rust there.
He'd always have like these big pockets
of rust.
The corner of Morocco.
Yeah.
That's why California cars,
everybody was wanting to rust free
California car.
If you're buying a muscle car,
like an older,
you know,
hot rod,
you'd find a rust free California Kar,
Woo,
California.
I mean salt,
big thing with salt,
destroy cars,
destroy that frame,
destroy everything.
That's salt.
Get up in there,
just sit there and just rot away the
metal guy to take the metal,
buffet that with edge it out.
And then you would have to spray
rustoleum on it and then you'd have.
Because I would see the guys in Colorado
how they would fix the cars and they
would take like a missing bumper colored
strategically welded in.
And then you bumped that in.
You colored your buffed,
you kept putting primer on it.
And that's how they got the rust.
Died in Colorado,
got a bike.
Jersey Bodywork,
man.
Lot of east coast cars had a tremendous
amount of body work.
If you wanted a constant job fixing
cars,
bodywork was always good,
not just because accidents,
but also just because of the rust work.
Now is the rest of the product of the
humidity.
Also on the east coast,
Colorado wasn't that human.
See a little bit of rest from the
Colorado.
You getting it from the moisture,
you getting it from Saul.
I'm sure if they salt the roads,
but the east coast,
you definitely getting more.
You know,
there's a variety of factors that caused
cars to rust out older cars,
but if you can find an old rust free car
now that is like,
that's what everybody wants.
You know,
you find out 1968 Camaro that's rust
free.
Like whoa.
You know,
it's beautiful thing about corvettes.
They didn't rust.
They are made out of fiberglass,
so you get an old corvette.
Most of the bodies were pretty good if
it wasn't cracked,
wasn't damaged because they didn't rust.
I'm cutting myself.
I'm one of those fiberglass quote vetch
one time my leg or something.
My ran past them because this is the
seventies,
right?
The fiberglass,
my 65 corvette.
That things fiberglass.
Why did they fight boot glass to make
make it lighter and because they could
make cooler shapes.
If you look at a 1965 corvette,
that shape is fantastic.
We look at it,
pull up mine.
I think I have an idea how it looks
like.
It looks like a sportster.
Yeah.
That's the one that 65 to six.
Well the defenders have curves to them.
Everything has curves.
It's like such a curvy car and if you
had to do that all by banging out metal
and there's mine look fucking humps in
the curves and that thing.
Just offenders alone,
like there's so much.
That's when I had my gross old wheels.
I got rid of those stupid wheels,
but the,
the,
the shape of those things,
man.
I mean,
I mean they could do that with metal,
but there are so many complicated curves
to.
It just occurred over the door to the
fender.
The back fender.
Yeah.
You're a fan of the car.
Is this car compare as a drive?
But that's not a,
that's not a real.
I mean if you,
if you drove a regular 19,
65 corvette,
they're sloppy,
they're suspension sloppy.
The brakes at dog show,
this one here,
that thing is not regular with that
things.
What's called a resto mod.
So what that is is a 1965 corvette,
but it has a 2007 corvette engine in it
that supercharged.
And then it has an entirely modern
suspension.
Everything is modern coilovers,
modern brakes,
big ass corps vet breaks,
big fucking fat wide tires,
sticky rubber on them.
That thing doesn't handle anything like
an old car.
That thing handles like a new car.
As much as you can get a car like that
to handle like a new car.
I'm wished you drive it.
I tried that.
Fuck her all the time.
I take to the store all the time.
You ever seen me take that thing to
store?
You should go for a ride with me.
It's so fun.
I'm thinking I'd fit more telephone,
made more people under 65
things.
You know the youth fit and that totally
soprano trying to get johnny's sex.
What's the,
what's the Italian car line?
Lamborghini or Ferrari or Lamborghini?
I don't remember.
Yeah.
And he couldn't fit in their skinny
italies yeah.
But those,
uh,
you know,
when you're making a car out of
fiberglass,
you know,
it's pretty weird.
Just to go back to the lady that quit
high school when she was 16,
she was one of the most wealthiest
people in the world.
Like they're Chinese lady,
whatever her name was.
We pronounced it wrong.
It's so weird how much stock we put it
in high school.
How much stock is really in high school
right now?
You have children I don't know about
high school.
Like,
I don't know.
I don't know about high school still and
I,
I've met so many people have quit high
school that have done better with their
lives.
I thought when I quit high school I was
done.
I was fucking done.
That was the one of the worst points in
my life.
I remember I was going to get a tattoo.
I wanted to get like an Ozzy Osborne has
ozzie on his fingers.
I wasn't really a cocoa on both fingers.
Coo,
CEO and I remember walking up there that
day and on,
so wait a second,
I'm going to get nausea,
cocoa tattooed on my fingers and I'm
going to quit high school.
Like what am I made meet my chances of
really doing anything.
Like I already quit high school and I'm
going to put that Tucson on my fingers.
I'm never to do anything on my life.
And that's why chicken not from tattoos,
you know,
because you're afraid you're going to be
a loser in 1982.
A Tattoo was not a work of art.
That tattoo was,
you went to jail,
you killed somebody,
but he had that in 69.
He's had that in [inaudible].
Sixty nine.
He was cooler than fuck.
He was Ozzy Osborne and I always known
Razi.
I was born.
I was just some fucking drugs criminal,
but I knew that if I quit high school
and put ceo,
Ceo I was doing for awhile,
like I'm both hands housing.
This is a true story.
Pro Walking to the tattoo place.
It was in cliffside park and how much
weight they put on high school and like
I quit high school my junior year.
Was I good at it?
Yes.
I was very good at it.
I was very good at school.
I just had to quit school because of
necessity.
I had no parents,
you know how to quit fucking high
school,
you know,
it's so weird how many people over the
years I've read and the only reason why
I got my ged.
Let me tell you something.
I refuse to get my ged because if I
would've failed my ged I would've killed
myself.
Like if you quit high school and then
failure ged you're really doing from
life.
I didn't even want to know about the ged
thing,
but when I got arrested you got to have
a ged because you got an extra point to
your sentence.
Thing like this is a variable that I had
to.
You not going to prison for that long.
So if you get arrested and you don't
have a ged and you're not working at the
time of your arrest,
this all counts towards your sentencing
guidelines.
So the only reason why that ged fucking
thing,
because I was petrified to taking the
Joe Rogan because once you fail your
ged,
they ain't no coming back.
So I got a tattoo on my fingers.
I fucking quit high school and I fucking
failed the first ged thing.
Like I would have died.
Like I studied hard for my ged.
I bought the fucking thing.
I took a night class with a bunch of
people,
didn't speak English.
I studied hard.
I passed my ged with flying colors.
But it's so weird how they put such a
stress on it.
When I was growing up and I know tons of
kids that sophomore year said my father
owns a fucking mechanic garage or we
have a fruit company or my father was in
the stock market and he's got me a job
and I know these kids and they're doing
fine.
I just saw one in West Palm beach that
he was one of the first guys to quit
school when I was like worried about my
good.
How the fuck the quit school.
He's doing fine.
He's rich as fuck.
Well,
quitting an education like getting
quitting learning is what's really
scary.
Quitting school.
The problem with school is school,
standardized education,
right?
The education that they would like you
to get is you go through
school,
get out of high school,
you go to a good college,
you get a degree and then you go to
graduate school and then your real
success,
but there's a lot of people that did
that that there was no job for them.
They have graduate degrees and they're
not doing well and it's just.
It's not a.
it's not a guarantee,
and especially in this weird fucking
economy.
The problem with a guy like you or a
problem with a guy like me is that we're
never going to have regular jobs.
It was never going to work.
We're too fucked up for whatever reason,
for both.
Fucked up for different reasons.
I quit every fucking job,
every job.
I've never had a job for days.
I was like,
label and make 50 bucks.
I got to wash dishes.
I wash dishes for four months,
but nobody recognized that you had the
potential to be an entertainer.
Nobody ever says like,
you could be an entertainer.
You're funny,
entertaining guy.
Nobody ever brings that up as a viable
job option.
Meanwhile,
it's obviously a giant job option.
All of our friends that are like you are
that are are comics,
they're all,
we're all fuck ups in high school.
They all barely made it through whatever
job they had.
They hated every second of it and they
all thought they were losers.
That's one thing we all have in common.
We were all worried that we were going
to be a loser,
but none,
no one,
none of us had someone who said,
Hey Joey,
you're fucking funny man.
You could be a comic.
Try being a comic.
Go to an open mic night,
give it a shot and how much comics make
a weekend comic headline and a club and
the meek and Mike made $1,500.
You'd be like,
what?
$1,500
for telling jokes.
I can $1,500.
And you'd be like,
that is crazy.
And you talked about what regular people
were making,
busting their ass all week.
You could just show up on a Friday,
do two shows on a Friday,
two shows on a Saturday,
one show on Sunday,
you'd make $1,500.
He'd get home.
A lot of times it was cash.
He would be like,
what?
How do I.
How do I do this job?
What are you going to start off with?
The bike night?
You got to become an apprentice.
If so weird.
I could look you in the face and tell
you something.
I knew my freshman year of high school.
You Ready?
Yeah,
I knew one thing for sure.
What?
I did not want a day job.
No job.
No,
no,
no.
Yeah,
I didn't say that I wanted the job,
but not a job in an office.
No,
no.
There was no day job.
I'm not a future.
I was either going to be a bartender or
a waiter.
I was going to work in a warehouse like
a,
uh,
there was a company,
white rose and seacaucus was frozen
warehouse where you just got lobster
tails and shit.
You had a.
well,
I bumbled up.
They paid your 20 to one hour.
They gave you a thousand every 90 days
to buy clothing.
Like I was set to do that.
I had no problem working nine to six.
I knew one thing about my life that I
was not taking a day job because the
people I grew up around,
my mother did not avid day job.
My mother went,
opened the bar.
I set the up,
be
a boom and by 10:30
she was in Harlem picking up this,
going to a met game,
eating Chinese food.
She didn't go back.
There was 7:00
at night.
Then she worked until three.
I had no problem with working.
My first big job was bartending from
five to one in Manhattan.
I just knew that my days were mine.
I liked that I didn't.
I wanted to be opposite of everybody
else.
I wanted you to leave the fucking house.
When I walked in,
I'm going to make my own eggs.
I'm going to smoke a joint.
I'm gonna.
Watch TV for an hour.
Sleep till to get uplift.
Way descendants.
That's what I want.
I did not want a day job that I want the
opposite.
Some people's personalities that they
want to go somewhere with,
someone tells them what to do.
They want to sit in a very safe,
structured environment and do boring
shit.
I didn't.
I was.
There's a company in my town,
they may pa Anthony Impairment Torah.
When I was a kid,
APA fed everybody.
The deal was you went down in 1982,
let's say it was a 1750 an hour.
So you shaped.
Did you ever shape.
What's that mean?
Shape is you just go down there and they
look at you like Marlin Brando on the
waterfront.
You stand there like a fucking moron and
they come up to you.
We need six people tonight.
You,
you look pretty strong.
You and there's 30 people going to
shape,
shape up work.
You got to go sign up at the hall.
So if you're a long shoreman all that
shit.
If you don't have work,
you'd go do shape up work.
So you just go down there and wait for
your badge number to be called and then
they give you a work.
So I used to work at APA is a shape guy.
She got on Apa,
right,
and the first night Joe Rogan picks me.
He sees I'm a fucking meal,
a meal,
like you ain't going to break me.
The shift started at seven and they went
through a six,
but sometimes it's six,
a load of fucking Volkswagen engine.
She came in and here you are with
another fucking gorilla picking up
Volkswagen engines.
So I used,
what I used to do was you couldn't work
more than six days a month or they had
to put you in the unit.
So I would work apa,
a white truck route,
whatever.
That was.
Three different companies that you could
shape for.
So what you did was to get into the
union was once I found that Joe was cool
and Joe knew I worked at drew joe a
yardstick.
I agree a 100.
So I had guarantee two days a week work,
which is still $18 an hour plus
overtime.
So I did shapeup work and then if you
complete it like 12,
if they made a mistake and that gave you
12 days in a month,
now they had a high year full time and
your life changed forever.
Apa,
that guy in tour that owns it,
nobody owns now.
The fucking fairy.
Hmm.
Like the ferry that goes back to New
Jersey,
back and forth from Jersey and New York
City.
That's imperatore.
He didn't stop growing,
but when we were kids,
his facility,
he took such care of his employees,
his gym.
When the New York mets went from a long
island to New Jersey,
that's where they practiced the first
year.
That's how good in the seventies is.
Jim was like,
have you loaded trucks?
You were allowed to use that gym.
He already had shit that nobody had.
He had fiberglass backboards.
He had water weights.
He had shit that nobody had.
Like at that time I saw.
But my point being that that was what I
had in high school.
I could do shape work and I could still
make a living and eventually somebody
was gonna hire me.
I was going to work like a fucking meal,
but I'd still be making $1,500
a week when you're in 1980,
which,
which wasn't a lot of money back then,
which wasn't bad.
Those are the guys that buy the boats
and they go to Atlantic city and they
wear white shoes on the weekends more
than everybody else.
Because you've made great money down
there.
Yeah,
so you shape.
You could also do that as long shoreman
you go down to Newark and stay there and
then after 15 days if they get the
union,
they'll charge you $500 for a book,
which is means that you get $5,000
and unit,
but you got benefits the rest of your
life insurance and a pension and.
Yeah.
And you realize that you weren't going
to work in a cubicle.
I did not.
I knew that,
but I liked that might load and shit.
You don't know how many nights I walked
home on route three with no money.
I'm a days after loading a truck all
night,
walking home on route three because I
didn't have enough money for the bus.
I just had enough money for a breakfast
and I would walk up and get breakfast at
a diner and I go wherever I was sleeping
and fucking go to sleep.
I didn't know anything.
Comedy didn't come into my radar to a
month before I went to prison,
a month before I got locked up,
a month before I got arrested for the
crime,
nevermind prison.
There was a salesman they hired and I
just.
We did not get along.
Me and him as Carson,
he had this,
he was American Indian,
a piece of them was American Indian and
he even had that Charles Bronson look in
his eyes and one day me and him got into
a beef over a customer.
He said the customers would say is and
it was mine and me and him banged up
face to face and they had to break us
up,
but about a week later I was on the
point that means you're outside waiting
for a customer to try to get a customer
on point.
And he came out and he goes,
man,
listen,
I don't know what happened between us.
His name was Brent.
I'll never forget that man,
if I was 25,
he was about 40 something 44,
45 and I had to fucking,
you know,
I was doing drugs and I had the tough
guy mentality and I rang and I would
never raise my hand to some of the old.
I don't know why I went after him that
day,
but he came up to me and put on his
hand.
He goes,
listen man,
I don't know nothing about nothing,
but he goes,
you know what I was doing for the last
20 years,
right?
I'm not going to.
No Damn Bae.
He was,
I was the entertainment coordinator for
Casino in Las Vegas.
And he goes,
I don't know man.
You make me fucking laugh.
And I was shaking his hand going,
thank you.
Get the fuck away from me.
I make you laugh when you stupid.
And he was telling me I had a career in
comedy and I was listening to him.
He said,
you should really give it a try.
I'm like,
you're fucking crazy.
Standup comedy.
I like Freddy Prince.
I like David Brandon.
I love Richard Pryor,
but some fucking criminal.
I can't do this shit.
Not a month.
And I got arrested and then when I came
out I didn't think about it and then
when I fucking came out for reals,
there was a guy that loosened a pismo
beach now and he used to talk to me
about it.
He goes,
you ever been to the standup comedy?
And I will come on though.
Leave me the fuck alone.
I'm a drug addict in stand up comedy.
I didn't know standup comedy was about
work.
I thought that Joe Rogan,
just call it the comedy store.
Should have a camera in 10 minutes.
I'm gonna be down and you take an hour.
I didn't know that you had to work 18
months to get an hour.
Our material.
Lucky what?
I thought.
That's how fucking off I was.
I just thought that when I saw John
Leguizamo,
but he just went down it.
He just went down into the.
Well,
that's what I thought for all that time.
We're perceptions of it,
but you know,
the thing about it is that it's a
possibility and no one ever says that
it's a possibility.
It's not an easy possibility,
but it's an.
It's an option.
But being a fucking physicians,
not an easy possibility either,
but he tells someone,
you want to be a doctor.
They don't look at you like you're
crazy.
The amount of work,
it's probably pretty similar.
There's a lot of work involved in being
a doctor,
but it's a path that's been taken by
many people.
It's clearly established.
You go through school,
you go through medical school,
you go through your residency.
There's all these different steps that
you have to take that everybody's really
aware of with the standup comedy career.
No one who's other than the people that
have done it.
No one knows what it is.
You and I both know that in order to be,
you know,
say I'm a physicist,
you have to go through a certain amount
of education.
We,
we,
you know,
if you had.
Oh Tim son,
he's really smart.
He wants to work for space x,
wants to build rocket ships.
Like,
oh,
okay,
that's a possibility.
You can do that.
You're really smart.
You go to school,
you get a good education,
you follow through you,
you eventually.
There's a path there with comedy,
like no one knows that path other than
people like you were at people that have
actually done that path and make a
living doing it.
We know it,
but for everybody on the outside it's
like,
what is that?
And sometimes you need someone to come
along and tell you like the guy who you
were working with.
For me it was my friend Steve,
Dr Steve Graham for he was my friend
when I was,
you know,
he was telling me this when I was like
19 and he's like,
you're really funny.
Like you should be a comedian.
Funny to you have like other people are
going to think I'm an asshole.
That's all I was thinking is that I,
I just,
I wasn't big on public speaking but got
me into public speaking.
Honestly.
What helped me was teaching,
when I was teaching martial arts,
I had to teach in front of all these
people.
I had never spoken in front of groups of
people,
but I was really good at the time at
teaching classes I had learned from,
you know,
my instructor and there was a way to do
it.
I was very enthusiastic.
Obviously it was my life,
so it was very intense about doing it
and I got used to speaking publicly in
front of these large groups of people,
but it was because I was speaking about
something that I was good at and then I
would teach at Boston University and
when I would go there and teach the
classes,
I'd start off the classes,
you know,
and I basically said to them,
listen,
you take this class,
try hard.
You're going to get an a,
it's pass fail a.
It actually counts for your GPA.
So this is an easy a,
I don't want you to be fucking Bruce Lee
or Jackie Chan.
You don't have to do that.
I just want you to try.
If you come here and try,
you get an a that's simple and so,
you know,
became friends with a lot of the kids
because they were like my age.
Some of them were even older than me and
I was teaching them.
So that was how I got into public
speaking.
When was the first time to think before
you even answer,
besides standup comedy,
were you ever,
ever,
ever on the stage before that Improv
troupe in grammar school,
a play in high school,
Playing Grammar School?
Cool.
In College I took.
No,
I didn't do any.
I don't,
I don't think I ever did anything.
Like maybe if I did,
I don't remember,
but I in college I took a course on
public speaking.
It was like some sort of,
um,
it was some sort of course where we
would do like little play was terrible.
The teacher was terrible.
She was just this short little lazy
lady.
She was so lazy.
Like the way she would give classes was
says it was continuing education program
at Umass.
She was just terrible.
And there was the people in the class
where it was very loosely organized and
explain the lessons very well.
And uh,
you know,
we had to put together some little play
I remember was me and this girl and this
guy we put together,
we made some little funny play.
We wrote it together.
It was around the same age.
I was probably thinking about doing
standup.
I was probably 19 or 20 at the time.
I never was.
I always shunned from all that stuff.
I was always embarrassed and my,
when I got thrown out of the Catholic
school in the sixth grade,
I had this guy,
Mr Lavato Fridays.
You had a choice to fucking go be part
of the ecology club or hang out in the
class.
I don't know what made me.
I was in love with Frankie Valli.
All right.
In my eyes adored.
So he
would make me every Friday go up to the
front of the class and put my eyes
adored John,
a record player.
And I'd sing it like not lip sync it,
I'd really sing it because I really have
a good voice.
Growing up,
I was in a band as a singer.
You,
you were in a band,
sixth grade.
You've done that fucking rock and roll
show.
What does that.
What does that just out of my more?
Yeah,
it was formed as foot is.
What does that show called?
God Damn God damn damn.
Comedy Jam.
Yeah.
You've done that?
What'd you say?
A killing in the name of love.
That's right.
You did a recent anxiety ever.
Did you?
Oh my God.
Singing and doing comedies.
Two different fucking worlds.
Did you have to learn the song and
practices?
Yeah.
They wanted me to go to a rehearsal,
but I couldn't go to a rehearsal that
day.
She had no rehearsal,
no rehearsal.
I knew the song.
You know,
and it's not.
Yes.
This being held that this is that.
A couple of years ago,
this is like a year and a half ago.
I love music.
I love all this shit.
I just can't.
Whatever
happened to rage against the machine,
whether they doing these days,
they all wanted different dirt.
They're there right now.
Today.
They're in that band would be real.
Be Real.
Be Real is in the band with them public
enemy.
Why?
They're all in the renegade super band.
Oh fuck.
A tremendous super band.
What band is this?
How do I not know about this?
Something of.
Please don't come on.
Don't embarrass me and I can't pull it
up.
Yeah.
Sons of rage or somethings of rage.
And it's Tom Morello.
Uh,
the signal from public enemy be real.
Chuck d,
Chuck D.
Wow.
Flavor flavor in it?
I don't think so.
I think they'd tow flavor flavor.
You care.
Is he still married to his salons?
Ex Wife?
No.
So long as x.
y just had a baby with soffits.
Fits of rage is what?
Prophets who's in the band.
A couple of guys from rage.
Public enemy and Cypress Hill?
Yes.
The loans ex wife had a baby.
She was 85 years old.
How the fuck did she have a baby?
She had the last egg.
They found the last week there was
tucked up in a quarter.
The Fallopian tubes.
Listen man,
Mick Jagger's singing that 75 again with
the women have eggs a little longer now.
I wonder if he's got to dig a little
deeper.
You've got to dig deep,
deep,
deep in that little monkey.
Oh,
it's gotta be an A.
Janet Jackson had one of the 50.
Yeah.
I mean they're in there.
You just need a guy to give you a stab
in the.
Generate everything at the same time,
be back a lot
of loads.
Just keep those loads for weeks.
No jerking off,
no nothing,
no wet dreams for weeks,
and then just release the hounds
48 as a woman after 48.
From what I've read,
46,
47,
your chances of that child having autism
have very high.
There's a lot of chances to have a lot
of little things going wrong.
Chances are with the male,
well,
you know,
really over 50 [inaudible] yeah,
with men.
There's a bunch of factors,
but one of the factors is also the age
of the father.
That's why you see more autistic kids
these days than before as people are
putting off,
having children and having careers later
and there's complications.
It's one of the theories as to why this
more autistic kids.
Another theory is that there's not more
autistic kids would just.
We're just better at diagnosing what the
issue is with children than we used to
be.
Before I say we very loosely,
obviously Bridgette Nielsen look at
that,
so she had her first kid.
This is her fifth.
She had her first kid when she was young
and vibrant,
and the fifth kid when she's basically a
monster,
bless her.
God bless her.
God fucking blephs and 55 healthy baby.
Good for her.
I don't want to.
My.
My little girl was born.
I kept looking at her eyes.
Her Age was 55.
Incredible.
I kept looking at my daughter's eyes.
She,
she was stoned because God knows tac was
in my rifle and I shut that load of
debt,
like shut that.
Stolen the load.
It's kind of
funny,
man,
when you just think about the window of
time that you have to get pregnant and
impregnate someone.
Just so you know,
you ever run into someone and you
haven't seen them in like 10,
15 years and you see them,
you're like,
Whoa,
okay.
Time.
Time is real.
Just wears on people.
You don't think about it when you see
people day in,
day out,
I see you all the time.
You look the same to me,
you know,
but if you don't see someone for 10,
15 years like,
oh,
with you,
look at a picture yourself in to a hotel
room and you go to a hotel room that
mirrored on live liberate.
Yeah.
Officers of fucking bullshit.
All this stuff.
Motherfucker hides curves and has and
your nose.
You go to vegas and you walked past the
mirror and you're like,
what the fuck happened?
That age is a month or you watch it.
I watch a tape of myself or something.
I'm like,
wow man,
I'm getting old.
But you'd be a monster.
Last week I fucking took a red eye to
cleveland.
I get to Cleveland.
Who's,
who's the only direct flight?
You know now that everything's fucking
crazy to direct flights a day to clean.
Everybody's got a flight potentially 19
hours.
So my job,
my or choices wouldn't leave at 11 in
the morning and leave a day earlier
which a happening or take a red eye that
night and I took the red eye and we at
six in the morning,
which is three La time,
which I'm never a past fucking 1230
anymore.
And uh,
I took a thing for the whole town,
me and George Perez,
you know,
and for a couple of minutes I was a
little like,
look at my fucking life.
I'm 55 and I'm fucking taking a red eye
to do Cleveland.
And when I got into the hotel room,
I sat down and said my computer,
I'm like,
I'll fuck.
I'm lucky in my.
I'm still doing spots at the store.
I'm still going out and do on weekends.
I never dreamt that this has 48 and I'm
55.
And the headline and having a great time
laughing my fucking balls off.
We forget for a moment in time.
What happened was the car that didn't
show,
and I didn't even get pissed off,
I just said,
George,
what's happened?
The car,
we walked 50 yards.
There was a cab and that was the end of
that.
You know what I'm saying?
I don't even know.
I told you that.
I'm just saying,
well,
you know,
it's perception.
I mean,
you know,
if you showed Brigitte Nielsen a photo
of her today when she was 20 and said
you're going to look like this and five
minutes she'd probably freak out.
Probably be terrified,
but now that she's 55,
she's like,
yeah,
that's what I look like.
We all,
we all become j Dot Howard,
Marshall,
Anna,
Nicole Smith's fucking husband.
We all were going to go this so much
time.
You don't stay beautiful forever.
This is going to be an amount of time
where your body just stops working.
Right?
And your tissue starts to hang off your
face and it's just.
It is what it is and it's perception.
A lot of it is perception.
You broke it down
for me.
What you owe Romero,
your jeans.
Look,
he looked somebody like,
what's girl?
We'd discuss it thousand times.
She was married to Richard Gear with the
beauty mark.
You said you saw her somewhere and she
was still fucking beautiful.
What's her name?
Who was married to Richard?
Good.
Cindy Crawford was beautiful,
but the end of that song and said,
you've got to be kidding me.
I ran into her six months ago.
There's two girls in my high school,
facebook.
They have not aged a year and a poached
by our kids and it's,
it's,
it's also how you take care of yourself
to alcohol.
Yes.
And whether or not you're happy to
happiness.
The alcohol.
Tobacco,
tobacco is tobacco.
Listen man,
I was thinking about this.
I was so weird that once every two
years,
I don't know what Joe Rogan.
I hate being this person sometimes.
I hate being this person.
I like to have something going wrong
like I still have that bug is self
sabotage.
Sabotage everyone.
Once in awhile I go to the comedy store
and I see everybody drinking and I see
everybody doing everything else in here.
I am with a fucking water,
like an asshole.
I don't smoke at night when I drive
because I can't see at night.
You know what I'm saying?
So I can't smoke.
I can't get high.
Sometimes I go into the back and I get
high,
so every time I go a red band or give me
a fucking cigarette
and I smoked five fucking cigarettes and
I'll smoke for a week.
Do you know that Joe Rogan?
I'm a pack of cigarettes at 8:00
at night and smoked like a fiend and
throw him out of the car on the way up
the hill.
You know how bad I feel the next day
you could see how bad fucking cigarettes
are for you.
And number two is alcohol.
You know,
you could sell.
When you say this,
like how many cigarettes would you
smoke?
Like in one night?
12.
Really all through all the other eight
away in the garbage.
Wow.
And then the other day,
that's a lot.
That's a lot because I'm a savage.
One was.
When was the last time you did this?
About two months ago.
Really?
Yeah.
And you don't worry.
I didn't do it.
No,
no,
no.
I could.
All that shit is bullshit than me.
Why do you think I said that shit to you
last week about the Ambien?
I wasn't fucking around.
Where you're trying to be cute.
I do everything.
I'm sober,
but I do everything.
I'm sober right now,
I don't do coke,
I don't do heroin,
I don't do oxycontins,
but on the road people give a shit and
sometimes I put it in my pocket.
People give people give me shit all the
time.
Take the chip.
People give you all the time.
I just took some acid.
Fucking.
Somebody gave me blather.
Addison and I put it in the invite.
I put it in a battery thing.
I have like a shaver,
like took the bladder acid and put it in
the battery thing.
So it became like battery acid.
They call Lee.
Like totally it was Wolfman.
Jack said he didn't know him as Jack was
rough man.
Jack.
There's a guy.
Remember that guy?
That motherfucker.
What?
Other than episode?
He was on an episode of the hunting of
the odd couple one time and Felix wanted
some music published and it was
horrible.
So I asked who was her friend?
The wolfman Jackson.
He goes up,
man,
let me give it the Wolfman Jack.
Maybe you don't like it.
And they're both outside the studio,
wave Wolfman,
Jack and Wolfman.
Jack comes out with two freaks.
It's got a weird look on his face.
He's like,
man,
I dig noises,
a dig.
But he goes,
I haven't been this depressed and alone.
He goes,
this is just bad now if you don't mind.
I got to come down on this battery as.
And I was drinking last night.
So I've never forgotten that line as a
kid.
That Wolfman Jack Lew.
Is he still alive?
I know there's a lot of videos.
I didn't see his CV still alive.
He died in 1995.
Wow.
That's a long time ago.
Oh yeah.
It was born in 38.
Jesus Christ.
Play that black and white video on the
lower right hand corner.
Yeah.
Let me hear that.
Give me some volume.
Wolf,
man.
Jack,
just going to get us kicked off.
Youtube
volt.
Matt Jacket.
Check from August 1979.
60 six w
by NBC New York.
First air check.
First night.
No.
Wow.
How weird.
Give me a little.
Screw that up.
A little bit.
Theatrical back then before the guy.
Even several minutes into the recording,
what the fuck?
No together
maybe got better as it went along.
It was a different world back then.
All you have to do is have a big
personality,
be loud and crazy and people got used to
listen to a certain person on the radio.
Radio personalities were different thing
men.
It's like you would become accustomed to
listening to someone's voice and that
was the person who wanted to hear.
I remember a certain Radio Djs,
Charles Laquidara on the big mattress in
wbcn in Boston.
Listened to it every morning.
Let's do.
When I was delivering newspapers,
he was the morning guy and like every
place would have a morning guy and this
is still a few of them out there.
There's still a few morning guys out
there,
but man,
they're cutting those guys back there,
cutting those folks back there.
Widdling away their budget,
taken away their money.
You know,
they have to do personal appearance at
wild wings and shit like that.
Fucking shoot tee shirts out of a cannon
and all that nonsense.
It's a dying,
dying institution.
The radio world is a dying world.
It's weird.
Used to be everybody had a car radio.
You listen to the radio,
drove around.
What do we got on the radio?
Oh,
let's tune in.
What's the good local stations?
You'd find them?
Listen to some good radio such.
It's gone now,
man.
It's gone.
It's crazy.
I was never like a talk radio guy.
I can't lie to you talk.
People listen,
talk sports and people call it.
Fuck you.
They love it.
The Yankees should've beat one last
night.
It was a rough job.
That shit drives me fucking crazy.
But by the way,
congratulations on the Boston red sox.
They will fuck the tough.
Tough.
I don't watch baseball throughout the.
I don't have time,
but the Cuban once September comes.
I love the art form Joe Rowe and it's a
beautiful,
by the way.
Not only that,
I got left back and I got to read the
album only.
I'm the only Cuban like and play
baseball.
I'm possibly the only Cuban that was the
worst baseball player in the fucking
world.
Even my mother's have gone to the game.
I can't.
I embarrass the shit out of me.
I was terrible,
but during the playoffs I watched that
shit religiously.
I talked to my uncle and he fills me in.
My uncle's tremendous.
My uncle fucking knows he's eight.
He's been watching,
but he knows so I'd get on the phone
with him during the playoffs and he'll
be watching and I've talked to him and
he said,
he said he's ratting me off in Spanish.
Look at the way he throws the ball and
look at his finger how it's whole.
I mean it just.
It's a different art and Boston was just
too tough.
This year.
Joe Rogen,
they had thieves,
baseball player with the years.
It's tough to play against.
That's why me and your old partner at
the UFC with tight Goldberg,
we're both Cincinnati red fans.
What do you mean by theme?
People still basis people still basis.
I love these because they don't let the
pitcher get into a rhythm.
They get into the pitcher's head and
they start dwindling their arms and now
the pitch has got to keep looking at the
show and if you ever get a chance to
watch an old,
sincerely red bull park,
a good game,
if I find one,
I'll send it to you and you watch what
that the pit.
You're not wanting to read.
The coach comes out and get,
takes the ball from the guy and the guy
walks off and they call a reliever with
Cincinnati reds.
The coach would come on the pitch would
go,
take this fucking boy.
I don't want to pitch again because
Cincinnati was the king of bunting.
Get on first and then playing with your
head start and they would steal second
and they would hit a single.
The Cincinnati reds one.
Those all those years where Pete rose,
Pete rose was in the home run hitter.
Pete rose was headed.
That means every time he came up to bat,
you're going to have a problem and him
and concepcion and Morgan and all those
people,
they were just single hitters.
Those are the worst.
At least a home run.
I know where I stand,
but these motherfuckers that club you
with singles and doubles,
that's a different game and then I'm
stealing from you to really get down
like I'm stealing second and stealing
third that that's,
that's uh,
that sparky Anderson,
that movie.
I know you've never watched it,
but that's what it was about.
The movie with Brad Pitt,
he did about baseball.
That's a great movie because he explains
to you that it's on base percentage.
All that other shit is bullshit.
They're like,
yeah,
but this guy walks a lot,
but they get on base.
That's what it's all about.
And that's the center and Boston play
that same game.
The thieves,
they steal.
It was heart attack baseball.
You couldn't watch it if you bet the
last five games got blusher brush and
try to attack.
I got back to my room and cleaned the
tutoring in the morning.
They were still planning to die in the
morning.
I went to bed.
The dodger game was still on.
Its tremendous.
This is the time of the year that I love
playing baseball.
When it starts in April,
I don't want,
I don't know,
nothing.
I don't watch none of that shit.
None of that shit.
I played baseball
when I was a kid.
Tara.
I stopped doing it.
When I got into martial arts,
I found out about taekwondo because it
was waiting for a red sox game,
waiting for the tea to get home and
there was a big ass line to get to the t
because the fenway park would let out
and walking back from fenway park to the
train station.
I saw the taekwondo school and I went up
there and there's this guy named John
Leaves a national heavyweight champion
light heavyweight champion at the time
and he was about to go to the World Cup
and he was up there kicking the shit out
of the heavy bag and I'd never seen
anything like it in my life.
I would here in the sounds of it,
I was walking up the stairs at hearing
lump Chink,
Chink in the womp was him kicking the
bank and the bank was the chain.
As the bag would go flying through the
air and slammed against the chain.
I was like,
that is the craziest fucking sound,
and I walked in and there was this guy
who was just at the peak of his physical
power.
He was just at his very best and he was
training for a world tournament and just
watching him do that was so terrifying.
Thinking like if someone kicked me like
that,
like what it would do to my body and
that's how I got into martial arts
because before I wasn't in the team
sports man.
That's one of the reasons why I got into
wrestling and Lisa wrestling,
it's me against that guy.
I hated team sports.
I hated the fact that we were losers
because a little billy dropped the ball
like I didn't and I didn't play for the
team either.
Like they would tell her heart Rogan,
go try to get a single.
I'd be like,
yeah,
yeah.
Get the fuck out of here.
I swung.
I either got a home run or I struck out
every fucking time I was at bat.
I either could cause I got a home run
once and I was like,
oh,
that is so much better than getting a
single.
You could suck Dick for the rest of your
life or singles.
I don't give a fuck about a single.
Didn't.
I felt bad if I go on base and I got a
single because I connected once,
cock Kirouac and that ball and I can hit
pretty hard.
Not Bald,
wet fucking full lion and it went into
the stands and I was like,
oh,
this is what it's about.
It's about doing that is the only thing
that's any good about the stupid fucking
that and catching balls.
So many cracks went out there and catch
it.
That's pretty fun.
I couldn't hit a ball like I a ball my
life.
I used to bug the strike out.
I'll make like,
I was just terrible at baseball.
I just had no nothing for I.
When I went to Miami I used to go to the
red berries,
baseball camp in the summers just for a
week.
It was a week camp that you went that it
like basketball was my shit.
Basketball,
real good,
real fucking good.
Really real good.
With the five star basketball camp with
a RV Garfinkel anymore.
You ever fuck around?
My shoulders are so bad that my
shoulders.
I can't do a jumbo Jujitsu.
Yeah,
but I can't.
You can't get me an Americana like you
can't.
I tell people on American economy you
would come more on me to that bad yet to
go physical therapy.
Do you ever get an Mri?
I should,
but by the,
you know,
I listen,
you got to pick your battles and today's
insurance world.
So they're to the point where I could
lift to go to kickboxing.
You know,
I got.
Hold the microphone.
I'm fucking right.
I'm fine for right now.
My left.
My right knee is fucked up.
That's going to have to do something
soon,
but for right now,
what's wrong with it?
It never fixed.
I think the one I was doing physical
therapy,
I read,
heard it after the surgery.
It never kind of surgeries.
You get municipal thrive,
this,
that whole thing.
So I'll go back in there again and let
it all cleaned up.
Now I love basketball,
but I also loved martial arts growing
up.
I loved the whole thing of going to
forums and practicing and they can do
some fucking tremendous shit with stem
cells right now.
Joey,
they could fix all your problems.
I bet you didn't show this and yeah,
my shoulders fixed.
They fixed it.
How flexible are you?
Let me see you grab your hand and do
that shit.
We go all the way back and we do all
that.
I can do everything.
Grab them.
Go and you do that shit like there's
people could grab them,
but my kickboxing place and go all the
oil.
They could rally all the way over.
What do you mean?
Yeah,
like they do something fucking
different.
Like you're saying like do this and go
all the way you.
Oh No,
no,
no.
I know what to do.
They take the broom and they go that way
all the way back.
I'm done.
You know what else is real good for you?
Hanging just hanging.
Just grab a hold of the bar,
Chin up bar and just hang from it.
Super good for your shoulder.
Stretches them out.
Releases impingements too.
Good for the joint.
Just go out there and my little gym area
out here.
Just stretch out the president's award
either because I couldn't do a pull up.
You don't have to do a pull up.
Pull up to greg still to this day.
Can't do one.
No,
never do a pull up.
Even when I was one 80 lifting weights.
Which strife guys,
you couldn't do a pull up when you were
180.
That doesn't even make any sense though.
What the fuck it was.
I moved to when I moved to when I'm to
snowmass village,
my roommate was from Brown and he had
another brother and that another friend
and they had trained them to this guy
named Ira Wolfe where I grew up.
I went to the Olympics to be a trainer
and these except for one guy to have
these guys are still alive and these
guys did not believe in traditional
lifting.
They believed in slow motion,
heavy lifting,
10 count on the way down and the 10
count on the way up.
A lot of guys still believe in that and
the strength doubles.
Your strength doubles the strength.
It's so slow motion.
It was really into that Einstein,
you know Eddie's a black belt.
Scott Epstein.
Yeah.
He's really into slowmo training.
It was always in motion.
Slow motion lifting.
These guys were really fucking into it
and say,
Hey,
the one guy we were talking a while ago
and he has no injuries.
All that,
all that.
Like they.
They switched me when I was doing behind
the next,
in front of the next.
They're like,
you're wasting your time.
Just do squats.
Cleans a.
what's the other one they do that gets
your fucking traps?
Jaden?
Ginormous.
You just get 1:30
seconds.
Impressed.
It's just first,
just the first clean.
Don't even press it.
Just just to first clean.
Don't even price it.
All that shit out.
Queens are tremendous.
I love all that shit.
In fact,
I went back to a straight bar.
I've been using the straight bargain.
Yeah,
totally.
Yeah.
I like the straight bar.
I've been squatting.
You're doing kettlebell classes for
awhile too,
right?
Weren't you?
Yeah,
but the kettle.
See,
the problem with the Kettlebell is that
if you read that that guy's book or
anything about Pavlov,
he says that the Kettlebells,
I don't even know if that's his name,
was Selena.
It's supposed to be 20 to 18,
15 minute workout.
What they do is they the crow,
the new crossfit community as taken
kettlebells and you're just hurting
people kettlebells or done for you to
feel good and to enhance a different
workout.
Like when I do kettlebells,
thank God for on it.
I combined it with a club well workout.
I berto crane taught me how to do swings
with club batch where you turn your
inside of your wrist.
So everything turned.
So yeah,
I burned a lot of Fascia on my shoulder
because I do it that way.
So when I do a Kettlebell workout,
I incorporated with the batch from on it
and I do it like a circuit training.
I do this a straight one,
all this.
And even with that,
even because I.
before I went to physical therapy,
I want them to try the club bats because
they have all the way down the end of
the.
Helps pull that shoulder all the way the
fuck down.
Like for me to do anything.
I had to stretch my shoulder before and
after really deep I had to go to law
against the wall.
I remember the guy brought on Alberto
Magaziney,
Galena,
glossy.
I do a lot of his little warmer,
great workouts and even,
uh,
right now,
on.
It's got that Kettlebell six Kendall,
six winds of transformation.
They got some great stuff on it.
The guy send it to me,
the beginning,
they call it something else instead of a
warm up,
they call it something else.
[inaudible] name is Josh,
not Josh Wolfe,
John,
John Wolfe,
John.
Both good.
He's fantastic.
Fantastic.
Fantastic clubs is that they're not that
heavy,
but they're odd.
So like you're holding onto the end of
it,
but the way it is isn't the other end
and it's this long thing.
So it's very awkward and you could get a
really good work on with 15 pounds,
you really can't.
That's all I use.
Fifteen and 10.
I got a five on it to break my wrist.
You get a five and you really could
really break the flash on your risks.
With the five,
they have an exercise that you go over
and we had a full set of them out here.
If you don't want to use your men.
Tremendous.
So that's,
that's what I was doing wrong.
The kettlebell class.
Why am I swinging the gorilla?
Why am I swinging the fucking gorilla?
Why are you swinging the grill?
I don't know.
And then you turned me onto Steve
Maxwell steady five pounds.
So now I do 35 and 44 pounds.
I love Stephen Maxwell stuff.
So I keep.
I keep Steve Max and then you will have
one.
I called you with the last dilemma and
you were like,
well,
let's do it.
So now I do three,
three and three,
and I'm out of there.
Oh yeah.
Do three Turkish getups.
Three fucking set to cleans and three
swings out while they believe often with
you.
Just do it a few days a week yet,
listen,
if I'm on the road,
most hotels now have kettlebells.
Really?
Most hotels are starting to come around.
I go to a hotel,
I check in,
I go up,
I rolled a joint,
I go downstairs,
I smoke on the way back.
I checked by the gym.
If I see Kettlebells,
I'm very happy,
but I keep it to that read three and
three because over 50 it should just be
three days a week.
It takes a lot for you to recuperate.
Well,
it's also that you can get in more reps
over the week.
That's really what you want.
If you do a lot of reps in one day,
the problem is you're destroyed
afterwards,
but if you do the same amount of reps
over the course of five days,
just do shorter workouts and do many of
them.
You don't get ever get destroyed.
Your body's fine.
You,
you do all the other things you do too,
and I think you become more consistent
with it.
You don't.
I need to do to kickboxing.
Conditionings to Jujitsu.
You know,
my Jujitsu incorporates my Jujitsu,
incorporates the class during the
technique and three,
five minute roles.
After that I get up and walk away
because then anything after that is
defeating,
defeating the purpose.
I hit the bed twice a week,
especially on Sunday.
What?
The Nova.
So a bed.
What does that.
The a bed is the one I told you about
the last time.
I think they sent you some information
because we were discussing it last time.
It's The red light therapy.
Oh,
okay.
I get the know Victoria bed twice a
week.
Nova?
Yes.
Nova.
Thor bed.
Look at up to Nova.
So a bed twice a week especially on a
Sunday to take all the oxidation.
That thing right there?
Yes.
Thinner,
fitter,
healthier,
happier.
And then I,
I,
I go in the Cryo therapy two or three
times a week.
So what I did was I shortened my workout
and I could do it more often.
Me going to a Jujitsu class and fighting
Eddie because that does nothing for
them.
Yeah.
I'm not going to improve.
Right.
And I'm not going to do that because I'm
not going to be able to row for three or
four more days now.
Yeah,
that's the thing is recovery.
I really went online and right after 50
and I number one,
you gotta go,
you got over 50 strength strength.
Oh Gosh,
that's tough too because that
sarcopenia.
I'll fucking kill you.
And that's when you start getting punchy
and we all become our grandfather.
And when you do stand up,
it's,
it's.
You just got to be stronger.
So I went back,
I meet these guys a week and we pack it
on.
I'll even go on what you put on there
because it gives me anxiety and we open
up with a squat to really get the system
into a fucking frenzy.
You will.
There's no jumping jacks.
There's no bench.
We opened up warm up first.
I will do a little warm up.
And the first two sets I see the fucking
devil.
It's on a stopwatch.
There's no sets.
What do you mean?
So he'll go four hours,
four minutes go.
So four minutes of squatting,
squatting for three minutes,
three minutes or so.
A lot of times squatting,
but it's 10 seconds up,
10 seconds back.
The last two.
I'm fucking.
I'm saying the devil.
I'm thinking about getting a heart
attack,
my whole thing.
And then right from there I go to a pull
down machine.
Right from there I go to a back twister.
It's really weird.
My mother in 22 minutes,
that's a good workout.
I mean two minutes.
Physical strain,
lifting some weights,
getting that a bone density,
tightening up all your.
All the muscle grabs the stick works.
That's the most important thing.
I don't end up on NBC doing commercials
for Ed Commercials.
You don't want any eat.
You got to get the stick.
And that's from lifting weights let bro.
She was day one.
Yeah.
I don't care what anybody tells you.
Give me an old guy that's doing lifting
a little lightweight three days a week
and he's doing it for his Maloof.
Stick all that shit.
They saw a what is the GNC with Frank
Thomas and it's good for your lady to
that Shit.
Don't work those frank.
Thomas,
a bunch of thirsty white people hanging
out.
Oh,
those commercials are the worst.
We played those commercials 30 times.
Shit,
how are you ladies going?
I wish you would do that.
In my meanwhile,
frank's a fat fuck.
You know what?
I'm.
He's overweight and shit.
I'm doing this.
That GNC shit don't work.
You want to keep them a loop.
Stickup oatmeal.
They did a study on this.
I did a study.
I did an independent study to see what
works the most.
OATMEAL,
coconut milk in that motherfucker.
Had some debt.
Listen,
some squats,
you'll be stabbing people to use those
things.
Elevate testosterone.
Increase your hormone levels.
That's for sure.
Dead Lifts and squats are the Kings of
exercise.
Those are so important because they work
your whole chain.
They work everything.
Dolce love is the fuck them.
Deadlift a dolce.
Me and him,
but everybody does some.
I read his book.
That's when I really.
I went to the y one day and I started
like.
I started like,
I got to coach the first time to go over
the basics with me and then like three
weeks later I thought that was my.
I went to the center of five.
That list,
Bro.
I could feel it in my central nervous
system.
It really does hit essentially like you
just feel like this fucking realizes,
oh Jesus,
this crazy fuck is.
It needs us to lift weights.
It needs us to carry heavy things all
the time.
So your body just get stronger and
there's only one way to get stronger.
Your body's got to increase
testosterones to rebuild
all that tissue that you're breaking
down.
You in right now,
brother.
Your first place in this context,
if I wasn't in first place,
I jump off a fucking building.
How's The [inaudible] number two?
I'm disturbed that they thought they
were going to win.
I'm ahead by like 2000 points.
This is what I'll tell you why right
now.
Right?
I mean obviously out of all these guys,
I'm the one who's been working out all
the time.
I'm obviously,
I've been working on my whole life,
so I have a 10,000,
39 res and second place with 8,299.
Yeah,
Tommy Buns in third place.
Tommy has just uh,
recently banged down another hundred.
So he's eight,
two,
five,
nine and Bert is strong in last place.
Strong talking to all kinds of mad shit
and he's more than 2000 points behind me
that slob and I haven't even worked out
today.
And when I'm working out today,
they're all going to quit.
I'm going to,
I'm going today even though I'm 2000
points at hand,
I'm going to go for six hours.
Today is a day of death.
As many as I've gotten as many as a
thousand points in a day.
No one has even gotten close to that.
You just got to fucking keep going.
The thing is,
when you're exhausted,
you can't go,
I can't do this anymore.
Yes,
you can go broke.
What do you do it for 20 minutes?
I do a variety of different things.
Break it down for a,
run the hills with the dog for good.
Our,
you know,
do about two miles in the hills with a
dog.
So he's exhausted.
Otherwise he's a puppy,
you know,
he's,
he's two years old.
He's a pain in the ass if he's not worn
out.
So I wear his little ass out.
So we run for two,
you know,
two miles,
which is in the hills.
These are pretty fucking steep hills.
It turns out to be about 40 minutes ish.
Forty five minutes closer now.
Get back,
stretch out a little.
And then I decided what else I want to
do.
Um,
yesterday it was a kickboxing,
so I hit the bag for another hour and a
half.
I turned on some old fights in the gym
and just fucking went to town,
put on the ringside timer.
So it's given me rounds and uh,
the ringside timer gives me 30 seconds
to.
So I go 30 seconds,
30 seconds,
not so hard.
Thirty seconds on 30 seconds.
And that's a hard one minute break.
She'd gotten water.
No,
no,
no.
Sure.
No Shin Guards.
No.
Really kicked the shit out of that
fucking backyard.
Oh God.
I'm fucking my shins up with the
kickboxing class,
like fucked up.
One of my phone guy toes just blew up.
It just blew up and blood started coming
out of there.
I went home later on and said,
what the fuck?
I did nothing.
My tail,
my toenails cut.
If you slam your Shin into a bag for an
hour and a half of full blast,
some tissues going to break down.
Something's going to like right now
everything's sore.
My ankles are sore,
my knees are sore,
my lower back is sore.
I went,
I went whole ham yesterday,
but you know,
that wasn't a big day for me.
Yesterday was like for 430 something
points.
That's a big day.
For some.
It's the most I've ever worked out is I
did six and a half hours and I got a
thousand points.
I did five and a half hours.
I got 900 points and then I did another
hour just to sort of like at the end of
the day,
just to loosen everything up,
which just hit the bag for an hour.
Just I just.
Because Bert was talking so much shit,
I was like,
where am I going to put the bill?
Who doesn't want to double
like,
okay,
okay.
We'll see.
We'll say he went hiking with Ari and
was quitting while he was hiking.
Hiking is walking.
It's walking.
These guys are walking and they're
getting tired and he's talking about
beating me in a fitness contest.
It's outrageous.
Plus he's enormously overweight.
The one who is the real issue is Ari.
Ari is a sneaky fuck are.
I might try to pull it out.
Even though it's 2000 points behind,
he might try to murder himself over the
next two days,
get to 2000 points and then put another
$1,000
to beat me on the third day.
He.
He literally might try to do that,
but I'm not going to let them know we're
here.
We're queer.
They're there,
so they're fighting for second place.
Good luck boys.
I let them get close up until a while
ago,
up until about a week and a half ago,
and then I just turned it on.
I'm like,
okay,
here we go.
I had a plan.
My plan was to to get,
you know,
first of all,
I was not doing this much cardio before,
so we're at 29 days instead of 30,
what is today?
The 29th,
29,
29 days in.
I've taken four days off.
I took three days off because I went to
Vegas with my family when I went with
the UFC and said,
we're going to go on Thursday,
Wednesday till Sunday.
I'm not going to work out.
Just go have a good time,
relax,
see if these guys catch up.
So they caught up to me and that's
posted opens and last please.
I really hadn't even worked out and so I
said,
okay,
I'm done with that.
Now it's time to kick it into full gear.
And then when I kicked into full gear,
I'm steady every day,
three hours a day,
three and a half hours a day,
four hours a day.
Sometimes,
sometimes two and a half hours in the
morning,
two and a half hours at night.
Just 600 points a day.
700 points a day,
800 points a day.
Whatever I got to do just to stay way
ahead and then my.
My goal was so the last few days to be
so far ahead that they're fucked and
they're all just scratching and clawing
for second place.
What's the,
what's the,
what's the stuff this year with you?
Don't get anything that I wanted to lose
it.
I have to drink a goblet of everybody
else's pissed.
That's what I wanted.
I want it because I wanted to drink
piss.
I felt like bird has to lose this.
I don't see how Tom's getting.
Tom was sick.
He was sick as a dog on antibiotics for
like five days.
Came back in one day and he ran 13
motherfucking miles for 600 points.
Yeah.
Ran around the neighborhood 13 fucking
miles to dude ran for three and a half
hours.
Just ran.
Doesn't want to lose and doesn't want to
lose the bird.
Even if you only comes in third place,
as long as he's not.
As long as he beats Bert.
That's where everybody's at.
Because burt talked so much shit.
Everybody just wants to make sure that
burt loses.
He's got the Dimaggio,
he thinks he can just half ass his way
through something that's an actual
competition because he's just,
look,
he can push himself,
but there's a big difference between
pushing yourself and pushing yourself
for a whole month.
That's where he's falling apart and he's
been talking so much shit that were all
laughing at him.
So yesterday were all,
everybody was going out.
Is it today?
A couple of hours yesterday.
Joe Rogan back and look at his tits.
Bouncing.
What he say?
Sandbags.
That Ren Thomas Sandbag headsets in.
Sorry if I sound super aggressive.
I still love them.
But man sandbaggers Bro.
Sandbaggers.
What's he like held on to this stats for
like a week before he turned him in.
He did Thomas Line about being no
already held onto his stats and he's
allowed to do that.
Look,
we're not supposed to do that.
You're supposed to look.
The manly thing to do is to put it all
on the table and make everybody tried to
fucking keep up.
That's the manly thing to do because it
already is obviously a sneaky fuck.
Right.
And he obviously is also the one who
worked out the least out of all of us,
so he at one point in time stored up a
thousand points and had them on his
device and then released him and Bert
had went fucking crazy.
You Fuck Woo Woo.
Because birth thought he was a head Ra.
Then all of a sudden already shot ahead
of him.
That's how it works.
This is a competition.
It's the fight for last right now,
right between this.
Between them.
It's a fight for less at burt's gonna
get.
He's gonna lose that fight.
He's going to be last.
Tom's going to work out today.
Tom is going to pay Tom.
I told you tom got 600 fucking points
yesterday.
Oh,
they're fighting.
They're fighting in a group text.
Let me see what's going on here.
Oh my God.
It's long.
It's very long.
Oh boy.
There's a lot.
There's a lot of fighting birds.
Very angry.
Very,
very,
very angry.
He's very angry because he's realized
he's going to come in last because he
was saying.
He was saying yesterday.
Here's what's hilarious.
He goes,
he goes in,
you're barely winning.
I go,
Bert,
I'm ahead of you.
Yesterday it was 2,300
points.
I go,
do you have any idea what the fuck you
would be saying if you were ahead by
2000,
300 points?
And he was hard to be respectful and
it'd be.
It'd be like,
you fucking liar.
You fucking liar.
Look this,
you know,
this is a.
it's a game.
It's.
If I don't get hurt,
it's a rigged game.
That's just what it is.
It'd be drink.
I believe snuggling really got caught
drinking the snack and nothing.
Didn't you think that?
Don't you think that birth dranken
didn't you say you looked at you funny.
Alright,
I'm talk the story.
You telling me what you think.
Okay.
Because this was the fucked up thing.
My feeling is raven hurt.
Every Wednesday I go to pizza after
karate with mercy.
We go eat pizza and we're sitting at the
neighborhood pizza drag.
We're sitting there and I look at my
wife like,
oh,
isn't that bird?
It's a dude walking through nature,
but look just like burt with a hat on.
I put my pizza down and go,
I go a cock sucker.
I see you're drinking because it looked
like he got a six pack or whatever
holding it.
He turned around and waved at me and
kept walking.
This is Bert Kreischer,
right Christ.
This is a guy who,
you know,
I figured he'd come back and talk to me.
So the next day Lee tells me,
I tell Lee that like,
well,
yeah,
I swapped birthday,
yelled at,
but he didn't come and talk to me.
Lee puts down.
Leads sells me that burt put down a
tweet that one of his fans yelled at
them.
They saw someone he didn't know who it
was and he didn't know who it was.
And he kept walking.
He knew who the fuck it dog.
If I yell at you,
you'll know it's fucking me.
If I say cock suck at the end of the
speech,
you know,
let me look what else burt does.
First of all,
Burton knows he's behind.
It's staggering amount.
He put in the most bitch ass workout
today.
He got,
what is this?
A 149 points that is.
That is not enough.
He worked out for an hour and 50
minutes.
You've got 149 points because look at
the end,
see the end.
All those grades,
maybe it stayed on or something.
He kept his.
He kept a strap on.
He worked out.
It says an hour for.
He worked there for 40 minutes and he
kept a strap on for an hour.
Trying to get some extra.
Yeah,
because he's dying so it was hard to
elevated.
So you get some points for having an
elevated heart.
But look at this.
All this gray shit at the end.
See folks,
see all of this?
I can barely see it.
You can't sit here.
Let me do something here.
I'll show people here all this nonsense.
Wow.
To work
you get for 80 percent of your heart
rate.
You get yellow for 90 percent of your
Max heart rate.
You get read.
I tried to go all read the first day.
I'm like,
I'm just going to kill them.
I'm just going to sprint for half an
hour and just make these guys catch up.
There's no way to catch up.
Then Ari and his fucking ingenious and
devious ways found out that you get just
as many points for 80 percent is good
for 90 percent.
We figured so that they avoid lawsuits.
So he said,
okay,
so it seems like the sweet spot is an 80
percent,
so just stick to 80 percent so you can
do that.
Or You could be like Bert and burt
barely gets to 70 percent,
mostly stays in the 60 percent range,
which is gray.
And then 80 percent,
which is.
Well,
60 percent is like there's 50,
60 and 70 and seventies green.
No,
yeah,
seventies,
green.
And then blue is 60.
So He's mostly blue.
Sixty percent of his mass heart rate,
which by the way I might be at right now
because I'm getting angry.
So if you've got mad,
you'd be in the blue and you get two
points in a minute for the blue,
you get four points a minute for the
yellow,
what do you see?
Sixty percent to 70 percent you get?
Blue Bird is almost all gray and blue.
And if you look at this fucking slobbery
workout,
he's got,
look at all that shit.
It's 60 percent and lower most of his
workout.
So that means most of the workout that
he did for an hour and 49 minutes,
it's him with a fucking thing on just
sitting around.
It's an hour and 30 minutes.
So it's.
Most of it is him with the thing on just
sitting there being fat.
It's all it is.
So let me ask you this.
What is this?
What is this called?
[inaudible].
I like to go on.
It's called.
This is my zone fitness tracker.
This is the thing.
You put it on your chest,
you.
It's a.
Once I snap this in,
it'll start measuring my heart rate and
I'm going to put it on when I get out of
here.
I'm going to start working out and today
these are the three days of death.
Today's Monday,
Tuesday and Wednesday we'd go crazy.
Joe.
He was Wednesday.
I work out to 1159 and then at 1159 I
pop that off and walk away at 1159 and
then I go have a glass of wine because
it hits midnight.
No wait.
Qualifications on this?
Nothing.
Nobody?
No,
no.
There's no losing weight.
I probably fucking gained weight.
I haven't lost any weight.
I've eaten everything that moves.
I've put in zero dietary restrictions.
I ate a whole carrot cake the other day
because the amount of calories that I'm
burning is fucking insane.
Like,
I mean,
I'll give you a,
for instance,
on a day,
like a good calorie day in terms of like
how much like yesterday,
one workout,
2000,
200,
14 calories,
one workout,
three hours,
25 minutes.
And then the day before that 1,930
calories.
The day before that there was two
workouts.
One was 1,876
calories,
one was 2000,
210 calories.
These are,
I mean this insane amount of calories.
One workout I had was 4,900.
What's that entail when you get your
heart up to add is at the running?
Yeah.
Well,
the lifting.
I can't.
I can't just do one thing.
I go crazy.
I'll get bored so I lift,
but the lift doesn't give me much lift
is like blue and green.
That's all you ever get from lifting his
wings or chin ups.
Presses,
cleans and presses windmills.
A clean press squats,
a renegade rows or Kettle Bell Hell
kettlebells and obviously doesn't give
you much.
It doesn't give me my Jujitsu.
Jujitsu would probably be pretty good,
but this thing we get in the way.
If anybody mounted you at crack,
this thing would crack.
You don't.
If you lost this.
Oh my God,
it'd be death.
Like I could break this with my finger.
I'm pretty sure I could break this.
It feels like time a lot.
Yes.
That's the number one.
Did an hour and a half bag yesterday.
You know,
because I have the gym at home so I went
fucking hog on the.
On the pitch.
I put fights on once I put fights on and
get fired up,
man,
just start fucking wailing on that bag
and keeping the party going.
Um,
but see if I,
if I got cocky right now,
these fucks could catch me,
especially Ari because he's probably
gonna sand back some more and,
and hide his numbers because he just
wants to beat Bert because he got super
pissed at Tom.
Like the fuck Tom,
because tom put up all those points
yesterday.
Six hundred points in a day is a lot of
points.
But like I said,
dude ran,
like,
I'll tell you what he did.
He ran 13 fucking miles in his
neighborhood and this is after being
sick.
But he's feeling it today.
Yeah.
Today it gets 145 points.
That's not good.
You're not going to win with that.
See,
they're not trying to win.
They're trying to beat people.
I know that one day he was a US crowd
therapy because I want to purchase left
ticket.
So I knew he was doing something,
but I know he hasn't been going
consistently.
He,
it doesn't do anything consistently,
but he doesn't watch his diet either.
That's the problem with burke.
He's not watching his diet.
He's not eating,
not an eater.
It's the boos.
That is a motherfucker.
It is.
That shit turns into sugar at night
because I'll kill you.
You know what else kills you?
I said,
how you both people think that that
fucking hell.
There's a ton of shit that fucking kills
you.
Just stick to what happened on a banana.
I try,
you know,
I love us.
I eat bowls,
dog.
They make them my,
my house or Chia seeds and Juju.
But I'll tell you what I read when I'm
in the middle of these brutal workouts.
I'll drink the whole soda and the work.
I drank a cream soda yesterday in the
middle of a workout.
I needed sugar.
I needed it.
I didn't know you need it because I felt
like I needed it.
I was fucking.
I'm burning so many calories and um,
um,
my,
my blood sugar is crashing so hard.
I mean fruit.
I mean,
when I,
the one day that I worked out where I
did five and a half hours,
I was eating boxes,
animal crackers.
I was eating everything I could.
What I do is what you told me to do when
I get home from Thai or lifting and I
make a protein shake,
I put,
I swear to God,
I take a Hershey's syrup.
He told me just a little bit and I just
go tick,
not even a second of it.
And with the Mexican chocolate works
perfect.
That tastes like fucking,
you know.
So I do that with the protein drinks,
but I try to avoid sugar.
Nothing,
no more sugar,
but see what's happening with these
workouts.
You're dealing with an extreme loss of
electrolytes and extreme loss of
glucose.
I mean,
I'm putting salt in all my water.
I'm drinking.
Bought a bunch of these nalgene.
You know what a nalgene bottle is like
with a twist top.
It's a thick,
heavy,
plastic,
32 ounce bottle of water.
I'm drinking three and four of those in
a workout in those I'm putting the
electrolytes and then I'm putting
sprinkles of Himalayan salt.
So I'm putting like a little,
like a half a teaspoon of Himalayan salt
in each one of them shaking it up
because I'm,
I am losing insane amounts of water.
I sweat so hard.
I set off the fucking alarm.
I set off my fire alarm in my gym from
sweat,
from my steam room.
The whole room was like a shower for me.
Steven and I put it up on instagram.
This is the kind of workout I'm doing.
I mean I'm pushing hard because they're
not making it easy.
These guys are actually doing it.
Fire alarm,
that's legit.
Those puddles on the ground.
That's not for me pissing my pants.
That's all sweat.
So I'm,
I'm,
I'm sweating so much because I'm staying
in the 80,
80 percent of your Max heart rate range
for hours.
I'm staying there for hours.
So my thought was there's no way they
can do that.
They're not going to do that.
There's no way they're not going to do
that for five hours.
That's just not.
So like if I did one day like that,
I felt like one day where I did,
I got 935 points in one workout and then
another 100 points afterwards.
I'm like,
one day like that will separate me from
the pack.
Just one day.
Just put feed fear in there.
Let me just ask you something,
just to be fair with everybody here.
What about stuff with some of the stuff?
Doesn't that kind of,
you mean like testosterone?
One hundred percent helps.
I told them,
uh,
I told them this is a fucking shit.
All those.
I gave them my doctor's information.
I told them what they should do,
but I'm also at least eight years older
than all of them.
Right.
How old are you?
Forty one.
I'm 51 now.
I'm older than all the testosterone.
Yeah.
You should.
I'm failing all those tests.
Yeah.
Testosterone replacement therapy,
hormone replacement therapy.
I started doing all that when I was 40.
So that's their age.
Yeah,
it makes a big difference.
Makes a big difference.
Fuck yeah.
Is,
look,
listen,
everybody,
everybody listen to this.
There's a stigma attached to that in a
lot of people like you know,
where do you your testosterone from or
get it from my balls.
All that matters is that you have in
your system.
If you don't have it in your system,
you're not going to feel as good.
It's real simple.
If you're fine with not feeling as good,
good,
go ahead,
stick with that,
but if you're not fine with it.
This is 2018.
Hormone replacement therapy exists for a
reason,
and that reason is it makes you feel way
better and makes your body work way
better.
You can avoid a host of ailments and
conditions that are related to your body
breaking down due to age with hormone
replacement therapy.
The key to doing it,
those that do it correctly,
he's supposed to go to a doctor that's
going to test your blood levels,
test your nutrient levels,
and adjust your diet first.
The first thing that happens is they
want to find out how much you're
sleeping,
house to house,
how stressed out you are,
what are you eating,
how much water you're drinking?
Are you getting the proper amount of
protein and vegetables you eating
correctly?
Let's get you off of the sugar.
Let's get you off the booze.
Let's get you off cigarettes or whatever
the else is before they do anything,
so they put you that this is a many,
many months process that I went through
with a.
They get you off all these different
things and you make these adjustments
and then they start adding a little
stuff,
add a little bit of growth hormone at a
little bit of testosterone.
First it was cream and then it became
injections.
Takes a little bit of time to figure out
what works best and then you get to a
point where you're.
You have the hormone levels of a healthy
young man.
He don't want to elevate.
You don't want to be higher than that.
That's when you run into problems.
You don't want to be in like some crazy.
Vito Belfort,
when he got popped from Nevada and he
was like super human levels.
That was 80 percent over my mother
Sunday night against.
He was supposed to fight rumble Johnson.
What's the guy from Doug with the
Christian?
Nice guy.
Nate Marquardt.
Nate Marquardt levels are really high in
Pittsburgh that night.
That's right.
Yeah.
He was in danger.
He was.
It was.
There is dangerous to his health,
the levels,
but he says that was his doctor.
Is Dr.
Fuck them.
The.
The,
the whole idea.
Well,
there's a difference between.
First of all,
there's a big difference in someone
who's competing in mixed martial arts.
Obviously you have to worry about your
opponent getting hurt because of the
fact that your enhanced,
and these are young guys that are doing
this.
When nate was doing this,
he was like 30 years old,
right?
When you are talking about just general
health and wellness,
testosterone replacement therapy,
hormone replacement therapy,
there's a reason why a lot of older
guys,
especially guys who can afford it,
they have money.
They're doing it.
It makes you feel better.
It just does,
and if you don't want to do it,
that's fine.
There's ways of elevating your
testosterone natural.
They just don't work as well with
whether it's dead lifts are running
hills,
doing sprints.
They work a little bit better.
It works a little bit better than
nothing,
but if there's lots of very good.
Yeah,
they released it but not enough for what
you're saying.
No,
there's gonna be a difference as they
could raise them through acupuncture.
I know that she's discussed raising
Melissa Testosterone.
Acupuncture.
I would like to see studies on that.
The problem is it's really painful.
Axondria,
same phone for that real.
That sits in your feet.
Yeah,
I like to see studies on that.
I don't know if that's really been
proven.
If that was really proven.
Look,
there's.
There's ways to raise it.
You know.
The chick I was with for years told me
different case studies that she had been
involved in.
Yeah.
She called me.
A guy came in once that found the
younger girlfriend.
His wife passed and they found the
younger girlfriend and he couldn't keep
up and he couldn't keep up,
so he came into the car and she did a
bunch of stuff and put them on a t.
He came back a week later and said,
turn that shit off.
Dick will not shut down like.
But she told me,
she goes,
I could raise your testosterone levels,
but it has to be needling for your feet.
Yeah,
you're going to find that a little bit
uncomfortable.
And I was like leaving.
I don't want to fucking walk around all
this stuff that we're talking about,
whether it's hormone replacement therapy
or squats or deadlifts,
are all these.
All these things will help hormone
replacement therapy helps them.
The thing about this kind of a
competition that we're doing now,
we're not doing anything that you need
massive amounts of testosterone.
What this is about is willpower
willpower for a month,
30 days.
So totally.
But a lot of it is discipline and
willpower and if that has any advantage,
it's that I have a gym in my house and I
have a gym in my studio and I run with
my dog almost everyday in the hills and
I've been doing that for years.
I've been taking that dog running since
he was six months old.
He runs in the hills with me all the
time.
You Fall in love with running.
I love it.
You know why I love it,
Joey,
here's a big thing because it makes me
feel better in terms of my mental state.
Like I'm happier when I run all the time
this whole month.
I'm fucking,
I feel great and I don't just feel great
because I'm not smoking pot like I made.
Maybe that's helped.
Maybe that's good in some way.
Maybe it's good to not smoke pot even
though I enjoy it.
Maybe it's not good to smoke as much as
I do.
You're going to smoke now?
Thursday morning?
Uh,
I don't know.
No.
Thursday I'm flying to New York.
I probably won't smoke.
I mean I might smoke a little over the
weekend.
I'm going to play some pool.
My boy Tommy junior down in New York.
Um,
but the,
um,
what the thing that really helps because
I'm,
I'm doing insane amounts of exercise
hours and hours of exercise a day.
You don't give a fuck about normal
bullshit.
Like all the chatter,
all the negative chatter in your head.
That shit goes away.
It doesn't exist.
I don't care.
I'm super calm.
No anxiety.
Anxiety goes away.
I think I'm not a depressed person.
I don't suffer from depression,
but we had Tyson fury on the podcast
listening.
Yeah.
Amazing.
He's a fucking.
He's a brave man.
The way he opened up about her,
I read the comments and what not held up
about his suicidal thoughts and
depression.
That goal,
that helps.
It doesn't just help.
It helps fucking tremendous.
If I.
If I found a drug,
if a doctor put me on medication,
I was like,
doc,
I'm fine.
I'm happy.
Everything's good.
The doctors like,
I would just like you to just try this
for a while and tell me,
tell me how it makes you feel.
Just put me on something and I had to
take a pill a day and I felt as good as
I feel right now,
sitting in front of you.
I would be like,
wow,
you were right.
I feel better with this exists,
but it only gets you through discipline
and nobody.
You can't give someone something that
forces them to work out almost every
fucking day.
I worked out this month.
I didn't want to do it almost every day.
The only thing that kept me doing it is
going a double with Joel does
all that.
That got me angry,
that got my competitive juices stirred
and just the.
The idea that these guys I've been
working out my whole life,
these guys barely work out like they're
going to beat me in some sort of a
fitness competition that involves
willpower.
I'm like,
that's not going to happen.
I'm going to put in more time than you.
I'm just going to.
But all that aside,
when I did do it,
just doing it,
I feel fucking fantastic.
Well,
member of the tapes,
you made a man in the house of Blues.
You were concerned.
I was like,
I don't want to live no more.
I wasn't working out.
Yeah,
no.
I do something four days a week minimum
since I've been on weight watchers.
I didn't hit the plateau one week
because I was on antibiotics.
I got a rash on my leg and so when I
left there I felt a little weird,
but I still did everything else.
It's hard to exercise on antibiotics.
I felt that lifting squats,
I had to stop.
We stopped,
so I,
I in fact,
that went off the air.
I was like,
I can't live this.
Very few things that will kill your
system.
I can't.
I couldn't do it,
and that that's a real wake up call for
people that don't understand the
benefits of probiotics
was probiotics,
like taking acidophilus or eating Kimchi
or in eating,
anything that's going to help your,
your microbiome.
It's so beneficial to your,
your wellbeing,
to the way you feel,
the way your health is,
your vitality and all that stuff is
connected.
I like yogurt.
Yogurt's fucking grateful.
I Love Yogurt.
Yogurt a lot.
I don't like the Greek as much as the
other one.
I get the low point one.
I'm a cheap guy.
I eat that shit every day.
I love that shit juice,
but you got to watch the sugar in that
one.
Oh,
Kombucha.
You got to watch the sugar in that.
I guess I got a two point can put you
for eight ounces.
That's not bad.
It's not bad.
It's not bad at all.
Beneficial though.
Very beneficial.
Can Be [inaudible] fucking amazing.
It's really good at avoiding sicknesses,
but with this exercise,
the amount of exercise that I'm doing,
I'll drink bottles of that shit.
I don't worry about nothing that there's
a lot of benefit in that to me just to
be able to eat whatever the fuck I want.
I mean,
I had been eating everything in front of
me,
man this whole month.
I mean I've doubled how much food I eat
because eating fucking.
It's crazy.
How much longer you got to watch
everything.
I get it.
I get,
I don't touch me.
What I'm doing is not sustainable that
night.
Salmon's good.
I do a lot of chicken breast and my meat
intake is cut just to a third.
I don't agree with you.
I didn't take any more,
especially at night.
I don't fuck with that shit at night no
more.
If I eat meat,
it's maybe three times a week.
Don't get me wrong.
I still crave a fucking stake,
but if I take my wife out on the day
through the state,
the first thing I'd do with color and I
save it for the next day for breakfast
or some.
Nothing wrong with that kid.
Meet early in my day,
let it digest by the time the end of the
night,
no more,
no mas,
no money funded.
They will talk.
When your mother was visiting,
you and I were talking about the talents
that they can be passed after that they
lose their mind.
You know,
as you get older you lose things,
you just can't eat them.
And I've had,
I think Sebastian told me the gravy
bothersome and my Buddy Jersey was
hysterical.
He's like,
I can't even walk past a pizza place
Domo.
Well,
it's don't lap the feet.
Gout,
gout,
gout from sauce,
from the acidity and the source.
People get it from wine.
You know?
It used to be called like emperors
disease because people would just sit
around and drink wine when they were
rich was a rich person's disease.
Way Back in the day is one bad.
No one's good for you.
Why is that balance good for you?
Everything's bad and access.
Access,
you know what I mean?
Sugar is terrible and access you have,
you know,
like the rock eats like a fucking plate
of cookies one day a week.
Nothing wrong with that.
Nothing wrong with a day where you fuck
off.
Have a cheat meal.
Something wrong with that.
As long as the majority of your diet is
healthy,
the majority of your diet should consist
of leafy green vegetables,
healthy fats,
healthy meat,
you know,
grass fed,
white fuck you pussies egg whites.
I Yo,
motherfucker.
One of our sponsors.
What was it?
The egg sponsor?
They,
uh,
forget the sponsor,
but they,
they,
they give you,
they sell actual cage free eggs.
People say cage free,
but they're all fucking jammed in
together.
They might as well be in a cage.
What is it?
Farms.
Spell it.
Vital farms bit.
All right.
Vital farms and they'll the eggs,
they have our fucking dark orange yolk.
That robust yoke,
they taste better than tastes better.
That's because those chickens see that
shit.
That's what a fucking eggs that the
chickens are.
They still giving you great eggs also
and they haven't been given me
excellently.
I began like a couple of eggs a day.
At the moment.
This is a company that sponsors you?
Yeah,
my chickens.
Again,
the old man just no send jc house.
Well,
I don't know the store.
I recognize that.
I think they're just selling a store,
but you know they have services that
will deliver stuff from stores to your
house.
Now,
how crazy is that?
Cubans eat eggs.
Fried eggs.
I'm white rice.
That's good.
She's Christ.
Eggs are fantastic.
They break the Yolk on the fried rice,
white rice,
white rice.
I love it.
And then the other Cuban thing is white
rice with a steak on top.
I love it.
With two eggs on top of that.
And you're supposed to bring what they
call it.
Whole eggs on horseback.
We're welcome.
How are you?
Oh,
where are your eggs on horseback.
That's gusting.
You're talking about.
Sounds amazing.
Oh my God.
When that yolk breaks over the stakes,
what are you saying that especially over
white rice?
Christ.
I eat steak and eggs all the time.
I love staking legs,
but I got.
I got to watch the fuck did a once a
week.
Once every 10 days I can't eat,
I can't eat fucking pancakes,
pancakes.
I can have one from cases and just a
bunch of bread.
It's just bread,
but they had the heart hardy oats ones
with a little bit of a one,
two zero calorie maple syrup.
Well,
you know when you can get.
There's a company called no foods,
k n o w foods,
and they make a fucking.
They make waffles that are like,
I don't know what they use.
Almond flour or something like that.
They taste good.
Low carb,
very low sugar.
They fucking tastes fantastic and they
have a zero sugar syrup that tastes
great.
I'll put melted butter on those
motherfuckers in that zero sugar syrup
and eat that shit.
Fucking shake tastes good.
Zero Sugar Syrup from match and you eat
it.
You don't feel bad.
It tastes good.
It tastes really fucking and when it's
over,
you don't feel like a fucking like you
got hit with an insulin dark.
You don't feel like that feeling that
you get when you eat.
Like real waffles with real sugar.
I never got never got shit as a kid.
An hour later you barely can walk.
Not with these,
these,
these fucking things.
You feel fantastic.
Joey Diaz,
your Netflix special.
It's out tomorrow.
Right tomorrow.
Jesus Christ.
I put up a thing that,
uh,
our boy Michael Klein,
made from one by one podcast.
Can't play a man's standing in front of
him.
Traveling medical problems looking at
myself.
But I like the clip.
The clip looks good.
Yeah,
it's funny.
It's funny.
I'm very thankful
of Netflix or given me the half hour,
you know,
I just feel at times like I didn't do
really well on the show.
Like I felt like I found it hard on
yourself.
You're an artist.
No,
but you know,
I felt like and not to be,
try to be cute.
It's funny,
like when you see Ron,
they get kicked and she was sitting
there for the first three minutes.
She was upset about the cake.
But you also said about the training.
You see all the holes in your training
where you made mistakes,
little mistakes you made even two weeks
ago in Canada went down for a couple
minutes.
He was just sitting there.
He's not thinking about the $30 million
he made.
There's nobody.
You're telling them about the mistakes
that got you there,
you know,
and it was weird that I didn't think I
did that well.
And then Netflix special,
I guess personally I want to do better,
you know,
but it.
But ever since that you can't ever.
Since you're a July to June 30th,
I have been a different level.
Was a standup comic.
I went back to the Mitzi shore
technique.
I don't give a fuck and 55,
we don't like me.
I don't give a fuck if I offend you.
I really don't give a fuck.
This is who I am and that's it.
I've been having some tremendous sets in
the original benefit of doing these
things.
I don't give a fuck the benefit of doing
these specials.
As you grow it,
abandoned all the material and then you
forced to regroup and you forced to look
at the material and look at your set,
see what you don't like.
Some people never do that,
Joe,
and they never grow because of that.
It's just.
But the growth I've had since June four,
I feel like Dustin Puri and Max Holloway
together,
like I see it like in the original room.
Now I'm back to rear for him.
Like I finally,
I had a watch.
I just just got in my head.
I had a watch couple,
I had some Red Fox specials.
I cop a couple of they bruce bachelor's.
I went back to my favorite.
I got all the vinyl from Richard Pryor
and I went back and listened to what I
came to the conclusion that what was I
giving a fuck about?
I can't give a fuck about audiences.
This is who the fuck I am.
I'm going to unleash the wrath of
fucking God on you and we come out of
here.
We'll see what the fuck it is.
You know,
the worst thing I did was a week before
Jim Norton says something that kind of
bothered me.
Once I understood after he said it,
he said he didn't watch people specials
me.
I like watching comedy specials.
I love watching it.
But the week before my special that the
worst thing in the world.
I watched John Malaney special,
who's a great writer,
who's a great writer.
I'm not a great ride.
Everything was me and my energy,
so I wanted to be John Malaney and
that's what I felt.
Looking back now,
now I got it all out of a way.
I know exactly what the fuck I am and
you're in trouble.
I'm taking into murky waters now.
Every show,
and I'm going to say something to offend
because that's
who I am.
I got to talk this dirty shit.
You know,
I don't give a fuck what anybody thinks
anymore,
but every once in a while my wife calls
it joey.
You having a white moment?
You're not white.
You're Cuban.
Knock the fuck off.
Like I get headshots.
My wife's like,
here he goes again.
Get Snow White moment.
I don't even know.
No,
I don't have a headshot headshots in
decades.
No,
you don't need them no more.
What do we give a fuck about a headshot.
She knows.
Will you just share with me offline?
I don't give a fuck.
Boy,
you look so you're older now.
I don't give a fuck.
She use it.
Thank you very much for having me break
and it's always a pleasure.
Will I see you this week?
I'll be around this week because I'm.
I'm,
I've got shit to do before I leave for
New York.
I'm not going to be around,
but I'll be around after that.
Okay.
November first to Tara.
I love you too,
man.
Thank you very much.
Pleasure,
brother.
Always great to see you.
Always.
So tonight it airs at midnight.
30 la time.
Yours is the 30th,
right?
So tonight you can check it out.
I'm live on Netflix.
Shout out to Netflix.
Thanks for.
Thank you very much.