Yeah,
what's up man?
How you didn't see it?
Like why?
I have never seen a single,
a silly statement like I could kill a
wolf
so much fucking night.
The people are so excited about this.
It's the weirdest thing I've ever seen,
man.
I can't,
I can't call it.
It was just tweet random shit all the
time and that just for some reason that
uh,
everybody had an opinion on it.
That's a weird one,
man.
It's funny though.
I've seen a lot of people tweet really
ridiculous shit,
but I don't think I've ever seen
anything get this much speculation,
discussion,
debate.
People are mad at you if have pissed
off.
Like,
fuck you.
You can't,
can't be wolf.
Jesus Christ,
Bro.
Yeah,
it is a weird thing,
man.
It's a weird thing.
The social media today.
It must,
you know what it's.
I think it is.
I think you said it at a time where
people were looking for some shit to
argue that has nothing to do with trump.
Nothing to do with climate change.
It's like,
oh,
we got something here.
I'm glad I can be that source of a
distressed containment.
Yeah,
it does seem like that though,
doesn't it?
It's like you caught like,
I think it's like peaks and waves
because if you did this the day nine
slash 11 happened,
nobody,
nobody would give a shit.
They probably don't.
Uh,
you don't respect it.
Probably be like,
yeah,
exactly,
but can't believe you're doing this on
that day.
Some people would probably,
if you did it today,
they'd be like,
I can't believe you said that on
national woman's day,
Bro.
National Woman's Day.
You to talk about fighting wolf.
What's wrong with men?
He says,
what's wrong with patriarchy?
I can't call it man.
That's it.
It was interesting though.
My mom called him his sylaria man.
People ain't talking to for years.
I can't be the wolf.
I don't know man.
I don't know.
So do you always just tweet random shit
man?
Just randomly,
just whatever's on my mind.
I'm pretty active on there.
Was that.
So twitter is supposed to be.
It's a great platform,
man.
It's better.
It's one of the,
I think is the best social media
platform.
Yeah.
Well it keeps people from Ramblin.
Well it is.
So it's a,
it's a,
an extended ramble.
Yeah.
Well you can,
you know,
you can go on those little one,
two,
three,
fours where people like to.
Okay.
But what I'm saying is like if you read
people's facebooks,
people get so verbose on facebook.
I can't do it.
I haven't been on facebook for awhile
and the reason why I decided to get off
with my grandma requested me so lucy
maze.
Shout out to Lucy.
She's like,
Lucy,
major question your friend.
I was like,
I can't,
I can't be on facebook.
Right?
Facebook.
Grandma's not on twitter too.
Not on twitter.
Know some people that did not in the
public guy.
They don't know what to do with twitter.
Like,
what do I do with this?
Exactly.
One of my boys just got on.
Matter of fact,
he just got a smartphone actually and he
just got
a smartphone.
Don't have to loop man.
And so he.
So he gets on twitter and he's like,
so what do I,
what do I do?
Tweet man said,
well what do I say?
Whatever you want to say,
man.
It's like,
it's hard to.
I guess it'd be hard to gain a following
from scratch,
like let's,
you know,
a lot of people or you have a platform,
so you gotta say something fucked up and
then someone's gonna retweet that and
then people start following you.
I've seen people do that.
I think that's where,
that's where trolling started.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
Being in an audience and just trying to
Piss people off.
So trolling this word weird.
It's like I wonder how many.
I wonder who has the most fake accounts.
Like there's gotta be some dude out
there that has like a record number,
like 150 fake accounts.
Just trolls.
People I don't understand.
Like,
well that's because you're a successful
man with an actual life.
It's,
I mean,
that's true.
I appreciate that man.
Says a lot coming from you.
But uh,
I don't know man.
It's just weird,
like your whole,
like a Internet existence is just to
piss people off.
I guess it was humans like that in real
life anyway.
So.
Oh the definitely is.
It makes sense.
Yeah,
that definitely is.
But it's a new thing,
you know,
the ability to do it without seeing the
person and being in contact with them
physically to be on the other side of
the planet.
Yeah.
Matter of fact,
I saw a documentary you were on that
you,
you described it beautifully about how
when we first got on the Internet and it
was that aol dial up and everybody just
kind of mumbling around.
Everybody's just kind of bumping into
each other and then slowly finding a way
to interweave it into our existence.
It was a Dopa analogy that you put up.
Well,
we're in a weird stage right now,
or it's gonna suck.
I don't know what it is,
what's coming next.
But whatever's coming next is going to
be way more invasive than this.
It's got to be an man probably.
Jamie's got some goofy glasses.
He's got on check these bitches up.
He's got these snapchat glasses,
map check.
They have light bulbs in the eye,
like,
look when you're filming as cold,
look at that so you can actually can
actually snapchat from them.
Go to my phone and then I put it up like
I don't have to put all of them up and
it's not going on.
Wow.
This,
see,
this is just stage one.
Eventually it's going to be live all the
time.
Contacts.
Right.
Put it in context.
That'd be cold.
That's definitely gonna happen.
It's definitely gonna happen now.
When you,
when you said that shit about wolves,
how serious were you?
We have serious fucking around.
Well it's had fucking around,
but it's like when you started thinking
about it and breaking it down,
I really,
I felt like I can't,
but everybody thinks I'm talking about
lay everybody,
especially on twitter,
like they're posting these big ass
wolves with 200 pound plus wolves.
I'm like,
all right,
listen.
Like those are rare.
Right?
Right.
I'm not the biggest human on earth.
And you go get me a picture of the
biggest wolf.
You can find some fair.
It's not fair.
Right?
So Google average wolf size and I feel
like if it was,
you know,
my life was dependent on it.
Like you have to think like that.
Right?
If you want it to a wolf
and he's threatening you and you'd like,
I can't get him,
but you did so well.
I feel like if you had something on you,
you'd have more of a chance.
I would have sort a knife or something.
I feel like I wouldn't be in the woods
without something.
But wolves.
Van,
do you know how hard they bite?
Yeah,
no,
I've done research.
I've done a little research.
Um,
I think it's like 1200,
five times stronger than a pit bull.
Right?
I think it's 2,500.
I think it's 2,500 pounds per square
inch.
See if he could find.
I was looking yesterday.
Yeah,
I think it up a mastiff was stronger
than a wolf,
which is weird.
It wasn't,
it wasn't even top five.
Fucking dog alligators and crocodiles
were stronger than that.
A gorilla was stronger.
The grills bites from you.
Wow.
I would've never imagined herbalism.
Yeah.
They're eating Broccoli and shit.
Strong branches.
Well,
they just have to fight other gorillas
for pussy because they have a one inch
Dick and they control a bunch of chicks.
I have to have a good bite.
How do you know that they have it?
Is that I know a lot of shit about girls
was a little tiny segment.
Well,
it's about uh,
whether or not the females are
promiscuous.
See when,
uh,
when you look at like it's,
it's,
it's actually a truth with humans too.
But testicular size and Dick size is
directly correlated to the amount of
promiscuous females around.
Really?
Yeah.
So if you're around a bunch of hoes,
your balls get bigger.
That's interesting.
What is the evolutionary advantage?
Like?
Well,
you got to,
you got a sling as much dick as you can
because these bitches are just running
around with every button.
I don't.
National Women's Day,
Bro.
No,
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
So sorry.
You're right.
I apologize.
So thoughtless of me.
But that's,
that's why chimps have big dicks and
chimps have giant balls.
Ever.
See Chimp balls?
Never seen a chimp chipboard.
Pull up some chip balls.
There's a
picture of this hairless chip who sit in
there and he has balls to just kick it
back to juicy,
right?
Payers like to Georgia peaches.
So he goes balls.
Wow.
Good.
Assize is fucking balls.
So like he's so big.
He's so jacked.
That's what chimps look like when you
take the hair off of them as crazy.
And that's the only 150 pounds.
So they have a shave.
This chimp?
No,
he has mange.
Okay.
See all his hands.
Like he's got the skin condition over
his hands and shit.
The animals a lot about.
Well here's what need even crazier one.
Pull up this picture.
Jamie.
Direct correlation between testicle size
and brain size and chimps versus humans.
Yeah.
See that's a human.
That's a chimp brain on the,
on the top and a chimp ball on the
bottom.
And what's the correlation?
Well,
they have giant balls and little brains.
If our balls were as big as our brains,
we would have a fucking serious problem.
First of all,
we wouldn't be able to walk that.
We would have to figure out some sort of
a harness.
I feel like my boss will be bigger
though
balls would be really in chimps than not
know that'd be a bigger than they are
now.
If what if we had smaller brains?
Yeah,
probably.
I guess.
Yeah.
What they think is that went with
chimps,
especially because chimps are seriously
promiscuous,
like there's no monogamy and the chimp
world.
Good for challenges.
Fuck everybody.
Good for getting it everywhere.
We still holding on barely.
We say,
well hold it on,
but it's like 50 percent divorce rate is
high man.
Yeah.
Which means 50 percent divorce rate and
out of the people that are not divorced,
how many of those people are living in
fucking abject misery?
Just constantly being beaten down by
life and not,
not being happy.
I sent old.
Uh,
it's an old customer for sure.
It's definitely an old customer.
There's an old quote from thoreau that
most men live lives of quiet
desperation.
That's really my favorite is a Chris
Rock.
He said,
uh,
he said a man is only as faithful as his
options.
Yeah,
that's a good quote to the,
uh,
the chimp thing though.
What's interesting about it is that
gorillas have figured out a way to hold
it down.
Like gorillas keep all those women like
faithful,
all female.
So he's a polygamous gorillas.
Okay,
well he has a bunch of women.
He has a Harem,
but the women don't fuck around with any
other males other than him.
So He's got this little dick ass and not
big balls either.
Gorillas are Mormons.
I didn't know.
Just giant,
you know.
So they're giant and they have giant
muscles,
giant faces,
giant jaws.
And they could kill other gorillas,
you know,
by biting them and tearing them apart
and shit.
But that's the only thing they use their
mouse for interested in branches and
Shit and leaves.
I don't know why,
uh,
they need that strong jodie fight off
all the other gorillas but a strong,
super strong.
But so other grills,
I'm always interested in the,
the,
like the evolutionary reason as to why
things are the way they are.
Yeah,
it's fast.
And so it's like,
it's their first instinct to bite,
you know what I mean?
Cause ours,
ours isn't.
I think they show their teeth more than
they bite,
you know,
they show the teeth,
they beat on each other.
Intimidation.
Yeah.
Because I've seen videos of gorillas
beating the shit out of each other.
This.
Oh yeah.
This is one recently,
right?
This is one at the zoo.
These two girls go at it.
It's like food bags.
Yeah.
And a big gorilla was like about 500
pounds.
Right.
And a big one of these dudes just start
circling each other.
But this is just because they're
assholes.
Whoever built this gym,
you're not supposed to have two
silverbacks together.
Yeah.
So most of what they're doing is just
like,
it's all for me to go to zoos anyway,
man.
It's depressing.
It's a prison,
you know,
it's not depressing.
Note,
I always say this,
the giraffe cage,
those drafts don't get seen me.
Give a fuck was just so chill.
I used to.
I had had a bit about it.
And when you need to go so slow,
but they don't.
There's no one's eating them.
They're happy.
That's all they want to do is just eat
and chill.
I did see a wild lines get after one
once.
Oh,
in real life.
You know the,
on the Internet.
I'll tell you one safari or something.
Nah,
hell no.
I went on safari and they saw,
they saw some lines out.
I think it got a Gimsburg or something
like that,
but they said it was crazy.
And so the female lions chase after this
thing and then they were there right
when it took it down.
That's crazy nature of scary place,
man.
Yeah,
that's why I'm surprised you think you
could take a wolf.
Well,
I'm not,
I'm not out here trying to hunt.
Well,
I'm just saying in the event if I catch
you avid,
like you look at like a grey wolf,
right?
They're small compared to me.
Well they just shot one of was 182
pounds in Minnesota.
She,
that was a bit.
Yeah,
everybody gave me that picture.
Sizable fucking bear.
That's something that was a big,
big wolf.
So if like that's on this side of the
spectrum.
If you go towards the middle.
So what do you think?
Like what size?
Like 100 pounds.
You can fuck up 100 pound thing.
So yeah,
that's dude man.
You know you can take some damage,
right?
Like you're gonna I'm not going to come
out like superman.
I got,
you know,
it's gonna hurt.
It's definitely gonna hurt.
Yeah.
I mean I might not.
I might bleed out afterwards.
Who knows?
But.
But you think you win overall.
You got to do,
what do you buy?
Like 2:30 or something.
So he sends me up over here.
Used to seeing dudes.
They're not going to make weight
70 going to be a problem.
Yeah.
Nah,
I don't know.
You see how you UFC or MMA fan.
Right?
So like how,
how,
how hard can humans.
Humans could kick pretty hard.
But the thing is all I gotta do is catch
them one on the bottom and all that.
I really don't think I could break a
wolf's job with my kid.
I don't think so.
It's crazy to think their body gives
better than ours does.
Like the thing about people,
one of the things about people getting
hit is that people resist.
They tighten up.
And that's true.
That's one of the reasons why people get
so hurt.
Ever seen.
The dude doesn't know how to fight.
They get stiff and
cracked and they wanted to hurt bad,
but as someone who's like loose and
relaxed,
I don't think a wolf is going to be
worried about you kicking him,
but that's what I'm saying.
So I'm also an athlete,
right?
So I have a different perspective of.
I've been in combat before that with the
wolves,
but I've been in combat before.
Fell out and it's basically combat,
right?
Definitely.
But,
uh,
I understand that you have to,
you have to,
you have to be as a,
as loose with your body as possible.
That's how you exert more energy,
more efficient energy here than,
than tensing up.
So all that's in my head and plus I know
what the wolf is thinking for the most
part.
I'm going to put up a video of a wolf
right now.
I'm going to put it up on a regular wolf
though.
Well,
this is just a video that someone got
recently at some dude found.
I'm going to put it up right now.
Check it out,
Jeremy.
Oh,
it's posted.
It's going to take like three seconds
for it to go up,
but it's a video that someone just sent
me and I watched it and I was like,
what the fuck?
It was a guy on a road and he saw this
wolf.
Um,
and you could see like,
the headlights are on this wolf,
this Wolf Lake.
Just checking them out on the road.
I'm terrified of wolves,
man.
I'm not saying I'm not scared.
I'm just saying,
oh,
I mean in a life or death situation.
Watch this.
Look at.
This is a Shitty fucking TV.
When is this guy coming to fix this?
To speed tomorrow.
Friday.
Thank God.
Look at that as a big as well.
Looking at him,
checking you out.
But how bold is this wolf?
And it's coming near headlight.
So odds are he probably got his pack
waiting though.
Oh yeah,
the pack somewhere.
Unless he got kicked out,
he might have got kicked him.
It looks like an older wolf.
He's got scars all over him.
You know,
he might be injured too.
I don't think he's injured.
I think he probably just got fucked up
by one of the other walls and they just
realized,
all right,
I'm going to find my own.
It was a scary man.
I'm with you.
I'm pleased you think you can kill one?
I do.
I says,
Dude,
man,
I think I killed coyote.
Coyote.
Yeah,
but I might be wrong.
I don't think you're wrong.
Well,
now,
coyotes,
foxes,
foxes.
Easy.
Fuck y'all.
Fuck a fox up.
Set it up.
Exactly.
It's interesting.
It's interesting to me how much,
um,
people have an opinion on wolves,
like all of a sudden these wolf experts
come at it.
Oh yeah.
No worries.
I get,
I think you kinda are though,
right?
Well,
I know definitely not a wolf expert,
but I know a lot about them.
You know what man I did.
Um,
I was on a Sitcom once and we had a
chimp on the set and it was a baby
chimp,
like a two year old chimp and it had
diapers on.
It was like a little baby and it climbed
it.
But I'm bad.
My back just slapped me a couple of
times on the back just to play.
It was just plan and I was shocked.
I was like,
how fucking hard this baby just hit me.
This is crazy.
And I grabbed his little body,
you know,
and he was being friendly.
It wasn't being mean or anything,
but I grabbed his little body and it
doesn't feel anything like a person like
you grew up with.
Even a strong person.
Like there's a little give to their
arms.
She looked even though like a fucking
power lifter dude like the mountain from
game of thrones.
I'm sure if that dude was just resting,
if you grabbed his arm,
this is a little bit of give to them
with chimps that like courted steel man.
There's,
it does not.
That's why a 150 pound chip is a strong
as a 500 pound man.
It feels like you're grabbing this
table.
Like literally.
Like it was confusing to me and then I
was thinking in my head like I just have
it in my head that that thing is like,
I would scale it down like okay,
but person was that big,
a person wouldn't be this strong,
but then when you touch it you realize
that is not composed at the same shit a
person
and do other things though.
Right?
Yeah.
Like you know,
they,
they swing around on trees and those,
those muscles develop.
You know what I'm saying?
So can't,
you can't compare a human size chimp?
No you can't.
That's why when you see that hairless
one and you see how jack has a different
and plus they got thumb.
So it's like they,
it's different.
So how big a chimp you think,
fuck,
I don't think I could fucking champ up
man.
Keep Champs.
Maybe the one that you
fucked me up.
Like he didn't know it.
I'm,
I'm not.
I don't know.
I'm pretty realistic.
Then we say what?
You're pretty realistic then.
Yeah.
So you think in like a kick to the face.
That's the opening move with the wolf.
Got To be God to be and he don't know
what's coming.
He doesn't go was coming,
but he's going to leap towards your
throat and I'm going to leap towards
your job.
I feel like you got to have that
mentality and somebody sent me.
Somebody sent me an article to write in
Russia.
Some woman,
uh,
survived the wolf attacked and killed
the wolf.
Yeah.
Yes you do that.
I'm not,
I,
I didn't read past she see.
But that goes back to the whole chimp
thing because the Russians are built
different than regular white people.
I feel you.
I'm gonna ask you are an athlete.
But it's true.
I just feel like saying,
I just feel like if you,
if,
if you come in with the mentality of I
got to beat this wolf.
Look,
there you go.
I will access it to death.
Come on man.
Shit.
Look at her.
Wow.
You probably have to be 56.
She's probably drunk from Dagestan.
Well those Dagestan people are hard as
fuck.
That's where Habib never got my office
from a bunch of a tough fighters from
Dagestan.
Dagestan's filled with just straight
killers.
Like we have to information man,
like right on him than anything.
Jesus Christ.
What does that human ken doll up in the
upper right hand corner can't breathe
properly,
do to plastic surgery.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Look at that guy's face.
What the fuck man?
What doctor did that?
They should find out.
What doctor did that as a dude that.
I guess it's a dude.
It seems like a not real thing.
It seems like physically.
Oh,
the help of plastic surgery.
Don't,
don't even.
I don't want to hear this talk.
What the fuck is that?
That's a.
that's the world we live in today,
man.
The thing you'd have going for you is
that a wolf doesn't really want to fight
to the death.
They just want to kill you.
Exactly.
They want to kill you.
If they can't kill you,
they might be like,
oh,
problem.
Because Fuck Outta here.
They said that about like mountain
lions.
I don't want to see them.
I need them.
I don't want to say one either.
But if you get attacked,
you're supposed to fight back.
I heard a because um,
my girl right now,
she from the northwest area and we went
on this little hike once and so she told
me while we were there,
it's like,
oh they have mountain lions.
They had little packets on how to deal
with if you see a mountain.
And I'm like,
if you'd have told me that there was
mountain lions here,
I will not have king.
But anyway,
so I'm reading the pamphlet and they say
if you get big they usually like they
get it back off their kids here.
Throw your arms up in the area.
Yeah.
They say if you have a kid with you,
you supposed to pick your kid up and
hold it over your head.
Man.
I'm not sure about that.
Yeah.
I don't know.
But people have killed mountain lions
before with knives and shit.
If you have a knife and get attack by,
it's possible.
Man,
that's all I'm saying.
Is this possible?
Well you definitely definitely have to
fight.
You don't want a wolf to just eat.
And if he had that mentality dog,
you just have to like mentality.
He has to be.
Because like you,
I'm an athlete,
so I come from like the mode of like
it's either hit or be hit,
kill or be killed,
like people out here trying to break my
bone.
So like you have to have kind of a
psychotic mentality.
Well you definitely do to play nfl.
Yeah.
Just no doubt about that.
I mean when you're staring down a team
of super athletes and you're just going
to collide with each other and try to
get across lines and just a totally
different way of living.
Your life's weird man.
That 99 percent of the world.
I tell people that like I've had 14
surgeries in my career.
It's just crazy.
Like it's normal to me.
And it's been one of the people that
play in the league like after the
season,
like usually everybody gets a Sergio of
something that that's been.
What have you had done?
I've had a meniscus several times.
I've had Achilles back,
uh,
my pinky,
my shoulder actually played,
um,
uh,
all of my 2000,
10 season with a broken collarbone.
Jesus did that game three and it's still
broke.
You can still feel it,
but with a broken collarbone.
Yeah.
How'd you do that mind over matter man?
Is it like.
Because.
Because at that time I was,
I went undrafted,
right?
So um,
I had just got my shot to start and it
was game three and I was having a really
good season and um,
it was either like if in the NFL,
if you're not already paid,
like your,
your,
your position is up for grabs.
And so it's either,
either you,
you push through it or somebody's gonna
take your spot.
And so at that,
that was my,
that was my time to shine.
So I was like,
Shh,
painkillers man.
So could you feel it moving around?
It was weird.
How had to protect it.
My brother in law has like a metal piece
there.
He lost his and BMX accident.
They put like a titanium rod.
I think I need that man.
Cause like right now it's dipped in.
You can feel it.
It's like dipped in.
Did you ever like get it looked at a na
[inaudible] cause I didn't want them to
know I was hurt.
And so because they bring that,
they bring that shit up,
like during when you're negotiating your
contract.
I was like,
Oh,
well he missed this because he was
hurting and they bring that,
they use it as leverage against you.
And so 2012 was when I signed my
contract the day after I was like,
I just want to let y'all know I broke my
collarbone two years ago and was like,
no way.
I was a kid.
I was like,
no way.
So I was like,
get an x,
y.
and so we got an extra.
I was like,
Holy Shit,
you did.
I would be impressed.
I believe that's the guy I want on my
team.
Dude.
Played with a broken collarbone.
It's bittersweet.
Right?
So like,
as soon as you tell them that that's
what happened,
then it's like,
oh,
well he gets injured.
Like it's a,
it's a weird word.
What is human?
Who the fuck doesn't get injured playing
in the NFL?
I mean,
you would think that's a rational way to
go about it.
You know,
anybody who's played pro football didn't
get injured.
I mean,
how's it impossible?
I don't feel like it's possible,
I haven't seen anybody.
I watched the super bowl and one of the
things I was thinking it was like,
okay,
you're watching all these dudes run and
collide with each other and watching all
these tackles.
And like I was trying to stockpile.
I was like,
in my head I was like,
how many injuries in my watch in here?
Like,
you know,
because a lot of times dudes will walk
off and then later that night they be
like,
Oh man,
my fucking back is killing me.
Right.
It's the word.
And then you get it diagnosed and
there's some sort of a bulging disc or
something.
The problem I had because most of my
issues that,
that kept me off the field with like
soft tissue injuries,
which you can't.
I can't run with,
uh,
with my hamstring won't get.
But like all the rest of my stuff.
Um,
my problem became like my pain,
my tolerance for pain,
my threshold.
It became so high that like,
I don't even know what hurt and what was
normal anymore.
So like,
I'm still kind of dealing with a lot of
those aches and pains and stuff now,
but it's like you just push through it
because the pain was normal and you just
get accustomed to it.
Yeah.
You just.
Pain becomes a part of life.
Wow.
Yeah.
Did you always know that,
like when you were,
when you,
I'm sure you played in high school and
you played college,
did you always know that this was
eventually going to lead to like a point
where your body just wasn't gonna be
able to do it anymore?
I mean,
did you think about that
you set,
you say that,
right?
Um,
and people tell you about it,
but you know,
they say ignorance is bliss.
Like you don't know it's,
it's,
it actually affects you until it
actually affects you.
And so like,
you're like one of the worst games I've
ever been a part of what we were paying
Chicago and 2012 I thing and it was
raining so they just run into the whole
game and the next day I woke up like I'm
limping,
like walking towards the bathroom,
like I couldn't.
It took me about five minutes in my
bathroom is like right there,
so I took like five minutes and I was
like,
literally,
like limping.
It was,
my body was just beat up most of
painkillers as well from the game and
like when you go,
when you're going through it,
you don't really realize it,
but like towards the end of my career,
um,
that's,
that's kind of why I decided to walk
away because I was like,
is,
is it worth it anymore?
You know what I'm saying?
I'm relatively healthy.
I could walk,
you know,
um,
who knows what I've done to my brain,
you know,
that,
that the onset of that comes on years
later,
but after awhile it was just,
it just stopped being worth it to me
anymore.
And plus I kind of just fell out of love
with it.
That's a weird place to be right now.
When you,
when you're saying like you don't know
what's going on with your brain,
do you notice anything now?
I'm not.
Nothing that I haven't.
No.
I mean I've definitely had concussions
before and,
and earlier on,
like the cte stuff kind of,
um,
that was like the product 2000,
1314 is when the science really started
in the news media really started talking
about it,
but growing up like it was kind of just
caught a dinger like he's got done and
what I'm saying you got dinged and no
one worried about the consequences and
so we didn't really know.
And so it was just,
it was just part of part of it.
I've definitely had concussions before
where you're like,
not really sure where you are,
but like somehow your subconscious knows
what to do when you play.
Wow,
that's weird man.
So you're out of it because you've got
cracked and you just kind of gone
through the game anyway.
Keep playing.
Do you remember it afterwards?
A parts parts that happens.
A lot of fighters,
like they'll get dropped in the first
round,
right.
And then there'll be on their corner and
the like the fourth round headed into
the fifth and they'll think it's the
second round two.
And then the coach go,
hey you,
you fought three more rounds and you
think he did.
They're like,
what?
Yeah,
it's crazy the second round,
right?
Like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
It's,
it's amazing to me that people are able
to function on such a high level,
not really conscious of what's going on.
That's got to be your training,
right?
Yes.
That's all training is you're training
your body to become second nature.
So now when you were in high school and
you were in college,
was there any talk at all about brain
damage?
Was there any talk about cte or the.
Not really.
Nobody worried about it now.
It was just not,
it wasn't.
The science wasn't complete.
I'm pretty sure there were,
there were neuroscientist saying like,
your brain damage is real,
but the science wasn't as definitive as
it is now,
but no one connected it the way they did
with boxing.
Uh,
not to us.
And to me,
um,
you know,
like,
like now people are,
are worrisome about putting the kids in
youth leagues and stuff like that.
And they're even talking about not
letting youth leagues happen.
I'll have tackle football at all,
which I'm an advocate for it.
I don't think there's a,
there's no point for it.
I'm like,
my kid,
my son did not gonna play football.
No,
no.
Wow.
That's crazy.
But you,
you made it my body.
So,
so they could have a free ride or
whatever they want to do,
man.
What if they want to play football?
I'm going to say sit down,
man.
You gotta trust my man.
Relax.
They want to be their own man.
You know,
I can't.
I'm not going to physically stop him.
I mean,
I probably could,
but um,
I would,
I would seriously sit them down and let
them know the consequences,
showing people and show them the risk
factors involved.
Like it is not worth it.
I know you want to enter and I mean,
as much as,
as,
as a son wants to walk into his father's
shoes,
uh,
it's just not worth it,
man.
It's really nice and you're probably not
going to be as good.
That's just how.
What if you kid wanting to fight like a,
like box?
Yeah.
Box or boxer.
I wouldn't advocate that either.
He wouldn't let them do that.
I'm pushing them to go towards like a
education.
I want them to be scientists.
Like if I had to do it over again,
I wouldn't never played football.
I really,
yeah,
it'd be a scientist.
Not even.
You would start from the beginning,
like if you could go back to college and
knowing what you know now,
wow.
Not even close and just because of the
damage to your body will that.
And uh,
so it's,
it's a weird,
it's a weird thing.
So like,
you're,
you're in your prime physically as a,
as a man,
but you're,
you're in your infancy mentally.
Right?
Right.
And so like I'm just now figuring out
who I am and what kind of man I want to
be.
And,
and you're,
you're,
while you're in your prime,
that's when you're in the public eye.
So you have to deal with all of that on
top of figures.
So you're figuring out who you are in a
fishbowl.
And it's,
it's a really weird,
really weird thing.
So I don't even want to deal like,
like any kind of recommendation or any
kind of
fame or whatever people want to call it.
Like I don't,
I don't like it,
I don't want it.
I feel like the best to me,
the best,
uh,
society would be a artist and a
scientist.
That would be a ideal society to me.
Wow.
That's an interesting take on things.
Considering how successful you've been
playing football,
playing football obviously was very
financially rewarding to you.
Made you famous for sure.
I mean if just some regular dude went on
twitter and start talking about I can
take a wolf farmer.
I know that he killed.
Nobody will care and be like,
shut up stupid that anybody cares
anyway,
but it's
fucking my twitter.
But I said you were coming to school and
was going to kill.
I don't know man.
It's,
it's a,
it's a weird.
I'm like,
once you get to that,
to that financial summit that um,
everybody strives for that American
dream.
You realize that there is no there and
if you ain't happy with $10,
you're not going to be happy with a
million.
It's just not happening.
Now,
granted,
there are some things that you need,
you need monetary
value in the society to,
to a certain extent.
I think they did a study.
It's like after $75,000 a year,
money can't buy happiness like so
everything else out there is kind of,
it's just luxury and really if you put
it in perspective,
I think like 35 percent.
I mean if,
if you,
if you make $35,000 a year,
you're in the top one percent of wealth
in the world.
Yeah.
Something like that.
So it's all about perspective man.
And once,
once,
once I.
It took me to get to that financial
summit to understand that unfortunately.
But the weird thing about it is once you
tell people that and you're on top of
this financial summit,
he's for you to say,
I'm like,
all right,
of course.
Yeah.
Easy for you to know.
A lot of miserable millionaires.
I do too.
It's really interesting that you said
that like growing up and figuring out
who you are while you're in a fishbowl
and you were also involved in not just
you,
not just in a fishbowl,
you're involved in like this competitive
fishbowl where you're,
you're,
your value is being judged by your
ability to cover distance and speed,
but your ability to score points or it
stopped people from scoring points.
That's kind of crazy too.
It's,
um,
football is not a place for a like
thinkers and I'm not,
I'm not saying that I'm the only person
that has these thoughts,
but it's like if you,
if you like questioning authority and
you're questioning a lot of things,
like football is not the place for you
because if,
if you're inquisitive at all,
it's kind of comes off as arrogant and
it comes off as I'm like disruptive.
And I never was.
I was,
I was always just like,
why do we do things this way?
Like why,
why?
Like especially like in college,
right?
So like football has this like weird,
um,
relationship with coach to player that
like you can talk to other men,
like you can treat them like shit.
So the coach,
the coach can yell at the player you
piece of Shit,
you're not doing it right.
But if I use,
if he was working at home depot and your
boss comes to upc shit,
you didn't stock that,
buys the,
it'd be like you'd be calling hr rather
saying basis or weird for some reason in
that arena.
It's okay.
And like I was like,
listen man,
if you want me to do something,
like I used to tell my coach was like,
don't yell at me.
Like there's no reason for you yet
because like one on one I could,
you know what I mean.
Easier than a wall.
Yeah.
Man
didn't make any sense to me.
Like why,
why on this field is it okay.
But as soon as we walk out to the field
you want,
you wouldn't,
you wouldn't dare yelled at me like
that.
Why is that okay?
And plus you got a hot head coming out
of high school.
Um,
I mean I was,
at least in a lot of us are because I
mean,
you usually come from those
neighborhoods were,
do you think that's just because they
have to control these big groups of
super athletes so they have to kind of
posture and like yelling at him,
like you would yell at like a guard dog
or something like that.
His cattle,
right?
So you just have to,
you just have to.
It was just that same old mechanism of
fear,
right?
So people,
people ruled by fear.
So you wrote the biggest stick.
So that,
that's,
that's how,
that's how humans have done it for
centuries.
That's how they get into your head about
who this leverage of you.
I have fear,
I have your scholarship,
I have this,
I have this.
If you don't do what I say,
all that gets taken away and it works.
But for me it did it.
And I was like,
I don't,
I'm in because of that.
You're,
you're labeled as like a trouble there.
Yeah,
like I was part of the reason why I
didn't get drafted.
I found out like the coaches said that,
um,
I was,
I wasn't coachable.
I was like,
Nah,
like getting yelled at.
Wow,
that's bizarre.
It's seen that before.
I've seen coaches screaming at athletes
that could kill them and you don't see
that in others.
What,
you definitely don't see that in mma,
mma also like the coach relationship
with the fighters,
like a father son relationship and a lot
of ways they're like brothers or at the
very least family,
you know,
that's like an intense bond.
I'm not saying every coach is like that,
but it's,
it's,
it's a,
it's definitely a culture.
Yeah,
it's definitely a coach.
Do you think that's changing and like
with this whole kaepernick thing and
people are sort of aware of people being
more socially conscious,
more aware of people using their,
their,
uh,
their fame for a platform to voice their
voice,
their opinions on certain social issues.
Is,
is that changing?
He has to because um,
well social media is just changing
everything.
It's changing the way we think.
It's changing the way situations are
monitored because it's like a,
there's a camera with you everywhere.
So,
um,
but I think,
uh,
in a,
in a bigger sense,
um,
athletes in general are becoming more
outspoken.
Athletes are becoming a more well
versed,
um,
they're really understanding their brand
power and with that,
uh,
you have to change the way things have
been,
things that have been done in the past,
like,
like a simple stuff like training camp,
training camp used to be two days full
pads and you're hitting at a time,
you can't do that anymore because the
athletes are getting bigger,
stronger,
faster.
So if you want your catalog last long,
but you got to take care of them when
you're practicing cattles that just talk
like that.
So it disturbs the truth though.
No,
it is.
That's why it's disturbing.
We get compensated heavily in the NFL or
the NCAA.
Is this a whole nother conversation?
Those,
those crooks don't pay their employees,
but as far as the NFL,
you get compensated and you,
you know,
the risks for the most part,
the risks going into the NFL.
Like I chose to do this as a at a young
age.
I'm glad you just said that.
Those crooks don't pay their employees.
Get out as a dark and dirty fucking
business.
College sports hate it.
I hate it.
I hate it now.
I don't have anything to do with it,
but I watch it.
I'm like,
that's cool.
When you find out how much those fucking
schools get from all those people in
order to make sure that their team is
successful because the alma maters wanna
Yay.
We fucking won again,
and they did.
They get billions of dollars.
There are fucking huge,
huge business man.
It's the athletes don't get paid
anything.
Nah,
man.
I've told many many times I've told my
side of that story,
man,
I don't.
I'm not a fan of the NCA.
I'm not a fan either.
I think it's stealing.
I think you're stealing from those
athletes and ruining their careers.
Most likely for you.
If you do four hard years of college
football,
what are the odds you're going to get
out of that without a permanent injury?
I had,
I think three or four of my surgeries
came from college.
Yeah.
It's playing for free.
You pay for and my buddy,
hey,
you get an education.
And See,
that's the thing that kills me when
people say that,
to say that I hate that.
So when I first went to school I wanted
to study astronomy.
Like that was what I wanted to study.
So I went to my academic advisor and I
was like,
okay,
this is what I want to do.
Like it took me a year to figure out,
okay,
this is what I do.
I was,
I was in love with the stars in the
college.
That's one of the,
I just wanted to know about it and,
and as soon as I said,
he's like,
oh,
you can't do that.
I was like,
why?
He's like,
because the,
those classes conflict with the practice
schedules in the meeting schedules.
And I was like,
well shit.
And so I had to wait another year in
order to find what I wanted to do and
ended up settling for a philosophy,
which was a cool major.
But it wasn't,
it didn't.
I felt like if,
if,
if I would've got influenced by,
by,
uh,
astronomy early on,
then it would have changed my trajectory
would have changed the way I thought
about a lot or I'd arrived to the
conclusion that I met now a lot sooner.
Yeah.
The,
the whole.
You're getting an education thing.
What are you getting a real education?
Yeah.
Hell No.
Hell no,
no,
it's about,
it's about a month,
maybe a month or three weeks after the
season before you go into spring ball,
which is like,
you're up at five in the morning lifting
and running and Yada Yada Yada.
Um,
but there was like a three,
three week period where they,
they leave you alone and you're just
like a regular student.
And I did not know what to do with my
time.
I'm like,
how,
how are these,
how are these people not ace in their
classes?
Like I didn't understand like how.
I mean,
granted they were taking courses but
it's just like you have so much time.
I didn't know what to do with my time
because it before.
Whereas before I'm up early in the
morning,
lifting weights,
running,
then go into class,
then after class get a little lunch,
then go to another class.
Then you come back in,
you're in meetings and after meetings
you go to practice and after practice
you get find some kind of energy study
yet.
Well give me a rundown.
So like what time of morning would you
get up?
So when you were in school?
Usually.
Usually I had some of the most.
Most of my classes were the 8:00
classes,
so 8:00 AM you're up now?
I up before that.
So,
so independent on the day.
So you have to get a workout in
depending on everybody.
Every strength coach has a different
protocol so you have to lift at least
three times a week.
Three,
three to two to three times a week.
And so you either lift before class or
before practice or after practice.
So you have to,
you have to find your time with after
practice you got to be hard,
right?
You're,
yeah.
Really.
Then you're just kinda going through the
motion so.
But do you,
do you want to do it before practice
because then you might be tired when you
go into practice,
you might not perform up to the best of
your abilities.
Uh,
I,
I was,
I was not the best at that.
I used to get in trouble a lot because I
was like,
there's no way you guys can expect me to
do all of this shit.
I used to get in trouble for skipping
weights
and I wasn't big on weight to anyway.
I'm like,
I was like,
I didn't see that because we had a lot
of Olympic weight lifting and that's
kind of changing too.
We had a lot of like dead lifts and
squats and shit like that.
And I was never a fan of that stuff.
I was like,
this is not a conducive to being
successful.
What do you think is Plyo,
Plyo?
Uh,
like yoga,
Yoga,
Yoga would real.
Yeah.
If we had a yoga,
I'd have been there every time because
it's like you're,
you're getting loose.
Any kind of you being limber is more
important to me and strong in my
opinion,
especially in my position.
And my position,
I mean that's something,
there are some positions like d linemen
and office alignment where you gotta you
gotTa Push,
but I'm not one of those because I
wasn't one of those positions.
Being a running back as like dbs
receivers,
like stay limber,
stay hydrated with good nutrition.
So for you it's more important to be
flexible and to be able to move your
body in very fluid ways.
So to be able to avoid take downs,
they will avoid somebody trying to
tackle you,
you,
you more pliable is better in my
opinion.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
That's an interesting way of looking at
it.
So you would uh,
they would force you to do certain
amount of lifts.
Yeah.
You got to do a certain amount of lifts
and then you got to go to class and you
got to stay up and then when you're
doing these lifts,
so they supervised or you have to do
coaches in there.
So that's another thing that bothers me
too.
I was like a rebel man because it's like
they will follow you around the weight
room.
Right?
Because some guys liked to like,
you know,
try to try to jerk the system and I'm
like,
this is what I want to do with my life.
Like I'm not going to cheat myself.
Like stop following me around.
Right.
It wasn't long.
Yeah,
it was like a weird.
And then they have class checkers that
follow you make sure you go to class
class.
It's just like,
Bro,
like I just feel like a little kid,
man.
I get out of my face.
And so like after a while that just wore
on me and like the whole system wore on
me and on top of that,
like I'm hungry.
You know what I'm saying?
You don't get the food out.
People get on me again.
People from Tennessee hate me bro.
It's weird.
But I'm from Tennessee.
Why?
As I went to,
I went to and for some reason,
anytime I say anything about the NCAA,
they think I'm talking about tenancy
itself because weird.
They're like,
fuck you man.
Like I,
I still have people like to this day,
matter of fact,
yesterday a mom mentioned something
about,
um,
like fumbles.
I had from like 10 years ago.
It's weird man.
People will.
Awkward Man.
Well people love to bring up things that
you've done wrong.
When I was like 18 years old.
I love it.
Love it.
It's funny man.
It is funny.
So you would get up in the morning and
you would have to figure out when
you're.
So would you schedule your lifts and
it's not a,
it's not necessarily schedule is more
like a um,
whatever suits your schedule the best.
So if you have an 8:00 class,
you get to go before class or whenever
your break is during.
How many classes are you doing today?
Like two or three.
And what?
You're supposed to keep a certain GPA.
Two point five.
So you have to keep up to par.
What is that?
Like a c average and just like see,
see averages.
So you would go to your class,
you do whatever you gotta do.
And then how many times a day are you
practicing?
A once a day.
Once you have meetings,
meetings are like an hour 30 and the
meetings are essential or going over
strategy and go here.
You get your playbook,
your game plan,
watch film on the other team or
yourself.
Is it hard to motivate yourself watching
all that shit?
Yeah,
after awhile for me because like um,
my quarterbacks are different.
They don't have to um,
exert as much physical energy as we do
and they're,
they're more on a mental game so they
have to know the defensive games that
the defensive coordinators playing.
Right.
So what covers then wider,
what the safety is doing.
Don't have to know that as a running
back you kind of have to know,
but I'm not as much.
You kind of just have to know where
their blitzes are coming from.
Oh boy.
With the,
with the intricacy,
but
after awhile I got it.
I didn't need to watch much film in
order me to get my assignment done.
So a lot of times I'm just sitting there
wasting time.
Like I feel like that too.
Yeah,
I would imagine sitting there watching
some stupid place.
I always told my coaches,
especially in the league,
I was like,
you could give me my game plan like
Saturday before the game and I'll
execute it like I didn't need.
I think a lot of what they do and the
NFL is just reinforcement.
It's just over and over and it's
repetition,
and after a while,
especially if you're a veteran,
I get on there.
That's why Brett Farve,
like when he was deciding on whether to
come back or not,
it was like I,
I would love to,
but all that other shit.
I don't like doing all that.
The meetings and that kept him back
here.
Man.
He really just gets old.
It gets super old man and you don't know
what you're doing and you and you will,
uh,
well versed in your craft.
Don't you don't need half of that shit.
And this is terrible for the younger
cats that are listening to this man was
something about a guy like Brett farve
too,
with all that fucking gray hair or
grizzled old veteran.
He's a goat milk still wanting to do it.
Go crazy.
Right?
It's just crazy.
They still wanted to do it.
I mean,
how many times I've been deemed as was
saying,
I don't know,
get hit a lot though.
Like,
like get enough.
You know,
Jim Mcmahon is all fucked up now.
I mean most ex players are.
Yeah.
Most experts are.
I was reading that sports illustrated
article about Mcmahon and they did an
interview on one of those sports radio
stations.
I was listening to it.
It was disturbing and it was talking
about it.
He'll be like somewhere and you just
totally forgot how he got there,
where he's going,
why,
why don't have my keys in my hand?
Where am I going?
Yeah,
I mean part,
it's part of the unfortunate part of the
prizes.
So they would follow you around.
They'd make sure you go to classes.
Like what?
Some dude with a clipboard.
Yes.
Extra foster.
Some ga.
Now they will say anything though,
right?
Does anyone say anything?
So like they would,
they would send them and they would
check and see if you're in there and if
you're not in there they report back to
coach and like,
oh he missed on.
So.
ANd then you gotta go up to the coaches.
I was like,
well,
why weren't you?
I'm like,
the crazy shit is in college.
That's where you kind of learn how to
time management as that's where you
learn your time management as,
as an adult,
right?
So they don't even allow you to become
an adult.
How most adults become adult in that
college system.
So like some teachers,
some professors will give you a syllabus
and say,
here's,
here's going to be the work for it and
show up when you want to show up,
but you're responsible for your own
information at the end of the day.
For the most part,
we don't even get that,
uh,
that,
that luxury you have to go every single
day,
every,
every class.
And I'm like,
not even,
students aren't even required.
Why am I required?
Yeah.
You could study at home.
You want it to maybe even learn more.
And that was really good.
Beginning of like online,
like syllabus is online stuff.
So like I'm not sure if maybe maybe
colleges have adjusted that to that
nowadays.
But from when I was,
when I was going,
they,
they made,
it was mandated you have to go to every
class.
Well it seems like you're preparing for
a career in professional sports,
but you're also pretending that you're
getting like a real education,
like a regular person.
Yeah.
But it is kind of pretending because
there's not a way you could be preparing
for like high level college athletics
and have the same time to devote towards
studies.
Nah,
you can't.
Yeah.
And that's why like that's why I say I
would,
I would do it again if I,
if I had to do it again,
I would do something else.
He just wouldn't go football at all
because I'm like the shit that keeps you
up at night now it's not football.
And that's how I knew I was tying to get
out.
Like I'm sitting on the sidelines and
I'm thinking about other shit.
Like what kind of show a physics like
really up at nightmare.
It keeps me up at night.
What kind of physics?
Theoretical physics.
So what got me into it was relativity.
That's what,
that's what hookeD me,
like einstein equals mc squared.
What kind of just fascinated by the
concept of it.
Uh,
it's,
I don't know how anybody isn't man,
like it's the whole store really.
So you still.
So relativity brought me in and how it
happened was one day I was,
I was actually hired man,
so I was smoking weed crazy here and it
kinda hit me because like you,
you hear about what einstein did but you
don't really understand it because I
mean unless it sparks interest.
Right?
And So I was just sitting there watching
the documentary and he proved how a
light bends,
right?
So like gravity,
gravity bends light and it just kinda
hit me.
I was like,
that shit is crazy.
So I just started digging more and more
and more.
And you researched,
uh,
the beginnings of when we started a
research enlightened,
the first place,
like newton figured out that like breaks
and it's just the whole entire science
history of,
of that,
that aspect of light gravity is just
blew me away.
And I just,
I just got hooked.
Neil degrasse tyson was here two weeks
ago and fuck my head up.
My head has been broken ever since.
He said that if you go one g like out
into space,
like you say,
if you are on a like a rocket,
it shoots one g out in space.
If it continues to go at one g,
that same force because there's no air
and space,
the momentum of that because most of the
time what they do with the rockets
cutoff and then you just move forward on
the momentum because you're in a vacuum,
you just flying through space.
But if you continue to propel at one g
you will reach like just under the speed
of light.
So if you like,
if you go into somewhere that's five
light years away,
it would take one year more.
So instead of five years it will take
you six years.
So it's 10 light years away.
It'll take you 11 years.
So it's a year under the speed of light.
I was like,
what in the fuck
light.
It's crazy how fast light moves and you
can get that fast almost as fast as the
speed of light by just going one.
Gee,
I didn't know that.
That's been fucking with me for two
weeks.
I've been just,
I'll sometimes get up in the morning and
I'll just trying to,
trying to think of how fast that is.
She's crazy.
Like if you were watched someone whiz by
you,
you wouldn't even be able to be able to
see it.
Yeah,
it would be too fast for you to see it.
And that's a person in a tube.
alright.
And then you started digging into the
relativity about that he's going to be
aging slower than you.
Yes,
he's moving faster.
That's really crazy.
So that shit shit like that keeps me up
at night man.
And so like I wish like I'm to the point
now where like I've done enough reading
about it like an in and unless I start
learning the math of it,
like I've,
I've reached my limit of,
of,
of what to know about physics.
Are you thinking about doing that?
Yeah,
I'm probably gonna get back in school.
Wow.
What have you become like some fucking
certain scientists that'd be dope,
man.
Go down there and work on the large
hadron collider or some shit to me that
that's more um,
I mean I guess any,
any kind of a goal that you set as a
seven year old and obtain is you should
be super proud of,
but like my conscious tells me he's
like,
you haven't given anything to the
society and that's just the way my brain
thinks.
And so it's like,
unless I do something like that,
like I just,
I just feel like I've been bumping
around on the.
How old are you now?
30.
Will you still got plenty of room?
Yeah,
for sure.
I'll be,
I'll be coming late in the game,
but um,
yeah,
yeah.
But you're
coming into the game with a lot of life
experience,
like at an intense level that most
people just couldn't ever even
comprehend I show.
You know what I mean?
There's gotta be some sort of enhanced
perspective from playing football at the
highest level in the world.
I mean there's,
there's gotta be something too that
you're playing in the nfl,
the just the,
just the amount of intensity and just
the problem solving that you're having
to deal with on the field and just the
overcoming the physical injuries,
that mental strength did you have to
have to deal with the kind of pain that
you've had to experience that alone,
all that stuff.
I mean,
It might not seem like it applies,
but I feel like everything applies.
I think every,
everything,
every book you read,
every relationship you're in,
every friendship you have,
everything that you see,
the changes,
the way you look at life,
all those things sort of added layers to
your existence.
Not appreciate the pep talk,
man.
it would be crazy if you became some
crazy huge physicist.
esther,
esther.
That was a goal of my man is to,
is to definitely
bachelor's.
What's completely possible now for sure.
Bachelor'S as possible and phd is
possible too if you really want to work
towards it.
YeAh,
it's a,
it's a long agregious process.
But,
um,
I think I'm up for a minute.
I just want to do a little more relaxing
because I just retired.
And what
november and what caused you to retire?
Like physically?
Are you okay or.
Yeah,
I'm,
I'm okay.
Physically it was just a little bit of
both.
So I had a couple of nagging injuries
and I also saw him sitting on the
sidelines and my,
I'm just not into it.
I,
I remember vividly thinking like,
I don't care at all who wins this game?
I don't care man.
And like,
and so like that's why
I love,
I love Adam Gates.
He's the,
he's the head coach of the miami
dolphins and um,
uh,
they,
the whole organization in miami,
like they,
they let me bow out gracefully.
They respected what I did in nfl and
they were like,
listen,
like,
you know,
you do how you want to do it and we're
not gonna make it hard for you because
some organizations can be a dick about
it.
Like they could take money from you,
they could do all kinds of shit.
But they were really good about the
process and It was because I guess it's
the way I explained it to him,
I was like,
man,
I feel like they have a good team.
And I felt like if I'm sitting here just
holding on for a check,
I'm wasting your time and you're wasting
my time.
And so there is no,
there's no reason for me to be here
anymore because of my heart just isn't
in it anymore.
I appreciate what the game did for
myself,
my family,
and it's kept me driven for 30 years
minute,
but it was just time ago.
That's a very balanced perspective for a
lot of people.
The big paychecks are harder to walk
away from,
of course,
but you have the point of view.
You have the enough perspective,
enough objective perspective,
look outside of it and go,
this is not,
is not where I want to be.
And uh,
it was,
uh,
it was a weird,
a parting too because I,
I,
it's all I've known since I was seven
years old every,
every fall,
like,
and for one before.
And even before that,
getting ready for football,
it's just all I've known,
it's been,
it's been my.
And
um,
I just got to the point where it's just
a whole big world out there and I just
need to,
I need to feed off that.
That's,
that's very confident of you too.
That's what's really powerful about that
is that you realize that you're kind of
starting from scratch,
obviously not because you're financially
successful and you've got some stuff
going on,
but you're entering into a completely
different world now as far as like the
potential of your future.
Right.
And it's,
you got to like,
I've always been a humble cat man.
I'm like,
I never thought that I was any bigger or
better than like,
none of that shit ever mad at me because
I always,
I would be in the middle of a game man
and think like,
this is weird.
People just watching this play a game
like this shit is so it's like 100,000
people and you're like,
this is so awkward to me.
But I've always kept that perspective.
Like I didn't think anything of it
because I didn't think anything of it
and it was just a game at the end of the
day.
And so,
um,
I don't know man,
if the future is,
is,
it's wide open now.
And I,
like I said,
extremely,
uh,
appreciative of everything that the game
has brought me though.
Now when you were in college that the
big thing in college football is always
like the players getting paid off.
They're getting money,
you know,
they're getting like any of that shit
ever happened with you.
Yeah.
[inaudible] uh,
uh,
caused a big stir awhile back because I
made it that,
um,
and this is a weird
thing too,
is like,
so players were mad at me for saying
that.
I was like,
why?
Why would you say that you fuckIng it up
for the younger cats.
And um,
so like once y'all realize that these
rules at the nca made or stupid and it,
all it takes is for everybody to stand
up and say this is stupid.
Like they'll go away that their own
separate entity.
Nobody answers,
like they don't answer to anybody,
they don't own,
they're just the ncaa and they have
contracts with the television stations
and so that's what's,
that's what's keeping them in play.
The millions of dollars.
Billions.
So if,
so,
if,
if the athletes finally wake up and say
like,
my dad had a great idea.
So say all the top recruits stopped
going to the big schools,
right?
So they stopped,
started going to place like grambling or
what are some,
some,
some of the smaller schools,
right?
Uh,
that would take away the ncaas leverage
and then you can start paying the
players.
And I'm not saying that they should get
a salary like the nfl.
I don't know.
Those semantics can be worked out when
the time comes.
All I'm saying is the ncaa is,
they're there,
they're holding everybody hostage by a
system that was put in place in the 19
thirties or twenties or something like
that when the big business of college
football wasn't even close to what it is
now.
Right?
Yeah.
So the sponsorships and all of that
stuff,
it wasn't even near what it is now.
You have the tostitos fiesta bowl,
you have to know is sugar bowl.
These are companies that are paying
millions of dollars in order to have
them play under that,
under that guise.
What seems to me like that.
What colleges almost like a farm
team,
if they don't want to call it that.
Yeah,
you're,
you're pretending that these are
students and the kinds of students,
I mean that you make them sit in class
and you make them get a c.
There are,
there are cats that play that are going
to go pro in something that has sports,
that's for sure.
Do you think that it would be okay if
they did it the way they're doing it
now,
but they pay the athletes and they make
school and option that,
that,
that to me,
we've discussed a lot of that van and
um,
I don't,
I don't see a problem with that.
And I'll tell you why.
And I also think you should be able to
get a degree in football because there
are so many jobs at the nfl has,
right?
You have commentators,
you have.
Do you have staff that work all
throughout the nfl offices?
Why can't you major in football?
That's a great idea.
It's a business.
It's a business,
but the reason we're treating it like
it's not a business and we continue as
soon as we wake up and say this is a
business,
I think progression will happen and it
always does,
but it,
it.
They're just holding onto this circular
reasoning.
No,
no,
they're amateur athletes.
Well,
why are the amateur athletes?
Because we don't pay him,
but why don't we paint?
Because they're amateur athletics.
Like,
man,
I guess it's ridiculous.
Yeah.
And I feel like if you did get a degree
in football,
then your time could be spent learning
physiology,
strength and conditioning protocol
because it took me until I didn't really
understand nutrition.
So I got out of college honestly.
Really?
Yeah.
I didn't really understand it.
Um,
there wasn't a nutritionist there,
but like it wasn't as detailed as it is
now.
Like what were they telling you?
Like what didn't care?
That was the thing.
I didn't care.
I was,
I was drinking a lot and I was eating a
lot of windows,
right,
because when you're young,
you're 19 years old,
it don't affect your body,
you can put whatever in your body
really.
Um,
but then when you start getting a to
where this is your job,
um,
and you can start filling those burgers
on you the next day it was like,
hold on,
maybe I need to look into this.
So I looked into it independently and
that's what I,
I didn't understand what nutrition for
the body,
I really don't understand,
but you can,
you could do nutrition,
physiology,
uh,
everything that you're interested in and
that is a helpful to your craft.
Do you think when you're young that it
doesn't affect your body or do you think
you're not tuned in enough to your body
to realize it's affecting you?
I think a little bit of both,
man.
Like you have to,
you have to watch what you eat as you
get older.
That's for sure.
And when I really started noticing it
was like a 23,
24 when I was like,
all right,
those heavy weekends where I'm eating
whatever I want and getting drunk or
they're,
they're fucking with me.
So I have to really start looking at
what is good to put them on board and
whether or not you kind of know just
based off the pyramid and you growing up
here and what's good and what's bad.
Um,
buT once you,
once you understand and break down the
carbs and all of this stuff that you're
putting in your body,
you really,
it takes your game to the next level.
And it did that to me.
So what kind of advice they give you in
college as far as nutrition,
what they tell you to eat?
A lot of the same stuff.
A lot of little grilled.
Make sure nothing fried.
You don't want to,
you don't want to load up on carbs.
A certain kind of carbs are good for
you.
like so some carbs like sweet potatoes
are really good.
So they were giving me that good
information.
I wasn't,
I,
I wasn't ready to receive the
information,
so I can't fault them,
but once you go to college then he
started really paying attention to it.
And what,
what,
like what did you follow after that?
Uh,
this ain't the same model that,
um,
so it was like the grill,
the grill,
the grill stuff,
that's stuff like that.
And then I have such an addictive
personality.
I started doing a lot,
so I started getting into being a vegan
and plant based,
um,
and,
and so it led me to,
they're like a researching food and
nutrition,
that lifestyle lifestyle's not for me.
Uh,
I tried it for about six,
seven months,
but um,
yeah man,
I mean I tried the best I could to eat
as healthy as I could.
But what happened with you,
with trying vegan?
Um,
it was really good,
man.
I met a lot of good people with vegans
come out of the woodworks to show the
support.
Uh,
they also put you into a good team when
you leave though.
Trader.
Yeah,
they get mad superman.
Um,
but,
uh,
you know,
I kind of support the lifestyle man.
I'm plant based,
you can be a vegan and drink coke and
eat chips all day,
but like plant based lifestyle,
I feel like it's really healthy and it
really,
I felt really good while I was eating
like that.
Um,
but for me I got tired of constantly
worrying about what I was going to put
in my body.
like,
so every meal was a prep,
I had to do it every single end and
everything in our,
in our lives is like a,
a celebration and all celebration is
usually centered around food and meat.
So I got tired of doing that,
so I was like,
all right,
if I died two years earlier,
do you really think you're going to
though?
Do you think it's bad for the eat meat?
no.
In moderation.
I think if you just load up on a lot of
me,
it can be unhealthy.
Did you,
when you were,
I'm eating a vegan diet,
did you notice performance benefits?
Uh,
it's all anecdotal.
I don't have any,
you know,
but uh,
I felt like I recovered a little faster.
Um,
but again,
it's all anecdotal and it could have
been holding my head.
I think just eating a lot of vegetables.
We'll do that for you for sure.
Whether or not you eat meat at all or
fish or anything,
I just think it's so beneficial to eat a
lot of vegetables.
One hundred percent.
And look at one thing.
I know a different show.
Is it cleanse me like your,
um,
your bowel movements?
Oh well it juSt slides out and that's
not to get too grotesque man.
But it's really
important.
Merrily I'll do it,
but it's,
it's you,
you noticed a difference and you really
understand what a healthy bowel movement
is and what,
or not healthy no matter if you're just
eating cheeseburgers and stuff and
you're not getting a lot of vegetables
and a lot of fiber and yeah,
people don't even know.
yeah,
it's a different,
it's a different uh,
especially if you blend it.
If we blend like kale shakes,
bridges,
lubes the whole process.
I wasn't big on the uh,
on the blender,
man.
I'm big on it because I can eat way more
than I would ever in a salad.
Right.
Like if,
uh,
there's only so much you can eat in a
salad,
but five,
blend that shit up and break it down to
24 ounces of like semi liquid.
RigHt.
That's a lot of weight of vegetables and
just seems to me that just massive boost
of nutrients that enter into your
bloodstream and your digestive tract.
I'm just not as good with the patients.
Yeah,
no,
I understand.
What,
what about protein when you were,
um,
being a vegan,
what did you,
uh,
did you use like pea protein or a hemp
protein?
Like what kind of protein?
We stay away from him because um,
uh,
they test for,
for,
for weed and they said sometimes I
don't,
I didn't want to,
I didn't want to take the chance.
I didn't.
Wow.
I'm not well versed on what is and what
is now some honest shit that doesn't
test positive.
No,
I'm done.
So I could do whatever I want and I
don't know why they would say that
because most,
if you get good hamp.
Well,
I guess that's the thing is good.
That's what they said.
They seen him.
they said flaxseeds can make you test
positive.
Well,
you know,
poppy Seeds can make you test positive
for marijuana.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
like people have tested positive on
those random drug tests to give people
their jobs from having a poppy seed
bagel that's,
you're shooting heroin.
It's just like the fucking stupid.
Anyway.
Like in the nfl,
they need to,
um,
uh,
let,
let guys use a weed for,
for pain.
Oh,
for sure.
It's ridiculous.
We'll definitely cbds for sure because
it's not even sipo aside.
Snagged the cbd oil that comes from.
It comes from hemp plant.
That's not psychoactive.
My were really good for you to super
good for inflammation and joint pain and
things along those lines.
Matter of fact,
when I had my,
um,
we actually,
we have some right here.
Sit right here.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
This is a charlotte's web.
This is actually one of my sponsors.
Now they make hemp oil.
Yeah.
I didn't mean to play.
I'm going to do it.
It's actually on this podcast.
I have to do a sponsor about it,
but this stuff is great and you just
take it drops.
It's good for you.
A negative effect.
When I had my back surgery in 2014 or
13.
And uh,
what did you have done?
l five s one.
I had a,
it's this ectomy.
Dissectomy.
Yeah.
Um,
they uh,
they prescribed percocet and percocet I
used to.
I used to take them for everything else.
They used to make me like gag and throw
up every single time I took them.
And so it really,
in any painkiller that was heavily,
heavily sedate you,
I would always like throw up and they,
they told me that if you like,
have a gag reflex too much,
like you could read.
I could of reset my desk really.
So for like two days I was just like in
pain after the surgery and my dad was
like,
man,
go some weed or alex,
I'm gonna,
go get you some weed.
I was like,
what?
He's like,
yeah man.
So he went to.
They're lucky that I was in la.
I got it in la and had to dispensary.
And so,
uh,
got some and uh,
it,
it helps immediately and I was like,
there's no way that they shouldn't be
okay,
just totally be lyrical.
Were being rude,
being fucked,
you know what I mean?
It's slowly but surely it's starting to
become legal recreationally.
It's legal now in California
recreationally.
But the federal government is still
resisting it because of the influence of
the pharmaceutical companies and also a
bunch of other people that like the
prison guard unions,
they don't want it to be legal because
they have less people to arrest.
It's kind of fucked up.
Yeah.
Know the prison industrial complex.
It's scary shit.
A real thing.
They're making money off people being in
cages.
It's like are people are human batteries
and you get money off of this matrix.
The matrix.
It really is.
It's like a very low level version of
the matrix.
But it's terrifying if that logic with
all the science that's in place about
what's dangerous and what's not.
They're prescribing percocet.
So like here fella,
take these.
Makes no sense.
Young strapping,
buck wants to take some shit that might
get you hooked.
They have this,
they have this,
this waiver we have to sign.
So there's,
this is painkiller called toradol in the
nfl,
right?
Yeah,
it's awful.
But I took it a lot because prescribed
that shit to my dog.
Really?
He's a great dog.
Got bit so like for.
So if a tornado we have to,
we have to sign this waiver that says
you're kind of just given up your.
It's not,
we're not responsible for but they'll
let us take that,
but they won't let us smoke weed and
they're abandoned dudes that smoke weed
and suspended dudes.
That's right.
He retired because even just,
um,
I leave josh gordon.
He played receiver for the browns.
He was one of the best young receivers
I've seen in a long time,
but he,
they banned him for a year because he
tested positive for two or three times
and it's like you throw it away.
I mean granted he needs to be smarter,
but like you're throwing away an entire
medical career because of weed,
like it's crack cocaine,
you know what I'm saying?
It's like it's trying to send a message
to the youth to stay away from the
illegal drugs.
Reagan all over again trying to rule off
of fear.
It's fear,
man,
let's not based on reality.
The reality is if you were to legalize
drugs,
period,
you can regulate it and that way you can
do it in a controlled environment and
that way you don't have all of this.
I mean that's what they do with the
prohibition of alcohol.
Legalize it.
Well,
that's also what they're doing right now
with an opiate.
Pills.
I mean oxy cottons are not illegal.
They can be prescribed.
They just have to have a doctor
prescribes this ridiculous.
It is pretty crazy.
well,
it's really crazy when people realize
that marijuana helps pain relief as much
if not better than all that stuff and it
doesn't have any of the addictive
properties and if you do the.
There have been people that have said
that it's addictive and there's some,
some studies that pointed that in
certain individuals,
but I would state that those people
probably addicted to fucking everything.
I couldn't.
I just don't call it physically.
I don't get how marijuana is addictive,
it just doesn't make any sense.
I've smoked pot every day for years.
Then I'll take like a month off and
nothing.
Not an ache.
A pain,
not a no shakes,
no nothing.
Just you just don't have it.
It's like drink orange juice then don't
drink the orange juice.
No.
Really nothing there.
Nothing happens.
I'll get it,
man.
I was,
I'm,
I'm not like a heavy smoker like that,
but like,
um,
like a,
a,
had on a saturday night when I ain't
going nowhere.
I'm all set up my pipe and my,
my second.
I'm going to watch a great movie.
Why not fall asleep?
Yeah.
What the fuck is wrong with that?
I don't get it man.
And meanwhile you can get percosets or
get drunk as hell and ruin your liver.
Yeah.
I got,
I had a nose operation.
They've got my deviated septum fixed and
this dogs began to nothing.
They told me it was bad.
It's people fucking complaining about
everything.
I remember before I got tattooed people
like,
oh my god,
patches are so painful in the first
tattoo.
I was like,
that's it.
That's the shit that everybody's
competitive,
man.
Shit hurts.
I always wonder,
right?
Not,
not saying like not playing tough guy,
but I really wonder what pain feels like
to other people.
I assume that I know what your pain is
like.
Right?
But I don't know if that's true because
why does,
why do I like certain foods and other
people think it tastes like shit.
Yeah,
and something's got to be different.
It bothers me too.
That's got to be different.
Like your taste buds.
It's not just simple like a.
I can take it.
I think there's a.
I think people will experience different
sensation.
It kills me how people don't like spicy
food.
Like I love spicy Food.
They make little kicking it.
He's like,
oh,
why would I want to burn my mouth?
I'm like,
oh,
why wouldn't you?
And maybe I just like a little bit of
pain every now and then.
Well,
it's not a,
it's a,
it's a kind of a sensation more than
it's a paint sorta.
No,
no,
no.
It is.
But it doesn't hurt to you,
but it doesn't hurt like have you ever
had a habanero pepper?
That's what I'm saying.
Do you know what I have in the morning?
I drink bone broth with habanero sauce
in it to fuck.
Yeah.
Why?
It's good.
It's good for you.
Okay.
Bone broth.
Both good and good for you.
It tastes good.
Like beef bone broth.
And I put some.
Put some habanero sauce in there.
See that's,
that's the.
You deep into that nutrition?
I can.
That's great.
I'm telling you,
it's like,
it's like a delicious tea,
like a warm fluid.
Sit down and have some bone broth.
Dude,
you would like it.
I'm telling you.
I'm open man.
there's a place down the street actually
that sells it.
The California.
So what kind of bones?
Chickens.
Really good.
Turkey's good.
You can taste it.
A different kind of guy.
Yeah.
Chicken is probably the best tasting
bone broth.
Jamie grease spot in New York.
I went to called bravo broth.
Yeah,
they like my grandma's do,
but it was just like,
it tasted like chicken soup,
just the water,
the broth,
whatever.
They just boiling bones.
That shit is brand.
I've never even heard of people drinking
boone's.
It's pretty recent.
I mean not really mean people
been doing it for a long time,
but it's pretty recent as a fad around
here in particular and there's a place
out here,
I think it's called sunlife organics.
The joint that cells bone broth and they
add,
they'll add a little hot sauce to it and
that's where I got the idea.
I was like,
ooh,
I like it.
And so then I buy bone broth,
buy it in bulk,
bring it home.
I have like at any given time I might
have 40 bottles of bone broth and
refrigerator that's been entered.
You know,
she's great.
I never even as it made his way to Texas
yet.
What about bone marrow?
Do every bone marrow.
Oh man.
Never had a bone before
in any aspect.
Well,
and a lot of fancy restaurants,
they sell bone marrow and what they're
doing is they're taking the femur of the
cow.
They saw it and then they slice it down.
The middle peter going crazy.
Then they cook it,
the bacon in the oven and there's like a
gelatinous fatty substance in the middle
that's incredibly nutritious and
especially like these days where people
are on these real high fat key to genic
based diets are all the rage.
A lot of people are eating bone marrow.
Show them some bone marrow.
Young jamie,
they don't like that.
So you'll get that and a lot of times
people see that like with a little
toast.
People like it with toast,
but you just take the bone marrow with a
fork and scoop it out of that,
that the dark stuff in the center there,
scoop it out of there with a fork and
just slurp it down.
I love it,
man.
If it's on the menu,
I fucking order it every time I got to
try this man.
This shit is.
What about organ meat?
You eat organ meat like from actual
liver heart and that's the way to Oregon
either.
Man.
I'm from the inner city man.
So I'm not that culture with the uh,
with the pallet man.
Well that's not even.
I've been to,
when I was a kid,
my grandmother used to cook that.
Live it.
yeah.
It's contrast to the city.
So.
Well I think it's one of those things
were poor people aided initially because
they didn't want it to go to waste.
Like we're wealthy.
People would eat like the finer cuts of
meat.
Like philemon,
yon,
you go to a restaurant.
I'll have the full,
a medium rare.
But um,
you know,
people would shy away from things like
liver and they do think that that's.
But it's real good for you,
man.
I heard people eating it and you eat the
chitlins too.
Oh yeah.
I'll eat that.
Christ.
Do you ever have a menudo with the tripe
in?
It does a joint.
ThAt's I gotta tell you,
take you to this place,
jamie.
There's a legit joint.
I will never say the address because Ins
will show up and they'll fucking
heartbeat.
It's not a single person in their eating
or working there.
That's illegal,
but it's so good.
It's so mexican.
That's menudo.
Menudo.
Menudo is they like to have it on
saturday and sunday.
I've heard of it.
What is it though?
It's a soup and it's a soup with a bunch
of different jazz in it,
but see that stuff in the middle?
That's tripe.
That's all cow stomach.
That stuff that looks like waffles too.
Like that.
That's the interior of a cow.
Stomach it.
Take that and boil and chop it up at.
Damn.
It is so delicious.
I know you think like,
I'm not eating that.
I'm telling you man.
And they.
It's supposed to be a cure for a
hangover.
She looks gross,
man.
I mean,
I'm not judging the taste.
I'm saying it looks terrible.
I'm telling you,
if you just try it and it was gross.
Put the uh,
the bather on it.
Pop a little bit.
I know they do that right.
That's always drives me crazy when they
put like a piece of celery on your
plate.
Am I supposed to eat that tower?
What's?
Yeah.
What's this?
Garnish with parsley there.
See that might look gross,
but I never had it,
but I've had it so many times.
It looks amazing.
You experienced with the motto,
man.
First time I heard it was in boulder.
This is joint in boulder called pupusas.
Is this just,
it's crazy because it's in boulder,
Colorado,
like what kind of mexican food they're
going to have in boulder,
Colorado,
so it makes things out there,
but it a mexican right by say I grew up
in albuquerque,
New Mexico,
so it's just south of New Mexico and to
me new mexican food is better than like
mexican food real because it's,
it's different.
It's like,
it's like smothered in the chili.
They have chili's hatch.
Green chili is real famous for.
Um,
and so it's,
We'll see Colorado New Mexico have this
debate over who started.
I don't know who fucking started it,
but it's good as hell.
What's more prevalent in New Mexico?
Think right?
It's like growing up.
yeah.
But like you hear people in Colorado,
but I had started here so I was like,
man,
you got It.
Whatever
man.
I don't know,
but I mean,
green chilies and New Mexico are
synonymous.
That's like one of the things.
Yeah,
that's what I grew up on.
So like when I,
when I left,
um,
you know,
I went to high school in san diego and I
left and I like ordered something with
green chili on it.
It was not to Chile.
I was accustomed to when I was like,
what is this?
Like an order mexican food.
It was like what I looked at as like
texmex yeah,
was just not the same and I was
disappointed to say the least,
but someone needs to talk to Donald
Trump for the kicker.
All these mexicans out,
you're gonna fuck up the entire.
He tripping.
It's crazy stripping.
But it's scary because you just give
these people look if you give people the
green light to start rating people and
catching people when they're dropping
their kids off at school,
which is some of the stuff that I've
been seen in the news.
I don't know how much of it as happening
or what's happening,
but when you're making it dangerous for
people to get an education,
you're making it dangerous for kids to
get educated.
Right?
It's crazy.
The shit that gets me,
man is like the majority of trump
supporters are like christians.
Right?
And if you look at jesus's main
messages,
like love thy neighbor and Mexico is our
neighbor.
Yeah.
I don't understand the disdain,
like I don't understand them.
If they do the right thing,
that's what I'm saying.
Their paperwork come over here the right
way.
The way my granddaddy did.
Your granddaddy got on a raft,
you piece of shit.
You know the grand daddy,
anybody came up with the mayflower,
didn't have any fucking paperwork.
It's crazy.
But for some reason,
like none of those facts matter.
Those people like I don't,
I don't.
I don't
understand that man.
All that turn the other cheek shit and
all that.
Some faggot.
True that jesus wrote about back in the
day before they understood that faggot
shit was.
People get mad whenever somebody said,
how come every time you talk about trump
supports use a shitty southern accent.
Oh,
well maybe because he'd get upset.
Maybe I will keep doing it now.
Yeah,
it's a weird time,
man.
It's a real weird time.
I fucking,
you know,
I have some weird ideas about
nationalism and boundaries and stuff
like that because I think that America
is more of an idea than it is a place.
I think America as an idea is a great
idea.
I think it's amazing to have this one
place where there's like a,
there's probably more creativity and
more innovation in this country and more
music and art,
more,
more fascinating things happening in
this country than almost any other
country.
I mean,
there's great things happening
everywhere.
Don't get me wrong,
but I mean this is a hotbed of
creativity and innovation and art and I
think that's what makes me proud to like
to be an american.
If I was proud,
I'd be proud of like all the people that
came before,
all the people that were here,
all the,
you know,
all the neil degrasse tyson's and jimi
hendrix and all the fucking greg,
you know,
lenny bruce and richard pryor and all
the art and comedy and writing and
history and all the science and
mathematics and all the great shit
that's been accomplished in this one
area.
It's amazing.
It's not a border,
it's not like a line in the sand.
To me it's more like an idea.
So to me,
the idea always been about people come
here because they want to do better,
so you're trying to stop people from
doing better and they're like,
well,
they gotta they gotta fill out their
paperwork and they got to do it right
the way our grandparents did know,
our grandparents didn't do it that way.
It was easy to come over here.
Back when my grandparents came over,
my grandparents came over on a boat.
They came over from Italy and they just
got on a boat.
It was fucking easy.
They got to ellis island.
Sign here.
All right,
everybody's good.
Go to work,
but now you know,
you say it's.
You got to make it harder for people to
come across,
but it's almost impossible.
If you want to immigrate from Mexico,
if you're a poor person and you want to
immigrate here from Mexico,
good fucking luck.
Good luck.
It is not easy.
It's not easy to come here from fucking
Canada.
I've had friends that have tried to come
here from Canada.
Yeah.
Try to get a green card or try to become
a citizen.
Holy shit.
Is it hard?
It's a massive process.
Like I,
I have a friend,
a good friend of mine and his daughter,
um,
met a guy in Colorado and she came down
here and just got a new boyfriend,
like,
I'll stay with you in Colorado.
She cannot work because she's from
Canada.
Well,
because,
you know,
I guess they just assume like,
oh,
you're from that patch of dirt.
You're not allowed to work over in this
patch of dirt.
And that shit,
man,
it's crazy.
She's a normal functioning shot,
terrorist.
She's educated,
she's smart.
She talks well like,
why can't you just work like everybody
else could work getting work at jamba
juice.
Nope.
I said it's paranoia man.
It's like people just are afraid of
everything and granted that
all real threats,
you know what I'm saying?
But it's like you can't,
I just don't feel.
I just don't believe in living in that
fear.
No.
It's just a constant state of hypnosis.
Nationalism,
you know,
and it's team.
It's a team mentality but not a team
mentality and a positive sense.
And a team mentality and an exclusionary
sense like you're excluding all these
other people from joining the team.
Like,
well if they all come over here then
they're going to ruin our quality of
life.
Are you sure?
I'm not.
I'm not sure
man.
National nationalism is.
It's one of the worst things actually.
I don't,
I don't like it at all.
Like I,
I'm,
I'm super proud.
I love America.
This is a dope place to be,
but like I'm not,
I'm not like,
oh fuck your country over my country.
Like it had never hit me.
Like my pride isn't,
isn't like that.
And my pride is just like,
it's dope to be from here and I enjoy it
here.
But like,
eh,
I don't have any disdain towards any of
the country.
I just don't.
Well,
you know,
what fucks me up,
it's that team mentality.
You could break it down to the macro
level because people in houston don't
like people from dallas.
You know what I'm saying?
It's like it gets goofY.
I mean,
dallas and houston might as well be
Mexico in America.
I mean it reallY might as well.
But you tell it's big though.
It's weird,
but you're from.
You're from houston,
right?
No,
you live in houston.
I lived in houston and dallas might as
well be in a fucking civil war if you
talked to half the people,
they don't fight like,
oh,
you're from dallas,
motherfucker.
Let's do this.
It's not like you want to fight,
but if you tell people that you're,
you know,
you live in houston or you love houston,
they're from dallas.
Like fuck.
ExactlY.
Did they get weird in austin?
It's kind of like the middle ground.
Austin like,
well hey man,
but it's kind of cool,
relaxed,
hippie brother tries to,
hey guys,
don't fight.
Let's just be cool here in Texas.
And then you got weird spots.
So they're like,
odessa.
You might as well be mexican,
I don't know.
Dust.
So you're trying to pretend you're not
mexican.
I've never,
I've never made it out to any of the
small,
small parts of the Texas
border.
I've,
I've had a friend of mine who lived a on
what is directly across from juarez,
el paso.
They said that one of the buildings that
he was at,
he got shot,
like got hit with a bullet from someone
involved in gang warfare on the other
side of the border like they were so
close to.
Or is thAt a bullet from war as hit one
of the buildings?
He was in a.
What is happening?
Well that should know the region right
there.
You dumb.
Fuck that.
We got to kick them out of our country
please.
It's so funny arguing people,
they just have talking points and they
don't ever think about anything.
Well,
you know what?
They.
You can have talking points and you can
have points and their points are okay.
They're not
to Be discussed and debated,
but when people get so many solid
opinions on certain things,
the problem is that nobody has rocks out
of the pens because they're usually.
Their beliefs aren't based on any kind
of a foundation and the research.
It's all based on somebody that says
something.
Right.
Usually on podcasts or television that
they agree with and all of a sudden your
opinion becomes a fax from sean hannity
type shit.
Yeah.
I've never really watched him and um,
I,
you know,
it's one thing if they weren't human,
like if,
if you had like some neanderthals to
lived in Mexico and they were dangerous,
they like to eat people like,
look,
we gotta we gotta fucking real problem
falls coming over here eating us.
But no,
they're just folks,
they're just,
they're just folks that people
dehumanize people all the time.
I may say I saw it at my sport and you
see it,
I mean in,
in every aspect of life.
Yeah.
Well,
how about Israel and palestine?
Yeah.
That is the craziest shit ever.
I was watching this documentary on the
history of Israel and palestine.
What is it?
Because I've been looking for one.
Oh man,
I'm So,
so trying to do to quite a few of them
out there.
I need,
I need to find one because I don't think
a documentary honestly is comprehensive
enough.
I'd really good book like I've tried to
read up on it and it just gets deeper
and deeper and deeper.
It's almost impossible to unravel.
These people have been,
uh,
at each other.
Like Israel is this one strange area,
right,
because you have this jewish state
that's surrounded virtually on all sides
by arab states and and they hate Israel.
Israel hates them and they're trying to
push people out and then the
palestinians are claiming that this is
their land and they were pushed out and
I used to do this bit and people just
get so fucking mad at me.
They used to get so mad at me because I
was.
I said that I was watching tv and I was
watching this thing about the
palestinians versus the israelis and I
go,
there's a brown skinned guy with dark
curly hair throwing rocks at a brown
skinned guy with dark curly hair holding
a machine gun.
And I'm like,
you guys look super fucking similar.
This like watching a tennis match
machine.
The williams sisters.
I mean this isn't like the africans
versus the nordic people.
Like you could clearly tell like one if
you've seen an african person and you
see someone from China.
Okay,
well I see you guys look real different,
but like israelis and palestinians there
fucking so close until they talk.
But you say that to people,
they get so mad at you.
We have a very different.
Okay.
I can't really.
I don't.
I think there's a difference,
man,
kind of,
but it's similar enough that they could
pass for each other,
you know,
things.
I think that's debatable.
Debatable.
We got the,
uh,
the,
we're going to figure it out.
That would be search type pictures way
people,
excuse me sir.
Turns out the panel of students or one
pound heavier on average.
It's just fucked up when you see that
kind of a dispute that you don't think
is ever going to get settled inside your
lifetime now.
No,
no,
it definitely won't be an hard time.
Like it's a state that was established
in the 19 forties.
It's still there today and there's still
hotly under debate and you're wondering
like,
see that.
That's why I,
I'm so confused about.
And it's such a hot button issue too
because it's like as soon as you bring
it up,
he was like,
hey,
uh,
you know what I mean?
And I'm just honest inquiry,
right?
Because I don't really know enough about
it.
So I'm trying to read up on it and it's,
it seems to Be super,
um,
uh,
there's little red flag that raised it
to me.
Then during this last republican,
before trump was president,
one of the republican debates were all
of them on a panel,
lIke they were just like,
I'm super privileged Israel.
I'm so pro Israel and all of them that
I'm pro Israel too.
And I'm just like,
why are you so proud?
It just made me think lIke,
and that's what made me start digging
into it.
And it's like,
I mean usually,
uh,
I don't agree with a lot of what the
republicans say and so it just makes me
think what is the underlying issue here?
And that's christianity.
That's a big thing because the pro
Israel people,
the really heavy duty evangelical
christians,
they really truly believed that inside
their lifetime jesus is going to return.
Right.
And he's going to return to Israel.
So.
Oh yeah,
there was a vice documentary on it.
So that's what I mean,
it's probably deeper than that.
It's probably the reason why.
Yeah,
well it's hard loan ally that's non
muslim in that area.
How did they,
how did they become our outlier?
Because we armed the fuck out of them,
but I know that had to be a reason
though,
right?
Well,
I think we see the way they live their
lifestyle.
I mean there's very many reasons I'm
simplifying it,
but it's much closer to ours.
Then these arab states,
I mean women in Israel,
first of all,
they have all the rights that women in
America do pretty sure other than the
fact that they have to go to the army,
they have to,
they have mandatory army service and
it's a lot of people think would be a
good thing for America.
Mandatory military service because it
would make you understand like this
about sacrifice and discipline and also
that you're a part of this thing instead
of saying,
you know,
we should go over there and kick their
ass like whose we are you doing that?
Well you're going to send your kid.
Exactly know.
I mean that's,
that's a lot.
I mean,
I think we'd have way fewer in her
interactions with other countries if
everybody's kids had to go over there
and do it.
People would be less than it would if it
wasn't a voluntary thing.
If it was an involuntary thing,
we'd be much more judicious in our use
of military.
When you brought up that a dehumanizing
thing.
It's to me when when people bring a war
and stuff like that,
it's like they just throw out these
numbers.
Like those Weren't humans that died.
That shit boggles my mind.
like if that was your mother or your
father,
sister,
like maybe maybe people do feel like we
as he gave his life to a cause.
But like for me it's like man,
at the end of the day I was fighting for
dirt and nobody owns.
You can't take it with you and your box.
I don't understand it.
Well,
not only that,
it's impossible to fix parts of the
world.
Like if you look at it like what's going
on right now in Syria,
how many people are gonna have to die
before they figure out that part of the
world.
I mean that like if you were there
you would just want to get the fuck out
of there as quickly as possible because
everybody could die at any moment there
and any moment anything could happen.
Missiles are slamming into apartment
buildings.
It's like you just gotta get the fuck
out and that can happen in this world.
Like the world conflicts can escalate to
the point where they're just nonsensical
where you can't make any sense of it.
You just gotta get the fuck out.
Like if you were living right now in
Syria,
I mean you would say,
you know,
part of me wants to fight for this.
This is my city,
this is my country,
this is where I'm from.
And parties like,
fuck
this Greece,
I will.
Why don't we go to journal?
I don't got that any man.
I just,
I just don't like.
My pride runs from my inner circle and
my family to my community and after that
it's like,
what are we fighting for?
You know what I'm saying?
Unless you're stepping in my,
my home base,
I don't understand the point,
man.
I don't got that emmy.
Well,
when you get to something like world war
two,
when you get to something like the nazis
were trying to take over the world,
that makes sense.
Pushing into Poland and you go,
okay,
we got a real problem here.
That make sense?
It's crazy.
Fuck.
Might really like what's going on.
North Korea,
North Korea scares the shit out of me.
See?
And that's what I don't understand is
like,
so you got a juggernaut country like
that who's basically waving a flag
saying,
I don't fuck with you,
you know,
I'm going,
I'm all by myself and we don't really do
anything.
We don't really.
Well,
the problem is they do do things and
they do know.
They know that what I'm saying we to
them you mean?
Yeah,
well we're looking at them now.
I mean those apparently this is all
rumor and not who knows what,
what was really sad,
but apparently that's the main thing
that Donald Trump was informed about.
When obama left office.
One of the things obama said like this
is the biggest issue is North Korea.
These is a maniac that kim jong un is a
fucking murderous maniac and he's
running a military dictatorship so and
he's got prison camps and they've got
these people that are born in prison.
They're born prisoners,
they're their slaves and they killed
them.
They do whatever the fuck they wanted
If you don't listen to those people,
if you don't listen to the military,
they can kill you.
You have no rights.
You have to do with you.
I mean,
people were put in jail because they
didn't mourn hard enough for the death
of his father.
Yeah.
They were given jail sentences,
hard labor,
because they didn't try hard enough.
We.
We played it recently.
There was these people.
It's like the worst acting you've ever
seen.
The people on the street,
while kim,
when kim jong il died and they were just
wailing,
just fallen down.
They couldn't.
They couldn't cry hard enough and they
had to do it.
They had to do it publicly.
It was so nuts.
See,
that's what I need to do,
man.
I need to.
I'm.
I'm pretty up on my domestic politics.
I'm kind of out of the loop on foreign
policy and I'm out of the loop on
everything.
I just talked.
Shit.
I watched a few Youtube videos.
I read a few articles occasionally.
A book crosses my eyes.
It's good to know.
Most of the time I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about.
It's too much to know.
That's true man.
That's.
That's definitely true man.
Like if you wanted to.
If I.
If I really sat down with someone who's
a real expert
on foreign policy,
you know what you really get you.
You really get a guy who knows a lot
aBout one area.
if a re a real expert on foreign policy,
say if you were talking to someone who's
an expert on China,
like international relationships with
China,
the international relationships with
it's probably super complex,
is probably so much to know and so much
to understand it so much to go over like
the,
the for you to be a real expert.
How could you fucking know all that?
All right.
How could you possibly know all that?
That's one of my problems is like once,
once I.
Once I want to learn something,
I got to learn everything about it.
Like I said,
I learned conceptually.
That's good though.
Yeah,
there's bad though because like I have a
one track mind so like it'll consume me
for three months
because that's how people get good at
things.
So that's probably why you were a great
football player.
It's probably the same thing.
I mean that's obsession becomes
obsessive.
Yeah.
But I feel like that's the case with
anybody who gets really good at things.
You get just completely nuts about it,
get absorbed with it.
That's true because if you just casual
about it,
but the dude next to is obsessed with
it.
He's going to get better at it,
going to get better,
you know,
just no doubt about it.
Snow,
no way around it,
man.
You know?
I remember when I was a training jujitsu
heavily,
I would still,
and I still had jobs and stuff,
you know,
I was busy,
but I would meet these young kids.
They're like 17 and 18.
They be training two times a day and
lifting weights as well,
and just constantly going over new moves
and I was like,
this dude has no way I'm catching up.
There's one they have that.
When you have that real true passion
obsession,
that's the only way to hit real
excellence.
That's true.
I always tell kids like,
man,
they'll tell me like,
um,
uh,
you know,
I want to do this,
I want this,
I want to be at this,
and I'm just like,
you have no idea to discipline it takes
in order to be the best at your craft.
Like people don't understand that shit.
Like people will look at like,
um,
the,
we,
we kind of take,
take for granted the,
the top of the top of the top of,
of anything really,
right?
We take that shit for granted because
you're looking at a finished product and
you don't see the story behind it until
it hits the news,
hits the,
the show that you love.
Watching what the people who are best at
what they do have been doing it for.
Like a great example is like,
I'm a comedy right?
So like,
this pisses me off when people say like
overnight sensation about a comic,
right?
But then you dig into their background
and they've been working on like 18,
20 years they've been doing gigs or
they've been going on shows and they've
been just kind of harnessing that craft
and then all of a sudden boom,
they blow up and people are like,
oh,
overnights,
bullshit.
Comedy looks so easy.
It does.
Because you're just talking like you're
talking right now.
I'll just do it in front of a
microphone.
Say funny shit.
You know how to talk and make a bicycle
club.
And a lot of ways it's kind of been kind
of like running like,
oh,
what is your running back?
Can run.
He's got to catch the ball to catch a
ball problem would be the greatest ever.
I'm the best at running.
How do you,
how are you the best?
I'll just add man.
I just my mentality,
I know I know how to do it,
but I don't know how to catch that ball
and run.
man.
I like this last like two or three
months.
I've been,
uh,
I've been going to the,
to the laugh factory and comedy stores
and stuff or a comedy venues and uh,
I just,
I just have a whole new respect for
comedians.
that shit is so hard,
man.
It's like you go to a venue and people
were just sitting in that chair,
like,
yo make me laugh.
It's the weirdest shit ever.
And you guys do it.
Like it's,
I got so much respect for comedians.
There's a weird gig.
Well,
Not only do it with chuck out our
material every two years.
Exactly.
That's where I'm at right now.
I'm like four months in.
Right?
That's hard dude,
because I'm working on shit.
That's like,
a lot of it's on rubber legs.
It's not so super solid.
yeah,
some of it's solid.
I would have asked.
So.
So what's the process?
So it's like,
do you think of jokes?
Like do you sit down and I mean,
I,
I'm totally ignorant to this.
So like,
do You sit down and you'd be like,
all right,
I'm going to write funny shit today for
like an hour or like,
or just randomly go throughout your day
and
this is
a body man,
that's the brazos.
Now I'll be tAlking about some talking
about some crazy shit.
That's the main process.
No,
that's part of the process.
The other part of the process is sitting
down,
um,
uh,
maybe a sit down,
thinking about things like maybe just
sometimes I'll watch a documentary to
watch a documentary and sometimes I'll
watch it because I go,
I bet there's some material in this
subject and then sometimes I'll just sit
right in front of my computer or
sometimes I'll sit with a pad and a pen
and a piece of paper or sometimes I'm
just in my car and an idea you don't
want.
One of the things that gets me,
it's,
it's tough to do because I like to,
I like to listen to shit when I'm in my
car,
but I find out when I don't listen to
shit wanna just have the,
the,
the sound off.
No radio.
I'll come up with ideas because my mInd
is forced to think and then I'll write
those ideas down and then once you wrIte
those ideas down,
any idea that you write down,
it was like a seed,
you know,
and then you try to water that seed and
you try to get It to grow into something
that's viable and half of them don't
ever grow.
At least if you're lucky,
have like,
I try,
I try to write some jokes and be like,
let me see what these people go through.
And it's just like,
you know where to start.
Yeah,
it's hard.
It's crazy.
It's just a matter of starting,
like knowing where to start is hard,
but the key is to really just start.
And then once you start then you sort of
chop it down like you start,
you write a bunch of shit down and
you're all this nonsense,
but maybe there's something right there.
And he'd take that little piece of It
and then I'll put that on copy and paste
out on another thing.
And then I'll start from scratch.
So like I might write 1500,
2000 words and then out of those words
is a paragraph there,
maybe something in that paragraph and
then I'll pull that paragraph thrown in
somewhere else and then maybe I'll go
back over that other 2000 words that I
didn't,
you know,
take and I'll do it with fresh eyes like
the next day and maybe a new thought.
It's that process that we don't that
like
I just,
I just have super respect for a man
because it's like,
it's,
it's a fun job though,
man.
Like,
look dude,
I've been doing it for like almost 30
years.
You can't play football for almost 30
She gave up
nothing.
He goes,
you're so glad about that.
Your mind gets a little fucked up.
Your mind can get fucked up.
Your mind gets fucked up wHen things
aren't going well.
It's,
it's always,
it's,
it's so intriguing to me how like
comedians are really kind of like the
narrators of our society and they kinda
just,
they,
they find a way to like explain that
shit.
That's,
that's normal everybody.
And to look at it and see how silly is
this shit.
You know what I mean?
And that's why.
That's why I love.
I love comedy is such an art to me man.
So you're thinking about doing it.
I want to do it just like as a bucket
list thing.
Just to try and say I'm not,
I'm not trying to be like a touring.
I just want to like retirement.
So I'm just like,
I'm looking at shit that's interesting
to me.
I was like,
I'm gonna try it man.
This comedians,
they get real upset about that kind of
shit.
Really?
Yeah.
They go,
these guys think they can do what we do
not,
but that's what I'm trying.
But I don't feel like that at all.
My,
my feelings totally opposite.
My feeling is you could,
you definitely could definitely do it.
I appreciate the smart guy.
I'm pretty sure you're funny.
I think you could do.
I think anybody could do it if you're
funny.
If you're smart and you're funny and
you're honest,
you'll start.
Everybody starts from a different spot.
Like there's some people that are just
naturally funny.
I met some people like my friend eddie
bravo,
I tried to talk him about doing standup.
He did it a bunch of times back in the
day,
but he's just naturally funny.
He just says funny shIt.
He sees funny shit and I was like,
dude,
you're a comedian.
You just never did it.
like you could be hilarious because
he'll fucking have us client some nights
just ridiculous shit,
but it's a matter of starting off with
one step and then you learn how to walk
and then you learn how to run and then
you're going to learn how to run better
and then you got to figure out the
moves.
I mean,
it's really the bunch.
There's a whole path to it.
It's whether or not you're willing to
take that path because that path might
take 10 years.
That's what.
That's what everybody says,
man,
I love good sets before those 10 years,
don't get me wrong.
It's not like 10 years.
Then finally I got a laugh.
Laughs all along the way,
but I sucked.
You know,
definitely kind of take you awhile to
find out who you are as a,
as a comic and then that's the other
thing though.
You do a special.
Like I just did my last netflix special
bro.
That shit with.
So comedy.
Oh thanks.
The dolphin.
Oh my god.
No,
that's a true story.
I fell out,
man.
That's a true story.
I was so high.
I was watching those dogs.
I'm like,
how come nobody ever catches dolphins on
official?
Oh fucking smarter than you,
man.
We're filling with water people.
I started really,
really made me think.
I bet it was gds.
oh,
thank you.
That was really something that I really
thought about.
I wrote a blog about it way back in the
day.
I think it's called hello stranger.
Alright.
About that.
That very subject.
That's what I love.
Comedy man.
Like yo,
you,
you find a way to like encapsulate the,
the weirdest and most brilliant thoughts
that we have tried.
The problem is once you do one every two
years,
one of the things that happens is you
run out of shit to talk about.
Right?
Right.
Oh,
you don't have necessarily anything to
talk about,
but what I liked to do then when I feel
like stagnant is I like to not do
anything,
just let my brain like reach its
balance.
Just come back.
You have ever just went on stage wIth no
materials.
winged it only on these shows that we
do.
We have these shows called stand up on
the spot.
My friend jeremiah watkins put on the
show where you actually wing it to the
audience of suggestion so the audience
will yell out like a a bushes paintings
because George Bush paints.
Now you're seeing his painting not seen
as this nice.
Some of them are weird.
Yeah.
Not bad.
Better than me.
That's dope man.
I mean,
I
don't know criminaLs or whatever,
but he can separate.
You kind of have to.
Right.
I was trying to explain that to somebody
about bill cosby and I was like,
It's a very complex situation because
he.
Yes,
he most likely did those things that
they're accusing him of crazy.
Pretty likely.
Pretty like,
I don't know.
I wasn't there,
but it seems highly unlikely that that
many people,
and there was always that rumor,
there was always that rumor,
but he also was a brilliant comedian who
was.
He was a rapist.
It was like he was a brilliant comedIan.
Alleged rapist,
man.
You got to got to say like,
like,
oh jay,
right?
Oh yeah,
fucking murder a man.
But like two could play.
That was nice.
Was nice man,
but I don't.
I don't understand how people can't
separate your performance from you who
you are as a human.
I never understood that.
Did you see the recent thing where his
doctor said that if the understanding of
cte was available back then,
they might've used that as a defense as
awful.
It's crazy.
Well,
what's really crazy is that doctor is
essentially saying that jose oj did it
even though he was acquitted.
Yeah.
He's in jail for.
That means jail for stealing and shit.
I know in that funny.
He might get out soon.
Yeah,
I know who he is though.
I thought it was like december.
I think he has an opportunity,
I think in october,
but I think it's one of those things
like a parole thing because I think he's
in jail for 25 years,
but I think he's been in jail for nine
and he might get released,
but is that what it is?
It says october,
but here's the thing man.
You kind of know that they're not reaLly
jailing him for that.
Not really jaylin him for that.
Which is weird that the the.
Because he was trying to get back his
stuff,
right?
Yeah.
If people don't know the story of oj,
I believe someone had stolen some of his
autographed merchandise or as
memorabilia and he was trying to get it
back and someone in the room with them
had a gun.
Like the guy he went,
we held.
They held them hostage.
They pulled a gun out.
I think they had it out,
but I think what it was was they went
into the room with the people and lock
the door and nobody's leaving,
which is
like a kidnapping charge.
Can't kidnap people.
Man.
That's crazy though,
that we're supposed to believe that.
That's what kept him in jail for nine
years.
So you definitely know because if you
watched the judges deliberation when he
was going to jail them,
you could tell it was like we deserved
the.
Yeah,
you deserve this.
Like just throwing the book.
If that was your first offense,
you might not even be in jail.
Yeah,
I kinda believe they're not going to
give him parole on the.
I don't know,
man.
I just got to hold.
The whole thing was so weird to me,
man.
There was a,
um,
there was a woman who was in the manson
family who,
uh,
was one of the people that murdered
Sharon Tate and she was up for parole
recently and they were talking to her
and there were,
you know,
asking her why she did it and how she
did it and she just sort of explained
that she was a part of this call to and
that they had really kinda like
convinced her that this was the way to
do it and this is the way to live.
We have to fight these people and
they're all on acid.
They're all fucking freaking out.
And she was trying to explain it and
they're like,
yeah,
no parole
explaining how she stabbed her and the
woman was pregnant too,
just to have the baby.
It's just not,
it's just crazy that some people go to
jail for life,
for stupid shit.
Like smoking pot.
Like there's people that are in jail for
selling pot in there,
in jail with life sentences.
It must have.
I mean,
I guarantee you people have died in jail
for marijuana sales.
Guaranteed.
But It's still of kind of possible that
if you tell somebody you could get out
early,
man.
It's a depends on who you are actually.
Oh,
it must.
But uh,
it also depends on the overcrowding of
the state,
right?
Like someone was telling me that a
Louisiana in particular,
uh,
during new orleans during katrina,
rather like when new orleans was getting
flooded,
my friend was like,
dude,
they had what they would call,
you know,
like instead of felt they would call it
misdemeanor murder as a joke because
dudes would be murdering guys and they'd
be out in really short sentences because
they just haven't heard about.
I heard about that.
Yeah,
see if you could pull up that term
misdemeanor murder neW orleans,
because like this guy was joking around
about it and I didn't.
I never looked into it deep enough to
know whether it was telling the truth,
but I had heard it more than once.
They were just letting people out.
Murderers.
Yeah,
I think,
yeah.
New orleans often accuses
institutionalized missy misdemeanor
murder.
Article seven.
Oh,
one of the criminal code requires the
state release.
A defendant who has not been charged
with a crime after 60 days before
hurricane katrina,
a few hundred people per year were
released under article seven slash 11,
so someone who committed murder,
they wouldn't be charged inside of 60
days because they probably overburdened
and they would let someone out.
Holy shit,
it's there.
The big easy to get away with murder
metal filler article.
Wow.
Yeah,
so some spots it's just so fucking
chaotic in a way with the people in
jail.
He's in prison for petty offenses.
Drugs,
still they are violating our rules.
It's ridiculous.
We have too many rules.
You know,
if that many people are in jail for
violating rules,
does that necessarily mean that many
people should be in jail or does it mean
we have too many roles,
but you got to figure out like if
someone is a victim of these situations
is so as soon as someone's a victim,
then that's probably where we should
serve and protect.
Right.
I don't understand how people,
um,
view our laws as the gospel.
I mean,
certain things obviously are
demonstrably bad for society,
but some shit like this is such a,
there,
there are things that could be amended
that just needed to be.
Man.
What would you change?
Like if you could,
if you could geT into the judicial
system?
Uh,
well for the drugs there is no way that
they should be first.
Right?
That's one of the big ones.
The first one.
Um,
what else?
oh no ma'am.
I have to deliberate on now.
I mean the,
uh,
the prison industrial complex as far as
a locking up people of color has been a
problem in our communities for years.
Uh,
I think that the policing needs to
change.
I think that,
and I think if you're going to look at
other,
I mean we juSt got done talking about
this yesterday,
but I think if you're going to look at
other parts of the world saying they
need our help places like Afghanistan
where we've sent massive amounts of
troops and resources into Iraq in
particular,
right?
I think if they put that amount of money
to figuring out how to build back these
impoverished communities,
I just,
instead of just leaving them the way
they are.
Yeah,
that's bad.
Figure out some way.
I don't know what the fuck it is mean
because you'd have to like go through a
couple of generations to get rid of the
cycle of the negativity that some of
these people have experienced growing up
with all the crime and all the crime.
PoverTy all the time.
Yeah.
that's right there together.
And then also the momentum of that crime
and poverty just,
it's hard to break loose of and it
doesn't help by putting them in jail or
worse,
it
becomes a mentality.
So like I always found a significant
like kind of growing up like in the
inner city,
like so like violence is so normalized,
right?
So it's like you like,
like being,
like being who you like being tough on
the streets was like the good thing to
be growing up and like,
so if you've heard of somebody like it
says committed murders or,
or beaten up people or whatever like
that,
like,
and this is fucked up,
but like that,
that mentality it reverberates through
some of the neighborhoods is like that's
cool.
Like that's what you want it to be,
not you don't want to kill people but
you want it to be,
to have that tough label and that,
that mentality and that site,
their psyche.
It's infectious.
And you sent me,
so you see it with,
with,
with music and entertainment,
it's,
it's something that's embedded in our
and our culture.
And I started way back then but it's
still hEre and it seems like it ramped
up when it became a big part of a
popular rap culture.
Like when I was a kid,
there was not,
you didn't hEar about nearly as much
gang violence as we did after,
like nwa came out when you started
hearing rap music with a lot of violence
in it.
Oh no.
Yeah.
That they were the originators of that.
Yeah,
for sure.
But the violence in the neighborhoods,
they really didn't start with the rap
era.
Started with the crack era,
which the rat very came out of the crack
era.
So it all came together.
Yeah.
That's good.
That's a really good point actually.
And it's,
you know,
what else is a really good point too,
is that,
that all sudden it glorified it and it
made a lot of wannabes and that's true.
Um,
and I mean it's,
it's unfortunate but.
And that's why I love art.
Art is always a reflection.
It's a mirror of society,
right?
So unless you go to that lacma place,
you ever go that la county museum of art
and never seen him don't go.
I appreciate that.
It's one of the modern places where they
have like a,
a box on the ground.
It was like a plexiglass box.
I go,
what is that?
Is that that's the actual art,
the plexiglass box,
because the box represents what you want
it to be.
The art looked down at the box.
It's really brilliant actually when you
think about it that way because the box
ended up.
Man,
that's a fucking box.
It's a box.
It's on the ground.
You know what that is?
That's a dude who you buy weed off of.
That's his coffee table,
right?
You go over his house.
He said,
hey man,
I love this fucking amber plastic coffee
table.
You got bro.
Yeah,
dude,
I fucking chop my buds up on this band
is a nice tent though.
Yeah,
it's not bad,
but the fact that it was roped off and
that it was an actual.
It's an actual piece of exhibit.
That's a piece of art.
Fuck you.
I would never have got it.
Looks like a fuck.
You know?
Someone else that's funded.
It's funded.
That's like,
isn't it like who funds that?
Who funds?
Isn't that a big part of it is public.
It's the la county museum of national
art.
Oh,
that's amazing.
Because what it represents a spaghetti
and we all liked spaghetti.
It makes you think about your child.
That's crazy.
You know,
like that.
What did you like string hanging from
the ceiling?
Yes.
Okay.
Well,
you know what,
it reminds me of like string hanging
from back when I was a kid.
When you had to rent porn,
you got to go through beads,
like to get to the porno section.
I was in my era,
man.
I'm way older than umass.
I was there when it all went down.
But see everybody,
like a lot of.
A lot of black moms and grandmas have to
beat
mexican mothers to wiser.
A rock there.
Is that an rps?
The la lacma thing?
Well that's an a rock and it represents
rocks.
Not appreciate how they got the rock.
No,
I don't because this guy could have paid
for a fucking teacher.
No bunch of shit.
We just hired a better
group of.
Of coaches for a football team.
Dog.
You do?
I liked that one.
Well that's why it's there.
You know why?
Because the world's all different,
like hot food tastes different to me
than it does to some folks.
It must be.
Some people looked at that and it goes,
it's hazing and they got this feeling.
I could just look at him.
I can appreciate somebody pulling that
rock there.
Somebody might've even looked at that
box on the ground and got that feeling.
I'm not denying.
They'd have to explain that one to me,
whether they'd be like with this is what
it is.
It's like everything is so defined.
Okay.
And when you read a book,
all the words are in the order.
I mean,
even if you're thinking about what this
person wrote,
they wrote it.
Okay,
so they're forcing this into your mind.
So this artist is giving the opportunity
to.
This is giving you the opportunity to
put inside that box or to whatever,
put whatever signification,
whatever,
whatever important significance of that
box.
It's all up to your interpretation,
man.
She has a point.
I don't know why she.
She,
she might.
She's transitioning.
She seemed like she was transitioning
while I was talking.
I was like,
I lost my girl.
I started out as a girl and then I got
annoyed and I became a gay guy for a
little while at the end.
That was
the old lady who smoked cigarettes
are very different.
Right?
Like you can go gay guy or lady was
spoke cigarettes.
There's that.
See,
this is where we put the stuff.
Lacma.
There's a video two.
There's a video that was playing at
giant screen and it was like people
playing catch with a ball thrown into
trip to like slow motion with like a
volleyball catch.
It was so fucking stupid.
I was like,
what are you doing?
This is,
you've got a video of a guy throwing a
ball to another guy.
Got to be able to express yourself.
I kind of feel them now,
man.
And that you uh,
what's,
who's funding it?
Who's funding it?
Did we find out the ball thing?
Oh,
the la county museum of art.
They're probably mad at me right now.
It's so snotty.
They're good pub man.
So snotty.
So many people that were snoball
taxpayers have last name.
Oh,
well
I disagree with your fucking schools in
la.
Think about what teachers get paid.
Think about cops lacmas most reliable
patrons,
10 million taxpayers,
and I guess people can sign up and give
money if you like,
being around on the weirdos.
But here's the deal.
Those weirdos,
man to them.
It's cool when they go there,
they like it,
you know,
I'm a fucking idiot.
It just because,
I mean,
are you a weirdo?
I'm aware I'm an idiot because I don't,
I don't know how you looking at that
plastic box in the ground.
Don't appreciate a bunch of people that
like it.
I got a question for you man.
Okay.
So,
um,
I've been a fan of you for a long time,
right?
so what?
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Appreciate you.
Appreciate what,
uh,
what Made you make this switch from like
being a moon landing denier to like
crazy if we didn't.
If you don't know,
I don't think we're crazy.
No,
this is.
This is my take on it.
Absolutely.
I don't know enough about astrophysics,
about space travel,
about the science.
That's the work that's been done about
how to get a rock rocket to the moon and
back.
I definitely don't know enough.
That's rocket science and I've looked at
a lot of very compelling documentaries
that explain why they think it was
hoaxed and they'll show you some footage
and you can look at some of the footage
and it looks fake as fuck.
There's some footage that to me looks
really doctored.
There's some delay yet to this day.
Some guy would.
When you ever seen ones where it looks
like they're on wire,
so to astronauts are on wires.
I have.
There's somewhere.
There's a video where they look at their
own trampoline there,
bounced around on trampolines.
The physics are different in different
videos.
This is where it gets weird,
like the physics are different from the
apollo 11 moon landing.
We see them waddle around on the surface
of the moon.
They moving it like half speed and then
you see them in other ones like the one
where they bounce around the area,
like they're moving different during the
same thing,
but it looks different.
The first one was very grainy.
They showed it on a projection screen.
It's just there's a.
There's a couple different
possibilities.
One possibility is it just looks weird
because it's on the moon and your brain
is trying to interpret it and your
brain's going,
well,
that's fake because you don't really
understand with one six ers,
gravity really does to a body of.
That's one possibility.
Another possibility,
which has been shown to be true is that
some of the stuff that they passed off
as being legitimate photographs of space
travel was actually test runs where they
blacked out the background and pretended
that they were in space and there's one
really clear example of this is Michael
Collins,
Michael Collins,
who was a guy who was a board apollo 11
and jim and I 15.
There's a photo of him in the middle of
a sea of.
What is it when they walk around outside
the space,
these facebook.
Why does that seem like a bad word?
It's like spacewalk,
like if it doesn't seem like that's the
official title is the middle of a
spacewalk probably something more.
A little more syllables.
Yeah,
something slicker.
Anyway,
so he's doing the space walk and he's
got this harness on is holding onto this
thing and it was apparently just an
image that had already been published,
have him in a training exercise and they
blacked out the background and flipped
the picture upside down.
So same exact photo,
same exact photo.
I mean people have lined it up and
switched it over.
It's the same photo.
It's just been edited.
So the one on the left was them
practicing how to use these.
I don't get that.
The harness is some sort of a thing that
you're hanging onto it.
I guess it moves them around a little
bit.
They were trying to practice it on the
left and the right.
They just pass it off.
But those are publicity photos.
Right.
Alright.
So you got to go.
Well,
okay,
well who approves the publicity photos?
It could easily be just some idiot who
works in the publicity department who
didn't marketing and who didn't think
they had enough photos from the moon
that we're good of spacewalks.
It's probably insanely difficult to take
a spacewalk photo.
So does that mean that they faked the
moon landing?
No,
but it means that people fake things.
So you've got to throw it,
like,
got to be really objective and looking
at that.
Okay.
So people say fake things.
They definitely filmed a lot of the um,
the training exercises that they did
have the moon landing.
They filmed a lot of shit.
They definitely did.
If that is already been proven that they
took this fake photograph and they tried
to pass it off as a real space.
Right.
It's entirely possible that some of the
stuff that they filmed,
they made out to look like they were on
the moon when they were not.
But does that mean they didn't go to the
moon?
No,
it doesn't.
And so when I was saying it proves that
they didn't go to the moon,
I,
my critique of myself is that I didn't
look at it objectively because I wanted
one conclusion to be true and I wanted
that conclusion to be that the moon
landing was fake.
So I looked at it and I Was and I was
saying to myself,
okay,
did I come to this conclusion because
there's a lot of evidence that shows it
to be fake or have I seen a lot of
evidence that looks fake and does that
mean that they didn't go to the moon?
No,
it doesn't.
There's,
there's a bunch of different
possibilities.
There's a ton of different
There's also the possibility that
whatever photographs they took can get
severely damaged in the radiation of
space and it was really difficult to do.
Right.
That's possible too.
And that they decided somehow or another
that they were going to pass off these,
that they actually did go and they're
deciding they're going to pass off some
of these fake videos.
So there's a bunch of possibilities.
The possibility that it looks fake
because I'm dumb and because I don't
understand anything about the physics of
one six earth's gravity and it just
looks weird because it's shitty film in
1969.
That's possibility number one.
Number two is they fake some things.
Or number three is they didn't really
have good footage because like you
couldn't take film through the airport,
remember that like people would go
through those right radar detectors and
you're filming get jacked and they
wouldn't,
weren't responsible,
you didn't use film.
But I know people that might,
you know,
I have friends that are photographers
and um,
my uncle's a photographer and he would
tell me,
you can't send the film.
Like if you have like you've taken a
roll of film and the awesome,
I don't know,
I don't know what the fuck they did,
but I know that some film has been
damaged or maybe it's an urban myth.
Maybe would find out.
Film got damaged by a,
those radar things in the air force.
X-rays,
ex-rays theory.
I could appreciate the mindset though of
looking at your opinion objective,
lee,
and saying,
am I tripping?
It's look at the facts and say,
I'm just not really sure.
I think that's the problem with people
today when people in period is that
they're afraid to say,
I don't know.
YoU know what I mean?
They're super afraid.
It's like,
to me,
ignorance is such a gift,
like it just gives you an opportunity to
learn some shit if you're humble enough,
like don't assume you know.
Even the shit I feel like I know I still
feel like I don't know.
Yeah.
Well that seems.
You have a very healthy ego for a big
young fucking super athlete.
It's fucking fucking football man.
Like no,
but I'm saying he goes very healthy.
You have a really good way of looking at
things.
I think that's the right way to be mad
at.
You can't be married to,
to like ideas and opinions like that
because they're not you,
but we think that they are.
They're like an extension of us,
so we want to win these arguments.
That's why we want to be right.
I think it gets real scary when you want
to be right,
and then you're willing to ignore
evidence that might show that you're
wrong.
That's how I felt about myself and by
the way,
if you wanted to see if you wanted a
conspiracy,
that's a good one.
That seems like it might be possible.
The moon landings.
One of the best ones,
and this is why it's so attractive
between 1969 in 1973.
He's still on the fence about this,
huh?
No,
no,
not at all.
I'm not enough.
I'm on the,
I don't know shit fence.
That's where I lived,
but between the facts on this side.
I'm with you though.
They sent,
I think it was seven mission.
Six of them were successful.
The only one that wasn't successful as
apollo 13.
right.
They sent these fucking people around
the moon.
Two hundred 50,000 plus miles out there
and back,
but ever since then all they've been
able to do is get people into near earth
orbit ever since then,
like the highest anyone's ever gone.
I think it'S 400 miles,
so they went from 260,000 miles all the
way to the moon and back to 400 miles.
Everything iS like inside and they've
never gone through the van.
Allen radiation belts.
I never got into deep space and return.
They haven't done that since 19,
60,
1973.
I thought,
and I could be wrong,
but I thought it was because of like
funding could be like,
because you know we not lacmas got
funds.
Show me,
show me how that makes sense.
You don't want to fund space travel.
You want to fund that fucking acrylic
box or box editor by the way.
That's perfect.
It is great.
One,
I don't,
I don't think that I know whether or not
we went to the moon,
but I'm telling you that if you wanted a
juicy conspiracy to get excited about,
I've looked into.
It's the best one to get excited about.
I lost all the data I see because I see
like,
you know,
you go down to youtube wormhole and you
start watching barry sanders highlight
and then I'm looking at a jfk being
Michael Jackson and it.
But like I,
I,
I just don't see what the motive would
be like what is the fucking cold war?
First of all,
we wanted to beat the russians because
we were in a race to see who didn't get
to the moon and here's one of the things
that we do know for a fact.
The russians faked
a bunch of shit.
They faked a bunch of footage.
Yeah.
Yuri gagarin,
who's the first man in space.
They had a video,
might be an expert on this man,
but there.
Well,
I studied this.
I debated a guy who was a really nice
guy,
but I'm phil plait,
who's a bad astronomer?
Astronomer.com.
Okay.
And um,
he,
he was a lot of thIngs he wasn't willing
to admit though that were unfortunate
because maybe he could have convinced me
more if he was.
And one of the big ones was that warner
von braun was a nazi.
We,
they hIred a bunch of nazis to,
to run the space program.
It was called operation paperclip and
what operation paperclip was,
where they took a bunch of nazi
scientists and relocated them to the
United States.
We lost some of them to Russia.
Russia scooped up some of them.
But when we ended the world war ii and
nazi Germany collapsed,
we went in and took the scientists,
will,
wernher von braun was the head of a
rocket factory in,
in,
um,
in berlin where these to hang the five
slow as jews in front of the rocket
factory for all the other workers to see
warner von braun,
the simon wIesenthal center said if
wernher von braun was alive today,
he'd be punished for crimes against
humanity.
This is news.
No,
wernher von braun was a straight up nazi
and this guy was not willing to admit
that,
you know,
it's like,
well,
you know,
just because someone's in Germany.
No,
no,
no.
He was a nazi.
Were there any actually killed anybody?
Maybe had to be a nazi.
I mean,
we're not saying that.
Look,
if you're fucked and you're in this
neighborhood and that it overcomes the
entire neighborhood,
you want to keep your family alive.
So you put that thing on your,
uh,
your jacket sleeve.
You put that swastika on and you see a
guy like everybody else.
Maybe you're not really a nazi.
Ideologically,
maybe you're not seeing your heart,
maybe just trying to stay alive.
That's entirely possible too,
but he was a nazi.
He was a fucking nazi and they had
slaves that were running rocket
factories in berlin where they were
figuring out how to make rockets.
I said,
brandon,
I got.
I need to.
Yeah.
Operation paperclip,
cold war president truman authorized
operation paperclip in august of 1945.
The us army secretly admitted 88 german
scientists and engineers to help the
development of rocket technology,
including wernher von braun,
arthur rudolph,
and her buttocks struggled.
Her berkus,
her roberta's hubertus ubertis.
That's a great name.
It's not a great name.
Bring that back.
If you have a fucking stud kid.
It was like one of the strongest men in
the world.
His name is hugh bertis.
My you.
It
was named after announcing,
so that was like something in the debate
that guy was not willing to admit,
which made me even more skeptical that
he was right about the other stuff.
The other thing was that they like and
moon rocks that they've collected from
the moon have turned out to not really
be moon rocks like a bunch of them for
sure have been tested by scientists and
they found that these rocks are from
another planet.
There was,
there was a rock that thEy gave to
whoever's the head of holland and it was
personally given with a plaque by neil
armstrong,
buzz aldrin,
and Michael Collins,
and it turned out to be petrified.
Wood moon rock given to holland by neil
armstrong and buzz aldrin is fake.
It's a moon rock given to the dutch
prime minister by the apollo 11
astronauts in 1969 turned out to be a
fake.
So they were giving people pieces of
petrified wood saying,
this is for you.
We went to the moon.
God bless America,
growing 300,
8,000 euros.
Now there's a bunch of possibilities.
Okay,
let's just be honest about this because
this story's from 2009.
It's entirely possible that between
1,969 that.
Well,
this is.
There's multiple sources,
but that's the telegraph.
That's a legit news source for sure.
What I'm saying is that it's entirely
possible that someone stole that moon
rock and replaced with that.
That's possible.
That's possible,
or as possible.
They just had some fake rocks.
Here's the thing.
Bill clinton had a fucking.
He had a quote in his book in one of his
books,
I think his book is called my life,
and he had a quote about the moon
landing and a story about him having
this conversation with a carpenter under
carpenter said that he didn't believe
the moon landing.
He goes,
them television fellers they can make
anything look real,
and he said,
this is a quote and bill clinton's
fucking book.
He saId,
back then I thought that guy was a
quack,
but after our crank,
whatever crazy person,
but after eight years in the white
house,
I was wondering if he wasn't ahead of
his time.
Oh wow.
This is a guy that was the fucking
president of the United States and he's
talking specifically about an old carpet
telling them the moon landing was fake,
and then he says,
I wondered after eight years in the
white house,
if that guy wasn't ahead of his time.
Causation,
correlation.
Yeah,
no,
look,
could be bullshit.
Yeah,
One hundred percent.
It could be just a good story and I
think that's the thing about conspiracy
theories is like they lead you on all
these dead end chases.
Oh yeah.
What's weiRd is that trump's a
conspiracy theorist is a lot more
adjectives.
You can add on to that.
Yeah,
but the conspiracy theory aspect is
interesting as far as I know.
he's to want to know about.
You have those.
That's probably what the first shit he
did.
He probably sat down.
What's going on with the aliens?
Where do we hAve an interest in it?
Where do we stand?
You would get It.
I do.
I don't think we have been visited.
Come on onto.
Let me tell you something.
Okay.
You become the president.
President foster.
How are you,
sir?
Would you,
uh,
would you like to do today?
Uh,
I like to find out if there's fucking
aliens.
First of all,
man.
Oh man.
First day on the job,
I'm like,
take me to the.
I need to know
what the fuck we're up against.
Are they real?
I need to know.
There's no way I would need to know if
you knew that there might be a
possibility.
They knew you sat down with all the
apps.
I definitely had to ask you.
Fuck ya know,
if you heard rumblings of you and mike
pence were in the elevator.
Um,
mr [inaudible] would be my vice
president.
Okay.
who would you vote for?
President and I am not mike.
Mike,
mike pence.
But yeah,
we own elevator.
Who would it be?
You don't want to be vice president?
No shit bro.
That's means you get shot at a sam
harris.
Man.
That's a good one.
That's,
that's my,
that's my girl.
I would let him be president though.
Have you had him on you a bunch of
times?
Really?
Yeah.
Bunch of times.
He's on a week.
two was crazy.
I'm subscribed to you on youtube and the
shit keeps kicking me off and I don't
know what's going on with that.
Uh,
that's,
uh,
the government tries to control me.
It can't handle the truth.
Man.
Shit pissed me off.
I don't know,
man.
I don't.
I think it's just an algorithm issue
because we also have an issue with them.
We retweet.
I'm like the,
there's an automatic tweet that youtube
does and it sends out that we're going
live that we're broadcasting live.
Tweets it out to people or sends it out,
but it sends it in a fucking spanish.
Was it like it was,
it was the dark today.
Today it says I started a live stream on
youtube,
but the last was,
yeah,
it was like dutch or swedish or a bunch
of weird languages that I didn't,
I couldn't speak.
I said,
interesting man.
Yeah,
my,
for some reason,
um,
my google shows up in my inbox,
this is my name,
like in german,
like the inbox thing and says just in
german,
I'm like,
I have no idea because you got hacked
some german,
godly man.
Yeah,
man,
I don't got shit to hack though.
Hm.
Yeah.
So the long answer of your question,
that's,
that's where I stood on this whole moon
landing thing.
That's why I came around to thinking in
a different way that was way too
convinced that I was.
Right,
right.
I'm like,
I'm convinced I was right,
but fucking real low levels of
understanding of any of the sciences and
stuff.
Yeah,
I think that's the problem is as a
society,
we're so scientifically illiterate,
you know,
and that,
that,
that causes so much room for speculation
and you're kind of um,
kind of prisoner of,
of,
of people who are masters of their
crafts,
you're kind of a prisoner to their quote
unquote agenda.
I don't want to put that,
that bad of a term on it,
but you're kind of prisoner of that
because we don't have,
we don't have any,
any,
any choice,
but to take their word for war,
to pursue it yourself.
Right.
To learn about what they're talking
about yourself,
but if they're right or not.
Well that's,
that's absolutely the case,
right?
BecauSe you know,
that's the case in almost everything
else.
Like that was always like a real problem
with martial arts was there was this one
dude who had all the information and you
didn't know and then you would listen to
them station and we're like,
whoa,
is that true?
And you would think it was true.
But now like there's videos you can
watch on youtube of like some crazy kung
fu.
Dude that's just talking nonsense.
He doesn't really know how to do
anything.
He's just got some crazy thing about
cheap power and if you don't know,
you think this guy is real.
But once you know you go,
oh you motherfucker.
So like someone can pull
the wool over your eyes about that.
They could just easily do it with any
kind of science
rocket traveler.
And see that's what really got me
interested in science.
It was like you fall,
especially with this climate change
shit.
So like you start reading the articles
people give you why it's not real and
then you go and follow the source.
Like that's where I really learned to
start filing the sources at all the
articles because it's those sources that
you lead to the main source of where the
information actually came from and it
usually leads to like a scientific paper
published in a journal and they're
fairly easy to understand because it's
very with the math and the in the,
in the actual science is probably won't
understand,
but like you can get to the break down
how they got to that conclusions and
that's what I can appreciate about is it
actually gives you a uh,
an understanding.
Yeah.
With citations shows you each what we,
each study was all about certain things
on it.
Yeah.
That's super important to be able to
look at that stuff.
And obviously they've got a lot of math.
I got a lot of times though,
man,
I do it.
It was biology.
Sometimes I do it with like,
um,
different discoveries event.
I got obsessed with this chimpanzee that
they found the Congo.
It's called the bondo ape.
And I start reading as much as I could
read about this chimpanzee is one
chimpanzee in the Congo.
That's way bigger than other
chimpanzees.
It's enormous.
It's like a six foot tall,
300 pounds.
Pansy.
They walk upright.
The huge,
enormous chimps.
Not.
Okay,
well they have two different kinds of
chimps to like the locals called him a
tree beaters and that they have another
one,
I think they call them the ground
dwellers and tree beaters.
I think that's what they call them
because the,
these chimps are so big that they nest
on the ground,
like gorillas.
They don't even bother climate trees
jesus,
but it's just,
they're limited to this one area.
They have a crest on their forehead,
like a gorilla where it's a high crest
of the bone.
So they have these big massive plates of
muscle that they bite down with.
and then they have like this gorilla
crest.
Regular chimps don't have that.
RIght?
So when they first found skulls from
these things,
they were confused.
They were trying to figure out was a
hybrid between a gorilla and a champion.
But then,
um,
did you,
where'd you get that?
That looks like that looks fake.
It looks weird.
That looks fake,
but see that one?
Okay,
go up to go push your cursor above and
then go slightly to the right.
Go all the way to the right.
Keep going.
No.
The bottom level.
Bottom level.
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
Were those those pictures right above?
Just go straight above.
Now.
Go to the right,
to the right,
to the right.
One more.
Next guy.
That picture.
Sorry.
Yeah,
just make it bigger.
That was taken by a guy named carl.
I'm on.
He's a swiss wildlife photographer and
he became obsessed with these bondo apes
in,
I feel like it was somewhere around 1996
and he moved to the Congo and he stayed
there for quite a while trying to take
photographs of these really elusive
animals,
but they got that one on a camera trap
and it's a fucking huge chimpanzee.
There's another line that is dead that
they shot
and it's uh,
these two guys hold it by the.
That'S one for sure.
But that's a pretty bIg one,
but there's that one right there.
That's a way bigger one.
They shot that one at the airport.
It is fucking huge and it was shot
somewhere,
some near some airstrip,
so that's like one of the big pieces of
evidence other than now they have bones
and they have a scat samples and tissue
samples so they know they exist but
they're really,
really,
really hard to get to because the Congo
is like almost as wide as the United
States and it's just filled with fucking
crazy shit that can kill you.
Everything everywhere you'd go is just
monsters.
Just everywhere.
Fucking crocodiles.
Wild man.
And the people that are dangerous as
fuck too.
Yeah.
But this area is particularly dangerous
where because it's so.
It's really difficult to get them.
But I got obsessed with this god damn
thing,
so I was reading everything I could read
about that.
All right.
I have never been.
No,
I've never heard of it.
Never fell in love with the apes like
that man.
I'm fascinated by apes,
man.
I feel like we're so close.
We're just,
we're just the hair,
but I just took.
So to me,
there's just,
when you look at them,
I,
I got super high once when I went to the
zoo and hung out,
I was by myself,
sat in front of a chimpanzee cage for
like a good solid hour man.
Washington's champs.
I was on an edible.
They sent you back and I remember like
watching them interact with each other,
thinking like they're,
it's like they're like people but not.
They're like people,
but wAy more brutal.
Way more.
Certainly way less paths.
Airy,
kind of airy.
Not too long ago I took my kids,
they love it go.
But um,
I don't remember what kind of primate it
was,
man,
but he was just hanging on the cage and
we was walking by and he was just kinda
like following us.
And I was like,
I felt so weird man.
Like it was almost like he was like,
what's going on man?
How y'all doing?
Like he wanted to.
It was the weirdest shit.
I wasn't even on the edible.
Yeah,
it's weird when you see their nature
come out there like us.
You ever seen one?
There's one where a little kid was like
pounding our chest in front of the
window and patch
himself after he cracked it.
I saw that was he cracked the glass man.
Y'all need to be in there,
man.
Yeah.
They shouldn't be in there.
I don't.
I mean,
the only.
The only thing that I could see that
would make sense why you want to keep
them there because if they're so
endangered that you need to keep them
alive in these contained environments
before they figured out a way to
reintroduce them back into the wild.
I don't know,
man.
It's thinking as part of the
evolutionary process.
It's like 99 percent of all species have
died off.
Yeah.
It's part.
It's part of.
So you think we should just let him die.
Let him die.
Whoa.
That's deep.
It is.
I know that people want.
People don't want to hear that,
but it's just showing me what everything
dies.
You know what's fucked up?
What if we're killing?
What if we're letting these gorilla stay
alive,
but really if we just let them die,
they would evolve into something way
cooler.
That's.
That's what I would have said,
don't know.
That's the shit that I've been thinking
about dog.
It's like,
all right,
so the evolutionary tree of life,
right?
Like we have fucked it up.
I don't want to say fuck it up because
it was definitely a part of it,
but it's like we're directly influencing
it and I just wonder what,
like where's it gonna go from here,
like what?
All lifeforms do that though,
but not like,
like we've kind of escaped because
natural selection is all about survival
and it's all about,
uh,
that's basically it.
Just adapting to the environment to
survive.
And now it's not about that anymore.
We don't,
we don't adapt to our environment to
survive anymore.
We,
we create our environment.
It's different.
It's definitely different.
But it's still adapting to the
environment because instead of using
like physical tools aNd attributes,
we figured out a way to do it mentally
where we create things that can alter
the environment.
What I'm saying.
So like still what it signals is to me
is a new form of life.
Like it's a physical structure like
structures and things that we're using,
whether they're um,
household appliances or electronics,
all that stuff is evolving as well,
like it's all happening.
Right?
And so that's the new,
like the new ability to adapt.
It's all coming out of these things
instead of coming out of us.
We're putting our work into that.
But that's what I'm saying.
I,
I'm,
I'm not sure about,
I don't think we've ever seen this part
of evolution a arise like this before.
No,
we haven't not like this now.
And it's crazy to me.
I don't like,
I'm just so like I love that live in the
time that we do the information age and
all that shit,
but like I still want to be able to live
like 300 years from now to see where
we're at in society.
I would love to see that.
Yeah.
Would love to see it too.
But I'm scared.
I want to see it happen though.
Like this now I like this.
Now I'm fascinated to see what this,
what's happening here.
I am too,
but like,
like I,
I want to see ai and I want to see,
um,
I want to see life on other planets.
I think ai is going to turn out like
blade runner.
I think they've run it.
I don't,
you never saw that.
My one thing,
so I saw blade.
He never said I saw that too.
I don't know.
Blade runner,
blade runner is harrison ford movie
about these artificial people that are
so difficult to tell that they don't
even know they're artificial.
People know.
Well,
they're gonna they're doing it again.
Right.
Who's going to be the blade runner guy
now is harrison ford in it.
Again,
that would be crazy.
Rutger hauer gosling and harrison.
Ryan gosling.
Yeah.
Good move.
But it was um,
two great science fiction movie,
man.
Ryan gosling can act till polish it off.
It's,
it's a really good movie,
man.
I got to check him out.
Still it holds up to.
It's one of those few movies that holds
up.
I got to check him out.
It was probably like about the,
I mean the movie was made,
I want to say in the nineties,
eighties,
82,
82.
Yeah,
that was before my time before
everybody's time,
but it seemed.
I think they were like saying it was
like 2030 or some shit like that.
Two years.
That is so funny.
They always think that it was going to
be way more crazy than it is crazy.
We got to have a boys man.
Yeah.
But you know,
what they never expected is the craziest
thing,
which is the internet.
They thought that our,
our evolution would term would be like
people would fly around in cars like
they had flying cars and shit.
That's what they thought was gonna
happen and then they would have
artificial people that you couldn't
distinguish like a surrogates.
Well,
they were the rutger hauer character was
the most fascinating one.
I check this movie out fucking movie.
That's my favorite shit.
And there's that girl that was.
What was the name?
Shawn?
What was her name?
She was a huge deal for a long time.
She was a huge movie star sean.
Goddammit.
But
she was one of those people,
one of the first people that we saw,
um,
and the younger generation,
Sean Young to like sort of crack from
the pressure of startup success,
just woo woo.
Crazy.
Yeah.
That fishbowl.
The fishbowls no joke.
Right?
It's,
it's a weird thing man.
He said weird,
funny shit.
a man.
So like I'm having dinner.
I got my kids and stuff.
We hAd the table and just a couple of
years ago.
And um,
I mean houston is,
some guy comes and says,
hey man,
big fan man.
Can you take a picture of my baby?
And then puts his baby on a table.
Well what the fuck?
Like it's the weirdest shit ever met.
And people do weird stuff like that all
the time.
I suppose baby on a table on the table,
I'd take a picture of my baby and I'm
like,
baby off the table.
That's so weird.
Yeah.
I mean you probably get all the time
people do weird shit.
It was.
So that's a weird one.
Click here to take a picture of a band.
People like,
people like,
oh,
I like hold my baby.
They take a picture.
I'm like,
if I drop your baby,
do you know what kind of shit I'd be
like,
I'm not holding your babies.
What is wrong?
Why would you want me to hold the baby?
Has no clue who I am.
Like doesn't care.
People are strange.
Maybe once milk people are fucking
strange.
I think the the.
At least you were a young man when you
experienced that would freaks me out.
It's child stars.
I couldn't because it's accused like you
never get normalcy.
No fucks you up.
You,
you.
There's no normal.
However you never get it.
I know you're,
you're,
you're born famous.
Like if you're famous when you're seven.
Telephone.
Do you remember before seven?
I don't remember.
For 74 is when I really started like,
okay,
I'm in the world.
jamie,
you got any memories or when you were
seven?
Few of like being at a babysitter and
like maybe.
So if everything from seven onwards.
Fame.
It's a funny story.
My mom to this day dot d,
she denIes it.
So I have this vivid memory.
I was three years old and I used to have
a babysitter right across the street
from my apartment complex.
I used to to africa to name,
but one day I come into the room and
there's paramedics.
I didn't know they were paramedics,
but there's paramedics and she's
sitting,
she's laying on the couch.
She was pregnant all the time and I see
her.
Her belly split open.
Well,
I saw csection at like three or four
years old.
My mom does not believe me to this day.
She's like,
there's no way you saw csection.
I'm like,
how do I notice like how,
how do I.
And I,
I didn't say anything at the time
because I mean,
how did I know that didn't happen in
every babysitter place run?
No,
I did,
but I saw it as a kid.
I was very bad.
They should have.
I'm not sure why they didn't take me out
of the room.
Like,
that's disturbing man.
But as a good fee to see this,
it's just information,
right?
Like nobody got hurt.
It seems like a crazy thing,
but it's how life gets into the world.
Like if I was like cutting a belly open
and I see a three year old,
I'm like,
you should probably leave the room just
in case.
I doN't know what it did to me.
Right.
I don't know.
I wouldn't encourage a three year old to
do it like that.
I know it'd be good.
Oh no,
it's good for the kid.
Didn't know.
He needs to leT them know what I'm
saying.
Get up,
quote billy.
Don't be a pussy.
If you're going to make this place
contaminated.
Some girls do it just to keep their
pussy tight.
Are you serious?
Yep.
I'm not taking any chances.
So selfish.
Mm.
Or they're just having a national
woman's.
They look.
They're like,
listen,
the kids going to be fine.
Debby son was born by csection.
He's fine.
The kids find that is crazy.
That's a real thing.
Yeah,
it's a real thing.
Yeah.
Aura.
There was a thing that you've
advertised.
Jody is used to have a joke about,
about vaginal rejuvenation.
You know,
they used to talk about that all the
time.
That was like a.
Because it became a thing where they
could type that baby back like so.
So to know everything else bro.
I bet if you have a big thing and you
have to make a small thing involves
cutting,
cutting and stitching and I would
imagine that would be.
That's a weird.
That's a weird place to get cuddled.
But I couldn't do it.
Ooh.
Yeah.
And then what happens after that?
What if it's too tight when it doesn't
work anymore with dr.
Fucks up nonsurgical.
Thirty minute treatment.
Thank god.
It's quick.
It only takes 30 minutes.
That's what everybody wants.
I can fix your pussy at 30 minutes.
Where do I sign a better Man?
What do I put my credit card?
A quick be better.
There was a 30 minute procedure.
Tightens up your box and girls just are
so lazy.
They don't go.
I don't have 30 minutes,
but
30 minutes tell you have to do.
Are you saying that's not good?
No,
no,
no.
baby baby.
It's amazing.
I'm not saying it's not good,
but you can make it perfect.
Make it purple.
I you fucking around.
Like if there was a 32nd dick
rejuvenation procedure where there was
like a place that you could go and they
can make your dick bigger vice national
rejuvenation flying in,
they would have like
flights out of kennedy that was directly
going there.
Good morning America.
YeaH.
It's a real thing.
Yeah.
Look at it.
I had no idea.
This is my favorite part.
did you know that you age and every part
of your body,
you're talking about old pussies.
They just planted a thought in your
head,
but knew patrice o'neal and say age,
like age,
like bread.
Now like why?
Hold on,
go back.
Don't,
don't scroll down.
Look at the top paragraph here.
female wellness is just as important as
taking care of your face.
What in the fuck does that mean?
I would agree.
Yeah,
but what she's saying,
female wellness.
She's talking about having a tight
pussy.
You got to be a low bit man.
Sell your product and you can't just be
saying,
yo,
fix your box.
Women,
what business are you in?
Um,
female.
What does that mean?
I've tightened them bitches up west side
aesthetics is introducing a
revolutionary technology that
rejuvenates the vaginal area and
remarkably restores women's confidence,
their confidence part of life,
though man,
sex is a huge part of life.
Look at this shit.
Thermiva is a 30 minute nonsurgical
treatment that gently applies radiation
radio,
free radio frequency,
rf frequency to reclaim,
restore and revive feminine wellness
without discomfort or downtime.
Downtime from dick.
Where's the.
Where's the small ones?
The small print that is a small print
like I'm really concerned that while
getting rejuvenated,
I can't take dick.
Oh no,
there's got to be a before jamie.
Go back.
Go back so I could read more of that
stuff.
yeah.
This,
this is crazy.
It increases nourishment to tissues by
stimulating blood vessel production and
increases sensitivity by stimulating
nerve regeneration.
Okay.
That doesn't seem true because I've.
If everything that I've read about nerve
regeneration is it as a very slow and
tedious process now it is like if you
get injured,
right?
Yeah.
So my dad actually had.
We not sure what happened,
but he kind of lost feeling in his arm.
He a pinched nerve.
I think that's probably what it was,
but like it's slowly creeping.
It's way too.
It was like two years ago and it's
slowly.
He still struggles with it,
but you know,
he's slowly getting better slowly as
slow process though.
Real slow,
super slow.
My friend boss route and the former ufc
champion had a neck surgery.
He had something fucked up in his neck
and his arm shrunk to the point where he
calls one arm is baby arm atrophy and
it's coming back now.
Slowly but surely.
But every time I see him like a year
later,
it's like a little bit better.
Yeah.
I mean it's multi,
multi year process and this guy was ufc
heavyweight champion and he was a bad
motherfucker has prime and it got him to
the point where it's.
And it doesn't even grow back.
So you telling me they just blast your
pussy with some radiation and those
nerves are going to go back.
Why wouldn't they take that nerve pussy
thing and put on boss rutan's arm?
You know,
I have a female wellness on my own.
Yeah.
Well,
It was embarrassing,
but to get my arm back had to go to the
female wellness center,
get I had a.
I had a stick in the vaginal
rejuvenation machine.
Hey,
whatever works though.
Yeah,
but if it did work,
that's probably one of the first places
they would use it on a lot of things
that we could use.
Female wellness or just call it female
wellness is hilarious.
Female wellness.
Definitely a cool women know what you're
talking about.
If we're talking about like give you
talk about like women's health issues,
you go,
oh abortion,
you know like women's rights,
abortion.
I know you're talking about abortion,
but you see women's rights when it comes
to like a woman's health rights,
reproductive rights.
We're really talking not just about
birth control pills but also about
abortion.
So if you say women's reproductive
rights immediately people think
abortion,
but if you say feminine wellness,
you don't think.
I think.
I think like breast cancer.
Yeah,
that's what pops up in my head.
Yeah.
I would say it is deeper than that.
Juvenile nation,
they're using it in a weird way.
They kind of co opted that term.
Feminine wellness is important,
bro.
It is important.
It is.
Sure.
Confidence is everything.
And if you know you got a rejuvenating
pussy,
this puts a sparkle in your eye.
There is no denying that pep in your
step.
It's just the way she's tried.
I know she got the procedure done.
I'm going to ask her.
Don't ask her bro.
Just get pissed.
So,
uh,
what have you been doing in your spare
time?
You get,
you're a pussy,
rejuvenated or anything.
They will never admit it to the end of
time.
No time.
Mother's pussies.
amazing.
Everybody's putting in my family is
We have amazing pussies.
Then
for this fucking conversation,
deteriorate.
Another word on here for just a pelvic
exam is another word for I just googled
wellness or whatever.
Female wellness exam that popped up and
yeah,
see,
that makes sense.
Like a pelvic examination,
checking you for issues,
not tightening up your box.
I'm scared of that prostate thing.
That's come scary.
Or you already did it.
The finger in the ass.
Checking for a physical.
For physical.
They put a finger mass.
Yeah,
whoa.
Hey man.
Very uncomfortable.
I wasn't,
they just lube it up,
stick it in there.
and I'm dreading it,
man.
It's weird.
People have problems though.
You got to be that prostate problems or
real issue with people like you.
How many people have like ball cancer,
prostate cancer,
and my grandpa,
my grandpa died from prostate cancer.
Cancer scare the shit out of me.
And what scares the shit out of me is
um,
our society,
like what we've created is so awesome.
Like have been in the city is amazing.
Being able to go to a restaurants,
amazing.
Being able to fly on a plane,
go across the country.
Look,
all of a sudden we're in Florida.
It's all amazing.
The food that we eat,
the fact we get food anywhere.
The fact that you can go to wendy's and
just pull right in and get a burger,
but what,
how much cost is that on our biology?
All that amazing stuff.
Like how bad is it to be in a polluted
area?
Like how bad is it?
What life expectancy is actually the
highest it's ever been though it's true.
It's true because people have great,
they have great medicine and procedures
and they catch things early,
the really good at treating cancer,
but what,
how good are we at recognizing what's
causing that stuff?
How much of it is diet?
You know,
how much of it is nutritional
deficiencies in your diet?
Probably think it was the number one
killer is heart disease I think.
Yeah.
I think heart disease,
which is also connected to obesity and a
lot of folks.
Is that the number one retailer?
oh,
cigarettes.
Terrible.
The fact that that's still around and
it's crazy.
When I was a kid,
um,
when I was like 15,
I smoked a cigarette once when my
sister,
my sister's,
she kept smoking for a few years after
that,
but it was a couple of friends.
We just moved into this neighborhood and
I'm like,
I'll try it.
And I was like,
this is so crazy.
Like the fact that anybody wants to
smoke that first pool,
like I felt like I was gonna die and
you're voluntarily and what are you
getting out of it?
You get like a little buzz a little bit.
You get a little bit of a.
That's what people who smoke cigarettes.
I'm like,
well I want you to just smoke weed.
Like you actually get something out of
it.
Like you just sit there and die.
But I felt you get like kind of an
opposite thing out of it because with
cigarettes you get an ah fuck it feeling
like I don't give a fuck.
Who gives a fuck the fuck it.
I've never felt that man.
That's what I got.
I never got this article came out.
Sorry.
Like came out like seven days ago or
earlier this month.
Building near freeways in la.
Not supposed to be within 500 feet of a
freeway.
Just definitely do.
Ellie keeps building near freeways even
though living there makes people sick.
Are you one of the two point 5 million?
Southern California is already living in
the pollution zone.
Wow.
Yeah.
When I pass on the four,
oh five,
and there's those.
Look at this jesus christ.
People there suffer higher rates of
asthma,
heart attacks,
strokes,
lung cancer and preterm births.
Reeks.
Recent research.
Recent research has added more health
risks to the risk.
To the list,
including childhood obesity,
autism and dementia.
Wow.
See that's when you click that recent
research button and see what they talk
about.
Boy.
Yeah.
There's apartment buildings like right
off the four.
Oh five when you're driving towards
santa monica.
And I'm like,
that is like,
you're living right there.
Especially in la man.
Don't go nowhere.
It's just like,
it's just a $15 everywhere man choking
in it.
Do you like living in Texas?
No.
No,
no.
Were you going to settle?
I haven't figured that one out yet.
I was um,
I was thinking around,
I think denver,
but I heard never was super dope,
but I had a buddy that just moved from
la.
I'm from denver to la and he's just
like,
man,
it's just,
he's just dead over there.
I can't.
I got to be alive.
And I'm like,
oh,
it crazy.
I feel you man.
Go to the mountains,
bitch.
The mountains,
not an outdoors do.
It's definitely dead in terms of like
city action.
It's nothing like this out here.
Yeah.
Denver is interesting though,
is denver's had legal weed for a long
time because they,
they basically weren't arresting people
for it for the longest time.
They had kind of said like a state or a
citywide thing that they weren't going
to arrest people when I first came
there,
like I don't remember what year,
but I've been working at the comedy
works in denver for a long time and when
I first went there they were like,
yeah,
we don't arrest people for weed and I
don't want to like,
yeah,
they passed something in the city where
they don't arrest people for weed in the
city.
I'm like,
that's crazy.
But this is Colorado.
Like I thought of colorado's like
cowboys,
like,
well you think of Wyoming,
the republicans and real strict,
but denver was never like that.
It's like a weird.
It's a weird town man.
What,
what's.
I mean,
you know a lot about dishes.
What started the movement in denver to
go towards progression and we.
Well I think the statewide movement of
Colorado making marijuana legal and
being the first state along with seattle
or Washington state rather.
I think,
um,
Colorado people don't like people
telling them what the fuck to do.
That's a big part of it.
I mean,
they're rugged people.
you've got to realize if you can,
if you're family made it to Colorado,
like in the 18 hundreds of whatever,
you got some rugged jeans is that deep.
Oh man,
those people move there.
There's a core group of people that
settled in Colorado during the gold rush
manifest destiny man,
when people came over and it's crazy.
homestead,
get blocks of land and stay on it for a
few years and he can get to own it.
Yeah,
man,
that shit all happened.
And those were the gold rush people,
man.
All right,
right.
I mean,
wasn't that what Colorado was originally
settled?
Wasn't California was right?
California gold rush.
Like why the fuck do people go to
Colorado?
That's what I have no idea.
We'll put google.
When was denver established?
I'm going to guess I'm going to take a
guess.
I'm going to say it was like the 17
hundreds.
Now I'm going to go after that.
Eighteen hundred 50 1800.
18 50 slash 50 18,
58.
Holy shit.
Perfect.
That was really good.
That was pretty good.
And I bet.
Very good.
So think about that.
What kind of gangsters traveling across
the country?
You know,
you had to be a bad motherfucker to get
across the country if you live here,
right?
In California.
The same thing holds true like the
people that first got here,
like in the 17 and 18 hundreds,
whatever it was and at first settled
here,
but then everybody comes in here and all
the actors and it's just the.
Well gene pools water down.
But in denver that gene pools not
watered down.
You've got a bunch of people in still,
right?
The original dna is of just gangsters
who came over here to try to make it in
the wild west.
So that's interesting.
So you're saying the liberalism of the
move from east to west and the,
uh,
the gene pool of not giving a fuck.
That'S interesting.
Yeah,
it has to be that there's definitely
something to it because if you think
about it,
all the,
like the really like there's a giant
group of immigrants in the east coast,
this country.
And there's also like a real hostility
that's almost like ancient on the east
coast of the country that's different
from the hostility on the west coast.
It was like an ancient sort of like
shitty way people get along with each
other in New York.
And you could attribute it to the call
that you can attribute it to the
weather.
You know,
you get attributed to about
overpopulation but on top of each other.
Yeah,
you could.
You could attribute it to that.
I think in both things could be possibly
true.
But there's other spots like you go to
Canada and the weather,
the weather's horrible.
Like toronto is crazy traffic and a lot
of people and they're nice as hell.
I heard.
Yeah,
I went to Canada once.
They're so nice,
so nice.
So I don't know what it is,
but I think it has something to do with
the fact that the original people that
came there or these hard scrabble people
that we're trying to make it by getting
on a boat and traveling across the ocean
to a land that they really didn't know
much about me.
He might've known someone here,
they might've had an uncle or family
members and they were going to try to
settle.
I mean those are gangster people.
You have to be so and then the people
that were sick of those people like,
fuck this,
we're going to keep going and kept going
west.
And then in 18,
58,
they settled in denver.
I mean those were rugged people,
man.
so when you see that city there and that
city is embraced by the rocky mountains,
so you have this constant natural beauty
around you.
It's like a little bowl to it.
I mean it's a bowl and you look out your
window.
Like if you stay in a hotel in denver,
you look out the window,
you're like,
whoa,
you see the rocky mountain and you're
like,
holy shit.
Real clean city to like a super guy was
while I was walking downtown and it's
like they keep it up here.
They do.
Yeah.
It's also like you have to be a certain
kind of person to be able to survive
that winter.
You know,
you got to be the kind of person that
can just fucking tolerate shit and still
show up at work and get things done.
you can't be a baby out here.
You could be a baby.
How you can be like,
I don't like to go out when it rains
because all the oil on the road,
it's like people don't know how to drive
in it.
It's not doing this.
I'm going to call in and I'm going to
say in,
in Colorado they have to go to work on
black ice.
People juSt sliding around on each other
like bumper cars fast,
very fast and the furious.
And you ever hit black ice or driving.
I've never hit black guy just like the
cold.
So I'm one of the whining people getting
out.
While you don't have to like the cold.
This is the thing man.
Especially a guy like you,
you've,
you've proven yourself.
So physically tough.
Nobody could ever say that.
The reason why you don't like the cold
because you're a pussy.
No,
no,
no.
I just don't
like.
Yeah,
I'm definitely not a pussy.
That's what I was fucking.
Definitely.
Not that.
That's what I was a famous football
player.
Pitcher,
right?
I'm not a pussy.
I just not stupid.
I don't want to be cold.
I just don't get to see it.
I also don't like being hot though,
you know?
Well you tell those people,
why don't you just be cold all the time
if you're such a bad ass,
why we're close.
What you need to be warm.
You fucking pussy.
Oh,
sometimes you need to be a pussy,
but right now you know,
fuck out of here.
Like people live in san diego.
Like one of the things that you'll,
you'll talk to you about,
you know,
if you have a bunch of buddies that live
in san diego and they asked him about
it,
like why do you live in san diego?
They're like,
it's never shitty here.
The weather's perfect always.
Why would you move?
I went to high school down there.
It's with part a mission bay.
Oh,
that's nice.
Mission beach area.
So that was the craziest part is la
jolla.
They've got a comedy store out there as
different and they got these mansions
that overlooked the ocean and
everybody's on pills as a whole is like
is like a different.
A different areas.
Too much money,
so much money out there.
There's too much money whenever you get
too much money in an area,
just like nobody knows what to do.
I didn't know what to do.
Yeah,
but they get crazy.
That's.
You start buying yachts,
snorting coke and on the yet.
Yeah.
You're crazy,
right?
I can't do the water either though.
That cornado island,
that's a.
That's a crazy rich island saying this
isn't a white white people and whites.
Usually the case.
White people.
White people go,
let's plant the flag.
Melvin
white sand to go with my wife.
My wife's parents.
Yeah.
That core.
Datto island.
There's a bunch of fucking donald
rumsfeld lives there.
It's one of those places are nice.
It's exclusive for sure.
yeah,
it's weird.
It's like a wave from san diego.
You actually have to go.
You can drive there though,
right?
You can drive with the drive over.
Some crazy bridge going out.
They probably have dynamite on the
bridge just in case fucking riots.
To me,
it's so weird.
Like the dog,
the dogs out there,
they're so friendly.
Everything.
It's weird.
Well that was one of the things you said
were you're talking about being able to
take a wolf feel like I grew up with
like straight pit bulls around.
I knew how to handle myself in it.
I mean you had to,
you know what I'm saying?
like usually like sometimes you had to
kick him and run and kick them in the
legs and they limp,
you know what I'm saying?
So you had to,
had to maneuver sometimes.
Sometimes.
I used to outrun them.
It's tough but it's like I'm,
I mean I'm new to the whole dog thing so
I got a dog,
I've got a husky was,
I used to be fearful of dogs,
like not fearful in a sense.
Like I was scared it was gonna kill me.
Like I just didn't want to have to fight
the dog.
Like it's not,
it's not in me.
Right.
So that's a crazy thing to have to worry
about.
Like it was every bit that I got,
I got bitten in the face when I was
seven.
Yeah.
So like my uncle,
he was staying with us at the time and
he had dogs and for like two weeks I
never had a problem before.
I was like eight.
I never a problem before,
so I was back from school
and a sudden like I woke up just happy
and I hear her and I was like,
you know,
it was me,
like,
you can't talk to dogs.
So I was scared as shit.
And so like I woke up and he just asked
me saying ever since then kind of dog.
Well,
yes.
German shepherd,
bite kids,
man,
those dogs bite kids.
When I was a kid,
my aunt got bit by a german shepherd.
She got a face fucked up by a german
shepherd.
I'm a,
I know two or three other kids that have
been bitten by german shepherds.
Yeah.
It was weird,
man.
And so ever since then,
fuck I don't,
I didn't,
I didn't fuck with dogs at all.
Like I hated them.
And then we had this one pit that I got
swept the like dog.
I walked by your fence every day,
like get it,
get it together,
man.
But lIke I used to run from him rum from
so many different.
You know what,
it probably became a game for him
privately
many different times.
You walk by and still couldn't get you
on one day.
Motherfuckers gonna come by and I'm
going to kinda figure my way through
this so I'm going to get them.
I got nothing else to do.
This one I found out about dogs.
So I finally was like,
I was 29 years old.
I was like,
I got to get over this fear.
Like I gotta get up gotta,
get a dog and see what it's all about.
So I got a husky cutest little thing
ever.
And after awhile I started understanding
the dogs more and you understand that
they're really only pieces of shit if
the owners are pieces of shit.
And so like the dog directly reflects
its owner.
And so now I understand like growing up
in the neighborhoods I grew up,
nobody has time or money to care for the
dog,
like they should.
So they're henri.
Yeah,
just like the people.
Yeah.
It's just like the people.
So as president,
what's your first move?
A.
Remember
I'm not going to be a vice president,
but I'll be like,
I'm gonna be in my cabinets to much a
house of cards.
Do you want to know?
I'll be like,
I'm the dude who got fucked up by the
hooker,
but I won't be involved in of that.
No.
Sean spIcer,
that fucking dude here take the hits.
He has to go up there and say,
say the bullshit that he knows is not
true.
That's what I need you to do.
You know what?
I do do it though.
I'll let the people know when I'm lying.
I just wear a fake mustache.
So I'll give the same press conference
and I'll have a fake mustache.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
But sentence the president is an
alerting me of this important news.
You know,
the first thing I probably do,
I probably pardon?
People in jail for weed.
Oh,
nothing to do with me being here and
talking.
Eat.
But it's like,
it's such a problem.
It's such a problem.
Yeah.
The president pardoned chelsea manning,
right?
Didn't obama pardoned chelsea manning?
He pardoned him,
I think at partner commuted her
sentence.
Yeah.
So pardon means you're exonerated of any
guilt,
whereas community your sentences just so
he's allowed to pardon a bunch of people
that.
Right.
Does he have like 20 pardon or something
like that?
No.
You get the most.
I think there's a limit though.
I don't think there's a limit.
I thought it was like comps,
like,
you know,
feel like you work at a comedy club.
You get 20 comps on saturday night.
My friends want to come to this
show.
Good.
Safe table.
Nineteen hundred and 27.
Go for him.
Whoa.
Convicted of federal crimes.
Wow.
Pardon?
Commutation of sentence.
Remission of fine or restitution and
reprieve?
No,
he.
He should have a list of the people.
Listen to the people.
Click the list.
It's fine.
To who?
Alicia did side of chicago.
Who's at two toolbox,
mom?
No,
no,
she was,
uh,
she was uh,
an activist back in the,
when the black panthers were rising and
she thinks she got political side of
them and I think it was Cuba and the,
I think it was the fbi was after this
was in the fbi,
was treating the black panthers like a
terrorist organization and they were
offering.
They offer huey p,
newton,
and it was a big deal and a side issue.
I think she's still on the run.
Whoa.
Where is she?
I couldn't say.
I think it's not
pushy.
Uh,
what was,
what were they accusing her of a that I
couldn't tell you,
man?
Uh,
there was,
there's a whole bunch of conspiracies
back then
little member when obama was running for
president and they found out he was
friends with a professor in chicago.
That was one of the weatherman.
I don't remember the weatherman was a
documentary that I watched duncan trust.
My friend called me up.
Dude,
you got to see this.
It was crazy.
They were taking acid and robbing banks
and having orgies together.
and I was like,
what?
Obama was known as the weatherman,
it was this group,
this radical group in the 19 seventies
that was trying to overthrow the
government and they were just a bunch of
crazy people and they were doing acid
and one of them wound up being a
professor one day.
Here it is bill ayers and the ninth and
the 2008 presidential election
controversy.
So this guy was one of the members of
the weathermen and he went from being
essentially an antigovernment terrorist
to me to be in a college professor.
And uh,
it was a college professor,
right?
What does it say here?
My eyes were way too shitty to read
those.
Trying to read what it says
great.
Confirms or denies,
but it was a big deal.
Yeah.
It says here,
the weathermen right there is a
committee heading the weathermen
starting at its creation the summer of
1969.
The hippie movement has sort of a hippie
movement,
but another one of those,
but a lot like a lot of those hippie
movements.
Hold on a second to claim that those
three members of the weatherman who had
died during the accident of explosion
all assembling.
Oh,
they were trying to blow shit up,
man.
Jesus christ,
project mayhem thing and a fight club.
That kind of idea.
Yeah.
They were trying to blow buildings up
and shit.
So,
uh,
he apparently knew obama,
so he was just like this real super
radical lefty.
Probably did some time.
got out,
became a college professor.
I mean,
did he go,
did
he do time?
Um,
I'm trying to figure out to thing that
how obama was connected to them.
I think obama just knew him,
you know,
it was like one of those thinGs.
Yeah.
Mama contacts with ehrs,
password bIking in the same neighborhood
or something like,
well,
what is it?
What's the big deal about that?
I think there's more than that.
I think they had some sort of a,
a cordial friendship and there was a
concern that he was connected to a guy
that used to be.
BuT the guy was free now.
Right.
So like what kind of mistakes of people
made when they're 18 that you can
exonerate them from when they're 50,
you know,
isn't there like a certain limit to the
amount of time that you have to be?
You know,
I
mean,
can you be held responsible for some
shit that you did when you were 18?
That's tough.
That's the tough about the murder thing.
Like weather underground,
that's what they call themselves.
That's not the weatherman.
The weather underground.
If you kill somebody at 16,
15 years old,
like life,
like I'm not.
I guess it's just a tough subject
because I was,
I had this argument the other day like
how subjective morality is and it's kind
of all just based on super subjective
life experiences and opinions will have
a war subjective.
You're allowing people to go over and do
it and then you,
you,
you know,
you slip them and say thank you for
killing those people that have always
been super affect cognitive dissonance
about that.
LIke it's,
it's because we,
we've,
we've normalized it to the point where
you see where you hear casualty of war
is a,
it is a normal term,
uh,
but those are like innocent civilians
being murdered sometimes,
sometimes,
and then there's the attitude that they
have to die in order to serve the
greater good.
Some casual observers have to
accidentally be killed and some
collateral damage.
Yeah,
that makes terrifying.
It really is.
Yeah.
Well,
the idea is that if we don't do that,
we will lose whatever headstart on
civilization we have over the rest of
the way.
just start all over how we do that.
Oh no,
It sounds right.
That sounds like some people say after
they smoke pot,
I know we should be able to write,
but how would we,
what would we do?
I feel like we got enough technology and
enough smart people to just sit around
and say,
iron man,
this ain't working.
I totally agree,
but I'm definitely have enough resources
to feed everybody.
Well,
we certainly are close.
I think we have.
Yeah,
I mean it's a matter of figuring out
where to put it in whether or not we
should be eating the same shit we're
already eating because you know,
if you look at all the different people
that are living in this country eating
corn products,
just that alone,
like why is that the case?
Like why is corn and so many different
things.
It's not because it's good for you,
it's not because we're doing the best
job arose in abundance,
right,
well you can grow massive amounts of it
and these fields and the government
subsidizes it and then it becomes a
whole entangled sort of a system where
the farmers are growing it and If they
didn't have a subsidy from the
government,
it wouldn't be profitable.
But it is profitable.
And then the government,
you know,
they,
they know that those places,
they got to count on those folks when it
comes to like elections and things along
those lines.
And I started going to mess.
He gets entangled I guess.
Messy man.
Yeah.
So do we have enough to feed each other
with the way we're eating now?
Yeah,
for sure.
But we shouldn't eat and the way we're
eating now,
so it's like,
yeah,
for sure we have enough food to feed
people the way we eat now,
but we should be eating like at whole
foods.
It's like when you go to whole foods is
like,
oh man,
you got to be registered shop here.
Like why is that?
It's food.
It's fucking real food.
Organic shit always.
I don't really understand that whole
thing either.
Well,
I mean it just means they don't have
pesticides on it.
right.
Everything is organic.
Phyllis,
philosophically you can make.
You can make that argument every short
organic.
Even if we tamper with it,
we're organic.
We're from the earth.
Poisons natural.
That's what I'm saying.
Yeah.
I mean everything that you make is made
out of something on earth.
So anything that's artificial or
chemical or whatever the fuck it is
still made out of raw materials that are
found here on earth.
I agree.
Yeah.
I mean some organic food is better for
you probably because it doesn't have
chemicals on it.
And with the idea of gmo is where it
gets real weird because almost
everything is genetically modified.
My uh,
my,
my stepdad's when they hit me today,
he's a geneticist.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Phd.
He actually developed one of the firSt
strands for the tyson chicken.
And so he's like a bad ass to this
making franken chicken,
man.
So what did he do?
What did he do?
I mean,
I couldn't tell you how many chicken the
fuck.
I don't know what he tells us stories
about how he like genetically modified.
You can genetically modified chickens
without feathers and all of this stuff.
That's crazy,
man.
Oh my god.
That gene spLicing shit is amazing to
me.
Have you heard,
have you heard of crispr?
That shit is so you.
So you open that pandora's box of once
you genetically modify human,
you can't go backwards because they've
already started to do with embryos in
China.
Really?
Yeah.
They're starting to do with non-viable
human embryos.
So they're taking non-viable human
embryos and they're doing all these
genetic experiments on them and altering
the genes.
But the thing is,
what it is now is it's like the baby
steps towards something that will
probably be just,
it's going to be standard maybe 100
years from now or whether that's the
next step in our evolutionary history.
What is this?
Jamie python breeder.
Genetically bred a python to have an
emoji on it home.
Oh my god.
I'm seeing it.
I didn't see it.
It's got smiley faces all over it.
This is fucking insane.
How did he do that?
I just breed.
I think you said it took like eight
generations of breeding and can I can
sell this worth 4,500 bucks and 40 it
might.
Might've been wearing initially.
That's amazing.
That's so cool.
That is so cool.
Looking emoji pythons as crazy.
And that's crazy because that's just
done through breeding.
Like like how to make a husky out of a
wolf and that's done through breeding.
But there's,
you know what you're talking about
chickens that don't have any feathers
like serious science.
So it goes deep,
like to the point of like how far do you
want to.
How far the restraints of our,
of our humanity and humanity is,
so if you genetically modify humans to
the point where,
uh,
you take out the genes that is the
cancer gene and you take out the jeans
and this and that and have that and to
the point of we're living our health
expectancy or the life expectancy goes
up exponentially.
Like,
is it,
would it be moral to not take those
genes out of your kids?
You know what I'm saying?
Here's a good question.
And then yeah,
the people that would be like,
look,
I know my kid's gonna have a disease,
but that's what god intended.
Like,
whoa.
For ns.
To me,
that shit is crazy.
It's.
but it's also debatable,
right?
The reason why.
yeah.
That's the reason why they have that
opinion in the first place is because
like,
I guess you could argue it even if I
don't agree with it.
You could argue that opinion.
And that's one of the weirdest things
about people.
There's just so much messiness to us
when it comes to something like that,
like some new technology.
That's a crazy technology.
You can make a super kid like you can
make your kids seven feet tall,
400 pounds solid muscle runs through
walls or make them a little pussy when
you want it to be a pussy,
whatever.
They only have two models.
You know,
if you have a prius or a mustang.
Shelby,
that's it.
One of the two.
What are you gonna do?
Oh,
we'll just take the prius.
My kids just going to read a lot of
books.
Fuck that.
My kids run through buildings now,
man.
I'm going to take the prius,
Would you?
Well,
you already ran through building.
My opinion.
Skewed.
Yeah.
You should probably write a book on how
not to play football and be a good book.
It might not be a bad book coming from a
guy like you.
People would.
People would definitely read it
official.
If maybe if I had to do again,
I'd never played football.
Yeah.
Maybe that would be your book.
see you started when you were seven.
Man.
How the fuck could,
you know?
That's what I'm saying.
Like I had no,
whose idea was it a,
it was ours,
so me and my brother was just like,
fuck it,
let's play football.
I mean,
fine,
You're fat,
you're fat of it as a kid.
And so to me it's fun playing sports is
fun and it's fun to watch.
Yeah.
And so,
but the comradery you got from it.
Like I loved the life experiences like
that,
but it's just like I just feel like I
have so much more to me than that and I
just don't want to say wasted because it
was a,
it was a grand experience,
but I just put so much time into my life
that ended in an instant.
You know what I mean?
And it just feels like a lot of,
I don't say wasted time,
but it just feels like a lot of things I
feel like could still be benefited
me to this day.
I think so too.
Now I'm going to say something,
but whenever I say it,
people get mad at me,
but I have to say,
you should start a podcast.
I should start a pocket.
fuck yeah,
definitely should start a podcast.
Don't you think so jamie?
People like fucking rogan.
stop telling.
Interesting people should have podcasts.
Your story's interesting.
You know the whole thing thAt you're
doing right now is interesting.
Trying to figure out who the fuck you
are and 30 years of age after being a
famous football player and thinking you
could fuck a wolf up with your bare
hands.
See,
that's fascinating.
It's not thinking she's going to jump on
it right now to jump into five.
Man.
Now I've thought about it.
Talk about some of them people,
but it's like,
oh no,
you don't even have to do it like all
the time.
You can do it whenever you want.
Right?
Like people are under no obligation to
get it every day.
It's not like you're forcing them to
like,
okay look,
I'm going to sign the contract.
Do you guys pay me x amount of money?
I'm going to do this every monday to
whenever you want.
You do it on your phone.
I'll show you how to do it on your
phone.
I guess I got a laptop,
but I mean if you're somewhere.
YeAh,
like right now if we want it to set my
phone down here,
press the voice recorder and I'm telling
you it sounds good.
Like this ideA that you need like a lot
of equipment to do a podcast and you've
really not really.
I mean it sounds better.
You keep killing the game.
Trying to stay one step ahead of the
free and I walked into a.
I like this is just for podcasts.
That's crazy.
Well we'll just wait till the next one
after we built studio dose.
I gotta come back,
man.
Yeah,
for sure.
Free party world headquarters.
We're having a party party world
headquarters is where the next building
as it's going down.
that's good praise man.
You would have the best doing it for
show.
Thanks man.
You could do it for sure.
One hundred percent.
like you could do.
Stand up too if you want to do that.
You don't do that.
Go man.
There you go.
Got it.
The stand up thing.
I know about the pocket brendan shops
doing it.
My friend brendan shop,
he played.
What did he play for?
You got to play does preseason with the
bills.
I think as far as any fought in the ufc,
he was on the ultimate fighter and the
uh,
fought in ufc,
had some big wins I've seen now.
He has a podcast,
a real successful to two podcasts
fighter and the kid and he does this
thing called the big brown breakdown
where he goes over all the different
fights that are coming up.
So he went and now he's doing standup.
So he went from fighting,
like deciding like as a,
as an athlete,
like he was getting towards the end of
his run,
left fighting,
and then now it's like way more
successful doing this podcast and doing
standup and doing live podcast shows so
he could do it.
And you talk way better than him.
No offense books,
man.
I appreciate
me under the bus.
I was kid and he's,
he's a funny dude,
man.
Brenda's really funny.
He says hilarious shit.
You can do it too,
man.
I'm telling.
The beautiful thing about podcasting too
is that you don't have to be anything
like you don't.
You could be funny or you could be smart
or you could be interesting like you,
whoever you are and just like that
stupid
box on the ground at the la county
museum of art.
Like some people might.
Some people might like that.
No matter who you are.
Some people.
I'm not saying that you will be that box
metaphor.
Let's go with hot food.
You are in amber box
in your own right.
I was.
I should've gone with hot food.
Hot food fan.
I'm not a fan of that box,
but I'm saying some people fucking hate
hot food.
right?
I don't understand those.
Yeah,
man.
He bring some people hot food.
They freak out.
TheY like like mashed potatoes.
That's what they like.
Mashed potatoes and boiled chicken.
Boiled chicken.
I like boiled chicken.
Disrespectful.
No,
no,
no.
Soup.
Chicken soup is boiled chicken.
You got grill that at least first and
then just know how to cook us.
Usc.
You will be a cook.
I cook a few things.
Do you low,
but yeah.
Where did that come from?
That's
last year.
Well listen,
here's what's crazy.
That picture has been redone.
Think about all the images on the
internet is a beautiful place.
There's one dude who's like,
what does he deal with?
Saudi original?
No,
I did.
Yeah,
he's in Turkey.
I thought he was in.
He's cutting this steak and he's dealing
with all this flare and every time he
cuts it he slaps his knife on the table,
but he does it with so much swag.
Yeah,
he's slicing through the.
I bet this guy get so much pussy.
It's not even close.
Right?
Because this is part of the reason.
I mean this germinating the latin lover,
romantic chef character.
So he geTs to the end.
He could just lay them out,
but he.
Yeah,
and then he takes this it.
He throws some,
sprinkled some salt on it.
That became that one thing.
A guy sprinkling salt became a meme that
just kept over and over and over again
was man,
it was black.
Twitter.
Was that what it was like?
Twitter,
black.
Twitter is probably the most.
That needs to be a documentary about
that to be because it pushes so much of
our culture.
It's a.
Twitter does.
Jamie says that people steal from black
twitter,
do it on like a tonight,
show movies,
not tv,
show montages,
snl,
snl steals from the time
it's not good.
It's just hashtag black twitter.
Just there's,
look,
I can't even get 100 percent.
Explain what it is,
but if someone's got to help me,
I got you man.
So how about did I get you?
I get like five or six accounts to
follow and you'll kind of get a feel
for.
Okay.
And then,
uh,
I follow accounts that those people
interact with.
Yeah.
And then you see like,
so,
so a lot of the content that you see,
you know that Jordan cry face me like
twitter.
Oh,
it's like they,
they moved to man,
I say a week and I'm on to it and I'm
black.
So I bought.
It's,
it's,
it's ignorance at a very high level,
but there's brilliant involved.
It's the coolest shit.
What's the brunch of humor?
The humor.
Yeah,
the,
I mean,
you know,
as you know,
any kind of like a lot of humans is his
intellect,
his intellect.
And so the brilliance that comes from
that.
Is this the funniest shit?
All right,
I'm going to check it out.
Jamie's very well educated.
You know about blacks were kept for.
So yeah,
he buys yeezys.
See I can never get them with jamie
online.
He's not on black twitter.
No,
he's not.
He's,
he's been ousted.
He'll be rough.
That'S my dude though,
man.
Well,
they asked him and then he immediately
Started producing it.
Anti-trump record.
he recognized what the fuck went down.
He deleted all his pro trump tweets.
All of them are gone and now he's
producing some ant.
A buddy hired who?
You got another rapper like,
hey man,
how about you do this song?
He's helping the duty for him.
He felt he felt it.
He's,
he's up there on a platform hovering
over people saying he would have voted
on trump yet craig.
No songs,
no songs properly at the propaganda.
It's propaganda.
Yeah,
that's what he did.
Deleted the tweet.
Said fake news.
I bet it's not fake news.
Uh,
but nobody wants to talk about it.
That is reconsidering about Donald
Trump.
Kanye,
kanye.
I thought you liked trump.
I thought you loved trump,
anti antitrypsin properly.
It's called propaganda,
but he didn't produce it.
Did he have anything to do with it?
I don't know.
How did he.
I think there's a bunch of white people
scrambling right now to keep this money
flowing.
Tanya,
kanye,
kanye.
That's usually the case,
man.
Listen,
It's been a lot of fun.
I really appreciate you coming down
here.
I'm glad we did it.
I'm glad it all came out of something
silly and props and neal brennan for
setting this up and uh,
thank you brother.
Appreciate it man.
It's reAlly fun to do a podcast.
I would listen.
You got to.
Come on now.
I'm on 100 percent.