Hey,
hey,
hey.
Hey everybody.
Hey,
I need a new way now.
It's not so boring.
This episode of the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by
squarespace.com.
Squarespace and is,
is,
is.
It is.
It is an extremely easy way to build an
awesome website.
Everything is integrated free domains
and great designs.
Hosting all in one place.
You can choose from over 20 bad ass
designs.
Use Your custom images and content if
you've never been to squarespace before.
It's beautiful invention.
It's one thing that I have wanted for
decades since I got online.
I guess it probably isn't decades,
a decade,
maybe two decades.
Jesus Christ,
I'm old.
Um,
I've always wanted to be able to create
my own website,
but I didn't have the patience and wait
to add to like sit down and learn how to
code.
But you could do something on
squarespace,
simple and easy and have it be a really
nice website.
In fact,
we're going to put on a contest.
We're working out the details right now.
Um,
but squarespace and this podcast are
working together to,
uh,
to.
We're going to set up some sort of a
contest where the person who has the
best website they designed using
squarespace get something cool or
something like that.
We'll figure out what it is,
but it's a,
it's a website.
It's a product that I really believe in.
They also have a new ecommerce product
called Galapagos,
so it's a new template that will
showcase your ecommerce products in a
more interesting way than typical
orderly grid and galapagos features,
a dynamic product mosaic with custom
rollover states that allow you to
display an alternate image when visitors
hover over each item.
So like when you go over night and with
your cursor,
your pointer,
you know,
that little arrow thing or a finger if
you're a fucking Weirdo.
Uh,
the template also,
uh,
is preset with the content pages.
You need to have your shop up and
running quickly.
If you're a musician,
you can sell music on squarespace.
Super easy.
You can set up your website to do that
digital downloads and merchandise
directly from your website.
You can set up an online store.
It works on everything.
Ipod,
android,
windows,
if you're one of those Unix Weirdos,
it works on all that shit.
Go to squarespace.com
and check it out.
Use the offer code Joe and the number 12
because we are in the month of December
and you will save 10 percent off.
You sign up for a yearly plan and that
discount applies to the entire year,
so you use the offer code Joe and the
number 12 because we're in the month of
December.
Get 10 percent off your first purchase
on new accounts.
That's squarespace.com.
And the offer code is Joe All one word
and the number 12.
We're also brought to you by lumosity
and lumosity.com
is one of my favorite podcast sponsors
because it's essentially a gym for your
brain.
As I've gotten older,
luckily I'm involved in things like the
podcast comedy and you know in mma
commentary to a certain extent that keep
my brain moving,
but a lot of us aren't.
You know,
a lot of us are stuck in cubicles and
your fucking brain turns to Jello and
your brain works.
I don't know how your brain works is.
I'm not a doctor,
but there's a science called
neuroplasticity and that's what square,
that's what lumosity is designed around
and lumosity is designed around the idea
that you can keep your brain active by
using games.
It's not boring.
It's not like sitting there trying to do
complex mathematics.
It's.
It's all designed as fun games and fun
games with your specific goals in mind,
like there is a bunch of different
options like memory and then when you
get to memory,
if you go to lumosity.com,
forward slash Joe,
you can check out how everything is set
up,
but there's a bunch of different options
like memory.
You go to the first page and it allows
you to work specifically on the things
that you're trying to work on,
like recalling the location of objects
or learning new subjects quickly and
accurately.
Then go to attention.
It has a bunch of different things that
are options for attention,
concentrating while learning something
new,
avoiding distractions and the the actual
programs are designed.
The games are designed to meet those
specific goals.
It's really interesting.
It's really fun and it's really
effective.
I've had a lot of positive feedback ever
since we started using lumosity as a
sponsor and it's all based on scientific
research by harnessing the brain's
natural ability to adapt to new
experiences.
It can help with mental functions like
memory,
attention,
mental speed,
problem solving,
etc.
The exercises are fun.
IT's a,
it's a really interesting thing and it's
something you get addicted to.
They also have apps for your phone so
you can,
uh,
you can download the lumosity app and
you know,
fuck around on the bus or,
or what have you.
So lumosity.com
forward slash joe.
Click the start training button and
start playing your first game.
That's lumosity.com
forward slash joe.
You,
you're really going to enjoy it.
It's an excellent website.
One of my personal favorites that
sponsor the show and I use it all the
time.
It's really something that's a,
it's a unique thing to be able to do
like a gym for your mind.
We're also brought to you by on it.
That's o n n I t.com.
if you've never been on it before on it
is essentially a human optimization
website.
If you notice a theme here,
ladies and gentlemen,
I'm trying to help people improve and
trying to get you to get your shit
together and ana can help you with
essential nutrients like alpha brain and
new mood,
different things that are designed to
help enhance your body's production of
human neurotransmitters and your body's
production of certain hormones like
testosterone.
You're your body's productIon of
serotonin,
all this different stuff that's on it.
There's science behind it.
It's all up at [inaudible] dot com.
Lots of information.
If you're curious,
and one of the things about it is we
offer a.
When you're,
when you're ordering supplements,
especially things that are controversial
in any way,
we offer a 90 pill,
30 day money back or a 30 pill,
fucked it up.
30 pill,
90 day money back guarantee where you
don't even have to return the product.
You just say,
you know what?
This shit didn't do anything for me.
Boom,
you get your money back.
It's that simple.
no one's trying to rip you off or just
trying to sell you really awesome shit,
including strength and conditioning
equipment like primal bells,
the kettle bells with the different
faces on them,
all sculpted in,
all made out of iron,
beautiful and cool and functional.
Three d mapped out so that they're all
balanced perfectly as well as looking
pretty slick,
too much to mention.
I'm just just.
It's an awesome website and a lot of
awesome stuff on it.
Dot com,
o n n I t use a codename brogan.
Save yourself 10 percent.
Alright ladies.
Gentleman,
mike birbiglia is here.
Why waste time by fuck around.
We are here to the music,
the joe rogan experience podcast all
day.
Birbiglia easily the most prepared
standup comedian gassed in the history
of this podcast.
Look at this.
Homeboy has got page after page after
page.
He also has printed stuff.
He's got it.
You're.
You're wriTing out in longhand,
so one of the last humans to use
cursive.
It's all insanity though.
It doesn't add up to anything really,
but it does.
You know,
it adds up to effort,
right?
Like all that is making sure you're
writing things down and puts it in your
brain.
That's what a short documentary about
lynch often mitch hedberg and one of the
things that he says in this old
interview is like he got people them for
advice all the time,
young comedians,
and he just says like,
write down what's funny.
Don't be lazy.
piece of advice.
Right.
Especially from a heroin addict.
It's very rare that you get like non
lazy heroin addicts.
I mean,
look,
I don't make me laugh at that.
It's not funny,
but it is true and I think it's
important to talk about because it's why
he's not with us anymore.
He's one of the greats.
He is,
in my opinion,
he is one of the most incredibly rich
guys of all time.
He was so good and so clean.
Super clean.
yeah.
Which like for no reason it was so
inventive.
Mind was so inventive.
Yeah.
He was a really unique comic,
but he also had a problem with heroin.
He had some drug issues,
it seemed.
I'd say that never your office.
Who am I to say?
I never.
I was friends with mitch,
I never saw him use drugs.
That's true.
Well,
I was friends with mitch and I never saw
him use drugs either,
but,
and,
and um,
I saw him.
yeah.
Nice.
I'm the final week,
uh,
and it's just,
it's very sad.
Well,
when
stan hope and I were working together on
the man show,
the bastardized second version of the
man show,
um,
I remember was when he got gangrene and
I remember that in Texas.
Yeah.
He almost lost his leg and uh,
you know,
they came back from that and everybody
was hoping that he was of clean up and
get his shit together,
but for whatever reason,
whatever,
you know what?
Yes,
he burned brightly and he's.
And he's gone.
Yeah.
What,
what was important though about his,
his artwork?
What he did was he was so prolific,
you know,
and constantly and it is super
disciplined,
very disciplined in his style is like a
really difficult style to be realistic
with.
Yeah.
Because it's not like weird observations
that are non sequiturs one nonsequitor
after another.
Yeah.
I know.
I have this memory when it always feels
like a blur,
but I remember when he passed away and
there was a memorial service like at
carolines in New York and I was with his
standing on the street with dave attell
and my wife and mitchell's mother,
mary,
and she's passed away now.
And,
and,
uh,
dave and mary were smoking cigarettes
and then dave goes,
uh,
and it was going to sound trite way.
I'm repeating it,
but dave has a profound nest to him that
it kind of gets away with this.
He was just like,
we'll always have the albums,
like we'll always have the albums.
And it's true.
There is something that,
that it's like we lose a lot of people,
but with mitch will,
we have this really special thing.
Like we have these beautiful comedy
albums which are like a moment in time
that are perfect jokes and like perfect
wisdom.
The wisdom.
There's wisdom in matches comedy as far
as I'm.
Yeah,
I agree.
They're just,
they're one of those things where he
know some of his jokes are just so
preposterous,
but other ones,
you know,
you'll,
you'll just,
you'll just listen to it and you just
go,
you know,
what the fuck,
like,
like my favorite is somebody asked me if
I wanted a frozen banana.
I said no,
but I want a regular banana later.
So yes,
they're just,
they're just so.
There's so uniquely him,
you know,
and almost like,
um,
there's like a vein of that comedy that
goes from I guess like Steven Wright
know who's got that sort of absurdist,
weird way of looking at things.
But then mitch would take it to a
totally new place.
Totally personal place
is this joke and I'm going to kind of
mess it up.
But because I don't remember people's
jokes that well,
but like where he goes,
ah,
he goes,
I said,
I said a thing and uh,
and then someone didn't hear me that
well and they asked me to repeat it.
And then,
uh,
oh,
it's the steam boat operator joke and
I'm forgetting the how it gets to it.
But,
but uh,
but it's about being,
it's all,
it's ultimately about being
misunderstood.
I feel bad.
I went down that road thinking that my
brain,
maybe I need some more of these
chemicals,
you dah,
dah,
dah.
What?
All of these things.
I have a fancy coffee that is super good
that you with the butter in it.
Yeah.
Bulletproof coffee.
It'S not working for me yet,
but it's early man for a comedian here
is,
there's a,
there's a joke.
I'm trying to find them.
If you do,
if you youtube steve mode operator,
you'll find that joke.
Yeah,
that's what I'm trying to find.
I got to say like,
of the things I even,
even like hearing you talk before we
started talking,
the thing that I admire about your
comedy and niches and like stan hope,
stan homes by favorite comeback by far.
And the reason why it's the same thing
that you have and all the comics are
maria bamford.
No one could steal their jokes.
Oh they do.
But you,
but you can't.
You can't steal them and have the other
person wouldn't.
Uh,
it wouldn't go so well as well as it
will for,
you know.
Well,
yeah,
if that's.
Isn't that the beautiful thing about
comedy when it comes from your
personality,
you know,
when like you listened to a mitch
hedberg Joke,
you know,
like the double tree hotel job,
like there's he minds in a way that I,
I would never mind,
you know,
like he minds from material in a way,
like another good example that is patent
patent oswald get to like,
I look at it like I've listened to some
of his cds and I go,
that's a bit that I probably would have
abandoned.
I would have started maybe working on,
tried it on stage a few times and just
moved on to something with more meat to
it.
But he'll take an idea that's like an
odd idea that maybe I would have
abandoned and turn it into an amazing 10
minute Chunk,
you know?
Yeah.
Patents totally like that.
It'll also,
one of the things I love about patents,
he's just genuinely passionate about
what he's talking about.
Here it is a,
I wrote a letter to my dad.
I wrote,
I really enjoy being here,
but I accidentally wrote rarely instead
of really,
but I still wanted to use it,
so I crossed it out and wrote,
I rarely drive steam boats dead.
You don't know about me.
Kind of act like I'm a steam boat
operator.
Took a harsh turn right away,
like one of my favorite jokes of all
time.
It's a perfect joke.
that was a great impression.
By the way,
this not exactly like that's like a
piece of philosophy I think.
Yeah,
just a joke.
I really do think that.
Well it's a piece of mitch didn't know
that,
that in and tells a way of saying it.
You know,
we,
we still have the albums we do.
We have that.
Yeah,
we do have that.
It was one of the coolest things about
the art form,
you know,
the,
the insight into how a person's mind
functions and how they put together
material that you know,
like gaffigan,
like I don't think like the african.
Is that his writing up there?
Yeah.
Isn't that great?
Don't believe people believe.
Is that the documentary?
Or even themselves believe in ghosts,
but they don't believe in themselves.
That's a great.
We should tell people what the url is of
that site because it's a.
It's a you.
It's on youtube.
This documentary.
We're lynn his widow in shock her off.
there's a very funny comic as well.
It's in the cabin that they shared and
she takes out his notebook and she's
showing what it was in his notebook.
Yeah.
And they're there.
Cabin was up in big bear,
right?
Like when he got a development deal,
you know,
some people go out and they buy a
mercedes.
He boughT a cabin in big bear.
Yeah,
exactly.
Nobody's said to me,
what's it's funny looking at this
notebook.
Mitch goes,
today,
I opened for him and the first time I
ever featured jokers comedy club in
dayton,
Ohio,
I know,
play and goes,
ah.
He goes,
uh,
don't ever show a girl your notebook
because she's not supposed to know about
it.
you're just supposed to see the final
jokes onstage.
That's so true.
Isn't that true?
When you date girls and they see your
act over and over and over again and
they lose all the magic you have to meet
and marry them or break up with it.
You got to do one or the other because
otherwise they're going to tell their
friends.
He just repeats the same shit every
night and then he gets it right.
It's not that big a deal.
I can do it.
The mystique goes away.
The mystique,
that mystique of writing,
but he was a.
He was such a unique guy in that he did
obviously have issues with drugs,
but he also obviously it was really
fucking prolific and really wrote a lot
and was really disciplined.
Yeah,
no,
in that sense it was just an odd
combination of things.
Yeah.
No.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Was.
He's a.
He was a phenomenon.
Yeah.
People should live.
If I.
I feel like I should almost plug this.
I was talking to mitch altogether.
Great album.
You can get an itunes or spotify or
whatever and a and strategic grill
locations was his first album.
I love that.
Perfect.
Strategic grill locations is an awesome,
awesome classic.
Now you've got a new album out coming
out is.
No,
it Just came out.
It's,
um,
yeah,
it's called my girlfriend's boyfriend.
It's about a,
it's about a lot of like heartbreak and
love and,
and how I decided to get married despite
the fact that I don't reallY believe in
the idea of marriage.
Yeah,
it's a stupid idea,
but it works for them.
It works for women.
Women love it.
They love it.
They love being able to tell their
friends are married getting.
That's what it is.
Oh yeah,
definitely.
They like winning.
They win and then you might get married
when they enjoyed that.
Yeah.
My wife,
totally one.
That's an interesting perspective.
I've never thought about it like that.
But uh,
yeah,
I'm happier though.
Are you?
Are you happy?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
But it's just because I'm in a great
relationship.
I would have been just as happy if I
didn't have some shit written down on
paper or wearing a little monkey ring.
It's all that stuff is.
It seems secondary,
but for women it means a lot that you go
through that nonsense.
Or for some women I should say,
I shouldn't never generalize like that.
Some of them they want that.
They want that nonsense.
They want that cultural nonsense.
They want to be able to tell their
friends are married.
Yeah.
I think.
Well I think part of it's the family
too.
Yes.
The families are like,
what's going on?
Oh yeah.
Real people start to go.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't know.
There's certain things that people just
don't like it.
They don't believe unless it has a
formal cultural understanding.
LIke this is maybe a tangential example,
but like my cat passed away this summer
and for your cap,
trying to figure out how you're going to
come back.
so like,
uh,
I don't know either yet,
but uh,
my cat I haven't passed away.
My wife and I were so upset like,
so like it,
like the whole summer was like our cat
passed away.
That's people will be like,
what's up?
We'd be like,
our cap.
I haven't passed away the whole summer.
Yeah,
we were really upset by it.
He was 17 years old.
I have a 17 year old category now.
Yeah.
So like we were so,
so close to ivan and explaining that
your cat died is a little bit like
explaining that your imaginary friend
died where you're like,
he ivan's dead and they're like,
write a event and you're like,
no,
really,
our cad ivan,
they're like your cat.
And I feel like marriage is a little bit
like that too.
You're like,
if you're not married you can be like,
it's my boyfriend and I love him and he
loves me.
And they were like,
right your boyfriend?
And he loves you.
Yeah,
exactly.
If yOu're married and it's like,
oh,
you got the document,
you've got the legal well okay,
I buy it.
Yeah.
And then there's some people that they
look at that as like there's like goals
that they have to achieve,
get in a relationship.
Okay,
check now next move.
You got to get this guy to sign this
paper.
And I hate that.
Yeah,
that's the part of it.
I have a friend who went through a
fucking absolutely brutal divorce.
I mean a really,
really bad one.
And then his new wife,
he,
you know,
he started dating this woman immediately
afterwards of course,
and she didn't want to sign a prenup.
Yeah.
And he lost everything and you know,
and it's like I don't know what to do.
And you don't know what to do.
You don't know what to do.
Do you,
do you hate yourself?
Like,
are you fucking crazy?
Like match doesn't always work out,
buddy.
It doesn't always work out the prenup on
the second marriage.
Oh,
interesting.
When he lost everything on the first
man.
Yes,
he lost everything on the first marriage
and I'm pretty sure they overlapped.
Like his first marriage was fine.
I'd have to ask him about this.
His first marriage was falling apart and
then he met her and there was like,
you know,
he knew her while he was still with his
wife and then he got divorced like he
had like,
you know,
the old expression about like swinging
from branch to branch that uh,
you know,
most women especially,
they don't like to let go of a branch.
They like to swing and then know that
there's another branch there when they
let go theIr first branch.
You don't have to say women.
You just said people.
Yes.
Humans.
Yeah.
But,
but like,
uh,
yeah.
The,
the,
the marriage thing is weird now
particularly to be in light of all of
these supplements and things that you
talk about because people are just going
to live longer.
Well,
not with this stuff.
I mean really,
I mean if you're lucky you get another
five years or 10 years.
Alpha and proteIn vitamins.
I'm like,
oh man.
What studies have been done on life
extension as far as like vitamins?
Well,
a little bit.
I mean I guess all that combined with
like hip replacements and heart
transplants and all is well,
there's so much futuristic stuff right
now that's gonna make people live longer
and then it's going to be like,
it already was weird that we were
married 30 years and what if I were
married 70 years?
Well,
in that sense,
I think that if it works,
it works and if you're married for 30
years and you really happy and then you
get to live for another hundred,
would you want to break up and start
fresh with a new person and try to put
it together?
Like part of what makes a marriage work
or friendship work or anything is you
kind of understand how each other works.
Kind of understand what the ins and the.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
That when that happens so much
theoretically in practice when it's done
perfectly,
which it never is,
but when it is done perfectly,
that's what makes it so cool is that you
know each other,
you know,
like you'd go to the store and like,
oh,
I know she loves this kind of shit.
I'll go to go get her this or you know,
you're going to go on a vacation.
She's never going to want to do this or
she loves doing this.
Yeah.
You know each other.
So in that sense,
would it really matter if you live to be
an extra hundred years?
Probably not,
except you'd start thinking about all
that extra pussy.
Yeah.
That age 100 pussies crazy I've heard.
Just gets different.
Just different.
It's like wine in a barrel or old
scotch.
I'm going to just read.
I just want to take that back from the
record.
I know this is live,
but I just want to take back that age
100 line.
These are just jokes folks.
You looked at this stuff written down on
paper.
You go,
these guys are assholes.
Statements are these,
but in the moment this is great.
Yeah.
Seeing the moment.
It's exciting.
I love that you have this.
Oh,
the studio.
The studio and you have your people who
listen and like you don't even have to
go.
I'm going on conan tonight.
You don't have to go on conan.
You don't have to go and talk just
because you have like your.
I looked on your website.
You're playing like goddamn chicago
theater,
chicago theater or what?
That is so huge.
You can't get bigger than that and
you're just here in your studio being
like,
hey guys,
I'm coming to chicago theater.
Yeah.
I'm coming soon.
When is that?
January 24th chicago theater.
Me and uh,
the great ari shaffir should.
She'll be good times.
Yeah.
That place is awesome res.
But he could close.
Ari shapiro is legit.
Headliner now.
Oh no,
I'm sure.
Do you know ari?
I think I'd do it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
This thing is,
um,
I remember seeing him in that video
though.
Carlos see a video?
Yes.
Yeah.
He was one of the first cars that carlos
ripped off back in the day when not.
I shouldn't say that.
I'm sure carl started ripping guys off
way before already,
but one of the first guys that I knew
that like suffered from it.
Yeah.
But yeah,
this place sort of as come together
slowly but surely.
It's pretty humble becoming more and
more child.
Like as I add special effects pieces.
When I look around here,
I'm like,
I feel like you could be.
I think you might be like a politician
in the future.
Do you ever get that feeling?
No.
Now how the fuck do you get that?
You look around,
you see a predator mask,
you see an alien had a zombie,
a lava lamp,
deer skull,
and you like,
you know what,
you should be running.
Shit,
here's what I,
here's what I get,
here's how I hire arrived there.
So,
so with jay,
with jfk,
you had the first president who was on
camera,
he was good looking and,
and before that you didn't have to be
good looking as a president.
That's interesting that,
that was like a big shift in culture and
they say that barack obama is the first
president at where it's like,
he's like a rockstar precedent.
Like people are like,
he's fucking cool.
Like I've,
you know,
like a lot of people say like,
people voted for him because they're
just excited.
It's so exciting.
I'm going to take it a step further,
like 20 years from now,
the president.
And it's hilarious.
Hilarious about wanting the military
industrial complex.
Unless some massive paradigm shift takes
place where we no longer have wore a.
I don't see anybody running any country.
Being hilarious.
President is hilarious and he's in a
great shape.
And uh,
yeah,
that's all I got.
That's why I think you could be a
politician in the future.
Right.
That's it.
Maybe the time has come because I feel
like if you were in charge,
I would vote for you because I would
feel confident.
I'd be like,
okay,
sure.
He smoked some pot jury posts,
most smoked some pot on that.
But he's really strong,
physically strong,
smart,
funny.
I'm,
that's enough for me.
Reasonable,
reasonable,
reasonable.
Is I probably the most important thing.
Anybody.
What do you think the most important
quality you need to govern?
I think it's probably not wanting to
govern.
Not wanting to be the guy that's in
charge.
I think that might be one of the best
qualities than anybody could ever have.
if you want to run things,
he should not want to be the guy who
runs things.
Yeah,
I think so.
I think low level headed I think is a
huge quality.
I mean I feel like the reason I voted
for barack obama is like,
I just felt like,
okay,
he seems smart,
but what was the alternative?
It seems levelheaded,
dead man in a dump.
That was the alternative.
And so what was the alternative?
The next.
It was a fucking mormon.
A guy who's literally believes in one of
the most preposterous religious stories
in the history of humanity.
And he,
his family was a part of a cult that
moved to Mexico so they can have more
wives.
Yeah.
You knoW that story about it?
Fuck his.
His,
uh,
mitt romney,
mitt romney's parents.
They lived in Mexico.
Oh yeah.
I didn't even know.
He didn't know that.
I think I had heard about it,
but I,
I don't know the full story.
His dad could never be president because
his dad was born in Mexico.
Oh,
his dad wasn't an american citizen that
way.
It wasn't born with a natural born
citizen where,
you know,
mit is.
He was born in America,
but his family comes from this sect of
mormonism that broke off from the United
States back in the 18 hundreds when it
really didn't matter if he lived in.
He can live in Mexico.
you live in America.
It doesn't matter.
There's no cars.
So that's what they did.
They moved to Mexico.
Shit didn't turn out so good for that
bet.
That bet suck.
Like the bet that.
Well,
it's nice down here.
It's pretty much the same as it is in
America.
We're just going to go over here and
have 10 wives.
Well obviously when the invention of
cars came along and the whole
age of machines in the industrial era
machines and you know,
the United States became this superpower
and Mexico became what it is today and
now they're involved in these,
these armed standoffs with the mexican
drug cartels.
They get kidnapped,
they have a fortified compounds and they
have centuries and snipers and rifles
and everything.
I mean,
it's really crazy.
Crazy shit.
Vice did a piece on that on the,
uh,
the varIous mormon families that are
living in.
But that was our other option or other
option was one of those guys,
a guy who believes in magic underwear
and a fucking con artist of who was 14
years old who Claimed the found golden
tablets that contained the last work of
jesus and that the american indians were
a tribe of Israel lights that came over.
I mean,
it's just,
that's a great book if people want to
know about mormonism at all,
is under the banner of heaven.
No good scrapbook.
yeah.
Did you see the book of mormon krakauer
wrote it?
Yeah.
Um,
the uh,
book of mormon is great.
I twice.
It's fucking amazing.
So good.
You know,
the crazy thing is mormons.
Mormons,
like when you get the playbill
advertising advertisement.
Yes.
Yeah.
For the.
That is so great.
Yeah.
Now you've seen the play could come find
out,
would be in a mormon is really all about
like they think they're going to like,
like people go to like go watch that
hilarious parody of what their religion
is all about.
I think that maybe I'm taking it too
far,
but I feel like matt and trey are the
closest to twain that we have where it's
like what they're doing is brilliant
satire.
It's completely over the top and insane
and perfectly written and they're
fucking gangsters.
They get away with the craziest shit on
tv.
it's not.
Did you ever see the sloughed off with
paris hilton,
paris hilton and the gay guy who was the
teacher?
And the gay guy wins because he stuffs
paris hilton up his ass.
man,
he's stuffed her up.
They can get away with so much because
they're cartoons I know.
And they take on like,
like the idea of drawing.
Muhammad muhammad was teddy bear.
I saw that episode.
they take on things.
Where is this?
The sloughed off.
Watch this.
He shoves it up his ass.
He jumped on her in a gay cowboy outfit
all with the big mustache and shoved her
up his ass.
I mean.
And then they cheer the kanye west gay
fish one with the kanye west and carlos
mencia episodes.
It's one of the greatest take downs and
like a history of kind of stuff is too
good of,
of,
of a pop culture.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
that's what it honestly intimidates me
about los angeles is like matt and trey
are here,
you know,
like these people who I admire so much.
They just all live here in this area and
I.
It's too much for me.
I live in New York.
I just,
I like being away from it,
like intimidates you.
I feel like like I don't want to,
it's almost like I don't want to see
baton.
Trey lIke eating at a restaurant or
something.
Like I don't why?
I don't want to think the real.
I don't want to think that they're
mortal or something like it's too.
It's I like,
I love the mystique of show business.
So you like being in New York because
you're outside of it.
I live in brooklyn.
I don't.
I'm not part of the show business
really.
That's interesting.
You're here on the joe rogan experience
podcast to promote your new comedy cd.
Right.
Yet you claim to not be in show
business.
What do you do?
Mr bib?
I travel around the country.
I've gone to other cities.
Is here.
Oh,
you just traveL.
Professional.
Travel.
Traveler.
Professional traveler.
I always say that.
I always say to them that traveling
salesman,
I sell comedy.
I get paid to fly and performed for
prey.
That's funny.
It's true.
I'm going to fucking 100 cities next
year.
Wow.
Thank god for jokester.
100.
I'm Going to.
I'm going to forester,
which though it's called thank god for
jokes isn't the name of the tour.
Oh,
uh oh.
Thank god for jokes tour.
Yeah.
I thought you were saying thank god for
jokester,
like joke.
Show that thing that sends you out to
these places like friendster or you
remember that?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
Like it's a,
some kind of book.
You're shit way in advance.
You can see the photo.
Maybe if we can bring it up.
Thank god for.
Or just exec comm.
I don't know.
You,
you,
um,
you play In your shit out way in
advance.
Then if you're doing 100.
Yeah.
I've announced 30.
What are the obscure places?
Because they go to fargo.
Oh yeah.
Here you go.
Go to fargo or minneapolis.
I'm going to traverse city,
Michigan,
east,
lansing fargo,
minneapolis,
minneapolis is not obscure now.
Now I guess you know,
but like eugene,
Oregon,
that's obscure ones.
Pretty obscure hippy place.
Lotta,
lotta like petrouli people in that
audience.
I was in New York.
That's kind of obscure,
obscure as fuck.
Where do you play there?
Uh,
there's no place to play.
Go to some dude's house.
I mean,
I'm going to charleston charleston's
kinda.
Well that's kind of a name though.
I think I could name 100 different
cities.
I mean I probably could if you sat me
down.
Yeah.
Someone put a blank map in front of you.
You get it.
Kentucky.
Huh?
Doing a little Kentucky.
Kentucky.
Louisville is fun and then it was a
great town.
It's a great town.
Here's the thing I've found about
traveling around America.
I'm sure you've probably found this.
A lot of great little towns will also
mike birbiglia fans.
they know who you are that I'm going to
show up.
They're in a good mood.
Yeah.
they're already.
They're already familiar with you.
You know,
like you go to like boise,
Idaho.
It's like,
oh,
this is a nice town.
Boise's great people make fun of these
towns.
And then you go there.
You're like,
oh no,
there's like five grade breakfast spots.
You know what I mean?
By the way,
might be a better place to live and it
might be a bad place to live.
Yeah.
That's tension.
Less stress.
Less traffic.
That's the one thing that stupid About
la is the massive humans all gathered
into one place.
It's insane.
It's a great place to have a podcast
because you could always get guests,
you know,
there's always people here,
but as far as like having sanity and
having peace and clarity,
this is not the best bot.
What's in santa barbara?
Coffee.
Try this nurse.
Do you like anything sweet?
I'll try that.
It's just stevia.
It's super strong.
It's a natural sweetener.
Only put a little bit in.
Okay.
So it's very powerful.
I already had butter in the coffee so I
feel like it's covered dishes,
but like los angeles is crazy because
like coming here for example,
I just google map everything on the way
and then it's like it'll be like A,
it's 26 miles and then for time it'll be
like,
it might take days.
That's no joke either.
You can get stuck in bumper to bumper
traffic,
a tukul just a little dash of that
stuff.
Don't fuck around.
Don't get crazy crazy.
My grandma trying not to just throw in a
little stevia in there.
Just that little bit more of that get a
little crazy.
They go,
stop right there.
It's amazing.
It's really strong stuff.
But this,
this sounds crazy.
It's uh,
it just,
it feels dangerous.
It feels like I'm in at risk of being in
a car accident at any moment.
well,
you're at west wintertime.
You're in a car,
you know the,
the.
It's an amazing really.
When you stop thinking about it really
good by the great,
right?
Yeah.
It's amazing when you to think about how
few car accidents there actually are the
ones in my special,
which I hope you'll watch,
but I watch it.
I'm very proud of.
I say I hope.
Well,
there's no need for hope's.
Okay.
So I get.
I talk about how I was hit by a car in
los angeles and then that was made to
pay for the drunk driver's car.
Really drunk driver.
I was made to pay for his cars.
His written maddening.
How you made to pay for his car.
He technically had the right away.
I was turning right.
He was speeding around a blind corner.
He technically had the right away.
And then by the time he got to the
hospital,
he blew under the legal limit once in a
while.
So I wanted to take before you get paid
$12,000
for his car,
like a couple hours later.
Wow.
That's hilarious.
Now I don't test them right away.
Nope.
In this instance,
no.
And then.
And so the thematic really what it's
about is about how like I couldn't let
go of it.
Like it sounds like you have this from,
you know,
when I listened to you on the podcast,
like certain times you're obsessed with
being right about something.
And I couldn't let this go.
I like,
it was kinda like this with the papers,
it's like I have charts and graphs and I
was like,
I was like,
and this is and this is the accident
report and this is the map is the google
map of the scene of the accident.
And it was,
it was 60 feet from here to the stop
sign and the speed limit was 35 and it
was in his matt onstage with like lenny
bruce at the end of his career when he
would go on with legal document.
You'll,
you'll see in this special I project to
the accident report.
The actual report.
Yeah.
It's bonkers.
I project the extra part in the show.
It's great.
It's so the guy was drunk.
He,
but he technically had the right away.
I'm trying to figure it out in my mind.
You were going around a blind corner and
coming around blind corners.
he was coming around,
we're speeding around a blind corner on
venice beach.
And you pulled into the trap.
I pulled into a,
into a road and then he t boned me
driver's side.
Wow.
and then.
And then I spun around and then he,
um,
drove away,
took a right turn at the intersection,
tried to speed away,
but he was so drunk he drove into a
tree.
So it was like a hit and run and hit and
still didn't get in trouble for that.
Yeah.
That's saying,
I talked to lawyers,
I talked to private investigators.
They were just like,
dude,
it's going to cost you more in legal
fees to fight this.
You know?
I was like,
I'm going to sue this guy and I'm going
to sue the los angeles police
department.
Like I was like,
chinatown,
chinatown.
It was maddening.
Well,
in the effort to protect people's
rights,
things get kind of squirrely.
Yeah,
I'm all for protecting people's rights,
but I think that once you start driving
intoxicated and slamming into people
like they need to figure out who's drunk
right away after an accident,
you can't let people go all the way to
the hospital again.
Fine.
You need that.
That's something that needs to be dealt
with on the spot,
but the question is,
who's going to be the guy who deals with
it?
It's going to be some knucklehead police
officer that's we're going to hold you
down,
tase you,
and then take your blood.
I mean,
how do they,
how do they get it?
They got to have blood,
right?
Don't they have to take.
They can test your blood alcohol
content.
They do the breathalyzer thing,
right.
But yeah,
the most accurate ways his blood and
that's way you could.
We could be on pills too.
Yeah,
that's true.
That's true.
He could be on drugs.
Yeah,
it,
when I went,
I went to the hospital just to make sure
I was okay.
I went to the emergency room and they
saw him first because he was a more
urgent case.
I don't know what had happened to him,
but I fucking tree.
That's.
Yeah,
exactly.
And I said to the doctor,
I was like,
was the other guy drunk?
and the doctor says,
well,
you know,
I can't answer that.
This is the same doctor.
So both of us.
And I was like,
well,
was he,
you know,
and uh,
and he goes,
well,
he's heading the jail now.
And uh,
and at the time I was like,
case closed,
you know,
like I thought like I was like,
I was like,
oh,
this isn't going to be an issue.
And then a couple of months later I get
the bill for his car.
It was maddening.
That's so crazy.
Who's this asshole?
What's his name?
I can't say,
fuck this guy,
I am.
I considered,
I don't saY this in the show,
but if there were certain points I
considered,
I had his phone number,
it was on the accident report.
I consider just calling him and being
like,
you should know that you are ruining my
life.
Hmm.
Well,
I think that's been a little bit
dramatic for isn't really ruining your
life.
It was just making you crazy,
but the fact that you have to pay for
them or let's be honest,
I'm just saying that's how I felt.
A couple of a couple of jokes and that
taken care of.
you're in a very fortunate position in
life.
Maybe you should cut your losses.
Thanks joe.
But you got comedy acts,
this 2020 insight hindsight.
Yeah.
It's really easy reflection.
I would have went to his house and
kicked his ass.
Locked up in jail.
You the least.
She got comedy out of it though,
right?
I mean,
I feel great.
I mean honestly the comedy is everything
to me.
I.
That's why.
Thank you.
But thank god for jokes.
Tore my new show that I'm developing is
actually all about how to like jokes are
in a certain way.
My religion,
like they're there.
They're the philosophy that I believe
in.
I believe life iS hard and then we make
jokes about it because it's all we can
do and it makes it more fun.
Yeah.
Still to this day,
stand up comedy is one of my favorite
things to watch.
I still enjoy it very much as an
audience member and if someone told me
that I could never perform comedy for
the rest of my life for some strange
reason,
but I could still watch it.
I was still love watching it.
Yeah,
it's great man.
I thought stan hope specialists year.
The beer hall push I think is how you
pronounce it.
Yeah.
That was like one of the best comedy
specials I've ever seen.
It was a really good one.
That was my wife and I were just like,
it was like a euphoric experience that
you have is watching it.
Yeah.
He's uh,
he's working hard man.
And one of the things that stand helps
doing is he's like,
really?
He is that guy.
He lives in the desert.
He lives in this weird fucking town,
Arizona.
That's base bisbee,
Seven miles from the mexican border.
He invites people over to his house for
a,
for superbowl parties.
I know he's a nut.
I mean,
he's a legit nut.
He's a great guy too.
He's really.
He's really like,
come into his own as an artist,
as a standup comedian.
That special is if there are any
aspiring comedians listening or
watching.
See that special before turning the gun
on himself as a great one too.
He's got a bunch of great ones.
He's got lots of good stuff.
This is the one where he talks about
letting his mother go.
Yeah.
That's an incredible story.
It's good stuff,
man.
I couldn't live in bisbee,
Arizona.
I don't know what the fuck is thinking.
He's just very strange.
I don't know how to describe what that
man.
He's got a great joke about lIving there
too though.
The idea of it being an artist community
and the difference between how his art
and there are.
It doesn't really go together.
They make turquoise belt buckles and
he's making a joke about tsunami
victims,
about how the the drowned japanese,
they start to swell and they take on
this korean look and I'm really
butchering the pit,
but it's fucking hilarious.
It's comparison between his art,
what he considers art and what they
consider art artists community.
You know,
one of the things I love about him is
hilt keeps twisting the knife and
different directions.
Yeah.
Like he'll take you one way and you'll
be like,
ooh,
I don't know if I could go there and
then he'll take you back farther in the
other direction farther,
right.
Than you could think you get go and then
I'll pull you farther left than you
thought.
You know what I mean?
Like he just always has you on your
toes.
He works,
you know that dude.
You see him sitting there smoking a
cigarette,
drinking coffee,
banging away on the keyboard,
you know?
And that is a,
like you said,
you know what you're saying,
that jokes or your religion.
Yeah.
That the discipline of creation is
really what it's all about.
Whether you're writing books,
whether you're writing jokes,
whether you're creating music,
whatever.
I admire the discipline involved and
creating things.
Anything,
podcasts,
music,
movies,
whatever the fuck you're making.
Matt and trey making south park and also
having some strange amount of time to
make the book of mormon as well.
You see that documentary about matt and
trey from south park is great nuts.
People should watch this on netflix.
It's called like 60,
60 seconds.
The air or something like that.
What is it?
Sixty minutes to air.
Six days to say area.
Super good.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
It's for instance,
inspirational too and you realize what a
bad mother fucker that.
Well both of them but yeah,
but trey bad motherfucker.
Yeah.
That guy's not nonstop.
Yeah,
he's just a nut,
but I think he obviously gets off on it.
I mean that's his thing.
He loves creating that fucking show and
that show such a perfect vehicle to.
Because by doing little cartoon kids
that don't look anything like reality
now and then also having them be kids.
So there's like a certain mount of
ignorance you can get away with a child,
sort of beautiful vehicle for creating
comedy when you write like all this shit
that you've got in front of you here.
Whereby do I feel heat?
Where's he coming from?
Space heater.
Oh,
that's what it is.
I was like,
man,
I know it heats broken.
You have to get someone to climb on the
roof,
turn her fucking pilot light on.
How retarded is up when you write,
do you sit down and go,
okay,
today I'm going to write from 8:00
AM to 10:00
AM or what?
I mean,
how do you do it?
I build it from like,
like it's like I built.
I brainstorm stories.
So like I'll like,
I'll talk to my brother joe who co
writes a lot of stuff with me and we'll
just talk.
Like one time this happened to me,
one time this happened to me.
One time this happened to me and we'll
talk about on the phone for like a
couple hours,
you know,
and then we'll talk about which,
which ones are good enough stories that
are worth telling.
And then,
uh,
and then I'll,
and then I'll go out and try it on stage
and I'll record it and I'll go back and
transcribe what I said and then I'll
edit from that transcription.
That's interesting.
So you,
you cowrite with your brother.
How long have you been doing that for?
Ten years.
Does your brother to stand up at all
now?
He tried.
He,
he doesn't like it at stage,
but he enjoys the creative process.
Is writing super funny guy and uh,
but he doesn't like being onstage.
What does he do for a living?
He works for me.
Oh really?
So he's a writer for you?
Yeah,
writer,
producer,
cowrote.
My movie sleepwalk with me.
Oh,
that's so cool.
Yeah,
the sleepwalk with me was really
interesting for folks.
Don't know mike,
uh,
for folks that don't know,
mike is your,
you're a sleepwalker.
Yeah,
I jumped,
I dangerously,
I jumped through a second story window
nicely.
Yeah.
And uh,
you talked about that on the podcast
last time you were here.
And that movie is sort of based on that,
on how weird that thing must be to have
that in you.
The ability to just get up and start
doing things while you're actually
asleep.
Yeah,
it's.
Yeah.
It's.
And it's.
And I still deal with it.
I sleep in a sleeping bag to this very
day.
I go to bed and I asleep and asleep.
Give,
bring a sleeping bag when you go,
like camping when you go to tyler road.
Yeah,
exactly.
They're camping when I met her.
Zip yourself up so you can't get up
myself up.
I used to wear mittens so I couldn't
open the sleeping bag.
The doctor told me the strangest things
that doctor has ever told me.
He goes,
I want you to go to bed at night and a
sleeping bag and sleep,
zip yourself up and then wear mittens so
you can't open the sleeping bag,
a doctor.
So that to me,
strange.
Wow.
Well this is after he jumped out the
window.
Yeah,
he was just,
he was a woman actually,
that my doctor now is a male.
But,
uh,
it was,
yeah,
she,
she was just like,
I'm not sure what to tell you.
In the meantime,
just do this with what floor do you live
on in New York?
We live on my bedroom's on the second
floor,
but we have these really super
reinforced shutters that we put in that
are pretty expensive just to keep you
from jumping through the window.
Yeah,
yeah.
It was strange.
I know.
Yeah.
You don't want to jump on the second
floor in manhattan.
Where did you jump?
No,
in brooklyn.
Um,
I jumped through the second story window
of la quinta inn in walla walla,
Washington.
As a matter of fact,
there's a plaque if you might be able to
google this laquinta inn birbiglia
plaque while back.
There's a plaque on the door of the
room,
why birbiglia jumped through this window
and there was a movie based on it.
And it's like,
because you're here and you're fine if
you died then,
you know.
Yeah.
It's um,
ira glass who wrote the movie and
produced the movie with me,
hosted this american life on public
media.
He,
um,
he was insistent that we get the plaque
put up that it was like he didn't care
about like oscars or golden gloves.
He was just like here,
like the out the plaque and ruined
january 26,
2005 comedian mike birbiglia sleep
walked out the window.
That story became the basis for the book
of the feature film.
Sleepwalk with me.
Seriously google it.
It was not great.
What a weird world we live in that.
That's a plaque.
Seriously.
Google it is on the plaque.
Yeah.
Wow.
Ira was really intent on getting a
plaque on the room.
He was like,
that was everything to him.
where's the plaque?
Is the plaque up yet?
It was like six months after I sent it
to them.
And so that's on the door.
Just as your walking by.
That's on the door.
People sometimes will go to that
laquinta inn.
They'll take photos in front of it and
then tweet it.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
Oh,
but you get a lot more now.
That's hilarious.
That's really fucking fun.
Well,
it's hilarious again,
because you're okay now when you,
when you jumped through the wall,
like when you jumped out the window,
the window through the window shattered.
Oh,
jump through.
And I have in the movie,
in the final credits,
there's actual photo
graphs of after I jumped through the
window,
I photographed it like it was a crime
scene because I was alone in walla
walla,
Washington,
and I was like,
nobody's going to believe me.
Right,
right,
right.
Did the hospital all this stuff.
But I was like,
this is too crazy of a story.
I need to photograph everything.
So it's all in the credits.
How did you get through that without
even getting really badly hurt?
Be the same reason that a lot times of
drunk drivers aren't hurt.
They're the ones not injured.
You know what I mean?
When they get in car accidents because
they're so relaxed,
so relaxed.
That's so crazy.
The idea that tension is what hurts you.
I dreamt.
I dreamt that I was being,
that there was a guided missile headed
towards my hotel room.
There's all this military personnel in
the room with me and the missile.
Could they,
the,
they told me that missile coordinates
are set specifically on me and so I
thought the only thing I could do is
jump out the window so as to detonate
outside the window for the sake of my
platoon.
Wow.
What are you are a hero in your crazy
story?
I know head.
Wow.
That's.
Fuck.
Now,
what was the extent of your injuries?
I just had,
I still have scars on my legs and there
was glass in my legs and they took out
the glass and uh,
and my arms were all cut up and I had
about 30 stitches.
That's nothing.
It's nothing.
It's nothing compared to what it could
have been.
Wow.
And what's wild is I actually jumped
through the window and landed and then
got up and kept running.
So you were still asleep?
Yeah.
Wow.
As I'm running
running,
I'm looking around and realizing like,
oh,
I just jumped through a window in walla
walla,
Washington,
and I was like,
oh no.
And I was like,
I guess I got to go to the front desk
and explain what happened.
Oh my god,
this is a funny addendum to the story.
I feel bad for my fans.
Your fans.
Maybe maybe you have seen the movie and
maybe having my fans have heard this a
zillion times.
I feel bad,
but I'll give you an addendum to the
story which is new,
which is.
I always say that I walked to the front
desk to explain what happened.
Fortunately,
the person working at the front desk was
mildly retarded.
And I say fortunately because he's
completely unfazed.
But what just happened?
It's three in the morning.
The phones are ringing off the hook from
people staying at the hotel who just saw
the guy jumped out the window screaming,
I'm bleeding in my underwear and I say
hello,
because you have to start somewhere.
I'm staying at the hotel.
I had an incident where I jumped out my
window.
I'm bleeding and I need to see a doctor.
And,
and I,
and I was so relieved because,
uh,
the guy working at the front desk goes,
right?
It was like completely unfazed.
What had just happened,
so I drove myself to the hospital.
He told me where it was.
The agenda is that guy who worked the
front desk facebook messaged me and
said,
hey,
I'm the guy at the front desk and I'm
not mildly retarded.
What's great is that the,
the,
the message is so incoherent that he
sent me that.
It's like,
well,
are you sure if I forwarded this to
someone?
They might take my side.
Oh my god.
That is such a crazy fucking story.
So from.
Did you.
Were you there for a weekend?
Like did you have to do stand up there?
The rest.
I was performing at whitman college that
night and then I was performing at
university of Oregon the next day and I
actually did the gig with all the
brokenness and I didn't tell anybody.
Wow.
So you just did the gig to understand
that the money you're broke and you were
just mangled cut up.
I wasn't,
nothing messed with my face up so no one
could tell I was wearing long sleeves
and everything.
That's so lucky.
It's unbelievably fortunate.
Yeah,
it was just,
it was,
honestly,
it was a moment in my life where I was
broke.
I was hustling so hard.
It all factored into the jump through
the window.
I was dealing with a lot of anxiety.
So the anxiety and the stress manifests
itself in the sleepwalking.
Yeah.
So,
so I,
I'm diagnosed with rem behavior
disorder,
which is a chemical imbalance.
It means people who have a dope,
some people who have a dopamine
deficiency,
which is the chemical that's released in
your brain and your body when you fall
asleep,
that paralyzes your body so you don't
act out your dreams.
That's essentially what happens when you
sleep is your body's paralyzed.
You can't do it.
I have a dopamine deficiency and as a
result I act out my dreams.
And so since then I was diagnosed,
so I take,
I shouldn't tell people that I take by
take an antianxiety yeah.
And then,
uh,
and it calms me down and then I don't
feel like I need in my dreams to run
away from things like why do you say you
shouldn't tell people what you take?
Well,
because I'm not a doctor,
so I don't want to tell you,
I don't want people to self diagnose and
go,
oh,
I have that.
And it's like you don't really know.
I did a sleep study.
I slept overnight at the hotel,
at the hospital for nights.
Like they really know what I have.
Yeah.
Well that's very responsible of you.
You know?
Yeah.
So when you start taking this
medication,
even though you're taking this
you still don't trust yourself.
You stills up?
Yeah,
kinda like a condom over a birth control
pill.
Wow.
Well,
I guess once you jump out of a fucking
window,
got to get some reinforcement bars over
your windows.
Mandy worried about break ins?
Nope.
Breakouts,
breakouts.
The crazy breakouts we're trying to keep
it in.
Wow.
Yeah.
And so by taking an anti anxiety
medication,
has that changed you like your regular,
everyday life?
I'd like to think no.
Uh,
I fear sometimes.
I mean like,
you know,
I,
um,
I feel like what I take for a while,
it felt like it made me a bit fuzzy
feeling when I wake up in the morning.
I have to drink a lot of coffee to get
to regular,
which I don't love.
Right.
And it's all because of that.
Yeah.
Is there any natural cure?
Is there anything that you've been going
to a holistic doctor recently who's been
given for as though.
Oh,
you don't think that's good?
I don't know.
I just always say that holistic doctor,
all those motherfuckers,
she took a,
she took like a 10 vials of blood and
did a whole thing on which vitamins I
should take to counterbalance things.
And uh,
I feel like that's leveling me off a
little bit.
Would you watch your diet?
Are you fairly healthy?
Try to,
yeah.
Trying to have protein in the morning
and stuff like that.
But do you like gluten?
And I'm trying to wean myself off of it.
You eat gluten.
I stopped about six months ago.
How do you feel about it?
A lot better.
Well,
I stopped when I was filming this show.
I was having back problems from jujitsu
and one of the things that this woman
who's a physical therapist told me,
she said real good results.
People that have injuries getting off of
gluten reduces inflammation and in a lot
of the symptoms of the injuries subside.
And I was like,
wait,
wait a minute,
you can tell me like bread,
like stopping bread makes an injury
better.
And she's like,
you really would be amazed.
And so,
uh,
I tried it and uh,
I,
my injury got better,
like slowly petroleum its own through a
lot of different therapies that I was
doing.
But what was amazing was my energy level
is different.
My energy level,
especially after meals.
That was the most shocking thing.
Like I would,
I eat so much bread and pasta and then I
was realized that like after I had
eaten,
it was like I got hit with a
tranquilizer dart.
I just thought that's what it was.
I thought I.
And this is what happens after you eat.
Eating is like sex,
but no man,
not now.
Now I eat and after I'm done eating,
I'm full but I'm not in a coma.
Yeah,
it's weird.
It's a totally different experience for
me because my basically my whole life,
I mean I'm italian mostly and most of my
life I grew up eating like that,
eating pasta and bread with every meal
and when I stopped eating it it was
like,
oh,
this is what had been dealing with my
whole life for no reason.
Like every time I eat I would eat these
big giant meals.
I'd be like,
oh,
I just kicked back and I know that
feeling that don't get that anymore.
Now I eat and you know,
obviously my body's digesting,
I feel full and I don't feel like
sedated los angeles is great for that.
New york is good for that,
but like when you travel,
do you have a hard time finding the food
that you want?
Steak and salad,
steak salad,
chicken salad.
I'm not ridiculous about it because I
don't have celiac's disease.
It's not like a half to avoid it.
So you know,
if something is breaded or you know,
it doesn't kill me,
it just,
it just.
I think it sets me back a little bit.
I think your body's not designed to pro.
The wheat that we eat today is very
different from the wheat that people had
100 years ago in the 19 fifties and
sixties is when they started engineering
wheat to be more hardy,
so for better yields and so it could
survive pesticides and whatnot and that
we is much more difficult for people to
process just is.
It's a fact that's a science.
Yeah,
I mean there,
there is science behind that.
So when people talk about,
oh,
it's just another fad,
it's just another fad.
It's actually not,
you know,
there,
there were most certainly fads,
you know,
as far as,
like the atkins diet and all these
various diets that can work,
you know,
they,
they can have an effect,
you know,
you go into ketosis,
I guess it's called and you know,
your body starts burning fat instead of
carbohydrates and I tried that.
I didn't like it at all.
This is very different.
This to me seems like cutting out
something that my body really just
doesn't enjoy process.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
No,
I mean I still look,
I'm not a.
I'm not a perfect eater.
I still eat ice cream and I still drink
milk.
And what do you do about pizza?
Gluten free pizza.
I don't.
I try it.
It's dark shit.
It's dog shit.
I haven't had pizza in alongside format
to have pizza.
Yeah,
I haven't had pizza and like it's been
at least six or seven months since I've
had except some gluten free pizza,
which was uh,
I just,
uh,
I made a tweet about it.
I said I'm having gluten free pizza and
to let you know,
you don't have to,
don't ever just don't.
It's not pizza,
it's nonsense.
Someone said there's a good kind out
there,
but I think that just builds fucking
people that don't want to believe.
Yeah.
I don't know.
But uh,
as far as like health,
I think the majority of people don't get
enough.
The big issue I think as far as
nutrition is,
is green leafy vegetables and uh,
and,
and lots of vegetables.
People just don't eat enough vegetables.
And if you don't eat enough vegetables
and you also don't take vitamins.
Yeah,
good luck.
You know,
your body's just basically operating on
proteins and carbohydrates and whatever
the fuck it can find,
but you're not getting enough vitamins.
You're just not like the idea of a
balanced diet.
Most people's diet or they're not even
close to balanced.
It's like I've watched friends like,
been like on,
on the road,
like comics.
I've been with them for every meal,
you know,
and I've watched what they eat and like
you,
you're not getting anywhere like you
got.
You got an egg in there.
Yeah.
There's some bread in that.
I think there's a piece of lettuce.
They're like,
where the fuck you getting your vitamins
from,
man?
Yeah,
I think I'm in that boat.
Do you take supplements?
You take vitamins.
I just started to like two months ago.
Just started.
Really?
Wow.
You're so disappointed.
No,
sorry.
It's interesting.
Did you notice a difference once you
started taking vitamins?
Yeah.
I feel better.
I have.
Everybody's on starving.
Yeah,
your vitamin starved.
I invited him and starved.
Yeah,
but most of us are.
If you eat the average quote unquote
average american diet,
your vitamin starved.
Yeah.
It's,
it's hard to travel and be healthy.
It is what I started doing nights or
doing yoga and I travel.
I feel better.
I feel a lot better than that.
That's because of all the girls
that yoga pants in the class.
It makes you feel better too.
Is that what it is?
Excited.
Maybe I'm misunderstanding the whole
thing.
No yoga.
I could just go to the yoga pants or.
Yeah,
you can just go to a strip club and you
feel great.
Well,
I started going to strip clubs in the
road and I just,
uh,
I really,
it really picked me be I wrote down a
strip club name.
I played largo the other night and
there's a place across from it that,
I don't know what it's called in the
phone book,
but the name on the outside of the door
is star strip is all the same font and
font size.
Star strip.
Totally nude live nude girls,
girls,
girls.
The star strip on la cienega.
Yeah.
Dude,
I had a bit about that it true story,
um,
where the girl was dancing and I said,
hey,
do you,
do you like doing this?
She goes,
I don't talk to guys who come here.
And I said,
well,
why?
I mean it's an open door.
I mean,
like,
nice people can come through too.
And she goes,
well,
most guys who come here,
the only come here for one reason.
I mean,
why did you come here?
Like she was shutting me down and I
said,
because someone told me there was a
place that I could do go where I could
see a strange girl's pussy for a dollar.
And that was the joke.
Like,
I'm the asshole.
I only did it show up where you work,
right?
I'm not a bad person because you work
here,
you know,
different people go to different places,
different reasons to go to strip clubs a
lot.
And you know,
it turned me off.
I was in nashville once,
I saw a commercial on tv for a strip
club and I was like,
I would like,
that seems fun.
I'll go there.
And uh,
and they went and then I gave the guy my
id when I walked in and he goes,
hey mike birbiglia,
I like your comedy.
And I was just like,
I'm never going to a strip club again.
I've never gone back.
Why?
Because I liked the anonymity of it.
I don't want to be,
I don't want anyone to watch me watch
someone beating it.
I just,
I'm not,
I can't handle that.
You need a wig and a fake mustache and
if you have a wig or a fake mustache
one,
we're in hollywood.
There's plenty of stores.
Yeah,
I,
that's why I'm here.
Sorry.
It took so long for me to get to the
point.
But uh,
yeah.
Do you have like a costume I can wear
because I'm really want to go guy.
And he goes,
no,
no.
It's funny you should say that about
you're asking like why,
why,
why the woman was there and everything.
Because that's when I used to go to
strip clubs.
That was what I was most interested in
the story.
I want to know the story.
How did you get here?
And maybe,
maybe it's kind of mean spirited and
suddenly,
but I actually,
it is interesting to me.
I don't think it's mean spirited.
No,
I mean you can have a look.
I have been to many a strip club with my
dad and I've had some fun conversations
with girls who are dancers.
It wasn't
demeaning,
it wasn't meant it respectfully.
When I would do it.
Very nice people,
they just happen to be dancers.
There's nothing wrong with it,
man.
I think there's a weird sort of a
connection between standup comics and
strippers anyway because they were.
Our worlds are so odd in comparison to
the average person,
oddly similar,
I think in a lot of ways.
Well,
because standup comedy,
you're as naked as you can be.
Yes.
Verbally and you're talking about,
you're talking about your life,
the best comedians essentially as you're
watching them make it a certain way.
Absolutely.
And you know,
and that's obviously the strippers who
literally.
Yeah.
And you're also living this weird
alternative life that most people can't
relate to it.
Most people with nine to five jobs can't
relate to.
Very strange.
Yeah.
Like if you did a stripper and she comes
over your house at 3:00
in the morning after she gets off work
and she's got a little glitter bag full
of money and it's like we're both weird,
you know,
I just got done telling jokes and
drinking on stage and here you got off
stage.
That's what they're weird lives.
Being an actor is a weird life if you
didn't act or strange.
Yes,
but in a more,
a less naked way.
And your wife,
girlfriends,
like making out with some guy in the
day.
True work over and over again.
That's ridiculous.
After take.
Fuck that.
Yeah,
I've seen that before.
I've seen people like watch their wives
or girlfriends a make out with other
guys like tongue and everything and
watch him and watch her and watch him
and watch her and go,
I don't want to do that.
Yeah,
but the acting thing is like the
opposite of being naked.
It's like putting on a fucking outfit
or.
You think so?
Yeah.
I don't think it's naked at all.
I think the acting is,
is putting on armor that's putting on
this armor of this bullshit character
that some writer created and you're
pretending to be this person,
whereas.
No,
but I think the best ones are opening
up,
opening up.
They're opening up their souls.
I think the best ones,
the best actors.
I mean they become that guy,
but I mean like,
okay,
here's a perfect example.
A christian bale in the machinist.
He wasn't really an anorexic,
that was the.
Couldn't sleep and he forced himself to
do that.
He just became that guy for that role.
It was a,
it was,
uh,
it was an affectation.
He put it on.
It was a costume.
It was a,
you know,
a role he played.
It wasn't him who.
He decided to be me.
We can find areas in ourselves.
That's one of the weirdest fucking that
is so weird that he was bullying.
It's him next to batman when he was
fucking swole,
which is only like six months later.
I think the one,
the photo on the left is real.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He starved himself.
He ate like a can of tuna and an apple
like every day.
That's all he ate and he got down to an
insanely small size.
I think he was to like 130 pounds or
something ridiculous like that.
He's a big guy and then he went up to
200 plus when he played batman.
Yeah.
Pretty nuts,
man.
That guy's nuts that,
that,
that thing that they do.
Like I just got back from last week and
I saw dallas buyers club here.
Matthew mcconaughey.
Fucking fantastic.
Heard.
It's great.
I have a friend who always shits on
matthew mcconaughey and thinks that
matthew mcconaughey's correcting is
terrible.
Matthew mcconaughey is like,
his ego is transparent and is acting.
It's mostly because my friends in actor,
but uh,
I said,
dude,
you got to watch dallas buyers club and
then shut the fuck up because the guy
knocks it out of the park is fantastic
in it.
I saw two movies this weekend.
I saw,
I saw the catching fire.
I liked it with catching fire.
The hunger games movie.
How dare you say that?
Why nothing.
I know.
Everybody makes fun of me.
I like gravity.
I don't know.
It was good.
I enjoyed it.
I,
you know what I thought was fascinating
about gravity,
which watching neil degrasse tyson a
tweet about everything that's wrong,
the movie and then watching people
attack him because I saw a lot of that
because neil degrasse tyson is like,
he's one of those guys that I don't
think ever takes heat,
you know,
because he's such a nice guy.
He's so brilliant.
He's so well informed about the ways of
the universe and so excellent at
expressing himself.
He's one of the best representatives of
science I think we have today,
and he always gets love everywhere.
He goes like everybody's all these
internet memes of pictures of him.
Then this came out and he starts
correcting the movie and the fucking
hate.
You can't correct a Sandra Bullock
movie.
He just can't.
Yeah,
you can't hate on Sandra Bullock.
They fucking went after him.
Well,
neil degrasse tyson says his criticisms
of gravity or a compliment to its
quality.
Huh?
That's,
that's because he took.
I took the hit the right to.
To earn the right to be criticized as a
high compliment indeed.
What?
Hmm.
That sounds like a guy fucking feeling
the heat talking nonsense,
feeling the heat.
Some people criticize the story of the
movie and I was like,
you know,
I felt like 10 minutes in I was like,
I got my $15 worth.
I never thought that I'd know what it
felt like to go to space.
Yeah.
I love the fact that everything was
silent.
Me too.
He's like in the middle of the
explosions and all this shit.
It's silent and yet you're still
freaking the fuck out is actually more
effective.
I thought.
Did you see the director's movie?
Children of men.
Children of men?
Yes.
I saw.
Yeah.
That was the one where people are like,
the males are like,
the people can't breed or something.
Yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
The,
um,
the thing that I found was most
fascinating about gravity,
um,
was the,
just the idea that people do really go
up there and really do stay up there for
long periods of time and space and they
really are in grave danger and they
this,
this possibility of things colliding and
space junk to very real,
real problem.
Yeah.
This fucking thousands of things
floating around above the earth.
Thousands.
It's so insane.
I'd love,
I'd love john august,
the screenwriter made this point that I
think is of brilliant about it,
which is what's exciting about the
movies.
It's $100 million dollar movie major
budget movie where the lead character
doesn't save the world.
She just saves herself.
And that's powerful.
Yeah.
What people didn't like to.
A lot of people didn't like the george
clooney guy because it was just so.
And the other thing was when he lets go
when he has to let go because it's
pulling him away.
There's no momentum in space.
People said the science if it's wrong.
Yeah,
science is so wrong.
I was fine with that though because I
don't know much about science.
The science is not just wrong about
that,
it's also wrong about the positions of
the various space stations,
like they're not anywhere near each
other.
Like what she did by skipping from one
to the next would be absolutely
completely impossible there.
They're not in the same hemisphere that
nowhere near to each other.
I just gave it the benefit,
the benefit of the doubt because she had
that weird divorce because of Jesse
James.
He gave this movie the benefit of the
doubt.
That's how it works.
We'll let it go with the science stuff
just because she's had a hard time last
couple of years.
Yeah,
that's sweet of you.
Yeah.
Well I'm,
I'm,
you know,
I'm a big fan of anything space.
I think space is probably the most
overlooked thing.
Fascinating.
The history of humanity.
It's incredible.
Which still have enough light.
I feel that way about the see the
season.
Other one.
Yeah.
The sea and space are the two most
interesting places I think.
Yeah,
the sea less so for me,
but still pretty fucking fascinating.
You know,
it's basically like a jungle or
underwater.
I loved what you were tweeting the other
day about black fish because I think
that that's a great cause.
Oh yeah.
We had the filled dimmers who was a
trainer over at seaworld or whatever the
heck it was,
marine land in Canada.
That was depressing.
I know it's miserable,
but it's good that you're tweeting about
it because it's a good cause.
Yeah,
I agree.
It is.
Um,
I see life very fascinating to me.
Intelligency life even more so.
I just think people are very.
This is not funny or an item here or
there,
but I just think people are generally
unwilling to accept sea life and animals
as having an intelligence that we just
don't understand.
Well,
they certainly to mean there,
there's no doubt about it.
When,
when you talk to people who understand
orcas are or dolphins,
they're very intelligent.
Yeah.
Just intelligent in a different way
because they don't alter their
environment.
And as we were talking about space,
about how fascinating spaces that the
real issue is,
if we treat intelligent lifeforms on
this planet that we can understand the
way that we do,
especially helpless ones essentially
help us once,
like orcas and dolphins,
they really can't do anything to prevent
us from doing what we want them to do.
It really can't prevent us from
kidnapping them.
They can just try to run away,
but they can't fight back.
They really can't do anything.
What w what?
What are.
What is an alien race going to do to us?
If they ever get ahold of us,
oh,
I'm so worried.
And they see how we treat intelligent
life forms.
Why would they respect us?
Why would they want to do anything?
Why would they?
Why would they be kind?
Why would they give us information?
Why would they try to help us evolve?
They'd go,
well,
it's going to go.
Aliens is going to go.
And it's not an if it's a.
When when the aliens come or we arrive
at the aliens,
it's going to go one of two ways.
We enslave them,
they enslave us.
That's it,
that's the only version of what can
happen or we eat them or they know.
Oh,
we fucked up.
Right.
Yeah.
Do you,
do you,
um,
ever get a chance when you do an all
your travel?
Do you ever get a chance to go to any
observatories?
The cat in Hawaii or you know,
any of the telescopes I tried to,
yeah,
I haven't done it recently,
but yeah,
I tried to,
one of the most life changing things
I've ever done besides psychedelic drugs
and having kids is a,
going to the keck observatory.
Where is that?
It's on the big island of Hawaii.
Oh,
the fucking view of the stars is so mind
blowing.
You can't believe it's real because
you're,
you're on the island.
It's 9,000
feet above sea level as the visitors
place.
And then there's the main observatory,
which is higher than that.
You're literally,
I'm looking at the picture.
It's not evil.
You're above the clouds.
That's literally above the clouds as we
were driving,
you know,
um,
I was with my family and we were like,
oh,
this sucks.
It's cloudy.
We're going to miss it.
This is not going to work because we're
gonna we're going to get up there and
we're not gonna be able to see through
the clouds,
but then you pass through the clouds and
then you look up.
Oh,
that's nothing with what you're saying.
Yeah.
That's nothing.
The only thing I can compare to this is
Alaska have ever been to Alaska.
Yes.
Like faire.
Fairbank's is unbelievable.
I highly recommend people listening to
this.
I've never been to Hawaii and I want to
go there.
People have never been to.
Alaska should go to Alaska if you have
the man.
Oh,
no doubt,
because it is.
They sit,
you know,
they call it the last frontier and
everything,
but it really is.
It's undiscovered areas.
It's uncultivated areas and it's
stunning.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
I went salmon fishing with ari fear.
We went up there this year in july and
we caught salmon and did a gig up there
and I fell in love with the place.
It's incredible.
Anchorage is incredible.
Really fucking cool.
People too.
Like there's a.
There's a quality to the people that
live up there because they're.
They're living in a legitimate
wilderness,
they have a city and that city is
surrounded by absolute legit wilderness.
Like someone on the university of
anchorage campus last year got killed by
a fucking moose.
Yeah,
it happens.
A moose came on the campus and stomped
someone to death and that's like part of
their life.
Well,
that's the thing that the students are
very competitive.
I don't think that's what it was about.
Mike birbiglia.
Well,
you think it was the same article that I
will know I talked to.
The guy was there.
My friend is actually a professor at the
university.
I got a hit.
I'm going to conan right now.
I got to drive.
There.
Might have no wallet,
has no wallet,
so if you get in an accident,
I'm screwed.
And it's the same sort of situation is
the last time you'll be doubly screwed.
I'm.
I'm worried about my whole day to be
honest with you.
You want conan tonight?
Yes.
Tonight.
What time is it?
Eleven on tbs and there's a new show
after konan now.
Doesn't somebody else have a show now?
Pete holmes.
Very funny.
Pete holmes,
has it started yet?
Yeah,
he's really funny.
no,
I haven't really seen it.
Yeah,
it's not st pete.
Holmes isn't funny.
It's very funny.
How dare you,
you know,
it's,
it's on tbs.
I think it's in reruns right now,
but it was on for a few weeks and then I
think they're waiting here whether it
gets picked up,
but it's.
Yeah,
it's great.
So your new cd is called my girlfriend's
friend's boyfriend.
It's available now.
Itunes,
spotify,
girlfriend's boyfriend.com
is the site,
but I'm [inaudible] dot com.
Is your website
biggs is your twitter and its.
Yeah,
aLl that stuff.
Thanks for having me on
man.
Man.
I'm sorry.
We uh,
we,
we had little um,
miscommunication.
I thought you were going back and forth.
I thought you meant last week.
I thought you meant this week.
Oh yeah.
You were coming in town this week,
but you were actually.
This is your last day,
right?
You're here.
Yeah,
that worked out fine though.
Well next time you're here man.
Let's do a longer one.
People love you.
Thank you.
Go buy it.
Go buy a cd.
It's hilarious.
I'm sure all your stuff is great.
You're very funny comic and he's been to
check them out tonight on conan,
on tbs.
And uh,
that's It.
You fucks.
All right.
We'll uh,
we'll be back later today with the
wonderful cliffy be from epic games,
formerly of epic games.
Cliff,
he is a,
uh,
a renegade on his own.
Now he gives zero fucks a thank you to
our sponsors.
Thank you to lumosity.
Thanks.
Go to lumosity.com
forward slash joe and click the start
training button,
get your learn on sun,
pump your brain up,
get your freak on.
And thanks also to squarespace.
Squarespace.com
is the website.
Use the offer code joe and the number
12.
That's one word,
joe.
And the number 12.
And save 10 percent for a limited time.
That's squarespace.com.
Joe number 12,
one word.
Save yourself 10 percent off.
And on it.com.
It's o,
n n I t use the code road rogan and save
10 percent off any and all supplements.
All right,
it is right now.
One 30.
We will be back in a an hour and a half.
So we'll see you guys soon.