Hey everybody,
what the fuck's going on?
This episode of the podcast is brought
to you by diff eyewear diff.
I where they offer stylish,
handmade sunglasses constructed with
high end materials.
They're as good or better than designer
sunglasses without the $200 or $300
price tags instead diff sunglasses start
it,
just 50 bucks a pair and the best part
is for every pair of sunglasses you buy
diff.
That's dif.
Ef eyewear will give a pair of reading
glasses to someone in need and these are
excellent glasses and I wear them.
One of the reasons they have those old
school cop aviator ones with the
mirrors.
Those are fucking hard to get.
It's hard to give good quality old
school mirrored sunglasses,
goddammit.
No people don't want to look like a
creeper.
Not Me.
I relish it.
I like looking like a fucking creeper
with the mirrored sunglasses.
Why it was wrong is everybody has to
know what you're looking at.
You know why his mirror bad.
You don't want to look at yourself.
I like them anyway.
Excellent sunglasses and you can get
pretty much any color,
any color you like,
and still pay less than some designer
brands.
They're excellent.
I really enjoy him.
Very high quality.
I wear them all the time.
Have you see me go,
hey man,
is it.
If I were probably bitch,
what's with the questions anyway?
Do good by smarter.
Be diff.
Go to diff.
I were dif ef.
I wear.com/Rogan right now to get 15
percent off your purchase.
That's diff eyewear.com.
Forward Slash Rogan for 15 percent off
diff eyewear.com.
Forward Slash rogen.
We are also brought to you by Casper.
This podcast is supported by Casper,
an online retailer of premium mattresses
for a fraction of the price and our very
own young Jamie has one of these
mattresses.
They installed it in his house and he
fucking raves about it.
He loves it.
He said is the best mattress that he's
ever had and they are shockingly
ridiculously low priced in comparison to
premium mattresses made by other brands.
Why is that?
Because they've done the wise thing.
What they've done is they have cut out
the middleman and done what so many
companies are doing now.
They make really high quality stuff and
they sell it to you directly online.
These mattresses are made in America,
very high quality and they have a risk
free trial and return policy.
I really liked this.
You don't have to worry about it.
Try it for a full 100 days with free
delivery to the US and Canada and
painless returns.
What more do you want?
You can't.
You can't go wrong there folks.
Pricing is $500 for twin size mattresses
and 9:50 for a king size mattress.
Now,
if you go to a premium mattress store
and compare those,
I guarantee you you are not going to
find the same quality for anything close
to that kind of price.
So go try,
check it out and look,
you can't go wrong.
If you want to try this,
you get to try it for a fucking hundred
days.
Come on folks,
and there's a special offer for
listeners of this podcast.
You can get $50 towards any mattresses
by visiting www dot.
Why don't they have to put ww?
Everybody knows that casper.com forward
slash joe and using the Promo Code Joe
at checkout terms and conditions apply,
but again,
this is an awesome mattress.
It's an awesome deal and easy return
policy and an and an awesome guarantee.
Risk free trial and return casper.com
forward slash Joe.
Use the Promo Code [inaudible] at
checkout to save yourself 50 bucks and
we are also brought to you each and
every episode by on it.com,
Cota o n n it,
use the code word Rogan and you will
save 10 percent off any of our amazing
supplements like Alpha brain,
shroom,
tech,
sport,
new mood,
things that John Dudley and I talked
about in this very podcast.
That's who's my guest.
You flux on it.com o n n it again.
Use the Codeword Rogan.
Check out the onnit academy link because
it is filled with hundreds of pages of
awesome articles on exercise physiology,
strength and conditioning routines,
different diets.
The science of nutrition.
John's flexing right now in front of me.
It's also an awesome gym in Austin,
Texas.
The actual physical onnit academy,
a great state of the art workout
facility with great instruction and 10th
Planet Jiu Jitsu.
Go to [inaudible] dot com.
Get on it.
You know,
you want to Goddammit,
get your fucking shit together and get
on it.
Oh,
and [inaudible] dot com.
And that's it.
My guest today is my good friend,
my archery guru and my hunting buddy,
John motherfucking Dudley.
And we are in Iowa.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're uh,
we're Dudley ended up and um,
and we're talking,
we did an impromptu podcast,
some,
uh,
let you guys have it.
So here we go.
Without any further ado,
ladies and gentlemen,
the Great John Dudley,
Joe Rogan experience
podcast
coming at.
You live from Iowa,
a deep,
deep,
deep in the Midwest.
That's where we are,
right?
I don't know where it came from.
Really drew me.
It was inspired by the lack of diversity
in this town.
A lot of white people out here,
folks,
white people and corn.
You know that,
that term corn fed that was created in
Iowa.
Yeah,
for sure it was.
I'm having a great time out here,
John Dudley.
I've been out here with my pal,
John Dudley and uh,
getting some archery coaching and doing
a lot of bowhunting and we're um,
CNL dear man.
I was like,
made a deer and corn deer,
corn and beans and white people.
Yup.
It's awesome.
The deer out here.
Incredible.
I mean,
I've never seen so many white tail deer
in my life.
Definitely never seen.
We hunted for three days so far
unsuccessfully,
but had a great time,
saw a lot of deer and today at least had
a couple pretty close opportunities.
Just,
you know,
if you don't know anything about
bowhunting,
yeah.
You have to be a certain distance from
the animal.
Yeah.
I have to have a certain kind of shy.
It's not like a rifle for,
with a rifle,
an animal could be 300 yards away.
All you need is a steady rest and a good
rifle and that's,
that's a dead deer.
But with bow hunting,
no,
no.
You gotTa,
you really ideally want to be inside of
40 yards if you're,
you know,
if you can.
But what we're seeing is these big,
giant,
mature wild 250 300 pound mammals that
are running around here.
There are these,
you don't think of him that way,
but when you're around them,
like you're,
when you drive down the road,
oh look,
there's a deer.
But when you're hunting them and you
make eye contact with these things,
you kind of,
it changes the nature of what they are
to you.
Like,
let's talk about that.
Uh,
the experience that we had was there the
first day,
the second day,
the first day,
the first day we decided we had a couple
encounters.
Then we decided to come down off of the
stand and I decided we just,
we said 1:30 or 1:40.
We said we're going to stop.
Yeah.
I personally said 1:30 and then at 1:25
you said let's fail.
So this is how that always goes at 1:25,
we had been in the stance at 6:30 in the
morning and 1:25 I got down and as I'm
getting my stuff,
we'd climb all the way down from this
tree.
John puts his thumb on either side of
his head,
like bullwinkle to make the classic sign
of a deer antlers and this big ole
honking deer is coming down the way and
first a little deer came by and got
within 15 feet of me.
I wasn't going to say 10 feet.
It might be 10 feet of me.
I was standing by this tree.
Obviously I'm in all camel and I'm not
moving.
I'm just freezing.
And young deer and old deer.
They might as well be a different
species that.
Yeah,
I think they are.
They don't look the same hair,
they don't look the same and they
definitely don't look at you the same.
So one young deer walked by me,
didn't notice me at all.
He was like within easily inside of 10
feet.
And then the second deer walked by.
He was inside of like 25,
30 yards,
walked right by me,
but then this mature deer came by and he
was.
His color was different and he spotted
me immediately and he looked at me with
this crazed intensity in his eyes and it
was so interesting because right away I
go,
oh,
that's why people love to hunt these
things.
Look how smart that thing is.
It's just looking at me.
I mean he.
I was frozen solid.
I wasn't moving at all and I was looking
at him and he was looking at me and his
eyes were wide,
like dinner plates.
He knew exactly what I was and he was
like,
fuck this,
and he just turned around and bolted,
but it was the electricity in the air
and the,
the intensity of his recognition of me.
It was so obvious and I remember
thinking immediately,
wow,
this is a really intelligent tuned in
animal that knows what a person is.
They know people equals hunting people
that are out danger,
danger.
They equal danger where the young ones
don't have any idea.
I took some pictures and I posted a
picture up on instagram.
We were sitting in the same stand the
second day and this young deer came by
and literally took a nap underneath us.
Oh,
that's right.
I forgot about that.
Not only did he not know we were there,
like he didn't give a shit.
He just laid down is a year old buck.
His mom was out being a Ho.
She's out getting the gang bang because
it's there in the middle of the what
they called the Rut.
And if you're a non,
uh,
wildlife,
enthusiast,
the Rut is one time a year and it's kind
of a crazy thing if you think about it
one time a year they have sex.
So the entire year everything's normal.
Everybody's buddy buddy.
And then all of a sudden,
one time out of the year for how long
does it last?
I would say three weeks.
Intensely.
Three weeks.
They lose their fucking minds.
They lose weight.
They can't think straight.
Now they run out into traffic,
they get hit by cars and they're,
they're literally just boner,
crazy,
boner,
crazy.
They have no idea what's going on.
And they go,
they go,
bananas.
I sent you a text,
I said,
these poor suckers for 340 days a year.
You can't even find one,
but then all of a sudden they go full
retard.
Yeah.
Imagine that was the case with people.
Imagine if you were like a normal person
and then one time out of the year you
start growing a sword at the top of your
head and you just get next swells up as
big around as your waist mean.
For people that don't know,
they lose those antlers.
A lot of people don't even know that,
that don't pay attention to deer,
but deer grow antlers fresh every year
and then once they're done having sex
and they're done with a Rut,
those antlers get weak and they just
fall off.
Which is what a bizarre metamorphosis.
As an animal.
Actually,
our horn grows is fascinating to me.
If if you.
If you shoot a deer that's still in
velvet and then you're holding that
velvet and you have to in order to
preserve lean velvet,
so velvets,
like when it's fuzzy,
like velvet on the horn when it's in the
growing phase before it actually
hardens.
It's,
it's fuzzy like,
you know,
just like velvet or fleece and um,
then what happens is that'll start to,
their hormones start to change and their
horns start to harden and then they rub
the velvet off so that it's just pure
hard bone and uh,
it's really interesting that it's like
a,
it's like fingernail type material,
right?
It's,
I don't know,
man.
It was harder than my fingernails.
Maybe yours bro.
It will.
Yeah.
Maybe.
Are Super Hard,
but is it made out of.
Why don't you google it?
Can you google it or you have a computer
in front of you?
We'll give you it.
It is.
They're really fascinating animals.
I mean,
I'm a wildlife enthusiast.
I've always been really into wildlife.
I've always been fascinated by wolves
and lions and predators and all kinds of
weird birds and stuff.
I just have always been drawn to like
nature shows and things along those
lines,
but it's massively intensified since I
started hunting.
Let's see what we have here.
This says the horns of a rhinoceros are
made of Keratin.
That's the same stuff.
His fingernails and grow continuously
will just google antlers instead of
horns because what are you?
You're a goddamn.
Yeah.
What are antlers made of?
It was like the second.
You're a goddamn.
Listen Jamie,
you're a professional wonder.
How the hell do you call them?
Horns,
antler,
son,
or the antlers?
The deer antlers are made of true bone
that is fed by the covering of velvet.
Wow.
You were right.
Antlers,
innovative,
true,
well,
you're right.
All the time.
Antlers and made of true bone that is
fed by blood which is carried to the
outer velvet covering.
Velvet Antlers are hot to the touch with
brushy hair and a waxy feeling,
coating dear need both protein and
minerals to grow their antlers,
and so what I'm saying,
letting them.
If you shoot a buck and velvet,
you have to.
You actually have to inject the velvet
with involving fluid so that they don't
like to see in order to preserve them,
but it's amazing that you can.
You have to find the and the horn and
you push the embalming fluid through an.
Actually flushes in the blood,
comes out
base of the horn.
How do you find the vein it?
There's one,
there's one vein that runs the entire
length of the main beam and there's one
that runs from each time.
It's really strange.
I shot a velvet buck in Colorado last
year and it's on my desk in my studio
and they said,
how do you want to take care of it?
Like when I was getting it treated,
because I get all my,
um,
the heads done what's called European
mount style.
The European mount style is like if you
see a mounted head on someone's wall
with the,
the,
the uh,
skin and the feather on it.
And then they have fake eyeballs and the
fake nose.
That's like traditionally what you see.
I find that offensive.
I know that's a,
it's a doll.
I'm looking at a doll pretending to be
the deer I shot.
There's a foam thing under there.
It's got fake guys.
I know it's fake,
but if you see the skull,
like that's a real skull radish patch,
buck.
That buck is awesome.
That is a massive book.
Is that the one that you shot on your
show in Colorado or in Wyoming?
Montana,
because it wasn't lighted nocks right.
You couldn't use it.
Um,
so I told them,
they go,
what do you want to do with the velvet?
And I said,
does it scrape off?
They were like offended.
They're like,
what do you want to scrape it off?
I was like,
there's this antler there,
right?
I go with two,
whatever you want to do this let me
know.
And they,
they,
they do that
in Europe,
in Europe.
It,
like if I'm the Danish Shida bucket I've
had,
I've been on a few hunts with Danish
people and they'll shoot a buck and it
fits in full velvet.
They strip it all off right away because
it's not like,
it's almost like that.
I think they feel like they shot an
adolescent even though it's in a fully
matured because by the time season
opens,
that velvet is on the verge of being
rubbed off.
The Horn is fully matured,
but it just hasn't come off off.
So that's Denmark,
right?
They don't know any better.
Says it's like they're,
they're barely developed.
I don't know.
They know.
And apparently that had just handed the
caves,
the caves that are a couple of weeks
ago.
If you listening from Denmark.
We're kidding folks.
We've been up since 6:00 in the morning.
Five,
five.
We got up.
Well,
he was hot.
Tubbing not with me.
Tell you that.
Oh,
hot tub would dudes.
I uh,
I got up at five.
But anyway,
we're out the door at 5:30.
So we've been up for a long time.
That's the point right now.
It is almost 10:00 PM.
And we got to do it again tomorrow.
Tomorrow's the last day of this
fantabulous hunt here in the great
midwest state of Iowa or Iowa.
What do you think?
IOL hunting.
Awesome.
Amazing.
What's the tradition here?
And it's,
it's obvious,
you know,
when you,
to all the folks,
the
locals,
uh,
our friend Craig,
who is the local game warden,
you know,
gives us all the details on all walls
that's going down your neighbor shot at
giant and oh my God,
he just shot a monster.
He sister animals.
He's on the uppity up.
But no,
what I really appreciate about Iowa is
ever great program too.
And you haven't got to experience it yet
because we haven't got to go to the meat
locker,
but Iowa has a program called the hush
and it's pretty much,
um,
hunter's feeding the hungry is really
what it is.
That's a great program to where people
are allowed to shoot,
um,
extra deer tags in order to.
And they can donate that to a hunters
for the hungry program.
So they actually feed it,
goes to homeless shelters and things
like that.
And it's a necessity.
Like I told you,
my county here,
I believe the number of antlerless deer
that have to be taken is like 4,200
extra tags.
And you will use,
you've seen how many,
how many times have we had to slow the
truck down to not hit a deer.
And you've been here three days.
Quite a few.
The sheer population numbers are pretty
incredible.
And one of the reasons for it is that
they've done a really good job of making
sure there's not overhunting.
They also regulate the type of hunting
you can do were mostly,
it's bowhunting in Iowa,
but you can shotgun hunt.
But you can only shot gun hunt for a few
days a year,
and by the way,
I'd rather have a boat and a shotgun.
You can make a longer shot with a bow.
Then he came with a shotgun and a more
efficient shot with a bow than you can
with a shotgun.
I just feel like you get to enjoy more
of nature out either.
Yeah.
What,
what?
That's an inside joke because a lot of
people.
We'll have blown ears from guns folks.
Minor ringing right now.
Yeah.
It's cams ring all the time too.
They did.
Yup.
I know a lot of guys who have been
hunters their whole life who have really
bad ear property now has ear problems.
Is he scam as deaf as I am?
Uh,
not quite as deaf as you are,
but he's got ringing problems.
He's got issues.
Yeah.
It's again,
from shooting firearms when these young
without ear protection.
I wear ear protection every time I fire
a gun every time.
It's smart.
Yeah.
Mine,
I was never told otherwise except this
last time I shot that elk.
I shut that awkward note your
production.
But uh,
where are they ringing then?
No,
just one shot.
You're too tough for to,
for your ears are ringing.
That's very kind of you,
but not true.
Does anybody have a tough,
tough go screaming my ears,
Bro?
No,
I've seen.
I've seen some cauliflower ear.
See,
there's no just no sound penetrating
those suckers.
Well,
it's not good sound.
You know,
people always asking why I don't have
cauliflower ears.
I wear your guards have always worn ear
guards for 20 years that we're in
regards.
I have a little tiny bit of cauliflower
ear,
like you could feel it here.
What cauliflower is,
if you don't know,
is um,
when your ears get bent over or broken,
it doesn't have to happen from wrestling
and can happen.
Sometimes boxers get it,
you can get it.
If somebody hits your ear,
if something hits your ear,
what it is is basically just bleeding.
And when it swells up with blood,
when blood sits there and pools up when
it heals,
it calcifies.
And so it literally becomes a rock like
Randy coture used to drive his
cauliflower ear into his opponents
eyeballs because it's like a rock.
So He's,
he's taken guys down and like he's
clenching with him and he's shoving his
ear into their eye socket and using it
as a weapon and drive them down.
But good luck getting some fucking ipod
earbuds into those things,
man,
you can't.
That's not happening.
You can't hear good either.
Like take your ears folks,
if you're listening at home,
take your ears and then take the top and
do this.
Fold them down like that and then hear
how different everything sounds.
And then let them go.
Your ears designed a very specific way.
And that way is to catch the sound
waves.
The sound waves come in,
it resonates off of the shape of your
ear and it goes into the whole.
These guys,
and I know I know a ton of guys whose
ears are so fucked up,
they can't get ear buds in.
They have to wear over.
The ear buds are super common.
Really,
really common.
It's probably why they always have the
big over that.
Your beats by Dre?
Yeah.
Just so they can bonsers oh,
okay.
Sponsor stuff.
They sponsor the US.
Okay.
But yeah,
but they,
it's hard for them to get ear buds and
they,
they're not going to.
They're not getting an ear bud.
And then how we got into earbuds started
with Iowa where,
how do we go with this?
Doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter,
but saw Caitlin Jenner's nipples.
Things $100
in this thing.
Right?
Or Alex.
I'm going to go with things you can't
unsee.
Yeah.
I'm all of a sudden they're big.
Caitlin has big boobs.
I want to,
I want to point out the political
correctness of all the people in your
hunting camp because everybody referred
to her as a.
she.
Yeah.
Really?
No.
We have,
uh,
one of my buddies came and one of his
buddies played.
Call played golf.
Yeah.
Did a charity outing and then had a
picture and it was um,
they were surprised that there was such
a transformation.
There's a surprise
surprise.
It was a lot going on.
Well,
what do you think about this fight card?
Got a Fox fight tomorrow night.
We're going to come back and watch the
fights after I kill a monster buck.
It's on the books.
Folks in the car cards.
I'm making a prediction.
Uh,
it's big fight.
The main event is huge.
It's half failed.
Dos Anjos who's the former UFC
lightweight champ versus Tony Ferguson
who is undoubtedly without question one
of the best lightweight in the world and
the guy has been knocking on the door to
a title shot for awhile.
It's a really interesting fight because
it highlights a real issue with MMA
right now.
Uh,
and that issues weight cutting.
I failed to.
Sandra's had a terrible weight cut for
the Eddie Alvarez fight.
I'm hearing a lot of conflicting
stories,
but all of them really bad now.
I shouldn't say conflicting,
I should say a different stories,
but of what went on when he was making
wait for his fight with Eddie Alvarez.
And apparently he was in bad shape,
like really bad shape,
like barely made wait for that.
And was just really in physical
discomfort and pain and just all screwed
up from that weight cut.
I think weight cutting is one of the
worst aspects of fighting.
I think it might be worse than the
beatings these guys take [inaudible].
We don't see it visually and on see cuts
in their face.
We don't see knockouts,
we don't see blood when they're cutting
weight.
So we don't think of it as the same kind
of damage that we do from a beating.
But I think it might be as bad if not
worse.
I would say worse.
It could very well be.
And then even more worse is the fact
these guys are dehydrating themselves
literally to death's door and then
fighting trained killers 24 hours later.
It's unavoidable.
It's unnecessary.
I mean,
it's unavoidable.
It's avoidable.
It's unnecessary.
And it's foolish.
I think it's a,
it's one of the most foolish aspects of
the,
for the sport.
And you know,
we were talking today,
uh,
with some of the guys at your camp
about,
um,
like issues with MMA and with the new
owners are going to do a now that the
UFC has been purchased and I hope they
institute a program to eliminate weight
cutting.
I think it is one of the biggest
problems and biggest,
it's a time bomb and it's just waiting
to go off and everybody's face and a guy
like Hofeld dos Anjos,
who's one of the elite of the elite
before he lost to Eddie Alvarez,
a lot of people,
including me,
were making the argument that he might
be the best lightweight ever.
You look at a knocked out Benson
Henderson.
He beat the shit out of Nate Diaz.
He knocked out cowboy serone in one
round.
He's a fucking monster.
I mean,
he's a killer.
He beat the shit out of Anthony Pettis
for five rounds to win the title.
Just roll them over.
Just beat him down.
I you can make the argument is one of
the greatest.
Certainly one of the greatest light
weights of all time might be the best in
terms of like champions and the
was so depleted from his weight cut that
he was like,
I had heard he was passing out
backstage.
You know,
I just,
I just.
If that guy died,
let's imagine.
I mean,
God forbid,
right?
But let's imagine if a guy like that
dies because of a weight cut and it has
happened the last week,
the last death in mma was in Brazil and
it was from a fighter who cut weight.
He died from wink cut.
He didn't die from the fight itself.
I just think it's a terrible thing that
can be eliminated.
And I think that if we did,
you would see better fights.
That's what I'm saying.
Yeah.
I think how,
I mean someone like that that's having
to cut that much.
Are they really?
Are you really seeing them at their
best?
Absolutely.
Are Not.
There's no question about it.
Yeah.
I think cowboy looks way better when
he's.
When he's fighting heavier,
much better.
Look how good he looks at one seven.
I think that's it.
He was always.
He's always been an elite fighter even
at 55.
But at one 70 he looks like a world
champion.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I'm waiting to see a title contention
right there that way.
I think it's an old thing
about Cyborg.
Yeah.
Because you were telling me what she
walks around at one 75.
Yeah,
she's.
And I said,
well,
as Jack does,
she is,
how does she,
how does she cut that much?
I mean,
that seems like an impossibility.
She does.
It is sheer strength of will.
George Lockhart,
who's her coach,
who's a,
a really good,
really high level nutritionist and
weight cutting expert and he gets her
down to that weight,
but it's not pretty,
you know,
there's a video of her struggling to
make 1:40 the weight classes in the UFC
for women as of right now there's only
two.
There is a 1:15 and then there's 1:35
and they've experimented with 1:25 that
talks about doing 1:25 pound weight
classes.
Um,
like a title at 1:25.
But as of yet it doesn't exist.
Um,
but I think honestly Cyborg has said
that really her best way classes even
45.
Well she's a champion of an invicta.
Her best way class would be 55.
Yeah.
I would say.
And there's other girls out there,
man build it and they will come.
I think 55 would be a really good
women's class because you'd almost,
you'd almost have that like Mark Hunt,
brock Lesnar's style.
You'd get some real powerhouses in there
that are still not too big where they're
out of shape,
but they could just be like Cyborg.
I think if you built it,
you'd have people coming from other
countries that you probably don't even
know about.
I think.
I think you certainly would after a few
years and that's just an investment that
I think they have to make with women's
MMA right now.
Women's MMA is where men's mma was when
the UFC was first purchased because a
lot of people don't realize,
but when the UFC bought,
when they purchased it from the old,
they eliminated 155 pound weight class
because they used to have a 1:55.
Then they had a one slash 70 and then
they had,
I think they had a middleweight and a
light heavyweight and heavyweight still,
but they didn't have anything lower than
one 70,
so a lot of guys either left the UFC to
fight in other organizations or they
moved up to one 70 and competed at one
70 and some guys were like really
oversized or undersized for that weight
class.
So
that's not enough.
Obviously it's really important that for
a guy like mighty mouse,
like if there wasn't a 125 pound weight
class,
which were mighty mouse competes,
we wouldn't be able to see the best
fighter of all time compete in is
perfect weight class or 1:35.
You know,
you wouldn't be able to see Dominic Cruz
compete at his optimal weight class
1:45.
You wouldn't be able to see Josie Aldo
gone that reign of terror for all those
years.
You wouldn't be able to see conor
mcgregor fight at 1:45 and beat Aldo and
then 55,
54 for the long time.
Fifty five,
which is one of the most competitive and
talent rich divisions in the UFC didn't
even exist and you know,
so I think that the UFC,
if they really want to make that
commitment for women's MMA,
they should have a full range of weight
classes for those girls to compete at.
I think they should start maybe even
lower than 1:15.
I mean you could,
you could make a real strong argument
for 100,
five pound woman's class a one to five,
1:15,
1:25,
and then I think really the trend of
those 10 pound per way class that should
exist.
The men's division as well.
There's two big gaps in the men's
divisions are way too big.
There's one 70 and then there's 15
counts higher.
One 85,
that's a big jump.
And then there's 20 pounds above that.
80 five to two.
Oh five,
20 pounds.
Think about taking 2016 ounce t bone
steaks and that's how much bigger that
guy is.
The guy before him.
Then you go to,
oh,
five,
two,
two 65.
So think about taking 60 t bone steak
six zero stacking up,
thinking about all the horsepower that
comes with all that weight.
It's just there's two.
The,
the gaps are too large.
It's too few week classes.
So I think the UFC would be,
it would be very smart for them to make
more weight classes,
do a weight class every 10 pounds and
eliminate the weight cutting if they
could.
And I think it can be done there.
They're probably going to have to get
rid of some champions though.
Not Get rid of,
but they're going to have to read.
You're gonna have to move pretty around
us around.
And the people who are champions,
yeah,
they're not going to want to do that.
You know,
you're not going to be able to.
It's going to be a hard fight to tell a
guy like dominick Cruz,
he can't cut weight,
you know,
when he's the world champion and say,
look man,
what do you weigh?
One 55,
you're going to have to fight at 1:55.
Yeah.
It'd be interesting though to see how
much
better fights we'd see if people were.
I mean,
there's obviously going to be a position
where people are getting in good shape
because there's a lot of fighters now
that the testing is happening to where
that when they come out you can tell
they're not as noticeable.
Good shape is what they were at one
time.
They're not as Jack.
Yeah.
They're not as muscular and it see,
it kind of seems like maybe we aren't
getting the same
class of fighting at times with some
guys with some.
Yeah,
with some guys.
But some guys,
I don't think that's the case because
like mighty mouse,
I mean,
you know,
he's still the elite of the elite.
You know,
you go down to 55,
Eddie Alverez looks sensational.
Fifty five and you know,
he has no issues with it.
He looks just as good a after the Usada
testing as he ever did.
Look at Tyron Woodley passes like flying
color and if anybody looks like they're
some sort of a science project,
it's Tyron Woodley.
So the best built guy in the UFC,
clean as a whistle,
just awesome genetics and hard training,
you know?
And then you go up to a one 85 yellow
Ramiro is the king of the freaks and
he's the freakiest freak that ever
freaked.
I mean that guy is.
If that guy's on steroids,
you just go,
what A.
Well,
you know,
some people just have amazing genetics.
Yeah.
Those people,
they're walking around at their weight.
They should be in.
Yeah.
I think that would help the whole sport.
If they could figure out how to do that,
if they could figure out how to
eliminate the weight cutting and do it
smart and do it over,
you know,
a period of time and figure out a way to
establish new champions and new
divisions and,
and give guys financial incentives and
to do this and just let them know for
your own good for everybody's good.
There's nothing wrong with being lean.
If you want to lose body fat and you
know,
and dropped down some weight in a
natural healthy way.
But this dehydration shit has got to
stop.
It's a time bomb.
It's a ticking time bomb and it's
waiting to blow up in the face of the
most exciting sport in the world and I
just think it's totally avoidable.
And if you're a,
if you're training the way these guys
are training,
you're losing your excess fat anyway.
Well you're also,
well if you're eating right.
Unfortunately some guys like,
look at,
uh,
you know,
look at uh,
a big country.
Roy Nelson trains like a madman,
but he's like,
shit
unfortunately eats like a madman too,
you know,
and you can't say that it's just
training because Roy's not out of shape.
I mean,
that sounds crazy to say when you look
at him,
but he's not out of shape.
I mean if you,
if you underestimated his cardio and you
go,
man,
I'm gonna have to train for this guy.
That guy will beat your ass.
You know,
he's in real good shape,
but it just got,
he just carries too much excess body
fat.
It's,
well always,
always talking about how cowboy likes
his candy.
Yeah.
But he
stopped.
He did.
Yeah.
He did say that.
Well,
once you started getting into on it,
he started getting into honored
supplements and he started listening to
a real nutritionists and he just
completely altered his diet and for the
first time in his life started
supplementing and you know,
take me to get that Kinda man.
I'm taking off these boots were this God
damn boots all day.
We haven't done on what we have done.
Almost nothing,
but yet I'm exhausted.
That's the irony of this,
this white tail hunting.
He's sitting in a tree stand all day.
We went for it.
It's totally a mental game.
It is,
it is.
And you're going in.
It's mental and it's completely a for a
guy like me takes me completely out of
my comfort zone.
I actually took video of you
on the second morning.
We're about two hours in and I could
tell joe is just like,
this is bullcrap because he's like,
wait,
we're going to see her 13 hours.
Um,
he was,
you did a,
you did like,
you were doing twisties.
You were like going side to side,
like twisting.
Then you were doing some squat thrusts.
You were like Kinda like doing like
quarter squats.
Then you ate a peanut butter and jelly
sandwich.
Then you like drink your coffee,
then you took a leak.
That was all in the first hour and a
half just trying to get amped up bro
prepared,
Bro.
I was like,
okay,
sure.
When it goes.
That's the other thing too.
It's like you.
There's all this time.
I mean,
think about all the time he re practice
archery.
You know,
I practice archery.
I try to practice four days a week.
If I don't practice four days a week,
I get upset with myself.
I'd like to practice every day,
but sometimes it doesn't work out,
but I can usually get in at least an
hour,
so four days a week.
So that's all these weeks and weeks and
weeks of practice and some days,
I mean I don't have shit to do.
I'll practice three or four hours,
you know?
And so I'm just shooting an Arrow after
Arrow after an hour waiting for one
moment.
We're an animal turns broadside.
It's like it's almost like it's not as
crazy as a fight because there's no
physical consequences to me,
but it's more crazy in some ways because
literally depends on one execution of
one move,
one execution,
the release of a perfect Arrow and the
concentration and the focus has to be
perfect and you have to launch that
Arrow,
whoosh,
right through the vitals of a wild
animal that has no idea you're alive.
It doesn't even know you're there until
then Arrow gets launched and that.
That to me is one of the most exciting
things about archery.
One of the most exciting things about it
is how much it really does get out of
your comfort zone.
How much it's so different than anything
else you do because like a fight,
a fight is more dangerous for you.
There's more physical consequences is
more nerve wracking.
It's scarier.
And,
but you got some time,
like they shut that gate and you know,
they say,
are you ready?
You Ready?
Let's get it on.
Come on.
You know,
sometimes you get knocked out quick,
you know,
and some.
That definitely happens,
but most of the time,
especially if you're good and you,
you fight intelligently,
you're moving around and you're avoiding
trouble in trying to solve the problem
and you know it's up to your
conditioning and your training to
experience this thing and did try to get
through it.
So if it all goes well,
you've gone through a three round or a
five round fight.
So longest case scenario for a
championship round our main event,
25 minutes.
So in 25 minutes you have enough time to
figure out how to get it done and solve
the riddle and the puzzle that your
opponent presents.
In bowhunting.
You have one execution,
so months and months and months and
months.
Say for a tag in Iowa,
super hard to get.
For most people you put in,
you might get one every five years.
And what a tag for people to know
anything about hunting,
the way they keep the populations
healthy is they regulate the amount of
people that can hunt,
so they have a limited amount of people
that are allowed to hunt.
In the great state of Iowa,
you got a tag every five years and when
you get that tag,
do you have as many days as you have off
of work that you can make it out here to
get it done.
There's a tremendous amount of pressure
and you have one deer tag.
It all boils down to one shot on one
wild animal for a lot of tension there.
A lot of shit going on.
It's like A.
I mean that's like saying you're going
to be in a fight,
but we're only a navy one punch.
Yeah.
Each of you get gets one and we'll see
who wins sort of,
but you're not going to get hit
and you're punching them with a of an
eastern full metal jacket,
you know,
Arrow going,
I don't know how many feet.
Probably 290 feet a second.
Probably somewhere around there.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Right.
Yeah.
You'd be equivalent to a 100 mile an
hour fastball I think.
Yeah.
$100 a mile hour fastball with razor
blades at the end of it.
I mean,
that's really what it is,
but as they probably watched the world
series,
if that's what they were,
but as a discipline,
it's um,
there's more to it than just the pursuit
of an animal or there's a bunch of shit
going on and I know people get tired of
me talking about hunting sometimes and
they know some people who are like
animal lovers or vegetarian or
something,
get really angry that they be like these
podcasts.
But I just try.
I'm just trying to relay what's going on
in my mind
and my thought process that this is like
a,
it's like a meditation,
like a discipline and this incredibly
difficult task through it.
You're,
um,
you're trying to,
you're trying to like find the layers of
the onion.
He try and dig deep,
dig deep into the heart of the thing to
find out what it really is.
It reveals itself to you.
Even archery reveals itself to you
through the intense pressure of
bowhunting because there's like archery.
When there's a target and you're 20
yards away from it and you draw back and
try to hit the x,
you know there's a little bit of
pressure and then you move the site back
to 40 yards.
Then there's a little bit more pressure
and then you move it back to 80 yards.
Who?
That's a long way.
Okay,
I got to concentrate.
Then after all these arrows,
then there's an animal and then there's
an animal and it's moving and it's
walking and what you have to do is wait
to the moment where that thing stops and
there's tremendous pressure and there's
tremendous responsibility and there's
tremendous consequences.
The last thing you want to do is see
that arrow fly and hit that deer,
that Dick and have that thing run off
screaming like no,
and you realize that not only does not
kill it,
you named it,
it's probably going to live.
It's going to be in pain for months and
you don't want that unknown.
Sure.
You don't want that.
So you have this massive requirement and
massive responsibility of you and
through the intense pressure of this
discipline,
archery reveals itself.
It reveals itself,
it is a martial art,
you know,
and I know people don't look at it as a
martial art because you're not throwing
kicks and you're not choking people,
but our tree was developed initially for
war and that's one of the fascinating
things about it is,
is developed as a weapon both to hunt
and to kill other people.
And that's really what it was intended.
Yeah,
it's definitely,
uh,
one of the most advanced penetrating
because armor came about,
right.
And the,
and the Arrow as a projectile is
extremely efficient at penetration.
Yes.
Because it's,
it's heavy mass with a very defined
point that impact have impact.
And it,
I mean,
it,
I told you about some,
um,
a time where I did some work with Oakley
on a ballistic helmet that they were
doing for one of our military teams and
they brought me over because at the time
I was at the,
um,
the US archery training center in Chula
Vista.
So I went over to Oakley and they had me
shooting these,
these masks that they had developed
because they were saying they wanted to
know whether or not an Arrow could
penetrate them and they were confident
that these things were gonna work
because they said it stopped shotguns,
sops nine millimeters.
They were like dropping these like,
I don't know,
these like big steel staffs on him and
everything was working.
But when I looked at it,
I said I'm going to punch right through
that thing and they put them on,
um,
on crash dummy heads.
And I shot them out in the parking lot
at 100 yards.
And I mean every one of those things,
we're dead meat.
There was Arrow hanging out.
Both ends.
I've probably have pictures.
I'm like,
what pound weight we pull in.
Um,
it was my target though.
I was only pulling 60.
Wow.
And I told them,
I said,
there's so much energy being generated
to the front of this tip.
I said,
even though this is made to block stuff
that flattens [inaudible],
like a bullet will flatten.
So,
um,
it disperses its energy out.
And you know,
obviously you absorb a lot of that shock
if you get hit with a bullet and it
flattens that energy gets,
you know,
it gets connected into you bruise and.
Yeah,
and you,
I mean it's shell,
it's shock.
Whereas with an Arrow it would just cut
through,
you know,
unless it hits solid mass,
it would cut through and go out and you
wouldn't even know it.
It's,
it's just like when you cut yourself
with a knife and you're like,
oh crap,
you know,
and you kind of grab it,
you know it's bad,
but you don't really want to look.
Whereas if you shot yourself in the
finger with a gun,
I mean,
you know,
your whole hand would have felt it,
right.
It's not like it's going to just feel
like a paper cut.
And that's really the difference.
Well,
especially when you consider the fact
that you're shooting
a light arrow through a target bow.
Like if you were using your hunting
setup and a heavy Arrow with,
oh that's hilarious.
He's shot right through that thing
through its eye,
off the back of the head.
It's so funny that they pulled out.
I signed a couple.
I did some glasses to you,
but I did.
Yeah.
That's funny that they thought it would
be fine.
See the penetration?
Yeah,
that's not good.
They wouldn't let me show the helmets
because they were using.
Wow.
That went a foot plus deep.
Kind of looks like elite it.
Click,
click.
Guido and your favorite had to be
remembered his name.
Look at Dudley looking at young and
dapper.
I was so that Beau is not as powerful as
your main bowl.
You're hunting and the arrows aren't as
heavy in the heavier get more.
And you're using a field tip too,
right?
Yeah.
So you don't even have like a cut a
year?
No.
I mean,
you think back in medieval times,
man,
they were cutting through chain mail
with arrows.
That's what I mean.
That's why.
That's what they were designed.
Have you ever seen those?
I wanted to ask you this before,
and I always forget.
Have you ever used
one of those mom goal?
Thumb rings.
The Mongols had a very peculiar way of
releasing their,
uh,
archery.
Um,
their,
their arrows.
The way they would use the release on
the boat,
they had a ring,
like a fat piece of bone that would fit
around their thumb and they would hook
with the thumb on the string and this
was how they would hold it.
They would hold it like this,
like almost like you're shooting pool so
they reach over seeing them do it,
but I didn't know they had a ring.
So most people they think of like Robin
Hood style of pulling back a Rico
recurve where you would grab it with
your fingers and pull it back with your
fingers.
But would they would do is that thumb
ring comes out and they wrapped that
around and if you go back to that
picture that you had early,
you can see that picture right there.
See that is where the,
the,
the cord,
the drawstring hits on that and the
thumb goes through that loop and then
they wrap their finger around it.
So that is what holds on.
That seems to me to be a way better way
than holding it with your fingers like
this and just let him go with your
fingers.
It seems like it would be more
repeatable and also that hard surface.
Yeah.
Well,
fingers you have more repeatable.
It'll be a boon he's using.
It looks like he's using a metal.
Some people don't like to mess around
with.
Could be titanium.
Yeah.
Could've melted down as his first loves
necklace and just went crazy.
I could have taken a cock ring and just
stretched out part of it.
I think that is for sure as a conquering
it is,
but they used to the Mongols use use
bone.
There's like a whole series of them.
Right.
They're pretty bad ass.
I haven't seen any other people that
have done this before and this is
something that I,
uh,
I got into after I listened to the
hardcore history series on the mon
goals,
I really got super fascinated about them
and their archery methods.
They,
according to Dan Carlin at least,
and he's done pretty extensive research.
Their bows were 160 pounds
pole recurves yeah.
They were tremendous.
But they would have to be because they
weren't near as efficient.
Then would have to be in order to
generate the.
I believe they invented the recurve.
Actually.
I'm pretty sure the Mongols did.
I'm pretty sure they were at least the
first adopters.
They might've vented it.
Well,
let's,
let's Google that shit.
Who invented the recurve bow?
What do you think?
Tayga?
Yes.
Um,
you're an archery fanatic.
Who invented recurve bow?
I would have to say it's either going to
be them or I think it's the Mongols.
I might've made that up though.
Let's see.
And survey says who invented the recurve
bow recurve.
I was going to say the Greeks.
See
that was the Greeks second millennium,
BC.
Wow.
The recurve bow spread to Egypt,
much of Asia and the second millennium
BC.
Okay.
So I'm definitely wrong because the
Mongols were when during the gang it's
con days at least.
That was $1,200.
Um,
so go to that Mongol bone with
wikipedia.
It's a type of recurve,
composite bow.
Think of that.
They had a specific type of bowl,
a recurve composite bow.
It can be two types of both.
In the 17th century onward,
most are traditional bows and Mongolia
were replaced with a symbol or Manchu
blow,
which is primarily a distinguished by
larger.
What's that word?
See us s I y a prison stage,
prominent string bridges.
The old Mongolian bows were used during
the rule of gingiss con were smaller
than the modern Manchu derived weapons
used by most Nadam an a d,
a m paintings as well as at least one
surviving example of a 13th century
Mongo boat.
Dude,
I want that.
Imagine having a 13th century Mongol
blow.
That would be the shoot.
I know I've shot one before.
How you really?
Yeah.
I wanted to always shoot one off
horseback,
but I want to do it.
I did.
Um,
I'll try to find a.
trying to find a picture here for you.
But I was presented one as a gift.
I don't know where I've got it.
I've got one here.
I've got a Mongo bull that I was given
as a gift and I.
and they said,
well traditionally these were always
shot off horseback.
That's why they're short.
Oh,
that makes sense.
That's why they're short so that you can
do it.
So I ended up,
um,
I was on one of my coaching tours
through Europe,
so the guy that was actually escort me,
his name was Andre.
I actually got on his back and I mean,
that's ridiculous.
You're a big guy.
Yeah.
And he's about 65.
No.
Yeah,
you were riding a 65 pound man.
Riding them like seabiscuit
picture that I'm going to buy it.
I need to see a picture.
You riding an old man,
you might have killed them.
That's not fair.
What do you wait?
You gotta wait.
At least 242,
three
pounds.
I'm up there.
How tall are you?
Um,
2:30 right now.
Tall,
tall.
Six five.
Yeah.
You're a big to be riding
a 65 year old man.
I don't think any 65 year old men should
be carrying around six foot five dudes.
That's just me though.
I know he was taking one for the team.
The one that my break is back.
I know.
I don't want to take that one.
I've got,
I forgot the picture somewhere,
but I'll have to post it later.
Um,
so the Mongols,
according to Dan Carlin,
they had developed timing where they
would release the bow as the horse was
in the air so that it didn't disturb
them with the bouncing.
So that totally makes sense.
So as the,
the horse was in the air,
that's when they would release.
That would.
Yeah.
I think I would have figured that part
out to
come a long way,
man,
because of you my friend because of you.
Well,
I wasn't saying it for that reason,
but that is,
was thoroughly impressed.
You're a,
you're a perfect protege because you
applied.
Everything taught.
When I think so cool about archery is
that people of any age can do it any
age,
any type of stature.
We're going through.
I got to show you some of these
pictures.
I wish you riding a man.
Well,
there will be a picture of me just
coaching pictures.
Yeah.
If there's thousands,
but now that I'm going through,
I'm like remembering some of these
people that I had to work with.
People don't even know why to laugh at
that,
but the things about archery,
um,
you know,
obviously bowhunting I think is one of
the most extreme expressions of it,
but I had no idea before I started
practicing it,
how deep the rabbit hole goes.
And I think that's the case with a lot
of things.
I think that's probably the case with
most disciplines,
most things that people do that are
really difficult.
I think that certainly probably the case
with golf and some other things that
I've never tried.
But with archery I just,
I can't believe how much effort is
involved in it.
And I saw,
I posted something about it on instagram
once about how rewarding it is to and
how difficult it is and how humbling it
is.
And You keep practicing.
And,
and uh,
this is you on this man.
That's hilarious.
This is our form.
It looks excellent considering that
you're crippling.
Someone
will have to post that on instagram.
Save that and post that.
Tonight we'll have a link to.
Oh,
that's another thing I wanted to ask you
about.
I'm sure you've seen this guy.
His name is lars and a senior and he's
got this method where he holds arrows in
between his fingers of the hand.
He's drawing the bow backward.
John's shaking his head right now.
I haven't got a call bullcrap on that
really well.
How are you calling bullcrap pr?
I think part of it was
somewhat believable and why they held
the arrows the way they did so they
could load and sheet fast.
Yeah,
but and I mean there's no doubt if you
would want him on your team because he
is obviously perfected that technique,
but it's not like historically there's
facts and stories around of people that
had that type of skill.
We know there are ancient photos or
ancient drawings rather have them during
the arrows that way.
I would,
yeah.
I would definitely say they carry it
that way because you could load it,
but his method of like shooting in this
trick style of shooting.
I don't know if people want to become
that proficient with it.
I do.
I think they would be.
I mean,
if that's what you did,
think about the Mongols and the fact
that they use that weapon so efficiently
to dominate massive chunks of the world.
And this is a conversation we were
having earlier today.
Yeah,
that was fascinating about,
uh,
the,
the New York Times article that said
that during gingiss cons day,
they killed so many people.
It changed the carbon footprint of the
world.
They killed 10 percent of the human
population on earth.
Ten percent were directly connected to
the Mongols.
The Mongols had killed 10 percent of the
earth.
That just,
when you hear that,
it just makes you think,
how could that be done?
How's that done?
The,
the numbers,
the conservative numbers are somewhere
around $20 million.
The liberal estimates go as high as 70.
That's,
I mean,
it is an unreal number.
It's unreal.
But they were
arguably madmen,
madmen,
100 percent mean 100 percent.
It was crazy times.
That's all we'd go to.
If all of a sudden everyone's cell phone
shut off,
like the sun stopped.
Well,
if one group came along that was that
ruthless,
they're willing to take it that far.
I mean,
life in 1200 was just particularly
ruthless,
right?
I mean,
it was a brutal time to be alive.
There was no medicine.
There's no surgery.
There was very little,
at least very little sophistication.
And these people,
most of them lived in felt tense.
I mean,
that's what most of the Mongols lived
in.
I mean,
that's part of the name Gingiss Khan and
the,
uh,
like,
his,
uh,
doctrine that he lived by was that he
was the ruler of all who lived and felt
tense and he believed that people who
lived in tents or superior to people
that lived in homes and those people
that lived in homes,
they sort of dehumanize them.
They thought they were like,
there were pieces of shit living in a
house.
Fuck these people,
they can't even live in a tent.
Like a civilized person.
You know,
they,
they were,
they were really crazy.
I always encourage people to do this,
but please,
if you're listening to this,
and this isn't at all intriguing,
go to Dan Carlin's hardcore history.
Apparently.
Now if you go on Itunes,
you have to pay for the wrath of the
cons ones because the way Dan Carlin's
works and it's only a dollar a show by
the way,
folks,
it's worth way more than that and you
say,
oh,
I paid for a podcast.
It's not really a podcast.
This is a podcast.
John and I,
we hunted all day.
We had some dinner,
we had a couple of drinks and we said we
gotta do this podcast,
so we sat down were just shooting the
shit with Dan Carlin does is exhaustive
research and he works on these things
for months at a time and they're
essentially like hour and a half.
Hard core history is the name of it,
but that is what it is,
is a hardcore historical audio book on
whatever subject it covers and all of
them are equally amazing and he the the
hardcore history series.
Unwrap the cons is a five part series.
It's one of my most cherished audio
recordings.
It's fucking incredible.
I've listened to it.
No bullshit.
Maybe 30 times.
I've just keep listening to it over and
over again.
Still absorb all the details because
it's so crazy.
These,
the way these people lived.
It is fascinating.
It's worth a bucket show.
Folks pay for it.
It's not like my show.
My show is a dollar show.
Go on bit torrent steel,
that fucking thing.
This,
this pay for it.
Pay For this because it's a work of art.
But um,
but archery until modern times consisted
of the,
you know,
the,
the sophisticated leaps in technology.
We're just like the recurve bow and more
efficient and better recoverable bows
and better materials until the compound
boat came along,
which was when,
I don't know.
I'm trying to think when it was.
I'm going to guess seven,
eight threadbare invented.
It didn't.
I think it was the Alan.
Oh,
was it?
Okay.
Who invented the combat that combat poe?
Who invented the compound bow first?
Compound bow.
That's fine.
I'm not a historian.
How dare you not be a historian?
I just shoot.
All right.
Let's see.
What does it say here?
Why is Oprah crying?
Hopers kronos.
Shocking.
Oprah secrets revealed.
Okay.
Wilbur Allen changed the face of archery
for everyone and he decided that he'd
make a bow by sawing off part of the
limbs are recurve and attaching police.
Nineteen sixties.
Okay.
My thing was fred bear,
I think I watched some bear archery
propaganda.
That's why.
Dang it all.
Okay.
So a wholeness.
H O l l e s s Wilbur Allen.
Hmm.
Yep.
And that was in the 19 sixties.
That's interesting because that looks
like a modern day elite po inside joke
folks.
Just kidding if you're an elite shooter
and you're like,
what the fuck?
You didn't know shit about our true.
You're right.
I don't.
I'm just joking.
Yeah,
we're googling stuff.
Don't get a docket.
So uppity.
Don't get so attached to your shit.
Goddammit.
I'm so 19 sixties is when it became what
it is now or the beginning of what it is
now.
But what we're shooting
right before I was born,
what we're shooting with now is these
new horror hoyt pro defiance.
Um,
and this one that I got literally three
days ago is the best barber shop.
It's amazing.
It's so good.
It feels so good when you,
when you shoot with it so smooth and
it's so accurate.
It's,
it's incredible how far the technology
has come.
I mean,
we're shooting today out to 80 yards and
shy the day before that,
85 yards and regularly placing it in the
10 range at 80 yards.
Yeah,
I mean that is,
that's incredible.
Sophistication and technology.
And you're shooting 84 pounds.
Yeah.
It's heavy with a 500 green arrow.
It's,
I mean that is Shit's gonna die
ballistic heads would would implode if
you were hitting them.
Like if you're shooting,
if you were at Oakley.
Oh yeah.
That's a new backs.
That's a different thing.
Yeah.
That's the kind of.
Well we had this discussion though.
It's all about what you can physically
manage.
We had this discussion on your podcasts.
You listen to this podcast,
want to hear another drunk and rambling
bullshit fast.
John John,
John and I did an episode of knock on,
which is if you get into archery,
John's podcast is,
in my opinion,
the best archery podcast in the world.
It's the most informative and it's how
John and I became friends.
We became friends because I went to
Hawaii and I'm hoyt.
The company that makes these bows.
I went there with my family because I
was in Salt Lake and I made.
I don't like skiing,
man.
I don't like it.
It's fucking boring to me,
but I do it because my family likes it.
Like we were going down the hill.
We in my car,
I'll go,
I'll go fine.
Oh,
but please can we just stop in Salt Lake
City so I can visit the factory.
I want to check it out.
So,
uh,
and I was in there and I was talking to
Mike looper and Mike looper,
one of the big wigs over at hoyt.
And I was telling them,
I go,
I listened to that.
John Dudley's podcasts all the time.
I'd podcast amazing.
I'm like,
it's so informative and then loop or
told you.
And then somehow or another he connected
us and next thing you know,
you're giving me some coaching and.
Well,
here,
it's funny because Mike,
a practical joker,
he's always like,
he'll always call and then he starts out
with like,
hi,
is Mr Dodd living
like he always does these different
voices and he,
he's always playing jokes one.
Anyway,
we,
Sharon and I went to Hawaii like in two
hours after you were there.
Oh,
that's funny.
And um,
we pull in and then Mike's like,
dude,
Brogan was just here and he loves your
podcast.
And I'm like,
thinking,
here we go.
No.
He's like,
no,
seriously.
And I'm like,
Oh yeah,
it does.
He.
And he's like,
yeah.
he's in town,
he's skin and he's going to go over to
the western expo.
And I said,
well that's what we're here for.
We're going to be over at the western
expo.
Because we were,
we actually went for felt bikes because
felt put their bikes at the western
expo.
And they said,
well,
you come here and like give a testimony
that you use these things will explain
what it is
felt.
Bike is.
We've been using them all week.
They're awesome.
They're their mountain bikes that have
like assisted.
He,
it's an Ebay,
so it's um,
it has a pedal assist.
It has a bosh motor on it and as long as
you're pedaling,
you can,
it has a battery that you charge and as
long as you're pedaling,
you can,
you have four settings and you can use a
setting where it actually assists you.
And it,
the way I describe it as each one of
those numbers,
whether it's eco sport to her,
um,
turbo turbo,
whichever one it is,
it's almost like that is equal to one
other person
being on your bike.
I want to just tell you something,
I never used those things with anything
less than terrible.
Whatever it was set out.
I was like,
Turbo shut the fuck up.
And they're unbelievable.
As long as you're turning the pedals,
is that they'll go set.
Yeah,
they'll go 17 miles an hour,
which I think is what by law.
Anything that goes over that,
I think it it gets kind of classify it
as a different type of.
It's not eligible to go on a non
motorized trails so you can use these
bikes on non motorized pass,
like in Montana and stuff.
You'd be able to take these like we're
green tree went.
You'd be able to take a bike on that
same trail.
Well what's important about it is two
things.
One,
you can charge these things with solar
power because they're electrical and to.
One of the things that happens in these
cold weather hunts is you hike far and
wide up mountains and if you're not,
if you didn't do a good job of layering,
so like you might have too much clothes
on on the way up there and you start
sweating and then once you get there
then you're hunting.
So you're not climbing hills anymore.
You're stop.
Now you're stop and you fucking phrase.
And Hypothermia is the number one cause
of death in the mountains.
Is it number one?
Yes.
It kills more people than grizzly bears.
Rattlesnakes,
mountain lions.
People fucking freeze to death.
And when,
when you're up there and you sweat and
you,
especially if you were in cotton,
one of the biggest improvements that
people figured out was Merino,
because if you were a merino wool,
there's something about the natural
fibers in,
in wool that allow you to stay warm.
Air Resistance is,
it is the under armour shirt.
Well,
I'm first light has an awesome a Merino
wool selection.
You has a lot of Merino wool and under
Harvard,
which what I'm wearing right now,
they have a bunch of Merino wool stuff
too.
They've had a ton of different styles.
Yeah.
Merino wool is like,
it's a big with the hiking crowd and
outdoorsman or backpackers and stuff
will
amazing characteristics.
There's a lot of cool stories about.
Well,
people that were on like plane crashes
are shipwrecks.
And the only ones that survived see were
the ones that had wool.
Everyone else would die of hypothermia.
When we,
um,
I was with a company that did some
Merino wool,
started a line of Merino wool.
So we brought in a lot of specialists
from New Zealand that actually showed us
the different kinds of marina wool.
And stuff,
and then that's when he started to learn
a lot about the stories of Merino wool
and a lot of them,
there's a ton of survivor stories with
people that would wear will versus
trying to where other types of
synthetics and like,
you know,
obviously that was an extreme case.
Um,
so it was pretty interesting.
That's fascinating.
You know nothing about it.
Is it for whatever reason it doesn't
stink.
Yeah.
Like I've been wearing wool socks.
I will always wear wool socks.
Um,
when I would do any type of hunting or
hiking or anything where I know my feet
are going to be sweating.
It makes such a big difference.
You take off her socks,
it doesn't even smell your warm.
Doesn't make any sense.
Whereas if I were cotton socks,
it smells like someone died in my shoes
as a Goddamn Eco castrophe going on
inside of my Nike's.
It's,
it's horrible.
The smell like if you work out all day
and to keep your,
your,
your socks on,
they just sweat and then fester and the
bacteria grows.
There's some natural antimicrobial
properties of a,
of Merino wool.
It's awesome stuff.
Very awesome.
So felt bikes,
great.
Western Bank
tells me that you're,
that you liked the podcast and he could
tell by my face.
I figured this was another one of the
Michael Hooper Pranks.
So I was like,
okay.
And I said,
well,
I said if he wants to hook up then you
know,
then connect us or whatever.
So we're back to the hotel and Sharon
and I,
we went and checked in.
We're there maybe two hours and Mike
texts me,
he says Joe and camera and the mountain
ops booth right now I'm doing a podcast.
Go by there and say hi to him.
And I'm like,
Oh really?
And he said yeah.
And I'm like,
okay.
So I literally hung up with them and I
told Sharon,
I'm like,
yeah,
I'm not going over there.
I said,
I'll guarantee you they're doing a
podcast and I'm going to go over there
and be like,
Hey Jill,
Mike told me that you wanted to meet me
and then he'd be like,
who the effort?
I just like,
Mike's like,
did you,
did you connect
for them?
I said,
no.
And he's like,
why not?
And I said,
well,
I thought I didn't believe you.
So he was crying wolf too many times.
See,
I didn't take him serious when he was
telling the truth,
but then you called me out on twitter,
which I wasn't really a twitter guy.
You kind of,
I think you sent me something or you
said something and then
I think I just said how much your
podcast is awesome.
Yeah.
And I got blasted by all my friends.
I'm like,
God,
Joe Rogan's talking about your podcast.
So.
Well,
this is very rare that someone
specializes in something to the extreme
that you do with archery where you don't
even like when I do a podcast in this
podcast is a perfect example.
Many times during this podcast I've had
to say,
well,
for people who don't know that means
this.
Or for people who haven't heard that,
that's a.
You don't even bother doing that.
You start talking about AC tends
different campaigns.
Zx K no you shouldn't because what
you're doing is you're.
You are a hard core archery podcasts and
it is,
you know,
catch up if you can stay with it,
if you can,
but you go deep,
deep,
deep into all of the variables of
archery.
And for me it makes me understand and
appreciate.
I still is.
I mean I've been shooting bows for a few
years now and really hardcore for most
of the time,
like really into it most of the time
still.
There's a lot of shit you talk about.
I don't know what the fuck you're saying
because it's so.
It's so detailed.
There's so much going on,
but also because you were very
successful target archer,
which is,
you know,
uh,
of course you see in,
you know,
you've seen on television in the
Olympics and all this different stuff.
Target archery,
which is almost as specialized and weird
in its own way as hunting as bowhunting.
Yeah.
Target our trees.
You learn so much about the sport one,
you really start to have to learn your
equipment.
And then for me,
I really learned a whole new aspect of
just competitiveness,
preparation,
diet,
how to travel,
how to travel smart.
Um,
because it's,
it's a huge investment to go to
tournaments across the world.
You know,
you look at some of those over there,
you know,
from Poland or Sweden or what was the
biggest tournament that you won?
I don't know.
They're all different.
I don't think anyone of them.
I always liked winning the team rounds
the best.
I always loved shooting team rounds.
I got really pumped up with that.
I don't really remember very many of
them.
I do remember,
but I don't see what's,
what I was trying to get to.
And this segues into it.
I started cheating competitive archery
to be a better bow hunter.
That's the only reason I competed
because I was in the same mental state
is what you were of,
okay,
if I'm going to go out and do this,
I want to know that if I've got one
shot,
I want to make sure that it's right.
Because when I started I was never
taught properly.
I was just,
we hunted a lot for our family's food.
I was down in Mississippi when I was
younger where I lived and I made a lot
of mistakes.
I would miss a lot and just,
you know,
I was self taught.
I think I was with a lot of people that
just like,
you know,
they'd pick it up and just try to do it
and you spend a lot of time sitting and
waiting for an opportunity and then when
you blow it,
it's extremely frustrating.
So I just decided to start shooting
competitive archery.
You know,
I ended up shooting one little
tournament and then all sudden I
realized,
wait a minute,
this is what's going to make me a really
good bowhunter if.
Because when I shot my first tournament,
it made me realize how bad of a hunter I
was from a point of being able to make a
shot.
So I'm like,
I have to get better at this because if
I'm going to be hunting and I'm going to
be spending that much time for an
opportunity,
I have to be able to seize the moment.
So.
And the reason I left the,
the U,
s team was because that year,
um,
when they posted the schedule,
the World Cup final was at the end of
September and so I knew that September
would be training and then we'd have to
fly mid September.
So if I wasn't willing to commit to go
to the World Cup final that I wasn't,
I couldn't stay on the team.
So that was elk season.
I mean,
and that's actually what I said.
I just told them,
I said,
listen,
I don't,
I do not shoot tournaments between
September and December.
That's it.
And they,
I said,
I won't be doing that tournament if
that's what it is.
And then they just said,
well,
you're not going to be able to stay on
the team.
And just said,
okay,
and that was it.
Don't get it.
They never heard of
that thousand pound forest horse with
swords coming out of its head running
over the top of the hill until you've
seen a bugling elk in the Rut.
So just foaming at the mouth and jizzing
all over himself,
literally jizzing all over himself and
does massive majestic beast that looks
like it's like in the Lord of the rings
or something.
I mean it really is.
There was a,
someone puts something up on twitter and
I thought it was really interesting
because it was from the perspective of
someone who's a complete non hunter and
it was a,
it was just a bugling elk screaming and
they were like the most insane sounds
that elk make when they bugle.
And the comments were like,
Whoa,
this thing is like some mythical beast
because somebody caught a really cool,
like,
you know,
like people,
they have different voices and some elk
have just bad ass voice.
Especially those heard bowls like the
way elk works.
Folks,
if you don't know,
there'll be.
Like when I was Al Connie recently,
last month cam and I found this one bowl
that uh,
at the ranch they were calling the sword
bull because he had just these crazy
long beams growing out of the side of
his head.
It was like a really odd.
Sometimes you get odd shaped beams that
grow out of these animals heads and he
was the of the ranch and there was like,
he had at least 12 chicks with them,
12 female cows and that's a pretty small
following them everywhere.
That's a pretty small high heroin.
Well for Immuno herd bull I guess,
but it was watching,
watching all the little satellite bowls
hang around this guy,
there's like a few like,
hey girls.
I'm pretty cool too.
He's like,
shut up.
And then they would run them off.
Was he a Groaner?
He was a screamer.
Does
that sound that they make?
But
yeah,
no,
it was.
Some of the ones that get blown out,
they just get to the point where they're
like,
it's like a bull frog.
Like a real old one.
They can't really beautiful anymore.
So they're just like,
sounds terrible.
But you know,
they're called,
you know,
everyone calls him like groaners and um,
if you're an elk country,
when you hear real blown out bugle like
that,
you know,
it's probably a super old bull.
Have you ever seen an Irish elk?
Now?
What is that?
You haven't know what is.
They're extinct now.
Check this out dude.
You have to Google this and
I'm right here with the role roam the
earth right here.
Whoa.
Oh my God.
They were.
They were awesome.
Look at that thing.
Is that awesome?
Or what?
It looks like a combination of a stag
and an elk,
but they're way more massive.
There's still fine and some look at
that.
Oh,
it's like a Mousse
thing.
It's,
yeah,
it's an Irish elk.
You need to look them up.
They're amazing.
When did they die off?
Um,
I think it said 20th century.
No kidding.
Wow.
Let's see.
Wait,
no,
let's look at it right here.
Most remains of Irish show date between
11 slash seven slash 54
present.
So definitely not the 20th century.
I wonder why they died off.
That's interesting.
I don't know.
There was a enormous,
um,
Eagle that you still live in New
Zealand.
I'm trying to remember the name of it.
Uh,
ge,
Google,
enormous eagle in New Zealand.
I forgot.
I'm trying to remember.
Nervous Eagle,
New Zealand because they'll give you a
heartbeat.
Ego,
which is,
which is the,
uh,
the biggest,
Eagle that exists today.
You know,
you can just go like that and then like
that.
Oh,
you hit the download.
Haast Eagle.
That's it.
That was the biggest eagle ever.
And they were so big.
They would eat people.
What?
500,
10 pounds.
Are you kid?
Yeah.
They had a 10 foot waves.
You get that freaking thing.
Five hundred and 10 pounds eagle with a
10 foot wingspan.
Hello?
That's straight out of Harry Potter,
Dude.
Yeah.
Amazing.
And they were so big and so powerful.
And New Zealand,
if you don't know,
does not have a lot of indigenous
mammals.
New Zealand was really shut off from the
rest of the world.
Yeah,
it's called h a s t dot eagle.
It was a new and they,
I believe they went extinct in the 14
hundreds.
I would,
it says 1400.
And the reason why they went extinct,
uh,
they were hunted to extinction by the
first mowery,
but that is a little bit controversial.
Some people think that it wasn't
necessarily that,
but that the mowery ate everything that
they ate and they didn't have any food
left,
but there were a lot of accounts by the
mowery of them eating people.
Oh my God.
Look at the size of this Irish.
See you're not appreciating it.
I've seen it.
I've seen an actual one that's in a
museum,
so it says two point 10 meters tall to
the bottom of the bottom of the bottom,
like before the face.
Why do they measure their.
Why don't they mentioned at the time of
his head,
so that's way bigger than a regular elk.
Way Bigger,
way bigger.
That looks like it's several thousand
pounds.
Look at that picture.
These people next to it.
Oh my God.
Folks,
what it looks like is a bowl with the
long legs and like a Moose on steroids.
Antlers.
Wow.
Irish elk.
Aren't they cool.
See,
fascinating.
Back woolly mammoths.
They need to bring back that thing and
do it on New Zealand so he can hunt it.
Make you know.
That's another.
Like in New Zealand,
it's kind of weird because they don't
have a hunting tags or seasons for most
of their animals,
so you just go there and fucking go
crazy and shoot everything because they
have no predators.
So they
have all these.
Yeah,
they have all these ungulates,
all these animals that exists there and
unfortunately that's amazing animal.
Unfortunately a lot of the,
um,
that the animals and New Zealand are
also in these high fence operations.
So like you'll go over there and
you know,
there'll be a few hundred acres or few
thousand acres depending on where you're
shot in Ireland,
elk,
these people chasing it down with their
shitty arrows.
The barely penetrate.
They,
they a backstrap backstrap yeah.
Look where they hit him.
I know.
Terrible pictures.
Even the drawing sucks.
They didn't even know how to do,
are treated with a drawing.
Just put it in the right spot.
You missed all the haters out there
about this hunt podcasts.
We historically,
and we thoroughly enjoyed our,
what we've been eating.
Oh yeah man.
God.
So good.
And I made a few posts on the.
We've had,
we've had elk tender loins.
Um,
I've talked to you about hog hunting.
I'm a big advocate of.
I love shooting hawks.
I love shooting gators.
Um,
we had a ridiculously good pork shoulder
today.
Incredible.
Does your friend Preston made progress
and made it into my head?
How many hours did you cook it for?
Slow cooked and for 17 something
crazy.
I mean it was falling apart as you stick
a fork into it,
but yeah,
we uh,
we've been eating wild game.
Amazing wild game.
I think wild pig hunting is one thing
that almost everybody wants to do.
Like even bill burr,
my friend bill who's never expressed any
interest in hunting,
I give him elk whenever he comes and
does my podcast.
Like he came last week and I gave him a
bunch of,
uh,
elk and uh,
he loves meat.
He eats meat.
He goes,
yeah,
I'd go wild pig hunting.
I go,
really?
He goes,
yeah,
you want to take me wild to on it?
I'll fuck.
Yeah,
dude,
let's do it.
So I'm going to take a pig hunting pigs.
Hunting is the one,
like even my agent.
My agent is the,
she's the nicest lady.
Shout out to stacy.
She's a sweetheart and she loves
animals.
She loves dogs.
She rescues dogs.
So I was cast and loves all animals and
when she finds out that I hunt,
she was like,
oh,
I don't know how I feel about that.
I go,
but you eat meat.
She goes,
I know.
you should hunt pigs.
I go,
why?
She goes,
because they're ugly.
I'm like,
why?
That's what Sharon started out with
Sharon,
my wife is from England.
And then she started out.
She started out having no interest in
hunting yourself.
But then when she started to realize
just how many deer there were,
um,
she was like,
we like,
this is a necessity because for sure,
well,
and we're in Wisconsin at the time and
then she really wanted to do it.
But like you,
she said,
I don't want to go.
I know I'm totally proficient.
So she shot for a long time for learning
the proper way.
Shot.
And then she said,
you know,
from the hunting aspect,
I think if I'm gonna like actually hunt,
I think I want to start with something
like maybe ugly,
like a,
like a rush Russian hog or something
like a Russian boar because like those,
those bores are there.
They overrun certain parts of Florida,
like on the sod farmers,
we do a lot of hunting on sod farms and
um,
we're down there with Osceola outfitters
hoppy,
Kemper's name and it's,
it's amazing how good the pig hunting
is,
but it's also equally amazing how much
destruction they due to his place.
I mean,
he runs hunts 360 days a year and
there's people shooting them every
single day and they're still just tons.
It's crazy.
Well,
you,
when you talk about how they breed,
that's where it gets so shocking when
you find out that they can get to full
maturity in six months.
They have a litter and I believe they're
only pregnant for six weeks and then
they shit out.
The kids get out of there six months
later,
they're having kids of their own and
they could do that cycle.
I think three times a year and they can
have a ton.
I mean they could have a ton of babies
and they just keep multiplying over and
over and over and over again and in the
less someone comes along and shoot them,
there is not enough mountain lions in
the world to keep a cap on that.
They just,
they're not going to be able to do it.
Pigs are very smart too.
They're super smart.
They're super turned,
turned in,
turn tuned in.
Their eyesight sucks,
but their sense of smell is incredible.
Yeah.
Ridiculous.
They smell you a fucking mile away and
like see a dude and they just start
running header over the hill.
They do so much damage to fences to.
I think someone told me something like
if,
if they can get it
their snout into something,
then they can get their whole body
through it.
Like they have that much will.
So if they can get the snout,
like into the fence or under the fence,
they will be through it.
Geez.
Yeah.
There they do some crazy far away.
They find a way.
Well,
there is so fucked up that is the only
animal in North America that allow you
to hunt from a helicopter with the
machine gun.
We're in Texas.
They're like,
go ahead.
That is so Texas.
We have a hard problem.
What should we do,
man?
You know what I've been thinking.
I've been thinking about helicopters,
man.
Helicopters and machine goes like,
what the fuck are you?
Who?
Who let this guy in the meeting?
Man,
we've got to curb these things.
I'm thinking nuclear weapons.
No,
no,
no.
Okay.
How about helicopter helicopters?
Helicopters and machine guns over
nuclear weapon.
All.
All grade.
Okay.
Next.
Next item on the agenda.
So they just.
They have this thing called Helen
hunters and there's an episode of
pigment.
There's a show called pigment and
pigment just goes around shooting pigs
all the time.
He got the name pig man and he lives in
Texas where again,
it has to be done.
Texas has Mu Eons of pigs.
They have so many pigs that Texas opened
up a new road.
I forget where the road was.
They opened up a new road and they had
40 car accidents the first night from
people slamming into pigs.
That's when you know you've got a fucked
up problem.
So when I told you,
oh,
go ahead.
This episode of Pigman,
it's called a pork lips now,
and a pork lips now is a Ted nugent,
had pigman you can watch on youtube.
They get into fucking helicopter and
they shoot 250 pigs in a day and they're
flying around and then just dark,
dark,
like a Goddamn platoon movie.
Detect that they're hitting these pigs
in the head as the pigs are running full
clip and the pigs are flipping head over
feet.
I mean it's fucked up and you know,
they're not eating those things.
Half of them,
they're just going to leave there.
No one cares.
They just have to do something.
Try to curb that population.
Now if you did that with lambs or josh
or with deer,
you know,
or any,
any normal farm animal.
We have a hierarchy of animals that will
allow people to do that too.
Yeah,
it is funny that people have that
they've got that one thing,
whereas as soon as you start shooting a
deer,
they're not cool with it.
Or the big one is bears.
Bears are certainly the biggest.
That's the big one.
Yup.
But again,
mean bears.
It's the same thing if you go with the
rivets live up in Alberta,
man,
black bears are everywhere.
They have so many bears anywhere in
Canada.
They are,
there's a lot of them,
tons,
tons of barriers.
And the only thing stopping their
population growth is hunters.
Yup.
That's it.
But,
um,
so back to this apocalypse now thing,
the,
um,
uh,
like I said,
the episodes are on twitter,
but if you need to just,
it gives you also a good source.
I don't think you'll ever get it unless
you see giant packs of pit.
What do they call?
What do they call know?
What do they call a pack of pigs?
I think pack a pig sounds pretty good.
You know what they call it?
Aborigines.
Um,
uh,
you know,
Adam Green tree,
our buddy from Australia,
he uh,
he owns a mining company or does dusting
company.
We does mining right,
is involved a lot of mining operations.
I don't know that part.
Okay.
But anyway,
he,
uh,
and he employs a bunch of aborigines and
so,
uh,
he got to know them really well and he
told me it's a fascinating,
fascinating stories about their culture
and their history.
It's really interesting stuff,
but one of the things,
as crazy as when you call a group,
you don't call them a tribe,
they call themselves a mob.
Is that just their term
analogy for it?
Yeah.
Terminology is a mob,
like an average.
The mob obviously it's just a different
meaning than the mob.
Yeah.
Not like the mob and the mafia,
like that's just a pack,
you know,
I'm a tribe,
a group,
a clan,
you know,
they call themselves a mob and he said
you will have,
they'll have one language and that they
speak and then 10 miles over there's
another group that has a totally
different language and they can't speak
each other's language.
Kinda like England is England,
like the dialects.
Oh,
but there's still an English.
These people are not speaking in Africa.
It's like that too.
There's a lot of.
You go from tribe to tribe and it's
almost like a completely different.
Yeah,
different dialect.
Totally.
That's probably where the whole tower of
Babel story came from,
from the Bible.
You know,
back when there was not that much travel
when you had to ride a fucking horse to
get somewhere.
If you were lucky,
if you had one.
So it's probably if you,
once you crossed over a mountain range
or something like that,
those fuckers over there,
there was totally your language.
Yeah.
Like look at Europe,
you know,
you could just travel a short distance
and you're dealing with completely
different languages.
Totally different culture.
Well yeah,
it was in Sweden.
I'm doing some coaching with the
national team and you know,
you can be in Italy or you can be in
France or you can be Germany and no
time.
Yeah,
I mean it's completely different
culture.
Completely different language,
completely different people,
different food,
different history.
It's amazing and it's all smaller than a
segment of the United States and that's
with
vehicles.
Yeah.
So I mean,
imagine before,
before when you've been in some of the
mountains,
we have elk it in.
Would you really want to have to go two
or three mountain ranges over just
because if you had a cool little house
and some running water and a little
place to dump and.
Yeah,
all that stuff,
you'd be kind of happy right there.
Yeah.
Hey,
I think I'm just going to go walk over
here and risk hypothermia because they
don't have marina wool.
On
how,
how long did you travel for archery?
I did just,
I think,
I think I've done three passports.
Three full passports.
What?
With extensions?
One point $3.
Million Miles I've got flying.
Wow.
All shooting bows and shooting a bow.
You know what's crazy is um,
three years ago,
Shit,
Sharon and I went to inherit him.
Our son went to Mexico for vacation and
it was the first time I'd ever traveled
without a bookcase.
Well,
those Puerto Vallarta.
Yup.
That's crazy.
We were down there at the same time.
Yup.
That was the yeah,
no kid and that was weird.
I was literally getting,
I was getting on the plane to go home
and you were,
you were just getting there.
The same exact time.
Fucking love Puerto Vallarta.
Oh,
so awesome.
Going Back Jack Spot.
It's a good spot,
right?
When this ruts done,
I'm going to.
Here's what's going to happen.
I'm going to be sitting in a tree for 13
hours a day for about another 21 days
and when that's done,
I'm going to sleep for about three days.
I'm going to shave this space and I'm
going to sling some onnit kettlebells
around like three or four hours a day.
Get a beach body.
Yup.
And I'm going to get,
I'm going to get my pv body going,
but uh,
no.
Since I met you,
you got me hooked on it and it's totally
changed me because when I did
in September,
well I started hunting in October 24th,
August,
24th is when I start.
I start in Alberta and then I worked my
way through several states and a lot of
different tags,
but I went 30 days with all I ate was
one meal a day idea meal at night.
But um,
I lived off the tpc packs.
I've,
I've packed them all in a big one gallon
Ziploc bag.
I do it the tpc packs for morning and
evening.
Um,
I would do three Alpha brains that I'd
put in three different bottles of water
throughout the day.
One of the,
um,
total gut house.
And then I would do two of the Omega
bars and to have the tonka bars and I
lived off that for 30 days.
That's all you and I.
and I was at for dinner too.
That was your dinner?
I would normally cook some kind of a
dinner at night.
But that was what you were eating during
the day?
Yup.
Why did you limit yourself to so little
food?
Because I was always in my backpack.
Oh.
And it was like super portable is easy
to travel with.
So you were,
you were doing the hardcore backpack on
thing?
Not,
I mean,
it wasn't truly hardcore,
it was just,
if,
I think if you're hunting,
I like to try to get as much rest as I
can because if you shoot something and
you're up all night and then a lot of
these places I have multiple tags so I'm
right back at it the next day.
Like in Alberta,
I was there,
I think I was there nine days and I
think I did 87 miles on my little Garmin
is what I covered on our feet.
So,
um,
it's,
you burn a lot of calories and then,
you know,
obviously Montana is way more rugged
than Alberta.
I mean it was some of that stuff.
I Bet I was,
I did half the distance but I feel like
I was probably having to put twice the
effort in,
but it was,
it totally sustained me when that would,
you know,
that's pretty hard beating on you,
just living off out of a backpack.
Really Limited sleep and being in
different places.
I wish I would've had that when I
competed.
Well,
keeping those neurotransmitters at good
levels is so important.
It's one of the reasons why if I fly
somewhere and I land,
I do two things,
two things like right away,
one,
unless I get there at night and I'm
tired,
I just go to sleep,
but one of the first things I do is I do
a 30 minute workout.
It doesn't even have to kill yourself.
I just,
I,
I a minimum of 30 minutes.
I like to go to the gym and just get
everything going.
Just fire up those engines,
blow out those pipes,
get that blood flowing,
and if I don't do that,
I don't feel as good.
It takes me a day or two to adjust,
but if I do do that and then I have a
nice salad or a healthy meal afterwards,
I feel great.
The other thing is Alpha brain,
it's so important to me to get those,
those levels of your neurotransmitters
high because it's one of the things that
affects you the most about jet lag and
travel.
Your sleep patterns off and your brain
chemistry is all funky.
I take new mood and I take Alpha brain,
new moods,
great,
but Alpha brain is imperative.
I have to take it,
if I do a UFC,
you know,
anytime where my mind has to be fired up
for long time
periods of time.
I do notice a difference with it and I
like the peach one that you put in with
water.
Um,
because I,
I probably,
I don't enjoy drinking water but I drink
a lot throughout the day.
So having a few of those that I can do
throughout the day with some flavoring.
Yeah,
tastes good if it doesn't make sure.
Yeah.
See I like a little taste,
but I don't like sugar.
Sugar would put me off if I tasted it,
but yeah,
they've been awesome.
And the new moods I normally take for
those at night with that tpc Apac and I
get to fuck with your dreams.
I love it.
I get into some crazy dream modes.
Alpha brain does that to Alpha brain
gives me these wolves on lucid dreams.
That's what you told me.
So I'm like on.
I do a tpc night.
I did.
Well,
I do.
I had a tpc nyt now.
I'll take for new moods,
but then I'll have one of my alfred
brains if I'm at home is when they go to
bed.
I like to.
I like to dream because then I at least
feel like I'm getting true deep sleep.
It sounds like you're having adventures,
like if you've taken that much,
me having you must be on magical mystery
tour is every night
a magical mystery tour.
Yeah.
It's a,
you know,
I'm glad.
I'm glad you got into that.
I'm glad you also,
uh,
I know you did a lot of work with some
of those guys down to onnit academy and
you learned a lot of shoulder mobility
exercises and shoulder strengthening
exercises that I think can be really
critical for archers.
You know,
archery is a,
as much as it is about technique and
it's,
as much as it is about proper form and
proper execution,
there's also muscle involved.
There's also strength involved.
Any.
Obviously it's an athletic endeavor.
You're dealing with your body and um,
I think it's really cool that you're
developing like a program of specific
things that you feel would benefit
archers,
give them shoulder stability,
range of motion.
Um,
I know we did some of them yesterday
with the club bells,
which I find really beneficial for a lot
of things.
Um,
club bells and I'm.
One of the things I like about them is
that they,
they're really awkward with.
It's a,
what it is,
it's,
it's exactly what it sounds like.
It's a club.
It's an iron club.
So this is long handle and then there's
a lot of mass at the top of the handle
and it's
baseball bat made out of cast iron is
Dang near what it would be a good
description.
Yeah.
And I have some longer heavier ones at
home,
um,
that I've really gotten into it.
Say when I say heavier,
I'm only talking about 35 pounds.
That's all you need.
I mean,
you don't need that much would.
We're doing these exercises called
shield casts.
It's so difficult to do,
to take a 35 pound club with all the
weight at the end of it,
so it's weird leverage and then control
it,
swinging it over the top of your head
and then bringing it down with full
control.
That pausing it in front of you.
I think that's incredible for archery
and I think it would be incredibly
beneficial for stability of your front
arm and having the strength to be able
to hold your front arm there without any
strain or any like shaking or weird.
Yeah,
just skip your scapula.
Stability is a is a huge weakness point
in archery when archers breakdown,
it's normally because of super weak
scapular stability muscles and there's a
lot of different movements that they
taught me at the Ana,
the cat,
because I really wanted to go there to
one.
I think since you showed me some of the
first moves you showed me,
just kettlebells.
I realize this is stuff that.
This is stuff I'd use every day.
I mean,
you've been here four days.
How often am I picking up that felt by
putting in the back of my truck and you
know,
picking up
and feed sacks or whatever.
I mean,
that's like true useful strength and
mobility and flexibility and so all of
these movements teaches that and I
really wanted something that,
um,
one thing I learned to appreciate when I
lived in England was Sharon for a long
time was you don't have some people just
don't have the space to have very much
workout equipment with kettlebells.
And some teams,
like some of the teams I work with,
especially with some of the smaller
countries,
they don't have huge budgets,
but with kettlebells they can,
that's a minimal investment and it's a
minimal space usage to you can take two
kettlebells and keep them in a corner.
It's not like you got the total gym with
Chuck Norris,
you know,
hiding in the corner and it's wasted a
bunch of space.
And I really wanted to go on one,
learn proper technique and learn
different movements and then realize,
okay,
which ones actually work good for
archery or what ones can help archers.
And my plan was originally we were going
to do some videos.
I'm with those guys on an academy
specific for some archers.
Um,
but this hunting season has,
I've been so busy,
I mean,
and even right now I'd like to be able
to go,
but I'm,
I'm in no way having time just because
I'm trying to get my hunt stone trying
to finish the TV show and do all that
stuff and
time.
But it is on the schedule because I
think so many people are going to
benefit from learning super simple
movements that really increase your
range.
Like that steel mace I liked just
because of how much range teach you all
the way around,
know you're getting so much range in
that shoulder joint and you're really
having to focus on that scapular
stability all the way around.
And then you even when he come around to
the front,
you know,
even though it doesn't look like you're
doing much,
if you're doing it properly,
you're really engaging your core to seed
everything down and then bring
everything to center.
And so much of being stable as an archer
is having a solid platform and a solid
base.
And that core stability is what we're
all that radiates from.
If the core is,
is loose or unstable,
then obviously everything outside of
that is going to be the same way.
Yeah.
And especially when you consider when
you do archery,
you're pulling with
your back and your scapula and involved
in the drawing of the bow and also in
the making the boat release,
the,
the executing the shot.
Another extra a exercise that I think is
critical for archers is chin ups.
And I think that um,
if it's like,
if I could say one piece of equipment,
if you could,
it could only afford one.
Get a chin up bar.
I think chin up bars are giant and
especially a good one that actually
comes off the wall.
Look,
if you can invest in one,
you have the space and you just,
you know,
get it mounted on some studs in your
house.
It's so critical,
I think.
Yes,
the hangs.
What I was going to say,
first of all,
hangs are so good for your shoulders.
And there's a bunch of articles and
videos,
watch the videos on youtube by some
doctors.
I was first turned onto this by Steve
Maxwell.
He told me about this.
There was a doctor,
this particular doctor,
I've,
sorry,
I forget his name,
but I'm sure you could find it really
quickly.
Uh,
and he invented this method of hanging
and releasing tension and pressure in
the shoulder joint because he thinks
that a lot of the pain that people
suffer from impacted shoulders is really
just a function of our,
our bodies are designed.
We have essentially like ancient primate
genetics and ancient primate structure.
And then one thing primates,
almost all of them have in common is
they swing from things by their arms.
They hang by their arms,
they swing by their arms and that
pulling and stretching,
stretching and lengthening of the,
those,
that soft tissue in those tendons,
that's imperative to both stay the
stability of the shoulder and the
alleviation of pain in the range of
motion.
I've,
I've experienced some really great
results with hanging from my shoulders
and also from something that I learned
from you,
which is hanging from a chin up bar and
then with my arms completely extended,
just contracting the Scapula,
so just contract and then I'll hold that
for as long as I can and then I'll
release it yet.
Yeah.
So you're almost hanging to the point
where you let your shoulders fully
extend where he,
you know,
you feel like,
you feel like you're on the verge of
letting go of something if you're
hanging.
But then in that same position you
literally take your shoulder sockets and
almost pull them down to your armpits.
So without bending your arms.
Yeah.
You don't bend your arms,
you're not using any bicep.
There's a video of John doing it online
too.
If you could find that,
would it.
Do you remember the name of your video?
I Dunno,
it was right after I had shoulder
surgery,
so I know that I wasn't able to do it
really well,
which was kind of the point I think,
you know,
I was having to,
I just came out of the shoulder surgery
so I was trying to,
to rebuild that string.
I'm trying to see here,
but there's a ton of exercises you can
do.
You can afford for perfect form in front
bolts,
both shoulder,
so knock on archery,
the knock on our tree youtube channel,
but it's the if you want to look at it,
and by the way,
that's all.
So also
an awesome channel for instruction.
You want to learn some stuff about
archery and I think that might be one of
the things I'd seen from you before ever
met you two is a bunch of little
instructional videos that you had put
out on the proper way to use releases on
a bunch of different things.
That's what I did.
I teach.
That's what he does.
Folks teach stuff.
And uh,
I know that sounds crazy,
but we're going to end this podcast.
Dude.
It's only an hour.
Forty five minutes.
Dude,
you only did one podcast.
Listen,
I'll be back.
Just relax.
If we tag out tomorrow,
maybe John and I will do a fight
companion.
Who,
how about that?
Yeah,
fucks a.
that's a,
that's a big F.
I mean,
who knows if we tag out and um,
so this one I'm going to,
uh,
I'll email this to young jamie and
hopefully he'll get this up pronto and
uh,
you guys will get it tomorrow.
So that's it for now.
Um,
you can check out John's instagram page.
It's knock on TV,
uh,
the youtube channels,
knock on archery and all the episodes
are up.
Also have your TV show.
They're all for free and unfettered
trade as well.
There you go,
ladies and gentlemen,
and if you're interested,
you're like,
man,
I need a hobby.
Pickup our tree,
goddammit.
And I wished it was a place near me that
was a,
a place that taught,
you know,
it's,
it's hard.
It's hard to find a good archery school.
And,
uh,
I mean we were talking about that today
about what archery clubs or like in
England or in,
um,
in Europe is that they're like country
clubs where people go and like the way
people go to play golf,
people go to do archery and you know,
they appreciate it as an,
a discipline.
Yeah.
They have memberships and full bars in
there and beautiful facility.
Yeah,
all kinds of cool,
cool stuff.
Yeah,
for sure.
Anyway,
we're exhausted folks.
We've been doing nothing but waiting all
day and getting up early to have a
little rnr here.
We're giving you guys a hour and 45
minutes,
but that's it.
Unless they're sagging,
it must have now.
Tomorrow we gotta drop the Hammer.
So thanks for tuning in.
Everybody.
Next week I'm back to a regularly
scheduled podcast.
I've got a podcast with the Great Dave
Rubin and I think that is on.
Um,
yeah,
that's on Monday.
Then Tuesday we're doing the big
election day and the world podcast live
from the comedy store with Doug Stan.
Hope bilber.
Bert Kreischer a bunch of other people
too.
I think Joey Diaz is coming in.
Tom Rhodes,
uh,
Bert crushers on the podcast on
Wednesday and uh,
and then the next week I got a lot to.
Next week I got Shannon the Canon
Briggs.
Let's go champ.
He'll be on the 14th.
Yeah,
that's right.
Fuckers.
Graham Hancock and rail.
No,
Carlson on the 15th.
I got a lot of shit going on folks.
So
even though I'm kind of a here,
I'm here for myself.
What about those man?
Sometimes I got to do shit for me.
That way it's more interesting when I do
shit for you,
man.
I'm living life.
God dammit.
I suggest you do the same.
Thanks for tuning in.
I appreciate you folks.
And big kiss
a thanks for tuning into the podcast
folks.
Thanks to John Dudley for hat.
Let me use his equipment and thanks to
diff eyewear diff.
I wear stylish,
handmade sunglasses,
ridiculously cheap made with high end
materials.
They're awesome.
And for each pair of sunglasses you buy
diff.
I where we'll give a pair of reading
glasses to someone in need.
Try it.
You folks do good by smarter be diff.
That's what the logo is.
That's not me.
Difm go to diff eyewear.com forward
slash rogen right now to get 15 percent
off your purchase.
That's d I f,
F I were.com.
Forward Slash Rogan to get 15 percent
off.
Diff eyewear.com.
Forward Slash rogen.
Yeah,
baby.
We're also brought to you by Casper.
Awesome mattresses,
ridiculously low prices and incredible
risk.
Free trial and return policy.
You can try it for 100 days.
What more do you want?
God dammit,
go to casper.com.
Forward Slash Joe.
Use the Promo Code Joe at checkout terms
and conditions may apply,
but you can say 50 bucks.
50 bucks by going to casper.com.
Forward Slash Joe.
All right folks,
that's it.
We're DVD DVD.
Done so see you next week.
Bye.
Love Ya.
Hugs.
Hugs for you all.