Boom, boom, boom. What's happening
brother? Let's do it, man. What's crack?
It's good to be back. Good to be back.
Good. It's always amazing. It's like,
it's like a little, it's a,
it's a bit of an amusement park
almost now with stuff to see and the,
and the gym equipment and everything.
I keep thinking I should just bring my
gear over and work out before the show or
after the show, but they lose, I
don't want to embarrass myself,
so I'm going to embarrass you. Say I'm
not going to watch or watch your workout.
And he would like Jamie's,
that kind of guy. Yeah,
I've seen him give me side-eye he
would give me, but no, it's, yeah,
it's all good. Everything's, everything's
good. I've been traveling a lot,
having to, we just talked
before we started about Idaho.
Haven't had a chance to get back there,
but, uh, yeah. All good. All good.
So you're around for a television show,
is that what you're doing? Um, yeah,
this is, this is a, there's, there's
several meetings going on here,
but we just finished,
uh, uh, filming a show,
a reality show, um, for, uh,
can I say the network they Kinda Hinky
on until we get closer to the hair day,
which is October. Uh, but it's for the
discovery network and it's gonna be,
it's gonna be a great show that I,
that I'm hosting. Well, you know what,
that's what I always said.
I always thought free
publicity is a good thing. Um,
but they're very tight on the marketing
protocols and so they want to make sure
they've got it all buttoned up. And I
get that right. They spend, you know,
a lot of money on these things and
fucking so freaks. Yeah. And so, anyway,
but it's going to be a
great, uh, a great show.
We spent the past three or four months,
um, filming it around the country,
a really good production team.
And the stories are fantastic.
It's basically looking at, I guess I'm
talking about it, I'm not supposed to,
but w we're looking at, um, uh,
military government organizations that
are typically in the shadows, right?
We're not releasing any
sources and methods.
We're not disclosing classified secrets,
but we're talking about elements
and units, operational activity, um,
events that, uh,
before now I've pretty much been in
the shadows and some incredible people.
That's one of the best parts about this
thing that's been going out there and
meet some of these guys that are doing
some of this high-speed shit. And it's,
it's pretty amazing. And when, when
they do release things like long,
long after, like I was reading something,
uh, I forget what the case was about,
but it was something about how the,
the files won't be released under the
freedom of Information Act until 2080.
Well, how do you, yeah, I know. What are
they, how do they make that decision?
Like that was the thing with the
Kennedy assassination, right?
And sometimes they roll it over
and it's not even then. Right?
So sometimes they extend that,
um, other times they don't.
And so some information comes
to light periodically. Um,
and so this does look at this, this
show we'll be looking at some historic,
but a lot of current things that are
going on and, and where the money goes,
right.
What are we spending on money on when
it comes to this high speed operations
that the special forces and others
are involved in? Um, so it'll be,
it'll be very good. I was, I was lucky
to be able to work with again, you know,
some really great people
on the production side,
but just also going out there and meeting
some of these cats. They're just, the,
the, the shit that they do is, is,
it's even after being around a while,
cause I have, um, it just amazes me. Well,
it's gotta be constantly
accelerating too. Right? There's,
they're constantly coming up with new
and spectacular things that nobody knows
about until they employ
them. Right, exactly.
And sometimes that shit stays on the
shelf. Right. You know, it was like the,
the running joke at the agency
at the, at the CIA was, you know,
we have a fantastic s and t group,
a science and technology group and
another one's responsible like cue from,
from bond, right. They're
the ones responsible for
developing all the gear, uh,
responding to specific
operational requirements.
How are we going to do
this particular thing?
Well it's develop a piece of kit
that's going to allow us to do it. Um,
but the running joke is
always that, you know,
they'll develop it and they'll
show it to you before an operation,
but then they'll put it back on the
shelf cause they don't want that shit
getting out there. Right. And people
finding out that they've got it.
So they'll give you like a,
a 20 year old piece of kit to use instead
and you'll be walking around with like
a phone the size of a brick. Um,
knowing that they've got
something high speed on the shelf.
Well that's what everybody always thinks.
Like when you talk to the average Joe
on the street about technology and the
government,
there was like dudes and stuff they have
that they probably don't tell us about
how much of that is real. Yeah.
Um, it's, it's pretty real.
Have you seen some stuff that made you
go, Holy Shit, yes. You can do that. Yes.
Really? Yeah. And how much
can you tell us? Um, well,
you know what one thing that
they're doing and, and there's, I,
this is actually something I wanted
to talk about today because it's gonna
affect everybody.
It's not just something that is going
to affect people in the military or else
in the intelligence community,
but one of the things that they've been
working on is imagine you've got gotta,
you've got to rock up on it
on a target and your butt,
your before you do that before you,
you get the customers on site
and you're gonna, you know,
hopefully obtain some high value,
uh, targets there at that location.
Before you do that, you gotta, you gotta
can euphemisms, Oh, I'm sorry. Before,
before you can go in there, loteria
listen to another dimension.
But sometimes you know, you're okay.
Actually I was going to say sometimes
you want to actually capture them and get
their intelligence. We've
gotten past that, right?
Because the years where we were getting
our ass kicked for holding onto people
in, in detention facilities,
um, you know what that did that,
that pretty much convinced everybody
that was involved in this to just just
whack them. Right? Because then you
don't have to deal with the aftermath.
You don't have to worry about, oh,
you're going to get in
trouble for interrogating
somebody. Right. Exactly. So,
so that actually increasingly
[inaudible] of operations,
you started painting targets and just
blowing the shit out of there rather than
trying to grab the target
and get their intel.
That's a problem because in the pipeline
dries up for the Intel. But anyway,
so imagine you've got
this, you got this site,
the first thing you gotta do is
determine if your target's there. Right.
Then it's not like that. You know,
the Tom Clancy movies where you're
looking through walls and all this shit.
It's it, you know, that that technology
night vision devices and, and,
and that ability and low
light conditions to, uh,
to monitor and do identify
specific individuals, um,
has always been a problem.
They've made great strides on
it to the point now where in no
light conditions, right, with the,
with the right stack database,
with the right information and that
database meaning the right amount of,
of information about individuals, right?
You just constantly populating this
database with new faces or with new
photographs of individuals
that you're going after, um,
with enough of that to sift through.
They're getting to the point now with
no light conditions that they can, uh,
identify positively the targets in that
room are the targets in that facility or
in that building, whatever it might
be. And that's pretty incredible.
I'd rather they can identify people
by their heart rate [inaudible]
with w well not just their heart. Right.
But I mean other, other bio-data right.
I mean other than other,
but they can literally with
video somehow or another,
they can zoom in on you with some
scanner and recognize that this is a
particular individual because
of their heart rate. This is,
there was an article that was written
about it and I know that there's a
company, do you know what
Hex is? Hecs. It's um,
it's a company that's been used, uh,
pretty extensively by
scuba diving community. Um,
and now, uh,
by the hunting community as well because
it blocks the electrical signal hecs.
It blocks the electrical signal
that your body gives off. Okay. Yup.
That makes sense.
And I think they're doing work with the
military as well to develop suits that
will somehow know another stop someone
from being able to recognize your
particular heart rate.
Right. And it does a lot of work on,
on what they call this sort of the
universe and their goals. Here.
Pentagon is a lady that I can
identify people from a distance,
other heartbeat. Yeah. It helps. It helps
if you have other data points. Right.
If you had, but um, this is all part
of it to some degree. What, you know,
they refer to as a universal
soldier, right? They, the,
the fighter of tomorrow and [inaudible].
Yeah, but they got shit. That's right.
Who doesn't remember [inaudible]
although he's all in with grin.
He's doing like chip commercials now.
I'm sure you haven't seen him at
[inaudible]. He knows or whatever. Dude,
70th trill. The splits. Yeah. Well ops,
I don't know when that becomes useful
though. Really the splits, I mean,
I've never actually felt that
that was something I need to do,
accomplish in any given moment from an
operational [inaudible] movies where you
have to do this. It's still
very important. But so the,
the universal soldier thing
where you, you, you, your,
you know, it's an
Exoskeleton, it's a soft suit.
It's all the data that you can
acquire for that war fighter.
How do you create the perfect environment
on that individual as he's moving
through an environment to, to, you
know, be a more efficient, effective,
lethal fighter and you know, things
like that. Identifying target,
whether it's with a laser,
whether it's with low light or no
light conditions where you can,
as you're rocking up on the target,
you can do all these things, you know,
the ability to, to carry more gear,
right? Hump it, another extra, you know,
10 kilometers, whatever
it might be. Uh, it's, it's pretty
incredible what they're doing and it's,
it's a joint. It's not just the military.
They're working with, uh, you know,
companies like hacks or they're working
with the, with the commercial sector,
um, and academics too. But anyway, and
I disappeared down a rabbit hole. Uh,
the, these like the, the idea of
like this universal soldier thing.
Have you been paying attention to this
Elon Musk neurolink thing that he's
coming out with,
whether they're going to somehow or
another insert fibers into your brain and
then have a Bluetooth enabled device that
you wear that's going to allow you to
somehow or another interface with
data at a much higher bandwidth?
I don't know what the fuck any
of those words mean. I just said,
but that was good though. That was
good. It sounded like you understood it.
That's my trick. So yeah, I,
you know, that comes up point.
Um, if you're talking
about, I mean that's,
that's going into a different area
that's going into civilian applications.
And by the way, the military
application would be great for that too.
Everyone could synchronize data. You
could give them navigation in their head.
Like if there's some sort
of augmented reality,
we could literally see the
targets in front of you.
Like if you had a map, say like the,
if the Pentagon really does have this
laser beam that could identify specific
individuals and you have a map of a
building that's in your head and they can
identify the very location,
absolute perfect location of each
individual person in that room.
And you could see that as you're
running into this building,
you're seeing like a three d grid in
front of you and you know, I mean,
you could shoot them right through
a fucking wall, right? And there's,
but there's, there, there does become a
problem, then that becomes a problem of,
of information overload. And when
you get into that situation, right,
everything starts to close
down a little bit. Right? And,
and so you've got to start
pushing some of that away.
And now what you end up doing is
you get the offsite, you know,
command center a relaying some
of that information as needed.
But that guy that's about to,
to breach that door, you know,
he doesn't want a lot of data points
anymore. Now having said that,
knowing where, you know,
knowing where the hostiles are
and the other side of that door,
that is key information, that's
not rocket science but so there,
but there's a lot that's going on.
It's also the ability to monitor the
health of the individual. You know,
soldiers are out there,
uh, through the, the,
the gear that they would then be wearing.
Um, it's an, it's an incredible, uh,
effort that has been going on
and, and so to answer your point,
long rambling answer, uh, yeah, I've
seen some things that are pretty amazing.
You can't talk about it
though. No, no. Some of this,
some of the shit actually we'll,
we'll get into with the new show
that's coming up sometime in fall.
I don't have a really state, and again,
I'm prescribed from talking about,
so I won't do that because
some I pay attention.
Some of the things that you saw
you'll be able to talk about. Yes.
So how does the government do that?
They just decide, well listen,
it's not a bad thing if you tell
people about this something,
I'll give you this. Right? Well, I
think this, there's an element of,
some of it's not what you
would refer to as classified.
It's just not readily available public
information and it's not out there in
the, because people aren't
aware of it or searching for it. Um,
some of it does. I think you're right.
Some of it is, look, the
military wants to say at times,
look what we're able to
do or we're doing this.
And oftentimes it's because it's
in a sort of a private public
cooperation and, and so
that encourages other, uh,
companies with innovative
technologies to step forward and,
and get involved in some of this. Um,
and I guess that opens up
all sorts of other, you know,
some people are out there saying,
well they shouldn't be working
and with the military.
Well you know, fuck,
well that's a question that I had the,
this brings me to a point that I think
is kind of important where people always
talk about the military budget and how
high the military budget is and you know,
we need to take some of that money and
put it in other places. And you know,
maybe some of that military money is
not being used to the best for the best
good of the human race or
maybe maybe some of it.
But in order to be able to develop stuff
that keeps people safer in order to
develop all this stuff that you're talking
about that could potentially save the
lives of soldiers and even
innocent civilians because
you're going to be able to
target the correct people. Like all
this stuff seems pretty critical. Right,
right. And it's also,
there is a, you know,
there's an upside if you want to get
more listic about the whole thing to
developing advanced technologies,
you can be more surgical, right?
[inaudible] the drone capability
as an example gives you a,
a much better understanding
of your target. You can
avoid the collateral damage,
you know, the deaths of
civilians on site, um,
through the use of proper technology.
And that creates that environment.
And so it's a good thing.
And, and again, I mean, CIA,
their s and t group over the years,
the shit that they've developed
for operational purposes
that then made its way
into the commercial sector and planet
fitted people. What battery technology,
anybody walking around with a
pacemaker or defibrillator, you know,
in part can thank the the agency
because what were they doing? They were,
they were working, they continue
to work on, on battery technology,
shrinking those batteries
as a power source.
What initially operational purposes.
So you could, uh, you know, uh,
it put a transmitter out some site,
you know, and, and, um, you know,
so what are you doing?
You're eavesdropping on a,
on a hostile target or you know,
gathering intelligence, but then that,
that effort,
all that work that was done then that
later on benefits the general public drone
technology. Same thing, right?
I mean the agency was front and
center on developing drone capability.
Now what are you doing? You're
doing that to, to, you know,
for environmental concerns? Um,
you know, for mining, uh, it's,
I'm a little concerned
about drone technology.
My old house that I used to live at this
motherfucker that lived down the street
from ace to hover a drone
over my house and film.
He like f like I know he's
like looking at me like,
what are you doing to ask me
swimming? You fucking Weirdo.
Did you ever go over and
talk to him? No. Ah, no.
Should've sent a drone over his house.
Yeah, I was thinking of shooting it down.
But it's hard to aim up. No,
you can now update the bow and Arrow.
I know that'd be a hell of a shot.
You have a good boat. Like, see, the way,
the way you calculate accuracy
with archery is you have
a range finder and that
range finder has a built in adjustments
for angle this angle compensation for up
or for down. But I don't know if it has
it for straight up in the air. Like,
cause you got to think the way you,
you're judging how much an arrow is going
to drop over the course of the flight.
Right, right, right. The same as the
bottles too. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Right.
But with a bullet, obviously it's less
compensation because it's much faster.
But, um, there's a video that's
hilarious of this guy, uh,
got tired of this block party in Brazil,
so he loaded up a drone
filled with fireworks and uh,
he hovered it over the block party and
started launching bottle rockets down on
these guys that are, uh, make it too
much noise. That's excellent though.
I mean, if you think, but that sounds
like something one of my boys would do.
And then I'm sure there'll be listening
to this at some point. So they, um,
did they tell you're going
to do this? Yes. Scooter.
Sluggo and Mugsy but it's when you have
a kid named sluggo or Mugsy or scooter
guaranteed, they're gonna do, they're
gonna do something like that. Yeah. Yeah.
[inaudible] when you're naming your kids,
I didn't know, it didn't occur to me.
It didn't occur to me, although I
wanted to get Eugene or something.
I wanted Eugene, Eugene, I wanted
to give him flattops. Right.
Every summer I want to have the
same discussion with, with, uh,
with my wife who's the
world's greatest person. Uh,
I wanted to give them a flat tops
and she always says, look, uh,
with names like scooter slug and Mugsy,
you give them a flat top as well,
then that's it. You a database. Exactly.
They're going somewhere. But, uh,
it's, you know, the best way to
take down a drone, uh, is, uh,
is just blanketed jam it and
drop it up well yet it's like a,
you know, it's like the old days of
jamming a radio signal basically. Right.
When you're, you're interrupting,
you're blanketing it and
you're interrupting the, the,
the data communication from the
controller to the drone. And, um,
like the drone that was taken down in
the Iranian drone that we took down,
I think you'll see USS boxer was involved
in that out there in the, uh, the,
the street. That's how they do it. They
don't fire a missile at it anymore,
you know, it's just,
it's much more effective.
Something on it that disrupts the
signal. Right. Yeah. It's just a,
it's essentially again, and not
to oversimplify, just jamming,
but is that jamming technology
available to civilians?
Um, to really, really smart civilians?
I guess it could. It could be. Yeah.
Really smart civilians would probably
be able to figure that stuff out. Jamie,
you know anybody that's work on that,
I'm looking to find some real, Jamie,
can you meet? Uh, so, uh, yeah.
Scooter to technology scooters
just out at a west point. Uh,
he wants to go to west point when he's,
when he's old enough and so he went out
there for a lacrosse program and I'd
forgotten. Have you been to west point?
No. You got, you got to go at some it's,
I know it's a ways away from here.
It's not a day trip, but it's this,
it's a beautiful campus
and forgotten about that.
Obviously it's got to cause that where
Jody foster wills and sounds of the limbs
and west point, it doesn't
sound right. I don't think so.
The drone kill gun.
Wow. That's crazy. Three
[inaudible] lightweight compact drone
counter-measure drone gun, 3000.
Jamie ordered me one of those
immediately. Yeah. Amazon please. Yeah.
That would have taken, that would
have taken care of this guy. Um, yeah,
but the problem is it's not as
satisfying as a bow and arrow. Yes.
That's a good point. That's
a good point. Uh, so, uh,
one of the things I wanted, I didn't
know how it's not as smooth segue,
but we were talking a bit about
technology technology, um,
is particularly with a 2020 election
coming up is this idea of deep fakes.
Yes. Fantastic stuff. Um,
and the technology to create this
nowadays to create a deep fake up,
which essentially just means
you're doctoring a photo
or video and making it do
what you want it to do to try to
convince people of whatever it is. Um,
technology is, is, is advancing
and it's stunning what can be done.
Kyle Dunnigan is Kyle
Dunnigan. I should know,
I should know hilarious standup comedian,
but he shines in doing deep fakes
and he's working with this other guy.
I think the guy's called Dr
Fagan's. Time for the faking. Yeah.
Two separate guys. But yeah, one of
those guys. But go to go to his, uh,
Instagram and see the new one that he
did with the Elon Musk. He was doing,
I'm really kind of crudely with like face
with, you know, um, face swap or face,
that's like a little filter that you get
from snapchat or something like that or
Instagram.
But now he's moved from that to
doing this really high end stuff.
Go to the Elan Musk one. Look at this,
play this vacancy into this. Yeah. Okay.
Uh, I just [inaudible] I Tessa labs,
which is pretty cool. It's pretty cool.
But, but, but we had a little snafu edit.
It looks like time is slowing down and
we'll eventually start going backwards at
an increasing rate.
So pretty soon you will become a baby
again and be sucked back into your
mother's vagina. Yeah.
Okay. Now pause.
Now go to another Kyle Donagen video so
he can tell what cow really looks like.
That's him to the right of that.
This is what he really looks like,
which is fucking madness. Yeah,
the guy's hilarious by the
way. He's awesome guy too.
And he's got a great Instagram page,
but his Instagram page is mostly him,
like the gold boom. So the gold
one was chip click on that.
Cause that's a normal one.
This is what he did with the
filters without doctor fake Stein.
Look at the seals of creepy face.
Yeah, yeah, but play that. So
Ellen did genesis sore ass a seems
friendly Blackson bud. But no,
don't get too close to her and
she'll bite your fucking head off.
Just ask the uh, Porsche Raptor
as he has. He has, he has,
he asks.
And that's really Yoda. Gotcha.
Railroad is always smoking. Yeah.
Although we gave it up, I, you remember,
but in the videos he's always
smoking the look. It's,
it's bad enough that it's
extra hilarious cause it's bad.
But the new one that he did with
Elon Musk is not bad. It's not bad.
But Caitlyn Jenner one go to the
Caitlin Jenner one on the far right.
That's fucking genius. Click on this one
carefully. Kylie. I have
shopping. Sherry has Chicago.
When you had your shared right here
is your go. I buried your old fasion,
a Pecha and Metairie by accident and I'm
sure, I'm just saying it's back. Yeah.
Yeah.
Okay. But those, those are my favorites.
He has the Kardashians, the elite.
That's the only way they talk.
They just say yum, yum. And then
he knows what they're saying.
Sort of like Groot in
guardians of the galaxy.
I don't know. I don't know
how I miss these things.
I clearly watching the wrong
shit on the Internet. Oh,
you're a former CIA
guy. I should know this.
The important thing is I don't have
time for college. Okay, well but this,
but what you just showed, I mean,
people look at that and I go, okay,
but you're right. The Ilan Mustang is
getting closer to creepy that Bobby,
a real guy. But you could have someone
like that say, give me $1 million or oh,
bull your house up or just come on. Yeah.
And imagine if he gave, um, you know,
some off the cuff, um, financial data on,
on Tesla now talks about it as if,
as if he'd just come out of a shareholder
call and now he was releasing some
information. Let me think
about what that means to the,
all of a sudden the stock price of, of a
company, if that, if that happens. But,
um, the quality is,
is so far beyond even that
now that we can be done by,
and we're talking mostly state
actors like, like Russia.
And so the problem we're facing now is
it's not just everybody's kind of kind of
aware of, you know, the, the sort
of, the tweet averse or whatever,
the Twitter and, um,
the trolls that exist on there and the
bots and all of that. But it's the video,
the ability to do the
video they released. One,
one was done not too long ago
with Nancy Pelosi. And it,
all it did was slow down
her speech just slightly,
but just enough to make it sound
as if she was slurring her words.
Maybe she'd had a couple of drinks and
that thing was blasted all over social
media and people to this day still think
and they still talk about it. Like,
you know, she's kind of losing it a
little bit and right. And that like,
or more by the way, if she did that, yeah,
I think she might make
a little more sense.
Get a little lightened up lady worth
$100 million and no one knows why you
should have be out there partying. I'm
sure it was all, oh, so legit. Yeah.
She earned that $100 million. Sure.
There's definitely no
shenanigans, no shenanigans, no,
there's nothing like that happening up
on Capitol Hill. Um, but it's, so this,
this is a, it's something
that people should watch.
It's something that people should,
you know, read up on a little bit,
look at it,
because the technology is advancing so
quickly that the effort to combat it,
the effort would detect it.
And there's some companies out there and
certainly the, the, the government is,
is working to do that. DARPA
and some others are working,
but the effort to try to
identify doctored videos,
right, and particularly when you're
talking about elections campaigns, um,
is, is it's going to be a,
an increasing problem that
we're not really discussing
that much and congress is
paying a little bit of attention
to it right now. Um, but it's, uh,
it's really problematic and
there's, there's things that,
that you used to be
able to look for, right?
Lighting and noise and just sort
of the movements of the face, uh,
what they call micro heartbeats and,
and all the little things is the,
is the subject in the video
blinking for instance,
when your doctor at sometimes they'd the
blinking wouldn't be there and that was
a tell. But the, the people
involved in all of this,
in creating these deep fakes
are working, um, you know,
at such a pace that they're getting
ahead of that. So, uh, it's, I mean,
it's fascinating anyway, they're coming
up with ways to try to counter it.
But I guess the, the biggest point is,
it sounds like a public
service announcement is
people need to be aware of it
and they need to be smart about
it. Of course they won't be,
everybody goes to the Internet and they,
they lose their minds and they believe
whatever it is that they read that agrees
with their opinion and there is no
bothering of checking, you know, uh,
whether anything is actually
legit anymore or not.
But if that would be my one piece of
advice going into 2020 starting now,
pay attention. Don't believe
anything you see until you prove it.
And that's part of the problem too, right?
If we stop believing anything we see.
But if I was a skeptical person, right,
if I was a conspiracy minded individual,
I'd say,
but you're not this guy who used to
work for the CIA is telling us not to
believe the news. Wait,
I see what you're saying.
What I'm saying is you
are setting us up. Okay,
well it's time for me to go look at that.
Wouldn't normal skeptical person want
to think like why is he danced? I guess?
I guess I'm saying I'm saying it wrong
cause you're right. I don't mean to say,
I don't mean to imply, I guess what
I'm saying is trust but verify,
right? When,
when when you're looking at a video of a
candidate or you're looking at anything
really on the Internet now just
be aware of the capabilities.
Maybe that's a better way of putting
all of this because you're right,
you don't want that part of the problem.
And one of the things
that Russia does and,
and others who are involved in
this whole propaganda effort, um,
one of the things they do want to do is
undermine our confidence obviously in
media. So, you know, by me saying
don't believe what you see,
I'm kind of feeding into that.
So you're right, I shouldn't,
I shouldn't go that route. Be
Aware of what the capabilities are,
pay attention.
Everybody should just be a little
bit smarter about what they're doing.
That's all I'm saying. So, and
also what we're looking at now,
it's so much more powerful than
what we had three or four years ago.
Three or four years ago, this technology
was not available for the consumer,
but now it is. Well, there was, I mean,
you think about it not to get too deep,
but if you think about the, the
photography, how long has photography been
around? There have been efforts to
manipulate photography, right? So the,
so altering photographs has been
around almost as long as the, the,
the medium itself. Um,
you go to a photo shop, um,
that kind of put it all in the
hands of the consumer, you know, um,
what you were talking about face swap,
uh, the new face app to age people.
Yeah. Um,
all these things make it easier for
whoever's got a smart phone to try to do
this. But what you really,
and that's a problem as well,
but one of the things that you really
have to worry about is against what are
the state actors like a Russia, I mean,
Russia was behind the faces
swamp thing. Well, yeah,
and that's a good first step, right?
There are Russian companies that are, uh,
pushing this technology out there. And
what are they doing every, you know,
every time you do that, it's recording
data about you. Well, not only that,
you have to give your name and your email,
right to get that application and then
they have a photo of your face that
correlates with your name and your email.
So what they've done is they've gathered
up more than 150 million emails and
faces and they have data
on people. Yeah, that is,
that's pretty powerful stuff. Like if
you think about what Facebook has done,
right?
What Facebook has made billions and
billions of dollars by essentially mining
data, right? That's what they're
about, right? Google's the same thing.
They're mining data. Well,
Russia managed to do that with
150 million people in a very,
very short amount of time just
by making something cute. Oh,
let's see what I look like.
What am I a hundred men now?
What do you think they're
doing with that data there?
They're slicing and dicing this, trying
to understand the American electorate,
right? They're going to,
they're not going to stop doing what
they did and they've been doing this
forever. We talked about this before,
they'd been doing this since 1940s. Right.
Busy trying to keep the US out of world
war two before they broke up with the
Nazis. It was as it was a serious breakup,
a, but when they were still aligned,
they were busy paying off journalists
and buying trade unions and all the rest
of it. So they're not,
they're never gonna stop what they do
because it's worked for them and it's just
kind of in their DNA. But isn't that
also what the United States does as well?
And there's gotta be some sort of
counter-intelligence stuff that we do
that is sort of shading. Shoot. Well,
I don't know about shade. Justifiably
shady. How about that? Gee,
I like that. Okay. That's a good
term. Yeah, of course there is.
And people always do that. [inaudible]
you know, when I, when I'm talking about,
if I, if I'm giving a talk about,
uh, uh, Chinese government, uh,
constant theft of
intellectual property, um,
somebody inevitably will
come up afterwards and they
will kind of roll their
eyes and go, well, we do it.
It's not like it's just them.
The U S is guilty of it too. What you
damn well better hope we are. Right.
Because if we backed off and said,
you know what, just you know,
for the sake of being
of righteous individual,
we're not gonna do any of this shit.
You would have to be with
willfully ignorant, naive,
or just fucking stupid to
think that Russia, China,
these other actors out there
are gonna stop also. Right.
And we're all gonna hold hands and
Unicorns going to flying out of our ass.
It's not gonna happen. So yeah,
I mean I guess the answer to that
is always the same, which is yeah,
better hope we do it and we've
been to hope we do it well. Yeah.
But people are nervous about that, right?
Like this is my point
about the military budget.
Like if you just cut the
military entirely, well,
we're all going to start speaking Chinese
because some shit's going to go down.
Like you can't just cut the military
budget. You just, you can't, I mean,
just cut it out. One. No, no military at
all. We're going to focus on ourselves.
Yeah, we'll got fucking luck
with that. That doesn't work.
So the question is like how much money
should you spend on the military?
How much money should you
spend on counter-intelligence?
How much money should
you spend on propaganda?
I mean there should be some money
spent on propaganda overseas, right?
Cause we're,
we're trying to manipulate them the
way they're trying to manipulate us.
The idea though is that where America
we're nice where the good guys,
we're doing it the right way supposedly.
Yeah. Well there is that right?
There is that and there's, and you know
what, honestly, I'll be honest with you,
I'd, I've always, you know, like
maybe I'm naive or whatever,
but that was always my thought process.
When we're out there in the operational
world and you think, you know what,
okay so doing this, but we're
doing it for the right reason.
And people laugh at that
or whatever. But you know,
this is my phone so I'll look at that,
see that flag dad long may a wave.
That's how I am.
I open up my phone to flag waves
that may have got a flag behind me.
I'm a hundred percent pro America.
I got, I opened up my phone,
we like to throw it. I got, I
got, I got nothing. I got nothing.
I got I over the phone too. Is that
some sort of like hack free? Yeah.
Phone from the 60s. This is
actually a windup. A phone.
It's a phone. Yeah, I do have a flip.
The government can't, oh, there you go.
Yeah. And you know what I've got,
I've got a collection of phones going all
the way back to the cinderblock phone.
Remember that one?
I bet you guys fantastic Saudi Arabian
numbers on them and shit letters.
I assumed everybody does, but yeah,
that I think do this is your phones that
like are like hack proof until you this
phones that you can't use? Well, yeah,
you certainly know that, you know,
from an operational perspective, um,
you know, phones are not a good idea.
Now the problem is they're ubiquitous
and everybody uses them and it, you know,
it's made life very easy and it's also
even made life a little bit less secure.
Obviously. I know a guy
that is a, let's just say,
done some very unusual journalism and, uh,
he still has a phone that you
can take the batteries out. Yes.
He said there's some places where you go
where they will not let you in the room
if you have a phone. And so the,
the work around is he has an older Samsung
phone where you can pop the back off
and remove the battery. And that's the
only way. Yeah. I mean, that's, um,
you know, I, I would still argue there's,
there's workarounds on that one, so.
Yeah. But, um, Eh, yeah. You
know, that's why when you,
when you go into a government facility,
you know, they go at a skiff, you know,
you got to leave your phones outside,
you know, the lead box. Right, right.
So you don't tell, you don't carry your
phones in, you know, unless you're,
what was her name that was
doing that and walking into, oh,
the fucking chick from the
apprentice. Yeah, that's Amarosa.
That's how hilarious is that by the way.
I know her. I did fear factor with her.
She was on Fairfax. She told me I was
drunk because I was making fun of her.
It's like you're drunk. I'm like, no, I'm
not. I'm just making fun of you. Yeah.
Why wouldn't you? But, but
she's, she's an unusual person.
The fact that she thought it was okay
to do what is a basically treasonous,
she was recording these conversations
inside the White House and then releasing
them to the press. How is she not
in jail? How does that work? Yeah.
I'm not quite sure. I didn't
quite understand how you,
how you get around that,
right? Because you've got
obligations, you signed paperwork,
you do all these things and say,
I'm going to do the right thing.
And if you run foul of that, then you're
supposed to suffer the consequences.
And occasionally it seems like people
aren't, uh, want to know what I think,
what, I think she saw some shit and they
pulled her aside and they said, listen,
I'm real,
so I know that you're some sort of a
social climb or whatever you're trying to
do here. And listen what you did.
We'll literally get you locked in
jail for the rest of your life.
So how bout this?
How about you just shut your pie
hole and we'll just let this slide.
Yeah. I don't know that she's,
I don't think anybody would,
I mean from a county intelligence
perspective and she'd be one of the last
people you would trust to actually keep
her mouth shut up already period of
time. So I'm saying, um, yeah, that's,
that's a tough one. But that was,
that's it. That's also part of
the, the, the issue of, of of, uh,
leaks as an example, right? I mean,
the issue of choices that you make
for your cabinet as well. Right.
Well that's true. Yeah. [inaudible]
closed circle around you. And that's,
you know, again, you
can argue, I mean, we,
I don't want to get into
a political discussion.
Trump is an unusual character and you
know, they certainly, they, I know. Wow.
Wow. That's going to be
the, that'll be headlines.
How about that fellow that's from England
that looks like the divorce judge.
Yeah. The boy John Trump. I was
just there last week when, uh,
when he went over to Buckingham
Palace and, and you know, uh,
was asked by the queen to form the new
government and he accepted. And so,
you know, he's, he's an
interesting character.
He went to eat and he went
to Oxford. Um, he's, uh,
he's proven himself to be
extremely adept at getting, uh,
getting elected and most importantly,
he looks like Trump's baby brother.
Yeah. Yeah. You know
what? I suck is fucked up.
Like Trump's dad went over to England
and bang some waitress and, uh, Bam.
Next thing you know, look at
the two of them together. Oh,
get the fuck outta here.
This is mine. This is,
I got a buddy of mine sent me this one
that's a south park one. It's
him with a bike helmet on.
That's the best side by side. I've
seen so far better. This one's better.
Oh yeah. I mean,
it literally looks like a young Trump
cousin or a brother or something like
that, but he's promised, you
know, he's promised their,
they're out as far as Brexit goes by,
you know, Halloween by 31 October.
They're done. And they're done with
the whole European Union. Yeah.
Well that's what, that's
what they're saying.
And basically now what they're
concerned about, of course, is that
it's a, it's a hard, uh,
hard exit, right. No deal.
But he's saying it doesn't
matter. If that's the case,
then that's what we've got to do. And
there's a lot of people, it's, it's,
it's interesting, the dynamic is a
little bit like here in the u s right.
If you're in the northeast corridor and
Washington, New York, whatever, Boston,
or you're out here on the
west coast and you, you,
you tend to view the world
differently than everything else,
the rest of the mass
of the country. Right.
Which is why people lost their
minds and they thought, you know,
how could Trump possibly get elected?
The UK is a little bit like that,
that Brexit vote came around and everybody
in London was convinced that we're,
you know, it's gonna be 95%.
You know, we're not leaving.
And so when it came time and they'd
voted to leave in 2001, it was 16, uh,
the people in London lost their
minds. They couldn't believe it,
and they still to this day, uh, think
everybody else is just an idiot. Right?
So there's a similarity say, which is
I think why in part Trump, you know,
feels sort of that this kinship with
Boris Johnson. Um, but yeah, so he's,
Boris Johnson has said, but that's
it. We're out of here. You know,
maybe we can get a deal if we can't,
it doesn't matter. We're still leaving.
And it'll be interesting to see what
happens. But, uh, you know, he's not, uh,
he's not unpopular. Um, what's
the argument for them leaving?
What's the pro Brexit argument? Do
you really want to have your country,
your sovereign nation,
run by a bunch of faceless technocrats
living in Brussels who have really zero
interest in your sovereign nation.
Right? Uh, that's at the heart of it.
It's not an economic decision.
And people always make that,
that problem with Brexit, they always
say, well, from an economic perspective,
this is not a good thing. Well, the
deal at heart isn't an economic concern.
It's a, it's the issue of, of serenity.
It's the issue of being run
again by Brussels W W and, and,
and sort of the morass of, of
regulations that they've imposed. Um,
the inability for the UK to make
their own decisions about trade. Um,
and so there's a, you know, there,
there's a good argument in that regard.
Is it going to be a financial problem for
them? It's not going to be a disaster.
Like some people, you know, throw out
there and say, oh my God, this is gonna.
You know, the UK is going down the toilet
fast. That won't happen. But it'll be,
there'll be an upheaval if they, if
they, you know, leave without a deal,
but they'll adjust. Cause everybody, you
know, people want to do deals, right?
They want to do trade. It's
not like Germany and France,
which are the only two partners in
the EU that really matter. You know,
how dare you, I know I had, I can't
believe I just said that. What's the, um,
what's the, staying in the
European Union argument, um,
show everybody not racist at you.
Yeah. Global globalism, you know, it's,
we're all working together and isn't
this a wonderful thing and look at,
you know, all the benefits of it free
movement and you know, that free movement,
you know, didn't really
work that well from,
from France and Germany's
perspective, you know,
they don't like to talk about that anymore
for women is basically what we enjoy
in the United States
though, isn't it? I mean,
if you look at the United States
relative size in comparison to Europe,
we're basically commensurate, right? Yeah.
In terms of the contiguous United
States. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
And we all speak
the same language, but I'm talking about,
I'm talking about immigration policies.
I'm not talking about movement within
the EU. No, no, I understand. But I mean,
yeah, even in immigration, right?
Like the size of these countries in
comparison to the size of states,
like Texas is basically bigger than a
lot of fucking European nations, right?
Yeah. Yeah. It's, um, it is, um,
that arguments, what are
the immigration argument?
Much like some of the other arguments
that comes down from the UK is perspective
on don't tell us what to
do. Right. And you know,
maybe there's still an element of,
look, we, you know, we, we're an empire.
They control most of the planet for
awhile. You know, we'd like to, you know,
have a little bit more say in
what we're doing. So there,
there's an independent streak.
The problem is from [inaudible]
perspective is if they
do leave and it's not a
disaster, then other countries
are going to line up, right.
And Italy maybe would be the next one.
So it'll be interesting to
see what happens. But yeah.
Boggio as they call them.
Um, is an interesting cat, not unlike
our, our president in this country.
We don't pay attention to other countries.
So when we see that we see that guy,
like who is that guy? This new guy,
where did he come from? Is this real?
It's like a new character on a show
that you don't watch. Right, right.
You know what season that he come
in better call Saul season four.
Like who the fuck is that guy? The
new bad guy. Ah, I didn't watch, uh,
haven't been watching. I just
uh, I finished rewatching,
I do that instead of watching new shows.
I ended up re watching shows that I
really liked and I've watched before and
it's been a while. So I re watched the
first season of breaking bad again.
God damn good show. Holy Shit. That
was so well done. Yeah. And that,
just that first season,
if that's all people watch and they
haven't seen it before, it's so good.
But uh, yeah. And then I just,
I just binge watched the first
season of the sopranos again.
That's a great show. That was the
first show that really in my mind,
it created the first real anti-hero
that everybody actually appreciated on
television. Everybody loved Tony
Soprano. He's a fucking murderer,
constantly cheated on his wife,
strangled his best friend. He's like, oh,
I'd like them. Yeah. He's like,
he's an interesting cat. Yeah.
Well it was at dynamic with
his mother, right? That was,
that's what the hook was. And that
certainly that first season was just that,
that was fascinating to
people and still, you know,
still is speaking of deep fakes,
remember when they tried to bring
them on back after she died? No.
Liked the Shitty CGI. Yeah.
That's what shows you like in 2005
CGI was goddamn terrible. Well,
if you think about when
Photoshop, Photoshop was out
in what the early nineties,
I guess, late eighties,
early nineties, um,
you think about where we've come
since then, um, not to, not,
again, not to go back into the, sort of,
the, this whole thing with deep fakes,
but it is when people talk about, um,
Russia collusion and they talk about,
we kind of lost our way. Right.
And you know, everybody's
Kinda guilty of it,
whether it's Mueller and
his investigative team,
or whether it's congress or whether
it's just the general public.
We all kind of lost our way over the past
couple of years imagining somehow that
the big story here was, uh,
Trump's collusion, right? Well,
that was a political
dodge, right? That was a shell game
that was being played on us. It was,
the big story is what did
Russia specifically do? Right?
What exactly did they do? How did
they do it? How successful were they?
Show us some case studies
of, of specific examples.
That's what an investigative team
should have been doing for two years.
And then deliver that information and
keep throwing it out at the public and
keep talking to the public about it.
A guarantee of the, the GRU and, and,
and others, uh, the FSU at the, in, in
the Intel services in the, in Russia,
they're happy that we didn't
do that, right. Because again,
they've been in advancing, they've been
improving their, their capabilities.
They're gonna do it again. So I guess
that's why I keep beating on this as that.
I don't think we,
we really focused our attention to where
we needed to because we all get lost in
this political bullshit. And while I feel,
I feel like this is the most easily
manipulated we've ever been as a,
as a culture,
like I think it's so easy to spin these
narratives and to get people upset about
anything. Right. And there I th I feel
like a lot of these are test cases,
like they're trying to see like what
happens when we spin up this story? How,
how outrage do they get at that
story? We'll look at and look at this,
look at the issue of racism. You
know, look at, look at, I mean,
th that thing gets thrown out there now
to the point where it's, it's, you know,
yeah, I hate to say it, but it's, it's
almost losing its meaning in a sense.
Right? They just keep hammering
away anybody they disagree with.
And I'm talking about the, the, the
hard left. Progressive. You're a racist,
right? It's not possible that you
could possibly disagree on policy.
I like that. Whatever. That's a squad,
you know, AOC and her competitors.
I don't give a shit about,
you know, where they're from.
I care about the fact that their
policies from my perspective,
other people I'm sure love 'em, you know,
a screwed up and screwed up
about their policies. Well, um,
I'm not a democratic
socialist, right? So, um, I,
I have a problem with everything from,
you look at the, the green new deal,
right?
And this idea that we're gonna roll
this out and fuck the economic impact we
know or I know about the economic impact.
I think what they're doing is
they're just, they're playing to the,
they're a base and they're doing it
successfully and people hear about it and
everybody wants to be righteous.
Everybody wants to think, sure,
if I care about the environment,
let's get rid of emissions.
That'll be a great idea.
And whether it's that or open borders
and the idea that somehow we're,
you know, do I think we're running
concentration camps down south? No,
I don't think that that gets
fucked up that we would,
that's the terminology that we
would have, right. For detainments,
for detainment centers. And
you know what, you want to,
you want to make it
better, we'll great. Let's,
let's actually do what your job is.
Let's make some changes to the, to the,
to the, uh, immigration
rules and to, to asylum laws.
Let's put some more money down there, um,
and make conditions a little bit
better. There's things that we could,
in terms of concrete steps, but we
don't, we don't seem to want to do that.
We seem to want to just throw shit
around at each other. And, and I, and,
but the open border thing is,
is, is, uh, is, is worrisome.
There's a guy named John
Norris who was just on, um, uh,
my friend Steve Grinnell's podcast.
It's called the mediator podcast.
And he's a, a a warden.
He's a game warden.
And one of the things that they had to
deal with somewhere along the line was
they had to become enforcers
for illegal drug, uh,
drug marijuana growing, um,
these establishments in public
lands in national parks.
So these guys that were supposed to be
just catching people with too many trout
on the stringer are now being
forced to stop illegal grow ops.
And it's all cartel members.
And what he's saying is that 80 to 90%
of all of the marijuana that gets sold
illegally in this country, in the Midwest,
and all the different places where it's
illegal is coming out of these grow ups.
And a lot of it is tainted with dangerous
pesticides because these guys are
trying to,
they're actually using poisons to keep
animals from eating the marijuana.
But so these kids that are, or
whoever the fuck is buying it,
they're buying this pot from these illegal
places. No one's testing this stuff.
You don't know what the
fuck you're getting.
And you very well could be
smoking pot that's poisoning you.
Yeah. This, uh, a guy that I know, really
good guy, so he's a huge land owner,
uh, here in California, uh,
to the point where you can spend all day
on an ATV and, and still not, you know,
get to the end of one of his plots of
land. And I'd be call it a plot of land.
And anyway, he's had those, uh,
incidents, right. He's had where they,
it's such a massive piece
of property that, uh,
ate a small element from a cartel will
set up a gross spot there and you know,
they'll camouflage it. It's
very well done. Uh, they,
you bring in the piping for the water
cause it w pot uses a huge amount of
water. I was talking about
one that they brought in,
they had a pipe that went
for three miles. Yeah.
These kids carried it on their
back. Yeah. That's what they,
that's what these guys do. And
then, and then eventually, you know,
you got to go in there and busted up,
but it's people that stumble
across it that, you know, it,
they're just out there doing their
regular ranching job and it's, it's,
it is fascinating. I look, I, um, I
feel like we should take those guys,
reprogram them.
You get a guy who's willing to carry a
hundred pounds of piping on his back and
walk eight miles into the backwoods.
That's a fucking industrious individual.
You got to, you got to lure them away
from the cartel with a better deal. Yeah.
If that guy worked for a competing
corporation, he'd be like, look,
I like the way you do business.
Right. Give them a job
on the ranch. You know,
give him a check on this guy and he was
working for Verizon. They'd be like,
Hey, come on over here, man.
Put in the time these guys carry
on three miles of hose on his back.
That's work. That's what
we call [inaudible]. Yeah.
So you said you use your power for good,
not evil. That's what I tell my boys.
It's hard though because evil's fun.
I think it's a way within the short
term it could be more lucrative.
Yeah. From their
perspective, there is that.
And they have a record and probably
murderer reasons. All right,
so maybe we're not talking about somebody
you're going to hire as a landscape or
they're your home, but uh,
but your point is open board is not a
good idea and borders not a good idea.
It's a lot of bad people that are
getting in already. And it's not,
it's not a stretch.
This is not if anybody who imagined this
to be a stretcher or it's going to take
offense at this. Every
nation maintains borders.
Every nation maintain some element
of, of immigration controls and,
and borders, uh, protection. Um,
the idea that we shouldn't have,
that we should somehow feel exceptionally
bad about it is I don't quite
understand that mentality. Uh,
we should feel bad when we see someone
who's just a poor mother who's trying to
come over to America to get a better job
cause she's stuck in Guatemala and it
sucks over there and there's
no opportunity whatsoever
for her to excel, right?
That's a different animal than
someone who is a, a member of a,
some fucking terrible
cartel gang that comes over.
The question is how do we differentiate
and how do we make it so that that woman
who's a mom can come over here, right?
How do we make it so it's legal?
That's the real question.
And that's when I wish that,
but that's not what they're
addressing, right? Well,
how many decades now have we, you know,
heard about immigration controls and
immigration process and regulations and
policy and then nothing ever
gets done. And so maybe,
and again, I think one of the things
that's interesting about Trump, um,
is as, as strange as as
it is the environment.
I mean maybe the fact
that he is disruptive and
sometimes it doesn't seem to
give a shit.
Maybe that's a good thing because it
gets us talking and gets us talking in
areas that we haven't before and
in ways that we haven't before.
So maybe that results in something,
maybe like the Chinese, Eh,
the public's just going to wait for
him to go and then we'll get back to
business as usual. That may
happen in business as usual.
The concern is like if it,
how do you differentiate between someone
who's coming in illegally because they
want a better life versus someone who's
coming in illegally because they're
literally going to commit murder and
sell fentanyl and deal, you know,
incredible harm to whatever
community they wind up in.
And they were a member of ms 13 and
they're going to hear there's both things
that are going on at the same time and
you're a heartless person if you don't
want that lady with a child from Guatemala
to come over here and do better and
she's probably gonna work as hard,
if not harder than any good old fashioned
red blooded American that's over here
trying to make their way through this
world and why should we be able to have
this opportunity when they can? Yeah. One
of the beautiful things about America,
right,
is that like if you're a poor person
and you live in Baltimore or you can get
your shit together and get out and you
can move to maybe silicon valley or you
can move somewhere where
there's more prosperity,
there's more opportunity and you can
get some other poor people in Baltimore.
I heard there are, okay, I heard
there's, I'm going to pay attention.
Some sort of a, there's a word, what
does the word he used? Infestation.
Infestation of rat infestation.
You can't use infestation when you're
talking about certain neighborhoods.
People get mad, even
though he said infested
with crime and rats, you
still, you're racist.
It doesn't matter. The,
the, the, the key here is,
and it's a democratic talking
point, right? I mean this is the,
this is a strategy and that's fine.
Both parties used different strategies,
you know, but the,
the Dems have obviously decided in this
period of time because it's so intense.
There was clearly discussions within
wherever the DNC or elsewhere that this is
our policy. We are going
to push this and we just,
you just keep hammering that word,
racist, racist, racist, no matter what.
And it's gonna stick. And it
does because you just, you,
you get hit by that hammer and you
kinda, you're staring into the light,
you don't know how to respond.
Right? So, and you think, oh my God,
I'm not a racist. But then,
you know, you're like, senator,
you're still beating your wife. And so
it's, it's one of those things you can't,
you can't answer. Um,
but I think it's bullshit because it's
like calling everybody a Nazi. It's,
you know, it loses its, its importance
and its meaning. And, and you know,
um, anyway, it's, it's a strange, strange
time, but I, I think you can do both.
You can, you can take care of that,
that woman with the kid or kids and,
and you can also, um, you know, look
at the issue of border security,
right? And enhance your ability to
understand who's coming across the border.
It costs money and it, and it requires
effort, but you can do, you can do both.
I don't think you can do
both, but the, I think the real
big picture, the real big picture,
like if you had to look at
the solution objectively,
the real problem is Mexico has like real
economic situations that we don't have
here in America. They're it, they're
far worse off than a lot of the areas.
And as is Guatemala, as is
the neighbor, El Salvador,
neighboring countries are economically
devastated until they are not until they
come up and until they
experience prosperity.
You're always going to have people that
are committing crime because they're
wanting to try to get by.
And you're always going to have people
that didn't want to gonna want to try to
get to America because it's a place
where there's more opportunity.
That's the real issue. The real issue
is that it's so much better over.
Right. And that's, and that makes sense.
And you get the same thing with
immigration and movement of, of, uh,
of people over in Europe coming up from,
from wherever, which is the mascot,
which is the Brexit
argument in part. I mean,
it's not just based on immigration, but
it's more control of your own nation's,
uh, security and destiny, et
cetera. But I think that that's,
you could argue that national security,
um, from a US perspective, uh,
would warrant, um,
improving your ability to impact
nations like Wa Tamala, El Salvador,
uh, wherever, uh,
and working with Mexico to not
just improve sort of the security,
the liaison that goes on and improving
that. But you're right, I mean,
working conditions, uh, criminal, you
know, uh, or crime and, and instability.
Um, that's in our national security
panel. People get, you know,
they get very upset. I said, why
should we give countries money? Right?
Well in part, you're right. I mean,
sometimes you give them money and it
just goes down some shit hole and it
doesn't, you know, and I don't mean to
tell, I'm not talking about the country,
I'm just talking literally it goes
into a hole and it never goes back.
It's in corruption and they, it, and at
the highest levels of government. Yeah.
So there's no, there's no controls over
how that money is spent. This note,
there's no metrics to say whether it's
spent wisely at the end of the day.
So you can [inaudible] but I would
argue that, yeah, I agree. I mean,
it's in our national security interest
when we're talking about, um, uh,
border security immigration to view
that as sort of the top line issue.
Why are they, why are they on the
move? Right. Well, like you said,
they're on the move because they want a
better life because where they're at and
good. Yes. How do you work with
them? And that's, you know, that's,
I think people sometimes
look at that and think, well,
that's pushing a rock up a hill.
It's never going to happen.
And so maybe they just
stop. Right. But, um,
we've ignored Latin America, Central
America, South America for decades. Right.
Which is how we ended up in part with,
with Chavez and Maduro have to follow.
And, and some of the Horse Shit that
went on down there, uh, because we,
we ignored it. We didn't
give it to resources. We
didn't give it the attention.
We didn't treat it seriously
as a national security concern.
We were all focused on wherever,
improving relations in Southeast
Asia or elsewhere. So, yeah,
we need to refocus. And I think
ultimately, do we see it immediately? No,
but I think you're so
anyway, it's, you know,
I think for people that are really
like a foreign policy, it is. Yeah.
With at least one dude who doesn't
know Jack Shit about foreign policy.
That would be me. That'd be a good
show though. But I, yeah, maybe, but I,
I really think in the
interest of national security,
legalizing marijuana federally would
stop the profitability of these gang
members because you'd be
able to have legal marijuana,
you wouldn't have to be able to,
you wouldn't need to buy
it in these other places.
You'd be able to grow it yourself and
the price would drop through the fucking
floor and it would be not profitable for
these guys to haul three miles of pipe
on their back and into the back country
and use someone else's land to make
these grow ops. And one of the
reasons why they're doing this,
particularly in California, I found out,
is that when marijuana
became legal in California,
these illegal grow ops became a
misdemeanor rather than a felony. So they,
they do them over here instead of doing
it in Ohio or somewhere else where it's
illegal. They do. And also, you know,
you could basically grow year round here.
I was going to say from a
logistical point of view,
if they'd just made it legal federally,
this cut the shit. We're all grownups.
Yeah.
Yeah. And there's a tremendous number
of issues related to the fact that,
you know, the state and the
federal laws don't match up. Right.
And from a law enforcement perspective,
it's a nightmare in a sense. Yeah.
So nightmare. Yeah, I agree. You know
what, I, I know what will happen is,
I don't imagine that
the, it makes the, uh,
cartel activity any different that sucking
sound that that is the revenues from,
uh, from weed leaving
their, their accounts
[inaudible] will be replaced by
something else. Who for sure.
Whether it's get into the weed business
or admit. Yeah. Well, yeah, I mean,
although these pharmaceutical companies
that are fighting against it as well as
these prison guard unions, which is really
crazy, that's the darkest one to me.
It's like the pharmaceutical
companies, look, I get it.
They're just creeps that are looking at
their bottom line that every business
wants to constantly have new growth
every year. They want to constantly
be making more money. I get it.
It's like this universal eternal
growth model that they operate under,
but the prison guard unions,
when you find out that they lobby against
the legalization of marijuana is so
insane. What to settle. I didn't know.
They just want more people in
jail so that they have jobs.
That's the idea behind it. It's, it's
the most un-american thing possible.
You want more people in jail so that
you could have a job looking over those
people. You basically, it's,
it's sickening. Yeah. That's a,
that's a new one to me. I had, I had
no idea. The, the guard unions. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. [inaudible] prisons in a
nutshell are called fucking crabs. Yeah.
Private prisons. Is, is something that,
you know, and there have been, I mean,
again, I'm, I'm with this current
administration, you know, there's,
there's been some prison reform issues
that have been making their way through.
Right. They've been actually
focused on it to some degree.
Maybe thanks to Kim Kardashian.
She said she's just looking at
fucking champion. She's a champion of,
of people that are wrongly
incarcerated. She really is.
I want to show you something. I'm like,
shout out to Kim K. I'm like one of the,
and I'm like, you crazy. A crazy grandpa
that clips newspaper articles out. Um,
but in preparation for the show,
I know most people think I did no
preparation whatsoever. I know those guys.
I still do to the newspaper. I do
as well. Look, you look at this,
college has offered degree in courses in
the pot business. Oh, good move. Yeah.
Yeah. So this is pop to now. Did you
know that podcast is a teaching podcast?
Have two people that have gone back
to school for that, for product,
not enough for pot. Pot. Yeah. It's
crazy. University of Maryland and Cornell,
that's the two that this
article talks about. Uh,
well the biggest sponsorship that the
UFC has ever gotten ever is this Aurora
company in Canada that grows
weed, CBD and marijuana.
They have football fields
fill with weed and you know,
the highest possible standards,
the best quality, no pesticides,
herbicides, no bullshit.
Yeah, super pure. And the CBD,
which is fantastic for
everybody's health. And I just,
I'm back when I first
started working for the UFC,
they were people that
worked for the organization,
organizations that didn't like it,
that I smoked pot. They were like,
why is he smoking? What's he doing?
It's going to sound pod company. Well,
I mean, that's it. I will tell you
this as a apropos of nothing. I got,
I've gotten calls,
a couple of calls from people
in the industry who was saying,
and the only reason they're
calling me is they're saying,
can you hook hook me up with Joe is
like, we hang out together all the time.
Of course. Right. Because we're always,
we're always hanging out in
the pool together. Uh, Joe
and I, but so I said, no,
look, dude, that's not my, that's not my
job. They want where they want from me.
Um, you know what?
I think they just want to pitch you on
business and bring some spokes in here.
Fucking case. That joint.
That's the one I do know that
people in the potty business.
People in the pot business. Yeah.
Yeah. Amen. See, I got the SCIA calls.
Great words. Yes. Spooks.
We gotta be careful using that word
though cause people think you're racist.
That was a racist term in the
70s. Well we did a black folks.
I worked on a show for in the UK,
uh, an espionage drama show that ran,
ran for eight or nine seasons and it was
called in the UK. It was called spooks.
It was about, uh, their, uh, Intel
operation and it ran for a long time,
but then they sold,
they brought it over here to the
states and I think it was on an awesome
channel. And um, but they had to change
the name. They changed to [inaudible],
which is the name for the domestic
security service because they were worried
about the term exactly. Spooks. It's
always been around. I mean it's,
it's always been around the ideas that
the sneaky people that are doing creepy
shit. There was no,
there is no creepy shit being
done. You see what I mean?
I'm here to tell you right now,
and you can write this down.
I'm going to write it down, right.
There is no, no creepy shit going on.
What's going on with a,
a ram caught a bunch of people that they
are claiming our CIA performance and
they may execute them. Yeah, yeah. They've
done this before. They've made this
before. Um, and look, Iran is a, hey the,
a couple of parts of this, um,
that's one of the heaviest lifts in the
business has been intel collection on
Iran over the years. I'm not
talking about just recently,
but over the years it's been,
it's been very difficult. Um,
they are extremely buttoned up
over there and they have, uh,
an incredible level of control over
their population, uh, and that, which is,
you know, at some point
you would think, well,
maybe the population is going
to object to this, but you know,
it hasn't happened yet. Um,
so part of it is they
came out with this, uh,
I think 17 individuals that they claim
were cooperating with the CIA in some
fashion or another, and they, you know,
they claimed that they were
fairly high level individuals. Um,
I have a, uh, I don't believe anything
that comes out of their mouths.
I don't believe that at all. I
think they've, they've got a long,
long track record of, of lying about
a variety of things. And so, you know,
why would they come out
with this? Um, you know,
perhaps they're cracking down and
it, it doesn't hurt to come out.
And if you're going after some of these
individuals anyway, why not put them,
put the paintbrush on them that they're
working for the CIA and that will
appease some of the population
there. Um, so, I dunno, I'm, again,
I'm not buying it. Um,
it has been a difficult intel task
and collecting intelligence on,
on their efforts with, uh,
with their ballistic missiles,
their nuke program as well, uh, has
always been as always been problematic.
But again,
they've done this before where they've
talked about how we've wrapped up a CIA
spying network and it's, it's kind of
horse shit. It has their propaganda.
I though, well, yeah, I mean,
you know, uh, yeah, I that,
that would be my take on it. I
don't know what I mean, I'm not,
I'm not internal. I'm not inside. And
so, you know, is it possible? Sure.
We've had, uh, we've had networks wrapped
up before by other countries, Cuba,
the Cuban Intel service years ago. Right.
Which was completely built by the
Russians, by the way, by the old KGB.
They owned and operated the Cuban Intel
service for a long time. Still do.
Um, they at one point wrapped up
pretty much everybody we had on. Right.
Um, and, and elsewhere people did. We
have over there, um, I have three. Uh, no,
we, we had, uh, you know, I don't, I
don't remember the numbers, but it was,
it was a few. Yeah, let's just say it
was, it was, it was not good. And they,
they, they had done a
very good, it was from a,
from a counterintelligence perspective,
it was a pretty impressive effort.
So it's happened, uh,
Russia's, you know, uh,
done the same when we've
usually, when with Russia,
usually when we've got a trade or a mole,
you know, somebody like Robert Hanson,
um, uh, Jim Nicholson and Lee
Howard, the Americans. Oh yeah.
From what I understand, it's a good show.
And it was a show based on the idea
that at one point in time there was a
Russian family that had come over here
and infiltrated and became American
citizens and seem like, you know,
Joe and Mary next door. Right.
But really they were Russian spies. You
don't had an aunt and uncle named Joan.
Mary. It's weird that you would say that.
I literally had an uncle named Joe and
Mary Gunselman tell, telling you, buddy,
I'm trying to look at it and
it's time to go. Um, yeah, I,
uh, there was, you know, there was a
story, the reason that the Americans was,
was created was written as do a lot of
things do based on some smart writer who
sees an opportunity because he reads
a newspaper, um, years back, uh,
2011, I think it was, we had a, uh,
a sleeper herself that
we wrapped up in Jersey.
I remember there was there
just takes place. Right.
And there was that one that the hot one
remember? Um, oh, that's right. Yeah,
the hot, broad, the hot bang
and everybody got operation.
And so bring them over and then you
look at anything they had hat. Well,
I mean we could, I think she's a,
I forgetting what her name was.
A fat Danna soccer on your lawn
and she walks over store. Yeah.
Got High heels on. Yeah. She looks
literally nothing. But that's all.
Not so much. There's
something about her took a,
I know that there's some better knows.
Do you integration ever knows. Yeah, no,
she's hot. You don't think that
lady looks hot? Not there. No.
That's not a good picture. So you can
picture mugshot one, any makeup now.
That's true. That's all her up. Yeah.
Put a little tighter up p and
g blue eye line around her.
She'd be a chick catches you with a
couple of Jack Daniels and you've got
trouble. Okay. She walks across
when you're mowing the lawn.
So she and a bunch of other people
lived in Jersey, in the suburbs.
And their whole reason for being with
just a spot people, right? It was,
it wasn't, they were not, you know,
these were not the heads of the,
of the organization. Right. So their
job is spot. People live there,
be social meet people
that might be of interest.
Maybe it turns out that somebody in
the PTA where your kids go to school,
maybe somebody who's working for Raytheon
or they're working for some, you know,
interesting company. That's what
they do. So that's their job.
Their job was basically to spot.
And then you've got other people
in that chain of, of events, uh,
who are a little bit higher up the
food chain who then assess, right.
And we'll look at that person and go,
yeah, there's maybe there's something,
there is person works for whatever
company and you know, that'd be it.
It could be, it doesn't matter what the
company is, by the way. It could be.
Qualcomm could be, you know, think
of one, cause the application
could be, Corning could be any.
And there's all sorts of
companies out there that,
that have applications that may be of
interest from an Intel perspective for a
hostile state. So then, you know,
they'd do a little assessment and maybe
they come away and go, yeah, yeah,
that person's interesting.
Jobless developed a little
relationship there. Now,
maybe one of those individuals will work
on that relationship and maybe somebody
else will come in, you know, within
this, uh, there's this group, um,
and they'll develop a
relationship and then, you know,
maybe they'll task the person.
So maybe say the guy works at
a tech company and you know,
you're going to think, okay, I want to
see if this person has any weaknesses.
You know, how can I leverage anything
here? And so what you'll say is a,
you know, a how I kid, you know, I was
doing this school paper and it's on,
you know, something and Ah,
okay, I can't, you know, I, they,
they just not getting it or they're not
doing the research or whatever. Hey,
do you have anything? You know, and
you're not asking for anything classified,
you're just saying, look, you, you
work in a tech company, you know,
don't you have something that
would be of interest? You know,
my kids gotta write the stupid paper and,
and you're not looking for
anything of, of Intel value.
You're looking to see whether
they'll accommodate you, right.
Will they actually come back and
go, yeah, well you know what,
we got this and it's Kinda
interesting and it's just, you know,
research paper that's, you know, been
out in the press for a long time.
But yeah, it's interesting. Hey, you
know, hands it over and well now you,
maybe you got something right now you've
got something that you can see that
they're responded to a
little task and then you'd,
so you set the hook a little bit and
then you just keep on working on that.
So in the meantime, they're
calling back to the KGB and saying,
we have guys who work at Raytheon,
right, knows information just,
and they say it just like
that, with that very accent.
They keep jobs and everything. So they
work, they go to work, go to work.
Maybe they don't, maybe their spouse,
you know, I'm a stay at home spouse,
but what do they do?
They hang out with other state owned
spouses and create friendships because of
kids. And the next thing you know,
you all haven't dinners with
each other and you know, you,
if you like that rush and broad,
she's banging everybody, right? No,
you wouldn't do that.
That would be a very disruptive
thing to do in that community. Right.
And so the premise of the Americans and
seem to show, but I watched on banks,
people I watched,
I watched about half an hour of the
first episode and then I'd get angry. No,
I just sit there and I go, I'm a very
hard person to watch shows like that with.
And so, so my wife was like,
I just, I know you can't,
you can't sit here cause it's like
Intel and I'm going like [inaudible].
But it was, I, you know,
for to understand it was a good show
with a show where people play pool.
No people really play pool.
I'm like fuck yeah. Yeah I was,
I was just in the UK and
boy, I'll tell you what,
I turned on the TV and there's a snooker
match on. Yeah, I'm in there sneaker,
I'm in there, right. I'll just sit and
sit and watch snooker tunes in there.
Oh my God. But it's also,
it's one of those things where either
you can sit and watch it or you like golf
or you can't. And I just haven't,
for some reason I've got some defect that
allows me to sit and watch a billiard
match. Have you ever played? It's
tough. It's hard. Yeah. Yeah. I, I,
we have a pool table at home. The boys
have become pretty damn good at, uh,
which is a skill of life skill.
Uh, but yeah. Billiards. Is
it, is it [inaudible] is a different
new crews way harder. Yeah.
It's way harder. They, they
excel in American pool.
I don't think any American player has
ever gone over there and excelled and
sneaker. I don't, I don't
believe so. Yeah. Yeah.
That'd be something for
you guys have tried,
but I don't think anybody's succeeded.
But there's been a ton of
guys from England that have
come over here and they do
very well on the American pool tour.
But you know what we do better on is,
is bowling. We do, we kicked the shit
out of them when it comes to bowling.
Yeah, but that's an American thing.
Well, yeah. There you go. Did they bowl,
come over here and bowl? I don't think
so. I don't know. I don't think so.
I don't think I'm advanced, but
it's been that migration this way.
Equally stupid sport. Yeah.
And they get really mad when I say
I've got all these texts. You Fuck No,
I'm not rolling a ball at these things
and you have to pick them back up again.
Have you ever bowled sober? I don't
think I've ever bowled. So, yeah,
both my kids always sober.
My kids love bowling and they put up the
little bumper thing so it doesn't go in
the gutter. So you cheating,
so you can just basically
whip that fucking thing down
there a hundred miles an
hour. That's what I do. My thrill
is to hear the [inaudible] ball.
Yeah. If it's up for that, what's
up for me? I'm going to sit up.
I give them an edge. No, you
know, don't even let them,
would you let your kids on the floor,
do you let your kids win and things?
All the time. Yeah, all the time.
But I did get a hamstring injury because
I didn't let my kid beat me in a race.
I will. She's 11. Okay. I
was rough. I was running.
I knew something was going on.
I'm like, who cares? Push through.
She's not winning my fucking
hamstrings hurt my middle boy.
A sluggo plays basketball. That's
all he wants to do day and night. Uh,
and he's, he's a bit like a, the sorta
like the rain man of basketball too.
So in terms of facts, figures,
characters, and you know,
he can go back to Jerry West and, and,
and he'll tell you about bill
Russell's career and I think,
but he loves basketball and he want to
play professionally. Yes, he does. Yeah.
So I'll tell you, uh, you know,
it doesn't look like it, but in a,
in a deep fake video, I look about six
foot 10, but what are you like six, six,
one that's quite six one. Yeah. Get
that kid on growth hormones. Yeah.
Well he already left. Yes. Stretch
them out and put it in his burgers,
hanging up by his ankles.
But he, that's all he does.
He plays and he just constantly, and
he just, all he wants to do is play.
And so he's got to the point where,
you know, for a long time I would just,
we'd go out, we got to court at home
and I, I'd, I'd play and, and uh,
I kinda let him, you know, as I say,
and then it gets to the point
where I can't really beat him.
I've got hide on him. Right. But
his handles are extremely good now.
And so, and I'm not the fastest
kid on the block anymore.
And so it's gotten to the point now where
he's legitimately beat me a handful of
times and it's very embarrassing because
he doesn't really have an edit button,
so he, he just rubs that shit out.
Right. And it's like, it's like a,
it's like the lion king when scar wants
to take over. Right. And he's just like,
oh, that was pretty good, wasn't
it? The lion king reference.
It's a good reference, eh. So anyway,
yeah, to let them do that though.
It's an exercise for you and
patients. So when he's talking shit,
that's how I look at it. And my kids
talk shit. If they beat me, I just go,
okay, go ahead and talk to them.
Shit. And that's like, you can't,
can't let it be personal. No, no.
You had to treat it like almost
like an Internet heckler. Well,
kids are allowed to hit
me full blast. So my,
my kids take martial arts and I
let them, well not the oldest one,
the oldest one's 22. She'll fuck me
up. Yeah. But the, uh, the young ones,
I let them tee off on me. They, they,
they're allowed to full blast leg kicked
me. They can hurt me, they'll hurt you.
But I want them to be able to feel what
it feels like to actually hit a person.
Cause when you're sparring
in martial arts class,
you're not allowed to like hit people
full blast. You just kinda touch them,
you know?
And so I let them just fucking slam shins
into my thighs and I teach them how to
turn it over and dig the, really dig that
bone into the sauce bar. That's good.
That's, that's actually really good
fucking hurt sometimes though. But uh,
it's good when we had the same problem
with my, with my boys, because they have,
they're fairly competitive in there.
They're aggressive and, you know,
I keep telling them, I said, look,
getting punched in the face isn't good
and you know, until you actually do well,
you know, they've gotten into some, into
some, uh, I was going to say 50 cups.
Uh, I don't know if you could
say that. [inaudible] okay.
You're allowed to say fisticuffs
I guess 50 coaches are dying.
We're continuing to talk over there and
he's, uh, has a hard time with water,
but it's hard to teach
your kids, you know, uh,
what that's like. Right. And you know,
at some point, you know, maybe they,
they, uh, they go through that. They're
the youngest one, uh, broke his nose,
a courtesy of the older, the oldest one.
So mugs, he got his nose broke in a,
in a contest with, uh, with the older
one, the oldest one scooter and uh,
and he found out that's no
fun. The thing is though,
that kid's going to be
the tough one. Yeah.
The kid that it's always the youngest
ones like you see in the UFC when there's
older brothers and younger brothers,
the older brothers genuine generally
pick on the younger brothers and the
younger brothers, once
they reach adulthood,
almost always can fuck up the older
brothers. Yeah. It's really weird. Yeah.
Yeah. I was,
I took a lot of beatings
when I was younger cause I'm
the youngest of four boys
and so, um, yeah, but it's,
yeah, it's good. It's good stuff.
And Oh my God, it's, there's this, it's
constant and attainment. All right.
I mean, you know what it's like, you
know, with kids there's always something,
and I'm sure right now
people are going, oh my God,
he's gonna start talking about
his kids again at length and they,
I'm not going to do that cause the kids
names are so cartoonish. Yeah, I know.
Well that's part of the reason why they
get mad. Yeah. As they are. But, uh,
anyways, so, uh, we talked about
oceans. Yeah. Okay. Like I like,
I'm like Uncle Joe here.
I've, I've cut out some,
some shit to talk about deep fakes.
We talked about that. Okay. Okay. Uh,
I wrote down some notes to my
God. I was prepared for it.
I've never been prepared for
your show before. And, you know,
why did you decide to get prepared
this time? You know, why? Because,
because you've got, you've got
some really, uh, great, uh, uh,
guests, uh, well, no, not really,
but viewers and listeners, I mean,
I was to think the people that
follow this show, um,
I find to be a really fascinating,
I get a lot of of, uh,
feedback and I feel
like, you know, I, yeah,
I should pay attention than I should.
I should prepare a little bit
because there's a lot of interest,
right. And some of these things
that we talk about and you know,
so while sometimes I go out
and I wing it, you know,
and to be fair on new segments,
I just make shit up now. I don't,
I don't do that. Uh, I
know you want to talk
about Huawei. Well, I'll Huawei,
which I think is a really
fascinating subject to me. Um,
and a lot of people that are tech inclined
because they are at the tip of the
spear when it comes to technological
innovation in the cell phone space.
And I know that they're
doing that with, in,
in regards to modems and a
bunch of other things as well,
but it appears at least,
and a lot of companies are exclusively
using their 5g modems as 5g rolls out.
Oh yeah. Yeah.
But it appears there they are involved
in some serious shenanigans and they have
deep roots with the Chinese government.
They do, they claim they don't,
they claim, look, we're independent.
We would never do whatever
the Chinese authorities say.
Think about that sentence.
Think about a company with a global
reach of Huawei of that importance to the
Chinese state and think about them saying,
trying to say with a straight face,
we wouldn't, we wouldn't do, you know,
things that the Chinese government
might ask us to do it alone to show real
Chinese company. And you said that you
meant it, they would shut. Yeah, yeah,
exactly. Yeah. Like you won't, yeah.
You would not be in business for that
long or there would be a change in the
senior management of the business.
Um, so, and Huawei's been caught out,
they've been caught out in Europe, uh,
to the degree where at a certain point
you think Germany and others that are
deeply involved with Huawei now in terms
of the 5g infrastructure where they've
just made this decision, look,
it's financially better for us to work
with wowway and we can set aside the
security risks. They literally
made that decision that it's
an article about that very recently,
that they've just decided to
have some sort of a risk, uh,
to reward conversation. And
the, the, the risk is worth
a reward. Right. Right.
And so, you know, that's,
that's their calculation
from a US perspective because
we are, you know, look,
there's, there's two essentially two
superpowers now, right? I mean, China's,
you know, um, advancing and, and, uh,
we're not the lone superpower
on the stage anymore.
And so we are the number one
target. Um, and you know,
our calculation has to be different.
So we've been going at it and I
know everybody, I think it's been,
it's been pretty well covered. It
didn't used to be covered very well,
but it's been pretty well covered
over the past couple of months.
And now what's happening is we've been
in these trade negotiations with China
and I think, unfortunately, I
think the current administration,
the Trump administration
is going to blink.
And I think that because Huawei is such
a huge issue for the Chinese and the,
that we would prevent, um,
our companies from selling
into or purchasing from or
dealing with and that we
were, have sanctions on other
countries that, that do. Um,
they view that as such a threat to their
own interests and their own future,
um, that Huawei is front and center
with any trade deal. So they're looking,
they're not doing any trade deal
unless we make concessions on Huawei.
And I have a feeling the
Trump administration is going
to make those concessions
because
from a political perspective,
they want a trade deal. Right.
And so far they've actually said to
Google that Google is going to stop using
the android operating system
for the, for the Chinese phones,
for walways phones, at least they're
going to not let them license out the,
so Walway has actually been at least
rumored to be in production of their own
operating system, which would mean
they would have to have their own,
not just operating system, but they,
they'd have to have their own ecosystems.
So they'd have to have an app
store, they'd have to have all the,
all the jazz that we have today.
When you, if you sign up for,
you buy an android phone, you have
access to the Google play market,
which is this huge resource
of applications. And as
soon as you take that away,
you've got to kind of rebuild that whole
thing from scratch. Right? Right. Well,
Huawei doesn't lack anything in resources,
you know, there'll be fine, you know,
because the state will provide and
ensure that they have the resources they
need. They also, you know, we're
the outlier here, right? I mean,
we've been working with New Zealand
and Canada and the UK to some degree,
but the UK has been, you know,
they've been kind of pushing back a little
bit on this idea that we're going to
isolate
well, way I, I don't think
that's going to happen.
And so they're using Walway devices.
Um, the, they, to some degree, yes. Uh,
they've been slower to adopt [inaudible]
and kind of mesh their infrastructure
with while ways for people
here, for people don't know
what we're talking about.
Could you please just lay
out what's the concern?
What do they think that
we're always doing? Um,
Huawei is essentially, um,
what's the, the, the way
to put this would be, uh,
imagine a communications network
that spans the globe and,
um, Huawei builds and provides, uh,
gear and certainly going into 5g. Um,
there are leading provider
and Sir and financially they,
they can offer countries a much better
deals than, than other providers,
but they are a, an intricate
part of that communications web.
So if you imagine that walkway is a state
sponsored entity and will respond to
Chinese authorities requests for
information or intelligence that's passing
through this communications
web around the globe, our, uh,
our business communications,
our military communications, um,
intelligence communications, that that
all kind of go through at some point.
This interconnected system, uh,
that's the problem because they're
essentially building back doors into that
system that allow them to
suck a communications out
of that network and use it
for their own purposes. It's a
great intelligence tool, right?
So if you think about it in a way,
basically that's a, it's a, uh,
it's an advancement on the idea that you
are wire tapping somebody or you know,
you've, you've created ability to
intercept some communications, right?
They link themselves with
the EU. What happens,
we've got military communications,
right? With the EU,
our military talks to the military and
we've got NATO concerns and everything.
So if,
if there's an element in
that infrastructure that
touches in and has a door that
opens to some walkway gear, right?
Then the danger here is, and they've,
they've had back doors discovered in the
past and then while we put your hands
up and go, oh, well we didn't know
that was there. We'll correct it.
And then it turns out they don't
correct it. And then, you know, oh,
sorry about that. You know, they, they,
they honestly don't give a shit. They,
I, when I say how aggressive they are
in terms of sucking up information,
I can't overstate it. Right? And so this,
that's why it's a problem for
us is because, you know, if we,
if we convince, uh, Australia
and, and you know, the five eyes,
nations new is [inaudible] and in others
not to work with wowway and then say
Canada, you know, which is
willing to do a deal. Well,
we've got seamless communications
infrastructure with Canada.
So all of a sudden, the fact that
they're doing business with Weiwei,
but we're not, we're still at risk.
We're still in jeopardy
because that information is
still flowing to some degree
where it's accessible to, to Huawei and
their ability to get. So I, you know,
again, I know, and I know people
listen to that and they go, ah,
why is that of any concern? Well,
it's a concern because it used to be in
the old days it was a, a, you know, uh,
it was us in the Russians.
So Union Russia's,
you know, they got the GDP of
a small EU nation. China is,
is on the march. They, they, they
view themselves in a certain fashion.
That's why they're pushing
down the south China Sea.
They've been building up their military.
They've been doing deals all over the
world, uh, for rare earth minerals to,
you know, to Labor, dosage,
uh, uh, access to enable ports.
It doesn't matter what it is,
they've been busy doing that because they
view themselves at the top of the food
chain. Now I guess we
could say, wow, okay fine.
Maybe it's their turn or something,
but I, that's not how I view the world.
Right? I mean, we can either be
on top of it, we can, you know,
be sucking wind and, and
so he goes back to that,
one of those early questions you asked
is how much did we spend on defense?
How much do we spend on, on Intel? How
much do we spend on whatever it may be?
And I think the answer is that's
where intelligence comes in.
You have to know what the opposite,
what the hostile nation is doing.
You have to know what the competitor's
doing. It's just like in business.
Then you have to spend enough
to stay ahead of that, right?
Even if it's a small amount, you gotta
stay ahead, you gotta and it's it,
it behooves us not to fall behind.
Um, that's never a good thing.
I know we don't always do things
right, but as a nation, um,
the world is much better off with us.
I'm sort of at the end of, this is
going to sound wrong to a lot of people,
they're going to think, oh my God,
that's terrible. But with us at the top,
we're, we're more altruistic. Uh,
maybe that is the Ed and that's the word
not, but I think word. Yeah. So anyway,
so I, that's, that's my
view. A lot of people say
bullshit, but you know, everyone's got
different experiences, you know. Well,
is there a way to detect,
like when they released,
say if they release a Walway
phone and which is a really rich,
really interesting that
just a few years ago,
Walway was not even a major player
by any stretch of the imagination.
Now it's the number two cell
phone provider in the world,
a past apple,
which is incredible when you consider
the fact that they barely have a foothold
in the American market.
They very few people buy their phones
and if they do buy their phones,
they buy unlocked phones from overseas.
Yeah. It's really kind of crazy. Um,
but is there a way where they could detect
whether or not there is a backdoor in
these phones? I mean,
or is it something where they could
develop it to the point where you really
would have no idea?
Um, no, we can, we, we stay pretty well,
you know, that your, your, yeah, it's a
good, it, it's a good question. But I,
I would say that, uh,
as long as we continue what
we're doing in terms of, uh,
counterintelligence and, and,
uh, tech advances and efforts in,
in cyberspace and elsewhere and certainly
in communications hardware to stay
ahead of potential hostile activity.
I think we're, we're OK. We, we, we,
we're good at detecting problems. We're
good at identifying weaknesses in,
in the systems. Um, the problem is, again,
it's a global community. We can't isolate
ourselves in terms of communications.
Infrastructure just
doesn't work. So you know,
it's like a chain and a
weak link. Okay. Yeah.
See I gave that analogy. Yeah, good.
Yeah. Thank you. I am [inaudible]
you are the weakest link.
So yeah, it's, I mean, anyway, but that's
Huawei and I, and I do think that it's
the interesting part will be what does
the administration do in their desire to
get a trade deal?
Are they willing to blink on this
because they put their foot down, right?
And now because we're so dysfunctional
here in the states from a political
perspective,
now you've got people like Chuck
Schumer going, well you know,
Trump better not blink
on this. This is boy.
So suddenly Chuck Schumer is a hawk on
his heart are protecting us from, from,
you know, Chinese espionage. Right?
And, but simply because, you know,
he sees it as a political
opening here. You know, if,
if Trump backtracks on Huawei now, hey,
good, from the democratic perspective,
they can use that to bang on
him, you know? And so it's all,
it all comes down to politics. But,
but this is something that people didn't
even understand was an issue like good
nationally.
This is something that no one was
even aware of until a few months ago.
And when I started reading about it,
one of the first things that I
was reading about was, you know,
I'm kind of a technology nerd and so I
was fascinated by some of their newest
phones, which were really
far advanced to what you're
getting offered in the United
States. Yeah. And a lot of that, uh,
ability to, to create in record time, um,
comes from [inaudible] property.
Yeah. And that's how they,
over the years, again, that was a,
that was a collective decision by
the authorities there that just,
this is how we're going to
advance. Right. And we, we,
they looked and they make a calculation
that says we can't afford to wait
decades while we do our own research
and development, you know, well, let's,
let's just take it.
And Weiwei is not the only
Chinese phone manufacturer.
There's quite a few
different ones over there,
but they're the only one that seems
to be band. What's that other one?
Zomy where there's, there's
quite a few there are,
but Huawei has been because of their size,
their in their connection
to the government. Um,
and because of the resources that
the government's been willing to, um,
to provide to them the
advantage that they have, um,
and the speed with which they were able
to kind of embed themselves into other
nations, a telecommunications
infrastructure. That's
why they're so important.
Right. But the general, yeah. You know,
are there other companies we, well,
of course, yeah.
I mean there's a variety of companies
we should be worried about from that
perspective. And it's
not like that'd be fair.
I spent some time on China
because it's just, you know,
they're the number one state, you know,
sponsored perpetrator of theft of
intellectual property. But you know,
there's just other countries involved
in it. So I'll copy entire cities,
which is really insane. You've seen
that they have a fake Paris over there.
Yeah. Yeah. I know. Well, you know,
they've got you go some of these places
I went and looked at and in Chinese
history, culture is fantastic. Right?
And I've been over there and times and
I've just like marveled at how, how,
you know, how interesting the people
are, how friendly they are, how,
I mean they look this, there's a
lot of wonderful things about China,
but I'm just saying the authorities,
right? The government policy of um,
no rule of law, of, of,
of the no protection when it
comes to intellectual property,
all these things and their aggressiveness
and stealing information and that's
the problem. Um, but China as a
country is, is a fascinating place. So,
uh, that was, I don't know
why I said that. That's my,
it is a fascinating place. It's
very, very, very, very, very old,
which is something that we don't totally
understand. That was like five varies.
Like when you look at the history of
China, it's really, it's amazing. Yeah.
It goes back so far. When
you look at this country,
it's a couple of hundred
years and that's it. Oh,
I know that we come across a house,
it's a hundred years old and someone
slaps a historic thing on there and you
can't stop me, can't do anything to it.
And we've, we've faced that in the past.
When you guys got a house,
it was built in the 20s and they
have a historic thing then 19,
27 it'll be soon. It'll be
the architecture of the 60s
that we want to protect.
Yeah. Probably plastic over couches.
Remember that? Oh, that was,
that was a good thing. Right. You know,
and nobody wanted to sit
on those in the summer,
but what do you think is going to
happen when you really think that the
government's going to cave and they're
going to give into a I think so because I
think they really, they, they definitely
want a trade deal in some capacity.
And China's not going to
blink on this, right. They'll,
they'll figure out how to,
how to kind of bear the burden of the
tariffs and make things work on that,
you know, for them to screen. Much
gets built over the too. I mean,
all the apple stuff's
getting built over there now.
And there was just a recent story, uh,
where Tim Cook was trying to get Trump
to back down off of some tariffs because
you know,
we're going to have a 25% tariff on some
apple products that they're building in
China. Yeah. Yeah. And it's the idea that,
look, it's not the idea that you can,
yeah. Rob Huawei Revenue Jumps
23% despite us crackdown. Yeah.
Because look over at C's, their phones
are gigantic. They figured out, you know,
Samsung made a huge, disastrous
mistake with their galaxy fold.
I don't know if you know,
but the foldable phone, well,
they have a mate x that apparently
is way better than the galaxy fold.
It's a better design and
it's viable works. Yeah.
Samsung's an incredible company and
it's, it's got an amazing history of,
of innovation and technology, but, but
you're right, they have had a couple of,
they've had a couple of missteps.
A fold wasn't the only one that they
had a misstep on. Seven, the blow up.
Right. That's a problem, right? When
you get on the phone that explodes.
That's not necessarily what you
want in a communications device.
What are you pointing out? The y
way made x is not as good as I said.
It says design changed just a few
weeks before the release. Well,
what's wrong even come out yet. It just
does not change the, I don't know. Yeah,
but it doesn't mean it's not better.
Why you saying it means it's not better?
The people that have tried
it, if you said it's better,
it's just saying it's last minute.
Tweaks have been made to the devices
ahead of the anticipated release in
September as an additional sensor appears
had been added to the phone's camera
module. That's to find out
where you live. Exactly.
I mean that doesn't mean it's
not better, Jamie. I thought yet.
So how would anybody know the
people that have reviewed it?
There's people that are reviewed
it. All the tech sites I've written,
they just changed it. You
just don't like, yeah.
Well they just tweet the sensor.
You just talking shit over there,
but he wants to go back to coffin on
water. Are you anti hawala? No, no.
They did use the Lichen name to like I
little, I licensed it for their camera.
I don't think that they're using
like, like a cameras and other Nara.
It's like a, I've used it, I use
it at ces like three years ago.
I thought they used liker cameras
for the pro or whatever it is.
They use the name, but I don't
believe that it's, it's not,
I mean it might be a like a sensor, but
it's like a very, it's a micro chip.
It's compared to the one I have in
this camera that's very expensive.
It's not definitely it's
been at all the camera,
but I mean I think they use Leica
lenses. Right. Or like a something good.
Can we get to the bottom of
this? When I was there lot,
so I was super interested in it and I
was trying to tell, I was like, what?
What are they using about this name?
There's a photographer I followed
that was promoting it and I was like,
just seems like they're
using the name is all.
I couldn't tell that it was a
better photo. I couldn't tell.
You don't even have [inaudible] my age,
but that's all I couldn't tell at all.
No, they're not. Right. Again,
I'm just saying I couldn't tell,
but as a photographer I couldn't. I
could like all you're using is the name.
This isn't a better photo. It's
not, doesn't have the value.
With the like what I was
getting have some pretty
spectacular cameras though. To me,
I mean they had the very best
ever night vision camera,
not night vision but night sight.
Like the ability to take photographs at
night and it looks like pull up a Huawei
night photograph examples cause Google
Pixel three is the second best one,
but the last one is
supposedly the Walway one.
Zoom came out a couple months ago and
people were saying that that was bullshit,
which put us out.
It was like I had a super zoom
technology lens that people were at.
Someone was far as like,
there's no way that that's real.
But who said it's no way that that's
real photographers, photographers,
reviewers, people that are
using this stuff and said,
but they weren't using this though.
Just one thing improved. Okay.
One thing has been proven that Weiwei
has taken some photographs and said they
were taken out of Weiwei phone and they
were actually taken on a very high end
or something like, yeah,
very high end camera. Oh.
Also Weiwei posted some stuff
on Instagram from iPhones,
caught a couple of times, cut
a couple times doing that,
which is also quite hilarious.
But, um, yeah, it's a,
it's a sneaky business and if, if
that's how they're going to do it,
they're going to get in through the back
door and get information through phones
and modems and,
and it may not be, you know, it, it,
it may not be something that they
worry about now in terms of access.
And when people say, well, why
did they want the access now?
They just want to know
that they can, I mean,
imagine a conflict in the future
where they have that ability, right.
Either to a realtime monitor
communications through
this network that they've
been able to build trapdoors
into, um, you know,
or to impact the flow of communication
more aggressively, more proactively to,
to do things. Uh, it's, you
know, it's, it's like, um,
it's like mapping out our
infrastructure, right? Um, the testing,
the probing that goes on of our, um,
of our electrical grid as an example.
I mean, that's just planning
for the future in, in,
in the event that something
bad's going to happen.
If there's going to be a conflict, you
know, they, they want to know as do we,
I mean, again, to your
point that, you know,
hopefully we're doing the
same stuff and, and um,
so yeah,
it's something else interesting when
you're talking about China though, is,
and you think about, okay,
what should we be watching?
And we touched on Russia a little bit is
the alliance between possible alliance
between Russia and China. And it's
an interesting dynamic. You know,
traditionally Russia, China
haven't been together. Um,
they've always been some areas
of concern. Um, you know, um,
uh, distrust. Uh, but if there are signs,
there are things happening that appear
as if China and Russia have made a
strategic decision to
align themselves closer.
And that would be because they've made
that determination that somehow it's in
their best interest of, you know,
and not necessarily that it's going to
be that way for any long period of time,
but right now in the current
environment, um, you see Russia, um,
acting as if what they want
is a stronger alliance,
military alliance and political
alliance, economic alliance
with China. Um, and it's, it's,
it's an interesting dynamic
that we need to be watching,
we need to be aware of. Um, and,
and part of that is, you know,
people again this, this idea that,
you know, there was this Russia, uh,
Trump collusion. And I'm
thinking, okay, well that's good,
except our relations with Russia
have been this bad in a long time.
So maybe it's all a very clever mind
game that they're playing because they're
closely aligned. But I don't think
so. So we've actually, um, um,
laid on more, uh, significant
sanctions on Russia. Uh,
we've attacked them from
an energy perspective in
terms of our ability to, um,
create our independence,
you know, particularly from,
from, uh, natural gas, um,
that has damaged Russia's abilities.
So I think there's reasons why they're
gravitating towards China right now.
But this idea that somehow Trump is
super friendly and as a useful idea of
Putin, it doesn't,
it doesn't play out when you look at
the reality of the relationship, uh,
between the two countries.
That whole Russian collusion thing is a
very confusing there because on one hand
you have the Democrats who are saying
without doubt there's Russian collusion.
And then the other side you have the
Republicans and say the Mueller report
essentially exonerated Trump from being
a part of any sort of Russian collusion.
I don't think either
one is totally accurate.
I think there's a lot of like weird
gray. Yeah, well both narratives. I think
the Democrat narrative
is easier to understand.
It just makes sense from their
perspective. Right. Why wouldn't,
why wouldn't we push that? Um,
to this day they're just still
amazed that they, they lost.
And so there must be
some grander reason why,
because we just clearly we couldn't
lose to this guy. Right. So, and,
and it was also a talking
point, much like, you know,
let's hit everybody
with the racist hammer.
It's a talking point and it's
worked for them over there.
The police the first couple of years,
um, on the, on the, on the,
on the Republican side, um,
look, the Russians
knew what they were doing, right?
They were fucking with the election
on several different levels.
And it wasn't just trolling through
the Internet. It wasn't, you know,
just placing stories that they could,
it wasn't just trying to foam it,
you know, a divisiveness and discontent.
It was also doing these little dangle
things, you know, where they're, you know,
they're looking to see what are they
going to bite and what are they gonna do.
You know what I mean?
You think about that Christopher Steele
dossier and it was a piece of shit.
I mean, if we saw that in the
commercial side of things, you know,
I've got a business in global intelligence
and, and, and research and security.
Um, that thing was just, there was
nothing. It was shot full of holes. Right.
And so you think, well, what's
somebody should have asked,
tell me about your sources. You know,
why are your sources talking? What,
what was, you know, you've
got gotta anytime you've
got a piece of intelligence,
right, you've gotta do a few basic
things, you know, where'd it come from?
Cause you explained to people with the
Steele dossier was all about, yeah,
it was basically just looked, they
were going after opposition research,
political opposition research, right?
So a Christopher Steele who was a,
you know, a paid a hired consultant, he
used to be with British intelligence,
not, you know, not a James Bond type.
Um, but you know, a decent enough,
by all accounts, a decent enough guy. Um,
but he entered the world of private
sector information gathering, right?
And I've got a company, that's what we
do all around the world. And, and you,
um,
you can't relax your standards
just because you're now
in the commercial sector,
right? When you get a
piece of information,
you need to test that
piece of information.
And one of the first things you need to
do is understand what's the sourcing for
it and why did, why did they have
access, you know, how credible are they,
what's their track record
and why, by the way,
are they providing this information
and how did it eventually, you know,
make its way to this report.
And those are the sort of simple things
that whether you're a a corporation
that's gathering intelligence about
a market that you may enter with, uh,
you know, an investment, um,
or whether you're still in the business
and you're an intel officer and you're,
you know, talking to a source that works
in some foreign ministry somewhere,
you've gotta be able to, you know,
stress test the intelligence and,
and Shit wasn't done. People,
people liked what they saw,
they saw negative
information about the, the,
the candidate and just run with that
shit. Right. And the more times you,
it's like,
it's like the old WMD reporting that
came out of the early days in Iraq.
The more you repeat it,
even if it's one source and
that sources is a piece of shit.
And what you repeated, people are going
to buy it. Right? So Russian collusion,
Russian collusion, you just keep repeating
that and that it's going to happen.
At some point it will
happen. But, um, anyway, so,
but it seems like Russia definitely likes
to disrupt our democracy. Absolutely.
And they would still benefit of
that. Well, a part of it is, um, in,
in the old days, it was sort of a struggle
for supremacy in the world, right?
I mean, that was, that's Kinda at its
core. That's what it was. Right. Um,
and their ability to chip away and faith
in democratic institutions was at the
core of a lot of the crap that they
pulled. And it still is. I mean,
so that's all the, when you're talking
about a propaganda effort, like the, uh,
the screwing with the last election, um,
what's their goal when the goal isn't
necessarily that, that's where they, they,
you know, do they care whether one
candidate or another wins? Well, maybe,
maybe they do. Right. But you'd be
hard pressed to argue that, you know,
they were working against, uh, Hillary
Clinton who had said, you know,
we want to have a reset
and, you know, and,
and have a new relationship with
Russia and work with them. I mean,
maybe they looked at
Trump and thought, yeah,
that's the guy we want to
work with. But over that,
the more important issue was in just
chipping away at, at, at, at Americans,
belief in democratic institutions
get us all so that we questioned the
credibility of, of a democracy.
And that's been the fundamental belief
for propaganda efforts within the old KGB
and now the FSU. And, and
so it's, it's, you know,
it's as simple as that in a way. Um,
and it worked. I mean, look at this,
you know,
we spent years now just bitching at
each other and yelling and screaming and
complaining. And we bought into it because
we all, like we talked about before,
we all, you know, we're easily duped and,
and I don't know how you get around that.
I don't know how he walked that back.
Maybe we don't. But, um,
I think it's an informed public that that
helps to battle this. But we haven't,
we lost sight of what was
important here. And that is,
and so I think the public needs, it's
their responsibility. You like this. Yeah.
You like where you live, then you gotta
make an effort to try to keep it right.
And,
and part of that is being an informed
public and understanding what the hostile
elements may be out there. You
know, without being paranoid,
but just understand why they're doing
things in the way that the world operates.
You know? And you'll always have
that group of people that, you know,
don't buy into any of that
bullshit and think it's all just,
we should all be holding
hands. Yeah. That's a, that's,
that's a fun one. That's, that's a
fun narrative. It's a good narrative.
It's a happy narrative. Yeah. Right.
When you've talked to people that have
seen terrible things that take place all
around the world, that
narrative is hard to swallow.
When you read about these gang members
that are coming in and growing pot and
fucking shooting at people and they've
got these high level task force just to
deal with these cartel members that have
grown weed. Right. And this is right.
And that's just one part of
what they're doing. Right.
That's just tends to human trafficking
and everything else that they get
involved in extortion to know, which is
probably the scariest shit. Yeah. Yeah.
And that's it. And that's, that's
what you have to worry about if you,
if you have pushed them out of the
market because you legalize everything,
which, you know, I assume that's kind
of the direction we're going. Um,
then do they fill that gap again from
a revenue perspective with fentanyl or
something else? Whatever
the next to choice is,
how do you stop the infiltration?
How do you stop the gang members
were coming in here. I mean,
how do you do that other than eliminating
them other than having some sort of a
tactical devastation? Well,
that seems like the only operation that
would make any sense in my mind. Yeah.
Well, it's like jihadism, you can't
kill your way out of it, right?
It doesn't mean you shouldn't make a
good faith effort, but, um, it's, uh,
for the, for the, for the drug control,
uh, for the narcotics counter narcotics,
um, part of it is what we talked about
also about working with the other
governments, right?
We've had some success in doing
that where you work with the Mexican
authorities, you work with the Colombians
or Allen, Southeast Asia, you know,
to try to, you know, uh, push on
the back on the heroin trade. Um,
and so you work through them to some
degree, but that's tough, right?
That's corruption. There's so much
corruption and that's, and that's,
that's the problem. And it's,
and it's unsatisfying because you don't
see an immediate return sometimes,
and it's, and it's also, it's, uh,
sometimes seems like it's just a big,
you know, a bottomless pit where
you're tossing money, right?
And effort and resources, but it's
something that has to be done.
Doesn't mean you shouldn't still
do it. Um, but it is, I mean,
corruption in a place like Mexico, right?
Where the people just don't have any
faith in the institutions, right.
Because they've lived in this system
for so long where all the officials in
their minds anyway are corrupted.
The police are corrupted,
federal is a corrupt, um, you know,
the, the marines down in Mexico,
probably the most trusted institution. Um,
because they're not viewed in the same
vein. They're not viewed as corrupt,
but only the marines. Well, yeah, pretty
much. I mean, that's a, which it's odd,
but it's a, it's a,
that's a large organization and they've
been able to kind of stay above the fray
to some degree, which is interesting.
I have no idea. But it's, um,
it's been the perception and just
for the most part, it's, it's true.
When you work down there often
enough, you do get that impression,
but it's how you get rid of that
endemic corruption in that society.
Um, and turn that public
perception around, you know,
because that will impact. But I
mean, look what happened, you know,
previous administration when they, they
seriously went after cartel members.
Right? Remember that spree of
violence that, that kicked off.
It was in part because the Mexican
authorities were going after cartels in a
more serious manner, right.
They previous to that they were managing
the problem. So they said, okay, look,
let's manage down the violence everybody
and we'll let you keep doing your
business. It's going to happen so you
guys do your business, but just, you know,
let's keep sort of public
order, you know, as,
as something that we want to
demonstrate that we're capable of.
And when you have to, when they went after
the cartels in a more serious manner,
um, that's when that real parse spree
of violence kicked off. And you know,
there was more head room. So these,
you know, these various members were,
you know, they,
they were combating each other and
they were going after the public.
They understood that they had to, you
know, basically wear down the public,
which is what happened. The public
said after a while they said, fuck it,
we can't deal with this. The
violence is too much. It's awful.
And so government, you know, eventually
went back to managing the problem.
Drug trade didn't go away.
Of course when they just went back to
the old waves of doing things so that the
violence is just so intense
that the public eventually
just said, we can't know.
And, and I think the cartels knew
that they understood that. Right.
And so they were willing
to do it. Um, well, the,
the most ridiculous aspect was that fat
fast and the furious deal where they
were literally selling drugs to the
cartels so they could track them.
And those drugs we use to eventually
kill some US officers. Right? Yeah.
I mean it was, yes, I say it
was drugs, drugs, weapons,
drugs. Yeah. Yeah. Conflating things.
Yeah. Those guns that they used,
they did kill officers, right?
Yeah. There was, there was a,
an officer in particular was that was
killed and, and the, the fast and furious,
anytime you talk about
time, you talk about, uh,
as part of a intelligence
collection effort, right. Um,
or law enforcement effort that you're
going to supply the hostile meant with
weapons or whatever it may
be. Um, Eh, it's going to go,
it's probably going to go sideways. Right.
Seems like a great way to cover the
fact that you were selling guns.
I mean, if I was really skeptical, I
would say, well, what are you going to do?
We're going to sell them guns. How the
fuck are you gonna sell them guns? Well,
we're going to say that it's an
intelligence gathering thing. Sound guns.
Yeah. We have some really cynical,
which a lot of people aren't.
A lot of people are. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. No, I mean, I think it was,
it was a fucked up operation.
There's no doubt about it. And I,
I'm not a fan of, you know, it's,
it's sort of like the same in the
gray arms marketing, you know,
sort of on a global basis. When you
talk about, you know, like, you know,
because you're getting,
what are you looking to do?
You're looking to create movement,
track, you know, movement of, of,
of gear or money or resources or personnel
the way there's ways you can do that
without creating a potential for a
complete goat rope. And unfortunately,
fast and furious did that
and had to be a goat rope.
You're giving people the ability to
kill people. You giving them guns. Yeah.
Like why do they have chips on the guns?
Like how they even tracking these goddamn
guns. Yeah. It sources method shit.
But um, it's, yeah, I
going back to Mexico.
And how do you, you know, how do you
resolve that? Because that impacts, again,
that impacts us. It impacts our
national security. Right. And so, well,
they're literally connected to us. We're
so concerned with Afghanistan and Iraq,
they're nowhere near us and we've
got this thing connected to us that's
literally filling this country
with illegal drugs. They sell Meth,
they sell fentanyl. Dan Afghanistan,
fuck that. Coming up on another election,
presidential election in mid, I
think mid September, you gotta run,
you're not thinking about it.
I'm thinking about moving the family
over there and thinking of Afghanistan.
Yeah. I could, me and Boris Johnson
and Trump would get together, but uh,
yeah, no, they've had an
increase in bombings, you know,
Taliban stepping it back out or,
and I mean, we don't think about it.
Nobody wants to think about that shit
anymore. You think about how many years,
you know, we've been digging in and it
always comes back to the same thing,
the Taliban, and what do we
think was going to happen?
They got no place else to go. Right.
And so difficult to track them down
the mountains and they, and they,
they will just wait it out. Right.
And so here they're back again.
They're increasing bombings.
They want to take, you know,
they want to take over again. And it's
just so you're right in a sense. Um, we,
did we take her off the
ball? Yeah, we did. Yeah.
And were there other issues that we
should have been more focused on? Yeah,
yeah, sure. But, you know,
then you're conflicted because you think
of all those people that fought and
died over there and the effort that
other people that came back and you know,
with, with, you know, horrible wounds
and, and the trauma of all of that. And,
you know, I feel somewhat conflicted
because then you talk about, you know,
I don't, you don't want to, you
don't want to minimize their,
what they did right for the country.
Um, but you also have a, an obligation,
I think they look at policy and what
did we do and what was the purpose of it
was the point of that exercise. Um, and
I don't think we still to this day, no,
right? I mean, what are we
gonna create some pseudo state,
federal government there that's going to
be a bastion of democracy and it's not
going
to happen. So anyway,
I don't want it disappeared on
the Afghanistan rabbit hole,
but we'd like to think that we could
turn that into another America.
That's what we like to think when
we think about nation building,
that we think that we can go in there
and establish democracy and these people
are going to be better and they're gonna
be able to go to school and it's going
to change the whole environment.
Yeah. Yeah. I guess. And that is true.
And we talked about Iraq that way.
If we just make a rock
a bastion of democracy,
then maybe it'll help to turn the tide
in the Middle East and suddenly it will
have more of a respect for individual
liberties and rights and all the rest of
that and how that worked out. You know,
I, I'm, I'm still looking into it. It's,
um, I'll come back again
and I'll give you my report.
I think it's going to be
negative. 1 million people
have done. Yeah. It's, yeah.
It's not good. Right? It's, that's
typically never good when you get,
you get to those numbers. A large
number. Yeah. Um, but again, look at it.
I mean, the, the shit that we
don't want to talk about it. Look,
we don't tell them about Syria, right.
Nobody wants to talk about Syria
and that and you know, Assad,
you know his butcher, he's still in
charge. Why is he charged with it?
Because Russia propped him up and want
to Russia proper along with Iran. Right.
As there's a, there's a nasty piece of
work there. And as an access goes, um,
you know, Russia had no
intention of letting Assad go.
[inaudible] we should have been
able to figure that one out. Right.
But we didn't, in part because we have
these, these, these impulses that say,
well, we're gonna do better.
And because we're gonna create this
ability for people to, you know, uh,
create their own democracy.
So, um, yeah. So anyway,
we, uh, we, Syria is again,
one of those places that nobody
really wants to discuss or talk about.
And we've got, we've got
attention deficit disorder.
Nobody talks about North Korea anymore.
I remember we were all going to get
blown up by Kim Jong Un. Yeah. Eh,
well, there's pictures of Trump shaking
his hands. So we're, we're buddies now.
Go home. We're all good. All good. I mean,
the last article I read about North Korea
was about how did Kim Jong Un get his
Mercedes since there's some
sort of a, she's a boycott or a,
you know, embargo.
Yeah. Well, and that's, you know,
that's another part of it is, is uh, um,
although we have been, we've, we've
been more successful, I will say this,
we've been more successful
than, than in the past.
And part of that is a technology issue.
We've gotten better at imposing and,
um, enforcing sanctions than we used
to be. And part of that is because our,
our abilities to understand a movement
of money, uh, tracking transactions,
um, is better than it used to be.
So the sanctions as an example
we put on around, um, this, yeah,
this is the most difficult time that
this regime has faced in Iran since the
fall of, of the shawl.
And it's because we've gotten
better at looking at, uh,
Russia, China in particular,
that have traditionally always
kind of circumvented the sanctions.
We're better at enforcing
that and were better at,
at working with the EU and pressuring
them. Right. I mean, so that's,
that's a good thing. Um, but I don't
know where that's, you know, I mean,
Iran is kind of flailing a bound a little
bit. They seized the tanker, you know,
British tank or they actually used a
couple, but they're holding onto one. Um,
in response to,
they were trying to ship a bunch of oil
over to Syria and against sanctions that
exist. Right. So,
so they had a tanker that was taken
2 million barrels or whatever,
of oil over to Syria. And the British, um,
in the territorial waters of Gibraltar,
uh, intercepted that ship now, uh,
beginning of July and in response, um,
the Iranians have done a
number of things right?
But the most recent thing that they've
done was they seized a British flag
tanker and they're still
holding the crew. And, um,
that's sort of an example of their, I
don't wanna say they're desperate, right?
Because they've got an ability,
I think to withstand in a,
their control over the Po population
is so strong, but it's an example,
I think to some degree of,
of them flailing a bit and trying to
figure out what are they going to do,
what's their next move. And,
uh, I know people say, well,
we shouldn't have gotten out of the
deal and we shouldn't, you know,
we shouldn't have this issue
anyway because we, you know,
it's Trump's fault for getting out
of the deal. Um, but you know, they,
again, I don't have a lot of
confidence in, in, in them, uh,
sticking to the terms.
And agreements of any deal because
they've never done in the past and there's
always been an effort and they've
always broken the agreement.
So I don't know why suddenly they would
change their tune if we can keep the
sanctions on hard enough
and force them to the table.
The only thing they care
about is staying in power.
If they think they're going
to lose that grip on power,
they'll come to the table
and then make a better deal.
And that deal would include us being
able to access their military facilities.
And for inspections we couldn't,
we had no access to any other military
sites in that country because now we
didn't make it a condition of the deal.
Right? So we basically said, sure,
we want verification that you are
following the agreements. And they said,
well fuck you. This is the,
these are the places that we agreed
to let you look at that. That was the,
I don't want to oversimplify, but that
was the terms of the deal. And so we, we,
any deal that we do with them in the
future needs to be able to say, no,
we want a hundred percent verification.
Because as John Kerry said,
that's what you want. You
wanna be able to verify.
So when we heard about it,
what we're hearing in the news from the
people that are opposed to the deal is
that Trump broke this deal and he was
foolhardy to do so that Obama had put in
place this deal and that Trump had broken.
And it sort of leaves us in
this terrible quagmire. Right?
But what you're saying is that the
deal was terrible and that they,
it didn't really give us
access to understand exactly
what their nuclear program
was with their military program was.
So it wasn't a good deal. It wasn't,
it wasn't wise to keep keep
it if you're, if you're, um, if,
if the way that you judge the
of the value of a deal and they,
this is what the previous administration,
the Obama ministration did,
was to talk about how, you know,
it's important that we verify and
we've got verification. Well, yeah,
you've got verification of the sites that
the Iranians agreed to let us look at
that. And so yeah, it was a
deal. Was it a good deal? No,
they wanted this, they wanted to sign
this deal in. The Iranians knew it.
And so, um, yeah,
I think that that justified saying, no,
we're going to redraw this. And even
the EU, which has been clinging to the,
the old agreement, even the EU says,
well yeah, we, we could improve it.
We could make it better, but there's no,
if you just keep things as they were,
there's no incentive for
the Iranian regime to,
to make any concessions or improve
it. So the point being is we're going,
we're trying to force them back to
the negotiating table and again,
given that their self interest is to
stay in power and remain in charge,
then you know, if with the economy in
the condition that it's in currently,
if it gets much worse than they feel as
if they're losing a grip on, on, on the,
the population, then I
suspect they will come there.
They're not going to lash
out, that Iran doesn't want a,
nobody wants a military conflict. We
don't want it. They don't want it, Yada,
Yada. Can they close the Strait of
Hormuz, you know, where, you know,
depending on who you're talking to,
a fifth of the world's oil
passes through or, um, yeah,
they could close the temporarily
or cause some friction,
but they don't have the ability
to shut it down for any,
any real period of time. Um,
we've just got too much, uh,
in terms of leverage over there and
our assets. And so, yeah, I, you know,
who knows, but I, I, I'm one of
those people that says, you know, we,
we shouldn't have done that deal until
we got it right. And just saying,
we've got to deal for the
sake of it because you had
partial verification doesn't
give you anything. We've,
we've had partial verification of
their programs for decades. Um,
and they just keep
advancing their program.
So do you think this criticism of backing
out of the deal that you're hearing
from Democrats is basically
just a criticism of Trump
to show an opportunity to,
yeah. Everything's a Curtis, I think
everything is a criticism of Trump.
Is that a problem?
[inaudible] because Trump has such a
polemic figure because he's so many people
just hate him that any opportunity to
have some sort of political talking point
against him sort of, uh,
confuses what the actual issue is itself.
Yeah. I mean, I think there's
no doubt he's, he, yeah.
I think what happens
is both sides we lose,
uh, in this one because the
Democrats sort of blindly, you know,
accuse him of a, everything's bad,
right? And no matter what he's doing,
no matter what policy is,
it's all bad, right? And so,
so that's not what you want to be.
And on the Republican side, you know,
you tend to think that that's
the case. And so, you know,
you don't have an honest, um,
intelligent discussion about the policy
landscape. Right? And so you again,
it was sitting in trenches,
throwing hand grenades together.
It's like World War One, right?
And nobody's going to get out and venture
into no man's land in the center and
nobody's living in the center anymore.
So I just think, um, everybody,
it's a disservice to everybody. But yes,
I think almost things that have come out
of Capitol Hill right now is based on,
um, on, uh, you know, look, here's,
here's an example. My daughter went, um,
she just got out of Grad school and
she's done a number of internships.
She's worked over in Asia. She's
been in China on, on, on, uh,
internships and she's, you know,
smart kid. I'm subjective, smart kid,
but she went for a job up in Capitol
Hill and it was not a direct hire,
meaning they'd office had to go
through the, um, the, the, uh,
other offices to get approval to hire
an individual to fill this position.
And because the house is
controlled by Democrats now,
uh, she was, uh, it, everybody looked
and said, yeah, she's a top candidate.
We want to offer the job. Well,
what happened was they
submitted her details.
So we want to hire this person to this
office within the Capitol Hill controlled
by the Democrats now because
it's the House majority.
And they came back and said,
no, because you know why?
Because she did an internship in
the current administration, right?
So young person wanting to work in DC, uh,
in policy and security studies and
elsewhere doing a variety of internships
around the globe, does an
internship at the White House.
Normally you would think that's a good
thing, right? But so they said, no,
because she did this internship
with the White House.
We're not going to approve the
hiring. And then it turns out, well,
she did an internship and build
the Blasio's office too. Right.
And so they said that, and the response
was, well, we don't like him either. So,
which I think was that actually
provided some humor, right.
To the whole situation. But
it shows you not, I mean that,
that's a little tiny thing and
it's a personal issue, but,
but it shows you Washington
d C is possibly the most
dysfunctional location in
all of North America. Um, that's
terrible. Yeah. And it's, and it's, uh,
and it's not the way it should be. We
should be able to have policy discussions.
We should be able to make
decisions. You may not like Trump,
you may not have liked the previous
president, but you know, again,
w we gotta stop this bullshit
where everybody's a racist.
Everybody's a sexist.
Everybody's like you, you,
it's not the way this country's
supposed to work. And people, you know,
you can't even get away from,
okay, well who's at fault?
Everybody's at fault, right? Well,
does the left are all guilty of, of
creating this divisiveness? What is this,
the cure to outrage culture? I
mean, how do you get past this?
That's the real question,
right? I mean, what is the,
I don't see a map and I was going to ask
you this about foreign policy because
as a guy who has been involved in the
CIA for as long as you have and has seen
all the inner workings of government
and all the conflict and d,
do you ever feel like you just,
we're just running up a 70 degrees sand
dune that you're never going to get to
the top of? You know what I mean? It
just seems like it never ends. I mean,
you're just basically trying to like,
oh, there's another hole in the dike.
Let me put my finger on this one.
Oh, water's coming out of this one.
Let me get my finger in this one. And
it never ends running up the sand Dune.
That's a good, that's a
good, uh, analogy, right?
It seems like a million mile
high sand dune and it is,
I think it's always looked at.
DC has always been divisive.
Politics have always created the division.
The press has always been biased
in one way or another. You know,
these things aren't new, but,
and we always tend to think it's the
worst we've ever seen. It looked,
the civil war was pretty bad. That
was pretty divisive. So, yeah.
So when you have a politician, like, like
I think it was Joe Biden, right? That,
that said that the president is,
is the most, um, you know, uh,
racist, you know, president we've ever
had. And you think, well, I don't know.
That's an own slaves. Exactly.
12 presidents own slaves.
I think that might've been a
problem, but, yeah. So, so, and,
or the race relations are the worst
they've ever been. And you think, yeah.
How about the 60s? That was pretty
bad, right? And the civil war.
And I think so every, every
time is, yeah, I know. And,
but I guess my point being
is that, you know, you can,
you can fall into that trap where you
think it's as bad as it's ever been. Um,
it's,
I think it's fair to say that it is more
polarizing now than in recent times.
And how do we walk it back?
How do we dial it down a little bit
and how do we actually focus on what's
important for the general population?
There's a lot of big issues we should
be solving, right? I mean, but,
but look at the insanity of, of when we
talk about healthcare, right? It's like,
oh, it's gotta be all this,
or it's gotta be all that.
Nobody's over in the middle
saying, well, you know,
you could take a little bit
of this and that. And again,
how do you walk that back?
It's way above my pay grade.
I hunkered down in Idaho and I'd, I'd
go fishing and I don't think about it.
I don't see any solution that
anybody has that makes any sense.
And that's one of the
things that terrifies me.
And I don't want to just step away.
I don't want to be that
guy that moves to fucking
Idaho. Yeah. I'd love to see
Alberta. Oh, there you go.
[inaudible] the North
Saskatoon, Edmonton New Zealand.
[inaudible] oh yeah, it is. I
love Edmonton. Yeah. But I mean,
it's like what we're doing in
Edmonton, UFC. Oh, okay. On a show. Oh,
you did river creek.
So, you know, yeah. It's, um,
I just feel like there's
no real general solution,
nor is there a map of a potential
solution. And in La, I mean,
and if we get a Democrat in the
White House, it's not gonna end.
Do Remember when Obama was in office,
they were mad that he wore a gray
suit or a Tan suit, a Tan suit,
making fun of his suit. Like the fuck.
Do you care? This is all you care.
But it's like this polarization,
the Fox News versus MSNBC polarization
that doesn't help anybody.
And it's, fuck,
it's so bananas that if you have
a podcast like mine and I have a,
a left wing person on, I'm a sell
out. If I have a right wing person on,
I'm a Nazi and it just
goes back and forth.
You can't even talk to
people anymore, which is
no, no, it does, it comes down to you
can't have policy differences anymore.
Right. It's gotta be some personal
animus that you've got towards that other
individual, which is, it's again,
his, his, uh, his, his horseshit.
You can have policy differences
with, with people. Um,
and that doesn't make you a bad person.
It doesn't make you a,
you know, they share,
those are the races that the question
fricking races out there. Right.
But that's,
we've lost the meaning of the term when
you just start hurling that around at
anybody you disagree with. Right. Or
when people say, well, if you like Trump,
you're a racist. Right?
Well, congratulations.
You're probably driving those people
to definitely vote for him in 2020.
So that's one thing that I
completely agree with you on that.
I think that this idea that everybody
who supports Trump is racist.
It makes those people so angry that they
just want to go, okay, I'm going to,
well, you're obviously nuts. I
can't, I can't be on your side.
You people are crazy.
You want to open up the borders and
you want to take all the money from the
everybody that's a hardworking American,
give it to all the poor
people and fuck you.
And it's like the arguments just get
so confused. Yeah. I not on the words.
I mean, if you think about
who, who might win, you know,
I don't think Joe Biden's gonna last.
I think they're going to eat him alive.
It's not, yeah, he's not going
make it. It's going to be,
I think Bernie and Carmela
Harris and um, Tulsi Gabbert,
those are the only ones that
makes Kelsey makes sense to me.
She's a veteran
congresswoman for six years.
She seems incredibly honest and to her
morals and our ethics are on point.
I like her. She's my
favorite. But, um, if the,
the left is going to have someone,
they're going to have to be able
to deal with Trump's insults.
You're going to be able to debate him
and that's where they all fall apart
because they,
they're trying to use that old model
of politics and he's not doing that.
He's a showman.
And I think what's happening is that the
pope looked at the people that count in
this in the primary or you know, that's
a completely different bag right there.
Then what goes on in the general,
and I think the people that
are in the primary right now,
all those people are going
to be voting in the primary.
They're watching like these debates as
an example or they're just watching the
daily Twitter, Twitter feed from
these people, the candidates,
and they're thinking, can I see
this person debating Trump? Right?
And so the not only are the policies
that these candidates are spouting are
moving further and further to the left,
which is going to make it harder when the
general election comes to shift to the
center and not gonna
be able to do it right.
That center is now shifted further to
left if they even make the effort to get
back there. But you know, you're,
you're getting sort of like the worst,
um, instincts coming off from these
candidates because they think, well,
I got to show that I can throw a fire
bomb here because they're looking at me
as, you know, can I debate Trump?
Right? And so you're gonna,
you're gonna get somebody who's not.
So I don't think Tulsa Gavin's gonna make
it because I think they're gonna make
that calculation. I think that they've
probably going to look in there.
You're gonna end up with,
with Harris or maybe Warren Warren
is not gonna make it. I don't know.
Amanda American thing's gonna say,
cause you would think so, right?
You would think so.
Harvard actually touted her and some of
their literature when they were talking
about their diversity
efforts over the years,
there's actually documents where
Harvard was saying, you know, hey,
and we hired, you know, at
first native American, you know,
professor and you're thinking,
that's a statistic I am 200 times
more African than is native American.
How bout that? Basically
African, uh, are Ya? Yeah.
I didn't know that 1.6%.
1.6%. Yeah. From where
we know 23andme, I did one of
them [inaudible] place today.
It's a whole continent. Someone from that
continent fucked one of my ancestors.
What did you find out in South Africa
though, Dan? It's not quite as, yeah.
Yeah. It's not quite, it's interesting,
but yeah. Well that's a Dutch, right?
Yeah. You get Dutch jabs. Boar Board.
Yeah. Um, yeah, I haven't done that.
You know, my daughter did it and,
um, I have not done that. I had,
I actually had a conversation the other
day about this whole thing about the
desire to know your ancestry and
everything. And I, my dad, uh, uh,
came over, uh, never talked about his
background, ever talked about his family.
Um, CIA dad, yeah. Put this in there
to keep his mouth shut. But uh,
and so he never, he never demonstrated
that interest. Right. And so therefore,
I don't think I've ever been, I've
never just been that focused on it. Um,
everything was in there that I
knew was in there. Mostly Italian,
a little bit of Irish, but
some weird shit, like 1% Asian.
I thought that was odd
to any Scottish. Nope.
It's always a little Scottish floating
around out there like to fuck. Yeah,
yeah, that's right. They get
out. They get out bout. Um,
yeah. Uh, yeah. I Dunno. I'm
the where it's all going.
But I do think that Warren, it
could be viewed. I don't, I don't,
I don't like her, but
I think that she will,
I think the base looks at her and
thinks, yeah, she could be a firebrand.
You can do this. After that
whole native American thing,
she built her career on a lie. They
don't care. They, that base doesn't care.
That's the problem. America cares.
You can't look past at the same way.
You couldn't look past
Hillary being a liar.
Hillary tried to say that her
name came from Edmund Hillary,
the guy who climbed Mount Everest.
He climbed Mount Everest three years
after she was born. But you know,
when he was still quite the
character before, so, you know,
it was still throwing that
name around. Uh, yeah. But, uh,
more than three years. Yeah.
Yeah. Um, after she was born.
It might've been seven years,
but you think it won't be,
I don't think it'll be Bernie.
I don't think you know John
Democratic Socialism. Well,
I'll tell you so much.
You go up to Vermont and look around for
Mont and see what kind of job Bernie's
done in. How about Pete? Did you
do a judge Judy? Judge, he treated,
they fucking hate him in
his own city. Mayor Pete,
they're pissed at him in south bend.
They wouldn't call him a
ticket with the blast. You,
that'd be a powerful
mayoral ticket right there.
There's no one person that stands out.
There's no one person that like stands
out as someone who's kind of when,
you know, everyone's like,
Ooh, could this person make it?
Could that person make it?
And then there's people that
want to challenge Trump,
which is hilarious. Well, I
think there's going to be,
we're going to lose a lot of these
folks after this next round of the,
which I guess tonight, tomorrow
night is, um, I think there's a,
it's not an a and a B card, but there's
two nights, two nights of debates.
Cause there's so many of them. There's
bouts, bouts. Did you see the pack fight?
Yes. Yeah. Yeah. I always see.
Great man. I got to tell you,
I drop Sturman in the first round.
They know Thurman's a beast too, man.
That's crazy. It was a, it was, that
was a great moment. And then it was a,
it was an interesting fight and I thought,
I wasn't quite sure at the end where
it was going to go, but I liked,
I've watched pack you'll
over the years. And I did.
There was kind of that typical, you know,
you get older and you're kind of
rooting for the old guy. Right?
He's 40 years old. He's the oldest man
to ever capture the welterweight title.
And particularly when you consider
those lighter weight classes,
like foreman won the heavyweight title
at 46, which was crazy. Yeah. But pack.
Yeah.
Winning the welterweight title at forties
fucking bunny working their ass off.
I mean, it was just, it was, it
was, it was a good, good fight.
I really enjoyed that.
That was first time I really watched
a fight that I really enjoyed, right.
Beginning to end. And uh, and I
was with some folks who were, were,
who were not for Paki and I kept looking
at, I'm thinking, how do you not like,
he's the old guy. He's been doing
this forever. He's a senator. Yeah.
Think about that. That's crazy.
Going back to work on a budget issues
in the Philippines after the fight.
That's crazy. Yeah. Yeah. I think he
made 10 million on that, I think. Yeah.
Good. Yeah. Good for him. Yeah. Yeah.
Keith Thurman too. He made two and a half.
It's got some chatter now. Key
College boy. I love it. It May,
whether it was in the audience. Yeah.
Yeah. Well that would be fantastic if the,
I mean, now's the time to do it if
Mayweather really wants to do it,
but may with a metal, watch
that fight and go. Yeah.
Because the first time they fought pack
y'all at a blown out shoulder and then
that was a lot of people were angry.
There was actually even talk of a class
action lawsuit against Pacquiao bef uh,
after the fight because people had bet
on him and his shoulder was fucked up
going, he'd heard it
in training and tried,
I think he got a cortisone shot and
said, I'm just going to try to fight on.
And then he wound up getting shoulder
surgery and then from then on after Rehab
looks fantastic. That's really interesting
though, the concept of could you,
could you push through a class action
lawsuit with an athlete who is in that
position? I mean, yeah. Where does that
go? I mean then if you're playing hurt,
I mean, you're in the NFL and you're
playing hurt. Right, right. Um,
do you have any obligation? No. I
mean, I mean it's interesting. Well,
UFC fighters fight hurt all the time.
I know for a fact guys fight with blown
out hcls and torn hamstrings and they
just listen. They get to that
point, they think I can still win.
And some of them still went,
Kamara will lose Monde,
won the title with a broken foot. He
broke his foot in training and he,
he was literally on crutches the week of
the fight and then the guy gets to the
fight and he's such a fucking
animal and so tough that he fought.
Like there was nothing wrong with him.
And then afterwards revealed that he had
broken his foot. It's fucking bananas.
The mental toughness that you have to
have to be able to do that for a living
and then you, you, and when you lose
to somebody with a broken foot. Yeah.
That's, and yeah, yeah, yeah. It was,
yeah. Dominated, dominated Tyron Woodley,
which is even crazier, but then Woodley
wins that fight injured as well. I mean,
it's just the nature of the beast.
If your job is to hurt people
and break their bodies,
you're going to have to practice breaking
bodies along the way and you're going
to have to practice it with people
that are trying to break your body
occasionally that they
succeed. Yeah. Yeah. Rough business.
Yeah. You got to come, come to an event.
I actually, I would like to do that.
I just want an Anaheim in a couple of
weeks. You should come to that one.
It's a big one. Daniel Cormier is
fighting steep Emile church. Okay.
For the heavyweight title in a couple of
weeks. Yup. Nate Diaz is fighting, uh,
Anthony Pettis. That's a crazy fight.
And Paulo Kosta is fighting UL Romero.
The two or three rather epic
fights in rain and Anaheim.
Graying. No one gets injured. [inaudible]
Jesus. Uh, yeah. You know what?
I can bring scooter. Scooter likes rings.
Yeah. He likes that. Come on down man.
Yeah, set it up. You know what?
I'll follow up on that. I will do.
All right and tell me when your
show comes out so I could let the,
let the people know. Maybe you
can come back on again when,
whenever it actually,
if you wouldn't mind once they give
me the go ahead because apparently I'm
prescribed, I'm talking about it,
but when they give me the go ahead,
you won't be able to just shut
up. Alright. Just keep talking.
Well thank you Joe. We'll do that. Thank
you sir. Thank you man. Good Times.
All right. Bye Buddy.
Okay.
Fun Time Style, man. Yeah. Thank you, man.