Okay.
Oh fuck yeah,
here we go.
Tony Hinchcliffe lives in the house.
Brian Redman is in the house.
Dun Dun Dun done Dun.
And we've been talking about turning
your come off with a light switch as I
work.
It's like a little switch that's in your
inner leg or something like that.
And if you want to make a baby it turns
on your income or your sperm.
So it's like a sperm switch,
but they made it look like a light
switch instead of having it like some
weird button.
Put it up on the screen again please.
It's so it's in between your legs.
Like what if you're jogging this.
Just go on and off and on and off.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
It is a light switch.
Come on.
This isn't real.
Dare you.
Why am I seeing that guy's Dick?
Huge.
Why is he big?
He semi.
Okay.
Look at this.
All right.
So what they're showing us is,
uh,
can we hear this?
Is it okay?
We're here is combined with seminars
like India.
Hold on,
I love this guy's accent.
Please start from the beginning because
it makes it even better.
He speaks in the slightly broken English
every day.
Andy Richter,
during his brother,
in order to begin the medical approval
procedure,
the human males testicles produce
millions of sperm cells.
Everyday.
These cells flow through the spermatic
ducts and then combined with seminar
related.
It would be so disappointed if he saw
what his technology was being used for.
Thomas Edison invented Dick Switches,
switches,
power on and off.
It's why is it more humorous?
Because this gentleman has an accent
mate.
Why would they spend so much time making
the texture of the balls and the Deq
that realistic?
Because they want you to know they're
not playing games.
So this is insane.
You can feel the switch and you can flip
it back and forth.
That is so fucking crazy.
And what are the odds that a girl who
wants a baby is not going to reach back
and click that switch right while you
were,
while she's rubbing your balls and when
did.
There would be the perfect time to hit
the switch.
If you really wanted to make a baby,
like let them release the hounds and
whenever there'd be comes still on the
tube,
you know,
like they ended the tube like hmm,
good question.
Yeah,
I think that is a,
that's an issue,
right?
Doesn't it like stay inside your decal?
It doesn't all come out one blast and
sometimes it can come out in the next
blast.
Yeah,
that's what do I know?
If it's fake,
that's craziness.
I mean,
I don't understand if you got an
operation to get all that stuff,
put it in,
just get a vasectomy.
Make a decision.
Stand by it.
Yeah.
It seems like in America,
um,
this,
these type of things are becoming more
and more attractive to us.
Like an instant solution to like
anything that we got going wrong.
Oh,
we're going to come up with a new
retinas.
These retinas,
they're artificial retinas.
You put them in your eyes and you could
see 2100 or 20,
uh,
what,
what is,
what's,
that's not good.
Like 2100 and be terrible.
Yeah.
Like 20,
45,
20 slash 20 is normal,
right?
Right.
40,
20.
No,
that's worse too,
right?
Isn't that better?
That's twice.
I don't think it is.
I'm not sure.
I don't think.
I think it's always been like low
numbers are really good.
Like pilots would say I have 20 slash 15
vision.
See an eagle attack assignment from a
mile away.
You know like people were always like
super proud of their vision,
like really good vision.
Like whoa.
Amazing.
You see clearly so lower would be
better.
Like four slash 20 would be the best for
20.
No it's too high on one side.
I don't know what's perfect on one side.
Write 20th,
20 slash 20 slash 20.
Right.
What the fuck does that even stand for?
Maybe we should know that.
What you see at 20 feet,
the first 20 is what normal person sees
at 20 feet and then what you see at 20
feet.
So you see if you have 2100,
you see what a normal person sees at 200
feet or 20 feet because your vision
sucks.
Oh,
okay.
That makes sense.
That actually totally makes sense.
I want to drag.
Yeah.
Do you have good,
perfect vision.
And Tony,
my vision is unbelievable.
I can,
I can read anything from like,
it's like insane.
That's cool.
A lot of fun.
Have you always had that?
He should probably be really good at
something like darts or something like
that.
Maybe.
Yeah,
I would think that something along those
lines where you.
It'd be like super precise.
Like when you're throwing up,
you're like,
I don't play darts,
but I would imagine that it's probably
pretty fun with all that pressure to get
a bowl side.
It seems kind of silly.
He's throwing a metal stick at a thing,
but those dudes seem to be having a good
time.
I'm a hell of a shot.
Is a natural with a dartboard with,
with an actual gun,
with like.
Oh really?
Yeah,
just shot,
like discuss one time.
Is that what it is?
What do they come?
Pigeons.
Pigeons,
clay pigeon.
And I was like 13 or 14 and I was
clipping him and I remember this group
of old guys were standing behind my
mom's boyfriend that took me just like,
Holy Shit,
I'm terrible with the shotgun.
I did Bert Kreischer show.
We had one of those clay shoot off
things.
I hit like one.
How do you get good at a shotgun now you
just practice.
You just have to understand how you're
orientating the um,
the site on it,
it's a little more tricky than like a
hunting rifle or the site is magnified
with a shotgun for the most part,
unless it has a scope on it.
Most of the times they don't,
you're,
you're using the barrel of the gun to
line up where the bullets are going to
go.
But any variation upward down by the
slightest amount results in a big
deviation of the intended path of the
weapon.
So like if you're trying to shoot
straight and your,
your thing is just,
it,
lets kind of add them but not really.
It'll go over his head.
So you have to line up this little thing
in the front which is like a little
tiny,
like a nub and,
and then the thing in the back,
the thing in the back is
the you and you're looking,
you're trying to align the two of them
up.
So there's like this little v and you're
trying to put this pin in between the
Little v and hold it there as you
squeeze the trigger and don't flinch.
So it's,
there's a lot involved in it.
It takes practice.
But once you get,
it's like anything else like archery or
bowling,
you know,
once you understand the technique behind
it,
then it's just a matter of drilling it
over and over again.
Like you ever seen a really good bowler?
Like Ari's friend Tommy.
What is that guy's name?
Tommy Tolo.
And whoa,
what the fuck is this?
He gave me a damage.
He gave me a uh,
sorry.
I already,
you'll find it right,
right.
Uh,
he gave me a really good dude.
Whoever that guy is.
Ballerina,
right?
No,
no,
no.
Tommy.
Jamie.
We'll figure it out.
Let him figure it out.
We'll,
we'll,
we'll talk.
But um,
if he taught you how to bowl,
like if you watch him bowl,
like those guys,
they throw like that curve ball where it
comes spinning and it smashes into
everything,
like had an angle and they can do it
consistently over and over and over and
over again until the point where they'll
bowl like pretty close to perfect games
a lot where they'll get like real close
to making eight,
nine strikes in a row.
And you're like,
what the fuck?
When a guy like you were,
I don't know how you boil.
I bullet shit,
I just shut that fucking thing.
Totally dilutes.
Tommy dilutes great guy by the way.
Super fucking Nice Guy.
He's hung out with us a couple of times
and he's a pro bowler.
So if that guy taught you how to bowl,
like he could teach you the technique,
then it would just be a matter of you
wanting to keep working at it.
Whether it's,
whether it's archery or that's darts or
anything,
man,
it's just a matter of someone showing
you how to do it.
You figured it out what's best for you.
And then numbers.
That's what that's why people don't like
to get good at shit.
The numbers involved or nuts.
If you want to be a professional golfer,
do you know what kind of numbers you
have to put in?
Good Lord all the practice and all the
fucking knock and then he like,
man,
this isn't gonna work out.
Okay.
If you say it's not gonna work out,
but I guess it's not going to work out
because it fucking worked out for tiger
woods.
Fucking worked out for Jack Nicholas.
How come it fucking worked out for them?
Because they got nutty because someone
taught them the technique.
They started to compete and then they
got nutty.
Yeah.
You just got to decide whether or not
you want to get nutty and getting that.
He's not the best idea in the world
either.
A lot of those guys want to fucking
hitting the rocks.
They never stopped at the beach.
Just fucking keep that cast going.
It's like stand up in a lot of ways.
Yeah.
I think it's like everything.
Everything that represents you,
you know,
you focus on it and the more you focus
on it,
the better it gets at it and if you
don't focus on it,
it doesn't get better.
And if you do,
it does.
And it's a matter of how much do you
want to focus on where you can enjoy the
rest of your life.
What,
what percentage of your life does it
become?
It always amazes me that people that get
like so great at video games.
No,
you never.
Did you ever meet Robert?
The dude who was the old
manager at the comedy store.
Um,
what was his job there?
Do you remember?
He was like talent.
Was He booking talent?
I don't know if he was doing that for
awhile.
Maybe he was doing that for awhile
anyway.
Really good magic.
I write magic.
The gathering.
He was addicted to that.
He was addicted to Everquest,
I believe at first.
Maybe it was magic.
The magic.
The gathering is a card game though,
isn't it?
It's also a video game.
It's video again to.
I'm pretty sure he was a everquest
junkie.
Bad Man.
Like bad.
And he would come to the comedy store
and you'd be depressed,
like he would get out of his house when
he could and when he could,
he would come out and hang out with,
with us in the real world.
I'll never forget this.
We were in the back bar and it was just
me and him and uh,
you know,
it was,
uh,
you know,
the back bar here,
we're just,
a lot of times comedians gathered there
and talk and he just goes,
it's just so weird that I can be so good
at making money in my online life and so
bad at it in my real life.
He goes,
I'm so good at being successful in this
artificial life,
but I can't get it together in my real
life.
And he was tired and he looked pale.
And I'm like,
this is a great guy.
He's like a really nice guy.
I'm like,
fuck man.
Like this game is like a vampire.
He was making money on it.
No,
you make money in the game.
Like you may collect gold coins.
He combined magic.
Said I worked by saying that,
right?
Yeah,
sure.
Yeah.
You level up the more he played,
so he was like king of kings,
you know,
he had like a crazy player and
everything like king of King.
Well,
when you get really good right in
everquest,
like the higher you get,
the more you can fuck people up.
He could do whatever you want,
right?
You just become like invincible.
Like,
oh my God,
if you're on that shit 24 hours a day
for 10 years,
no one fuck with you.
They just can't fuck with you.
Isn't that how world of warcraft death?
They're encouraging addiction.
It's so obvious.
They're there.
They're very clever,
but this is a money vampire.
I figured out a really entertaining
money vampire just sucks it out of
south park.
Did one on it and it's just like
unbelievably hilarious.
You know what's interesting?
The concept that you can get better at
it the more time you put in it because
you get more stuff.
Like that's a really weird concept
because that's not how it is in any
other game and in any other game.
What's cool about playing quake?
Right?
I hate to harp on quick all the time,
but I used to love playing it,
um,
was that you both start out like she,
you guys were going to have a death
match.
He was both start out with 150 life
points,
the same amount of access to weapons,
you know,
you have like a little pistol,
like you have a little blaster and then
you run around the map to try to find
where the other weapons are.
So you have to know the map,
you have to know where the weapons are
and when they spawn because the,
they spawn in increments like every 15,
20 seconds or something like,
I forget what it is,
maybe a minute for some weapons,
maybe some weapons spun differently.
So these guys had programs in their code
where it would alert them when,
uh,
the rocket launcher was about spawn.
So they had it timed into their,
their code.
So they would receive little messages up
on their screen that would let them know
that rocket launchers,
we're about to spawn.
So they'd run to get to the rocket
launch because he who gets a rocket
launcher first most likely wins a death
match because these guys know the maps
and they start blasting each other.
Well then they,
everybody starts.
Even everybody starts even it's.
So that's what's exciting about it.
It's a mad scramble if you got to a
point where you could just fog people up
and turn their cities into dust and
bring down fire and brimstone.
That's too much.
And we get.
Everybody's got to be even more your
games bullshit.
He just got a giant addiction thing.
Go.
You got an addiction pyramid scheme
going on,
right?
And you're talking to yourself in third
person as if it wasn't you that did all
this.
Well sort of.
But I'm thinking about Robert because
I'm thinking about the game of everquest
and this is way more addictive element,
like the element of the long you do it,
the more power you have and the more you
can accomplish,
the more dragons you can slay and what
have you.
What I was into was a these crazy
one-on-one death matches.
They were so fun and I,
I was never good at them,
man.
I used to get fucked up.
Like it wasn't a matter of like me being
successful at quake.
It was the opposite.
Like I could never catch up.
I could be able to beat dudes who were
clueless if some dude was clueless and
he got into one of those maps with me,
I could fuck them up,
but most of the time I got fucked up.
Most of the time you're getting fucked
up with these young kids were so good.
They're fucking hand.
Eye Coordination is like,
it's designed through the game because
as they were a bit hesitant were
children.
They're using a mouse and keyboard as
their little brains were forming
connections with their fingertips.
A lot of what it involved moving a
mouse.
Obama,
right.
Does he?
Yeah.
He's like on one of those like halo or
something like that.
What's one of those popular one?
Halos.
Popular Halo is bad.
I think it might be,
but he plays.
It's A.
I always think that that's like so crazy
to think that Obama is.
Sometimes it's just chill and just
getting a lit up by like some seven year
old kid.
You know what I mean?
Obama please.
Titanfall tight xbox one.
It's similar to call of duty.
Right?
So is it a war game?
So you're like running around and you
can jump in a big machines Mac or in the
game like transformers,
robotech.
Wow,
that's wild.
Who would have ever thought that?
So this is like that movie with fucking
a wolverine.
What's his name?
What's the Wolverine Guy's name?
Hugh Jackman.
Mike Australian.
Isn't that amazing?
So hides his accident so.
Well,
it's always weird.
One of those guys talks in a regular
accent.
You're like,
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
Like did you ever watch homeland?
There's a guy named brody who's in
homeland and he plays the dude who was
kidnapped and tortured by the
terrorists.
Then comes back to America and he's
like,
kind of like a,
you know,
he's like acting as a pawn for the
terrorist is like,
it's very far fucking crazy.
But he sounds like a,
like a regular,
almost like a southern American,
like a Texan,
like a slight Texas accent on the show.
And then in real life he talks with like
this crazy English accent and you hear
him talk and you can't believe it's the
same man.
One of my favorite actors right now who
I'm like obsessed with because I saw him
on this show bloodline.
You heard of this show?
Bloodline.
What's bloodline is a netflix original
series that came out like six months ago
and it's basically about like this rich
family that takes a vacation.
They like have this vacation in Hawaii
and they all get together and shit just
goes down with this family and they're
all doing like,
you don't know who's covering up what
and it's just all these diabolical
characters.
Anyway,
there's this guy named Ben Mendelsohn
who is a monster.
He's one of those guys that's just so
compelling to watch.
Like his face is always moving.
He plays like a bad guy in everything
and I watched like six or seven of his
movies going back and they're all
amazing.
It's one of these like real actors and
then I found out that he's just
Australian,
but complete Australian dude,
total Australian accent,
and he was my favorite American actor up
until I found out he's from Australia.
There's a lot of killer actors from
Australia.
Russell Crowe's from Australia,
right?
Isn't it?
Yeah.
That guy there.
That's monster.
How many
fucking Australian accents?
Mel Gibson.
Australian.
Thank you.
How many of those guys?
What's Tom Hardy?
English.
Tom Hardy's a bad ass.
He's a bad motherfucker.
Just so many of them from over there.
It's incredible.
Sometimes I don't even realize I was
watching a Tom Hardy movie until the end
of the movie and his name comes up and
I'm like,
who was Tom Hart?
Oh my God.
He was the main character the whole
time.
Like he has some.
He's another one.
One of the only other guides.
It's funny,
bring him up because he's another one
where I literally will look up their
name in Vr because you can.
Some of these guys,
you can actually read the scripts and
pick the things that they want to do.
Well,
he can at this point,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He's a bad motherfucker.
That guy can act his ass off.
It's sometimes he's like a ripped
monster,
like in Mad Max and then sometimes he's
built like me in these movies and it's
like,
how the hell like he,
he's one of those guys that cuts weight
and puts it on and really gets into
character.
He plays a,
I can't remember the name of it,
but one of these things,
he's,
he's a twin,
so he's playing the two lead characters
because he's,
it's him and his twin the entire time
playing the,
uh,
the Kray brothers right there.
Remember that movie?
The craze that was out a long time ago.
It was basically on the same brothers,
two brothers who were into organized
crime in England.
They're legendary and he's playing both
of them.
The last time they did,
I think they had two actual twins in the
last version of it,
which is probably they had to,
for whatever actors they could get that
we're twins.
Tom Hardy's one of these guys that I
didn't even know about until my
girlfriend who's like a huge movie buff,
kept showing me movies like,
and she's,
she would always talk about like how hot
he is and this,
and she's just like,
this guy's fucking amazing and I'm like,
you're just making me watch these Tom
Hardy movies because you have a crush on
him.
And sure enough,
this fucker won me over like big time.
That's really no,
he's good.
Right?
So where you're like,
oh,
you know what?
It's fucking great man.
Fuck it.
Fuck
my girlfriend.
How many guys do you think have ever
played themselves in a movie like side
by side?
Like twins,
like that.
So you're playing like,
what I want to know is does he get paid
double for that?
Is that all done?
That only seems fair,
right?
Well,
he's got to be getting a shitload of
money for this because that's half of
the movie is seeing if they can pull
that off.
Right?
Because you're dealing with
Agi.
They're combining somehow or another.
I don't know how they're doing it.
I would imagine what they can do now,
this is just my guess is that you can
get a guy like you and you and Brian
could have like a tussle and as long as
you wear the same size,
you could superimpose his features on
you.
There's a way they could do that with
CGI.
Well,
what's interesting is that if the camera
was locked off than up until,
I'm sure this movie,
it's not locked off on everything.
What does that mean?
Locked off completely.
Not moving stabilized then it was always
easier to do that.
I think,
you know,
the CGI type of things where you can put
somebody into things,
but this is like a real movie with real
dialogue.
I don't think that.
I think they're doing it all with
computers.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
I think that if.
But he's got to act both sides of it.
Right?
So he's got to somehow or another act
both sides of it and he has to.
I mean,
I'm only assuming he,
he's physically in contact with someone.
They would have to somehow or another
get him to act out those scenes and
replace his face on the other person's
body or something.
Well,
they just did like,
if they're doing a tussle,
they're just doing the thing where like,
you know,
it's just the back of the head and then
they just flip,
you know,
when they're wrong around where it's
like a smaller,
weird,
creepy version of them that I did it
with,
that Pepsi Spice Commercial where I just
pretty much recorded the same two things
and then just split right down the
middle.
That's right.
I forgot about this.
This was like 15 years ago I did this.
Yeah.
These are hilarious myself.
This looks exactly like the commercial
for that.
Tom was talking about.
This is hilarious.
I forgot about that this morning and it.
Look,
I even put that in the Coffee Cup and
then I grabbed the coffee cup.
Look at that.
Boom.
That's actually cool.
Dude.
That was one of your finest,
finest hours.
The Pepsi Spice Days,
and I did that on paintbrush,
but what would you do if you had to have
like a confrontation?
Does he have a confrontation with his
brother?
I'm assuming he does.
Probably.
That's the only thing that I would think
would be the issue.
It was like you fighting with you
because that'd be really hard to mesh
together,
but otherwise if it's just you in a
separate scene,
are you in a scene with two of you?
Is You just have to do the scene twice?
It's still.
They have to combine it.
If you have to do one and then probably
they play back your thing when you're
talking to it.
Put shut.
God.
You ever seen Bronson?
Yes.
Amazing.
Yeah.
I saw that.
He was really good in that he's giving
everything.
He's just one of those guys.
He just knows how to just knows how to
do it.
Yeah.
It's a weird type of um,
like a respect we have for people also
that come from other countries.
Mean Americans love Americans,
but we also hold people from other
countries.
Have you have an English accent?
Will cut.
You all lost.
My God,
we love slack.
No
major raise.
It's everybody.
Everybody everywhere.
There's British accents everywhere,
everywhere,
every show.
Because I only watch normal TV when I'm
at a hotel and I've been doing the road
a lot lately,
so I've been stuck watching commercials
for the first time anyway.
Every I watched world problems.
I watched this James Corden or whatever
they've been.
Yeah,
he was in.
He's the guy that just took over for
Craig Ferguson.
Oh,
what's also had an accent.
Everybody has an accent now on
everything.
Don't you think?
Craig Ferguson was good though.
I liked Craig Ferguson.
He was really good.
Totally good.
He brought a different element when it
was the Brittany spears thing when that
Brittany spears thing was going on and
she was shaving her head and he was
like,
why aren't we doing this?
Like why?
Why would we like attack this girl?
And I think in a lot of ways like his,
like sort of reasonable approach to
addressing the subject instead of like
cracking jokes about it when it was like
she was shaving her head and just like
you're,
you're looking at a person that's having
some,
some serious stress and mental problems
probably.
And all we're doing is just piling onto
that.
And he made this like really reasonable
measured plea and I remember thinking
like,
wow,
that was a genuine thing.
Like that wasn't a,
that didn't seem like some of fake
pumped up pr move to try to get people
to view him a different way.
It seemed very genuine.
And um,
unfortunately Brittany spears wasn't
watching Craig Ferguson messages never
got throats.
You know,
people did leave her alone.
They kind of leave her alone now.
But she was obviously having some sort
of a breakdown.
Yeah,
she was something going on.
There was,
she was.
And I don't know if anybody could ever
be expected to respond well to the kind
of stress that someone in her position
and doors.
She's like some stupid,
crazy superstar,
like a beyonce type character or Jamesy
like that of stress.
Level's
got to be insane.
She's calmed down a lot.
Right?
She does that thing in Vegas now.
She does like a vegas show.
Did you,
were you a fan of Craig Ferguson show?
He's good.
Do you know the robot?
The Guy,
the guy that played the robot in his
name is Josh,
Robert Thompson.
And he played the robot for whatever,
11 years on that show or however long
the show is,
he kinda got screwed by the show because
no one knows who he was.
They never said,
hey,
by the way,
this is him.
So this guy,
he's on periscope all the time.
Really interesting guy.
A check him out.
He's just really,
it's really sad though as names Josh,
Robert Thompson.
And it's just like imagine being on a
fucking tonight show or no one knew who
you were the whole time.
So does he just complain about this on
it's Paris.
He does seem like he's always getting
screwed.
Like he made.
He just released this new video the
other day with George Lucas and it has
her friend,
uh,
what's the guy with the really built
body?
Uh,
uh,
that used to be a writer on that show.
He's been on killed Tony before.
Fuck,
I can't really good body member.
He always takes off his shirt and like a
six pack of.
Oh,
Bob.
Yeah.
So bob did a video with a.
never thought you were talking about Bob
Osha Gay porn star that's infiltrated
the comments,
preparing myself for future encounters.
Like why is this is what Brian considers
a guy with a good body pop.
You see Tommy,
he's very fit.
He might be the nicest guy that's ever
lived.
Totally.
If he's not the nicest,
he's in the top 10 of the nicest people
of all time.
I love him.
Nah,
but anyway,
he made a video with Josh.
Robert Thompson where they.
Josh,
Robert Thompson Played George Lucas
after you on his ranch and he looks just
like a George Lucas.
Wow.
Fun Little.
Oh yeah.
I think I saw some of that.
Yeah,
Dude.
Dude,
he's a funny fucking guy.
Bob Osha.
I love him.
One of the best.
He should be doing a podcast.
I think
I was supposed to start mine with him.
He was going to be my cohost and then I
decided not to have a cohort.
It's that the last time he also really
busy.
You don't.
It's not like you have 52 different
things you have to do all day long.
You could do another podcast once a week
with him.
Yeah.
I said great guy to where he could do
one on his own is one of the great guy.
He's such a good dude and kill Tony
Sharp.
Such a.
He just loves joke writing so much does
and so when these guys come in with a
premise or whatever,
he'll just go,
you know,
if you go Bah,
Bah,
Bah Bah and band the crowd that already
heard that premise and punchline,
but it's all restructured.
He just repeats it back because he has
that math brain.
It's just like dit dit,
dit,
one of the notoriously like one of the
most respected comedy writers around
town and the and the writing gigs that
I've done.
He's come up in every writer's room and
everybody around the table
that are working together always ends up
talking about where and when they worked
with Bob [inaudible] and how cool and
nice he is.
That's awesome.
That's so good to hear.
Always a good say.
Good stomach back.
Always organically.
Not Mcguire stomach.
I'm using mcguire.
It's mcguire who?
Chris Mcguire.
Oh Chris Mcguire.
STOIC,
how's that?
I've never seen Chris.
He's a normal guy.
The only one I ever seen Chris Mcguire,
stomach reference like that might be the
most difficult to put your head around
because if you don't know Chris Mcguire,
funny,
standup comedian.
He's not.
He doesn't have like an unusual stomach.
It's normal stuff.
He looks like a normal guy.
If he's standing there,
it's stupid to be sure that that was
his.
Like if you had like if you saw joey
Diaz,
his stomach and like a side view you
like,
yeah,
that looks like.
Well,
right.
That's about joey.
If you saw silhouette and someone said
whose stomach is that?
He wouldn't go.
Tony Hinchcliffe know.
But Chris Mcguire.
Fuck man.
It can be.
It can be Jamie.
We,
Chris Mcguire.
Now I want to know now.
I want to see it.
I wish he'd
let me see.
Yeah,
he's um,
he's a great guy to Christopher Dwyer,
him,
Greg Fitzsimmons and I started out like
within a week of each other.
That's so crazy.
It's interesting.
All these years later,
I have that same thing with a few guys
and it's amazing because there's
definitely like a special bond that
happens when,
you know,
this started around the same time.
Yeah,
for sure.
You hadn't,
you'd known each other through the whole
process of being fucking horrible,
totally incompetent,
but just starry eyed for the,
the idea of being a comic and chasing
these dreams together and there's
nothing more fun than when you see one
of those guys doing something cool,
you know.
But it's cool to see in comics do
something cool.
And we all been talking about this at
the store lately that this is one of the
things about this generation and this,
uh,
this era as it were,
is that a good thing to say this era of
comedy,
but this time is that people like comics
are real supportive of each other and I
don't think that ever existed before.
There wasn't like a bunch of comics
promoting each other on shows like the
way people are now.
It didn't really exist before because
there were so few spots.
Like if you got on tv,
you had a coveted,
you had it,
this is mine,
it was like this famine mentality,
but now that a lot of what we're doing
is internet driven,
whether it's your Netflix special
which comes out this Friday,
January eight,
18th,
January,
fifth,
15th,
one shot.
It's available this Friday.
Whether it's stuff like that which is
Internet based in which is almost all of
the fucking specials that you're hearing
about now,
are these Internet based specials and
television shows that are Internet
based.
I mean Netflix is just.
They have so much fucking programming
now.
There's so many different things that
you can watch that are Internet based,
but I think comics have,
like most of us have gotten to podcast a
giant amount of
us and he realized like this is way more
fun and way easier to do than a
television show.
And through that everybody says you
should do it too and you should do it
too.
And they all do it together and he
developed this weird network and this is
like a network of supporters.
So I think when we all see someone who's
doing really good,
you know,
it's uh,
it's interesting.
It's interesting to watch like,
Ooh,
it's happening again.
Yeah.
You know,
it's amazing.
Brian,
your new podcast was the top 15.
Yeah,
it got down to seven.
Really?
Yeah.
That's amazing.
St Francis.
It's really amazing.
We had among the second episode it
awesome.
Dude.
I'm so glad you decided to do it too
because you know,
you have a very unusual sense of humor
that a lot of people like.
It's like trying to find the right
vehicle for it.
It's like,
I think the right vehicle for you is
just do your own thing,
do your own thing,
and when you do do it,
it's a,
it's fucking fun because you get to be
free.
You get to be,
you know,
you're just such a silly Weirdo
and I'm trying to lose 40 pounds in
three months.
The first three months of the episodes I
weigh in every episode and today I
weighed in a 14 pounds less since
January first.
Wow.
That's awesome.
I love doing these with you too.
I mean,
it's always fun.
We always have a good time.
It's always silly,
but I'm really glad you're doing your
own as well because I think that it's
going to be.
I think it's got to be real successful.
It's going to be.
It's,
it's all,
it's,
it's something that you can pursue and
like you could say,
I want to talk to this interesting
person.
I want to talk to this cool guy,
like maybe I can get him on my podcast
and then all of a sudden you get them
and you're sitting there talking to this
person and as a Pir,
as a human being,
like if you're allowed to pursue your
interests like that.
It's very enriching and I think what the
audience gets out of it.
That's such a fucking pompous word,
but that is what it's like.
It's like enriching and what the
audience gets out of it.
It's like they get to go on this like
really cool adventure with you and some
of the best aspects of the adventure,
like having conversations with these
cool and funny and interesting people.
They get to be in on them.
They get to sit there and be a part of
like your little adventure through
choosing your interests and so that's
what I think everybody should have every
like comic who has any interest in
whatsoever should have a podcast because
you get to see them go down there a
little.
The adventure of their interests,
you know,
like if you listen to bill birth
podcast,
like I don't pay attention to football,
so the only part I can't listen to it
when he started talking about football
and they should've done this and the
defense was that I'd done because he's a
football fanatic,
but the rest of it is just bill talking
about how he's living his life and how
he's going through his life.
And it's really interesting.
It's really interesting to follow
someone follow their interests.
Follow like what make,
what's,
what's curious to them.
Like when you don't have any other
agenda like in your agenda isn't man
what we need to get good ratings.
We're going to need to get some people
in here that are doing some things that
people are aware of.
Which is how you think of like every
other talk show,
right?
They all become almost generic in a way
because even like letterman who was like
fiercely independent and very smart and
just overly critical of like shitty
stuff and a smart guy like didn't like
his own stuff.
Half the time he would do his own show
and it would be brilliant and he'd be
like,
fuck,
I hate myself that he was crazy like
that.
Right.
That was like the thing about Letterman,
but who would he have on his show?
He's like regular people,
man who sell on a fucking movie,
who selling a song,
who selling to this,
who's got a TV show and it does the same
thing.
And so David have humorous or a
conversation with these people and say
funny stuff,
but the bottom line is that's not who he
chooses.
That's not what he wants to do.
Right?
If he,
if you could say,
all cost aside,
all consideration of ratings aside,
who would you want to talk to Dave?
Then you would get a chance to see,
but the way the system is set up,
even though it's a fantastic system,
if it works out and you get something
like the Jimmy Fallon tonight show,
which I think is excellent,
I think Jimmy Fallon's the best tonight
show guy ever.
I have a showcase for it tonight.
I think he's the best.
He's fucking great.
I can't talk about anything that I've
been working on and that's what's funny
though.
I have this brand new,
a 15 minute chunk that I'm just in love
with right now,
like it's just expanding and breathing
and I'm talking about crazy,
crazy shit,
but I thought I was thinking about it on
the way here because I just got the
call.
My manager is like,
Hey,
are you available to do a tonight show
showcase tonight?
And I'm literally like,
yeah,
heck yeah blah,
blah blah.
And I'd get off the phone and I start
thinking about everything I've been
working out and I know for a fact I
can't do any of it.
Not a single bit.
That sucks.
Yeah.
You get these new weapons.
Oh yeah.
And they're right there and I know I
would kill harder than anybody else on
this.
I don't even know who's on it,
but I just know like how I feel about my
material right now is like I'm in like
championship mode.
And uh,
with this new stuff though,
that's what's crazy is I'm going to have
to really figure out and fanangle
thank [inaudible].
Well let's look at it this way.
But think of the tonight show with no
censorship.
Think of the tonight show on Netflix.
Lead with that show.
But totally.
How good would that show be if someone
like Jamie Foxx could go on and sit next
to the couch and say whatever the fuck
you want,
you know,
someone like Mike Tyson swearing,
you know some.
Why don't I go with two black people.
I love your Jamie Foxx.
Love.
I love that guy.
I think Jamie Foxx is amazing.
If you heard his interview with Tim
Ferriss,
you would,
you would look at him in a different
life.
Like I've always thought he's insanely
talented.
I like the fact that he could play Ray
Charles and then he played that.
I'm the guy with mental illness that was
a homeless guy who was a musician and
the Robert Downey jr movie,
and he can act his fucking ass
and he's singing in Django unchained.
I mean,
unbelievable.
When you,
uh,
you listened to his,
the way he talks to tim first,
you kind of get an understanding of why
he's the way he is.
Just a bad motherfucker.
Just a super talented,
super,
super sharp thinking.
Dude.
Interesting.
I love that guys like that exist.
You know,
like,
do,
you don't necessarily want to do what
they're doing,
but just knowing that there's people
like that that exists,
you're like,
wow,
yeah,
real rock stars,
redos or just they're operating on a
fucking super high level with a lot of
different things.
Like Jamie Foxx can sing his ass off.
Like he's saying,
he's a really good,
totally insane.
Like he could have,
he could just do,
he could do any one of those careers
regularly.
I know it's interesting,
right?
It's interesting.
He,
I don't know how much standup he does
anymore though.
I don't know.
I think he got to doing too many
different things.
Standups.
Definitely one of those things where
you've got to be doing just that.
Yeah.
Got To work at.
If you're not doing it,
if you're not doing it all the time,
boy,
it gets slippery,
Huh?
Yeah.
I just took a four nights off in a row
for the first time in forever.
Four nights in a row.
I should feel.
I have felt.
I came back.
Shay was reinvigorating.
Animalistic.
I just saw last night was my first spot
and four nights and I'm just standing in
the back of the room with just fucking
like.
I was like,
I'm crazy.
You know what I mean?
I just love crazy.
You're so silly or crazy,
but literally like I go up there and uh,
it was at the Irvine Improv.
It was insane.
This lady stood up during my set at one
point because I'm talking about this one
part of one thing where I talk about how
trump's going on win this shit and
here's why.
You know what I mean?
And,
and basically like this lady stands up
and you can tell that I'm a comedian on
a stage and everybody else could.
But this one lady out of 200 stands up
and starts waving her arms and she's
like,
stop,
stop.
I'm like,
Oh shit.
But I'm still like staying in the
pocket.
Go on with the joke.
But for another like 10 seconds.
But she's still like,
stop,
stop.
And it's.
My jokes were killing so I'm like,
you motherfucker.
So I bailed out and I go,
what the fuck is your problem,
lady?
What is the what?
What's going on?
She's like,
Donald trump will never be our
president.
Oh my God.
What makes your opinion so big that
you're talking?
And none of these other 200 people are
yelling right now.
I go,
what the fuck makes sure vote such a big
deal.
What do you do for a living?
And she goes,
well basically I'm A.
I go,
what the fuck do you do for a living?
Crowd's going crazy.
She goes,
well,
right now I'm unemployed.
I go,
then your vote doesn't even fucking that
art.
You're not even paying taxes.
Wow is this whole crazy thing?
But she ended up leaving.
Of course you should have been kicked
out because I'm going to end up in
interrupt a bit in the middle of the
bed.
You stand up at a movie and say,
don't kill a solo.
You don't do it right.
You don't do it.
It's so stupid.
Stupid.
She was flipping me off.
It was so great.
I was just destroying her entire long
walk out of the Irvine Improv.
It's a long walk too.
Yeah,
Dude.
Come on.
So much fun.
People to stop.
Hecklers need to fucking just not ever
go see shows.
They need to stop Ron Guy.
When you make that our drive to Irvine,
it's just.
They don't know man.
I think people just don't know how
ridiculous it is.
You know?
You just don't think they realize that
it's you're in the middle of this piece
and this piece is a lot of places that
it has to go to.
You have to go left and you have to go
right and you have to trick them a
little bit and then you bring it home at
the end and this woman is like in the
middle of this thing screaming out and
it's interesting because I'm,
I never,
and I've tried here and there with jokes
over,
you know,
the eight years of doing this,
but I'm never really a a political guy,
but with this new election thing that
I'm doing right now,
I feel really good about it,
but it's amazing how the different
reactions that you get around the
country doing this dust is a charged
subject.
It's a charged subject in a weird time.
This is probably the weirdest selection
ever because this is the only election I
can ever remember where there's only one
candidate that his supporters are really
fucking excited about them.
And then there's a bunch of other people
that you're like,
man,
I don't know.
I mean like Bernie Sanders seems like a
really Nice Guy,
you know?
I mean,
he doesn't seem evil at all.
Right?
I mean,
maybe he's the best of all the choices
available except for people make money.
I'd love it if you got in.
I'd love it if he just interesting won
the election.
It was just like,
oh,
I was just fucking with you guys the
whole time.
I'm a,
I'm an old white man.
Go fuck yourselves.
Back to the old system,
you know?
Well,
I don't think he would survive.
I mean,
he already looks like he's done a few
terms,
you know what I mean?
Like does,
right.
All these other presidents go in there
looking good,
you know,
dark brown hair and then they all come
out looking like,
like,
uh,
what's his name?
But not who we're talking about Obama.
Look at Obama.
We,
we've,
we've shown side by side images of him
from 2009 to 2015.
It's crazy.
He looks like he's aged like 20 plus
years.
Yeah,
easily.
It's hard job,
man.
I don't think anybody can do it.
I think at one point in time we're going
to realize that the idea that we keep
clinging to have a single guy that's in
charge of the whole country is stupid.
It doesn't make any sense.
Like why would you have one person be in
charge of anything?
Why don't have like a giant,
gigantic team of people and why not have
the influence of the public a daily
basis be tuned into this gigantic group
of people with,
of course reasonable filters for
hysterics when something crazy happens
and all of a sudden people want to nuke,
you know,
some country or something like that
system to change.
What's amazing is like,
I think that we would have to have
basically a trump as a president for
people to really have a discussion over
four years about how things have to
change because of,
you know,
it depends on how he does at the same
time.
Well,
there's some of the things he says like,
I actually can,
like the other day,
I don't know,
I was just walking out of a hotel and
the news was on the TV and it says,
you know,
trump says that Germany terrorist
attacks or because they let those people
in.
That's all that I saw at first.
I'm like,
yeah,
what an idiotic thing to say.
And then I thought about it and it's
like,
well,
they did let what,
like a million people in or something
crazy.
Well,
there's a real issue in Germany.
Yeah,
and the mayor of Cologne,
which is in this insane move was telling
women how they should behave around
these men and that they should stay
within arm's length.
It's fucking crazy.
It's victim blaming.
I mean they're resorting to victim
blaming to try to take focus away from
the fact that what they've done is
they've led in a bunch of people from
another culture who behave differently.
It's maybe not their fault.
Maybe let's look at it this way.
This is the way they lived in their
other country.
They're coming into your country.
They're going to behave the way they've
behaved all 37 years of their life
because that's what they do,
and so now you have to deal with that in
your culture and the way to deal with is
not to say women should fucking stay
arms length away from these people is to
educate these people about the rules of
this place.
You can't do that.
You can't just sexually assault women.
They're going to get drunk.
Girls could dress however the fuck they
want and you can't tell those girls.
Now you're on your own.
You just have to stay arms length away
from somebody.
You can't because everybody's so scared
of being racist.
Everybody's so scared of being
Islamophobic that they don't want to
point out the forget about ideologies or
forget about skin color,
people of origin.
You have some people that are doing
something that's not good to some people
that haven't had these things done to
them like this before.
You got to figure out what to do.
You got you let in a different culture.
It's not,
it's not their fault,
but it is.
It is what it is.
You know what?
I'm saying,
I mean,
it's not,
you can't deny that it exists.
It is,
it is a thing,
and there's a lot of people,
uh,
that were pointing to,
they're pointing to letting people like
that in this country and they're saying,
well,
you know,
what are we going to do?
What are we going to do?
Have Syrian refugees coming to America?
I was just gonna invite a million Syrian
refugees in America.
And if you look at the history of
America,
that's what people have always done.
We've always led in.
People from other countries are trying
to get away.
I mean,
that's how this country got founded.
So ideally we'd all want to say,
yeah,
these are the people that are running
away from the people that are doing
terrible things to them,
but you're going to get some shitheads
who definitely going to get some
shitheads.
So how do you deal with that?
That's a good question.
I don't think that's a question for one
person.
I mean,
even in one person at a cabinet and when
one person has veto power and what man,
I think there
should be.
I fucking team of phds and Super Smart
motherfuckers with who get evaluated on
a regular basis for ego problems,
alcoholism,
all of the above.
I mean,
you should have,
if you're testing mixed martial arts
fighter to see if they're on steroids,
you should be testing congressmen and
senators.
See if they're fucking crazy.
Right?
See if the what?
What are they on?
You know,
what kind of fucking antidepressants are
you on?
It's affecting your judgment.
What you know.
How often do you take volume?
How often do you take ambien to go to
sleep?
What do you.
What happens?
You lose a sleep cycle there.
Something.
Is there some wacky non sleep that's
going on when your ambient out of your
head?
Oh yeah.
Viagara these congressmen.
What are they doing with all the blood
rushing down and we'll be doing with
them whenever tony making their wieners
bigger.
Sure.
Yeah.
I think,
yeah.
Congressmen and Senators and
representatives.
State representatives is a
representative government.
It's all a pot.
Weird popularity contests like Arnold
Schwarzenegger was.
The governor like that doesn't make any
sense,
but it does.
He's a fiscal conservative guy who's
open minded in a sense of like socially
open minded like as in terms of how he
views a gay people and and even
recreational drug use and things along
those lines is a very open minded almost
like with a libertarian bent but a
Republican,
so it actually wasn't a bad choice.
It didn't do a great job,
but guess what,
if you're dealing with a bunch a shit,
a bunch of red tape and bullshit and if
you ever hear him describe his time in
office,
it's pretty interesting stuff like you
don't realize,
I think from the outside like some like
Uri have zero political aspirations or
motivations or once you get in man,
you're dealing with this insane system
of like how things get done and how
people will filibuster and people will
block this because it'll anger their
constituents because these people are
paying for that and these people are
paying you to make sure that this
doesn't pass through because that'll get
that through watch house of cards.
Yeah.
I just started.
Oh my God.
That's my favorite thing.
I don't know how accurate it is,
but if it's even fucking 10 percent,
we're doing fact.
Ten percent.
It's a great show though.
Kevin Spacey is a bad motherfucker.
I love it when he looks at the camera
and just starts talking.
He's another one.
He's a different guy in this.
He's a different guy in the show with a
very distinct accent and you buy it.
You're not going like,
that's Kevin Spacey,
right?
It's.
He just becomes.
That person becomes another person.
Frank Underwood.
What's going on with that shirt?
Brian?
What is that?
Right?
Oh,
the security guard shirt.
Is that what it is?
Thrift stores.
It's funny when I wear it because I went
to starbucks and Mexicans gave me double
looks real quick.
It was pretty funny how rude.
That's so racist,
but it happened twice.
Today.
Happened twice
when.
Why is it that they chose a blue color
with like a dark blue pocket thing for
security.
That's universal.
It looks like he got his badge ripped
off of them and because it's maybe did
it himself when he quit.
Fuck this job.
Yeah,
that's what you want to do when you quit
the sheriff's department.
Right.
Pull that star off and you throw it on
the ground.
I've done.
You've watched making a murderer,
right?
I have not watched waking.
Wow.
I know.
I keep hearing that.
Wow.
I watched soaked in bleach.
That's good.
Yeah.
Drop it.
You think about that soaked in bleach.
Um,
there's a lot in that movie,
man.
It's the movie that alleges that
Courtney Love was involved in some way
and Kurt cobain's death.
Too Long of a movie.
But yeah,
it's too long.
If you watch the other movie and then
watch that movie each other.
Moving to the,
the official one with his daughter made
Francis.
What is it called again?
Montage.
Montage of heck yeah,
that's the HBO one.
Right,
right,
right.
That's,
that seems more like closer to what I
think really happened,
you know,
I didn't even see that drugs and it
doesn't make it look like he's
murdering.
It just looks like he wanted to kill
himself the whole time.
And he put it in his lyrics.
He wrote about it.
He,
he was,
you know,
it was like it was going to happen.
I mean that's what that movie made it
seem more like it's so hard to decipher
when someone's gone,
what they were,
what they actually thought and what they
actually were like.
Because when you put it through the
filter of what we know about how we
describe other people,
it might be off about something or how
people describe the past and they try to
idealize certain aspects of it.
Like if it was made by his daughter,
she wasn't alive when he was doing that.
So she's getting it from other people
who were there who,
you know,
he's getting it from her own,
his own journalistic music and
journalism has a whole movies and it has
everything in it like that.
It's pretty much,
I believe that montage of heck is like a
documentary about Kurt cobain and soaked
in bleach is a documentary about the
possibility of Courtney and I'll tell
you this,
is that no matter what happened,
it's unbelievable how bad the Seattle
Police Department dropped the ball on
that to walk in on some guy just killed
himself.
That's worth,
God only knows what I mean.
I don't even know if they say during
that,
but you know,
his collection has to be worth at least
$100,
million dollars or something crazy.
Well,
it was just a.
A bad police department.
Yeah.
It was just what it was is a high
profile case in a bad police department,
but now imagine that they had probably
been running that police department in a
shitty way for as long as that guy had
been running it because as long as
you're a regular person that doesn't
have the public's eye paying attention
to the case with extreme scrutiny.
And again,
this was in 1994,
right.
You know,
today it would be a different animal
today.
It would be in social media and it would
blow up,
but it'd be gigantic.
It'd be way more scrutiny,
but back then they can kind of
consolidate
everything.
They can compartmentalize everything and
they just shifted the whole thing up.
They did their fucking.
Their accounts different from the first
responders accounts,
their description of the room deferred.
There's so much of it that was off.
It was that they are,
they're terrible,
and it was just,
they had never done a high profile case,
so they're,
they're terrible police work hadn't been
revealed to anybody that wasn't like the
victim of it.
You know,
someone who who.
I mean,
I'm assuming that if they fucked up this
case,
he probably fucked up other ones as
well.
You're going to shit yourself when you
watch this show,
man.
You should just cut all the shows off
right now and just watch the first
episode and you will making a murderer.
Yeah,
you will go crazy.
You'll,
you will,
you'll have podcasts.
Scared,
scared to dive deep into this fucking
guy's poor guy's life.
It's crazy.
It's unbelievable.
Amen.
Police officers or people.
That's it.
There's going to be real good ones and
bad ones.
There's no,
no doubt about it.
And just because you get through the
fucking academy tasks and get into the,
uh,
the position,
that doesn't mean you've got your shit
together or you're worthy.
It just means you didn't fuck up yet.
And just because you're a cop doesn't
mean you're a bad person.
There's a lot of cops that are fucking
awesome,
they're great people,
and that's a job that they think is
important.
It's a job that they think is very
beneficial to our society and they do it
the best they can and those people are
important.
Those people were the ones that get
overlooked and when you see terrible
cops doing terrible things terrible.
When you see terrible people doing
terrible things,
do you give up on people?
Do you say,
fuck man,
I hate people.
Now.
Some guy just stomped a kitten to death
on a youtube video.
I hate people.
I can't.
I fucking.
I don't want to talk to anybody anymore.
That's ridiculous because most of us
would never do that and I think that's
the same thing with cops.
There's a lot of fucking cops and
they're dealing with a lot of
interactions every day,
every day,
all day long.
You're dealing with people stealing
things,
people doing things to people and people
who might do things to you and they're
fucking.
They're just overwhelmed with stress all
the time.
Especially now that the media is coming
hard.
God Bad.
I just spent a couple of days on a top
secret project,
but with cops and uh,
it is,
I learned so much.
You learn a lot immediately about the
current perception,
like,
you know,
they're very,
defensive and it's,
it's incredible to watch.
But like,
so it got me more into like I've been
watching a lot of these police shootings
and things.
There's not many where,
you know,
if you're going for a gun or if you have
your hand in your pocket and they're
like,
take your hand out of your pocket,
you have to take your hand out of your
pocket.
I don't,
I don't have any sympathy for anyone who
doesn't do that immediately.
And I get it.
There's like mental health issues and
stuff and I think that's the exception
to it.
And yeah,
sometimes it's totally,
like you said,
incident to incident,
but the media really,
really messed up the cops.
Man.
Everybody's on edge with them right now.
Well,
how can you see the media mess them up
when there's all these videos of cops
shooting people for no doing terrible
shit.
Like planting evidence that God throws
the Taser down when he shoots that guy
who's running away from them.
There's a lot of really hardcore video
evidence of cops doing terrible things.
I think they just have to look at it in
a balanced perspective.
The media is not doing anything wrong by
reporting these things.
They're making those cops accountable,
but I think what we have to be really
careful as blaming all cops.
Exactly,
and that's where it's fun to fats were
like the media makes it a little bit
blander than just the specific guy that
they use the word police instead of
officer Blah Blah Blah.
Well,
how about this?
Like if you.
If you saw something and you saw a cop
like on a youtube video,
do something.
You did something terrible.
When you see another cop,
that guy,
you're not in the same city.
You don't even know this guy.
This guy is just a person.
You don't.
You don't make him responsible for
something that some guy did in North
Carolina,
but kind of people do kind of.
People do.
If you go and watch some youtube video
of some cop doing some horrible shit and
the Oakland subway and then all the
sudden you're in downtown La and some
cop looks at you funny like fucking pig,
you know,
like you hate that guy because of
something that someone else did that's
in his organization that he most likely
has never met in his life.
Imagine if we did that with people.
Imagine if some person did something
fucked up in New York and you're down in
Florida and you're like,
fucking piece of shit and this guy's
like,
what are you talking about?
I know what you are,
man.
You're a fucking person.
You're a regular dude.
The deq and you.
I know what that guy did in New York and
you're just like him.
Like was one cop told me,
you know,
like a kid ran up to him the other day,
like he's walking down a sidewalk or
Sarah or whatever,
donut shop or somewhere and a little kid
walks up and is like,
Hey,
hi Mr. Officer.
Like a little like,
you know,
three or four year old and some lady
walks over and she's,
she grabs her little boy and it's like,
no,
you stay away from these murders like
that and had an in depth talk with this
police officer and it's like not only is
that terrible that they're being called
a murder,
but imagine the feeling of knowing that
that's the next generation and that's
the type of,
you know,
things that they're being taught about
police officers right now.
I think that there's two ways I look at
it.
I think in one way I look at it that the
police are necessary and we need police
because we have too much crime and we
have too much violence and it's just,
it's the way it is now.
It's like there are shield that protects
us from bad people,
but another part of me looks at it and
says that
the dynamic of a person in control with
ultimate lethal power and then everyone
else around them is a bad dynamic.
It's not an.
It's the dynamic in and of itself can
create conflict because there's always
going to be resistance to this idea of
someone who lives amongst you who has
ultimate power over you and who.
If the chips go down the wrong way,
they might shoot you and kill you and
they can away with that
and they could say you attack them,
or you were reaching for something they
thought was a gun.
Who knows what kind of personal vendetta
that they might have against you?
Who knows what kind of stress that they
might have been under when they pulled
the trigger,
but they could do to you.
They're allowed to have a gun on them
and you you can't.
Even.
If you're a guy who's never done
anything wrong and you're walking
around,
you're going to feel weird around cops
like you.
You'll maybe you respect them
intellectually.
You'll say,
thank you for your service.
I appreciate everything you guys are
doing.
Stay safe,
but in the back of your head you fucking
know that if things got ugly,
they could shoot you.
Like if somehow or another you got in an
altercation with them,
you,
you go towards them and you're in
somehow or another way threatening or
physical,
they'll gun you down.
You know the gun,
your dog down.
If your dog starts running at them at
barking,
we've seen videos of that adrenaline
and that really just puts a blanket on
your head that's like when you say,
when people say,
get your hand out of your pocket,
man,
that guy's adrenaline's overtaken his
body to the point he doesn't understand
words.
Man,
I got robbed.
I had no idea what was going on.
Exactly.
That's a real good point.
Really good point.
As far as the people they pull over when
you get a
dude,
I got to the.
Yeah,
and I,
I feel like I'm shady when the cop comes
up and I was like,
nothing even going.
You know what I mean?
I'm just like,
no.
And then all of a sudden I'll be like
turning down the radio and they're like,
take your hand out of the middle of
there,
put your hand on the car.
I'm like,
Oh God.
Then I cans go up.
You know what I mean?
Instead of I said the steering wheel,
you know,
and it's like,
I haven't even seen this guy yet.
And I'm the.
It is.
It's really.
It just takes over everything.
Yeah.
And imagine you know,
you,
you pull someone over and there's some
brock lesnar looking motherfucker
sitting in the driver's seat and he
doesn't want to make eye contact for you
and says,
what did I do wrong?
Officer?
And you're like,
oh shit.
Yeah.
Oh Jesus.
You know,
if this guy gets out of the truck,
he's just going to literally rip you to
pieces.
Or he might pull out a machine gun under
his car seat.
Start gunning you down.
Who knows?
Who knows when you're pulling some guy
over,
you don't know if he's got a body in the
trunk.
You don't know if he's got 100 kilos of
cocaine in his spare tire.
You don't know shit.
How much is the home?
That seemed like a lot.
One hundred kilos,
but 220 pounds or something like that.
Two hundred 22 kilos of acid paper
asset.
Oh my God,
that's enough acid to kill the world.
Right.
But you don't know.
Maybe you pull somebody over.
Even a woman,
she could be some crazy bitch.
You just got done killing her entire
family and he's.
She's driving her mom's house to kill
her too.
Did you see the video that was released
like two days ago from Boston?
Have a guy recording his ex girlfriend
just breaking his windows,
scratching his car.
Then he goes outside.
You'd be like,
look,
look what she did.
She like crushed my bumper and then have
nowhere.
She just comes from behind going like 50
miles an hour and hits him.
Know he misses just by an inch,
but it hit his car and if Jamie could
pull up that video you will freak.
I mean the,
the anger,
this crazy woman and that right there,
she's supposedly has already gone to
court twice and said that he has hit her
and done all this shit.
But just watching this video go,
oh no,
look at this poor guy.
What he's dealing with.
That guy needs to get one of those.
That guy needs to get one of those
sperms switches.
Make sure you
and you will wind up fucking her again.
She's that crazy.
You know what kind of pussy she must be
thrown around.
Just fucking illiquid thunder.
She wants.
She's been wrecking that dude.
Oh yeah.
God.
And He.
Yeah,
he couldn't leave his house and just had
to.
He was like kid,
like it was scary being in that
situation because she seemed like she
would pull out a gun and just start
shooting them or what.
Anybody tries to hit you with a car,
right?
That's,
you might as well be shooting at me
trying to hit someone with a car that's
death.
Oh yeah.
Tim,
let's give some volume.
Young champions.
This is what he's showing what she did.
So you just keep this out of my car.
I actually just got painted over because
I was lousy guess.
Jeez God.
Oh my God.
He's got a Mercedes.
And what does he have?
A Honda,
which she tried to hit him.
What could she just tried to hit him
with the car and then if you saw the
beginning of it,
she is outside.
Just smashing windows and stuff.
But dude,
he didn't even know she was coming.
No,
he wasn't even looking and she almost
killed him.
She's coming.
She's coming back.
No Way.
Oh my God.
My vehicle into my neighbor's vehicle.
This is crazy.
Back that ass up.
Who wrote who?
What is she going to do
going inside because I want to avoid any
further if she rammed.
Okay.
I think she's gonna Finish her Mercedes
into his Honda.
She's finishing up on the car.
How you treat me,
right?
Oh my God.
She's coming out with a crowbar and
broke his back.
No,
she has just smashed my window.
My rear windshield.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
And at the beginning he,
she broke windows in his house and he's
in the house like she's breaking my
windows in my house now.
A whoa.
It's a freaking video.
Does that make your blood pressure go
up?
Jesus crying when she got out of her car
with the Crowbar.
I was like,
Oh shit,
this just got real as fuck.
That's how people does.
She got him.
She got him arrested earlier,
like previous because she was at her
brother's house or something and she
just said like he was beating her up and
the cops came and arrested him.
Yeah,
it's been tormenting him for a long
time.
I hope that does advocate too.
What if she's telling the truth and he
was beaten and robbed and she's like,
enough of this punk ass mother fucker.
I'm going over his house with a crow
bar.
I'm going to run this bitch over with a
fucking truck.
Right.
And fun fact,
if you google her name Jamie or his
name,
I don't know if you can find this,
but they actually were a rap duo and
they have rap videos.
Oh my God,
what have you done?
What spiral have you let us down?
I hope you at least did something good.
You know what I mean?
Like banged a supermodel or something
because you know it.
I'd be really disappointed to find out
that like he left her with a bill,
like red lobster or something like that.
She was furious.
Yeah.
What could have possibly been that bad
that she wanted to kill him with a car?
Well,
to ram a Mercedes into his Honda is
like,
you know,
it's like throwing fucking money at
somebody's face.
Like you piece of shit.
I hate you.
That's a pump moved though.
That's a pumped up move that is pumped
up.
Fucking throwing money in someone's head
off.
Fuck.
Didn't someone did someone did that to
like two P diddy.
It was like a story and some article
about,
uh,
some violence that had broken out in
this club.
People getting shot because some guys
showed up at one of these things,
you know,
p diddy's famous for going to these
clubs and he'd have the velvet rope and
all this money and all those bottles.
That was his whole thing.
His whole thing was flossing and some
guy came up to him and like through $100
bills in his face.
Oh,
that had to hurt.
I bet.
I bet one of his eyes got puffy and then
puff daddy joke right there.
That's maybe when it became diddy didn't
like coffee and maybe that was.
Maybe they corresponded.
Yeah.
Depends.
Yeah,
but something happened and that was a.
I think somebody gets shot that
incident,
right?
Didn't tell him to get shot or trampled
or something like that.
I'm pretty sure I'm trying to look it up
right now.
I think Chris Brown was involved and
there was something about a bottle
getting broken in someone's eyes.
Oh,
that's a different one.
I think that's a different one.
No,
that's a different one.
That's a recent one.
The P diddy one.
He might even been puff.
Daddy was in New York.
That other one was out here,
but I mean I'm sure there's been a lot
of incidents with drake at a club to p
diddy.
Who One please tell me drake.
I don't know.
It was over a girl.
Oh Man.
Fighting over chicks.
I just sent you the video.
The music video of the two people.
Jamie,
throwing money in a guy's face is a
real.
I mean,
that's like the ultimate,
like hitting a man with a glove or
whatever,
like starting at dual.
It's,
that's the energy that he's put out to
the world.
It's perfect because like if you see P
diddy walking down the beach with a dude
who's holding an umbrella over his head,
I was seeing that.
No,
you haven't seen that.
He has a man.
Servant Servant will follow him around
with an umbrella.
Oh my God.
Oh yes.
Here we go.
Jamie,
his name was barnes the apparently
that's amazing.
He's a,
he's a character in a spiderman comic
book.
Bonds with.
Can I have my unparallel please?
I mean if for p dot diddy was like some
diabolical.
Look at this.
He's got a guy following him around with
an umbrella.
Oh my.
The gentleman has a bow tie on.
Why wouldn't you have a girl do that?
You know,
like if I win the powerball I'll have
that.
But a girl
and she has to wear a bikini.
I don't know man.
Well it's a weird position,
but maybe it's a really good gig.
Like maybe he just gets to jet all over
the world and wear bow ties and just
allowing us to hold an umbrella.
How fucking hard is that in a fake
world?
What if p diddy liked guys and that was
a way to have his boyfriend always with
him in a fake world,
a thinly veiled
Farnsworth.
Bentley attends the 2003 MTV music video
was
gotten to work and hanging out with
snoop dog quite a bit and he has an
Asian guy who his only job and he's the
best at it is rolling blunts and he just
rolls blunts and he's just the best
blunt roller and it just comes up and
it's like,
Hey,
this is,
you know,
I don't remember his name exactly,
but it's like,
this is bubba.
He's the blonde girl or guy and he just.
And when you hit it,
it just is like you.
It's like our rate laser coming at you.
You know how the end of A.
Anything Cherries up.
It's always even,
it's like perfect.
Like it does it with his hands.
Yeah,
like a science.
Like he really like really like Cubans
massages that you could tell that he
really takes his time.
Very adhesive,
perfect cylinder,
Tam hand rolled.
You can almost tell that it was just
rolled.
There's no substitute for quality and
craftsmanship.
It's true.
And you know,
I understand it.
Yeah.
You're snoop Dogg,
you smoke blunts all day continuously
and he does like,
you know,
you see all the,
all these different celebrities of their
things and you're like,
oh,
I bet he doesn't.
He doesn't really like that offstage.
Like snoop just,
he's unbelievably hilarious when it
comes to smoking.
Yeah.
You would think that the balance of
wonder what kind of paper they using,
are they using like legit blunt,
which is what a blunt is for folks who
are not aware is they take a cigarette,
um,
or rather a cigar and take the tobacco
out and then put weed in and roll it up
together.
And I never had one until I hung out
with Charlie Murphy and his cousin rich.
They find daughter Lauder,
first of all,
because you're breathing in the tobacco
smoke,
which is an added element in it.
It does something,
it opens up your capillaries in your
lungs,
that the tea more thc gets in your
blood.
It
also has an effect of its own.
You know,
the nicotine in the tobacco leaf.
It has an effect of its own and it's
also unusual in the fact that that
tobacco leaf is generally not inhaled
you.
When you smoke tobacco a cigar,
you puff it,
but you don't take the big deep inhaling
like long filling breaths that you do
when you smoke weed.
So if you smoke a blunt,
really kind of the only time you're
breathing that smoke in and it's a
serious irritant,
I,
I think that's real unhealthy for you to
smoke those tobacco leaves all the way
down.
Right?
I think you can't do that every day.
That's why.
That's why the Geno's little that
electronic cigarette blind that tastes
great and you don't have to get the
nicotine part of,
you know,
Geno's the shit at La speed weed.
He knows what he's doing.
Man.
He got pulled down from instagram was
then hilariously instagram deleted his
account or suspended as account or
whatever the hell they did because he's
a weed related like Geez,
operating within the California laws,
he's selling something to everybody
loves how come you have all these wind
companies that have instagram accounts
and all these beer companies,
which I like wine.
I like beer.
We all do well.
Why?
What's wrong with weed?
Well,
you know,
services like the greatest thing ever,
by the way he should get back at
instagram by making a promo that's like
they instagram special were like,
you get a gram of pot,
like within 10 minutes,
some type of crazy promotion where it's
like,
hey,
did you hear about the instagram thing?
Just use them as a marketing thing.
Yeah.
That's funny.
Instagrams bitches,
man.
I can't believe that.
It's great.
It's to.
It's just a.
they're a company.
They're trying to fucking make some
money.
I get it.
How is it though that twitter,
you're allowed to see both holes,
but instagram you can't even see
nipples,
you know,
like twitter because of the fact that
you can see all that stuff.
There's like a more,
maybe more of a limit in as far as her
kind of as they'll get.
Whereas maybe instagram because they've
been proactive in censoring people's
material,
censoring the images and stuff that
you're allowed to put up,
you know,
maybe there'll be an.
They could sell more of those sponsored
instagram ads.
That way they have a lot of those
sponsored ads.
Yeah.
You see them all the time now in your
feed.
You can have a problem with it.
You get shipped potholes on twitter.
You can do whatever you want onto think
sponsored ads on instagram are probably
the least offensive ads ever because
they take a fucking half of a second to
go through.
I agree.
Whereas in the ad on TV is the most
offensive.
You're watching the walking dead and
they're about to get jack by zombies and
it fucking fades to black and it's,
don't you want your car to shine light
new
believeable fuckers.
You fuckers have ruined the entire mood
of this awesome show to sell me a some
wax or whatever the fuck yourself.
Yeah.
The artist took time to set a tone and
feel so much better if you watch it on
itunes.
Crazy to me,
like I remember when we were making the
show,
uh,
that burn a couple of years ago on
comedy central,
Jeff Ross show and I wrote and produced
it and uh,
you know,
you've,
I've,
it was the only show that I ever watched
on tv because I was always doing standup
and stuff and I didn't even have a TV,
you know,
that's back like this is like four or
five years ago anyway.
Uh,
but every after every day going into
every commercial break during this
comedy show that's at 10:30 at night,
it was always a life alert commercial,
like straight into like,
I've fallen and I'm,
I need help.
I'm here.
You know what I mean?
Like who's going to save your grandma if
you don't have life alert?
And it's like,
then it's like now back to your comedy
experience.
Yeah.
It's like the worst type of stuff.
Well,
we all know that from doing standup or
from going to the movies,
you don't.
If a movie got interrupted every 15
minutes for commercial,
you know how fucking pissed you would be
at the end of that movie.
The problem with network television is
the model they're using where you
interrupt shows and show these
commercials.
It sucks.
It sucks and you're stuck with it.
You got to figure out a whole new way to
show ads because people are done.
And so the idea was,
well,
we'll just make ads more interesting.
We'll just make ads more creative.
And they did that to a certain extent,
but they still suck.
Nobody wants to see him.
He did.
Even if it's the most awesome ad ever,
it's interrupting whether or not fucking
Rick is going to get jacked by the
zombies.
Right?
Right.
And that's their cable that's even more
fucked up.
He's like AMC and uh,
you know,
the independent film channel,
IFC and all these different channels or
cable,
they can do whatever they want,
like they have to,
they have to censor themselves to ensure
that they get the right ads.
So they self sensor just to get ads.
It's not like the ABC,
CBS,
NBC,
those are governed by the FCC.
And so when,
when you're on television,
you're not allowed to swear.
You're not allowed to.
Like there's,
there's a law,
but on cable there's no fucking laws.
That's why they say shit.
Now Llc c asshole leads a lot of shows.
They get real close to st fuck you.
But they don't really say fuck you.
But they get real close and it's because
they're on cable.
The only reason why they don't do
everything full nudity do ever do they
want is ads.
That's it.
That's why hbo gets away with just going
buck wild no ads,
but to try getting people to pay for
shit today.
Like if they don't produce things like
game of thrones,
if they don't have like specials like
Whitney Cummings special.
They don't have like a lot of original
content,
Amy Schumer's last special,
a lot of original content where people
are going to seek it out specifically,
but big time fights whenever they have a
big time fights on Hbo.
If it's not that it's hard getting
people to pay today.
Yeah,
it really is.
I mean,
but at the same time it sort of isn't
like I feel like it's hard for like the
middle of the country I think is making
the transition now,
but Netflix is up to over $75 million
subscribers or something like that.
It's going up by millions and HBO is I
think at like 25 million households
right now.
So it's nuts.
I mean I,
I personally I run completely off of.
I have netflix and I have hbo go and
that is yet like if there's a sporting
event on the TV then I have to go to a
local,
you know,
bar or something or restaurant to check
it out.
That's just how I roll.
You just don't want cable or satellite
or anything like that,
you know,
young.
I don't ever use it.
The only thing that might come on,
it's like a college football game or the
UFC or something like that.
You,
but you got the UFC pass now like I,
I mean I cut the cable bill.
I haven't looked back at all,
you know,
with Hulu plus.
And you have the UFC app where it's
just,
that's all you need.
A lot of people go in that direction.
No,
that's what they think the future is.
They think the future is not going to be
television,
especially now that TV's hookup to a
Hcmi cables that hookup to computers
right away and a lot of tvs and not
getting online,
like a lot of tvs out of the box of
online ability.
And so they act as a small computer.
So you'll just be able to go straight.
I like my tv by itself.
Go straight to youtube.
I can go to youtube like what the fuck?
Like you through Itunes,
you do everything.
Itunes connect you to Netflix,
apple,
uh,
apple TV connects you to Netflix.
Did you get the new one yet?
I tell you that's worth the upgrade.
It's one of my favorite things ever.
Just being able to go a Steve Martin and
it pulls up every single Steve Martin
who they talked to him.
Yeah.
You just tell it,
so you're like a walking dead and then
you click on walking down.
It says available on Hulu or itunes or
Netflix and it just takes you right
there.
So googling.
Yeah,
that's what puff daddy as barns worth.
Do something walking dead worth.
Does he?
Does he have to massage his feet at the
end of a long day?
I totally get the lotion but okay.
But if it's barnes,
words choice,
particularly save barnes worth was like
living in Columbus News,
working at a tire factory.
That was just like.
And then all of a sudden this guy came
into town and go,
dude,
I've been looking for a guy to carry my
umbrella.
I'll pay you a million dollars a year.
You've got to go with me to Paris,
France and all over the world,
but you'd be with me 24 hours a day and
you are at my beck and call and you must
massage my feet the end of every night.
I'd be like,
he'd be like,
I'm a millionaire and I don't work at a
tire factory.
Pinky in.
I think he's out.
Oh,
in him.
He's asking for that.
No,
I just don't understand why you want to
have a girl.
But because he would probably start
fucking her and she would interfere in
his business and you know,
if she was hot,
especially in they're around each other
all the time.
At a certain point in time she started
complaining about not getting a new
deck.
Like,
ah,
these guys.
I don't know what's wrong.
I mean,
it's just not allowed to talk and have
sex with me.
You're going to talk to these girls.
You know,
you're,
you're finding an acumen that you want,
you'd want as a robot,
you know,
you want a replicant like blade runner
style,
which we're going to have.
It's going to happen.
It's 20 years away.
We're 20 years away from going over
someone's house and they have a
replicant.
You're going to go over your buddy's
house and he's going to have a Chinese
lady with giant ridiculous tits and a
waste.
That doesn't seem to be possible for the
size of her tits and ass that's out of
this world and she's going to be cleaned
it up and you're not going to be sure if
she's really not going to be like,
um,
what's that?
Is that a person?
Is this a person or is that a replicant?
And he'll pull you into
the fucking kitchen and they'll explain
it to you.
Do you think,
do you think when we get close to that,
that they're going to first just let
them out into the world and try to fool
everybody to see if they can do it?
Like a Beta test?
No,
they're too expensive,
but they're tracking them.
I like hardcore.
I think we'll.
No,
no,
I think we'll know when they develop
one,
when they get one to the point where
it's almost like a person we're going to
know and it's going to be terrifying
when they sit that one down on
television and we have a robot that
adjusts his clothes and goes,
so what would you like to know?
You're going to go,
oh my God,
what have we done?
Like what the fuck have we done and how
do,
what do we know about what this thing
has done to protect itself?
What do we know about what this thing
has done to ensure that the idea is that
it has,
will continue and in some other form and
the most important question,
how do you fuck it?
Oh,
you're gonna be able to fuck it.
Like you would a normal woman if they're
going to be able to have artificial
skin.
They have artificial skin that they've
already developed.
So they've been able to develop skin in
um,
in a,
like a,
like some sort of an experiment where
they recreated a woman's bladder,
they use stem cells and they recreated
her bladder.
They created a new bladder and then they
put it back into her body and it acts as
a functioning bladder like they're going
to,
they're going to be able to develop
artificial skin.
So when these are lab created skin,
when these robots that you can fuck
become like easily accessible,
how much longer until women go extinct.
How much longer until you go over your
ex's house.
Your ex is like 60 years old.
She's dressed like the wife on three's
company,
the one you know with Mrs. She dress
like Mrs. Frilly and behind her are an
army of seven foot tall black guys with
giant dicks and there's just stroking
their shafts all day.
Shuts that door.
She goes,
yeah,
I just put it over there.
She shuts that door back to work and
they just fucking stuff or all day and
she takes Mr Hurley's money and she
invested in these gigantic Bob Sapp
looking mandingo warrior dudes with
giant Ebony Dicks.
They're so she comes to the door and uh,
yeah,
I'll thank you Mr. ups driver and the
ups driver takes a look down the hallway
over her shoulder and sees all these
guys just stroking it,
staring out the window with glowing
eyes.
Oh yeah.
Do you think a big crazy vibrating
robotics?
Oh yeah.
Why would they,
why wouldn't they vibrate?
Of course.
Punch.
You multiply switches on these fucking
thing.
They whip like a whip push.
Do you think you'd have to clean the
comment out of it or if it would just
reuse the comfort tiers later?
You know,
like it was that advanced where it is
useful,
lives off come ideally stays alive,
so that has to constantly be trying to
turn you on.
I sure would love a good charging this
morning from behind.
Please put it in my palm.
Oversensitive people right now will be
tuning in and going,
I can't believe what they're saying.
I can't believe Tony Hinchcliffe is
saying that women would go extinct if
someone made a perfect artificial woman
that did everything that a man wants.
No nagging.
Why don't you want the nagging right?
You want a real woman because all women
don't have a mute button badge.
You Mute and clean.
All right,
I'll be back in a couple hours by bed.
Well,
think about all the negative aspects of
people,
right?
Jealousy and anger and that lady fucking
they're homicidal.
Rage,
smashing into that dude's car and then
break those windows.
Think about all this negative aspects of
being a person.
Now,
think of all the positive aspects of the
great things people can do when they're
wonderful and they're nice and
supportive and loving and friendly and
caressing and affectionate and just get
rid of the bad stuff and then you have
this perfect person.
Maybe Barnes worth is a robot and we
just don't know anybody.
Maybe P diddy.
He's just a man of the possible that
there's something super shady about the
guy that holds an umbrella for a living.
They've always existed though.
I mean,
that's the Butler and fucking Batman.
He never wants to kick ass.
He never is like,
look,
I'm tired of this bullshit,
dude.
You leave me.
You get all this fucking press.
You're out there kicking ass.
Nobody even knows me.
I'm down here and vent and shit.
No,
he doesn't care.
I wonder if there's always been that
guy.
Yeah,
right.
There's always been the man servant role
and those,
those television shows.
I wonder if anybody's ever gone to p
diddy's house and accidentally left the
door open and Barnes was born in a barn.
Worth be a great law.
You son of a bitch.
I mean,
if you're only
winning roads,
butlers,
or a weird thing,
right on man standing there with a
little white towel over his arm with his
hand,
like upright in a very correct and
proper posture.
Good day,
sir.
May I help you?
So like someone falling around,
getting things Barton's worth,
please fix me a drink.
Scotch,
two cubes of ice and a turn the music up
very low and please close the door when
you leave right away.
So come in and take care of you.
Imagine getting a woman rattled in
better managing.
Also like switching of roles would have
like you with a really,
really wealthy guy and you had you had
yourself,
a barnes worth and barnes worth did a
wonderful job,
but bonds with had ambitions of his own
and barnes worth left and he left to
start his own business and that business
was ultimately a gigantic success.
Boy,
it took off,
but your business or the internet came
along and got it and record companies
just weren't making any money anymore.
Those records stores,
they don't exist and you owned a chain
of them and that's how you had barnes
worth and they went under,
but barnes worth.
He created napster.
Yeah.
Barns were started bawling.
Barnes worth was he figured out how to
make money off of youtube ads and barnes
worth.
You know what he did,
man.
He starts selling mp3s,
sort of putting that shit on itunes now.
Worth hundreds of millions of dollars
in Farnsworth wants to hire you to be as
butler.
What do he do that?
That sounds like a great movie idea.
Yeah,
like a face off trading,
trading,
trading phases.
Well,
people who have butlers would hate to be
a butler.
Like once you have a butler,
you never want to go to being a butler.
Yeah,
that would be.
That would be diabolical.
Yeah.
Once you have some dude who stands there
like a,
like a night in front of a castle with
his little white perfect Tuxedo looking
jacket on though.
Tuxedo shirt and I would love that.
The few times that I've gotten to fly
first class,
I mean having just having somebody come
up once in a while and be like,
is there anything I can get for you?
Anything at all?
It's always just the greatest feeling.
I can't imagine having a fulltime barnes
worth.
They would grow to hate you.
They would tase you.
Look,
David spades.
Guy tasered him,
but I totally think that David spade out
of barns worth any tasered him tapped
him.
What?
Yeah.
Tacked him.
Allegedly I wasn't there.
Allegedly tasered him fucked him up.
It was like a big case.
It was in the news.
I think the dude just got enough.
David spade at Butler.
He had an assistant which is a milder
version of a barnes worth.
Yeah.
Follows you around and tells you when
you're supposed to be somewhere skippy.
Skippy.
Do you guys remember skippy from family
ties?
Your numbers keep you from family ties?
Yeah.
He was on that show with Michael J.
Fox and then went from that into standup
and he would be like on the road and
like places we were like uh,
in the early,
early days.
But now,
I don't know,
that's hard,
like,
screech did that for awhile to write
from seeing by the bell.
I had to roast them one time.
We did one of these roasts of the uh,
no,
it was the roast of Ron.
Jeremy and I had to roast screech.
Oh my God.
It was so much fun that he's completely
out of his element.
But it was so much fun,
like a.
I told them,
uh,
nowadays when I watched episodes of
saved by the bell,
I think to myself,
why couldn't there be a school shooting
back then
too soon?
Too soon.
I guess he stabbed someone at a,
at a nightclub in,
um,
Minnesota.
Did he stab someone or was he involved
in a stabbing?
I had heard about it.
He was at a bar or some dude was fucking
with his check.
He pulled out his knife.
Oh my God.
I was actually talking to him like the
day before that happened.
And then like a day after that happened.
Yeah.
Really?
What's he like?
He's nice.
I like him a lot.
So you're good guy.
You called him or he called you.
Did you reach out to the
DMD,
each other?
Jamie's clearly had too much.
I mean,
Tony's clearly,
uh,
too much weed today.
Yeah.
Reach out to the screech owl
came out of your mouth.
You know,
it's funny.
Is last time I did a podcast with you,
we talked about um,
puns and I defended puns and I said,
people make,
uh,
you know,
only people that can't make puns like
say that puns or hacky because everybody
loves puns when they're good.
And so I've been getting,
like,
smashed in my twitter mentions a in a
great way.
Like people sent me like funny things
that they thought of and it's like my
favorite thing now people are like,
Hey,
this happened today,
crazy pun,
right?
Like Blah,
blah,
blah.
And they sent me the thing.
That's funny.
Yeah,
you love those.
Those two are like little gifts that the
universe gives you and you know,
they're corny because as you're saying
them,
I see your,
your,
your smile starts to turn up as you're
saying it.
It's my favorite thing fucker.
It's so like,
because they're always in the moment.
I always love stuff that's like,
right,
that just happened and only it can last
a second.
Fleeting.
So this is the special that comes out
this Friday is the one that you did at
our world famous Ice House Comedy Club.
Our favorite spot or one of our favorite
spots next to.
Oh,
let's play the trailer or your trailer.
Yep.
Let's play the trailer.
That'll something powerful.
Tony Hinchcliffe entrepreneur.
That's me.
That's how it starts.
This is how it starts.
It's one complete shot and this is
what's really cool about it.
You follow Tony from the outside where
he's smoking in front of headliner spot
and the parking lot into the club and
onstage and it never misses a beat.
One continuous take.
No cuts,
no editing,
but there is a cut right there in the
trailer,
unfortunately.
Or else you'd see joey as bringing me
up,
which was awesome.
Why'd you throw your cigarette on the
ground?
Yeah,
right at
the beginning of their videos.
You're fucking slobs.
I'm done.
Because you're littering done.
I had a Farnsworth there to pick it up.
Just wanted to be the cool guy.
Josh.
Josh,
Josh and Mark Barnes worth,
we've got to call him Barton's and her
now.
I have no idea why these guys call me
bonds who have now.
I was with somebody the other day and I
was like,
who was your favorite comic on the
night?
And had josh on the show and she goes,
oh,
Josh Martin was my favorite,
but josh really,
you like Josh and goes,
Dude.
He says rape with a w.
That was hilarious.
He's absolutely murdering.
I've been randomly,
you know,
Monday nights are weird.
I randomly once in a while just to check
in at like 10:00 PM whenever we're done
with the podcast every time and he's
always on because he just got done with
our podcast,
so he has a thing where he always gets
to go on right when we're done.
So he goes downstairs and that's always.
I always say hi to a few people and then
I'm in there.
He's murdering right now.
Josh.
That like has that speech impediment
with his gun?
He followed Rogan on the secret the
other day,
like 300 people.
He had to go up right after Logan.
It was great to see you.
Okay,
stay alive,
you know,
and he's only been doing it how long
now?
A two and a half years.
I fell in love with him the first time
that I saw him,
I was,
I was hosting that night and they were
making like some little promo video for
the comedy store and it was the first
time that I ever saw him on stage and I,
it,
they asked me to interview,
you know,
just walk around and explain how potluck
works because they wanted to make a
little two minute video for the comedy.
So I think it's still on their website
actually.
And I talked to him and I met him that
night and he goes,
I go,
what do you do for work?
He has,
I'm a manager at a Mcdonald's a like an
hour outside of La San.
So that something like you have such an
interesting look and you sound so funny
that if you get good at this you are
going to be on fucking stoppable.
And I'm starting to see this fucking
like when the car starts to turn over
and it's like,
you're like,
Ooh,
there's a fucking engine in here.
I'm seeing it every Monday.
And like I said earlier,
like there's nothing more fun than
watching people that you know,
and that like,
you're in you root for just fucking
start ripping it.
And he's doing it right now.
It's so cool.
Especially since he has such a defined
style.
Like he literally,
you know,
they say it takes 10 years to find your
voice,
but he has his voice like literally it's
going to.
It is as long as he keeps doing it.
And why?
No speech therapy.
You don't think so.
Oh,
I see.
Oh no way.
I say you fix that.
You're crazy.
Look at that.
This was like literally,
I think his first time at the comedy
store and he's bombing,
so it's probably really quick.
Oh,
let's,
we don't want to watch them bomb.
There's no reason.
There's no reason to watch that.
But this was his first time and I go,
dude,
you gotTa fucking get in the game,
Bro.
And sure enough he did well,
we worked with the store.
No.
Yeah,
he's worked there for and he's been the
producer of kill Tony.
I mean this guy fucking hustles and he
tries to do as many spots as possible.
He's gotten,
you know,
like you,
I've watched him grow on and off stage
because like he used to like start
arguments with people and just talk
shit.
And it's one of the guys,
you know,
like so many others where you get to
watch them grow as a human.
Some for some people doing standup
comedy,
all of a sudden you're in a social
setting for the first time ever.
Well,
it just,
it can be,
it can be a real bad scene.
You know,
when you're struggling and you're young
and you,
you know,
look,
you have no future lived in his car for
awhile.
Paid paid dues for while,
like over a year.
He lived in his car one time.
Brian Moses on the way to the ice house.
Uh,
he had to pee.
I was in the car for that and it was the
most unbelievable thing ever.
So Josh is driving in the car that he
sleeps in his house.
We're going to the ice house for one of
these Friday night shows.
I'm sitting shotgun and our good pal
Brian Moses host a roast battle is
sitting in the backseat and we get off
as soon as we're.
It's like we're almost.
There were like five minutes away.
It's like a 25 minute drive,
right?
All of a sudden Moses is like,
Oh fuck man,
I gotTa pee bad.
Like real bad.
Oh fuck.
I'm peeing.
And me and Josh are both like,
what?
What are you rallies like,
I can't stop it now I'm paying.
And they were like this out of nowhere.
Moses doesn't mind me telling this
story.
It's funny.
Sorry guys.
You're cool.
You're cool,
you're cool.
You can handle this.
But.
And what?
But what's unbelievable about this story
is who cares that he peed himself?
What are the odds that a guy peed
himself that never pays himself ever?
What are the odds that he peed himself
in the back seat of where this kid's
sleep?
Now he has to.
No matter where he's staying,
has to put his feet on that end of the
backseat.
Hey,
by the way,
just giving a few minutes of warning.
We get a gun
so quick.
Whoever,
God,
how great this story really was on the
Ice House,
right?
Because they came right to the ice house
and then Brian just says,
I just had to go.
It just came out of nowhere.
I just had to go and you could tell it.
Even he as it was happening,
like he's like,
yeah,
this never happens.
I don't know what the fuck's going on.
Well,
that's.
It happens when people pooped
themselves.
Right.
That deck almost makes more sense.
Like sometimes people get diarrhea and
you're like,
oh God.
Like I remember just a couple of weeks
ago,
I barely made it to the toilet.
I had these insane pains in my lower
stomach and I was climbing.
I was going upstairs.
When I started to have them,
I'm like,
oh no,
this is like a real battle.
So I was squeezing right now.
I couldn't talk to anybody in my.
I can't talk,
can't talk,
excuse me,
and I had to push past my kids and get
to the toilet and I shut the door.
Like,
Daddy's got to go.
Hold on.
I'll be right out in the Mr. asking me
questions and shit,
and I sit down.
I had a lock that door because they
start working the knob five year old
saying,
give a fuck if you have to go to that.
This isn't.
Doesn't register with them.
Like Daddy,
I've talked to you about some stuff like
hold on,
hold on.
And just were
rushed out of me like a hoard of
barbarians,
just swinging broadswords fucking
pushing the enemy over the cliff.
It was insane how it was coming out.
I can't even imagine.
You must have like real man shit.
It's like I could never.
My little tiny dear droplets come out.
You're starting to eat meat now.
Tony to meet now has a different diet.
I've been eating meat for a few weeks
and I am pumped about it.
I'm excited about it at a whole chicken
breast yesterday.
That's great.
You went from being a Vegan to being a
carnivore?
Yeah,
sandwich for dinner last night.
Chicken breasts for lunch.
What was it?
What pushed you over the top?
It was,
besides the mocking of everyone around
it was
I wanted to have friends again.
My Dad,
I haven't,
I didn't get to go back to youngstown
where I'm from for a few years.
I've just been,
you know,
it's blah,
blah,
blah.
But anyway,
I went into my dad's restaurant.
He owns a great Italian restaurant where
I'm from in Youngstown and a cable to
plug.
Well,
I actually shouldn't this idea.
Yeah,
I've talked about other stuff about in
another podcast.
Anyway,
uh,
um,
what's his restaurant?
Applebee's.
It's,
it's,
it's a,
it's an independent great Italian
restaurant.
But he looked at me so disappointed when
he.
He goes,
all right,
what do you want me to make for you?
I'm going back,
I'm going to make something like that.
And I go,
uh,
whatever you want.
I just,
I,
I don't eat meat and I don't eat dairy.
And the look he gave me,
like it was like,
I could see it was like emperor
palpatine electricity that like out of
nowhere and you're just like,
oh my God,
31 years,
this guy has been my dad and I've never
gotten a look of.
Like,
he stopped and looked at me confused and
sort of turned his head like a dog.
Like,
are you fucking kidding me?
So was your dad like Sebastian?
Totally.
Yeah.
My Dad's like a complete perfect hybrid
of Sebastian and dice.
That's my dad fleet hybrid of those two
guys.
Are you
kidding me?
So then there you quit.
No,
he waited until we got back in the day.
Got Back.
Well nobody out of all the years out of
everything it's been,
you know,
it was like five or six years of
vegetarianism,
veganism.
But I eat fish so it's like pescatarian,
but I don't eat dairy so it's weird.
Anyway,
nobody's busted my balls more about it
than Brian Red band here.
And our very good friend Pete,
uh,
because I hang out with them all the
time and so something happened but blah
blah.
And I just sorta like after the few days
of being back and being like,
I wonder how good my dad's.
I mean the seafood pasta that he made
for me was the most mind bending seafood
pasta I've ever had in my life.
But there was something about the look
that he gave me in which it's like,
do you have any idea what you're missing
out on?
You fucking idiot.
I'll make you the seafood.
Positive face looks fuller.
Yeah.
His body looks forward to.
It looks like you've,
you've stopped this growth stunt.
Like you had to maybe like a bend in a
garden hose and just opened it up and
niosh time you seen.
But lately.
But he's got a new boy.
You got a little bit you to show me your
book.
You do seem like.
Are you really standing up to show your
but don't listen to him.
Was looking to see if I had a.
But I wasn't showing you.
I was looking to see if I have.
Could you check?
How can you be sure?
It's a terrible angle that there's no
way to be sure to see that little poof.
You lifting weights or something?
Oh yeah.
Squats now know squat.
Um,
I just have a couple of dumbbells.
I just work shoulders and press and
curl.
You should
go to a trainer.
Yeah.
I should be a funny show.
You and Brian Losing weight and gaining
weight both
of you together and then now and call it
in and out.
What's creating every team should do
that.
It helps muscles recover and it helps
them grow and it helps them retain water
in some people.
When you take too much of it,
it gives you kind of like a puffy look
cause you,
uh,
you will retain a little bit more water
apparently.
I'm not allowed to talk out of school,
but it's a bit.
It's definitely been shown to be
beneficial for gaining muscle.
Yeah.
And it's also something that they
measure.
If you are overtrained you can have
cree,
I think it's called creatinine.
I think it's a little bit of a different
thing,
but it's a,
it's,
it's something that shows the damage of
your muscles.
So like if you're like grossly
overtrained,
you might have really high levels of
this stuff and then like I know if a guy
is a guy,
I think it was pulled out of a fight
because of it,
like they tested him and he tested
really high for this Korea to stuff.
I want to say tim can,
I know it's harder for me to remember,
but there's another organization outside
of the UFC a long time ago.
I don't remember that.
Remember that.
But a creatine works illegal to it.
What's your energy like five hour energy
before doing your work for you?
Because I know I'm so paranoid with my
[inaudible] this thing like tracks your
heartbeat all times.
And it's like,
well the milligrams caffeine,
if you look at a five hour energy drink,
I think it's only a little bit over 200
milligrams caffeine.
It's vitamin B 12,
which is healthy for you.
You get some uh,
some stimulation from that.
It's a lot of vitamin B,
12 about a vitamin B,
12 is water soluble.
It goes right out of your system and in
and out.
It's not like you'd have to like take
like a giant amount of it for a long
period of time to have any negative
effects.
So like using it as a stimulant or a
potential energy source like that in a
five hour energy drinks fun.
It's not bad for you.
The only thing with the five hour
energies,
you could have a niacin flush.
You ever have one of those?
Oh yeah.
Well I take um,
I take and I'd take flash Niacin which
makes my whole skin tingle.
It makes me fucking Shit's really bad.
Happened before I went on this five hour
energy.
I thought five hour energies were just
the greatest thing for awhile and uh,
maybe like my 10th or 15th one over like
a couple months and one of those hit me
and it just freaked me out.
Oh,
you got a nice and flat.
Yeah.
See that's nothing compared to taking
the actual nice and you'd take actual
nice and it's nuts,
man.
The feeling you get the tingling on your
skin.
Like it freaks some people out.
It freaked me out.
What is it?
I like it.
It's a supplement.
I like it because I know it's not going
to kill me,
but it's,
it's,
you're,
you're feeling the reaction of this
nutrient.
Like it makes you your skin tingle and
flush.
Yeah.
They call it flash.
Nice.
And um,
but it's an essential nutrient really
good for your body.
A lot of people are low in it,
good for sex.
I imagined the shit she a son.
Well it's also,
that's what that stuff like.
I'm a nitrous oxide,
which a lot of people take like
different pump up phones.
Those things they have a effect to
Viagra and cialis.
They have a similar effect and being
like somehow or another it aids the
blood flow or it stimulates the blood
flow.
Like um,
a lot of those same drugs are banned in
the Olympics like Viagra and Cialis is
banned in the Olympics because it's
actually a performance enhancing
supplement.
Not The judge you on your fucking,
but that they your muscles at selleck.
When the reason why your Dick,
it's harder.
Everything gets bigger.
Like you,
you,
you get like harder.
You get your body like has more
resources available for a brief amount
of time.
At least they determined enough to make
it illegal in the Olympics.
Pretty interesting stuff.
You know,
I wonder if there's any sports or having
a boner actually helps you at the time.
Like Jerry Seiner.
Oh yeah.
Wrestling freaked.
The other guy just let him know.
Yeah,
to the death.
It's having.
Taking salaries and biographies sucks
when you're working out though because
you can't control it when you're on the
treadmill and stuff,
so you just have crazy boners are all
these guys tap homeboy down,
tack them down right now.
You have to have some type jammies.
You can't.
Yeah.
You can't be wearing those boxer shorts
that you wear fucking hard slapping
against the inside of your thigh.
There's a guy,
there's a guy about those dirty girls
that you know.
Here's a guy at the gym that's that
muscle.
There's a guy that has that muscle,
like the crazy builder,
but it's so ridiculous.
Like it looks like heat pumps.
The gelan tonight.
It's so uncomfortable when he's around
now they do do that.
You know about that stuff,
that there's this stuff called synth oil
that I'm some crazy people shoot into
their bodies to make it look like they
have giant muscles,
but they don't really have giant
muscles.
They have these oil swollen limbs that
don't look real,
so it looks like they have fake boobs on
their arms,
fake boobs and their shoulders,
fake boobs and their boobs.
There's a weirdness to it where you can
tell that the guy's not really strong,
but he has these crazy fake giant arms
that don't look real at all and dread
giant traps.
Like there's this one.
Luckily this guy get out a.
yeah,
that's a synthol.
That's what the guy looks like at my
gym.
It's scary looking.
Yeah,
it looks like.
Look at that guy.
If you cut that guy open,
he would spill out like a bottle of
olive oil.
That's exactly what he looks like.
That's so creepy that these guys make
their entire lives around like the size
of their bodies to the top right.
One is this guy.
This isn't even.
Isn't that ridiculous?
Insane.
Oh my God.
Look at his arms,
man.
Get his neck boob.
Well,
that's all that synthol because like
look at his abs and look at his chest
like it doesn't even make any sense.
He has a built in neck pillow.
Must be fun to fly with.
What was that other one that you just
showed?
Is that the guy who we used to look
like?
Oh,
photoshop face.
She that guy.
That's a real body builder body.
That guy.
That's just steroids and lifting
weights.
You can tell the difference when you see
those synth oil bodies is a video of
one.
Find the video of the Brazilian dude.
There's a Brazilian dude,
he's got his shirt off and he's dancing
and it's so weird,
man.
You're looking at his tits move and his
shoulders move and his biceps move and
you're like,
what the fuck is why?
They get crazy,
but it's just like Anorexia,
man.
You don't know what you look like.
Your mind gets warped.
Oh yeah.
Body dysmorphia is 100 percent real.
People's,
their mind gets warped and they just
decide I'm not skinny enough and they
just keep starving themselves,
so there's nothing left that happens
with people that get all kinds of crazy
shit done to them.
GC,
amy,
that documentary on Amy winehouse.
I didn't want.
I didn't want to watch.
That's another one.
Unbelievable.
Someone was sitting next to me.
Maybe it was Ian.
We're on the plane.
Was it you,
Jamie?
We're watching it and I looked over a
little bit of it.
I'm like,
I don't want to watch this kid.
Like having a great time having all this
talent and then turn into a junkie and
fall apart and an alcoholic.
It just makes me sad.
Yeah,
it's depressing.
Well,
the main thing is that she had
dysmorphia and she was totally believe
that the entire time,
and it's probably basically what sorta
killed there is like her body was just
uncomplete shut down.
When you get to that point,
you know,
her face started swelling up like
there's crazy things that happened deep
into bulemia Goddamn.
And towards the end she had bulimia.
Oh,
she had it the whole time and it was
like a huge part of everything.
She was always.
She would always just throw up
everything that she had,
but amazing documentary.
Oh my God.
Really?
It starts with this.
There's so much old video footage of her
and it starts with her hanging out with
their friends and they're singing happy
birthday to one of their friends.
There's like five girls all hanging out
and they're just like little girls like,
I don't know,
10,
11 or 12 and they're all singing happy
birthday and then she keeps going on
this solo and you're like,
oh my gosh.
Already like totally a star.
She has that amy winehouse fucking voice
that just kills.
And No,
I love it.
Also the documentary,
because she was amazing.
She has had pipes and she has that cool,
like old bluesy fucking big band feel.
That just gets me pumped up.
I've been listening to a lot of it.
Yeah,
I listened to her a lot.
Um,
I've always been a big fan of hers,
but she has this like an authenticity to
the sound of her voice.
Right?
Totally,
totally.
Standalone.
Almost there with like an ella
fitzgerald type or like,
have you ever heard of
Raye Montague Montague?
So I know how you say his name though.
I can't remember what he,
what he's done.
This fucking guy.
I'm rose at the comedy store.
She,
uh,
out of nowhere she goes,
um,
we,
we're leaving.
Everybody's leaving and she pulls into
the parking lot and she's like,
you gotta hear this fucking Song?
She goes,
you've got,
you've got to hear this guy.
I go,
who?
And she goes to this guy just out of
nowhere.
She's like,
this Guy Ray Montague and he's got this
song.
I'm trying.
No,
not trouble.
It's not trouble.
He's got this jolene.
See if he could find jolene.
Um,
so she,
um,
she plays this song.
Yeah,
there it is.
Jolene,
that's like his,
his most famous one.
Where do you hear this?
Motherfucker's voice
don't play until you get everything in
line because I don't want it to.
I don't want it to like half play and
then play again because this guy,
his voice is so good.
It deserves to be uninterrupted for the
brief amount that we don't do a live
version.
Do the studio version is the studio
version?
Yeah.
Okay,
cool.
I cut this off at Youtube.
Okay.
Here.
This real quick.
Well,
he fills as loud as you can.
Just listen to it.
Mom.
Mom,
mom.
It's amazing.
Like he's a bad motherfucker.
Listen this.
What's this?
That's a bad motherfucker.
That's undeniable bad motherfucker.
I get.
He's got like a touch of that Rod.
Stewart raspiness,
but not like all the way Rod Stewart
just him is him.
You know,
whatever.
It's kind of Raspy,
but I wouldn't love to anybody else.
It's not like a rod stewart.
He's got his own vibe going on,
man.
That's a crazy song to song about a
junkie that's just talent.
His love.
I'm not going straight like this is it?
I'm fucking riding it out.
Woo.
That's a dark song.
It's fucking soul to it.
Is that a guy that's still alive or.
Yeah,
he's still alive.
I mean,
it's just a song.
He's not a junkie for real.
No,
no,
no.
I mean,
I mean he actually might be,
might be kind of fucked up real then.
That's another thing about the ame thing
is it's like.
Yeah,
and Kurt Cobain,
Tim,
it's like,
Whoa,
what is that connection?
We're like these freaky,
freaky both both vocal wise and they
write their songs like it makes you
wonder like,
why is there always like this crazy
adverse effect on the other end are like
heroin.
Yeah,
yeah.
Or yeah,
well heroin has some sort of connection
to like this deep moody pain that a lot
of blues singers and a lot of jazz
musicians and a lot of a lot of and roll
stars figured
out a way to tap into and find some
resource of creativity in that realm is
just so destructive to your body while
you're there.
It's so,
so devastating.
The fact that you're a junkie,
you're not taking care of your health,
and it's not even necessarily even
primarily the effects of heroin,
but the side effects of the lifestyle of
being a junkie,
that the lack of sleep and the terrible
life and the,
the terrible food and just the chaos,
you know,
that's,
that's what cripples them all,
crushes them all.
There's people that are like functional
junkies that exist for a long time.
They can live for a long time.
It's weird,
but it's like even being an alcoholic,
it's not just the alcohol,
it's also the lifestyle that you live
this unhealthy,
lack of sleep,
lack of recovery,
you know,
lack of nutrients.
It's not just the alcohol,
it's the fact that because of you're
throwing all this alcohol down your shit
hole or your,
your mouth hole,
you're,
it's,
it's coming.
It's,
it's affecting your whole body like
that.
Those decisions to drink that much booze
that affects everything you do.
You're not gonna,
you're not gonna.
Drink that much booze and also eat like
an incredibly nutrient rich organic diet
and you got to go to Erewhon and get
fucking salad bar.
You know,
you're not going to do that or a drunk.
Yeah,
I think it all goes bad and I think with
a lot of these junkies they just give in
to the fucking sound that given to the
siren to given to the song of that beast
to takes it into its veins.
Then you sing a song like that.
That's another thing with amy is like,
you also see that she had this amazing
voice to her whole growing up and she
wanted to be a musician and she was
doing good and she was doing good and
good and good.
Good.
And then she,
then she started heroin and then it's
like immediately,
you know,
even the documentary shows and it's
like,
all right.
And she started doing heroin.
All of a sudden it goes from these tiny
little jazz clubs to like amphitheaters
to hold new songs,
you know,
Rehab the album,
uh,
back back to black or back in black,
which is just all hits like out of this
world.
And it made me wonder.
It's like,
wow,
I just wish there was like a,
a like some kind of a,
what's the word?
Like fake system or a prototype or
something that you could try.
That would be like,
what would I write if I was on heroin?
You get to peak.
We shouldn't try to open up the present.
We should all get together like a
professional issue in any drugs with you
do some heroin ride the white snake,
whatever broken pot with you is probably
45 percent of the time.
Why would anybody want to do heroin with
you?
That's what do you understand?
I always love that you never come to any
of those mushroom trips with us either.
Like it makes me think like you know
something about yourself that you don't
want to solve it.
No,
no,
it's just,
you know,
when I'm on mushrooms and stuff I,
I like hanging out and not being a
retard and not having like a bunch of
people around me.
Like I like I like just know one
other person,
you know,
either a girlfriend or like a best
friend.
I don't need 20 people getting in like
20 different things that could go wrong.
Well,
not only that,
at least one of them's going to have a
problem.
Yeah.
Every time you have a group of six or
more people that are doing mushrooms,
one person freaks out.
They always freak out,
become your problem if you don't watch
out,
you know,
like I,
I like being quiet.
Not just fold them your problem,
but there's some people that when you're
on trips with them,
they want to dedicate the trip to their
trip.
They want to dedicate your trip to their
They want your trip to be about their
trip.
Dude,
I'm seeing this and do this as
happening.
Dude.
I'm feeling this like,
Hey,
I'm over here doing my own thing,
man.
I don't want to constantly be involved
in your reporting of your trip while I'm
tripping.
So like if you have too many people
together,
you can't.
Like you gotta have you gotta trip with
someone who knows how to shut the fuck
up.
Right?
That's a big part.
And that's what's incredible,
is that that always blows my mind is
that's how it ends up happening when we
take our little,
like the holiday that are shipped,
fear started streaming fest.
So once a year we go out there in the
middle of the beautiful desert.
You wait until the moon set its
brightest of the year,
the supermen.
And it's always incredible how quiet and
beautiful it gets.
All these guys like six slash seven,
I guess it's normally like five,
six,
seven comedians that spend every other
night talking,
just you see them.
We all end up scattering.
It's not like we're sitting by a
campfire or anything and you see little
story outlines of like,
oh,
that's Ryan Mervis over there just
standing there and you.
It is.
It's amazing how quiet that beautiful
desert can be with these personalities.
You almost feel like the power of it a
little bit.
It's a potent psychedelic drug man.
And if you use the right intention,
if you have the right ideas going into
it,
and if you can handle it,
you can get some wild thoughts out of
it.
They're very beneficial and people will
dismiss people like,
you know,
people that have done it.
They'll say,
well,
you know,
I don't even like what he does.
He's done mushrooms and why would I do
it?
It ain't.
It's not disputable.
Like the experience is not disputable.
It's powerful.
It's undeniably powerful.
It might not be for you.
I don't know you.
It cares.
People have depression cures,
people of addiction,
cures,
people of cigarette addiction,
people of Alcohol,
addiction,
curious people.
It's give.
It gives you a chance to look at
yourself in a way that you probably
would never be able to get to without
it,
and it'll give it to you for a short
window to get to see yourself.
You get to see live.
You get to see intention.
You just see the past.
You get to see the present.
You get to see it all combined together
and some strange light of this other
worldly intelligence.
It's weird,
like overwhelmingly powerful new thought
process that's going on in your head or
just overwhelmed and you're seeing
things and the visualizations when you
close your eyes are spectacular.
And uh,
somehow or another it's illegal.
Insane as the best part about
it.
It's so stupid.
It's the stupidest thing to have illegal
ever.
Yeah.
Like this.
The one thing that makes people better,
like we,
we know it,
like it's John Hopkins University did
the whole thing.
They did a thing on people that are
dying.
People that have had.
No,
actually it was a personality that was a
different one.
They did one on people that are dying.
They gave them a silicide ben and
significantly alleviated their stress
levels.
And then they did another one on people
that John Hopkins one was,
they had these people do a psychedelic
experiment,
psychedelic experience.
And then like over a decade later,
they were still saying that the quality
of their life significantly changed.
After that experience.
A lot of them were saying it.
There's a lot of benefits.
There's a lot of these different things
that they made illegal in 1970.
We just got to face up to the facts.
We've got fucked by the same people that
had Nixon in power,
Lyndon Johnson and those types of people
that we shouldn't be held prisoner these
old ways of thinking.
Totally.
You know,
but I think that law enforcement and
the,
you know,
a lot of people that control laws and
have laws in place,
they're very reluctant to give up a law
or to admit that all the arrests that
they made were unjust because it opens
up this giant bow backs of,
of Shit.
You know,
like looking at all these people that
are in jail for nonviolent drug crimes.
Now those drugs are legal.
What the fuck do you do with all those
people in jail?
You know?
Yeah.
It's crazy.
Once Seattle,
they,
they're letting people out there letting
people,
people that were in for pot and people
that were selling pot,
they're dropping their cases
and you know,
it's one of those things too where,
you know,
what's crazy is like,
I guess you haven't seen making a
murder,
but it's like,
I know the premise though,
but the pain,
the premise is that like,
you know what?
He was in prison for all those years,
so maybe he did do this and if he did do
this,
he did it because he learned these bad
ways in prison.
Yeah.
Which brings it back to the jug people
is.
It's like they might go in,
be in a pot dealer and come out being a
rapist murderer because they jerked off
for months to their bunk mates fantasy
that he told them,
oh yeah,
I tied this bitch up and it was the most
fun,
you know?
And they're like,
wow,
that sounds interesting.
And they get out and just start doing
crazy stuff like that.
That.
Yeah,
that,
that.
There's a lot of those things,
right?
[inaudible].
I mean,
that's the recidivism rate of these
presences.
Insane because.
And I did all this research on it when
Jeff Ross did his prison special for
comedy central.
I learned all about this stuff.
Jeff had a really powerful thing about
that,
that he.
He didn't like,
it wasn't an interview or what it was.
I tweeted it,
I forget what it was,
but he was talking about like what he
learned about the prison system and how
hopeless it is for the people that get
stuck inside of it and then you hear
about things like that guy in
Pennsylvania,
that judge that was sending these kids
to a juvenile detention setting these
kids up the river for like nothing
because he was getting paid for it now,
God that he's in jail now,
but he was selling children to
prisoners,
to prisons,
to private prisons.
Essentially.
That's what he was doing.
It was.
There was a scam.
He was being paid off to continue to
supply them with prisoners.
So he was taking these kids and just
ruining their lives.
Wow.
Like ruined countless people's lives.
Took people for minor offenses that
should have never done time.
They just kids and just locked him up
and fucked him over and then he kept
them trapped and imagine how terrified
you'd be your 15,
16 year old kid and you do some normal
kid shit and all sudden you get
railroaded through this justice system
and this guy who corrupt sends you to a
detention to get you away from your
parents and all of a sudden you're
locked up and some fucking juvenile
center somewhere with a bunch of real
legit criminals.
Yeah.
That's like insane.
It doesn't mean that all judges are bad.
Right?
Right,
right.
It doesn't mean all judges would do
that,
but fuck,
fuck.
GotTa gotta come up with
better system for dealing with people
because it's almost like when someone
does something wrong,
we just write them off.
Just write them off and send them to
this hole and lock them up in this cage
where Shit's just going to get way
worse.
And if you.
If you don't want shit to get way worse,
you have to follow by the rules or you
get stuffed into a concrete and metal
box forever.
Craziness.
It's insane.
But what do you do?
What do you do with someone who is like
a lifelong criminal and is broken
mentally,
like how do you fix that person?
I think you've put them in a
stormtrooper type of setup and just make
them a soldier and ship them around the
country and program them to only be able
to do certain things like robocop
program.
Yeah.
Like Hobo Cop.
Like have like these fucking.
You got to there just because you had
hobo copy of your head down.
You said Robocop.
I
wouldn't,
I wouldn't set myself up for a Hobo cop
that.
But uh,
what movie was that were they reprogram
people's mind returning.
Ah,
that's it.
Thank you John.
The answer to that.
And the other guy,
not just van dam.
The other guy.
Yes.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Universal soldier was shit.
That was a good movie.
Yeah,
it turned them into.
That's right.
That's exactly what it was.
Look,
that's totally possible.
That's probably possible before they
even figured out how to do the robot
thing.
Yeah.
I probably figured out how to program
people's minds.
Oh yeah.
No Man.
It's just a matter of time,
you mean?
Yeah.
It seems like Schunk glove and dum,
dum,
dum.
We got laser design.
It must be serious.
It was so hilarious.
What's that?
Oh yeah.
Tiny Lester in the background.
That's hilarious.
Those movies were fun.
I roasted tiny list are at that same
roast with a.
That screech.
Was that what?
Let me ask you this.
If someone came along.
Okay.
Like what if somebody
was in a motorcycle accident and they
were essentially brain dead and some
doctors came along and said that they
have the ability to turn this guy into a
soldier robot and you can go fight for
his country like your,
your,
you know,
your brother's Dad,
Tony.
But uh,
we can keep them alive and have them go
defend his country.
I'm going to send them over to
Afghanistan.
I mean,
hey,
might as well better.
They haven't buried,
right?
Do you think so?
Isn't that what deadpool does?
Deadpool comic isn't think I love.
Isn't that what?
Isn't he have like a super powers or
some shit?
They gave him some sort of bad ass
powers.
He was going to die or he's given
terminal.
Oh,
see,
that's a comic book that I was never
aware of.
So when this one comes out,
I am completely out of my element.
I don't know anything about.
That was a marvel though,
right?
It was a marvel comic arguing for it
too.
That's pretty good.
He didn't dress well.
This is a movie that almost didn't get
made,
but then they made a really cool like
trailer.
Someone made a fun trailer and the
interest for it picked up.
So they decided to make the movie.
What's the movie?
Deadpool,
they made this fake Valentine's Day.
Tried to trick some people a true love
never dies.
Valentine's Day.
Romcom style posters and Ryan Mental.
Just taking full advantage.
Oh yeah man.
It's going to be interesting.
We're gonna have.
There's gonna come a time where they can
sort of re reanimate a human body,
put an artificial brain and it might be
the first thing they do before they go
to artificial intelligence.
Take some dude because his head blown
off.
It's like that dead dog.
It was hard.
It's still hanging on.
Not,
not,
not thought out yet or not.
Uh,
not thickened up.
Yeah,
they just keep it going to slap some
robot head on there.
Screw it down
like robocop style,
like a pit crew.
Isn't it funny how like Robocop,
when you watch that movie back in the
day it was like this is so never going
to happen.
Right,
but today you're like,
well I bet they could probably do it
there,
but we're probably pretty close to being
able to come up with some artificial
limbs that are more strong and more
dynamic and they just have to have some
sort of a power source.
There is robocop.
Wow.
He had a dope outfit to the new robocop.
I never saw.
I wasn't really into the new outfit that
you just didn't.
This is the new one.
Did you watch the new one?
No,
I didn't know either.
I think that is the new one.
I met that dude.
Yeah.
See why?
Why does he have his hands covered?
I'm gonna Chop your hands off,
which we've got to have your hands
covered.
How come you.
Your mouth isn't covered either.
Shoot you right in the mouth one
identified the weak spots.
Yeah.
You don't want to have an exposed mouth
hole one.
Yeah.
Why would you ever have your exposed
mouth?
He's got his whole face.
His whole faith is ready to be shot
because I'm assuming
there's a brain back there,
right?
You got skin.
So there's,
you know,
I'm gonna shoot the right to your
eyeballs in your brain.
So stupid.
You know,
like he's got like a regular human
mouth.
Why would you have that?
When everything else is protected,
you can't project.
You'll have some sort of a speaker on
the outside.
There's so many veins and important
arteries that run around equity or how's
it gonna eat with no teeth.
It's gonna get shot in the face with a
Canon in Detroit to do,
you know,
it seems like the best place to put it
today.
It is.
Yeah.
Right.
No one seems to have seen this movie.
It must have been a robo flop.
He out.
He had it.
He delivered it.
You were stunned and now you're
defensive.
True.
I actually went and saw the movie and I
eat a lot of popcorn during it.
I was a Robo slop.
Oh,
come on,
Robo.
Stop
cleaning house in here.
Somebody grab us a robo mop.
Your guys' expectations are too high,
right elbow.
This is a pun battle battle.
But red badges.
One to you.
One to me.
He did.
Oh,
why do you keep making this?
What I do?
I go,
how would you like me to react?
I'll do whatever you like.
I don't know.
Like,
oh,
la La,
la,
la.
That's the pun.
Laugh.
Could you imagine
cracks upon on stage and the whole
cargo.
Ah,
LA,
la.
That would be awesome.
Dude.
Fucking manifested.
You better.
Be careful what you wish for full.
But you wishful young Tony.
Tony's going to be with me Friday night
and then land in my special comes out
and then Saturday night and Tampa,
you will already be a star by the time
you get on stage.
It'll already have launched and people
will know and you'll be doing all new
material.
Yeah,
that's the beautiful thing with this.
You did this a few months back,
like how many months?
March.
So it's almost a year.
Yeah.
So,
um,
and in that time you've got a whole new
hour.
Uh,
I have a new,
yeah,
30,
35,
somewhere in there.
It's ever changing.
You know,
sometimes I've been realizing lately.
I don't know.
Yeah,
it's wibbly wobbly.
So you about your,
bounced some of it out and started going
all knew as soon as I taped it.
A lot of guys I guess like start when
uh,
when it comes out.
Yeah.
But like I,
I was ready to move on anyway.
Well you already,
you knew,
um,
also the,
you were going to try to get this on and
you get ahead of the game,
right?
Going out of the bat knew.
Yeah,
I just did the fighter and the kid and
it actually came up that like they're
like,
you know,
are you doing all new stuff
now?
And I talked about how,
you know,
working with you being,
you're one of the few guys in the whole
game that also,
you know what I mean,
like generates not also you're one of
the few comedians that has like a new
hour a year or you know,
and so like working with you even though
you've never said to me personally like
you need to write more material.
Like it naturally I think rubs off that,
you know,
were you got to just keep going and plow
and like if um,
if you,
if you can do it with an hour and a half
or two hours after my half hour than I
should be doing it with my half hour,
you know.
So it's,
it helps a little.
When you do a longer sets,
longer sets on the weekends helps,
you know what.
But anytime you can get it in a half
hour,
if you can get in a half an hour set,
you know,
the real problem with La is if you're
going to do a spot in La,
you probably going to get 15 minutes.
Right?
And when you get those 15 minutes spots,
most likely you'll have room for one or
two new ideas and you'll have,
you know,
I always try to balance it out if I'm
doing new stuff,
unless I did like I did stand up on a
spot last night,
which is obviously all adlibbed and that
was really fun.
But when you do new stuff you've got to
kind of like,
it's,
it's hard to decide like when to start
the new stuff.
Do you open with the new stuff or do you
open with something established?
Get the ball rolling and then introduced
the new stuff.
You don't have a lot of time to fuck
around and like 15 minutes set.
Yeah.
And I also,
you know,
I like to bounce in and out once in a
while of crowd work,
you know,
and him improvising stuff onstage and
uh,
said that's also mixed into things.
And that's also part of the reason why I
shot this in one shot because I just
went with my gut and I'm like,
if things go off the track,
that's normally when I shine is like
you,
you see like sometimes when we do our
shows that those big theaters,
like I'll do a thing where our roast
people,
a group of people,
if they come in late and I warned the
crowd in the beginning.
Like if somebody comes in late I'm going
to light them up,
our little secret.
Okay.
And the place just loves it.
And I love that,
you know,
just improvising in the moment.
I love that pressure.
I love that feeling of like,
you know like being a quarterback and
you feel like that line backer coming,
but you still have to get rid of the
ball.
You have to just stay calm and deliver.
And I think part of the reason why I did
it all in one shot is because I knew
that if something,
which it didn't at all and I didn't end
up doing any crowd work and I sort of
was half planning,
like I was on the towing the line right
before I went on,
like,
you know,
anything can happen.
I knew that I only had one show which is
rare in itself when shooting a special
to only have one show in one audience
and one camera and I was ready to do
crowd work,
but I just sort of,
you'll see in like the first 15 seconds
I just sorta like,
you know,
just saying hello.
And then I go right into material.
You get into it,
you wouldn't do it like a regular show,
right?
Yeah.
I ended up just doing material and it
sort of stayed on track.
There was a part where uh,
like,
I dunno like 35,
40 minutes in or something.
My throat goes dry,
which like never happens.
But like I was like sorta like,
choked up a little bit.
And I take a sip of my water that's
sitting there.
Now you'll most comedians do a.
most comedians take a sip of their drink
when they're getting a huge applause
break.
This is a special special.
Then they just giggled because they all
know that,
hey,
I gotta take a leak.
I'm so sorry to interrupt you,
but I've been holding this in for awhile
for some strange reason.
So Brian talked to him real quick.
Tony.
Wow.
Normally you bust my balls when I have
to pay
Brian White.
Uh,
yeah.
It was cool that they're doing the one
shot.
Did you,
after it was done,
did you think like,
oh,
I wish I would have done that different
or this different?
Was there anything that you kind of wish
now looking at it that you did
different?
Other if you had the chance?
Of course.
I mean naturally,
you know,
after doing that,
I mean there's always like,
you know,
things that change are different.
Like for example,
like I close with,
you know,
even in March I had a different version
of the cosby thing that I do now.
But it totally different joke entirely.
You were like,
Bill Cosby's innocent.
I know it's true.
Well,
sort of it was because now in my cosby
joke now has everything to do with how
he admitted to giving girls Quaye lutes
and rape them and the cosby joke that's
on one shot.
It just covers the fact that like
basically it's all these little white
girls that hooked up with a rich black
man for the first time and they just
felt dizzy because his dick was so good.
That's right.
So I just ruined the ending.
Is that A.
is that a real curl?
If you show the camera,
your curly hair with this one,
it looks like it's like a tightly curled
up in.
Sometimes if you have a bow now it's
just my curly Italian hair sometimes.
I remember when I had long hair.
Yeah,
that's right.
He's going to from my apologies.
All good.
That was a close one.
Oh,
it was interfering with my ability to
form conversation.
I was like,
Ooh,
yeah.
Maybe he's Brian Moses Story.
Turn it planted the seed.
Maybe just let it go.
Yeah.
That's not a good idea.
Imagine if we come in here and it smells
like piss everyday.
ASPARAGUS piss.
Hmm.
Have you repeat herself?
Oh,
for sure.
Yeah.
Who hasn't?
I mean and then had to wear your pants
for a long period
car once in a like a mountain dew bottle
or something like that.
Like whatever.
I had like some sort of a soda bottle
got pissed all over my Fiat.
It's really hard to do because you don't
realize that you need to have enough
extra air around it or else it just
sprays back at you.
I've done that three bottles.
Good.
Gatorade's good.
Yeah.
It's very girthy,
gatorades.
Other ones you have to also use two
hands because you want to hold your Dick
over the hole and you want to hold the
bottle and you can't do that while
you're driving so you're trying to like
get your Dick in between your two
fingers and then use your ring finger
and you're to kind of hold the bottle
while you're squeezing your dick through
and don't put your balls in either,
just to keep those out when you're doing
it.
There's no reason to put your policy in
there.
Well,
you Brian can actually falls into a
bottle of mountain dew unless you have a
moonshine jug and your truck.
Imagine if that's how you died.
You hit a bump in the moonshine jar,
broke and cut a vital artery under your
cock because you turn to
the mountain dews a dangerous bottle.
The pen,
because it's green,
so you may have forgotten that,
uh,
you know,
you peed in it.
That's true.
That would be.
You're just one of those fucking
Weirdos.
It picks up bottles on the floor of
your,
your car and just start drinking warm
liquid and you can fuck up.
Yeah.
I used to know this guy who would take a
mountain dew bottle of mountain dew or
Ginger Ale and he,
one of those green plastic bottles.
He would fill it up with booze and he
would drink it all day long.
He was like a serious,
serious alcoholic that I worked with on
this construction site when I was a kid.
It was weird,
man.
He would just drink all day.
It scared me,
scare me watching him because this guy
who just drink this stuff all day and it
was only going a day or two into the job
that I realized that it was booze,
talking to people that it was,
he would drink malt liquor and just all
day,
all day,
just drink a fucking.
And he lived in this house.
The house had no electricity,
um,
most of the windows were out,
like we were working on it.
We were renovating this house and he
lived in it while we were renovating it
and it was real weird and he was like a
construction guy.
He worked,
he worked with the guy who owned the
construction company that was renovating
the House and I'm pretty sure as hard as
foggy to remember because I was a
teenager,
but I'm pretty sure the guy who was
renovating the house also owned it.
It was just like fixing it up.
And so this guy was living in it at the
time when it was like gutted out,
just raw wood and no insulation.
Some windows are missing and just don't.
Some of the floor was missing and Scott
would just get wasted all day,
just drink and shake hands,
would shake any on hammer and nails and
shit and his hands are shaking,
carrying things out and it's just,
he,
he was just deep in the web of
addiction.
Yeah.
Did you ever see anybody like that when
you're young because you grew up in a
rough neighborhood,
right?
I,
uh,
yeah.
I'm actually very close to somebody who,
who am I?
My oldest brother uh,
became a slowly over time,
a big alcoholic and he's been a three
months sober now,
which is a miracle.
Like it's unbelievable.
And because it seemed like he was never
going to stop and when he stopped
drinking he was shaking so
uncontrollably that he had to.
He couldn't even walk.
He would just fall down and he's a
strong guy.
This is a guy who like,
I remember going to Venice beach with
them when I came and visited,
just to check this place out when I was
18 to visit our other brother.
We,
me and my other,
me and my brother came out to visit our
brother that lived here and they played
basketball on Venice beach and they were
just balling all over everybody,
like he's an amazing athlete and this
and that and what he was doing that he
was drinking.
Yeah,
but even still on that,
he was drinking at night.
Not during the,
the,
I mean,
yeah,
they were drinking during the day too.
It was so much booze that his body was
just completely hooked on it.
Totally Day every single day and night
because he was a professional bartender
and in Columbus,
Columbus,
Ohio even has a big drinking culture,
like huge drinking culture park.
Europe does huge.
And um,
he was like at the helm of it,
he's like the head bartender at all the
best places in Columbus over the past 20
years or whatever and that even Columbus
as a culture for it.
But also I don't think a lot of people
know that the restaurant industry has a
real,
real culture for it.
Everybody that works in fine dining
restaurants goes out and gets shit faced
every year,
like 80,
90 percent of the people because you're
taking care of people all the time.
You need to get fucked up.
You need to.
You need to go get treated.
They walk in shot beer,
shot beer and then starting with
restaurant workers.
Right?
Huge,
huge.
Jeff's waitresses,
bartenders,
huge culture of it and I'm sure Barnes
worth has to get liquored up once in a
while.
You know what I mean?
Barnes worth probably does.
Estrogen locks the door and just takes
extra shots,
drinks it.
But yeah,
to watch my,
you know,
physically powerful.
A brother will not watch,
but I heard about it because he's in
Columbus and I'm here,
but those dark.
But luckily he's.
He's doing really good three months
sober,
which I,
if you would've told me three months ago
that he had actually stopped drinking.
You know,
I've gotTa said that's very hard to do.
I wonder if mushrooms were legal and if
they had real treatment centers,
how many people would be curative
diseases like that.
I want to say diseases,
addictions like that.
How many people would be cured of,
uh,
a lot of different things that they've
been struggling with psychologically,
if they could use Ibogaine here in
America,
which is super effective in Mexico and a
lot of other countries where it's legal,
where they use it for treatment for
addictive diseases.
It's supposed to be incredible for
kicking people off of pills and opiates
re literally reprograms your addictive
tendencies in your system.
Somehow with molly,
molly,
molly related,
they said that too about ptsd for
soldiers.
That molly's giant for that
the government paid for tests on
psilocybin.
It like Carnegie or Harvard or Cornell
or some stuff and they kept finding that
it cured chronic depression on people
that like they had given up and just
said,
it's for life.
You're going to be depressed for life
programs.
Totally see why I'm reprograms your
brain apps.
It's like a shower for your brain,
like when everything's just too
cluttered and dirty.
It's the only real analogy that I think
is effective for mushrooms.
It's like a brain shower.
It did this thing that I absolutely love
that I found out about a couple of years
ago called Neti Pot,
you know about that run warm water
through your nasal passage and it's the
same thing like I think to myself every
time I do it,
like I can't believe people don't know
about this because you know the squeeze
one.
Yeah,
that's what I have.
That's what I have for you.
Blasted up there.
Oh my God.
It'd be was crazy.
I remember I used to use that when I had
my nose operation when I had my nose
chewed open.
I had a really bad scar tissue inside my
nose and I had a deviated septum and a
lot of the scar tissue was like a.
It comes calcified because if you've
been hitting the nose a few times,
if it bleeds inside your nose,
it's like cauliflower ear,
but inside your nose,
this is a cutaway.
All this different tissue and open up
this passage and then to clean it,
I used to use a waterpik so it squirt
the water,
pick up one nostril and it'd be pouring
out the other nostril and I would blow
out these fucking titanic boogers.
They looked like they were from another
planet.
There were giant and covered in blood
and they were like the size of a thumb.
Like they would come out and I would
treasure them.
I'd be like,
I want everybody to see this.
It was like at your Dick pic back in the
day I showed.
I opened up the Napkin Forum,
did Tom's cigar and he went
over in the airport.
I'll never forget it.
I go,
dude,
I just fucking blew the most insane
booger out of my nose.
I go,
do you want to see it?
He goes,
AH,
okay.
I'll open it up and it's like this.
It's like rubber cement glue.
So like as you pull the page on the side
that the Burger was so big that it just
didn't seem like it come out of a human.
Didn't make any sense and he's
immediately have.
You have to get that done though,
folks,
if you find a good doctor.
I know some people have had bad
experiences with a doctor that didn't
really know what they're doing.
That was a life changer for me to get my
nose cleaned up so I could breathe
in Neti pot.
I mean,
uh,
you know,
you got to do it right.
You gotta make sure you put the packet
in and use distilled water and warm it
up.
And I mean,
it's one of those things too where when
I do it,
I'm like,
Ooh,
tonight's going to be a good night.
It.
If you have a broken nose,
that's still not going to work.
If someone did,
you need to get that operation.
If you have a deviated septum so you
can't,
you really can't like do yoga correctly
without breathing in through your nose.
It kept me from doing yoga a lot because
they would always tell me,
you have to breathe that.
He knows.
I'm like,
I don't have one.
It doesn't.
It doesn't exist.
I could smell a few things,
but it's just jacked in there,
so Neti pots wouldn't have worked.
It just.
It just wouldn't have worked,
but now that it's clean works.
Awesome.
Yeah,
so salt water to pour those little salt
packets in the water and shake it up.
It's my favorite fucking thing.
Do you ever find yourself,
don't you bend over to tie your shoes
like Oh,
an hour later and some water leaks out
of your nose a little bit.
Where the fuck was that water hide in
the corner of a hole in my head.
Maybe store in water.
Like I bent over to tie my shoes and I
was like,
what is this drip drip,
drip,
drip.
Drip
happened to me during that set,
like just one little drop,
but that's that last night when that
ladies like,
no,
trump's,
you're never going to.
It came out of nowhere like bloop and
I'm like,
what is salty?
You get it gives grab someone like that
and take them out of the room.
You can't interrupt the show like that.
That's so stupid because that's one
person that the Irvine Improv,
500 people,
so it's one person deciding that in 500
people that I'm sure a giant percentage
of more laughing because I know the bits
hilarious.
Oh,
it was insane.
That's why like people were booing her
before I even said,
what's your problem lady like it was
just can't have to deal with that.
Just people don't get it because they
look at you and they go,
he's just talking,
right?
They go,
Oh man,
he's going to make people in this room
vote for trump.
It's like,
no lady.
You're the only one that's not realizing
that you're at a professional show right
now.
Well,
not only that,
how,
how weak is your candidate.
A comedian could talk you out of it and
goes,
fuck these poor people.
Bernie Sanders is an old loser.
Donald Trump's right.
Do you think trump really wants to be
president because it seems like he's
going to be.
Yeah.
I'm not bullshitting people like you're
wrong.
You're wrong.
He is way out ahead on the republican
side.
Yeah,
and more people are willing to vote
Republican now than before Obama was in
office.
There's a lot of people that have
strengthened the resolve against
liberals and against the left and
against the Democratic Party.
It's highly.
If he just.
If he just changes his tune on a few
things,
he could get me know if he needs to
change his tune.
He's saying stuff that I think a lot of
people are thinking.
That's one of my alien bugger.
Oh my God,
that's a bugger.
That was a bugger isn't it?
Looked like a cockroach nest or
something.
So look at my hand.
Looks like one of the planets from Star
Wars.
Look at my hand here to wean the thing
that you can get a good because that's
the kind of a inflated picture,
but you could see how big that was.
It was like that,
but that is a real booger.
That and that was a little dry like it
when it came out like maybe a minute or
two before that.
It was a little larger that when you had
that crazy shit the other day and you're
like pushing your kids out of your way
and everything,
do you remember what you ate or what
causes?
My God,
that's the one that made Tommy gag
because that's the one that made Tommy
Gaggs God.
He was like,
I took a photo of it in the bathroom.
Then I put it in a Napkin and I brought
it out to them that weren't really.
Is that something else?
What did you ask?
What did you just ask?
What made that crazy shit that you're
talking about?
Oil.
Pretty sure I had too much mct oil.
If you put too much mct oil in a kale
shake or a protein shake or something
like that.
Occasionally there's like a tipping
point.
I don't know like how many cups is like
I should probably figure out like what's
a beneficial dose instead of just adding
cap foals and I might have added an
extra cap full and I might have drinking
much more than I usually drank and a
whatever it was the fucking click,
the sear snapped and the fuck.
Oh,
it's funny,
Max,
when you have five year olds,
they don't want to hear nothing.
Like you can't say the house is on fire,
but Daddy,
I can't find my toy.
Like whatever they're dealing with is
like so critically important.
I'm like,
I got to get it.
I'm going to shit on you.
How many shit.
I knew your faces.
Where my ass is.
You've got to get out of.
Can't stop it.
Like I was with all my bike,
my bike.
I was tightening up a massive crowds
squat you've ever done in your life
counts for this moment.
The cramps when I was like,
oh no,
I don't know if we're going to make it.
There was that moment where I was like,
I'm going to shit at least a little bit
in my pants.
Maybe we'll just let the prisoners out.
A few hostages out.
And then we renegotiate.
Once I get to the bathroom,
I managed to keep it together just right
to that point where I was born.
Yeah.
Can you just hear Mike Goldberg's voice?
It's all over.
Um,
mct oil though.
We'll make you shit yourself.
Well,
you have to be careful.
You have too much of it.
It will definitely.
It just lives up the old pipes and just
releases the hounds,
but it's probably a good thing because
once it goes through like a blast out
boy feel.
I've been taking healthier poops than
ever lately with this new meat in flux.
My body is just loving it.
They're so solid that every time now,
every time I take a poop,
you know when the.
When you get the splash back to I'm at.
I'm at $100.
I get.
I'm at 100 percent slash back now.
Have you ever gone back?
Have you ever had your Bible Open up
enough?
Just after it splashes and gets a little
teardrop inside the net.
A little bit comes out later when you
retire.
Shifts.
Dilly vegetables though.
You still emotionally?
Totally.
I'm definitely look different.
I'm not bullshitting.
Your face looks filled here and I
haven't even had breakfast or lunch
today.
You look like your face looks thicker.
I feel better.
Yeah.
Vegans right now are so angry.
No,
you just stay the course.
You just didn't follow the right.
You didn't have enough keen one,
your diet.
What about Avocados?
What about olive oil?
Hey,
Mr. Verge on.
It's been.
It's been a lot of fun to get back
because I love food.
I'm huge on food.
When you guys went to Fogo de Chao,
right?
That's where you broke your cherry,
which is meat lovers paradise.
I've been there for a child a couple of
times with you without eating meat and
salad.
It's amazing.
You could easily fill up on the salad
bar with no fucking meat whatsoever.
It's a great restaurant.
Yeah.
Those Brazilians know how to eat,
man.
The two.
Haas Korea's.
They're amazing that if you don't know
what it is,
there's Fogo de Chao,
Texas de Brazil.
Those are the chains,
but there's a bunch of independent.
You asked her ears and a Brazilian style
barbecue.
What it is is you have a chip and one
side is green and the other side is red
and when it's green they come over with
these trays of meats like sausages and
chicken wrapped in Bacon and Full Layman
Yon and p Kanya,
which is like top Sirloin,
which is like the best one.
That's the best.
Hide that one all the time.
There's just so many people want it.
And there is the place you used.
We used to go to.
That was called [inaudible].
Where was that?
Oh,
that's in Pasadena?
No,
no.
Uh,
Burbank.
Yeah.
Right.
Is there a place in Burbank called
Pecan?
Yeah.
Where was that?
I think it's in Burbank.
I think there's a place in Burbank
called pecan yet,
but it's the same,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Same style food.
It's fucking so good.
Yeah.
So they come over with these,
these pitchforks with meat on them.
These skewers with meat on them and
slice it off.
Yeah.
That's the one on the right.
A Bay hide it.
But uh,
if you like meat,
you got to go at least once.
It's Pr.
It's so good though too.
They figured out the right way to baste
it in front of an open fire.
Now they slowly cook it so good.
And it's unlike a regular stick with.
They come over and they slice pieces on
the outside and they put them on your
plate and then they go back to cooking
it again.
Like they based it again with their
whatever they have that it's like a salt
and some sort of an oil to it and bred
in 13 days.
You to.
When you came to the comedy store the
other night,
we were all saying that.
Yeah,
I could clearly see it.
You were glowing the other day.
I even went home and mentioned to my
girlfriend.
I'm like,
Brian looked good today and you just say
that while you were inside her.
She goes,
she goes,
what do you mean?
I go,
he's been working out for like 24 hours
and he already looks better.
She goes,
that's impossible.
I go,
no.
I just think Brian was so unhealthy that
literally if he doesn't poison himself
for like a few hours,
you start to turn into Tom Hardy or
something.
It's great.
You're doing so much good shit.
Now you taking care of yourself.
You're.
You're on the side kick that's lasted
through the entire month of December or
January.
Whether you're doing your podcast now,
like so much good shit's happening.
That's awesome.
It's awesome,
man.
Feel Jon Benet Ramsey,
you know,
you feel lighter.
What does that mean?
What does a Ramsey me?
Good,
fucked.
No,
I don't know what.
That doesn't make any sense.
He's laughing to cover up as.
I don't know what was like the joker now
from
that joker photo I made of Tony.
Uh,
that's crazy.
Have you seen that photo?
That's like one of my dreams is I want
to play.
I want to go onstage.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I really want to be like the next joke
or I think they think Nicolas,
what Nicholson did is amazing and I
think what a heath ledger did is great.
And uh,
I'd love to eventually get to the point
to where down the road,
you know,
it could be like a young joker.
That's totally possible,
especially if they keep making more
Batman's.
And I think like,
especially if I keep growing as a
popular comedian,
I think it's like a cool twist.
Like,
you know,
marvel hires actual comedian to put the
joker.
Who Better?
Who better stand up,
comedian turned evil.
Look at you,
insult comic,
feel it turned evil.
Dude,
you're,
you're porn for that room.
Tie first before you
come on.
Brian.
Brian,
if you break your diet,
you're doing so good in this house.
What happened?
We're going to go bad on
Tony.
You've always felt like you've,
you're going to die young and stuff,
but you always talking about like,
like
notes on me over there.
What are you doing?
Just checking.
You're a fucking wikipedia.
Has
Brian made that to promote the.
It's more like a Zombie Jared leto joker
that he made.
That's not the right.
Oh,
well Jaron Leno's joker like pretty
fucking deal too.
So he's the joker in the suicide squad.
Was another one that got.
He got ripped for that.
Why?
Because the joker is a bad motherfucker.
The joker's the best bad guy of all
time.
Why did he get report?
Uh,
you got to look that up.
Um,
because,
uh,
because the joker is a bad motherfucker.
Like normally it was a bad motherfucker
as an actor.
Totally come on.
But there's a thing where like,
he shows himself working out in the,
in a superman shirt or something.
Anyway,
a problem with people just look for Shit
to complain about.
No,
it's good.
It's a good thing.
It's amazing,
like he's pumped.
Whoa.
That totally could be used,
Tony.
Totally.
Especially now with your new Diet and
you're looking at lifting a little Tush,
what kind of car is that?
What does that.
Is that a real car?
A PONTIAC?
Jamie.
See they're probably introduce some new
car.
They do that sometimes we'll click on
it.
I'm assuming.
Is that an Acura Nsx?
No,
that's a Jaguar,
right?
What is it?
Does it say so cool.
What does it fade or Aveda?
Huh?
Oh,
okay.
Some car I'd never heard of.
So neat.
Tony Hinchcliffe.
We're starting to make some money now.
You're bowling.
Going to get a new automobile.
Tony.
Angela Bay door.
You gotta get a new vehicle.
Um,
maybe.
Maybe I can see Tony in a corvette.
Oh God,
I'd love on those ones.
No backseat.
Sorry.
Oh,
sorry.
Your friends can't come.
I want one so bad.
But I have to be smart.
But the truth a little bit for it until
at least until Friday.
January 13.
I want to spend.
When you knew nothing special comes out.
Yeah.
So what it is the 13th.
Is that what I say?
Fifteen,
15,
two days away?
How did I get it wrong?
Both times by three?
I said 18 and 13 to 1:15,
2016.
Our two by two I can't even count.
And a lot of uh,
cool guest appearances in it.
Like a,
um,
Joey Diaz brings me onstage and Brian
Red Ban I high five because he goes in
and goes up after me while check drop
happens and stuff because it was a real
show.
Right.
And uh,
do you,
um,
did you feel more comfortable because it
was at the Ice House place you performed
countless times.
Oh yeah,
no doubt about it at home.
Two weeks out when I booked it,
which by the way,
super huge shout out for the Ice House.
Sean Sullivan over there two weeks out
goes two weeks before I shot this.
He goes,
Hey,
you want a headline?
The Ice House to Saturday,
7:30.
I go,
ies,
and quick question,
would you mind if I taped it with one
camera in an attempt to shoot a special?
And he goes,
absolutely,
that'd awesome.
I go,
oh,
okay.
Okay.
Bye.
Like,
you know,
the rest is history.
He was there that night.
In fact.
Well,
fun fact about that is if you noticed
when we saw the trailer,
there was one guy that's sort of like
walked off.
That's Shawn,
which I think is so cool.
It's like a perfect little tiny,
tiny,
tiny cameo you have.
You'd have to really pause it at the
right moment to see him.
But he was so responsible for it
happening.
And uh,
wait,
what was the question?
Oh yeah.
Being comfortable with the ice houses
with the two weeks notice that I had.
I literally,
I'm not even kidding or exaggerating in
my dreams at night was envisioning it
and I'd like,
you know,
it would be a nightmare or a great dream
depending on.
But I was like picturing it and during
the day I was picturing it and where I
wanted the steady cam to be because,
you know,
Ben Wolfensohn,
my really good friend,
amazing director directed the beginning
of a Ari Shaffir special and uh,
and um,
trip tank on comedy central.
But like,
you know,
this was my idea of shooting it all in
one shot.
It's a great idea.
That's a great way to also to capitalize
on that small club.
Right.
Well,
I knew I had to do something special
that really stand out,
you know what I mean?
Because I don't have,
you know,
tv fame or anything like that.
That's so many,
you know,
networks and everything
looks for anything that anybody's going
to view it based on the fact that you
shot in one shot.
I think
more people.
I think that's why they got it.
I don't think they're like,
you know,
let's,
let's take this.
Nobody out it
nowhere.
And you know what it means.
You're funny.
You stopped.
That's bullshit.
You ain't got it anyway.
If you did that thing at the Irvine
Improv,
you,
you would have still sold to Netflix.
You're very funny.
You're doing great and you have heat
behind you.
You have heat behind you and you
connected to a network of other
comedians that have heat behind them.
That's another thing that I'm so honored
to be up there with Sigur.
Uh,
you know who joe,
who's came out two weeks ago and is
amazing and everything about it's
amazing.
This whole fucking national persona
changed.
Like people really became aware of who
barry.
His paper was always like peeking.
He was always like ramping up,
becoming more and more famous every
year.
But once his netflix special came out
and it was probably his best special to
date,
he just smashed it and then became a guy
who sold out Madison Square Garden and
that's,
that easily can happen to you.
It could happen as a girl to cigars.
New special is even better than his
other one.
He's fucking smashing it right now.
Yeah,
he's killing it.
It's,
it's the best platform for comedy.
It's an amazing time that we live in to
where like that can happen.
A guy that's never done the tonight show
or I've never done standup on TV at all.
I'm starting first time ever
public.
Netflix our.
Yeah.
I mean,
think about cigarette too.
Same thing.
It doesn't have like TV credits,
right?
These are selling out theaters
over and over again.
They keep adding shows to his comedy
works this week.
How about Sebastian's shows Thursday two
shows.
Friday three shows Saturday.
They just added a midnight for him.
This Denver Bert
comedy works to me selling out comedy
works.
Yep.
Well,
he's a monster,
right?
Amazingly,
he's a legit,
like worldclass national headline are
right now.
And it's all from,
you know,
working and grinding and doing specials
on the Internet.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
And from podcasting,
getting connected to people through
podcast,
his podcast to him and his wife at your
mom's house.
They have this tour that they do on the
road with it and it's,
it's a whole thing of it's own.
Like they have all these little things
that people look forward to like Tom or
black,
like they'll play tom or black.
They'll play like they have little games
that they play.
Brian and I do the road when we,
uh,
when we go to ones that we drive to,
like if at the San Diego or Phoenix or
San Fran or a sacramento,
which is like the majority of the places
that we do go.
Uh,
that's the only podcast that we listened
to and we'd fucking crackup hilarious.
You just laugh and laugh and laugh.
It's the,
it's the funniest podcasts.
It's the only podcast that I really
listened to.
That
last one I did with Tom,
last podcast I did with Tom was one of
the best ones we ever did.
It was fucking hilarious.
Like the entire time we're just laughing
and gagging and slapping the table for
three hours.
Just me and him like cracking each other
up.
He's such a great guy.
He really is.
And He,
you know,
he's just the best.
He gave me a call yesterday and he gave
me some cool advice and just is a great,
great guy.
And he and I,
because you know,
this netflix thing is also like a
different path.
It's a,
it's unchartered territory and he's
helping me out.
Being like a cool big brother that's
awesome to me is this whole thing
happens and unfolds.
I couldn't be luckier.
We were so lucky that something like
Netflix exists because if you do a
special on anything else,
like say if you do an HBO special,
they aerate whenever they aerate.
They might hear at once,
they might have it twice,
they might erode a few other times.
It might air it randomly 3:00 in the
morning on some special night.
But with Netflix it's always there.
You just press start,
you just press play.
That's the secret.
That's everything with their amazing
algorithms that people that would like
it is,
are going to get a shot at it.
You know,
everybody has a different screen when
they turn theirs on based on what they
watched and if they liked it and if they
rated it and even if you don't rate
things,
it's still knows you that their
algorithm is like world world,
world class.
It's really interesting.
So the more that people would like you,
the closer you're going to get to their
front page.
So
yeah.
You know,
I didn't know there's the ratings on
Netflix movies,
like if it says like four stars or
whatever,
that's not actually the rating or the
mood.
It's what they think you would say the
rating is.
So like.
Yeah,
so like there was one movie I watched
the other day and I was like,
how has it half a star?
That movie sucks so bad,
but it's really,
it has a half a star and I was like,
oh wait,
that's.
If you look at somebody else's,
it'd be like three stars and we'll.
Yeah,
I didn't know that.
That's bizarre.
It's really bizarre.
That doesn't seem like that doesn't seem
kosher.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
I could.
A star system should be kind of like
what people think.
Maybe they'd want it to get that to
avoid like a disgruntled person,
like giving it like a really bad reviews
under a bunch of different fake names or
the opposite,
like maybe a company that like,
like we've,
there's been that before where someone
put out an independent film and then
someone hacked into the itunes comments
section and it's all just overwhelmingly
positive,
like fake reviews of this terrible
fucking movie.
And then someone in the comments,
we'll post.
These are paid reviews.
Like this is not real.
This movie's fucking terrible.
I've seen them.
Yeah,
me too.
So maybe that's what Netflix,
trying to avoid rotten tomatoes.
Pretty guilty of that in general,
I think it's like there's some hard.
Yeah,
it's hard when you've got a comment
system,
people don't hack it,
you know,
people like they've hacked itunes
ratings,
they figured out how to get higher
ratings and pretend they have more
downloads or have like multiple
different services that are like,
download your shit just to like juice up
your ratings and,
and add comments and like the algorithms
that someone like itunes has like easy
to manipulate because they're based on
downloads,
they're based on comments and they're
based on New People.
So if you just have a bunch of new
people sign up and then they leave a
comment and they download it,
it'll jump you up in the rankings.
It's kind of interesting how they.
But I guess you can only sign up for
itunes so many times.
Right?
So that's probably how they avoid it.
Right.
And it has your public name on their
side.
It's like even if you lose your account,
you don't want to be like,
this sucks.
And then have your real name on there.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's true.
Maybe itunes is the right way,
but it seems like the right way.
I don't know,
man.
I don't think there's anything like
Netflix might have a point there though.
Like in your circle of people that you
like.
What did those people think it was star
wise versus in the circle of like 70
year old people that live in nursing
homes.
What did they think of Bob and Dave's
new show,
you know.
Fuck.
Are we talking about
business?
Our Algorithms.
All right,
let's wrap this up.
Let's bring it home.
Um,
Friday.
I'm Tony Hinchcliffe will be with me in
Atlanta and heartland at the tabernacle.
The Shit it's sold out if you did not
get tickets.
So sorry,
we'll be back.
But uh,
that night Tony's one shot will appear
magically on Netflix in your queue.
That's Q,
u,
e downloaded and joy.
Let a motherfucker know on shot one shot
five.
Keep that bitch fivestars.
And um,
then we'll be in Tampa on Saturday night
and then we'll be at the UFC on Sunday.
Excited about that one?
Yeah,
that's a big one.
It's a big world championship.
Dominick Cruz versus Tj dillashaw.
That shit should be off the hook and a
good end of the weekend for us,
you know,
have a couple of great shows and then
head on there.
Brian red band.
Who's your guest this week?
I'm still finalizing it,
but uh,
I'll let you,
I'll announce at Cognito and gentlemen,
we keep it on the dl until we release.
But you do on Fridays.
Usually do every Friday.
If I have two episodes,
a one with St Francis and sovereign and
one with Mc crist and Christian mingle.
It's called what Brian Redman do.
It's itunes subscribe,
rate and review.
Helped me out.
Boom.
And uh,
January 22nd and 23rd or 24th.
Me and George Perez will be at the,
at Improv.
So boom.
Okay.
Beautiful.
That's death squad TV.
You can get information for that.
Killed Tony is every Monday,
pretty much every Monday at the comedy
store.
We have our biggest one
ever at this Monday.
That was the one that everybody's been
asking for.
The biggest one.
I'm not kidding.
I'm not always doing now because we're
going to announce it on the Guy God cast
tomorrow,
so you're going to know who that is
tomorrow afternoon and also real quick,
caroline's.
I'm headlining New York City for the
first time ever,
February fifth and six a week after we
do the beacon theater together.
Carolines on Broadway.
February,
fifth and sixth helped me out in New
York City
to fill those seats and a beacon
theaters.
I think it sold out.
It was not sold out.
It's basically sold out almost.
So if you're thinking about getting some
tickets,
jump on that end of the month.
You fuckers.
Thanks everybody.
Much love but by big cash.
No.