Top of the morning to your fuck face.
Hi everybody.
It's early for her very early frost.
This episode of the Joe Rogan experience
is brought to you by stamps.com if you
have not heard postage
rates have changed yet.
Again Ladies and gentlemen,
which by the way don't complain about
that because if you had a fucking take
that it's postal service
is a great service.
If you had to actually take your shit and
move it across the country and give it
to somebody else,
it would be worth so much more than you
actually have to pay in postage but and
even easier,
more convenient way to handle everything
is stamps.com with stamps.com you will
eliminate those time consuming
trips to the post office.
Everything you do at the post office
you can do from your desk at home,
buy and print official US postage for
any letter or package using your own
computer or printer and printed
brother and stamps.com always updates,
updates the postage rates
for you automatically,
so you will always get the exact postage
that you need the instant you need it.
You never have to go to
the post office again.
How Gloria says that I say quite,
quite glorious and I want
to use quite that often.
Um,
if you enter in the code word J r e on
stamps.com there's a little old school in
microphone.
In the upper right hand corner,
you will get a no risk trial.
That includes a $110 bonus offer,
a digital scale and up
to $55 or free postage.
So don't wait.
Go to stamps.com before
you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinjrethatstamps.com
and
enter
j r e were also brought to you by ting.
Ting is a no bullshit mobile service
that uses the sprint backbone.
They make it so that all the stuff that
you normally have to deal with when
you're dealing with large providers
is eliminated early termination fees,
eliminated,
contracts eliminated.
They just want to sell you good cell phone
coverage at a reasonable rate and 98%
of people would save money with Tang.
That's a bold statement,
but it's not my statement,
it's Dang statement.
So if it turns out to be bullshit,
don't come back to me.
But what I do know is that I have friends,
like a doctor,
Chris Ryan who switched over to tig.
Fucking loves it.
A Red Band switched over to ting,
loves it.
Excellent service and much cheaper
than what they were getting before.
Um,
the waiting is set up.
You can buy high end android phones.
Like they,
the ones that they sell,
they sell the top end phones like
the HTC one or the galaxy note three,
which is what I have.
They sell the um,
all,
all the like the really cool and groovy.
Okay.
Android phones,
excuse me.
Like the,
I guess the mega black,
if you're like so fucking crazy that a
six inch phone is not big enough for you,
you need a bigger home,
take it down a notch son.
That's just going to go away.
You know,
that's like,
that's like spinners on wheels.
It's not going to last.
It's a fad.
It's a fad kid.
Uh,
but ting,
the way they have it set up is a,
you can even bring over phones,
some of the phones from sprint.
Um,
if you have,
uh,
like one of the android phones,
HTC one LG g two a million of these
fucking things at this point in time.
There were these to be a large gap
between the iPhone and the android phones,
but that gap has been crossed and what
they have now is just a bunch of really
cool phones.
And,
uh,
all the bullshit that you would
normally have to deal with is a,
is out the window with Tang.
So we're,
we're happy to things a sponsor.
We're happy that people that have
used Ting and a contacted us,
excuse me,
have had nothing but
positive things to say.
Everybody
delicious coffee to try
to warm my brain up.
Everybody that's used it,
uh,
has had nothing but
positive things to say.
So the website is rogan.ting.com.
Go there and you'll save 25 bucks off of
any new cell phone that they have there
at tig.
We love it.
We're big fans.
Go there and enjoy.
We're also brought to you by on it.
That's o.
N,
n.
I.
T.
If you haven't been to on it for a while
then you probably missed the launch of
our Zombie Bells.
If you are preparing for
the Zombie apocalypse,
there's no better way to get in
shaped in a fucking kettle bell.
It looks like a Zombie's head cause
it's scary and it's motivating and it's
acid.
Actually Three d balanced to
give you a proper workout.
Just like a real kettle bell.
It is a real kettle bell
and it will last forever.
I mean,
these things are fucking solid metal.
The 72 won the 54,
the 36 and the uh,
the 18 pounds,
all these different kettle bells,
um,
they're not just beautiful to look at.
They're actually fully functional.
The only thing you have to make sure is
that you have the face facing towards
you when you do like cleans
and things along those lines.
So the,
the back of the Kettle Bell,
which is nice and smooth,
it's what slaps into your forum.
You don't want that knows
to go digging into your arm.
But it's simple.
It's easy to use.
Uh,
if you are interested in getting in
shape and starting to do a strength and
conditioning workout,
I beg of you.
If you can please go
to a personal trainer,
someone who knows what they're doing
and just learn the basic fundamentals of
the movements.
And when you're learning and when
you're doing it and practicing it,
do it with a lightweight.
I know you want to be a manly man.
I know you want to show everybody.
How would yo dude do focus 72 pounds?
Don't do that.
You're going to fucking hurt yourself.
Started out with lightweights
and one of the websites that a,
when the videos that we support on
the website is the Keith Webber,
extreme kettlebell cardio workout.
And I've told many a person,
I work out with 35 pounds with
this and I am in fact a manly man,
but that's all you need is 35 pounds.
This what this workout will kick your ass.
Crank it up to 45 pounds
and you'll be a dead man.
That's right.
I said it.
Keith Weber is a stud
and he does it 45 pounds.
But he's more studly than me.
All right?
That's something I'm
dealing with with my life.
But what you need to deal with with
your life is get your shit together,
son.
Get yourself in shape,
feel better,
be happier.
And one of the best ways to do that
folks is get your body move in.
If you don't have the money to buy a
kettle bells and fucking workout DVDs,
goddammit,
go online and watch some
videos on bodyweight movements.
Just bodyweight exercises,
body weight squats,
sit ups,
pushups,
do something you lazy.
Fuck.
Get your life in order.
A big factor in getting your life
in order is pumping the blood,
getting everything moving,
giving yourself a feeling
of accomplishment every day.
Wake up and do a little
work out just a little.
Give her some 10,
15 minutes,
something.
Drink water instead of soda.
You fucking freak.
Come on,
get your shit together and we
would love to help you at on it.
Um,
use a codeword Rogan and save
10% off any and all supplements.
It's o,
n n I t code word is Rogan.
Rejoice.
Kara Santa Maria is here.
We're going to talk some shit about,
some people want to drop some knowledge.
She's going to science us.
She's going to educate us.
Who are we talking shit about?
I don't know.
Okay.
I'm sure you'll find somebody.
Boom.
Create the music.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Try by day Joe Rogan podcast by night.
Well,
the last time you were here
you coined a phrase or you,
you used a phrase that I have stolen
and abused over and over and over again.
I give you credit,
but it's Wu peddler.
Oh Yeah,
love that box show pro.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
I typically didn't coin that,
but I,
I love it too.
I use a lot every time I see that dude,
I just think Wu peddler.
Yeah.
We have a little kind of Twitter
thing with him that yeah,
it was,
I was calling him,
I asked him if he whooped pedaled much.
Yeah.
And then,
and then it was something about,
he was saying like,
I am a god and you were like Woo,
pedal much.
And he was like,
oh,
it was really funny.
I favorite at it.
But yeah,
he was actually like,
he was,
he had a good sense of humor about it.
I don't think he takes
himself totally seriously.
Yeah.
He's not like cult leader.
Seriously.
Yeah.
I think he gets a,
he gets a hell ahead of himself and
he said some really ridiculous shit.
And then when people call him on it,
you know,
he just starts using the word quantum.
Yeah.
There was that shit in there with a bunch.
Quantum consciousness is room.
Mm hmm.
You know,
I think better him than a lot of other
people in his position better him.
Then you know that Kevin
Trudeau guy that's selling
you weight loss secrets that
they don't want you to
know about [inaudible].
It doesn't seem like depot,
I mean is trying to sell his books.
But outside of that,
I don't really feel
like he is that much of,
you know,
like a predator.
Like he's not using this
kind of pseudoscience and,
and truth be told there is a little bit
of truth to some of the things that he
talks about,
but,
but he does kind of,
I think step way outside of the boundaries
of what's reasonable and healthy.
But you're right,
I don't think he's actually trying to
take advantage of people fundamentally.
I think that Deepak Chopra
thinks what he's talking about.
I mean he believes in what he's talking
about and I think that he actually
thinks that he's helping people
and maybe it's helping some people,
but he's also peddling a lot of,
Whoa,
I think,
I think he probably is helping a lot of,
yeah,
I think he's definitely
peddling a lot of woo.
And the one thing that I always get out
of him is that I don't think even he
knows what he's saying.
I think there's a lot of times where
we'll put the people and we'll try to
impress upon you then what
they're saying is important.
And one of the ways they do that is by
using these like really kind of like
vague terms.
That sound fantastic.
Yeah.
I mean that's really,
I think where that term
pseudoscience comes from.
It's not real science.
It's,
it's,
it's fake science.
It's bad science.
But it sorta sounds like
science to an untrained ear.
And that's the dangerous thing is if you
throw around a lot of really big words
and you are really authoritative,
a lot of people kind of believe what
you're telling them what also there,
there's an issue in that.
Some of it does have some truth to it
and when you fuck around and pretend that
it all does what you mush it all together,
you,
you create this really cloudy atmosphere.
Well I'm under,
I'm not sure what the fuck you're saying
and I'm not sure if it's true and it's
really hard for like an
everyday person who goes,
okay,
well I've heard that before and you know,
my doctor told me that and you know,
that seems important.
And then they throw in all
these other things will,
I mean,
if you're an authority figure and you're
saying all these things that are true,
I guess I should believe you.
When you say all these other things,
it's a really dangerous,
um,
you know,
that's the,
that's it right up there.
He says,
I was an atheist Hashtag
until I discovered I was God.
And then I said,
son,
don't make me smack you.
We'll peddle bunch.
And then he responded.
He responded something really funny.
I don't know if you can find it.
Yeah.
Like I roll God in drag.
We're all God in drag.
That actually is very funny.
I was like,
oh,
that's pretty awesome.
No,
he did a thing with his son where his
son followed him around with a camera and
completely exposed him.
And he went on tour,
like promoted this with his son and did
like interviews on like opie and Anthony
and all these different places.
But one of them was like his son,
like caught him sleeping when he
was supposed to be meditating.
I'm going to the tumbled to meditate.
I mean,
they go into the tumbleweeds,
he's completely out cold
line on his back and it's,
it's,
it's quite funny because his son sort of,
you know,
grew up with him and his sons and
fathers have notoriously contentious
relationships.
I'm always incredibly impressed when I
meet a daughter who gets along great with
her mom or a son who gets along great
with his dad because somewhere along the
line and those male,
male,
female,
female relationships,
there seems to be this like changing of
the guard or something like that or this
need to be your own.
And
[inaudible] son has that shit in buckets,
buckets full of that.
And it's cool that Deepak doesn't
really take himself too seriously.
It's cool that he,
you know,
his son catches him asleep and he's like,
yeah,
but put it on the Internet.
And again,
I was not,
was traveling,
it was a way I was,
my third eye was open
to the possibilities.
Yeah.
He did a,
uh,
an interview or a debate rather with
Richard Dawkins fairly recently on,
I think it was,
uh,
he was challenging Dawkins on the
concept of atheism and you know,
and Dawkins was just being
his cadre old country settled,
but it actually made it actually
made him Dawkins look bad.
That's the thing.
It's,
it's when you engage in those kinds of
conversations with people who can really
hold their own,
you've gotta be really
careful because Dawkins,
I think he's take and I
respect the man immensely.
His take is very much an educated,
you know,
I'm an evolutionist,
I'm an evolutionary biologist.
These are the reasons that
I don't believe in God,
but he's very hard lined about it.
And there is something about
being this kind of ivory tower,
British elite that just kind
of makes you seem like a dick.
He's not a dick.
He's a really sweet man.
I've met him before.
He's,
he's soft spoken.
But the truth is you,
you put those two men in a room together.
I mean Depok knows what he's doing.
He knows that like part of a debate
or part of the conversation is about
bringing out certain aspects
of somebody's character.
It's about likability and I think it's
easy for people who aren't already kind
of hard lined atheist and
who aren't already big dock
and supporters to be like,
that guy seems mean.
Well,
I think he is mean.
I disagree with you.
I think he is a dick and I think he is
mean and I think that's because he's had
to deal with idiots over and over
and over again and he's an extremely
intelligent man and he's tired of it.
It could be that and it gets this
quivering and his lips when he talks to
people,
no,
that's not what's going on.
Then it gets so furious about defending
science and defending the truth.
I don't think he's a dick in an unjust
way and he's a dick for a reason.
He's a Dick because he's a normal guy.
I think he's also a dick because he's a
normal guy with a lot of knowledge that
doesn't have a lot of
release in his life probably.
And he's also,
I think he's also sheltered
a little bit because of the,
his position because of,
you know,
when you work in academia and you're
kind of surrounded by likeminded people a
lot and only periodically do you go out
into the real world where there's a lot
of people who don't have the education
that you have and who have totally
different values and belief systems.
Uh,
I'm sure it can be really,
really frustrating because
you're constantly having
to defend a position that's
the rational position that like anybody
else who's come up through the ranks
that you came up,
uh,
you know,
97% of practicing scientists or
something like that don't believe in God.
And maybe it's not that high,
but 97% definitely,
you know,
know that global warming is true.
And I think maybe it's something like
75% in America don't believe in God.
Um,
but we're like a very religious country.
But when you kind of go
through the motions and you just come
to these logical conclusions because of
all of the different
life choices you've made,
but then you interact with people who
are from such different background,
who have never studied evolution,
who have never studied,
you know,
global climate change or whatever.
It's like talking to a wall sometimes
because you almost can't have the same
kind of reasonable conversations because
when you're talking to somebody who's
not coming from a rational
evidence based place,
who's coming from kind of appeals to
emotion or who's coming from folklore or
whatever reason,
they have to defend their
kind of belief structure,
their faith position.
It's really frustrating because you don't
really have a lot of ammunition at a
certain point,
but especially when you're talking to
somebody like Ge Chopra who has like made
a career kind of being good at debating,
who knows exactly the way to twist your
words and to make it sound like what he
is speaking is the truth.
And then he's got this like
very benevolent kind of
kind and calm demeanor and
he's gonna make Dawkins look like a dick.
Oh,
see,
I didn't think that he did any,
any twisting them,
any words at all?
Oh really?
No.
I think,
you know,
he seemed like a woo peddler.
I mean,
to use your term,
he,
that's what he seems like,
but Dawkins was just getting so angry.
Yeah.
And it's that old saying,
you know,
never argue with an idiot because
people won't be able to tell who's who,
you know,
or that's not the same.
I don't know.
It works for me.
I would never,
like,
I would never debate a creation.
It's like people say,
Oh,
you should blah,
blah,
blah.
And I think like Bill Nye,
I don't know if it's happened yet,
but I suppose stowed debate.
Ken Ham.
That's insane.
I don't know why he's doing it.
I mean,
I have friends,
you know,
I'm friends with Sean Carroll who's a
physicist at Caltech and writes these
really great books about,
about time and about,
um,
uh,
quantum physics.
And he does periodically
debate creationists.
And I'm always like,
what are you doing?
That sounds like such a bad idea.
You know,
like because these people are skilled
just in the art of conversation.
They're skilled in the art of debate.
Even if what they're saying has no weight,
they know how to argue these positions
and try and trap you and get you on the
defensive.
They have all of these
different kind of uh,
uh,
skillsets,
but he always says,
it's not for me.
It's not to try and prove him wrong.
It's not to try and convince
him not to believe in God.
You know,
like this guy is it,
Ken Ham is like a hardcore
fundamentalist Christian.
We're never going to change his mind.
So they say the reason that we do
these debates is for the people who are
sitting there watching who may be like,
Ooh,
I don't know the difference between
evolution and intelligent design.
I've never thought about it.
I've never really looked at the evidence
that may be even a small percentage of
the people who decide to tune in.
We'll be given some sort of information
that they didn't have before that they
can be armed with to
make better decisions.
But I don't know.
To me it just seems like,
I mean I think it's a noble pursuit,
but at the same time,
I'm not sure how effective it
really is to debate a creationist.
I say,
I disagree with you.
I think you'd,
I don't think you're going to
convince the creationist no.
Dot.
Not at all.
But I do think that there's,
there's value in someone who's good at it.
If someone has the ability to speak and
speak well and also they have to have a
certain amount of charisma.
And I think the issue,
the Dawkins issue is that he gets so
emotionally invested in this fucking
horseshit that Depok spewing that he
gets angry and furious instead of mocking
him.
Like there's a brilliant exchange with a,
there was a scientist,
there was a,
a,
a panel and Deepak was
on the panel and this,
this,
a scientists stepped up and uh,
asked Depok a question and Deepak
clearly didn't know what the fuck he was
talking about.
But the way the guy handled it was very
sweet and he was smiling while he did
it.
Explain that he was in the process of
writing a book with Stephen Hawkings and
that he was in the middle
of this and then that I,
I don't,
he's like,
I understand those words you said,
but uh,
I'm not sure if they mean anything.
The way he said it was,
it was adorable.
Like,
because the guy didn't lose his cool
and it made Depok look like a fucking
idiot.
Where's it?
The same guy got up and said,
you know,
what is this quantum talk?
You're talking a bunch of fucking
bullshit and shut up and you don't know.
Then all of a sudden,
you know,
Deepak is this pudgy Indian
man that you're picking up
screams of racism and all
these other fucking
hot buttons get pushed.
Yeah.
I think the same thing can be done
skillfully with these creationists.
Fellows like shy.
I think the idea behind creationism
is it's so preposterous in,
in the form that we see it in the form of,
you know,
not,
not in the form of something
created the universe,
whether it's some sort of a universal
force that creates stars or the reason why
Adam's exists in the first place.
All these like fundamental questions
that scientists have as to why the
structure of the universe is what it is.
There's that,
but then there's this book that has been
translated from other books and then
they're sticking to
this fucking crazy book.
Just point out the other shit
in the book that's ridiculous.
Like the shit in the book
about not being on the,
where to deploy different types of cloth.
And they do that.
Usually they'll point out the shit
in the book that's ridiculous.
And they figure out,
you know,
and point out how,
if the book says this,
you truly believe this in this century
and science has unequivocally disproven
what it is that you believe.
You know,
it's one thing to talk about,
like you said,
uh,
you know,
these big questions like what came before
the Big Bang or you know what a lot
of,
I feel like I'm intelligent design
advocates confused for example,
evolution via natural
selection with a a biogenesis.
So they confuse the idea of
how a organisms have evolved
over time with how life
began in the first place,
which is a fundamentally
different scientific question,
different topic,
totally different field of inquiry.
And so,
you know,
a lot of times what they do is
they appeal to these two questions.
They say like,
well,
you don't know what existed
before the Big Bang,
therefore God done mic drop every time.
And instead of kind of allowing that,
it's to say,
you know,
okay,
neither of us know why.
Why has God the first,
you know,
answer that you jumped to,
let's look at all the other times when
you're saying that the answer is God and
we've disproven it over
and over and over and over.
And just because we don't have all of
the answers to every question right now
using the scientific
method doesn't mean that,
you know,
through through new tools,
through new lines of inquiry that we
might be able to answer those in the
future.
It doesn't mean that like,
just because we don't have,
that doesn't mean that there aren't
other philosophical answers to these
questions that don't rely on this
like very fundamentalist view.
I think personally that for example,
Bill Nye is going to be
able to hold his own.
He's a total bad ass.
He's not going to lose
his cool and Ken Ham,
if you've ever watched him in PE,
I mean he's a nut job.
Like he's a total oops,
some videos,
he's a total nutter butter and he will
lose his cool and he's totally not
likable like nothing about this guy.
He's likable.
So I think that maybe that's why bill and
I was willing to do it cause I've seen
Bill Nye,
right?
Go on like Bill O'reilly a million times
and there's kind of a mutual respect
there.
He,
he deals with bill O'Reilly very well
and I'm always impressed and just do the
one where is the O'Reilly is like
the Todd comes in to do that.
You can't explain that.
Yeah,
he was with Steve.
I'm with God.
Yeah.
It was so fucking funny.
I mean,
it's such a face balm.
It's,
he's a bullshitter I think.
I think he's a panderer.
I think what he's doing,
he's,
he knows that there's a bunch of fucking
scared old ladies bibles in their hand
that listened to his show
and he's on their side.
Totally.
I mean,
he's,
and he's honestly not even as bad as
rush Limbaugh and fucking who's the other
guy?
The Mormon guy.
Glenn Beck.
The late in life Mormon guy.
Yeah,
exactly.
You know,
I was Mormon.
Did we have this conversation
last time I was on,
I was raised Mormon.
Yeah.
My folks are still,
well my dad's still Mormon.
His whole side of the
family or are you from Utah?
No,
I'm from Texas.
Wow.
Mormon Texas.
There's a,
I mean,
what could everywhere.
They're everywhere,
but uh,
yeah,
born and raised.
Um,
less attrition has 14.
Wow.
When you were 14,
what was it that got you to,
I just didn't like I was,
it's,
it's so funny too,
because I hadn't found science yet.
It's not like I knew I didn't have
like all these answers available to me.
I just probably around like 12,
maybe 11,
like when you start questioning things,
I really started questioning things and
a lot of things weren't making sense for
me.
And uh,
you know,
just a lot of the answers that they give
you an the church like weren't sitting
well with me.
And so I was studying and I
was trying to figure out like,
you know,
I've been taught this is my whole life,
but it just doesn't make sense.
It doesn't sit well with reality.
And I remember going to
my father and saying,
you know,
I have all these questions.
I'm very confused.
I'm not sure.
I believe.
And the answer they always give you
is just to like really pray about it.
You know,
it's like they give you all of these
answers that aren't helping at all.
They don't,
they don't really improve
your confusion at all.
And so ultimately I finally
just came to him and said,
like,
I,
I'm pretty sure at this point that
I really don't believe in God.
And,
and attending,
which is a huge part of
your life when you're 14.
I mean,
when you're in high
school and you're Mormon,
you go to church for three hours every
Sunday you go to youth group every
Wednesday night you have all sorts of
family things like family home evening
every Monday night.
And then you go to seminary,
which is either Bible,
book of Mormon and then like pearl of
great price in doctrine and covenants
study every morning before school I would
go at 6:00 AM for like an hour before
school.
And it's,
I mean it's really intense.
It takes up a huge part of your life.
And when you don't believe it's kind of,
I mean you have to come out,
you have to come out.
Like it's,
it's so painful.
Like you're stuck in
this skin that's not you.
And I mean,
obviously,
I don't know what it's like for
somebody who is gay who's like,
you know,
scared to come out in their community.
But,
um,
I would assume that there's like at least
a faint similarity to that feeling of
like,
I can't live like this because
I'm lying to myself every day.
So I finally came out to my
father and it was like not good.
It was a difficult situation.
It was hard for the family
and I didn't end up like,
I ended up actually not having a
relationship with them for many years.
It's,
it's,
it's better now,
but at the time it was like
a really intense thing,
like as a 14 year old kid to be like,
oh I need to make this like
really intense life decision.
So your dad didn't want to interact with
you or you didn't want to interact with
him?
He pressure it was like,
so,
so my parents were divorced,
so I went to my dad's house every
other weekend and then like,
I think like a month in the
summer or something like that.
But we also went to his house on Sundays
to go to church together cause my mom
wasn't attending after they got divorced.
And so he basically told me,
um,
I remember the quote to this day,
I have a moral obligation to God to
force you to go to church until you're 18
years old,
as long as you're living under my roof.
And I was like,
I'm not gonna go anymore.
And he was like,
well then I guess you're not going
to live under my roof anymore.
Yeah.
So it was a really tough decision.
It was kind of like me or me or your
atheism and at the time I just felt like I
can't not make this decision.
So we didn't speak for a long time.
And I like didn't go to his
house for a really long time.
We didn't have a relationship,
but it improved over time.
It improved your very smart person.
I always assume that that's genetic or
it was assumed that there's at least some
element of that that's genetic.
I mean,
there,
it's intelligence is,
um,
thank you by the way.
But intelligence is a really,
really complicated topic in
neuroscience and psychology.
And so there's really not a lot of
evidence available that says that
intellectual ability is hereditary.
I have a friend,
he's dumb,
his wives dumb,
their kids stupid as fuck.
Okay,
there's something there.
There probably is something there.
And especially in terms of,
especially in terms of environment.
So a lot of times what can happen is that,
let's say that you have to,
you,
they do these twin studies all the time.
It's one of the only real ways
with human behavior to um,
to understand pure genetics,
right?
Because like my sister and I have
very different lives and we have very
different personalities and we have
very different intellectual abilities.
But my sister and I are genetically,
even though we came from
the same source DNA,
right?
Half Mom,
half dad,
it's all shuffled together.
You didn't get the same millennials on
your genes and we are literally night and
day.
But if you took two people who were
monozygotic twins who are identical twins
and those two kids got adopted out when
they were babies and they were raised by
two totally different people.
And this happens in nature,
a letter or not nature,
but you know,
it happens in society a lot.
And you study those two kids,
you'll find that the kid who grew up
in an impoverished environment with,
um,
you know,
who wasn't getting appropriate
or adequate nutrition,
whose parents were not highly intelligent
or educated versus the kid who grew up
in this very rich environment like this,
the kid who grew up in the impoverished
environment will not be as intelligent.
Like a huge part of it is environmental,
a huge part.
Same thing with my,
I mean,
you see it in animals to,
you put a mouse in a cage with nothing
there and you put a mouse in a cage with
all sorts of amazing things
for it to interact with.
Its brain is going to,
to actually grow larger,
you're going to see more
kind of neural interactions,
much more intense,
um,
branching of different neurons.
So now that's not to say that
there's not a genetic component,
it's just very hard to pinpoint
what the genetic component is.
It's been kind of an enigma
to be able to chase that.
It totally makes sense.
I mean,
there's so many different
variables and so many,
and like let's say you have a friend
who's dumb and his wife is dumb,
their kid might be dumb
because they don't know.
You know,
it's like they're not speaking
intelligently to the child.
They don't,
they don't have a really great
grasp of the English language.
They're probably not reading
very challenging books.
But sometimes you do see parents who may
be are limited but they so desperately
want everything that their kid deserves.
And the kid,
you know,
shines intellectually from the time their
kid and they really foster that even
though they might not even be able to
have an intelligent conversation with
their kid,
they're going to put their kid in
a great school and they're going,
oh,
he's so,
he's so gifted.
I want to make sure he's
always taken care of.
And that kid might grow up to be,
you know,
just a little genius and you see it a lot,
you see it where a child
grows up to be this really,
um,
you know,
academic star and his parents maybe
weren't exactly on the same page.
Yeah,
it is such a crap shoot when you deal
with life experiences and then you deal
with education.
I mean what,
just the teachers that you
get the school that you go to,
the books that someone
just by chance mate,
hey,
you might be interested in this.
And then boom,
a light bulb goes off,
a new door opens up your mind and
then you start pursuing that path.
And then there's like
even silly things like,
you know,
do you,
are you eating well?
Are you exercising?
Are you doing drugs?
Like those kinds of,
yeah,
exactly.
But those kinds of things,
they're actually the most fundamental,
you know,
because if you are,
there's actually a really high
correlation between intelligence and um,
or a,
a high inverse relationship between
intelligence and poverty because it's just
when you were growing up and you,
you don't eat enough and
then you're going to school,
you can't focus,
you can't pay attention,
you don't sleep enough,
you're working an extra job.
It's just so hard to get
ahead of the game that way.
And so there's so many
different variables.
And that's why I think fundamentally
whenever you have these conversations,
like is it nature,
is it nurture?
Well,
it's always both.
It's all,
almost everything is nature nurture.
There's some things that
are very heavily genetic,
like especially when it comes to deficits.
Like if you're,
you know,
if these two genes didn't split the right
way or if this cell migrated in this
direction and it didn't work that way in,
and then you end up,
let's say with some
sort of intense genetic,
uh,
difficulty,
you end up with a down
syndrome for example.
There's only so much you can do,
you can do a lot environmentally to
improve the lives it to approve your life
and improve your abilities,
but you still have down syndrome,
right?
And so you still might be dealing with
something of a ceiling even though I
think you can push that
ceiling up and vice versa.
You know,
you can do a lot kind of
environmentally to improve or whatever.
Um,
but there are still always
going to be some sort of,
there's always going to be some
sort of like genetic component,
but it is very difficult.
Sometimes the lines get really blurred
and it's so hard to tell from the
outside.
That's why we do experiments with animals.
I mean it's a really heavy reason that
geneticists so commonly use animals in
the lab because you can
clone a bunch of animals,
you can have a very specific
line of animals and then
you can do something where
you change some sort of environmental
component or some sort of drug,
or you do something with the brain
of these 10 different mice will,
all of the mice were clones.
So they started out
genetically exactly the same.
So you can't do this in humans.
You can't like make sure every other
variable is kept the same and then only
manipulate one variable because
we just grow up with these rich,
intense,
interesting lives.
But you can do that with animals,
which is why animal research is so
important to answer a lot of fundamental
questions.
It's really kind of fucked if
you stop and think about it.
There's like 300 million experiments
going on in this country.
I mean that's what humans are.
We're all experiments were all like,
this is what happens when someone plays
soccer from the time they were five.
Exactly.
What happens.
They only eat cake.
Yes.
What happens if your dad beats you?
This is what happens if
your parents ignore you.
Can you imagine if like your dad or
your mom was a really intense kind of a
cognitive psychologist or
experimental psychologists?
Like,
you know,
there's all these,
I don't,
I don't think that they're
necessarily true or,
I'm not sure how much
truth there is to it,
but there's all these like
tales about like BF Skinner,
who's probably one of the most
famous behaviorists and in history,
every psychology student
learns about Skinner.
Um,
you know,
like Skinner has a kid and then like all
of the things that he might do to the,
to the crib that his daughter
grows up in and exactly how,
oh,
I'm going to do an enrichment
experiment with my child.
Like I cannot imagine that
would be really intense.
Yeah,
that's a,
there's a lot at stake.
Yeah.
You kid might resent you for that.
Well,
you know,
we all resigned her parents
for some reason or another,
don't I?
Yes,
dude.
There's,
um,
there's a,
a story about a woman who,
uh,
owned a comedy club and had
a son who was a comedian.
And when he would cry when he was younger,
she would ignore him because she
felt like if she ignored him,
he grew up funny.
Yeah.
And it probably is true.
No,
not funny.
It didn't work.
It wasn't fine at all.
He grew up to be a con.
Yeah.
I grew up super depressed.
It's just shitty human.
But there is kind of,
it's interesting,
you know,
there's a recent study actually,
and I'm,
I don't know how much stock I put into
this because whenever there's like a
single study that gets a
lot of media attention,
that's how we do it in,
in this country specifically when it
comes to the media and science were really
bad about picking up.
Oh,
that study is really interesting.
So let's,
um,
let's pick it up and all the different
media outlets are going to talk about
this one study where we got one,
you know,
a dose of results and we're
going to say it like it's truth,
right?
But there was this recent study that uh,
we're all these different
comedians I guess.
I think it was in the UK actually were,
yeah,
like answered a self report questionnaire
and they found that there's a really
high percentage of um,
it wasn't psychopathy,
it was,
uh,
it was psychotic,
a personality traits in Comedians.
And so it's actually
kind of interested in,
in almost every comedian I talked to.
It's always like most comedians
are kind of fucked up.
Like,
it's like,
you know,
they're,
they're anecdotal kind of stories.
Are a lot of comedians deal with this
or they deal with that and you know,
that humor is kind of a tool that a
lot of comedians develop over their
lifetime.
I think,
especially Comedians who
specifically have like a shtick.
Like,
you know,
I deal with weight issues,
so all my jokes are about my weight,
ideal with my bad
relationship with my parents.
So all my jokes are about that.
And um,
yeah,
I,
I mean,
I dunno,
I don't think you can make any
sort of blanket statements.
There's probably like incredibly high
functioning people who have never dealt
with mental illness at all.
But I think there is some sort of like
really beautiful truth in comedy where,
you know,
there are a lot of people who are
very highly skilled at taking these
fundamentally human challenges
that we all deal with.
Uh,
whether it's mental illness,
whether it's feelings of regret or
feelings of loneliness or feeling like you
don't fit in and using humor as a tool
to really deliver these kinds of very
universal messages.
And there's a skill in that.
And I wonder if it's that maybe we
all deal a little bit with psychotic
personality traits.
We all deal a little bit with depression,
with anxiety,
you know,
pick your poison and that
a lot of comedians are much
more in touch with that.
They figured out a way to have this
vehicle for talking about these very human
experiences and they do it in such a way
that we can all kind of share in it and
laugh together about it.
I mean,
I dunno,
but,
well,
I read that study and I thought one of
the things it's a found issue with is
that they found 500
funny people in England.
Yeah,
I seriously,
I don't see that.
Maybe for England actually
never been to England.
Have you been to English?
Great.
I want to go.
I'm fucking around.
I love it over there.
I've been,
I've been all over Europe,
but I've never,
it's like so strange.
I've never been to like the,
the easiest country to travel to
because we speak the same language.
Yeah,
they're great.
They're,
they're fantastic comedy club audiences.
They love American stand up to their,
their,
their site type of standup
is different I'm sure.
But they're huge fans of American standup.
They tend to be witty and
a bit more reserved and um,
you know,
very good,
great wordsmiths great writers.
Um,
but they,
they studied 500 comedians.
This is the thing,
there's not that many comedians.
If you took America,
which is 300 million people and you said,
okay,
how many comedians are there?
There's maybe a thousand professional
comedians at a 300 million out of those
thousand how many of
them are actually good?
There's maybe 250 there might be 250
comedians in this country that are worth a
fuck.
Yeah,
it does make you question like how like
are they self described can be like how
did they find these people and
how do you get 500 in England?
You're going to have 250 in America.
I mean,
I just don't,
I don't buy it.
Maybe they weren't
professional committees.
We were,
they're just people who
found themselves to be funny.
Well it's also,
I don't know if their circuit
is as deep and wide is.
Ours is,
I mean you go to like New
York City has 20 comedy clubs,
you know,
I mean Los Angeles has,
God knows how many,
I mean we could just
sit here and just count.
Especially when you count
the Greater La area,
you branch out to places like Braya and
Irvine and Ontario and La might have 50
fucking comedy clubs.
It's not just la,
New York.
I mean every major city has at least
one or two comedy clubs and you know,
comic go on tour.
I'll look at the country and really big
comics don't even play in comedy clubs
at a certain point,
you know,
they're,
they're packing theaters
and we still do though.
We still work our shit
out at comedy clubs.
You have to,
at least for me,
I find that there's a certain amount of,
um,
the,
the intimacy that you get in a comedy
club is you can't get that anywhere else
in big theaters.
The big theater shows,
like I did the Chicago
theater this weekend,
which is like 3000 plus seats.
But like then I'll do the ice house,
like the little room,
which is 80 seats.
But that 80 seat room is like,
I'm sitting in like as close
as I am to you and you,
if they're laughing,
it's because it's funny.
It's a real intimate sort of in a a thing,
comedy,
you know,
to do it correctly in my opinion.
And to be really in touch
with what you're doing.
You need a,
you need a lot of different
environments to do it in.
I think that's smart.
I mean to,
to have kind of a lot of
different experiences.
So then you can really tell what sticks
and what works with different audiences.
And it's not just that,
it's also how you feel about
saying it to these people,
how they react to it and
how that resonates with you.
Because what a person says is,
is not just like,
this is what I have inside of me and uh,
this is how you react to it.
Comedy is one of the rare art forms
where you can't even practice it without
other people's input.
And so it's not just what you're saying,
it's how like this
conversation that we're having,
we'd be very different
if you were your dad,
if you were the guy who's the
Mormon who is still sticking to you.
So like the way I say
things would be different.
The way we would interact would
be different and much like,
you know,
we're talking about all the variables
that go into creating a human.
There's also massive variables going
into just creating conversations.
A conversation.
One of the things that I'm finding about
podcasts is that a conversation really
is kind of a piece of art if you can
listen to it and it's really interesting
and it becomes like something that's
enriching to you and inspiring to you and,
and the person and the people that are
engaging in this conversation are careful
with the things that they say in terms
of like they're an intensely focusing on
what they're saying and not just
just spitting out word salad.
There's an art to that and that that
art gets to you and then just sort of
enriches you.
I think that that conversation
and stand up comedy,
they're very similar in that way.
That standup comedy is like,
it's,
it's dependent almost entirely on the
environments that you do it in and the
people that are that are experiencing it.
Yeah.
And it seems like there's
kind of always a goal,
um,
whether it's spoken or not have
this sort of sense of universality.
The sense of like,
just because you and I are having a
conversation right now doesn't mean that
everybody at home who's listening
isn't a part of the conversation.
You know what I mean?
I think it's so important that
the topics that we engage in,
the things that we,
you know,
the emotions that we share have,
uh,
they resonate with other people.
And that's so important in comedy too.
Like there is,
I think there's something to be said about
just like a wacky person who says all
sorts of wacky things that are
totally out of step with everybody.
Oh,
that's so weird and
different and that's funny.
But I think that would lose
it stick after a while.
I think part of what's really important
in comedy is that there's these like a
universal kind of themes that are
touched on that people really relate to.
Because when you're like,
ah,
you're totally talking about me right now,
it's cause we're like
fundamentally selfish.
And I think it's important
that when we watch TV,
when we're,
when we sit down and you know,
pay money to be entertained,
that it feels like you're talking to me,
you know,
not the person next to me but me,
that I'm engaged in this conversation.
It's,
it's a part of our nature.
And so I think that there,
there is,
like you said,
a big art to that,
to reaching people,
especially people who may be sometimes
don't feel like they're reached,
you know,
I can't watch two and a half men and
feel like it relates to me at all.
Like it's like the worst
fucking show on television.
It's so not funny.
It's so does not speak to me
and I don't get it because it,
it,
it's like the most popular show,
you know,
everybody loves it.
Or like duck dynasty for example.
It's like one of the highest
rated shows of all time,
which is fucking insane to me.
But,
um,
but there is something,
I mean there,
there's a reason that these things do
really well is because there's a whole
cross section of people that they find
it to be like really relatable for them.
You know what I mean?
And I think that there's an art in that.
There's an art in creating television.
There's an art and doing radio,
there's an art and doing comedy,
any of these kind of
spoken word kind of avenues
I think shows like two and a half men.
Uh,
especially duck dynasty is sort of
a trick because what duck dynasty is
pretending is that you're looking into
the lives of these wholesome God fearing,
you know,
duck call chroma massive
now.
But what we find out now is
that they're just idiots.
And that also they've been doctored up,
they've talked to these people and to
grow in those fucking beards and wearing
cammo in doors and all the stupid
shit that they do is contrived.
And Yeah,
I do think that there's a
difference between feeling like,
you know,
I'm a part of this and
they're speaking to me.
And then there's this gross kind of a
base human desire to like be a voice to
like look in on somebody else's life
who has it worse off than you do so that
you can like,
okay,
no matter how hard I have it,
no matter what kind of
Shit I'm dealing with,
these people are fucking freak shows and
they make me feel better about myself,
which is such a gross.
Like that's one thing,
you know,
I work in television,
but I've also done work in
journalism and you know,
I'm still,
you know,
I'm 30 years old,
I'm on my course,
my career course,
I've been successful.
But at the same time you're always kind
of reinventing yourself and trying to
figure out your track in life.
And one thing that I've,
you know,
I go to,
I take a lot of meetings in Hollywood,
I go to a lot of,
you know,
this person pitches this science show
and I really want to do this thing.
And it sounds like,
okay,
cool,
that sounds interesting.
Let's talk about it.
We can take it to this network.
And one of the things that I
fundamentally always say no to,
I do draw a line in the sand.
I don't have the luxury of,
I don't have time to take that meeting,
you know,
like that's not,
I'm not there by any stretch and I
don't think that that's even a goal.
But,
um,
yeah,
just to be able to say fuck off.
I know I'm better than.
Yeah,
but,
but the one thing is if I do go to a
meeting my fundamentals that I don't do
what I have dumped kind
of humiliation television,
it's not something I ever want
to have anything to do with,
you know,
in the,
in the industry they might
call it conflict reality.
There's all these
different euphemisms for,
because what I do fundamentally is
reality TV because it's nonfiction
programming,
right?
I'm,
I'm mostly into the edutainment sphere.
I'm really interested in,
you know,
science based programming
or political base program.
So it's all nonfiction.
So it's reality in a sense.
It's not scripted duck dynasty or the,
or in the same,
I know genres.
So for me specifically,
I call that kind of TV humiliation,
TV.
A lot of producers call
it conflict reality,
which is not not a
place I ever want to be,
which sucks because
that's where TV's moving.
Like that's where the jobs are,
but I won't do it.
You know what I mean?
I don't see,
oh come on.
Like all the most popular,
highest rated shows are like that.
It's just a trend.
I really believe,
but it's trending down,
you know what I mean?
Don't you feel like we are well on our
way to idiocracy like you watch that
movie and they're literally watching
a show called ouch my balls.
Like the whole movie they're
watching out for my balls or,
yeah.
How my balls or something where they
just follow each other around and like
punch each other in the
balls and then the people,
oh that's hilarious.
As punching him in the
balls and it's like,
wasn't that jacket like,
isn't that what we're watching now?
Like that's so fucking,
you know,
speaking of the UK and TV,
have you seen this show?
Black Mirror?
Have heard of it?
It's,
I've not seen it,
but I've heard it's so fucking good.
And I'm super depressed
because I watched it.
I like binge watch it all in a weekend
and then realize that it was an
anthology,
but they only made three in like 2011
and like three in 2013 so it's done.
Like there was only six episodes ever,
which is super depressing.
So those of you at home who
want to watch this like morning,
there's only six episodes.
So make them laugh.
It's you.
It's like a,
it's like a modern day twilight zone.
It's really well done.
It's super dark.
But one of the really
interesting components about
it is that it has this sort
of Dystopian a technology angle,
right?
It's like future,
but not too far in the future.
So as you're watching it,
it's very relatable.
Like they use technology really smartly,
but just like we are,
you know,
just like I was talking
about this idea of um,
ouch,
my balls being the way
that television is going.
You watch this,
the show and they're all on their phones.
They have these,
you know,
these implants in their
heads are in their ear.
They're,
each episode is different but it's like
so believable and so sad that this could
potentially be the direction
that our culture is going.
Because I,
I mean now I'm driving,
you know I was just driving here,
which is a kind of a hike from Hollywood.
So I'm on the freeway like for quite
a long time and I'm looking at,
there's a little bit of traffic so when
we're stopped I'm looking into cars or
especially like city buses.
You look in the city buses and literally
every single person headphones in on
their phone,
like no interaction between other
people so dialed into their phones.
And what this show does really well is
take that component and like what happens
when we push it,
what happens when we go into the future
where nobody even cares about one
another anymore.
And they just live in this like weird
digital world and their Avatar is who they
are and they,
they,
they spend all their money
like buying their Avatar,
a new hat or something.
Like they don't like the concept of
wearing a hat and life wouldn't make sense
because who gives a shit what you're
wearing because your avatar's wearing this
hat and all the avatars interactive,
but you don't interact with it.
It's like fascinating because there's a
fear that that's kind of the direction
we're going
as far as like that was a long
interesting rent as far as a television,
like a television dumbing down
and becoming a part of idiocracy.
I think one of the issues is the
delivery method of television.
The first place is massively
flawed because first of all,
you're dealing with censorship,
censorship,
huge fucks everything up.
You're dealing with a gang
of people that you are,
you're getting involved with that
don't want to offend anybody.
They want to make sure that you promote
whatever values that represent their
sponsor.
Yeah,
it's all about the sponsor.
You're fundamentally behold into
your advertisers in television
and then you have those advertisers to
consider cause there that's going to
interact.
The intersect into your program.
Every,
you know,
x amount of minutes,
boom,
there's your show's gonna shut off
and then there's going to be dancing.
Fucking lizards are selling
and that's the most
important thing to consider,
right?
Because if you can't get
the advertisers come in,
you can't get the budget to make the show,
which means that you
can build an audience,
which means that you're not going
to get the ratings that you need,
but fundamentally you've
got to keep the advertiser.
So you are,
I think the bottom line for most is being
beholden to those advertisers.
Then you have something like Hbo that
produces something like game of Thrones
and it becomes massively popular.
It's a brilliant show,
incredibly well done.
And then you say,
oh,
wait a minute.
There's that too.
But that is not being
represented the that,
that,
that type of art form is
not being represented on
regular television because of
the restrictions.
Because exactly the delivery
method is just so fucked up.
That's,
I think more of the issue than the
dumbing down of people because things like
podcasts are a perfect
example of why that's that.
It's not the case that it's just
you're not reaching those people,
you're not stimulating those people.
Like podcasts are reaching
more and more people every day.
And one of the reasons being is
that they're completely uncensored.
And I still,
I mean this is my fear and I don't want
to be cynical and I don't want to be
negative,
but you take,
you take the number of people that you
reach in a podcast and compare it to the
number of people tune in every
night to fucking two and a half men.
And it's like depressing to see the
difference in the just sheer quantity of
people tuning in.
And I completely agree that the,
the world of podcasts
and the world of HBO,
which is this beautiful kind of,
you know,
only subscription television said,
we don't give a shit
about the advertisers.
The way that the HBO Model Right
is to higher production cut.
Somebody pitches them a show,
they love the show.
The production company believes in it,
they hire them and they're very hands off.
They're like,
you sold us a show that you
thought would be brilliant.
We want to give you a chance,
show us how brilliant it is.
And it works.
I mean,
it very much works cause they don't get
in there and fuck everything up like
they do on most networks.
Um,
and yes,
there's a small portion of the
population who just eats that up.
And I think that we are
probably those people.
I think that your listeners are those
who I think everybody listening to the
show right now,
it's like,
oh fuck yeah.
You know,
I loved breaking bad or I've and breaking
that is actually a really interesting
example because it was
on cable television,
walking dead used to be that example.
I think like the first season was
just absolutely amazing and brilliant.
And also on television with
commercials now it's kind of shit.
I don't watch it.
So I don't know.
I know that a lot of people still love it.
So I'm like a person in
a piece of relationship.
I'll still tune in when it comes back.
I'm the same way with like,
there's a handful of shows like that.
I'm like that with girls.
I watched girls on Hbo
even though I'm like,
I don't even know if I like this.
I'm going to keep watching.
Yeah.
I think the delivery method is just
what's really flawed and I think there's
also the,
the noninteractive
quality of of television.
We just sit there and the best you
can do is go on a blog somewhere and,
and you know and,
and bitch about it.
But no,
I know it's like it we've got,
I feel like the networks have to
understand that second screen viewing.
It's like the way of the future.
Like if if you want for television to
actually work because as we know it's sort
of dying and like the
web is really kind of,
I think picking up that slack.
But if you do want to maintain a
function in the television sphere,
and this is where I work,
like obviously I want to maintain function
and the in the t v sphere even though
I'm perfectly happy to do a lot of cool
stuff and web two I have a lot of fun.
I like to kind of bounce my time with it.
You've got to understand how
to integrate those two things.
You've got to understand
that most people nowadays,
while we're watching TV,
we're multitasking.
It's very rare.
There's a handful of shows
where like true detective now,
right on Hbo,
it's like the new,
there's three episodes so far.
When it's time to watch true detective,
I hit play on my DVR and I'm
like pissed if the phone rang,
you know what I mean?
I'm like focused.
I'm not picking up my phone
and checking my email.
Every five set,
I'm really focused,
but that's like one hour every week.
The rest of the time if
I am watching TV at all,
I'm on my phone,
I'm on my laptop doing work.
I need to be able to do other
things at the same time.
And so if there's a way to have
the second screen functionality,
I'm watching TV and then I have like
things on my TV or things on my phone that
will contribute to my experience.
Watching this show,
I'll engage in that.
What do you mean by that?
A show.
Like what?
How could you ever have that?
So like,
let's say that you,
you know,
like my show,
I'm on,
on pivot TV.
So I do a show called take part
live and it's nightly and it,
um,
up until yesterday actually we
were shooting it completely live.
So we're shooting at 9:00 PM,
um,
uh,
on the west coast,
midnight on the east coast.
And because of the live component,
people can tweet us,
people can interact,
we have these panel discussions we can
like in real time like look at social
media and say,
oh,
so and so was saying this,
like how do you respond to that?
Which I think is really cool because
we're all living in a world now where like
we want more customized entertainment,
you know what I mean?
Because it's capable.
We have a capability for it now.
And so I think watching TV and knowing
that TV is going to reflect the questions
that we have is really interesting.
And now we're shooting live to tape,
which I think even actually
allows more flexibility.
So we shoot a little
bit earlier in the day.
By the time it airs,
we've already shot it.
But we can have sourced all
of this cool social component.
So like one of the things that we
do as a segment called viewers,
like you were uh,
let's say you watch an episode and we
have this really great panel on like
Autonomo Bay and then you know,
somebody who's watching,
it's like you never answered this one
question that's always bugged me about
Guantanamo Bay.
So they like Skype in,
they record a little question.
Then we have the expert on the panel who
can answer that question directly and
we can pop it on the air.
So just even baby steps like that I
think are really important when you're
watching TV.
But I also think that
there's a way to do it wrong.
And I think that's what a lot of these,
I'm talking head like news networks
do like see it in an MSNBC,
like it's not social interaction.
If you just have a Twitter ticker
on the bottom of the screen,
that's like the laziest way noise.
It's just noise.
It's just,
there's like tickers everywhere.
Sorry.
There's tickers like everywhere.
And I just,
I can't even focus at that point.
The ticker thing drives me fucking crazy.
They do that on sports shows,
like if you're watching fights,
a lot of times like while
the fights are going on,
there's a ticker underneath.
It's showing like football scores and
baseball scores and this car out cause
he's knees hurt.
And then also like you've got
like a Joe Schmo number two says,
I can't believe he blew out his knee.
And you're like,
I don't give a shit.
I don't care.
I think we're talking about completely
different genres because that wouldn't
work with like a sitcom or that wouldn't
work with scripted entertainment.
It is a completely different arena and
that's an arena that I don't work in.
You know,
I work in unscripted television,
which is a totally different thing.
I think that the problem with
scripted television right now is,
like you said,
if you are beholden to the advertisers,
you're basically beholden to fear.
And there is a bad habit,
I think in television right now where
a network executive wants the third,
fourth,
and fifth version of the same show.
He said,
oh,
that's,
that worked one time.
Let's try it again.
And then they like run it into the ground
instead of we want something that's
new and innovative and out of step with
what we all see because this re it's too
expensive of a risk to take.
If this show fails,
we're out millions of
dollars and it's just,
it's not feasible for their network.
So there's a lot of fear that comes
along with taking intense risks,
whereas HBO doesn't even
give a shit about any of it.
All they need to do is maintain their
subscriptions because they're much more
interested in how they're received.
Critically.
They would much rather
get 20 mes then get,
you know,
x amount of viewers.
That doesn't matter to them.
They have a set number of subscriptions,
they'd love it if subscriptions went up.
But for the most part they understand
that only certain type of person is ever
going to be able to afford.
They've got already pay for cable,
they've got to be able to pay for
an expanded package and you know,
they know the stats on their
subscribers so they want to make quality
television.
But like you said,
you're beholden to the advertisers.
You're beholden to,
you know,
network executives that are incredibly
afraid to lose their positions at their
jobs because they've got to bring numbers
into the network and they've got to
bring more advertising
money into the network.
And that fear I think in some ways is
what fuels this fundamental dumbing down
of America.
Because instead of saying we're going
to create content from an editorial
perspective that we think
would be beneficial,
they say,
what do you want to see?
And this is huge in the news arena.
This is the real problem in
the news arena in America.
Instead of saying this is
what's happening in the world,
I'm giving you a platform so that you
can see what's happening in the world.
I've worked as a
journalist for many years,
so I have the editorial distinction
or discretion to be able to say,
this is what's important
to share the news.
People.
Now we're saying,
what do you want us to talk about?
What's interesting to you?
And then you end up having this
like negative feedback of like,
shit going down the toilet.
It's so dangerous.
I was watching CNN headline
news and they had a poll.
Who Do you think is a better person?
Brittany Spears or Paris
Hilton was a fucking ball.
It's insane.
They broke in,
they broke in on CNN m and an m s
fuck MSNBC when Bieber got arrested,
like broke in to actual news.
Give us this update because
it's so fucking important
that we know to the minute
about Justin Bieber's arrest.
By the way,
all the charges were dropped as a
complete nonissue wasn't drunk by the way,
and he wasn't speeding.
I have no idea.
They just,
there's just constant arrested
him because he's a crazy fuck.
That's Florida also.
You're dealing with a 19 year
old kid that has $100 billion.
He's gonna go off the
rail around conversations.
I think it's,
it's more interesting that we talk about
income inequality in this country and
we talk about how,
you know,
the sociology of having that kind of
responsibility and what it's like growing
up in the limelight.
When you put pressure on these people,
it's a much less interesting
conversation to say,
oh,
meanwhile,
while I'm speaking to you about Syria
or while I'm talking about tensions that
are rising and Sochi around the law,
whatever the fuck you know,
talking about the state of the like,
can you imagine?
And then breaking it.
Oh,
more on Bieber.
Why believe the CNN one with MSNBC?
I think they were talking about the NSA.
Oh my God.
Hilarious.
That the broken,
the ultimate distraction.
Seriously little hairless boy.
And that's the thing that's like,
so it's so funny that I feel like anybody
who was alive in the 50s who is still
alive to this day,
who was reading the Scifi
authors that I now love,
like Vonnegut and Orwell and,
and they,
they were warned about
this dystopian future.
How many of those things are just
coming to fruition all the time.
You know,
this big brother mentality,
this like fundamental,
we're going to keep you distracted and
keep you lazy and try and eliminate any
sort of ability for massive revolution.
It's like,
it's just so scary.
I don't think so.
I don't think your actions are engineers.
I don't think that there's
some mass conspiracy that
there's like five people at
the top with like nefarious mustaches.
You know,
saying this is how we're
going to control everybody.
But I do think that what
happens is that money,
money comes into it and power comes
into it and people desperately,
people with money and power
desperately don't want to lose it.
People who don't have money or
power desperately want to gain it.
And so the system is really fixed in a
fucked up way where egalitarian values
and socialist values are not respected
in this country because you know,
you see it all the time.
People voting against their own interests
because not because they fundamentally
believe that,
you know,
this fat cat politician who's trying to
pass policy that keeps the little guy
down in that like really intensifies
the income inequality in this country.
They don't believe,
oh,
that's like morally the way we should go.
They believe,
well,
one day I'm going to be rich and I want
to make sure that the laws protect me.
It's,
it's horrible and I think that the one
thing that maybe we can say is more
engineered than other is this
concept of the American dream.
This really fucked up concept
and it don't get me wrong,
it happens for some people.
There are rags to riches stories
out there and they're great,
but they shouldn't be a template
for all of us to live our lives by.
We shouldn't all be like,
you know,
hoping and praying that one day we're
going strike it rich and we're going to go
from,
you know,
this place to that place.
It should be much more piecemeal.
We should be living in a country where,
where it's,
it's plausible that you can work really
hard in your life and you can actually
make a,
make a life for yourself and
maybe get out of a shit situation,
getting a slightly better situation.
I think that that's a real goal
and it should be a reasonable goal.
But in this country,
it's getting to the point where it's
very hard to climb that social ladder.
And I think a lot of it comes from this
idea of like keeping up this narrative,
this rags to riches,
American dream narrative,
the kinds of policies
that are put into place.
Because that narrative is
what fundamentally underlies
everybody in America is
really dangerous.
It's a really,
really dangerous point of view.
And it's something that I think that
has gotten worse in recent years.
How do you think it's dangerous?
So you don't want what makes you feel
like it's a dangerous idea to think that
you could pull yourself up from poverty
and become a wealthy person and,
uh,
this,
this anti socialism,
uh,
ideal that we,
we sort of,
uh,
you find a lot of people
that are vehemently opposed
to the idea of socialism.
I think a root of that is in laziness.
I think a lot of people believe
that socialism enforces laziness.
And I don't even think
it's about laziness.
I think I personally think a
root of that comes from racism,
racism,
intolerance.
And I think that religion is a,
is an easy tool for people to use to,
to perpetuate these kinds of ideals.
Because I think what happens is that when
most people who are wealthy were born
wealthy,
that's just the case.
There is a real true,
very much true.
Most people who are,
who are wealthy came from wealth there
because social mobility in this country
is worse than in most countries.
And it's worse than it's
ever been in the past.
So it's,
it's very difficult.
I mean,
if you look at the data,
if you look at,
um,
uh,
evidence,
it's very difficult to move up in social
class in any sort of real meaningful
way.
They're,
they're definitely,
there are,
are piecemeal,
like I said,
like stepwise elevations that do occur.
But,
um,
if you read anything by Robert Reich,
if you look at,
I mean,
listened to Obama's state
of the Union address,
it's going to happen to night.
That's what he's going to talk
about is this growing rift,
this growing income
inequality and how the,
the rift between rich and poor has
gotten worse and worse and worse.
And so I think what fundamentally
happens is that if you're born poor,
you're very likely to be poor in life.
That it's not to say that you have to be,
but you're very likely for your kids
to be poor and those kids to be poor.
If you're born rich,
you're more likely to be able to
maintain some level of wealth.
And I think what happens is that the
wealthy people who have the money and and
fundamentally have the political power
because they have the money and the
social power in many ways have this
like really bad sense of entitlement.
Well,
we must have been somehow better
because if we have more money,
there's some sort of connection
between money and more reality.
There's some sort of connection between
money and some sort of positive valence.
So if I have more money and I must be
better than people who are less fortunate
than I must've done
something to deserve that.
There must be a reason that people who
live in poverty live in poverty and
that's where you get these horribly
regressive social policies like that.
That asshole in Florida who was trying
to pass a law requiring people who are on
welfare to all be drug test.
It's just like blanket drug tests for
people too who are on welfare to continue
to receive their government assistance.
Things where,
where there's this fundamental fear of
government assistance and of welfare
when,
you know,
we know that we give more welfare,
uh,
to corporations and we even do to people,
right?
We know that a large majority of people
who are on welfare at this point are
people who work full time and
people who are supporting families,
people who are not fucking lazy.
There's like this fear that there's
some sort of like social leaching of the
system that there's this like,
I think there's a lot of racism in a,
you know,
there's the,
poor black single mothers who don't
know any better and their welfare queen,
you know,
there's these terms that are really like
invented by policymakers on the right,
uh,
by be like big PR machines like
welfare queens and things like that.
When the statistics show us over and
over that that's the tiniest fraction of
our population.
And that the massive,
uh,
the majority of people who actually
receive welfare throughout their lives use
it as a stepping stone to be able to
get off of welfare and that it actually
ends up saving the entire
country a lot of money.
And so,
I mean,
I feel very strongly that this
rift comes from entitlement,
that this,
this idea of like if I'm rich,
it must be because I'm better in
some way is a really dangerous idea.
And that's where like you were asking,
why do I think it's dangerous?
I think that's where it comes from.
One thing for a lot of people becoming
rich or getting to a position where
you're wealthy is a competition.
Once they've achieved that,
they,
uh,
they want to say,
look,
I've won.
And there's that old expression,
people that were born on third base,
but they think they hit
a triple and that's like,
look,
I've won.
Like,
but how many,
how many of those people?
Yeah,
exactly.
Really did win.
Like I,
I,
I would be blown away if somebody could
show me a high statistic of individuals
who actually started off in an
impoverished position and became wealthy.
Now there is a,
there are a fair amount of people
who really have pulled them out,
pull themselves up from their
bootstraps and gotten an education.
And most of the time,
the reason that that's happened is
because they've made use of public,
uh,
assistance that's been available.
They've been able to use a federal
grants that have helped them get through
school for whatever reason.
If you come from an
impoverished neighborhood and
you use education as a way
out,
right,
and you,
you do your Undergrad,
you do your graduate training,
you're able to get the funding that you
need to basically get the education to
be able to get a really good job.
That's one way that people get out,
but these people aren't rich afterward.
They're comfortable.
There's a big difference between
moving from lower class to moving from
middleclass.
But as we know,
the middle class in this
country is shrinking.
The majority of people who
I think would probably say,
well,
I didn't,
I came from modest means
and now I'm wealthy.
They probably didn't
come from modest means.
They're probably white already.
They probably had,
uh,
two parents at home who
were really helping them.
You know,
mom was there and could make it easier
for this kid to maybe not have to have a
job when they were in high school,
maybe not have to deal with a lot of
the things that real poverty is not just
about not having money.
It's about all sorts of socioeconomic
problems that come along with poverty.
And so I think even growing
up middle class at this point,
we need to fundamentally
understand that that's a privilege.
You know what I mean?
I grew up in the middle class.
I grew up in a suburb of
Dallas and it was comfortable.
I grew up in a single parent home for
the most part because my parents got
divorced when I was like seven,
but we were fine.
My mom worked three jobs.
I gave money to my mom when
I worked in high school.
You know,
she did need that.
We did need that.
But I had it so much better
off than a lot of other people.
And I know that about myself and I don't
want to ever forget that because I'm in
a comfortable position now,
but I didn't start impoverished.
And I think that that is what made it
easier for me to be in a comfortable
position.
Now
that sounds impoverished.
I mean it sounds poor like you,
you had to give money to your mom
when you were working at high school,
but I don't think we have four.
I think that if you actually look at
what the poverty line is in this country,
I don't think we would've qualified
because of your contributions.
But if it was just based on your mother,
she worked three jobs.
She was hardworking.
She was an amazing mom.
And I think that probably,
I mean the,
the poverty line is very low.
If you really think about where
you have to be to qualify,
for example,
for assistance with Obamacare,
like to be able to,
uh,
qualify with assistance on the,
on the insurance trades or to,
to be able to qualify for certain
government programs like it's low.
You have to make very little money.
There's a lot of issues.
I mean this,
a lot of what we talked about earlier
when we were talking about the variables
that go into creating
a human being that's,
that plays a part in who is your parents?
Where did you grow up?
What is the environment
that you're forced to be in?
And the,
the difference between welfare
and subsidies is it's entirely,
and how we view it.
You know,
we've used subsidies as being an
important part of maintaining business,
whereas essentially that's a,
um,
a much more expensive form of welfare
that cost tax payers way more and
oftentimes has dubious results.
Exactly.
Like when it comes to like
down at subsidizing corn
and then you find out about
the fucking high fructose corn
syrup and it's enforcing everything.
Yeah.
Like,
wait a minute,
wait a moment.
Where did they're paying money.
Tax money goes to that.
Like this is a weird thing.
While the farmers,
the farmers are getting
help out Sorda Kinda
but look what's going on.
We'll look what's really going on.
Cost more to produce that.
I'm not a fan of giving people money.
Um,
in order to make sure that they,
uh,
you know,
they do things like,
I,
I don't,
I don't think you can give people money
and make sure that they do drug tests.
I don't think you can do ma give
people money and make sure that they,
uh,
are forced to apply to x
amount of jobs per month.
I think all of that time and energy
that's spent enforcing that is probably,
it's probably just going to create this
sort of authoritarian environment that
people are only going to count for
something like three to 5% of those people
anyway.
That you're really like
obsessing over whether or not,
because the vast majority of people,
for example,
on unemployment don't want to fucking
live their lives on unemployment.
The vast,
whew,
I'm rolling in my unemployment.
They're like,
fuck,
this sucks,
but I can't find a job.
And especially in California,
if we collect unemployment,
we fucking paid into it.
It's our money.
We earned it.
And that's something that I think we have
to understand about the tax structure
to when you spend your entire
life paying into taxes,
there are social programs
that those taxes fund.
And so when you fall on hard times,
what that safety net is
supposed to be there for,
you've been paying into
it your entire life.
I have a question for you.
I want to know what you
think about this recent,
um,
this recent article that I,
that I read and we covered
on my show in Utah,
which is a very conservative state,
right?
It's,
it's totally like
overtly republican state.
They are solving the homelessness crisis
and the way that they've decided to do
it is completely evidence based.
And so for me,
I look at this story and I think of it
much more in scientific terms and in
moral terms,
but I want to know what
you think about it.
So they looked at the average homeless
person in their state and they realize
that in terms of um,
medical treatment and uh,
social services that the average homeless
person was costing the states $17,000
a year.
They were $17,000 burden per person.
And that if they put this person into
government housing and offered them a
social worker,
it only cost $9,000 a year.
And so no strings attached there taking
these individuals off the streets and
giving them apartments.
Now they may check in
with their social worker,
they may fall off the grid,
they may work on getting a job,
they may resort to alcoholism,
you don't know.
And no matter what,
they don't have any strings attached to
that apartment is theirs and they can
live there.
It's provided by the government.
It's helping them clear the
homeless people off the street.
But fundamentally when it
comes to a bottom line via,
which to me is a much more
conservative Republican viewpoint.
This is cheaper,
this is saving the state money.
Do you think that this is a good idea?
I definitely think that's a good idea.
I think also what's what's
really important when you're
dealing with the quote
unquote homeless
people is to differentiate between
how many people have had bad luck,
how many people grew
up in bad environments,
and how many people have
mental health problems.
The vast majority of match part of it,
the Reagan administration changed the
standards for people being put into mental
health facilities and
they allow these people,
they were clearly ill to just fend for
themselves and a society that doesn't
take care of it's sick
is a society that's sick.
That's so true.
I mean,
yeah,
I love that you bring that up because
even more than this issue like we're
talking,
which I agree.
I think the homelessness,
the way that they're approaching
it in Utah's brilliant.
I am a very progressive thinker,
but I think it's one of those interesting
things where conservative thinkers may
be on my team with this,
but for different reasons.
But fundamentally the fact that
healthcare is a for profit system in this
country I think is is so a moral,
it's such a disgusting system because
it's built on a capitalist framework.
And as much as I think that capitalism
has a very important place in modern
society,
I don't think that capitalism
is a moral framework.
I don't,
I think that's why we need regulation
because I think that if it's all about
trying to make money,
it's very easy for greed and like
really bad practices to come into play.
That's where people
get taken advantage of.
That's why we need fucking,
you know,
like meat regulation and it's like
read Upton Sinclair's the jungle.
Like it's very important that this
happens because if it's all about profit
motive and bottom line,
people are going to make
disgusting decisions and
they're not going to take care
of the consumer.
So what happens in a,
in a healthcare framework is that we
have a healthcare system that's a for
profit system.
The more sick people there are,
the more money there is to be made.
So there's absolutely no
incentive to help people get well.
And there's also no incentive for people
to motivate their patients to seek
nonsurgical methods,
nonsurgical to seek preventative method.
I mean,
at least with Obamacare,
even though there's like lots
of problems with this law,
even though I fully think that
if we had gone single payer,
it would have been a
significantly better system.
At least now,
you know,
I can get a pap for free.
I can,
you know,
yeah,
sorry guys.
And,
and you might be able to,
you know,
get a prostate exam for free and their
spoon and how much cheaper is it for the
state to subsidize or this or the
country to subsidize preventative,
uh,
actually preventative as the right word.
Preventative is not a word that's not,
no,
isn't that crazy?
If you look it up in the dictionary,
I'll say that like it's now become a
word because people use it so often.
But technically the
correct word is preventive,
which isn't on,
I know,
but it's so natural to prevention.
Yeah.
But read,
it'll say something like the
preventative preventative,
like most of the dictionary definition
say that like however they word it,
but like over time it's
been used much to that.
They've added it to the dictionary.
It's one of those things.
Is Anything wrong with that?
Because all words are invented eventually.
Originally rather.
Yeah,
that's true.
Um,
but anyway,
how much cheaper is it right for the
government to subsidize those kinds of
things versus intense
cancer treatment later on?
So many things.
If they can be caught early
or going to be cheaper,
I can give you a personal story.
I hurt my neck doing Jujitsu and I have
bulging disc in my neck and the bulging
disc was causing numbness in my
fingers and the Ulnar nerve was it.
I was feeling pain in my elbow that
was going and I talked to doctors that
wanted to cut me.
They wanted to do surgery.
They were like,
you know this,
this is the best way to deal with this.
We'll do surgery,
we'll do,
we can give you an epidural,
which just numbs the pain.
You don't,
you don't feel the pain anymore.
And then the other option is you go in
and they'll cut a piece of your disk off.
This was a year ago.
I treated it completely non
nonsurgically with spinal decompression,
rolfing,
deep tissue massage.
The spinal decompression was big.
And then a recently a
thing called Regena keen,
which is something that was invented in
Germany where they take your blood and
they heat it and spin it in
a centrifuge and take out,
uh,
some aspects of the blood and then
reinjected into the area and it becomes a
very potent anti inflammatory medication.
It's gone.
Totally gone.
I had a new MRI,
no bulging disc at all.
No,
no symptoms,
no issues,
no issues with it.
With exercise,
I could have gone through a
fucking surgery for nothing.
We could have gotten my back cut open,
my pieces of my disc removed.
And I think there's a real issue with,
with doctors that are motivated
to automatically point
towards a surgical option
because surgical options are fucking
expensive and there's a huge profit motive
in them.
Yeah,
I mean for the most part it's just labor.
All they're paying for his Labor,
maybe,
maybe some medical device that
as we've seen over and over,
the marketplace doesn't regulate at all.
So like some surgery in this town in
Colorado costs 10 times as much as the
surgery in this town in Vermont only
because their medical regulations there.
It's,
it's crazy.
Like there's no bottom line at all.
It's,
it's pure profit for them to do surgery.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with giving someone incentive to become a
really excellent surgeon.
And if a guy is an amazing surgeon and
because of the fact that he's the best in
the world,
he gets paid more and that
motivates him towards excellence.
You should get paid more.
Yeah.
But it's weird.
There's a weird gray
area there because it's,
that's capitalism and
that's not the doctors that,
it's not the doctors' salaries that
are making all of this so expensive.
It's,
it's the fucking profit motive at the
hospitals and the pharmaceutical companies
and the medical device companies.
That's where all of the
money is coming from.
I think that the way that we pay or we
probably still don't pay our doctors
enough.
If you think about how much they put
into medical school and how much they put
into professional liability insurance,
I don't think that doctors are actually
walking around like super wealthy.
Well,
some of them are,
but the liability is also a huge
issue because then you're dealing with
predatory practices where
you're dealing with,
there's
people that absolutely did get fucked
over and their doctor screwed up and
their,
their lives have been changed.
Like I read about some woman yesterday
who was an opera singer who gave birth
and they ruined the,
you know,
the,
the wall between the vagina and the
anus somehow or another during the
operation.
They fucked it up and now she can't sing
without farting and it's like ruined
her career.
I mean I can't,
I'm laughing,
but it is really safe.
Farts farts are funny.
Yeah,
but why?
I guess,
I guess she can't sing.
You don't want to be on stage singing
opera in like you're farting all the time.
There's one here.
It unless your farts are unbelievable.
Unbelievable.
It's just really stinky too.
I think it'd be the sound.
Well now that I guess,
but now that it's out to all the people
in the front row are going to be like
they're sniffing,
waiting for her to hit the high notes.
There's a reason that she should
be able to file a tort there.
It is malpractice.
I mean whenever you have that,
then you leave open the,
the,
you know,
those fucking late night commercials,
uh,
have you been an injury
called James Suck or fuck,
you know,
I'm the,
I specialize in getting
people what they deserve.
No matter what policies that are passed,
no matter what regulation is available,
there's always going to be
a small percentage of the
population that's going to
figure out.
It's going to try to take advantage of it.
And that's why we need strong laws.
And that's why we need a judiciary.
You know,
that's the point of having
three branches of government.
We need a judiciary who can watch
out for the rights of the people.
That's always going to happen.
And I think that when we legislate
for fear of that happening,
that's when we start to
get into huge trouble.
Let's,
let's explore that cause why does that
have to happen and what a half do?
I just think that,
but it always has.
But why is that?
Why?
Why does that have to,
why?
Why is that a factor and is
there a variable that can
be considered amongst the
many variables that go into raising
and developing a human being?
Is there some way that we can
engineer people to be less like that?
Well,
there is something to be said about the
type of society that were raised at now.
Now fundamentally if you
want to go even beneath that,
if you want to talk about
evolution for example,
there is a survival instinct and all of
us and maybe you could make the argument
that the survival instinct can
downstream have something to do with a
competitive nature,
right?
This like I need to make
sure that I'm eating enough,
I need to make sure that
I protect my family.
I need to make sure that I don't die.
There is probably actually an
environmental or I'm sorry,
I'm an evolutionary basis for that,
but I think beyond that,
if you compare,
for example our society,
too many societies in East Asia,
what you find is a massive difference
between what we call an individual society
and
a collectivist society.
Our society,
and I don't know if it's
based fundamentally on how
we govern or if it's based
on like massive cultural norms,
but we are raised from the time
we're very small to feel highly,
to have a highly competitive nature.
I got to get the best grades,
I got to get the best,
you know,
I got a win in sports.
I've somehow got to stand
out as an individual.
Me,
me,
III,
and when you look at these
collectivist cultures,
it's all about we us,
we're only as strong as
the weakest amongst us.
They have these like huge families where
you know grandma lives with multiple
kids and then all the,
you know the daughters and sons of them
live together and they help raise each
other and it's a very different culture.
I don't know what the root
cause of that is but I,
I do wonder if having that
very individualist nature
also contributes to having
this cutthroat kind of approach and
sometimes what from the outside might look
like a lack of empathy and a lack of
fundamental caring for those that are less
fortunate amongst us.
It's also I think the,
the type of society that thrives on
innovation and the type of society that
thrives and success and type of Psi
that's going to foster these sort of
individual mentalities.
Whereas these other more family oriented,
more tribal community oriented cultures,
they're not going to
be so driven to succeed
Communist.
I mean these are,
these are off the society,
communism,
these are societies that have a
history of communism in America,
have never had a communist government.
We've always been a
republic since we started.
And I think that there's this
like fear of the word communism.
There's this fear of the word socialism.
And there's,
even though we have a heavily
socialistic society as it is,
I mean,
we're a capitalist society that has a lot
of socialist values and that has a lot
of social programs that are available.
If the minute you start pointing that out,
a lot of people get really
squeezed the word compassionate,
passionate,
like the fire department,
you know,
it's compassionate.
It's not something where we pool all of
our income together and pay taxes and
then have a public service
that's available to everyone.
I found it interesting.
I think that a lot of conservative people
would agree with you that because of
the bottom line would be less money
spent on these homeless people.
I say a lot of younger conservatives
would agree with me cause I think a lot of
younger conservatives are much less
concerned about conservative values.
Uh,
when it comes to social issues,
a lot of young conservatives,
for example,
or for gay rights,
but they're still fiscal conservatives.
And that's why I would say that they'd
be much more concerned about the bottom
line cause their fiscal conservatives
gone.
It is,
if you really are a patriotic person who
really believes in the idea of America
as a team,
the best way to strengthen the
team is to have less losers.
I agree.
The best way to have less losers is to
find the people at the lowest rung of the
socio economic food chain
and help them simple and,
and think of them as children.
Don't think of them as lazy adults
because the lazy adults that you,
you,
you point out and demonize are just,
they're the,
they're the fucking factories that are
making the babies that are going to grow
up to be human beings that are going to
have to deal with and interact with on a
daily basis and in life.
But w w whether they're lazy or
not is outside of the question.
Forget them.
Concentrate on the fucking
children constantly in these
children that have this
horrible roll the dice and these children
are going to become those people who
are lazy.
And when you concentrate
on those children,
I think you will understand that these
people that you're pointing to and
demonizing that I've had this horrible
roll of the dice that they've been dealt
this entirely impossible
to deal with hand.
These are the fucking adults
that you're demonizing.
They haven't had the easiest road.
And taking that word lazy and really like,
what are you projecting when you
think of these people as being lazy,
like live a fucking week in their shoes
and tell me that they probably don't
work just as hard for no fucking income.
You know what I mean?
I want to fucking be a fry cook.
That sounds horrible.
It sounds like a horrible
fucking job on it.
It does not sound like fun.
It wasn't fun,
but it was all right.
But I was a kid.
But did you feel like you were exactly,
and that's how it used to be.
It used to be the case that the,
that kind of labor force was
taken up by young people.
And now more and more,
I think the average person that
works in the fast food industry,
it's like 28 years old and like,
is that person lazy?
Um,
I don't think they're lazy.
I think,
I think there without a doubt
they're in a shitty road,
they're in Shitty road and they're
working a shit job that's hard and not on.
I don't know if there's a solution
to that that are universally apply,
like say,
Oh,
well the reason why all these people
have these jobs cause a blank,
let's just fit that into the system
and then we won't have a 28 year olds.
It's,
it's,
it's about a lot of
policies across the board.
The problem is when you
actually are filling,
uh,
legislation with a lot of policies that
keep income inequality where it is and
that keep,
you know,
the little guy down and they keep
the rich people getting richer.
Did you see that recent study?
Oh God,
I hope I get the numbers right.
That something like 85 people,
the top 85 people in the world have as
much wealth as the next 350 million.
It's a problem.
When he tried to bang numbers
out like 85 85 350 million,
what the fuck?
That never,
that's never happened in the history of,
of our global society.
I mean it's insane.
Like it used to be something that the
average CEO made 40 times the salary of
his lowest paid worker and now
it's skyrocketed to like 400 plus.
That's insane.
Here it is.
85 richest people,
not 350 million.
3.5 billion.
Yeah,
it's,
wow.
It's horrifying.
3 billion,
85 richest people in the
world own more wealth
than 3 billion at a certain point.
Who the fuck needs that much money?
It's like a sickness.
Like you look at bill and Melinda Gates
who are incredibly wealthy and they've
given more,
they're the biggest
philanthropists in the world.
They have given so much money to people
who are less fortunate and that's how it
should be.
It's a windows or a MAC computer.
I use Mac.
I'm thinking about using a
windows just because of that,
just because that's a Steve jobs.
Kind of a con
read recently that this guy
who's a billionaire investor
just dumped all of his
apple stock after you read Steve Jobs
biography and really like the guy's an
asshole.
Don't care if he was good products.
I hate it.
I hate the idea behind it.
It wasn't me kind of like on the spectrum.
I'm sure he was switched
over to an android phone.
I still use my iPhone.
Same fuck you slowly.
That's what I'm saying.
You're a,
you're voting with your dollar
crazy with it is what we should do.
But I agree with you that you don't need
that much money and I agree with you,
but why?
How does that happen
and how do you fix that?
Well,
I think one thing that you do
is you ensured that the laws,
it's not about preventing
rich people from getting rich.
There's nothing wrong with
somebody pulling themselves
up from their bootstraps.
There's nothing wrong.
If you come from a wealthy family,
being able to maintain your wealth,
but the system shouldn't be rigged in
such a way that you get more help from
your government than poor people do.
That's unfair.
So having the kind of tax code so that
rich people can find so many loopholes
that they're actually
paying less effective tax.
Then you know,
somebody who's working as
an administrative assistant
than somebody who's
working.
It's true.
I mean,
look,
there's unavoidable taxes.
There's,
there's a certain amount of taxes
that if you are a very wealthy person,
you just have to pay.
But a lot of people have certain,
uh,
a lot of their assets
in offshore accounts.
A lot of people are able to pay themselves
almost a nil salary and put the rest
of their money into some
sort of corporate entity.
And corporate tax rates are significantly
lower than individual tax rates in
certain examples.
And so,
yes,
we have so much corporate
welfare in this country.
I mean a lot of people,
even where we are in life,
I know a lot of people who work as
independent contractors and Hollywood and
what they do is they kind of rigged
their taxes so that their accountant they
have,
they're incorporated.
So like you would be like
Joe Rogan incorporated,
and what you would do is
you would get everything,
every check you ever earned
made out to your corporation,
and then you would pay yourself a salary.
You pay yourself the bare minimum salary
to be able to pay rent and bills with
like no spending money.
And so,
okay,
Joe Rogan only makes $20,000
a year because of that,
which means you only pay taxes on
$20,000 a year at an individual tax rate,
and your corporation pays corporate
taxes on everything else that you earned
during the year.
It's a very,
I mean that's just a very simple example
of completely cheating the tax system.
But what happens with
these people who can hire,
who can afford to hire like
10,000 an hour lawyers,
they can get away with not
paying almost any taxes.
And the,
again,
the little guys kept down.
He can't afford that.
He's going to h and r block.
He's trying to figure out how to deduct
things just to be able to afford to pay
the taxes and still be able to,
you know,
put food in his kids' mouths.
It's just,
it's a fucked up system.
You're just going to keep the richer
a bit of a problem with that type of
thinking.
I don't agree that it's a good idea to
give the government more money and I
don't agree that giving them more tax
money is in some way going to help out
these poor people and I don't agree
that taking money from these people like
saying like what France just pass pass
recently a new log chart taking the most
rich and making their tax of 75% I don't,
I don't trust them to take that money
and do anything prudent with it.
I don't did under Eisenhower when
the rich had the highest tax rate,
we have the best economy that
we've seen in a really long time,
but that's a completely different as arm.
It's totally different.
It's very different to compare those
things and so I'm not saying that,
I mean for whatever,
I believe whether we would advocate for
a higher tax bracket for rich people
versus poor people,
blah,
blah.
The fundamental thing is we're not living
in a good system where rich people can
get away with paying significantly less
percentage of their income in taxes.
Then somebody who's poor,
well that's certainly not good,
but is that what's keeping
these people pour in his,
that was keeping these people rich?
Is it just the taxes that will,
that's the,
that's the only thing,
but that is a huge thing
that helps keep rich people.
The idea of giving that money
to the government there,
therefore the people
aren't as rich anymore.
Therefore everything's good.
I don't think it is because then the
government just has this money and what
does it do?
It just bloats up.
The bureaucracy adds more
people in government functions.
We don't even need me because that money
should be going to really good social
programs.
It should be going to them.
I think that we would be way better off
if people contributed to these social
problems,
social programs voluntarily.
I think it would be even better if we
had some sort of a system like you see in
a lot of developed European countries
where there is a certain amount of public
service that we're required to make.
Like in a lot of European countries,
what happens is that you're required to
basically give let's say a year of your
life or maybe more um,
to the government.
Like you're,
you're required to serve your country for
a full year and then your education is
covered in,
you know,
college or something like that.
And it can be anything.
It could be militarily,
it could be some,
you know,
in,
in volunteer work,
whatever reason so that as
young people are growing up,
they just know when I
get to a certain age,
this is what I do.
I'm going to serve my country and
with it I'm going to get a secure
understanding that I'm going
to be able to get an education.
And it ends up being incredibly
good for the economy.
And I think it's actually
from a moral perspective,
good for people.
I think people should serve.
I think that's a good idea.
If the system is in
place isn't
politically cockeyed and fucked and
that's a huge problem in America because
their system is
not giving these dummies
a year of my life.
Well yeah,
I think the way they manage right now,
that would be a huge problem.
But fundamentally,
and this is the thing,
whenever you have,
you know,
these like long conversations about any
of these real heavy kind of social or
governmental issues is that I think
truly it comes down to campaign finance
reform.
A lot of the problems with the way that
our country's governed comes down to the
fact that the incentive is
always to win elections.
It's not actually to be an effective,
uh,
executor or legislator.
So you work so hard and you raise so
much money to have the better ads so that
you can then win your election
and the entire time that you're,
you're expected to actually
be serving the public,
all you're doing is fundraising.
That's your whole job is to fundraise to
make more money so that you can stay in
office and it's,
it's the crux of our system and it's
what keeps it so incredibly broken.
If it didn't cost money
to run for elected office,
if you weren't allowed to
have advertisements that
were paid for with private
funds,
there would be a totally different way
that people govern because when it comes
down to the money,
it,
it really does Solly every single
part of the governmental process.
I certainly think that there's the,
the motivation becomes financial and when
a financial motivations take precedent
above all others,
you have this a moral drive to just
increase numbers and I think that's a huge
issue with corporations in general.
Just the idea of corporations being this
entity that consumes and and produces
and is all about ones and Zeros
in the bottom line above humanity
and that's the problem.
There is absolutely nothing wrong with
doing something brilliant and making a
shitload of money off of it.
If you're not destroying the environment,
you're not stepping on the backs of
people who are easy to take advantage of.
In order to get your bottom
line down even lower.
You know there,
there are fundamental things
that you have to fulfill.
And above and beyond that,
if you can profit good for fucking you.
I want you to be a billionaire.
I want you to get as rich as possible.
The,
the attitude in this country is,
so what if there's a
certain amount of pollution?
So what if there's a certain amount of
environmental damage as long as there's a
certain amount of profit.
And so what if you are literally like
fucking stepping on the backs of people
who,
who can't defend themselves
if you get a certain amount.
I mean,
it's the same core argument.
It's the same reason that our economy
is booming in the first place because it
was all founded on slavery.
And it's not that different.
Like if you look at these kind of,
this moral perspective that
that Americans had early is,
is we had an agricultural society right
before the industrial revolution and
then it moved into a factory society.
But when slavery was still legal it,
fuck,
yeah.
It's easy to make a shitload of profits
when you're not paying any of your
workers when they're required
to work for you for free.
And you can treat them as Shitty as you
want to and you don't have basic human
dignity that you have
to take care of them.
That's in the Bible.
Exactly.
I mean,
you're allowed to have slaves,
and don't get me wrong,
this goes long before American caution.
I'll beat him to death.
But you're allowed to have,
yeah,
that's beautiful.
It's a beautiful piece of work and
they live for a couple of days.
It's okay.
Yeah.
And then after that you've got indentured
servitude and then after that you've
got,
you know,
the fucking Lowell factory girls
and you've got child labor.
We have a,
we have a long history of taking advantage
of those who are less fortunate in
order to make a buck off of their backs.
And it's gross.
And I think it's something
that if that could change,
yes,
we might not be as much
of a fucking booming,
you know,
wealthy society.
But at least we would
be taking care of the,
the weakest amongst us and as a whole
we would have strengths and we wouldn't
see the top 85 people getting richer and
richer and the bottom three in the next
3 billion over only
having that much money.
What is the solution to something
that's so disproportionate like that?
Like how does one step in in 2014 and
look at the 85 people that have so much
money,
the billions that you know,
look at these people and say,
how the fuck,
how was that?
How's it possible to,
I mean,
I don't know how to engineer that.
I Dunno if there's a
simple answer to that,
but I think probably the first thing
that you have to start doing is cleaning
house.
You have to look at the books,
you have to look at it.
Let's look at the legacy of making this
kind of money and let's make sure that
all of that money was
made completely morally.
Let's make sure that nobody was
fucking destroyed in the process.
Let's make sure that nobody was taking
heavily taken advantage of heavily.
Let's make sure that the,
the globe wasn't getting
fucked in the ass.
And in doing this,
and as soon as you start taking those,
those things out and you start saying,
okay,
well you've got to make sure that your
lowest paid workers are treated with
fucking dignity and that
they earn a living wage.
You've got to make sure that you offer
health insurance to the people that work
underneath.
You've got to make,
you know,
once you go through all these things,
maybe that person makes less money.
Maybe they make more money.
I have no problem with
rich people being rich.
I've problem with rich people being
rich on the backs of poor people.
That's my real problem.
You are the total
counterpoint to Peter Schiff,
who's on the podcast last
week who defended fracking.
You know,
who's,
who's like a few places get fucked up.
Who Cares?
The farmers got millions of
dollars because they got fucked up.
Like it's no big deal.
Companies look at it.
I mean,
I had,
um,
I used to work for a neuropsychologist
back in Texas and he,
uh,
we had a contract with the
Texas Commission for the blind.
So a lot of the patients that we saw had,
I'm sorry it had visual
impairment or blindness and um,
oh,
that's a totally different tack that
doesn't even apply to this story.
And another thing that he did is he was a,
he was an expert witness in court cases.
And so one time he was,
uh,
going on to be an expert witness about
this girl who had taken cough medicine
like totally over the
counter cough medicine.
And she had a fucking,
she was like a,
you know,
a healthy nine year old girl
took this cough medicine,
had a stroke.
And I really don't know anything about
the medical implications or why it
happened.
But apparently you look at the records
and you look at the history and something
like one in 1 billion cases,
a kid's going to take this cough
medicine and have a fucking stroke.
And the truth is,
the bottom line is so low that it's more
cost effective for this pharmaceutical
company to just pay these
people out and say like,
oh,
that fucking sucks.
We're so sorry this happened.
But the risk benefit analysis shows us
that it's still worth it to have this
cough medicine on the market.
Here's your money to take care
of you for the rest of your life.
Cause he had a fucking stroke and there's
like no way you're going to be able to
work the same way you could have before.
We're going to keep our product on the
market because we still are making a
massive profit.
Even if we pay you out
for having your stroke.
And this is the way that a lot of,
uh,
you know,
pharmaceutical companies operate.
And sometimes it makes sense.
You have to look at a
risk benefit analysis.
Let's say you have HIV
and there's a drone.
I mean,
every,
everybody probably saw Dallas buyers club,
like,
you know,
uh,
when they were first looking at AACT,
you know,
different,
different drugs that were on the
market were really dangerous.
And is it,
are you worse off being sick from the
drug or are you worse off with Your Hiv,
uh,
getting worse and progressing to AIDS?
You know,
it's always a risk benefit
analysis and it's never that clean.
And that's the problem when
we have these conversations,
like what is the solution?
What is the cure?
Well,
it's fucking nuanced and it's always,
it's not always that straight forward
and it's really about risk and benefit.
But this is where capitalism
can go awry really quickly.
Because if you say the bottom
line is the number one measure,
then you get in a lot of trouble.
But what about,
I mean,
when you're dealing with medications,
you have also these extreme variables
as far as like biological diversity,
the difference in human bodies.
Some people are allergic to peanuts,
some people,
they're around dogs and
their eyes close shot.
It was so much difference and it's,
yeah,
it's,
it's really tough.
And,
and,
and you can give a hundred people
that same medication have no issues
whatsoever,
and one person dies.
What do you do if a hundred people
benefit and one person dies from,
sometimes that shit's going to happen.
But on top of that,
one thing you can do is make sure
that when you do your human trials,
you don't normally give it to 300 people.
I mean,
there are too many drugs on the market
right now where the human trials were,
um,
were fast tracked,
where the FDA wasn't as
thorough as they needed to be.
Argument.
He was saying that we don't
need ready regulation.
Oh my God,
that's the most insane.
I mean,
look at what's happening
in West Virginia right now.
We didn't have regulation.
All of those people in West
Virginia would be fucking dead.
You know what I mean?
They'd be drinking this one.
They're fucked anyway.
And like this is what happens
when we have regulations.
Fucking might not even know
what's happening in West Virginia.
So,
right.
It was because of fracking and
there was like some horrible,
or it was like oil.
No,
it was like,
yeah,
it was a chemical spill,
but it was from like an oil company.
And so what happened is there were these
reserves that were down river from a
water processing plant.
There was a spell,
it fell into the,
uh,
into the river and
people started drinking,
or actually a lot of people were saved
because the water smelled like licorice
and they noticed the water smells weird,
maybe I shouldn't drink it.
So a lot of people actually didn't get
sick because they didn't drink the water
for a while.
And then the government
came back and said,
okay,
we've,
you know,
mitigated the situation as best we can,
go ahead and drink the water.
And people started drinking it,
but it still was not nearly as
detoxified as it needed to be.
So now people are having
all sorts of complaints,
injuries that are having,
you know,
rashes and allergies and all the way
down to like neurological issues based on
this.
And this is the end part of
the reason that this happened,
they say is because
this plant hadn't been.
Um,
uh,
so,
so the regulations in place
required that these plants,
uh,
have inspections and it hadn't
been inspected since like 1991.
Is that right?
91 or 92.
It was a fucking long time ago.
It was two.
And this is what happens when we have,
as a lot of these anti-regulation
people say quote unquote,
too much regulation in this country.
What I found fascinating was after
the conversation with Peter Schiff,
how many people were a defending him
and be being really aggressive about how
safe fracking is and you know,
and insulting me and like
the Twitter comments.
But it's that hard right wing.
The people,
and by the way,
a guarantee you,
the majority of them are not rich,
but they have this attitude that they
want things to be in place so that when
their time comes,
the regulations are free and clear.
So they have a straight
highway to success.
I think you even see a lot of pro
science people that are very split about
fracking because the evidence isn't
completely in and there are some dangers,
but in some ways it's still safer
than maybe other ways to drill.
Um,
but truth be told,
our fucking dependence on fossil
fuels is what's really getting us.
You know what I mean?
It's like,
I don't want to keep inventing
new ways to get fossil fuels.
Like that's not the
direction we should be good.
That's a regressive
direction to go in it like,
like fucking,
let's work on getting alternative sources
of energy and let's get the fuck off
of these fossil fuels.
Let's stop driving these
fucking gas guzzling cars.
Let's move into a new energy when it
comes to the way that we consume are
true.
That's easy to say,
but the real issue is that the situation
we have right now is people are
operating cars based on fossil
fuels are heating coils.
That's because of the
well fucking lobby.
We know this watch who
killed the electric car.
We have the capability to be able to,
to move off of fossil
fuels fucking years ago.
You think the Tesla is
like a new technology?
Yeah,
money in the ground is there and once
it's located it becomes a huge issue.
Right?
Is a huge commodity because,
and we also,
like you were talking about
with corporate welfare,
like who the fuck are we giving
so much corporate welfare too?
Fucking big oil.
These big energy companies.
There's some of the biggest lobbies in
this country and they are lining the
pockets of our politicians
and our politicians are
never going to vote for laws
that shut them out because then they're
not going to get their beautiful
corporate sponsorship and they're
not going to win reelection.
Here's a perfect example.
When was the last time
you ever a politician
say that we should ban cigarettes?
Cigarettes kill in this
country and this is not fake?
450,000 people a year.
That's insane.
450,000 people just in this country
lower than it used to be because we have
education and because we had our surgeon
general come out like almost 50 years
ago and say this is fucking bad for you,
but could you imagine if there was a
terrorist that killed 450,000 people in
this country every year and how much we
would be trying to get that terrorist
crime?
11 that was 3,500 people.
Yeah,
exactly.
If there was a food product that
killed 450,000 people every year,
if there was anything
that killed those numbers,
it's just dirty money.
It's just dirty money and everyone turns
a blind eye to it and it's one of the
great hypocrisy is of our time.
I completely agree.
And cigarettes as you're saying,
let's say it was like tainted
spinach that did that.
I don't think I'd be hearing anybody
cry for no regulations after that.
And that's the problem with
those arguments is that
you make them conveniently
after some sort of horrible event.
Well,
the thing about regulations is that you
put money into this and you maintain it
so that nothing bad happens.
It's very hard to prove a negative,
right?
If nothing bad is happening,
that means our regulation is working.
That's a good thing.
When bad things happen,
sometimes it happens because
we're under-regulated,
but you don't know it until
people fucking get sick and die.
If people aren't getting sick and dying,
that means we're actually maintaining
at a good regulatory pace.
But people don't want
to hear those arguments.
People want to look at like,
Oh,
look how inflated our budget is.
Look at all the money that we're
putting into all of these different
regulations.
I don't see any effects from it.
It's like,
yes you do.
It's just hard to
measure negative effects.
People aren't dying.
That's a good thing.
I'm going to switch gears here because
there's one thing they really wanted to
ask you about this cause we're,
I know we're almost out of time.
You got a hard out Fukushima.
Are you worried about that?
Are you worried about the,
uh,
the ocean?
Are you worried about a fish being,
I know that there's a lot of pseudoscience
out there and I know that there's a
lot of good science out there and it's
a very hard to come through and I really
haven't done my due diligence mostly
because of the new job that I'm doing.
And you know,
that the direction that
my career is going.
If I were still a science writer,
I would probably know a lot more about
this and I would feel much more competent
to talk about it.
I definitely have certain,
uh,
news outlets and media outlets
that I trust more than others.
And obviously I'm
worried about this spill.
It's fucking horrible.
I'm,
I have the luxury of saying I'm not that
worried about tainted fish because I
don't eat seafood as a
general rule like at all.
First of all,
I don't like it,
but I also have always had concerns about
certain types of toxins that fish can
carry in a greater quantity
than most domestic animals.
So you know how you look
at these lists sometimes,
like if you've ever known somebody who
is pregnant and the doctor will say,
Oh,
you can't do this and this and that,
hey,
you probably shouldn't eat this then.
And I'm like,
well,
if you're pregnant and you're not
supposed to eat like certain types
of fish,
maybe probably just don't do it anyway.
Because if it's harmful for the baby,
I don't see why it's not
that harmful for you.
This is the lower concentration,
but still,
but I also fucking hate seafood.
I hate the way it tastes.
I'm not a big fan at all.
It all tastes the same to me.
All seafood has this underlying
like briny don't really,
you're with me?
Yeah.
Even seaweed,
I can't eat because it
has this briny like,
Ooh,
Shinny Yucky taste.
So,
um,
so in that way I'm being selfish.
Like I don't fucking know
because I'm not eating it.
But of course,
I mean nuclear radiation being
dumped into the ocean is dangerous.
Whether or not it's dangerous
for me it's kind of a moot point.
Like is it dangerous?
Dangerous for the ecology of the ocean,
of course.
And that fundamentally is
going to affect all of us.
So I think it's about actually really
doing our research and figuring out like,
are these scare tactics or is this
like legitimate scientific evidence and
trying to sort through the bullshit,
which is really hard to do.
I mean,
digital media literacy is something that
I think we all need to be armed with.
Living in a world where we
have so much information,
how we need regulations,
God dammit,
who let them build those fucking
things in the first place,
knowing that if the power goes out,
we're doomed.
If the power goes out,
you're going to create a spot
that you can never cool off,
that's going to be fucked for
the next hundred thousand.
You maybe don't put it in a place where,
uh,
there's a history of massive tsunamis.
You know,
it's like the same thing.
We have different issues
all over this country,
right?
I did,
I did a show for the weather
channel called hacking the
planet and then we did a
fun kind of spin off of it called the
truth about twisters and they were really
fun.
And they also helped us realize
that like no matter where you live,
like Mother Nature could fucking get ya,
but in different ways.
So you know,
if you live in tornado alley,
you have to tornado proof
your infrastructure.
If you live in a place that's prone to
earthquakes because you're on a fault
line,
you have to earthquake proof your
infrastructure and you should think about
building these dangerous things.
You should think about the
safest places to do it.
And I don't think that on in a fucking
flood zone on the coast is a good place
to put a nuclear reactor,
but they do it all the time because they
want to have that water to cool off.
The core becomes more convenient.
Convenience and cost effective.
I mean those are words we keep
coming back to mother fucker.
Kara,
we can talk for the end of the time.
It's so much fun over and over again.
Yeah,
we need to do this more often.
I'd love to do it was a year and also
I got to say like I'm thinking about
starting my own podcast.
I'm very much inspired by you Joe,
and you know those of you guys who are
listening and who are tweeting and being
really cool,
I haven't even had time
to look through them,
but I'll be doing that
the rest of the day.
Yeah,
that's true.
But you know,
but I would love to get some feedback and
some insights and what kinds of things
you would want to hear.
You know,
I always,
you know,
if I'm going to start a podcast,
I'm going to do it for you guys.
So I want don't do that.
You're a great talker.
Just talk.
Just do
it.
Just do it.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yes.
I want to talk to people.
Well,
nothing wrong with that as well.
I mean,
definitely have a guest,
but look,
you're awesome at talking.
Just get together and talk about
things that you find that interesting.
I'm gonna quote that to tweet or
I'm going to quote that as a tweet.
Joe Says,
I'm awesome at Tom.
It's,
it's not hard to do a podcast.
It's a car.
I mean,
you just did it.
It's so much fun.
This is a little different.
When I sit here,
it's like so much fun.
And I walk away and I'm like,
why the fuck am I not
doing this more often?
Yeah,
well,
it's also,
you completely own it.
100% yours.
There's no input.
There's no production company.
There's no executive network.
There's nothing.
I mean,
look,
you see how easy this is?
This is going to ridge
reach millions of people.
We get 9 million downloads a month now.
It's fucking crazy.
You could,
you could do that too.
It's not hard.
You know the last time
I came on your podcast,
which was about a little over a year ago,
I walked away and I got something like
5,000 new Twitter followers from being a
guest on your podcast,
not shots.
It's probably going to
be even more this time.
Kara,
Santa Maria follower on Twitter.
Let's prove a point.
Let's see how many we could do a Kara
Santa Maria and your show is one more
time.
Right now I'm working on a show
called take part live on pivot TV,
take part,
live on pivot TV in his pivot.
How widely distributed is that mostly and
I think 40 million homes have directv.
If you have Uverse,
if you have fires,
you,
you have a capability.
If you don't,
you can go on the website,
take part.com/live and you can watch
each episode a few hours after it airs
until the following 24 hours.
So you can pick up basically each day's
episode the following day until the new
episode airs.
So that's pretty cool to
vision impaired people there.
Yeah.
Look,
yeah,
we're super nerdy.
Also if you go to my website,
which is where Joe is
right now on the screen,
my website,
I have cataloged and archived
every single clip I've ever done.
So all my podcasts,
all my TV appearances,
all my internet appearance.
So,
so you can click on take part live and
you can see any clip that that's been
clipped out from that.
You can click on,
talk nerdy to me and see all my
old talk nerdy is from huffpost.
Those are great.
Yeah,
I love that.
That was really to organize your website.
Squarespace fucking gem fucking
told you peaceful or spaces.
The I do it all.
I literally do it all myself.
You can see uh,
you know all my young Turks appearances
every time I've been on TV from Sundance
to travel to whatever and they're all,
they're beautiful.
We'll do this more often.
I love to every couple of months or so.
And I'll do your show as well.
Whatever you need.
I can't wait.
Oh you'll be my first guest.
Cool.
Tweet me at Cara Santa Maria.
Cause I want to hear from you.
Thank you Kara,
and a thank you to our sponsors.
Thanks to ting.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com save 25
bucks off of one of those delicious and
nutritious cellular phones.
Thanks.
Also to
save 10% off any and all supplements and
thanks to stamps.com use the code j r
e and get yourself $110 bonus offer.
We will be back tomorrow.
Uh,
I'm not sure who's on a comedian,
but something good ma
big kiss to everybody.
Much love.
See you soon.