Scott adams,
ladies and gentlemen,
here we are.
Hey Joe.
Good to see you again man.
Good to see you again.
Um,
I met you decades ago.
Do you remember that?
Horrible story?
I don't remember a horrible story,
but it was on news radio was horrible
stories you remember about humiliation
that day.
Know what happened.
So for those of you who weren't with us
on that set,
I had a small line,
just one line on news radio because it
was an episode that mentioned Dilbert.
So I was invited as a guest and you were
giving the line before my line.
So I just came in and they said,
joe is going to say this.
Joe.
Say you're lying and you've turned to me
and you said you lied.
And they said,
when he says that you say your line.
And of course I panicked because I,
you know,
I don't do this right?
Not An actor.
So the scene starts and it's one of
these scenes that runs continuous from
beginning to end.
It's not like a movie where you cut it
every 10 seconds.
So you have to do a ride all the way
through and we get to my,
my line and you're turning the other
direction.
So the line I'm waiting to hear instead
of hearing it clearly,
like in practice when you were facing
me,
I hear Walmart.
Oh No.
And I think to myself,
I don't know what his other lines are,
so I don't know if that sounds like my
line or is that,
should I go?
And I said to myself,
50 slash 50 chance
either.
Either ruin the scene by saying
something the wrong time or I ruined the
scene by being silent when I should've
been talking.
So I said I'm going to go with silent
and I just,
I just stood there in silence and
everybody,
everybody got really quiet.
I don't know if you remember why you
did.
But uh oh,
it's burned in my mind.
You were very nice that day,
but you just sort of slowly turned
around and looked at me and meanwhile
all the other actors sort of slowly
turned around and looked at me because
that was the source of the problem.
And then,
uh,
but I have to admit I was impressed
because that all the actors went back to
square one and did the entire scene
through again,
perfectly.
There is very impressive if you're not
an actor to watch how many lines a bunch
of professionals can do without screwing
up any of them.
It was,
it was,
uh,
it was an awesome kind of an afternoon.
Well,
news radio was a very unusual show in
that we did.
There was a lot of changing stuff on the
fly.
Like the writers come in and rewrite a
line,
like on the fly,
like they would do one line that we do
one take and then Paul Sams,
Josh Lieb on these guys would get
together and they go,
okay,
that's,
let's try this.
Let's try this,
we'll go back.
But then when he went,
Scott turns to you now to say this and
then we'd have a totally new line for
the next scene.
And so we'd have to like be standing
over there by the elevator going,
no,
that's not gonna work.
No,
We do like come up with a bunch of
different ways to say it and then just
run with it on the fly and people don't
realize how hard that is.
Isn't that hard?
Honestly,
it's not coal mining.
What will you have to have the right
kind of mind for them?
Memory?
Yeah.
Sort of like when a musician
can do you know,
50 songs from memory.
Yeah,
and I'm thinking I could do seven notes,
you know,
and then I'm good.
That's all I can remember in a row and
after that it'd be just be guessing.
Well,
if you think about how many you just
think about language itself,
how many words you can access just
instantaneously.
Just pulled them up from your memory.
You know,
it's just that's what you do all the
time and if you all the time we're
reading sitcoms,
scripts,
you just get used to that sort of flow
and how things go.
It's not,
it's not really that everything looks
difficult if you don't know how to do
it.
Exactly.
People say that about my job as well as
how do you do that?
It's like,
well,
it happens to be the one thing I can do
well and I can't do most things well,
but one little thing I can do well.
Well,
one thing that people have a hard time
with the Sitcom world,
especially the old school sitcom world
is the audience like performing in front
of the audience.
This is a weird element,
you know,
I do feel that,
well,
you know,
I do tons of public speaking,
so in that environment I liked the
energy and I like all of it,
but usually if I'm speaking I know
exactly what I'm going to say and even
if I mess it up,
it doesn't matter.
It doesn't have to be specific,
but that was a,
that was a frightening situation
because.
So,
so keep in mind also that most of the
actors were stars,
you know,
there,
there were pretty big names and so I was
meeting everybody that.
So I was a little bit star struck and
you know,
I was completely out of my element and
that completely blew the scene.
You know,
just me.
It was like,
oh,
maybe there wasn't anybody else.
It was just me,
sounds like I fucked up.
Sounds like I was looking in the wrong
direction,
which is totally possible.
We were standing in line so you have to
be facing the way you were,
but.
Oh.
So I was looking at you during the
rehearsal or something.
Yeah,
the setup was we were standing in line
to get coffee and so during the practice
you turned to me so you.
So I would know exactly what you were
saying,
but in the actual thing we were in line.
So you're talking to somebody else.
Right?
I get it.
Yeah,
man,
I don't remember that at all.
It's like it's so funny how like one
person can remember something and it's
like a big moment and then another
person go,
like,
I just erased that.
Well I knew that I met you and I
remember,
oh,
Scott Adams is cool.
I like that cartoon and then all of a
sudden it's over.
You know,
it was that.
It was,
you know,
there's no other memories in my database
at a totally different experience that
day.
Well,
it's also,
I did 100 of them or 98 or whatever the
hell we did.
So it's,
it's a weird thing as you get older too.
Like I,
there's memories that I just have
scrubbed.
I'm like,
no room for him.
I got new data coming in,
I got to make some space.
It's like cleaning out your garage,
you know,
so there's nothing scarier than getting
together with your siblings after you
haven't seen him for years and you start
talking about your childhood and one of
you will be telling the story like,
do you remember the time?
I know it doesn't matter what it is.
I,
I jumped on a zebra and I ran it across
the zoo and they read the Ltb and the
other sibling will say,
that wasn't you.
That was me.
I was the one on the zebra.
It'll be such like,
you know,
a memory
that you couldn't forget what you did.
You actually wrote yourself into a
scene.
You weren't even there.
You were watching and you,
you wrote yourself into the hero's
theme.
That does happen with people.
Human Memories really flawed.
It's really flawed.
Well,
if you want to go real deep real fast,
you just gave me the good opening.
Uh,
uh,
I am a proponent of the,
we are all a software simulation,
um,
view of reality and that would also
explain why memories are so screwed up
and the explanation would be that the
past doesn't exist until you need it.
In other words,
the past writes itself on demand because
if we're software you wouldn't have
everything in the universe preprogram
just in case you needed it.
It would take too much resources.
I might have to spark up a joint.
So you just want real deep,
real quick.
I was hoping I was hoping to go that
way.
Do you want some smoke?
The weed?
I could do it for the first time.
I'd be willing to try it once.
Well,
I don't know if I want to give it to you
for the first time and I want you to
freak out.
You don't smoke pot at all.
The truth is I smoked pot once ever was
in first day of college,
but I never stopped.
So that's really just once.
Oh,
I understand.
So you smoked pot all the time,
so he did it once and you just kept
going.
I'd be willing to try it a second time
is what I'm saying.
I understand what you're saying.
Sure,
sure.
What you like,
what has life been like for Scott Adams
during this election?
You,
um,
came into the,
well,
you're obviously always well known for
being a creator of Dilbert,
but
I'm along selection cycle.
All of a sudden there was,
I had,
you know,
people that are already in contact with.
They were saying,
you know,
Scott Adams is a trump supporter.
And I was like,
what?
Scott Adams,
the Dilbert guys and trump supporter
because everyone assumes you meet
someone and they're a,
in the creative business,
you know,
you're in a creative business,
your,
you write a comic strip,
you would assume that you would be left
wing guy like almost,
almost immediately.
Well,
I'm neither left nor right.
I'm sort of all over the place.
My,
my views didn't match,
you know,
either of the major candidates on
anything.
So you're a free thinker.
I like to think I'm right and everybody
else was wrong.
I would like that too.
I'm actually,
um,
my larger philosophical grounding is
that is informed by my experience as a
hypnotist.
I'm not sure if you knew that.
No,
I didn't know you're a hypnotist.
So in my twenties I went to hypnosis
school and became an actual train
certified hypnotist.
Wow.
Yeah.
One of the things you learn as a
hypnotist is that the world is backwards
to the way people normally perceive it.
So normally you see the world as,
Hey,
you know,
90 percent of the time people are
irrational and doing rational things,
but 10 percent of the time we just go
knots and we do stupid things and it's
because something happened.
This sparked,
right?
That's the normal view of the world.
The hypnotist view of the world is
opposite.
The hypnotist says that 90 percent of
the time we're a completely irrational
and we're just making rationalizations
for why we did things after the fact.
Ten percent of the time we're rational.
But that's only when there's no
emotional content to the decision.
You know,
you're balancing a checkbook or
something,
you know,
trying to pick a,
the best route to someplace.
Um,
so that's how I see the world.
And so when I look at either the trump
supporters or the Clinton supporters,
to me from the hypnotist perspective and
someone who's studied persuasion for
decades,
I used it in my writing.
Um,
I see both sides as completely
ridiculous both and both of them are
grounded in complete absurdity is
they're just different.
Yeah.
But nobody knows why they're deciding
the real reasons that people make
decisions.
Our fear identity,
um,
you know,
they have some aspiration,
they've got something they're trying to
solve.
There's something that they're trying to
work out,
but the reasons we give are usually
completely false.
And the grounding for this
is that if you think about evolution,
I assume you believe we evolved.
Yes.
Um,
there was no requirement in evolution
that we ever understand our environment
the way we imagined we do.
And here's an example of that.
You could believe that you are a monk.
You know you're reincarnated from the
10th century monk like Steven Seagal.
It does.
He believe that,
yeah,
he's like a Buddha or something from an
actual,
like he actually got it bestowed upon
him by some Tibetan character.
All right,
so let's use Steven Seagal.
So Steven Seagal can be standing in a
grocery store next to,
let's say a Muslim who believes that his
profit literally flew to heaven on a
winged horse.
Those two people don't live the same
reality,
but they both buy groceries.
They both go,
they cook it,
they live,
they survive.
So it turns out that understanding your
reality at an actual,
you know,
I really know what is objectively
happening and I get it and I've got a
mental model that's quite accurate.
We don't need any of that.
So it would be deeply unlikely that we
evolved such a specific skill that's
completely unnecessary as far as we can
tell.
You know,
we do need to know that if I,
if you run into this wall,
you know your head is going to hurt.
So there's some basic stuff,
but we're probably all in even
interpreting that experience
differently.
So there's no reason to think that the
way I think of it as the way you think
of it.
So I see the world is this big
irrational ball and I use the hypnotist
persuaders skills to back up and try to
deduce,
you know,
what's really driving things.
And when people said that was a trump
supporter,
what they meant was,
um,
they may have only seen part of what I
was talking about.
I was writing about his skill as a
persuader.
And what I mean is that I noticed in him
the skills that I've over decades for
persuasion,
but I had a higher level than I've ever
seen.
Meaning that he is the most persuasive
living human I've ever experienced.
And I mean that in terms of actual
technique.
You know,
he's,
he's full of technique and it's all the
time.
I'll give you,
give you some examples.
That first time I noticed it was the
very first debate when Megan Kelly was
asking him the question about the
insults he had allegedly said to women,
not allegedly.
You said them.
And this is a setup that any other
politician with this setup is totally
trapped because they can either try to
deny,
they set it and then somebody has a
videotape and that doesn't work.
Or they can say,
oh,
I didn't mean it.
There's almost nothing you can say.
You're just trapped.
And that would've been the end of his
campaign.
First debate should have been over.
And if you remember,
do you remember what he said?
No,
I don't.
She said,
you said this,
this and this about women.
And he smiled.
He sort of looked at the audience and it
looked like or the camera.
And he said only Rosie O'donnell and the
audience erupted in laughter.
Completely unexpected and a place
inappropriate.
Provocative.
And what I noticed was that Rosie
O'donnell is a,
is a visual image that everybody shares,
right?
You've got a picture of her soon,
as I say the name and for his base that
he was catering to.
It was an unpopular image and one that
would just suck all the energy away from
the question which was toxic.
And really,
you know,
you can't touch the question.
You just have to suck all the energy
into another part of the room and wait
for the time to run out.
And that's what he did and it became the
headline,
Blah,
blah blah.
And He,
you know,
uh,
certainly,
highlighted the things he said about
women maybe more than it would have,
but the way he escaped that got my
attention and I thought that doesn't
look normal,
right?
That,
that's a,
that's operating at another level.
And so I looked for more examples of it
and you can see it everywhere and it was
especially clear by the time you started
saying,
well,
the other visual things he does is he
says,
build a wall and you can just imagine a
wall when he says,
uh,
we're,
we're paying too much ransom to Iran for
those soldiers.
He says,
we paid $400,
million,
or whatever the number is.
He goes,
imagine that money piled up.
It'd be so much money you would fill
this room.
You can't even imagine that big pile of
money.
He always goes to the visual because we
know that the visual part of our
brayden's the dominant part.
If you can get its attention and get it
on your message,
it talks to the rest of your brain into
anything you want it to.
Um,
when he talks about Isis,
he goes visual also.
He doesn't say they are bad people who's
religions has been distorted to the type
of thing you might hear from Hillary
Clinton.
He says they put you in cages and they
trained you in the cage.
They chop your head off.
I mean you can see that you're playing
in your head.
So everything he does,
he gets more attention than everything
everybody else does because he puts it
into a provocative picture.
So that was the first thing I noticed.
Then when he got to Jeb Bush and he
needed to defeat Jeb because he was the
strongest competitor.
So if he couldn't get past two of them,
there was no point.
And he went after him and strong and he
went after him fast and he went after
him with a low energy kill shot.
That's why I call these linguistic kill
shots.
It's not just an insult.
It was not just a clever nickname.
And we saw Clinton tried to come up with
clever nicknames that had no,
no purchase whatsoever,
like dangerous Donald,
you know,
it just didn't work.
But look at the.
Look at low Energy Jeb.
Here's how it's engineered.
It's engineered for confirmation bias,
meaning that you want the future to make
this look like a better nickname every
day.
And you want it to match his
physicality.
So before I ever heard low energy Jeb,
I had a good impression of Jeb Bush.
W,
when you look at Jeb Bush,
didn't you say to yourself,
this guy,
it looks like a cool character,
like if no,
but he looked like he was an incontrol.
I'm calm,
reasonable.
Exactly the person you'd want if that.
If the nuclear question came up,
if there was some big decision Jeb Bush
isn't going to get excited about.
Seemed like a competent CEO competency.
Yeah,
exactly.
And as soon as trump said low energy,
could you see him?
And the other way he was low energy,
low energy,
lying ted,
lying ted.
Lying Ted was beautiful because you knew
that because he's a politician,
sometime in the next several months he's
going to say stuff that you can say is a
lie,
whether it is or not,
just it doesn't have to,
but more importantly a ted has a
physicality about him that unfortunately
he's got beady eyes and I've said this
before,
if you're going to cast a movie,
you know,
we need a guy who's looks dishonest.
It would be his face and unfortunately,
I mean,
I don't know if he's actually dishonest.
I'm not going to make a judgment.
So came up with the Zodiac killer thing.
Was that a trump fan or was it trump
himself that started saying that Ted was
the Zodiac killer.
I think that probably started with the
fan,
but.
So the other thing that was fucking
harsh man,
he be given speeches.
Are you the Zodiac killer?
People would scream it out like you
imagine having to deal with that.
And did your father killed somebody?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
His father was maybe dad was the Zodiac
killer.
Is that with the Zodiac killer?
It was like the seventies,
right?
Might not be old enough.
Uh,
so crooked Hillary,
Crooked Hillary,
same thing,
circle millions of brilliant one.
So she wasn't physically,
you know,
as limber as a young person.
So you could imagine her sort of a
little bit crooked physically,
and you knew that there would be stories
coming out in which people could say,
well,
there's another example of that
crookedness did you see?
But you thought that that a physical
sense,
like
the way she looked all I thought about
his corruption,
I heard Crooked Hillary.
I saw her like with like a burglar's
mask on trying to sneak away with bags
that had dollar signs on them.
You know,
that's what I saw.
If you look at anyone of these
individually,
his nickname's you,
you could say,
well,
it's sort of random.
He just got lucky.
But if you look at a ball,
they all have that physicality.
They all have the,
uh,
the priming so that,
you know,
you'll confirmation bias will kick in.
Whatever you see.
After that,
we'll just fit the label because it's
the first thing you think,
well,
he's a performer.
You know,
you,
you can say Donald Trump is a
businessman.
He most certainly is.
It certainly is a real estate investor,
but he's been a public figure for
decades and when you're a public figure,
you're a performer and he's performing
all the time and he's also,
he likes to win.
And so when he's engaging in people,
he makes it personal.
So he's gotten very good at what's
called playing the dozens,
you know,
playing the dozens is tell us it's a
insult thing,
you know,
like you can like one guy like guys in
the hood,
in the inner cities,
this started out as a black term,
but it's essentially like a version of
your mama contest.
Like some guys are way better at your
mama jokes.
They're way better at playing the
dozens.
They're way better at shitting on other
people around them.
And it's for the entertainment of each
other.
So huge thing amongst comedians.
We shit on each other constantly left
and right,
but it's generally encouraged and we all
enjoy it,
you know,
but when a guy has decades and decades
and decades of this like Donald Trump,
but a very high level because he's known
to be a billionaire investor who puts
his name on everything,
everything and still win big,
which I talk about developing systems
for succeeding.
One of the systems is to you do this to
a stack together,
what I would call ordinary skills until
your stack is different than anybody
else's.
So in my case,
I'm not a great artist.
I didn't take any writing courses,
but I'm pretty good at drawing and I'm
pretty good at writing a little bit of
funny so it put them together and I
couldn't do a comic strip because it's
rare that you get somebody who's,
let's say in the top 10 percent of three
different things,
but it's not hard to be in the top 10
percent of things if you're.
If you're going after them.
So if you look at trump,
he wrote a book on negotiating.
So he knows business.
He knows negotiating.
He knows public speaking,
he has a sense of humor,
a really good one.
He's quick on his feet now.
He knows politics from both the inside
and the outside.
Um,
he knows twitter.
If you,
you know,
I could probably go on and you would say
if you looked at any one of those
things,
he's not the best you've ever seen.
You know,
he's not the best public speaker,
the funniest person,
etc. But there aren't many people who
can do all of those things in the top 10
percent.
You put it as a puBlic speaker.
I don't think he's nearly in the top 10
percent.
I think he's a,
I mean,
I'm just being honest.
I think he has a very poor efficiency
of,
of words like,
um,
he uses,
he repeats himself when it's not really
important.
And when it repeats itself,
what I usually see is like someone's
searching for the next thing to say,
you know what I'm saying?
Like he'll say,
you know,
I'm gonna,
be honest with you.
I'm going to be honest with you.
Okay,
I'm going to be honest with you here.
He'll do that in a way that is not.
It's not efficient,
not efficient,
but it's persuasive in this way
sometimes,
but it also.
No repetition,
repetition sometimes.
Sometimes,
and sometimes it's clunky.
Yeah.
I feel like he.
I feel like there's a lot of times where
it's his style to do that and he's done
it before,
but even like in delivering lines,
you've got to know when to not talk.
Like here's a perfect example.
When he said that he called the
president of the president of Mexico up
and they had the conversation about the
wall and he said,
the wall just got 10 foot higher.
He's like,
yeah,
that's what I said.
That is what I said.
Like he repeats that said he should've
just let it hang.
He should have just said the wall just
got 10 foot high.
They would've went crazy and you gotta
walk back and forth and just sucked it
in.
But he kept talking.
So that's not the best speaker like
obama.
I feels way better public speaker,
way more efficient with his words,
way better control of the sentences that
he speaks,
but it's more professional.
I think you're judging a standard that I
probably wouldn't use,
so I took the dale carnegie course
teaching you how to be a public speaker
and their course taught you a zero
technique.
It was,
it was a course on public speaking in
which theY tell you nothing about
technique.
The things that you're saying he's
doing,
not necessarily technique.
Well,
let me just finish this off shore.
I'm sorry.
What they tell you is just confidence
and,
and if you were happy and confident,
you would almost always do well even if
you make a mistake,
you correct.
so he strikes me as the confident dale
carnegie type of speaker,
the person who's selling an emotion.
It's an experience.
You're not going there really to get
information.
It's not really a well crafted joke
she'll looking for.
You're going there to feel something and
you can't.
You can't deny that 30,000 people in a
stadium with red hats on know they were
feeling something.
So in terms of delivering and emotion,
top 10 percent.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Well,
I think that for absolutely one thing
you could say is he knows how to do the
Donald Trump thing and the Donald Trump
thing is very different than the rest of
the politicians thing.
The Donald Trump thing is not humble.
The Donald Trump thing will tell you
about his past successes and use them to
tell you how he's going to be successful
in the future.
The Donald Trump thing when confronted
with certain things like the thing about
it,
you know him saying something about
hillary,
lacking stamina,
and then you start goes off about having
a winning temperament.
I have a winning temperament.
There's not a lot of people who could do
that in that sort of a political forum.
Like if if say mitt romney was running
for president,
he started saying,
I have a winning temperament.
I.
They'd be like,
oh,
ms dot gone fucking crazy.
Right?
You remember how howard dean got knocked
out of the race just for screaming.
He just screamed at a rally and it was
over.
The wind came out
of the balloon,
but you know,
you know what howard dean did wrong.
What you always screamed once,
it's all,
it's all about contrast.
Well,
he also didn't make fun of it,
you know,
he should have come on and he should
have done something to make fun of it.
He should've had a speech where he
talked about.
So I got a little carried away folks,
you know,
like he,
he,
he hid from it.
It feels like he could have fixed that.
Yes.
Yeah,
I had that at the time.
Well,
if the problem was it was contrary to
what he was selling,
he was selling this buttoned up,
packaged deal and in the middle of that
package deal is a fucking pro wrestling
fans screaming from a suplex,
you know,
like hulk hogan suplexes the iron sheik.
And I mean that's what it was like.
I mean,
that's not the guy who,
you want to have the button.
So have you heard of these studies?
I think this has been replicated in
fairly reliable that if you want to
addict somebody to something,
let's say this year,
your show,
if you gave them a really good product
every time,
it actually wouldn't be as addictive as
if once in a while it wasn't good and
they had to sort of like wait and
anticipate,
oh,
there's that good weather again.
So a unpredIctable rewards are far more
addicting than predictable.
So a hillary clinton who reward you
every time and it,
but it's just about the same is not
gonna be nearly as addicting as Donald
Trump.
Who disappoints the fuck out of you?
You're like,
god,
I was just starting to like you.
Why did you say that that way?
And then two weeks later he comes out
with something.
You say,
shit,
I love you again.
And you know,
so it's,
he's got that addictive pattern going.
Well I'll tell you what,
once all that grab the pussy stuff got
out of the way.
He was doIng a lot of speeches and the
rundown the last few days and I watched
a few of them on television because I
almost felt like even though I knew I
was gonna vote,
I almost felt like some sort of a
spectator like this is this cannot
possibly be real to speak to your
software simulation idea in the
beginning that a lot of people share,
by the way,
it's not just crazy Scott Adams and me,
but there's a lot of folks out there
that think that we're living in a
simulation.
Right.
But as he would give these speeches,
and there were some of his speeches he
gave where there was these moments where
you're like,
if someone could tell that guy to keep
it at seven,
like where he's at right there and talk
like that always and avoid all the crazy
shit.
But man,
the crazy shit is what you get.
Like that's.
That's the thing about people like trump
or like any powerful super dominator
type character like that.
You'd have some flaws.
A lot of them,
the liquid,
he kept saying all the time,
he was always saying he was the energy
guy.
Yesterday.
I look at my crowds.
The other one has no stamina.
This one's,
you know,
low energy.
Um,
he knew the facts didn't matter,
he knew the policy didn't matter.
And by the end,
I think everybody agrees they didn't
mean by,
by election day.
Not a lot of people were saying,
well,
I sure like that tpp stand,
nothing like that was happening.
There was no,
no issues.
It just,
it just came down to which one you
hated.
The more.
Well,
there was one issue though that was real
and that was amongst feminists,
there was amongst women who were willing
to exonerate hillary on all the weird
shit that she had ever done involving
women.
Uh,
all the stuff that she had done
involving deleted emails and,
you know,
and I had heard people even say that
people were giving her a hard time
because she's a woman on her health and
I was like,
you are out of your fucking mind if you
believe that she's falling asleep when
she standing up.
That is bad.
That is so bad.
If that was anyone close to me,
anyone close to me,
I'd be like,
you're not going to be president.
We got to get you healthy.
You're fuckIng blacking out while you're
standing up and it's not just.
Once she fell down once in 2012,
got a serious concussion and was fucked
up for six months.
Me as a person who's terrified of brain
trauma,
that freaks me the fuck out because I
know the repercussions of brain trauma.
I know the impulsiveness that it bestows
upon people.
It's a horrible curse that happens.
It's happened to a lot of people I know,
so I knew there was this weird
delusional thing where people didn't
want to address the fact that our health
is poor and then it was revealed that
one of the wikileaks emails that she had
suffered from some sort of a,
not a stroke,
but a seizure in 2015 like that's a
fucking year ago what is happening,
but nobody wanted to talk about that and
there was this strange air that she's
not being treated fairly.
I'm like,
here's treated fairly.
She is a person who deleted 30,000
emails after she got a subpoena.
She's an older rich white woman.
If she was a 40 year old black guy and
she deleted 30,000 emails after
subpoena,
they would just shoot you.
It would just come over here.
They would kick down your fucking door
and cuff you and drag you off to a cage
somewhere.
So how weird is.
Am I right way here?
What's going on here?
How weird is it that we went through the
entire election cycle and so many people
like it wouldn't like,
like me were saying,
I'm not sure she looks healthy enough.
She's definitely not healthy now.
She of course metal the standards,
best presidents,
but what to what person ever interviewed
her and said,
look,
there are a lot of questions about your
health and so the question this way,
can you look the american public in the
eye and tell us there's no major health
problems that you haven't disclosed?
I would never ask her a question like
that because I don't think she'd ever
give you a real answer the same way with
the fbi,
but you could tell by the way she evaded
it whether she was.
She's a wizard at that though.
That's her shit.
That's the shit man.
That red cape with the bull just goes
flying by.
wow.
You could always tell a lie or light.
Layers will say something like,
so if so if you said to me,
scott,
have you ever had any major health
problems?
I'd say,
I haven't met all the requirements of
the presidency.
I was like,
oh no,
no.
I'm asking you a specific question.
Is there not disclosed?
And then I say,
Donald Trump hasn't disclosed any more
than I've disclosed.
That's a person who's hiding something.
right?
Otherwise they look you right in the eye
and they go,
I swear I'm great.
You know,
everything's good.
I promise you nothing's going to come
out lAter when I'm president.
You will not be disappointed in any way
because nobody can say that if they
think they're going to get bitten in the
ass in a year and a half when they
collapsed in the white house lawn.
My,
my point was insane.
that is that if you,
if you anyway described her health
issues,
that you would somehow be a sexist and
that the idea of her gender and being
the first female president,
which obviously would be very historic,
right?
Huge issue.
Huge,
huge honor that,
that,
that was a part of what they were votIng
for.
It became a part.
Her gender became a part of what they
were voting for.
And so that was an issue.
Let me give you the,
the,
the positive spin on the same topic.
Cnn polished 24,
a pundit explanations of why trump won
unexpectedly.
Twenty four different theories about why
we didn't see coming in the top 24.
None of them were.
she's a woman,
so couldn't get,
couldn't get it.
Not in the top 24.
Right?
So if we may pause for a moment from
piling on.
Ms dot clinton.
I got to say that the whole breaking the
glass ceiling thing,
she fucking did that.
That's toast.
There's no six year old born today who
says women can't be president.
That's not even in their worldview.
That's not true.
I'll find you five,
six year olds and say it right to your
face.
I'll bet not.
I get a bunch of them together.
Can a to be president.
I get some boys together.
I give them candy high five them.
You can trick them.
That's true.
You can talk.
Talk buys into anything for candy.
I mean,
I know what you're saying though.
I know what you're saying.
That she got as she won the popular
vote,
right?
As far as current count.
Right?
But who are you seeing saying,
oh,
if it was sexism that didn't get her
elected feminists,
feminists,
that I know.
I mean there's a lot of people that
actually believe that.
And you know what man,
there's a whole spectrum of variables
and if someone's thinking about if
they're hovering over a,
you know,
if they're looking at Gary Johnson and
hillary clinton,
maybe that was.
Maybe they'll never trump.
Maybe they're one of those people,
they're like,
one,
one of these motherfuckers going to get
my vote.
They might start thinking,
man,
I don't know if I want a woman
president.
That's absolutely a factor.
Have you heard anybody say that?
Yes.
And what dId they say?
Did they friend of mine?
A yoga instructor?
So as a woman,
she was,
bitches are crazy.
I don't want a woman running this
country.
That's for real.
That's a real statement.
I mean that's a human being who was just
talking to me and we're friends and no
one was around.
And do you think that she would vote on
that?
Yes.
I think there's many people that would
vote on that,
but there's many people that will like,
fuck this man.
I don't care what hillary did.
I don't care if hillary's got a bunch of
rape victims buried in her backyard.
That's a woman.
She represents women and probably
donald's got more.
You know,
there's that attitude too.
There's a of people that would only vote
for a woman if given the chance.
Other know how you'd net it down because
I think it was a net positive.
Three hundred million people in this
country plus mexicans.
I don't think you really can net it down
like that.
I just think there's too many of us.
I don't think.
I think that's one of the things that we
learned from this really important
lesson when it comes to polls,
they're not real anymore.
They're not real.
You're not talking to me.
You're not.
You're not answering polls.
Jamie doesn't answer a goddamn pole.
Look at them.
So no one,
no one,
you know,
answers poles.
It's a such a small sampling of people
and the people that answer polls,
they don't have anything better to do
than answer a fucking pole.
Right?
That's not good as the jury duty
product.
That's exactLy what the problem is.
So I think we learned that definitively.
These polls do not work well.
If I could defend a native silver for a
moment was okay.
Again,
he does 5:38 to a website.
The best best statistician on politics.
What's not his fault?
He's worked with the data he has.
Well,
but he was also within two percent I
think wasn't.
yeah.
So yeah,
so at the end,
but you know,
they,
they always converge toward the end,
you know,
they started out wIldly ridiculous and
then when it's clear that it's going to
be one way or the other,
all the polls are coming toward the end
because they want to say,
well,
if they hadn't,
that was only two percent.
Well jamie and I were watching this
video clip of the young turks calling
down the election yesterday and at the
beginning of it they were 100 percent
convinced that hillary could not lose.
You know,
there's this one guy was saying,
you know,
hillary can't lose.
She like literally it's mathematically
and then by the end they were fucking
screaming and swearing.
It was like,
wow,
these numbers that people like count on
like 84 percent say this 15 percent.
Try to Imagine my life.
I don't know if you know this,
but a year ago,
more than a year ago,
I predicted that trump would win with 98
percent certainty in a landslide win at
all.
I was one of the few people who said it
earlier,
and this is because of the way he was so
persuasive.
Yeah.
Just based on his,
his talents.
Not.
But this was pre the rosie o'donnell
thing.
If it was a year ago,
I think it was over the summer.
That was like august last year,
the first debates where I think yOu're
right,
but that wasn't a year ago,
right?
There was a little bit more than a year
ago,
but whatever.
We're splitting harrison.
Okay.
Um,
so back then when I predicted it,
uh,
you can imagine the heat I took because
it was such an unlikely pick and how
many people just wanting to dance on my
grave for be enrolling and the angry at
you and angry.
Yes.
Going to be going over to amazon and get
me a bad book reviews because they
didn't like what I said about Donald
Trump.
So that moment when I found out that I
haven't wasted my whole year because it
would have been a terrible year to be so
wrong for a year,
and then there's like no pay off
whatsoever.
It was like,
it was like the worst gamble ever.
Bad risk management.
Um,
but then to have it come,
come through just the way
I predicted it was this amazing,
amazing moment.
You only get a few of those in your
life.
Well,
he did really lend win by a landslide.
So that you were off by that.
That's an electoral landslide.
Oh,
electoral.
Yeah,
I guess so.
Electorally one by quite a few points.
Right?
But it wasn't.
It was pretty close up until how many
hours in,
as soon as you started,
it doesn't,
doesn't matter.
Yeah.
It doesn't matter.
Here's the thing that I think it's
important to make a distinction,
and this is what I recognize.
I knew when I watched some of your
periscopes and when you just weren't
making a moral judgment of him as a
person,
and that's what people expected.
People expected a line in the sand to be
drawn morally.
What you were doing was talking about
all of his traits,
you compounding all of his positive
traits and what he what he does well and
then people got mad at you for bringing
your.
You're analyzing it like say if you're a
scientist and you take up a plant that
you find in the amazon,
you're like,
well,
what is this plant consists of?
What's break down the parts?
You were kind of breaking down the parts
of what he does and where what is
effective and it didn't seem to me.
Now I'm like,
this doesn't seem like a guy who was
like,
oh,
there's a few guys out there that are
like rabid rah rah trump supporters and
some of them were at super transparent.
There's a few guys out there that I'm
watching them and I know what they're
doing.
What they're doing is they're latching
onto the trump train,
the latching on like really shamelessly
where they try.
They tweet about trump all the time now
where they never give a fuck about him.
Awhile ago,
like over the last six months,
they've jumped on this because they
recognize there's a tremendous amount of
loyalty and momentum behind being a
trump supporter and a fan because it's a
tough stance to take.
So guys that are already marginalized or
already kind of like fringe and people
think they're kinda maybe creepy.
They're like,
fuck this,
I'm going to full cream and they jump
right in and it's kinda,
it's real transparent.
Interesting.
You know,
obviously that's just my take on it.
They might actually be really trump
supporters and they're super excited,
but I sent some disingenuous behavior
out there.
Careful,
careful trump train.
He might have some hobos on your fucking
wagons.
I think what's different about this
election and about trump in particular
is that it used to be we're electing a
leader,
someone who would be a role model and
all that.
I think he threw that all out the door
and social media throws even moral
authority.
What I mean is I think the public is the
leader knew.
I mean,
I think no laws get passed that less
than majority of the public wants it to
get past anything that gets a little
adeline.
Social media just throws it back in
line.
And more than ever I think we hired an
employee rather than a leader.
I feel like I hired a plumber,
you know,
someone who's just really good at a
specific set of skills,
negotiating,
you know,
maybe doing something with a budget,
whatever it needs to be done,
secure the borders.
But it's sort of like picking a lawyer.
I don't care what he's doing in his
personal life.
He's not my role model.
And by the way,
which of our kids are looking to 70 year
old men as their role models anyway.
I mean,
I don't know if that happens a lot
anyway,
but I think I think he really is going
to be the first sort of people's
president you see as policies changing
in real time.
And the example we talked about earlier
when,
um,
you know,
he had,
he misspoke and he said women should be
punished if they get an illegal
abortion.
It turns out that the law and both
republicans and democrats think that's
crazy because it would discourage,
you know,
who didn't encourage the wrong behavior
and so only the doctor is punished,
but you saw him change his opinion in 24
hours just by being a little more
informed and hearing that the public was
all on the same side,
so that's interesting.
So he,
he'll beNd with the breeze in and I kind
of flip flopping.
Common political term is in the
political realm.
It would be flip flopping and you know,
he has no moral backbone,
but you're saying it's receptive to the
public's desires.
He's a businessperson in the business
realm is more like ab testing,
which is you're rapidly testing things.
You see what the response is and you
adjust if you don't get the right,
but that's also like one of the
criticisms of him is that he talks off
the cuff without really having
researched or thought deeply about these
subjects.
And when you're talking about a guy
who's supposed to be the leader of the
greatest country in the world's ever
known,
like,
that guy should probably not do that.
I'm going to put,
I'm going to put a different filter on
that.
Okay.
From the persuasion filter,
since facts and logic and policies and
stuff don't matter as much as you want.
When you See him ignoring things that
you just think,
man,
a reasonable person would not say that a
reasonable person would not ignore that
he ignores things because they don't
matter.
You think he's ignoring something very
important and he would perform better if
he did what you imagine is the right way
to act?
I don't think so,
but you don't think it's important to
not arrest women who get illegal
abortions?
No.
I'm saying,
do you know what I'm saying?
Like that's an important thing to pay
attention to,
right?
If you have an opinion on it.
Well,
what I'm saying,
what I'm saying is that the things you
would need to know to be a president.
Okay.
And let's say,
let's say hillary clinton knows them
all.
Let's let's say she's attended attended
of just knowledge.
if he's a six,
which probably is a generous,
there probably isn't any decision that
he won't have.
Advisors were filling it.
Say they becomes an informed as he needs
to know exactly the way a ceo would run
something.
Okay,
so this is not really related to that
one particular subject.
No,
that was just an example of him.
I understand what You're saying is
changing.
When he became more Informed,
he didn't.
He didn't stick to an old opinion.
Even as the facts change.
And this has done the same thing with
obamacare as well.
Right?
Met with obama and said,
okay,
maybe there's some things about
obamacare that we might want to keep.
So what he does,
we call pacIng and leading in the.
In the hypnosis I the bullshitting.
No,
and here's how it's different.
What he does is he agrees with people
emotionally first.
It gets you on your side emotionally.
So if you're really concerned about
immigration,
for example,
he doesn't just say,
hey,
yeah,
I'm,
I'm concerned about that too.
That would be sort of a hillary clinton
approach.
Being less concerned that you are,
but you know,
I got other priorities.
he's way more concerned than you are if
you're a little bit worried about
immigration and he's worried about,
you know,
isis coming over here and putting people
in cages and cutting off heads and my
god,
there's a hordes coming over the border,
so he's so on your side that when he
changes toward the middle and you knew
we had to because you have to do that
when you get in the general election
that his side was not feeling betrayed
because they're saying,
well,
if he's changing the specifics of his
policy,
it must be because he looked into it and
that's what's interesting.
that's what's practical,
so they're willing to go with him if
they feel that he's on their side
emotionally,
so he always sides with people
emotionally goes as big as possible.
Uses hyperbole.
He says he does that and it gives them
also gives them room to negotiate back
to the middle and everybody says,
my god,
I'm happy now you're negotiated back to
the middle.
Wow,
that's interesting.
It's interesting,
but why do I feel like just getting
lucky?
I feel like it's really shitty
competition.
Hillary clinton is a terrible example of
someone who should be running the
country in so many ways and she beat him
in the popular vote.
You know what I mean?
She's like,
she's got a lot of dirt on.
So she beat him in the contest.
They weren't having the result.
That was the only one contest.
It's true.
And he won that one.
That's true.
What's hilarious is in 2012,
he was saying it was a rigged system
because of that contest.
You know what I mean?
He was talking about the popular vote
and you know,
how it,
what was it?
Which,
which,
what year was it where it went to al
gore?
What year was it where al gore won the
popular vote,
but it was,
it did carry when.
No,
kerry number one the popular road.
Right.
It was just al gore.
Al gore won the popular vote against
bush,
right?
Yeah.
By like a half a million.
So every year there's going to be this
conversation anytime the voter's rights
close.
Um,
but what you see is that
trump doesn't care about,
let's say,
the consistency or what somebody would
say is being a hypocrite.
I've tweeted this recently that the
least persuasive thing you could ever
say in politics,
if you're trying to change somebody's
mind,
is that person's a hypocrite in all,
in all of history.
That's never changed anybody's mind.
Nobody ever said,
oh,
slap my head.
I didn't really realize that bottoms up.
You mean about a politician by
politician?
Yeah.
Well,
we accept a certain amount of bullshit,
but we also accept that they used to say
one thing and now they say another and
it just seems so normal.
It's in the baseline.
Don't you think that the being the
president is an impossible job?
It's impossible.
It just doesn't seem like anybody could
really do it.
It's both impossible and the easiest job
in the sense that the office of the
president and all the advisors and all
the public opinion is going to force you
down to just a few possible options and
those two options will,
you will not have enough information to
know which one's better.
So,
so anyone,
anybody among the last two options that
they've narrowed it down to,
there's a little bit of luck involved.
I got to say now.
So what do you mean by this?
WeLl,
you have to match the personality and
the time,
right?
So you could have a,
a president who is just terrific in
wartime but weren't much good at
anything else.
So they'd be,
you know,
next thing you know,
they're on mount rushmore because.
But you have obama whose primary job was
winding down to ors and basically
cleaning up and bass and keeping us from
a larger product problem.
You know,
the economy melting down.
So obama is really the presidency of
things he prevented that could have been
worse,
but I would put them in the top 20
percent of presidents.
So my view of him is very positive and I
think even obamacare is a genius
persuasive move even in its failure
because he set it up that way.
And he said that publicly.
He said,
I'm going to launch it ugly.
I'm paraphrasing,
didn't get exactly what I wanted in this
law,
but once it's out there,
it will be impossible for politicians to
pull back coverage.
They'll just have to fix it.
So where are we today?
Everybody's saying obama,
total failure without obamacare because
we're going to keep the good parts.
Keywords keep the good parts exactly as
he fucking plan and said so publicly.
He said it,
he said it publicly.
He said,
I'm going to do this ugly,
wrong,
and you're going to have to fix it
because it's going to be the only choice
you have.
And that's what,
that's what trump's gonna do.
He's gonna fix it.
So what is he going to fix?
Probably he's going to keep the main
parts and probably shift some money
around from something,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not sure that fix looks like a
miracle fix.
I don't knoW that that's in our future.
And I'm.
No,
I'm no expert on obamacare.
Well,
there's this weird thing that we've done
now with,
uh,
with trump that I've never seen before.
We've,
we've narrowed them down to chance and
slogans like I talked to in this podcast
about I was in New York city at the time
of the protests because I was there for
the ufc and uh,
we were walking from the gym to the
hotel and we just got caught in this
wave of people screaming with really
fucking crazy science man.
There wasn't a whole lot of love and
compassion on their signs that we were
talking about this before the podcast
started,
that the left has become something very
different.
It's like this really aggressive,
uh,
insulting shaming and even the call for
violence,
like there's people with rape melania
signs.
It's like,
this is crazy.
Yeah,
there's pictures of him online.
So the big question is,
well,
I have one foot in the,
you know,
the alt right world because I sample
everything over there.
But I'm also watching cnn and regular
media and these,
these folks live in completely different
realities because they have different
inforMation because they're looking at
different sources.
So within the conservative of things,
it is,
it is understood universally understood
that the protesters are professional and
they're paid by soros.
And by the way,
I'm not saying this,
I'm saying what their view is on the
other side,
people think it's a true grassroots
movement.
Um,
and so the view is completely two
different worlds.
Well,
there may very well be some people that
have been paid to protest,
but there is absolutely a bunch of
people that are protesting because
they're upset.
I mean,
it might be fluffed up a little bit,
I don't know,
but there's definitely people that are
just young people that are pissed off or
old people that are pissed off.
There's people that are just upset.
The question was whether the protests
would have lasted in spread.
And ben as well organized protest.
Scott adams.
It's fun.
You feel like you're doing something.
You're blocking wilshire.
Fuck you people,
you know.
And this guy,
I mean,
what I was saying about it boiled down
to a slogan like,
there's a bunch of,
not my fucking president,
you know,
like that kind of shit like Donald
Trump,
k,
k.
It's like they want to like yell out
things they associate with him,
which I've never seen before.
So there's about a president.
So.
So I write about this extensively.
So the best persuasion is fear,
right?
So in the beginning of the election,
trump had the best persuasion because he
was saying the terrorists are coming in
and you know,
I'll stop them.
There's criminals,
criminal cross the border.
Clinton was talking boring policies and
um,
experienced.
So she didn't have a chance against,
you know,
you're going to die tomorrow by summer.
She obviously had some professional
help,
meaning somebody who's a cognitive
scientist or a professional persuader.
And she started using the term dark all
the time and all the surrogates used it
at the same time.
It's dark,
dark,
dark.
And she started coloring him as a huge
racist.
Dictators.
Dangerous to the world and the most
dangerous thing in the world.
Because if you're worried about
terrorism,
you're really worried about somebody
else getting killed because you're not
really thinking you get killed by
terrorists.
You know,
even if it's pretty bad,
somebody else's getting killed.
But clinton painted a picture to make
you afraid of,
of,
uh,
you know,
the nuclear holocaust created by trump
tweeting something at 3:00 AM and I
don't know,
hitting the button accidentally.
And so that was the ultimate fear.
So she really had that going.
So,
uh,
and when she lost,
she had all these people activated who
would've been instantly deactivated if
trump had lost,
but there's no deactivation on the
bottom.
Now she created this society societal
bomb that is these protests in the way
people feel they're.
These people literally believe that
hitler was just elected,
you know,
a version of hitler who will will.
And I saw,
I actually saw today journalists talking
about concentration camps and that sort
of thing.
I believe nothing even remotely like,
that's going to happen or you know,
or I would obviously be on,
on the side of the protestors.
So it's not their view of the world.
Is that the trump supporters?
No,
he's a racist.
And they installed them because they
want them to go do racist things.
Trump supporters know that even within
the ranks,
it's like two percent people are our
actual races.
And I've never met one,
like the hardcore guide and I'd never
even met one.
I bet we can introduce you to some
people if we just asked around.
I think it wouldn't be hard to find one,
but the boat and had a very funny line.
He said not all trump supporters are
racist,
but all racists or trump's
porters.
So the,
so what we have here is a situation
where the racists are living in their
own little world and they think they
actually got their guy.
Most trump supporters just like,
hey,
less taxes,
you know,
that they're thinking they like his
personality though,
just like something about him.
And the clinton supporters think that
hitler actually got elected.
So they're acting on that.
So.
And so what's happened is that clinton
has somewhat accidentally,
because she thought she was going to
win,
at which point this whole problem goes
away.
Uh,
somewhat accidentally created this
gigantic societal bomb that there's no
way to diffuse.
But a number of people including me are
trying to figure it out.
I had to literally d hypnotize people
who were in this illusion that the world
war three just started.
Well,
it's,
it was very disturbing to me.
One of the,
one of the big ones was when she was
confronted about the dnc hack and uh,
her emails and all that stuff,
the hacked emails from our server where
she diverted attention by saying that it
was Russia that did this and that there
would be repercussions.
And tHen she said,
even possibly militarily,
like that's the worst diffusion of
responsibility ever.
Like you were talking about you deleting
emails after a subpoena and your
argument is that the russians got those
emails and we should bomb them.
I mean,
that's literally what she saying.
That was crazy when she said there would
be repercussions militarily to fucking
Russia.
Like what?
We're not talking about invading puerto
rico.
It's fucking Russia.
Like you're saying there's going to be
military invasions because someone stole
your email
that wasn't secure.
I'm going to defend her.
Please do.
I'm going to go to surprise you a little
bit.
Oh boy.
Here we go.
We should have a drink.
Do you drink?
I don't anymore at any moment.
You stop.
It just gave me sinus problems.
So I stopped several years ago.
I feel much healthier.
Alright dude.
Um,
no pressure.
What was I talking about?
Uh,
you were gonna defend hillary clinton
because I was saying that her saying
that we're going to attack Russia
because of emails is kinda crazy.
So the way leaders stock
with each other Is,
you know,
this is my red line,
don't do this.
This is serious.
That's not the same as saying if you got
my email,
I'm going to you tomorrow.
There is,
there's a certain amount of seriousness
which you must convey,
which is separate from what he actually
going to do.
So she was conveying I'm a Ten and a 10
maximum code red seriousness if you,
if you got my fucking emails.
And,
and,
and it changed the course of our,
of our republic because that's where she
was at the legend.
Now I don't know if anything,
any of this happened and they're smart
people who said maybe the russians were
in or some russian hackers were involved
in.
WeLl,
here's the problem.
There's no evidence that the russians
did it.
Not only that,
the fbi and the cia don't think there's
russians don't think the russians did
it.
Like it wasn't something that there was
any definitive proof.
It was find out who jamie see if he
could pull this up,
who believed that it was Russia and who
didn't believe it was Russia because
there was some like very prominent
security people that were hired to
investigate zero evidence.
It was Russia,
so it was just a diffusion.
It's an end.
You could tell that it was a planned
diffusion because of that white house
correspondents dinner.
She made a joke about riding a horse
with putin.
like she made this russian joke.
So there's this like theme and it was a
shit joke to whoever wrote it should be
slapped.
It was terrible.
Like the way it was set up was it was if
somebody,
if somebody pitched that around the joke
writers table,
you know,
like it was like it was tony hinchcliffe
and Jeff Ross,
or they'd be like,
no,
that one's not going to do that.
THat's a terrible joke.
It's just not a good joke and she,
you know,
didn't know how to deliver it either and
it was just a clunky,
an extra attempt to connect putin and
trump because people are scared of
Russia,
but it was so shitty and ham handed that
it just didn't work.
And everybody knows there's no fucking
evidence.
I mean,
there's no evidence of russia's doing
anything.
None.
Russia thing took her from,
you know,
serious statesperson,
the most experienced person who ever ran
for president to a little bit.
Ridiculous.
Yes.
She had desperate
bose desperate move.
So you didn't have any other options.
She,
she went code red.
She started talking shit back.
She started making things up back and
connecting him to like,
he was just.
The whole thing was so sorted.
To me that was the most unfortunate
thing about it.
When you do see all this stuff on tv,
one thing that you can't deny,
it might not affect you and it might not
affect me,
but there are certain people that fall
the tone of the leaders of this country.
And when you have a guy who's the
president,
who you know is going to say insulting,
should call John Stewart a pussy in,
in a tweet at 1:30 in the morning,
like that sets the tone for the country
and it's going to make some people very
happy.
There's some people that love to talk
shit.
They loved insult people and they're
like,
fuck yeah,
open season.
the way I described that,
I said political correctness took a
missile to the deq because that's what
it was like.
This is the,
this is the guy at the top of the totem
pole and we can relax our standards now.
All The things that had been annoying
you,
but people nitpicking about behaviors
and insults and safe words and safe
spaces and all that stuff's kinda gone.
Uh,
yeah.
I mean,
So it does affect the way people think
and behave right there.
There's almost nobody who won't use the
word pussy in public.
They do,
do,
do you remember so many months ago when
that just wasn't a thing.
You couldn't say that.
That's so drew.
It became like a constant like dinner
table talk,
like people sitting around talking st
grab the pussy and discovery from women.
It's not even deciding.
Not even bend.
My girlfriend says so true.
It's so true.
That is so true.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
I think that we go one way and we go to
the other and I think that people get
tired of too much left and they want
some.
Right.
And I think that's why we went from
carter to reagan.
That's why we went from bush to clinton.
I just think that's what we do.
I think it's what we've always done and
I think people are.
I,
I also believe,
and I've said this publicly,
I think the whole caitlyn jenner thing
had a big effect on because people were
like,
why in the fuck are we doing?
That's the athlete of the year.
This is woman of the year for glamour
magazine,
and then you see her on the ellen show
and she doesn't believe in gay marriage
and you're like,
we're,
this is madness.
We're,
we're accepting madness as being okay.
And I think because of that,
like we're so accepting and so sensitive
that anything involving gender gets a
free pass on all of its ludicrous
aspects.
Like she's a ludicrous person.
but we gave it a free pass because she
used to be a man that she became a
woman.
She will fucking doesn't believe in gay
marriage.
It's so crazy.
When,
when ellen asked her about it,
she was like,
well,
I'm cronenberg traditional welsh.
Like,
what?
What?
Wait,
what the fuck did you even just say
you're,
you're a traditional girl.
holy shit,
this is crazy.
But we're not supposed to say anything.
We're supposed to just accept it.
Well,
there's people at home all across the
country throwing their fucking beer cans
in the kitchen.
Just flipped out.
Fuck.
Are we doing?
What are we doing?
And I think there's this reaction when
things go way too far left when there's
78 different gender pronouns that you
have to learn.
When you know political correctness,
take some crazy path where you're
removing the general these confederate
flag from the roof and pulling it off a
tv land.
We've got to get this fucking.
It just like things go so far left that
there's an automatic slingshot effect
and they start going right again.
I'm okay with getting rid of the
confederate flag By the way.
I think they could have.
Well,
you know,
it,
it does represent bad things to people,
but can you just fucking go in there and
cgi that shit or something or is it okay
to have it in there because it
represents the past,
right?
like you could go to,
you can go to watch,
um,
al jolson videos on youtube and you
could watch them.
Here's my take on that.
People don't ask a lot from other
people,
but you.
So you have this confederate flag,
bunch of people like it because it's
like,
oh,
it's the best.
It'S the south.
So you know,
you want to respect the people like what
they like.
But another big part of the public,
it's just really,
really offended by it.
Like not in a normal offensive way,
like you said,
a bad word,
but like,
you know,
the deepest pain the country has ever
experienced the slavery.
So if you can't,
if you can't allow your fellow citizen,
you know,
that little bit of respect,
it's like,
yeah,
this is really inconvenient.
I wish I could keep my confederate flag,
whatever.
But they're not asking a lot.
It's just not a lot.
It's true.
Unless you own the dukes of hazard,
you're like,
where's my fucking mOney?
What are you kidding me?
We've had played it for 50 years.
What happened?
Well,
it represents not just slavery,
which is one of the most awful things
that has ever happened to human beings.
The other awful thing is war represents
a war civil war,
so the two most awful things,
slavery and war,
it represents both of those represents a
war between two people in the same two
groups of people on the same land,
mass over slavery.
So It's death on top of horrific in
capturing and enslaving of people.
It's like everything bad,
and I hate to be insensitive,
but they weren't the winning side
troops,
so they did lose.
But what's interesting is it just a few
decades ago,
whenever the dukes of hazzard was on tv,
it didn't bother us at all.
That's really fascinating to me that
they were allowed to have it and it
wasn't an issue,
but I don't know.
I don't.
Yeah,
maybe just people weren't thinking about
it that way,
but once you started thinking about it,
so the thing isn't that fascinating that
it wasn't an issue,
but we were all aware of it.
All of our issues or psychological.
I mean,
you know,
once you got food and nobody's shooting
at you,
your problems tend to be mental.
Yeah.
Unless that whatever that image is
provoking violence.
Right.
You know,
like the nazi flag you can't have,
they lost to which you can't have that
one.
We won't give you that one.
Right.
Yeah.
And again,
it's like people don't ask a lot.
That's just not a lot to ask to.
Isn't that fascinating?
Like the english came when we had a war
with england,
right?
For our independence.
They killed a lot of americans.
You could have an english flag flying
high.
Nobody gives a fuck.
You know,
that ended so politely though,
did it?
I mean,
I think,
I think the british,
they lose territory better than anybody.
They'll give you their sword.
Well,
we conquered much of the world,
but uh,
okay.
This one didn't work out.
You put up a good fight,
good for you.
Good for you.
Take your country back.
it is interesting though that there's
some people that would argue for the
confederate flag,
but almost no one would argue for the
nazi flag.
Well,
it was probably somebody does,
but yeah,
I know what you're saying.
You know what I mean?
The nazis.
I mean,
it couldn't have been that everyone in
Germany was represented by the nazis.
Right.
There's never a group.
There's never 100 percent compliance and
group mindset of any fucking country.
It's never existed.
Right.
It's just not how people are.
So we give the
germans a pass because they were a part
of that whole nazi flag thing.
But when we look at the confederate
flag,
like if you're down with that,
you have to be.
It has to be like the two core things.
One,
you're at war with the north until you
believe in slavery.
That's it.
You know,
it can't just be,
I'm a leonard scattered fan,
you know,
images,
images.
like I said,
in the very beginning,
visual persuasion is the strongest it
is.
You just want,
you just don't want to look at that
thing if you're on the wrong side of,
you know,
that part of history.
I was thinking about that once because I
went to cheech and eatsa the where the
mayan pyramids are in the yucatan.
And uh,
when we were driving,
it's a long drive to get to the
pyramids.
And as we're driving and saw this giant
cocacola billboard,
I said,
how bizarre is that symbol like that
symbols so etched in the consciousness
of most people in the modern world.
But to see it in the jungle was so
strange.
It's just this giant thing that
represent.
I mean,
it,
it's like instantaneous representation.
Was it new or was it leftover from the,
the,
the mayan civilization that had it.
It was newer than that.
Newer than that.
but I mean,
symbols are very strange.
I mean,
we,
uh,
we accept them and they have become a
normal part of our society.
When you drive it down the road and you
go,
oh,
what kind of car is that?
And you see the bow tie.
Oh,
it's a chevy.
Like these symbols,
like the instantaneous recognizable
symbols.
Have you noticed how easily boys can
recognize the model of a car?
Oh yeah.
There's some kind of weird,
um,
gender specific skill.
Oh,
I don't think so because brian cowen
doesn't know jack shit about cars.
Brian kennedy could recognize like a
tesla and a car.
Maybe he's owned maybe,
but it would have to be in the last
couple of years.
He is.
No,
I've never met a grown man.
It's like a manly guy who knows less
cares less about cars,
but still if you said what's that model
of car?
And it was probably wouldn't know.
He'd see a mustang and the camaro.
Okay.
Trust me,
lIke he is just brutal.
I've had conversation with them.
I'm not a fucking 69 mustang.
You can't tell.
They look at that.
The debt doesn't say that's a
[inaudible] 69 mustang to you turning
your god damn America card.
Turn it in.
Boy.
Sixty nine camaro.
Casey.
A 69 camaro.
You should fucking know what that is.
You should just know as a man.
I wouldn't know a 68,
69.
You should look at the headlights.
Taillights are different.
Everything's different.
In 68 have the same boxy tail lights
that the 67 hand,
whereas the 69 is lengthened a little
bit.
Well,
$69 a year.
That's the right year to change my name
to caitlyn and no,
you don't have to get.
Maybe she knows a lot about cars.
That was the other thIng about the
caitlin thing that drove me crazy.
She killed somebody,
knock someone into traffic,
knock some leading the traffic and she
wasn't paying attention.
Lady went head on into traffic.
Someone slammed into her and killed her
hummer.
One of the last hummers in America
slammed in her and killed her and it
never gets discussed.
She goes,
does talk shows and instead of talking
about this horrific accident that caused
some fellow human their life,
she talks about gender and nail polish.
Well,
yeah,
exactly.
I did not know about this.
We didn't know about that.
Yeah,
you didn't know.
See,
that's a big part of the problem.
I've been bad at caitlin,
uh,
since,
she was bruce because I happened to be
at a flight one time across country and
bruce at the time was in the seat in
front of me and leaned is a seed all the
way back and I couldn't use my laptop
for five hours.
And you're mad about that,
but that's.
Can you lean your back?
You have more room?
It doesn't really work that way because
can you put your laptop on your lap?
Like a actual lap top?
That coulD work.
You could have done it if I was right
next to you how to fix this whole thing.
If only the lab you were like,
I'm glad he's a Chickie.
Fucking ruined my typing this.
This is why it's called the laptop.
Yeah,
it sits in your lap,
but then your balls get really warm and
they say it kills sperm.
So it depends on what you're trying to
accomplish.
For some people they'd be just heating
them babies up all the time.
It was a long flight.
I might want to kill a few just to.
Just to take the pressure off is to
relax the my friend already should fear
always gets mad at that too.
People lean back on him because he's so
big.
He's like six [inaudible] six three or
something.
Six four.
He's super tall,
so he's got these goofy ass stork legs
and he can't fit them under the seat.
Anyway.
God,
I feel sorry for tall people.
Anytime they try to travel anywhere
outside their own house.
Even in cars,
you know,
you get in someone's car sometimes and
your legs are jammed up.
I'm like,
I'm fucking five.
Eight and my legs are jammed up on what
is a giant person do.
Yeah.
I'm trying to think like what would be
my equivalent,
like how small would the car have to be
so I could feel what was shack feels
like when he gets the car,
he has to take seats out and put seats
in the back.
Have you ever seen him with a do to cars
for him?
Really?
Yeah.
He's had some custom made cars where
they literally take the seat out of the
front and install it in the back.
I mean,
that's not,
that might look,
you know,
you think about it,
he's seven feet tall so that this thing
about how much more length you're
dealing with his arms,
his legs,
and then his,
the height,
like I bet they would have to lower the
seat down so you could see better out of
the windshield.
Otherwise he has to kind of bend down
every time he's driving.
I just says this vision of him with a
miata sitting in the trunk,
the trunk open,
you know,
just.
I bet he can't drive a miata.
I bet he can't.
I bet there's no way that he can get
farther,
far enough back strap one to each foot
and skated.
Well he would,
he could do is just put the steering
wheel.
He's so rich because could have the
steering wheel put in the middle and
then push everything back.
No,
forget that idea.
But I know for sure for sure they had
one of those custom tv shows,
custom car shows where they do things
for people.
Maybe it was west side.
What does that one show?
West coast,
west coast,
west coast customers.
Maybe that one famous company,
so they took her car and they put the
seat in the back for him.
Probably still needed extra room,
like suddenly you do for tv.
Can we gotta we gotta put the seat in
the back maybe because I got a feeling
he drives a regular cars somehow.
Maybe there's probably some cars that he
can't drive though.
Like one of those old porsches little
tiny ones.
Probably most of the.
Yeah.
Anyway,
point being what were we?
Oh,
it's terrible to be as general leaned
back and fucked up your day.
Yeah.
All went bad from there.
You know,
and look,
there's nothing.
I mean he's not terrible person.
She's not a terrible person.
It's not the worst human in the world.
It's just like when this gets paraded
out as being like this very important
point.
As soon as he gets paraded out and you
make a big deal and you want to go on
all these talk shows,
you want to talk about yourself and done
well,
they have to examine you as an actual
person and not just stop at gender.
You know what I'm saying?
Like there's,
there's a lot of representatives,
like for instance,
um,
the,
the woman who created sirius satellite
radio and also,
I believe she invented gps.
She was born a man and had a sex change.
And uh,
I met with her and had an interview with
her about her.
Um,
her.
She made a robot,
she's super fucking smart,
like crazy smart and is working on
artificial intelligence and programming
this woman,
um,
this like it's ahead of her wife being
like she married her when she was a man
and then became a woman.
They stayed together and being a is like
this,
uh,
artificial intelligence thing that she's
consistently updating as technology gets
better.
She updates it and gives it more and
more intense.
Like if you want to focus on someone
who's a transgender person,
like maybe that would be a good example
instead of just concentrating on a guy
who used to be really good at running
and uh,
you know,
and now lived with a bunch of
materialists on a reality show,
not just running,
but they come and they have no,
no purpose.
And really.
Yeah,
I mean,
so now no one's really into the
decathlon.
Sorry.
I'm sure he's awesome,
but nobody gives a fuck.
That's why he does any of those sports
where there's no professional side of
it,
like it's probably a reason for that.
I say that,
but then that's not true because a
wrestling.
I think wrestling is a great sport.
It doesn't have a professional venue,
you know,
other than like fake wrestling.
Do you ever think about how weird it is
that people can get invested in like a
team?
Yes.
Like why?
Why?
Why do you care so much about your team?
I think about that all the time.
I'm constantly.
Really?
Yes,
all the time.
We talk about it all the time.
It's a tribal thing.
People love being in a group.
They like being on team trump.
They liked being on team hillary,
you know there's there.
I saw I was watching so much tribal
behavior leading down like arguments
between people on twitter.
It's like you guys are crazy.
Like what are you doing?
You're arguing with people you don't
even know,
and I look at their timeline,
I'll look at the timeline.
They're arguing for seven,
eight hours in a row.
You could be doing so much to improve
your life instead of like insulting.
Hillary supporters are insulting trump
supporters.
They're all,
it's,
it says weird natural thing.
People joined teams that joined tribes.
They have groups that they like,
but it makes sense when you're looking
at say your ethnicity because probably
biologically we're,
we're primed to prefer it.
Whatever it looks like us,
you know,
just just naturally primed for that.
Do you think that's true?
Explain black eyes and asian chicks
ready.
Go.
I'm done.
So,
but in general
anyway,
so,
but so it makes sense if you're looking
at like big groups or a country or
something,
but a sports team as such,
a random collection of rules that,
why you could be emotionally invested in
that.
I've tried because it seems like such
cheap entertainment.
Well,
I want to.
You live a wonderful life,
Scott Adams and you're wealthy.
Successful man.
And uh,
for some people there's not a whole lot
to look forward to it.
And this is not.
Obviously I'm not using a broad blanket
to paint all sports fans,
but I think that there's a lot of people
out there that look to the success of
their team and they get happiness or
sadness from that and if you're in a
team,
like if you're in cleveland and they
kick ass and win the world title,
I mean they have the world heavyweight
champion of the ufc lives in cleveland
too.
Like you get some cleveland pride,
you know,
well that almost works until you
consider that there are like raiders
fans,
like they just keep losing and losing
raiders is a different thing and they
got to be thinking this will not make me
feel good at the end of the year.
He.
But raiders is like,
I'm a bad ass.
Raters is a weird one because raiders is
like rap music.
I'm a thug,
you know,
I don't give a fuck.
I'm a raiders fan.
It's a different thing.
Raiders is a,
that's a whole different animal.
And then the cubs fan cubs fans up until
this year,
we're like the loyal we,
hey,
I'm not really in it for the winds.
I just love the cubs.
Meanwhile,
the cubs are new every year.
It's a different fucking person.
Yeah,
that's what's crazy.
It's a totally different group of
humans.
Then the cubs from five years ago,
how could you love the cubs?
These aren't the same people and then
the team can just go to another town.
It's not.
Yeah,
it's fucking nuts.
Like the la rams.
How do we get the rams?
What the fuck happened?
What are we doing here?
You know,
like,
and then what's going to happen to the
raiders are going to go to vegas now.
Then the raiders fans going to follow
them over to vegas.
You know?
Sometimes they don't.
Sometimes people get mad.
Teams leave and they get pissed off.
Vegas seems like a good fit though,
doesn't it?
Yeah,
but he was all created because,
I mean,
all sports teams in this country
essentially were a response to war being
over and people thinking with real good
reason that men at least need war.
They need some form of war to develop
character and to,
to build strong like strong definitive
nations almost need to unite and bond
with war.
And the concept was like,
well,
if we can't do that,
let's figure out some sort of a game
that they can play.
And that's where football emerge.
Do you think that was conscious or
unconscious?
Yeah,
no,
it was,
yeah,
it was actually discussed like it's been
discussed and there's been a lot of
historians that have concentrated on
leaders that have talked about the
importance of conflict,
the importance of war in the,
um,
the,
the bringing the country together and
uh,
the support of nationalism,
the supportive loyalty and honor and
pride.
Like all of that.
A lot of it has to be connected with
consequence and loss.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I like that line of thinking.
well,
there was a radio lab podcast about when
they invented football that went into
this and pretty,
pretty much in depth.
God dammit,
I think it was radio lab,
I'm pretty sure it was.
It was either,
I don't know how else it could have
been,
but it went into it pretty,
pretty in depth about the creation of
football and how it was originally put
together.
So that would explain why sports that
are just clearly dangerous or it's still
illegal and popular.
And.
Is that a jamie?
Yeah,
that's it.
American football.
Yeah.
Cv.
Make that a little larger for my shitty
eyes.
Scroll up there.
Yeah.
Okay.
18,
79.
Yeah,
that's right.
It was made in the carlisle indian
school formed in 18,
79 to assimilate children.
The grandchildren of native americans
who fought in the plains wars fields.
The most american team of all.
Yeah.
This was about these american indians
that were fucking kicking ass playing
football.
There was another.
There was another one that was about the
ghost of football past.
That could be what?
Hm.
Maybe this was the one that was about
this american indian team that was
really interesting.
So football was invented by native
americans.
No,
no,
no.
There's just one bad ass team.
Here it is right here.
And to the 19th century,
the civil war was over.
Frontier was dead.
Young college,
better anxious.
This is what great struggle with test
their character.
That along comes a new craze.
Football,
a brutally violent game where young men
show a stadium full of fans,
just what they're made of.
Harvard,
yale,
princeton,
penn,
the sons of the most powerful men in the
country are literally knocking
themselves out to win these gladiatorial
battles.
So that's when it came up.
And then the carlisle indian school,
they were beating the fuck out.
All the white dudes.
Surprise.
Interesting.
Yeah,
I think.
And then I forget.
I think they all assimilated.
I forget the plot of the rules came
because the indians kept beating every
to make,
making a new rule and they all right,
going to change this.
Native americans need to make a back.
They had a lot of cool ideas.
I think we fucked them over by giving
them casinos to other towns.
Vegas,
I've got a small amount of native
american in me.
Can you get money?
Not,
not a profit.
What do you need?
Like 16 percent to get money.
You need like a certain amount you can
get some cash.
Uh,
I think it's even maybe less than that
really.
Or to qualify for whatever.
I'll have To look into that.
It might be the worst thing you can do
too.
some people just tuck them away and this
little patch of land isolate them from
everybody else and you know,
they're watching the rest of the world
changed around them,
some sort of a strange way and they're
americans,
but they're not.
They're in some sort of a weird
territory that they have ultimate
control over and then they started
having gambling there and doing whatever
the fuck they want.
Very strange,
but in some ways like what are the
other,
what were the other options at the time?
Giving them territory.
Probably pretty ugly optimism.
Sure.
It's dark.
You really stop and think about the
genocide of the native americans in this
country and how that,
how rarely that comes up and there's no
flag.
Which is really interesting when you,
you know,
obviously there are some plaques,
are some nations,
but I mean there's no,
no one thing that represents our war
with them.
That's no,
no offensive symbol other than like a
few sports teams.
Right?
Like the redskins are.
The braves were both my high school and
college were both the warriors.
Warriors is not specific to a
nationality or ethnicity.
logo.
Logo was,
you know know.
It's weird man.
It's real weird that the fact that it
was only a couple of hundred years ago
is really weird.
It's a blink of an eye.
How long do you think people are going
to live now?
It's a good question because I'm
thinking I'm good for 100 at least.
Oh,
okay.
But you personally?
Yeah,
I think you're probably,
you look healthy,
but a kid born today,
thousand years old.
It's going to be able to read minds.
Well,
it depends also upon what it person
becomes because I have a feeling they're
going to come up with legs that are
artificial,
that work way better than your legs.
Like I have a bunch of friends that have
like fake hips or fake knees or you
know,
they've had surgery and they had a bunch
of stuff fixed.
I know a lot of people that have had hip
replacements,
like maybe a dozen.
So I've figured out that if I create
enough public information about me,
you know,
there was enough times I'm recorded like
I'm being right now.
Uh,
enough of my writing is in the public.
There's no video of me that after I die
I could be recreated and software almost
in full because you would have my,
everything from my personality,
my sense of humor,
my choice of words.
So some future program could just go to
the internet,
google my name and take all those
sources and bring together an actual
physical hologram that walks and talks
like me a hundred years after I'm dead.
What jamie,
you were just telling me about some
software that they've developed that you
can take someone's,
someone can say like,
I could make a statement.
Scott adams is a really cool guy and I
always love hanging out with them and
they can move the words all over the
place was where it's a jumbled sentence
that it doesn't make any sense.
And then change the inflection and it
sounds perfect.
Like,
listen to this.
We'll play some of it here called I'll
see if
I can get
and,
uh,
I kiss my wife and my dogs
other dogs.
Okay.
How can we let the dogs out who,
who mIght not be a great example of it
was terrible.
Yeah.
It's like a five minute video where they
just think he's called like photoshop
for audio.
Oh,
okay.
Like it's manipulating audio in a way
that people aren't used to or I've even
seen up until they've just shown this
kind of demonstration.
So the point being,
if you could automate this,
if you could put this inside some sort
of an artificial intelligence structure
that kneW when to inflect,
when to have a question when to like,
or maybe you will be a tech guy and
talking up,
speak up.
Speak is right.
I love up speak because it's so fuck it.
It's this weird thing that these tech
dorks do where they sort of talk in this
really weird,
unpredictable way and they all do it and
basically it makes you seem like you're
sensitive and intelligent and on the
ball and it's a weird fucking little
sneaky thing that some of these tech
guys do where it takes you a while to
go,
oh,
you're not smart at all.
You're fucking crazy.
But you talk in ups speak,
you know,
they've,
they've decided to take on the persona
of a tech person.
Somebody is really into,
I believe in android,
android's the future and they,
they start,
they have this weird thing that they do
at the end of each sentence.
They go up.
I'm not sure that exists outside of
Virginia or California,
silicone valley.
It's huge in silicone valley.
I think it's more,
it's more prevalent in northern
California that it is in southern
California.
It's almost like they're halfway like an
npr sort of a radio personality halfway
that and halfway a strip club dj.
It's like they have this thing going on
where it's a fake voice and they're
talking about technology.
That's all.
I'm going to here now.
Now I'm going to hear that.
Oh,
you'll hear it.
I'll,
I'll give you some audio of people.
There's a bunch of people that they
speak and it is an accent.
The same way in New York accent or a
boston accent is like you can recognize,
oh,
that's a tech dork.
Like it's a non original tech person
who's speaking in this weird there.
You want people to understand that
you're a tech person,
so you're speaking in a literally a tech
accent,
up speak.
I might try that and it's really
fascinating.
Women can do it too.
It's super important.
You know,
like there's a,
almost a woman up speak that you'll see
occasionally on daytime talk shows where
like a bunch of women will sit around
and they'll be on a show and the woman
or it's all audience,
the wwe women's.
Um,
the audience is all women and there's
all women on the panel and then they're
cooking or they're talking about clothes
and what the woman's up speak.
His sentences don't end.
They just sort of stopped talking.
Do you ever notice somebody who didn't
have any way to end a story?
Yes,
they would.
They would talk forever.
They keep going.
And then
during the time of a early cell phones
when one person was talking,
the other person couldn't talk because
you didn't realize it all the time,
but it really was one way communication.
And somebody would start and I would
start yelling into the phone,
stop stopped.
Okay,
bang,
bang.
You know,
let me in,
let me in.
Well,
with what I mean by sentences don't ever
end.
It's not that they don't stop talking,
but that they don't have it.
Like if I said to you,
hey scott,
it's 3:00,
we should probably wrap this up in about
an hour.
Instead of that,
they would say,
hey scott,
it's 3:00.
we should probably wrap this up in about
an hour and um,
and then just keep going and then
someone else chimes in.
What about 4:00?
It's 4:00 a good time.
Four o'clock is a good time.
Five o'clock is a good time.
Six o'clock is a good time.
what about seven?
Can we do it at seven slash 11 is fine.
We can definitely keep going and there's
no end.
There's no.
This is my laptop.
My laptop is black.
Do they hear it themselves?
They love it.
They love to talk to get together.
Do you think,
do you think that if you meet somebody
who has heard this podcast and they talk
like that normally,
would they be unable to talk to,
you know,
it'd be to self coach now.
They'd be fine,
they'd say he's a dick.
And also
I think that's what he said,
dick.
Um,
it's,
I didn't give the best example of it
either,
but yeah,
I think what it is,
is that's how they enjoy talking.
I think they're,
they've had to edit their conversations
because men get tired quicker.
We just don't want to talk as much about
certain stuff.
Like we'd be like,
jesus christ,
get on with the story,
finish it.
When does the story end?
But women get together.
They love it.
They can just keep going.
a lot of them can you reminded me of
the,
the worst advice anybody ever gave his
be natural.
Be yourself because what the hell does
that mean?
Who are you?
If I were myself,
I'd be like,
you know,
sitting here and make it masturbating
and really,
well maybe not right here,
but yeah,
that was a terrible example.
Sometimes let's go back,
get rid of that.
So that would be used sometimes.
right?
And that's,
that is yourself,
but it's like yourself varies depending
upon your company,
depending upon the environment,
depending upon the circumstances were
all acting all the time.
We're,
we're adapting to every Situation.
Yeah,
and you and you also want to be
different sometimes,
so it's not even necessarily an act.
It's like,
you know,
someone says,
hey,
he's got,
show me.
Show me that fucking crazy handstand.
You did.
Like,
it really does not me right now.
Right,
right.
Yeah,
but we're always adapting to the
situation.
Yeah.
But there's women that are like men too
in that way.
The women want other women to shut the
fuck up and they want men to shut the
fuck up to like I like got damaged
people.
They're long ass boring stories.
It's not necessarily genDer specific,
but it seems to be like women on talk
shows during the day that are Cooking.
Do you ever have people who can't tell
when they've gone on too long?
Yes.
Maybe me right there.
And you look at them and you think,
do they not know?
I'm giving the signals
of stop.
you know,
in the corporate world,
you know you always have a pen in your
hand.
If Somebody came into your cubicle and
you wanted to leave,
you wouldn't put the pen down so you
turn toward them,
but you keep the pen in your hand to
signal them that you're there for them,
you know,
you'd put it down and you turn toward
them.
But if you,
if you turn to but just the pen and I'd
be like,
dude,
the pan,
you do not see,
this patent is still in my hand.
There's a weird thing that people will
do to you.
If you're on the phone while you're on
your cell phone,
they will come up to you because you're,
the physical presence trumps whatever
you're.
Whatever you got going on digitally,
right?
So like you're on the phone.
You might be having a really important
conversation and someone go,
hey man,
Scott Adams.
Hey,
how you doIng man?
And you're like,
hey,
I'm the phone.
Hey,
I just want to tell you I really love
dealer.
Why white still talking?
You?
Fuck,
you know,
I'm in the middle of another
conversation.
You've decided this person isn't here.
Fuck them.
You said,
I want your attention.
I'm right in front of you.
I can touch you,
Scott Adams.
Dilbert's my hero.
I love you and behold,
juror shoulder,
but you know,
you,
you get the,
you get the celebrity thing that I don't
get because I'm invisible.
Like your visual,
you're visual.
You're on periscope.
I knew exactly what you look like.
Oh,
you wouldn't?
7,000 people on earth.
Uh,
it's,
I think it's more,
I think their shadow banning you.
Uh,
I like that term
that we were talking about that the
other day,
hillary for prison.
Remember when we were saying rape?
Melania was actually a hashtag,
but hillary for prison wasn't.
That's not what people were saying was
people were saying was they were shadow
banning that hillary for prison.
Hashtag meaning if You put hashtag
hillary for prison,
someone could search it and find it,
but if you put it,
it wouldn't show up in other people's
feeds.
I don't know if that's true though.
Has that been proven?
I,
I'm having a real tough time with what's
proven because lots of people are
sending me my own stuff and saying,
here's proof that you have been shadow
banned because look at this page and
then compare it to this page,
and I always look at them and I go,
I'm not really a lawyer.
I,
I can't tell
how you find out.
Very simple reason.
You're wealthy,
man.
You have two laptops.
You make a second twitter account.
Don't use it for nefarious reasons.
Don't get on and start shitting on
people under 59 or whatever the fuck you
call it,
but you start a laptop,
you follow you,
you follow a few other people just for a
goof,
and then you sit there and you watch
your timeline.
Well,
no,
I,
I do know that people are not getting my
stuff.
Yeah,
but here's the thing.
You could find out yourself.
You could tweet from another computer as
scott adam says,
so you do.
Scott.
Adam says you're followIng you on
another computer that's in a different
account and you're such,
but have you done that?
No,
but I'm saying that other people have
done that and they sent me the
screenshot,
but when I look at her crazy,
they just want to talk to you,
scott.
They want to be your friend.
They want to talk to you when you're on
your cell phone.
Hey man,
I love gilbert.
Who he talked to.
You don't fuck it.
I'm right here,
man.
Why don't you try it yourself?
Um,
I guess I wasn't that curious.
Come on and he talked about it.
You have to be curious.
I kind of liked being shadow banned.
Do you like being shadow banned or you
liked the idea of you being shadow
bands?
I liked that definitive proof that your
shadow bands I liked,
I liked the thought that I might be so
dangerous to the minds of America that
there's a major corporation who is
actually making a conscious decision to
say who the americas had a little bit
too much of this guy.
So let's dial it back a little bit.
Well of like that if twitter didn't have
a history of banning people,
you know,
like the milo thing,
milo yiannopoulos,
that was a big mistake,
big mistake because they didn't ban them
for anything that like you could like
put your finger on.
TheY banned them for influence and other
people were saying mean things,
but you looked at the stuff that he
actually said,
man,
you can't ban them for that.
That's just not,
that's not fair.
Well,
certainly not compared to everything
else that's on twitter,
not even compared to the things that
leslie jones wrote,
you know,
I mean,
the,
the person that he was supposedly
attacking and what he was doing was he
was targeting a piece of art and he
critiqued it very harshly,
but that's what he does and he's very
wise with his choice of words is very
snippy and bitchy and that's his persona
and that's what he's put together.
He's a lovely guy.
Like I've had them on the podcast a
couple of times.
I enjoy his company.
He's a fun guy,
but god damned.
People get pissed off and then it's kind
of hilarious.
And so when that whole thing went down
with the leslie jones things,
and I've absolutely didn't agree with
all the people that were being mean
insulting to leslie,
but that's kind of what happens if you
put yourself out there with a piece of
art,
right,
that people don't like.
And all he did was saY that they were
all ugly,
you know,
he was saying that it's a bad feminist
film because all the men are buffoons
and all the women are saving the world.
And he's like,
it's preposterous.
It's sucks,
it's not good.
And the women are all gross.
And that's what he said and you know,
for that was that the last part was all
the trouble.
Well it was,
I mean,
the fact that he was saying they're
unattractive.
He was saying that not just to be
bitchy,
but also at a point it was like he,
he made a point,
he's like,
they've decided lee picked people that
were unattractive to make this sort of
feminist point of these overweight women
can save the world.
That they're the ones who are gonna like
they're targeting.
And that's why all the men are buffoons.
it's sort of revenge,
like the idea being,
if you wanted to look at it broadly,
the idea being that these are the type
of women that the guy like the thor
dude,
what's his name?
the guy who was in that movie,
that really handsome fellow that plays
thor,
chris quits name.
Now chris is super spy.
Captain american to see liam hemsworth.
Is that the grams worth comes worth
chris hemsworth,
right?
It's one of them.
Am I right?
Or is it chris?
The guy who plays captain America
hemsworth.
Let's just call them thor.
Okay.
Doors impossibly beautiful.
It's beautiful man.
It's super handsome.
Big fucking perfect body.
And of course in this movie,
he's a fucking moron.
I mean he is the dumbest guy that's ever
walked the face of the planet.
He's preposterously dm and then becomes
the villain at the end.
So he represents this unattainable goal
of like a having this gigantic beautiful
man be attracted to you.
So they've turned him in this complete
retard.
Like if this was a woman in a movie,
it would be one of the most offensive
portrayals of a woman ever.
And I'm sure it's been done.
I'm sure it's been done right.
Especially like in the old days.
I mean,
there was how many fucking dopey
secretary roles were there in the world,
right?
so he was that the male caricature of
that.
But there's not a single other male in
the movie that wasn't a complete
buffoon.
Every male iS a failure and ultimately
gets killed and dies.
Every woman's saves the day.
And this was my lowest point.
So in most forms of entertainment you
need the dumb one and the smart one,
you know,
there's always going to be that
contract.
Sure.
And in earlier times there were other
people you could poke fun at and society
would say,
oh yeah,
we make fun of that.
And you know,
the,
the wife was the dumb one in the fifties
and now some of it is just what target
can you get away with?
So there's,
there's a little bit of that.
It's like,
you know who's a soft target,
nobody's going to complain and men are
the,
you know,
the current target.
If you look at commercials,
almost all the commercials are.
The woman is the smart one in the man.
Did something stupid that she had to fix
it.
Every sitcom,
every sitcom.
But I mean,
even in the fifties,
that was the case like the honeymooners.
Ralph kramden was a fucking moron.
His wife has one is always keeping them
calm,
right?
He was always to the moon.
Alice,
he's threatening to beat her.
Right.
And his buddy,
his buddy was this fucking idiot to.
And his buddy's wife was keeping him in
line.
Yeah.
That was true for the honeymooners.
I mean,
at any couples sort of comedy,
the man is a buffoon.
Married with children.
Pegs always want sex is all fucked up.
He's trying to get away from her.
He hates his life.
Everything falls apart on him.
His daughter's acting like a little
hussy,
right?
I mean that's the whole thing.
This poor guy,
his life's falling apart.
The guys never.
Okay.
All those movies,
that guy's a buffoon and all those
sitcoms.
That guy's a buffoon.
That's what people like to see.
Yeah.
But you know,
I'm looking at elvis right behind you.
Let's different animal baby.
Yeah.
come on in.
So there were a lot of movies where it
was,
you know,
frank sinatra,
charles bronson,
maybe you have to go back further where,
where the man was the competent one and
the woman was always losing her high
hill.
OH,
there's plenty of movies like that.
But in sitcoms and the sitcom world and
the comedy world,
it's pretty much always the men's.
A man's phone.
Yeah.
I think that's fair to say for a lot.
You know,
king of queens.
There's another one,
Kevin James is always ridiculous.
His wife always had to figure everything
out.
He Was ridiculous.
But how did you get this hot wife?
She's on tv.
I mean,
this is a.
we're going back to the twitter thing.
This is the problem with censoring
people,
uh,
Is that if you don't like what they
stand for,
you know,
you're not really,
like they were looking for the reason to
pull the plug on him.
It wasn't a good one.
So it left people like what that like
that him saying that.
And then when you pull up things that
she has said about white people that she
has said about other ethnicities and
some of the,
she's like literally said get someone,
like someone tweeted something matter.
She was telling people to get them.
That's like this targeted harassment,
right?
Like that is like actual targeted
harassment and the idea that she's doing
it in revenge for someone coming after
her.
I understand,
but in the position that she's at,
like she's a huge celebrity for her to
actively say go get this person.
Like that is the clearest example you're
ever going to see of targeted
harassment.
So if that doesn't get punished in any
way,
shape or form,
like you got to say,
well why is it because she's female is
because she's black?
Is it a combination of those things is
because she represents what you think is
like liberal progressive mindset and
then he represents this all right,
that people are terrified of and hate.
He represents the gamer gate which gave
birth to the alt right,
like gamergate allowed people to realize
like,
hey,
there's actually some intelligent people
that are tired of all this bullshit that
these feminists are trying to push down
our throats and intelligent people that
are coming together and go,
no,
laura croft is not the fucking bane of
civilization.
It's fun to watch her run around with
her tits.
Jiggling,
shoot guns at things.
It doesn't mean you hate women just
doesn't.
You know,
and women were playing that game too anD
saying the same thing and this portrayal
of these people as being these ugly
massage.
Just monsters.
The backlash of that is what gave birth
to gamergate and a loT of gamergate was
harassment,
targeted harassment of women.
Horrible stuff.
Right?
But I think as you were saying when it
was,
when you're talking about trump
supporters,
there's a certain percentage of these
trump supporters that probably are
racist,
doesn't mean they all are like,
what is the number?
Is it two percent?
Is at four percent.
There's a certain percent of the
probably absolute misogynist.
What's that number?
I don't know what that number is,
but there's also some other people in
there.
There has to be that a reasonable.
Because if you look at the number of
people that voted for obama and you look
at the number of people that voted for
trump,
a lot of those people at the same people
will actually,
if you look at romney's vote compared to
trump,
I think ron,
the trump did better in most ethnic
groups.
Yes he did.
Just across the board.
They didn't trust that white dude.
And,
and what was the,
what was the problem with romney?
He just didn't have the policies they
wanted to write.
I mean,
it was also the mormon thing.
Well,
yeah,
but it was also the mormon thing.
But the mormon thing was pretty big,
I think.
I mean,
he,
he believes one of the wackiest strains
of christianity would even call it
christianity.
Well,
we don't know.
We don't know which parts of it.
He believes literally.
Well,
we know that his dad was actually born
in Mexico.
Do you know the whole story about that?
I don't.
Oh,
I'm going to school you scott,
because this is wonderful.
Please do.
Mitt romney comes from a faction of the
mormons that were so hardcore that when
the United States banned polygamy,
they went,
we'll fuck this.
We're moving to Mexico.
so they moved to Mexico.
So mitt romney's dad could never be the
president United States because he was
born in Mexico.
It was a mexican citizen.
They have these giant compounds and they
have to fight off the drug and there's
more than one gigantic compound owned by
mormons in Mexico.
They literally have carved out their own
camps down there and they're armed and
they did as vice piece on them where
they interviewed them and went over
there and talked about it,
and that is the whole reason why mitt
romney's mommy's dad's mexican.
I mean literally mexican,
born in Mexico,
mexican citizen,
they'll look at that.
Mitt romney's mexican roots.
His father was born in Mexico and could
choose.
He could choose dual citizenship.
That is interesting.
Yeah.
How did I noT know that?
How did you not know that matters?
Anything?
Well,
I'm a.
I'm obsesseD with mormons,
so that's how I found out about it and
obsessed for a long time.
So did you do The deep dive and look at
all this stuff that they believe in?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
The seer stone,
like Joseph Smith in 18,
12 found magic tablets that were the
last work of jesus and only he could
read him because he had a magic rock and
he was like 14 at the time,
which is fucking hilarious.
All this happened when he was 14.
This is when he first concocted this
goofy ass story apparently where he
lived.
It was fairly common for people to come
up with this kind of calm.
Really?
Yeah.
I mean it was,
it wasn't like the only one doing this.
It was.
I read that somewhere is just stuck.
Yes.
my sources.
I read that somewhere and I
misremembered it now,
so I'll say it in public because that
settles pretty authoritative thing about
mormons though.
They're really nice people.
I really,
I like a lot of mormons.
I'm frienDs with quite a few more
minutes.
I know a bunch of them and like in
general they promote a lot of
camaraderie,
a loT of community.
They're very friendly.
The people like in the mormon church,
like the friends that I know that are
mormons,
they go to church on a regular basis and
it's almost like this community
gathering of super polite people that
agree to be super polite.
I've said the same thing and I don't
know if it's because they don't drink
and don't have coffee or something,
but I don't think I've ever met a
mormon,
but I didn't really like.
they're nice people.
They just all seem great.
Just almost like it's okay to believe
wacky shit if it works for you.
I've never met one that really believed
the,
you know,
the deeper stuff.
Oh my friends wear the underwear.
Seriously.
Yeah.
They have to wear the underwear,
but that's not a belief so much as a
customer,
wouldn't you say?
Yeah.
Well they're a little hypocritical,
right?
Like you're not allowed to drink coffee.
so this do drinks,
energy drinks,
monsters,
those giant ones.
He pounds those things and you know,
you're not supposed to do drugs,
but you can get away with it.
If the doctor prescribes the xanax,
you're allowed to take that
because it's not in.
It's not any of their books.
They didn't have xanax.
Xanax is a loophole.
You just can't.
You can't pound booze.
So he just fucking pop pills and freak
out all day.
That was a good compromise.
That's a good.
Religion is flexible.
Well,
they're nice people.
They're really nice people like,
um,
I'm a fan of the mormon people.
Like in general,
I think what they believe is nonsense,
but maybe they don't really believe
that.
Maybe you're right.
I said that I've talked to one who
actually believed the,
the stuff that's just be.
They enjoy the community aspect of it
and the bonding of it and they believe
in god and maybe they just let all that
other stuff slide.
That's totally possible.
That feels like it.
I mean,
I don't know if it feels like,
you know,
if they die,
they get their own planet.
That is a perk.
You get a whole planet.
You know what?
I die if I die.
I get what she had.
Dude,
that's not true.
I decomposed.
I'm going to get you in tight with the
mormons and you're going to get a planet
because I like you.
If you're seeing the osman brothers,
um,
album where they,
uh,
they all have.
It's named after the planet that you
get.
What the fuck is the or named after
this,
this thing that they believe that makes
you get all these planets like this
place that you go,
you get your own planet.
But in the osman album,
the osbourne family album,
whenever the fuck it is,
they all have like their own little
planets and it's inside like the album
jacket,
like he opened it up.
There's like planets.
It's hilarious.
It's really fun,
but again,
perfect example,
Donny osmond and marie osmond,
very nice people.
Uh,
I'm going to shop around for new
religion because They'll have different
afterlives and I think you have to
compare them to do because the planet
thing is due.
So it was pretty appealing.
Well a may imagine if we go back to your
original idea that this is some sort of
a software simulation and that's why
your memories are so wacky and nothing
sticks and imagine if you literally are
choosing by virtue of your decision to
join a certain religion,
what your afterlife will be like if
you're in a video game and there's like
a bunch of different doors you have to
figure out which one's the right door to
go through and you go through that door.
It's a totally different adventure.
What if we really are a software
simulation and just like you say,
the software allows you to pick an
afterlife and you do actually.
I mean that's what you're actually
experiencing because for software that
would be totally practical if we're
software that would be totally
practical.
And that simulation theory thing is a
mindfuck because you don't know what
we're talking about.
Here's the rub.
The rub is one day without a doubt,
if we continue,
if we don't get hit by an asteroid,
if we don't get swallowed up in a super
volcano or a tsunami or an earthquake or
something crazy,
human beings will reach a point where if
you look at the exponential growth of
technology,
we are going to be able to create an
artificial reality that is
indistinguishable from regular reality.
If that's the case,
how will we know if we're in it?
We won't.
So how do we know if we're not in it
right now?
I'll take the math one.
One step further is that by the time
there's one of those,
if it's a perfect simulation,
the simulation will create another
simulation and so on.
So it's turtles all the way down.
So then,
so this is actually what the scientists,
they say that the number of original
species will be one and the number of
copies will eventually be gigantic.
You know,
it could be thousands,
millions,
trillions.
So the odds that you're the original
copy,
you know,
the original might be one in a trillion
if that's a real,
that's the big f,
but it's an f tHat if not possible now
or if not reality will one day be.
Yeah,
we can't tell where we are in the cycle.
If we're,
if we're a simulation,
we don't know if there were hundreds of
simulations before us.
There's no way to know.
Well,
there's also the very slippery aspect of
consciousness where we shut it off every
night and then turn it back on in the
morning and we assume that our memories
when we wake up in the morning are all
accurate.
We assume that we really did,
you know,
wake up November 17th,
2016 in our bed,
put our clothes on with his database of
life experiences leading up to that
point.
But how the fuck do you know?
It didn't just start,
he just woke up and they might have been
installed with this goofy life memory
that you might have started this life
this morning.
Yeah.
If you look into physics,
we know when I say we,
I mean people much smarter who are
physicists,
know that things don't really exist
until you observe them.
I'm going,
what the hell does that mean?
That's a tricky thing that people say.
That's not necessarily true.
You know what they mean by that?
That when you observe something in the
act of observing it,
you change it.
Now that's,
that's a different concept,
but.
But knowing that something's true like
the.
There's the tree falls in the forest,
right?
Is that what you're saying?
The,
the observation changes that so that the
change thing.
Maybe we are talking about the same.
Right,
but the observation really only changes
it when you measure it.
That's what it's the measurement.
When you know they do those particle
tests,
those are off.
Have you ever talked to a physicist
about that?
Observing is enough.
You don't have to.
It doesn't have to technically be made.
You have to observe it.
If you're not measuring well,
just looking at it like looking at what?
Seeing it or seeing any sign of it.
Right,
but not anything that's an indication
that it must have been enough to
solidify the past.
Well,
if you never observed it before and then
you are observing and how do you know
that there's a difference between the
two results?
I don't know even know what I'm talking
about.
I have no idea the way it's been
explained to me by a friend of mine
who's actually a physicist,
he said it's often,
there's a lot of woo woo that's tacked
onto this,
but when you're talking about these
measurements that people say like that
in the act of measuring something and
looking at something,
you change the result.
He's lIke,
that is much better interpreted by the
measurement itself,
the actual act of seeing something or
recording something or interfacing with
it in some way to get them a reading.
As a result.
He's like,
that's much more likely what's going on.
There's no real evidence that looking at
something changes it because if you
weren't looking at it before,
how do you know if it was different?
Whoa,
well that was good.
It was crazy,
man,
and that's not the way I understood it,
but I'm
also not a physicist,
nor do I have a friend who's a physicist
who can explain it to.
I get confused at these things because
they're often repeated and the repeated
by people who haven't looked into it and
it gets me worried.
It's one of those things like the wage
gap thing.
Do you know The wage gap argument versus
reality?
I do.
I've looked into it deeply,
so crazy one because people really smart
people will tell you,
women make seventy nine cents for every
dollar a man makes,
and that gives you the impression that
they're working side by side in the same
factory and the woman's make it seventy
nine cents and the man's making a
dollar.
That's not what it means.
What it means is overall men make a
dollar to seventy nine cents that women
make because of career choices,
because of jobs,
the different jobs that they choose.
If you're going to make the argument
that it's more difficult for women to
get those jobs,
that's a different argument and you
might be right,
but that's not when you're saying that
the wage discrimination gap.
Like when obama says we have to change
with wage discrimination,
like,
whoa,
what are you talking about?
Like do you think that an engineer
should get the same as you know,
a person who works,
you know,
whatever,
fill in the blank some,
you know,
typical female job.
But like when it comes to science and
engineering and a lot of those stem sort
of subjects,
men sort of gravitate towards them.
Men gravitate towards riskier jobs.
Men are more likely to die on the job.
Men choose different paths because of
testosterone and their gender and to
die.
That seems kind of silly,
but so when they start talking about
this gender gap,
which everybody throws around all willy
nilly with no research whatsoever,
they really believe that.
You're talking about two lawyers working
in the same firm side by side.
The man makes a dollar.
The one who makes seventy nine cents.
So it's not
how many statistics,
how many times have you been in a
conversation with somebody who believed
in in the 79,
seven figure and then you explained it
to them and they said,
oh no,
I don't think that's the case.
Then you showed them a link,
you proved it beyond any doubt and it
still didn't change their mind.
I won't accept the fact that could have
been wrong about something because
they've attached their identity to being
correct.
Right.
It's a huge problem with anything gender
related.
The gender thing is that the idea is
that women have been suppressed and they
have for sure.
I mean women didn't get the right to
vote until the 20th century.
Right.
That's kinda crazy.
You know,
I mean we,
we went through a Long time in this
country where women couldn't even vote,
so absolutely they been suppressed and
absolutely,
there's a lot of things that brought
them out of that.
First of all,
birth control,
like the ability to choose whether or
not they're going to be pregnant.
The,
the,
the laws,
changing discrimination laws,
changing people's perceptions of what
women are changing.
All those things are absolutely real,
but that's.
You can't lie about numbers.
Like as soon as you bullshit people,
then they have reason to disbelieve you,
but everything.
So if you start bullshitting about the
wage gap,
and this is not saying that it's not
More difficult to be a woman.
I think it is.
I think it's moRe difficult because I
think men are pieces of shit and there's
a lot of violent,
dangerous,
creepy men that probably want to rape
you and I would hate to be a woman in
that sort of a scenario.
So I'm not denying that.
It's probably more difficult in our
society because of a lot of shitty men.
it's more difficult to be a woman,
but you can't lie about numbers.
As soon as you start lose students,
you start pretending that women get paid
less for the same job across the board.
You ruin the whole argument because now
we're not dealing in reality.
Now we're doing the same thing where
we're not looking at caitlin jenner is a
human.
We're looking at as a gender identity
hero.
You know,
like,
well,
what about as a human?
Like we were supposed to celebrate
someone or or not as a human being as a
total package.
We're not doing that and this is where
we're treating the whole subject with
blinders because it pertains to gender.
We can't look at the reality of it.
I would generalize that to say that
nobody's ever won an argument with data.
It almost never happens because the
problem is that people just say,
well,
your data's role,
so and that's the end of the
conversation,
but does that.
Isn't that less and less the case now
that ever before issue would be shed,
but I'm,
I'm actively in conversations with
people in which I can show them all the
data that I want.
It makes no difference.
Humans are twitter people,
even regular people in the world in real
life.
yeah,
but you know,
there's a broad spectrum of people in
the world,
right?
He's.
When you're talking about people that
you respect,
your peers,
colleagues,
fellow cartoonIsts,
I mean,
you're talking about them.
are you talking about regular educated
people?
I've never seen anybody change their
mind on that topic,
that specific topic.
That's a weird one.
Yeah,
that's a weird one.
Yeah.
I've seen people have some pretty heated
discussions about it too and completely
uninformed.
If people don't have an emotional,
a lock on the topic,
then you can move them with data just
because they don't care.
It's like,
oh,
there's better data.
Okay,
but people are so dug in on that
particular topic.
It's very insidious,
very insidious because I think it like
we were talking about what the hillary
clinton thing about lying about Russia.
As soon as you lie about that,
as soon as you lie about something,
well I'm going,
what the fuck?
You know when when you see you,
I'm sure you've seen it,
that director comey video where compares
what cami said versus what hillary is
saying.
He said,
and it's like,
holy shit.
Like you're just lying.
Like you just keep lying.
Like this is a crazy moment where you
seeing this because it didn't.
DIdn't exist until recently.
We had This youtube phenomenon where you
can watch and get millions of hits on
these videos where it shows the reality
versus what you're saying and when you.
When you soon as you throw a non-reality
into it,
I know that you're dealing with it from
a team perspective,
like you're just trying to manipulate
whatever the facts are or wherever the
argument is to get your team in.
You don't really care what's true.
You women get paid less period.
You fucking piece of shit.
Seventy nine cents to a dollar,
read the facts and you know,
you can't even argue with it.
You can't even bring it up.
But that's everything all the time.
If there's any emotional connection,
we just think that,
you know,
logic and data and you know,
arguments matter.
But yeah,
they're just so rare.
And if you disagree also,
you're like,
so happy to be a man.
You must be so happy to be a man.
You think
men are the only ones who could run this
world.
You think men don't discriminate against
women every step of the way.
It must be really nice to have that
white male privileged.
Scott adams.
The sarcasm as a replacement for reason
is probably the most annoying thing in
the world.
And I've been,
you know,
the sarcasm has been raining on me for a
year for writing about trump,
but yeah,
it's exactly what you said is like,
so then trump would get elected and then
he'll just make everything good and then
there will be just unicorns,
right?
Yeah.
That's a weird argument that people love
to put words in your mouth and then
force you to defend them.
I talk about the word,
so as a tell for that,
whatever's going to come next as a
hallucination.
So,
so if you say to say to me,
you know,
it doesn't matter who said,
uh,
you know,
I went to the store yesterday,
I would say.
So you abandoned your children,
have,
you know,
whatever comes,
we'll just won't make any sense.
Oh my god,
that's hilarious.
That's really funny.
Yeah,
you can definitely do that.
I mean,
that's the art of persuasion,
right?
That's hypnosis.
That's what you're into.
Do you have a pocket watch?
You have one of those?
No,
that's not part of the process.
Weirdly enough.
But it isn't cartoons and movies.
Yes.
I think there was it ever.
I think there was one movie,
so that's well known in the history that
this one movie,
I don't know what it was a showed
somebody doing using a watch to
hypnotize and then it just became a
thing,
but it was never a thing within the
hypnotist world.
Was theRe ever a moment during this
whole campaign where it was getting
really crazy and people were angry about
so many different things?
Like how about when all those women came
out in mass?
Right.
There was this and moss and moss.
There was at one time were all these
women were coming out saYing Donald
Trump tried to grab my tits and Donald
Trump and some of them were pretty
innocuous,
but it was all together like a
coordinated effort.
Was there ever a moment wHere you're
like,
what the fuck that I do?
Like why did I come out and supported
this guy?
Like what Did I.
The hate that I'm getting right now that
that was the moment that I switched my
endorsement that Gary Johnson.
I remember that and my reasoning was
because Gary Johnson only touches
himself and that's something that I can
respect in a leader.
No trouble there,
but that was tongue in cheek.
It was tongue and cheek,
but I was also getting out of the blast
zone.
I remember I was never as supporting him
based on policies or I was just talking
about is persuasion,
but was there ever a time where you
thought,
I should probably make a moral
distinction because I'm getting caught
up in this wave of angry white people
and their massage and racism and all the
credit.
I mean that was the worst aspects,
right?
That the two percent that we already
discussed it and you get caught up in
this association game that people are
doing when they have this us versus them
little battle going on.
Did you ever think like,
what the fuck man,
what did I do?
Not in those words,
but I'm.
I'm fortunately
in,
in a situation where I have what I call
fuck you money and I can.
I can kind of take some risks that you
wouldn't take earlier in your career and
one of them is the risk to say what ever
I think is useful and necessary and I
want to say,
and so that is a huge risk to be
associated with anybody unpleasant.
But uh,
at the same time I self identify with
being ultra liberal,
like liberal people seem a little too
conservative for me.
I'm left to them.
That is interesting about you and I,
I definitely wanted to get to that
because you're not a right wing guy.
You know,
you,
you're very reasonable.
And that's what I,
what I thought was so fascinating about
this.
I'm like,
and it actually makes sense now.
You say it,
you have fuck you money,
so why shouldn't you just speak about
whatever attributes,
positive or negative you might see and
when look at it,
almost like you're looking at a puzzle,
you know,
all low.
We'll look at this piece here.
This piece is going to go right there
and see there's an opening here.
It's weird.
There was a space for this of somebody
who didn't have a team.
Yes.
As part of the reason I don't vote,
I don't join a party.
You didn't vote at all?
No,
it
isn't that ironic.
It would bias me.
Oh,
I see.
As soon as you vote,
you joined the team but you like a
klingon in this world.
He just wrote roman through the streets
and then people make those rules and use
to bide by them.
How does that work?
Ah,
non participant in our democracy.
Scott adams.
Well,
secretly canadian by California.
And so I didn't think it mattered that
much who I voted for.
Um,
but I also think that staying unbiased
is important.
So I'm just not a joiner.
But wHat about others?
Things like you could always write in a
presidential candidate if you want to do
that,
but like voting on things like
legalizing marijuana,
things that are really important.
I mean that's.
You don't notice I go right to that.
Forget fuck the death penalty.
There's a lot of important issues you
could vote on,
right?
Yeah.
But my take on that is that the people
who think they understand those issues
almost never do.
And the few that I could understand well
enough,
like legalizing weed,
um,
it was going the way I wanted it anyway.
so according to the polls that thought
that hillary clinton was gonna win,
see all these polls,
the problem,
the weed pulls where we're much more
accurate and it
or a gap there,
the weed pulls are more accurate.
Well,
they are for sure it won.
It won by a landslide.
But I thought it was important.
I felt like if I was going to vote,
I mean the voting for freedom,
wherever it is,
wherever it's possible,
especially freedom is not,
you're not hurting anybody and you're
removing the possibility of being locked
up for something.
IT's not hurting anybody across the
board whether it's pot or whether it's
wearing dresses.
Um,
for that I would be just as enthusiastic
about a transgender law if someone made
it a law where a man couldn't become a
woman,
you know?
And then we were fighting against that.
I would be as enthusiastic as I am about
almost almost enthusiasts to pot thing
to is a,
represents a freedom issue as much as it
is anything else.
I put those in a different frame.
So,
um,
you know,
the birth of the nation,
there was this debate about states'
rights and you know,
what's the federal government do and the
idea was that the more local the
government,
the better they understood the people
and stuff like that.
But fast forward today with the internet
and,
and more and the states are like little
laboratories so we can watch,
hey,
how'd it go in Colorado?
So we're,
we don't Have to argue on principle or
morality anymore.
we're actually beyond that because we
can measure,
we can ab test with the,
uh,
with the states.
So with everything from abortion law to
a weed,
um,
you can say,
hey,
let the states Do it and let's just make
sure we measure it,
make sure we have a real,
a thing that matters,
that,
that we can say if it reaches this
level,
they work.
If there's crime it didn't.
Um,
and I think that's the direction we're
going,
which is insanely useful because it
takes all the emotion out of it because
like we don't have to wonder if it's our
right to smoke weed or anything,
just see how it worked out.
I,
uh,
I don't disagree With what you're
saying,
but I also think that it's that too.
I think the morality and ethics play a
part of it as well.
I think reading for the first state.
Okay.
But after that you can just see what
happened,
man,
I don't know because that means in the
49 other states you leave open the
possibility that people are going to be
locked up in jail for nonviolent crimes
that don't hurt anyone.
And that seems to be a giant ethic
temporarily.
Even if it's temporarily,
it could ruin their life knowing that
the law,
is this temporary,
it was temporarily still,
they're still there.
That's not optimal.
It's not optimal and the consequences
are too grave.
You're taking away people's freedom.
So to me it becomes primarily a freedom
issue.
The same way it'd be if men wanted to
wear dresses or if women wanted to wear
combat boots and all of sudden we said,
we can't have that anymore.
Well,
you're giving two examples that I
consider easy.
You know,
the weed and the,
you know,
the,
the gender thing.
Those are easy.
Those should be available to everybody.
I go,
okay,
so let's go with one that's hard.
Which would be automated cars.
Oh,
that's.
I love that one.
Yeah.
How about this one?
Good example,
like when we get to a certain point in
time,
will we lose our freedom to be
autonomous?
Will we lose our freedom to be able to
drive a car and be able to steer and
trust you to hit the brakes when you're
supposed to?
Oh,
all of your autonomy is going away.
It's going aWay.
So.
So think about this.
I blogged about this today.
Suppose you had a fitness band and it
was like the future.
I'm not,
not long time of five or 10 years and
they can do everything from tell you
when you should take a sip of water
because you're dehydrated.
It knows what kind of food you should
eat and when it was,
when you should sleep and it tells you
how the,
in the beginning you're going to say,
oh,
good suggestion.
I'll either do that or not,
but eventually you're going to see that
their suggestion is better than whatever
the hell you would have done on your own
and you're just going to start following
the app and eventually that app is going
to be controlling your
life while you have the sensation that
you're deciding.
maybe you dude nomy rebel out there.
I to make my own choices.
I'm going to rip off that fitbit.
Yeah man.
Fuck that.
Fitbit were free.
I'm going to run and when I feel tired
I'll stop or keep pushing because that's
what I do.
Push harder.
Hashtag push harder.
Um,
I know what you're saying.
I agree.
I think also people like when things
become,
when you have less stuff to talk about
or think about,
you know,
and as soon as you get in your car and
the car drives itself,
well now I don't have to think about
that anymore.
You know,
I was going to invest in alcohol
companies,
you know,
companies that produced and manufactured
alcohol because it could be drunk in
your car now because self driving cars
are coming.
Right,
right.
And the day they do,
80 percent of the reasons not to drink
just goes away,
which is how do you get home?
That's a good point.
Yeah.
Do you think they'll have no steering
wheel at all?
Like what?
If everything goes wrong?
I think it will have his steering wheel
because you know,
you have to get off the road and
present.
If you get drunk you're like fuck it.
I could drive.
You want to drive.
Even though it's autonomous,
right?
You'll be too drunk to program the
address and you're like,
what kind of drive?
And it started driving.
Good point.
We don't have that problem with uber,
you know,
no matter how drunk I am,
I never tried to come out from the back
and yeah,
but it's not right in front of you.
And also with uber you're too busy
trying to figure out whether the guy
driving needs a serial killer.
You need a breathalyzer on there to get
control of the steering wheel.
You need to be able to take a swab and
run it through machines from them.
What kind of dna that's fucking creep.
Has you ever gone through security
lately and they do the little swab.
They put it in the machine and I'm
thinking,
what does it know about me?
How much can it figure it out for me?
Because from your odor and your dna or
whatever the hell they're looking at,
they could probably know a lot about me.
Yeah,
they definitely could if they.
Well tHat's the big argument about those
fingerprint scanners on cell phones that
they're slowly but surely accumulating a
database of fingerprints of all the
people in this country.
Yeah.
That's scary to
slowly but surely the boundaries between
people and data are eroding.
So let me ask you this.
So in the news today,
um,
I don't know who said it,
it wasn't trump himself.
I think that the discussion of a muslim
database,
did you hear them?
The idea of collecting names.
I think only the people who are
noncitizens coming into the country
which raises,
you know,
every kind of nazi concentration camp
alarm and should um,
but do you think we don't already have
that list?
Don't question,
don't you think that somewhere in our
big data,
which they can't tell the citizens and
in fact they can even tell the
politicians because they're probably
only a few people who
know,
probably a few people in the government
who know what we know about citizens.
But the idea that there's anybody coming
into the country and we don't have a
really good idea of where they are at
any time.
I mean if they have back doors into
everything from the credit card
processing companies to,
you know,
all the other big cell phone companies,
they have a working profile on
everybody.
If they want it done.
In other words,
I have to push the button to run the
program.
But if they wanted to know,
if they wanted to know your religion,
they wouldn't need to have you fill it
out in a form becauSe they could check
your credIt card and say,
hey,
you buys gas next to the,
you know,
the synagogue or the mosque or whatever.
And his friends are.
They use because they do the same things
at the same time.
Big data already knows your religion.
If someone wants to track down all that
stuff,
it's the thing is who is the someone?
How many?
Like I have a friend.
It's always worried.
The government's like looking into his
email and following them.
And I.
This is what I always say,
like who's,
how many people are they doing this to?
There's hundreds of millions of people.
How many people work in the government?
How are they doing that?
Like,
here's a,
here's a good story.
This is how people will think,
oh,
the following me,
man,
listen to this story.
The guy who broke into the white house,
do you know about that story?
The guy who ran through the white.
I add a bit about it in my last netflix
special because this is where
progressiveness goddess is ridiculous
idea that everybody's equal.
They left a woman guarding the door of
the white house by herself.
This is a true story.
The guy hopped the fence.
He was crazy.
Ptsd down out of his fucking mind
veteran ran across the lawn.
The guy who was in charge of monitoring
the,
the grassy area where this guy ran
across,
took his earpiece out and was on the
phone with his girlfriend.
So this guy was like having a
conversation with a girlfriend while
this guy's running across the lawn.
The guy gets to the front door,
the alarm system is down because he kept
fucking up,
so they just shut it off.
So they left a girl by herself at the
door with no alarm or a guy just ran
across the lawn.
Then you find out about the guy.
Well,
the guy turns out was arrested just a
couple of months before this with 800
fucking rounds of ammunition for like
four rifles,
two handguns and machete and acts the
arm to the tits with a fucking map of
Washington dc with an x where the white
house is.
They weren't watching that guy like they
weren't even watching him.
Like we are dealing with way more in
competence than we would like to believe
or that we would care to admit.
So that was the case of a criminal
investigation that the law enforcement
people didn't coordinate.
Right?
Well,
it was both that and complete arrogance
and not having an alarm system on not
having more than one person guarding the
lawn,
not having more than one person at the
door,
having a woman at the door,
like by herself with his fucking giant
soldier comes running through and
knocked her to the ground and runs
around the white house.
Say thIs is a perfect example.
So since that never had happened before,
like,
you know,
probably.
Well maybe not 100 years of 18.
12 was the last time it happened before
that.
Oh,
well,
1912 excuse,
so you're never really ready for the
thing that hasn't happened.
I always think about if if nuclear war
broke out,
like let's say Russia and the United
States decided,
all right,
it's on and we're gonna launch.
I don't think they'd work the two bombs,
the bombs,
because we'd never done it before.
like we've only tested.
We've tested the bomb and we've tested
the missile,
but we haven't tested the missile on the
bomb and the chain of command and who
puts the codes and sure we've tested all
the parts.
imagine it was all fucking for gazy
scheme and like there's nothing even in
those things.
I just taken that tax dollars and using
it for satanic rituals and flying on
private jets everywhere.
did you read all that stuff?
That podesta stuff that came out in the
wiki leaks emails about all the weird
rituals they were going to the spirit
cooking involved sperm and blood and why
in the fuck are they doing like,
I don't like to believe when Alex Jones
goes onto his fucking crazy.
TheY're all satanists.
EverY one of them.
They're all worshiping satan.
You know,
you'd go wIth Alex Jones is crazy,
he's going crazy.
Obama is a devil,
literally a devil in hell.
and you go,
Alex Jones out of his fucking mind.
and then you see this pedesta thing
where you know some,
they're doing satan rituals like this
went to it went to watch something
called spirit cooking.
Well,
but you heard the explanation.
I did not.
So the explanation was the woman who I
guess was the hostess says,
oh yeah,
it does mean those other things,
but we've sort of,
you know,
cutely just generalized it to whatever
we're doing.
So,
so the spirit,
carole king,
but didn't meet any of that.
I don't buy that.
I don't buy that for a second.
I'm not sure I buy that they were all
getting together to eat blood and sperm.
well,
why are they even talking about it?
My friends and I,
we never get together and talk about
blood and sperm.
No,
never comes out.
They didn't talk about it,
but somebody did.
well,
the email just said,
do you want to go to the spirit cooking
thing?
right?
But then when you find out what the
spirit cooking is and involves blood and
sperm,
right,
was one of the things that means.
So is there a good party by the way?
It's not a party until somebody believes
so many bleeds and somebody comes.
I didn't look into the explanation
because to me it's one of those things
that I don't want to know any further
pat because it's too fun to think these
wacky fucks are out there.
Just a puck bucket of blood and drinking
it and throwing it on themselves.
That's more fun to me than rational
explanation.
I think the best moment of the whole
year was related to that.
It was a mike cernovich was tweeting
about it the most.
And I realized that,
I think it was the Washington post ran a
piece by piece sort of explaining why it
wasn't what it was.
And I thought,
where have we come to the point where
mike cernovich makes,
uh,
the Washington post,
defend how much sperm pedesta it's like,
no,
no.
It was way less burden than you think.
It was a couple of drops.
That's all you need.
A couple of drops.
It's,
it's a symbolic thing.
this is totally unrelated,
but did you see the real sports from
this week with a beak from yoga guy?
You see brian?
Uh,
what's his name?
Brian gumbel.
Thank you.
Uh,
he uh,
did this real sports,
one of his episodes,
he had this woman go away and
investigate a beaker from knowing,
I think his name is.
He's the guy that's the lead of bikram
yoga and uh,
apparently he's allegedly banged a bunch
of chicks that work there and you know,
sexually harassed him,
allegedly,
allegedly keep saying that.
But he was,
they were saying.
And he was like,
why would I do that when women will pay
$1 for one drop of my sperm saying he
was saying,
yeah,
he was saying there's thousands of women
signing up to fuck him and that four of
them committed suicide because he
wouldn't fuck them and that people are
willing to pay a million dollars for a
drop of his sperm.
Well,
they're out there folks.
That's a good argument.
There's some crazy fucking people out
there.
I would have defended myself
differently.
I would say,
well,
the women who come here for yoga,
they were very flexible.
That's money laundering right there.
Someone's paying a million dollars for
his sperm for one drop of sperm.
That's a guy who's selling drugs,
trying to get rid of cash,
is trying to move some money around.
That's what he's doing.
Well,
I mean it's the ultimate telecommuting
job.
It's like,
I can't come to the office.
I'll be home today.
I'm like,
what is a gallon today?
Well,
one drop.
I mean,
you got a lot of drops if you're.
If you're healthy,
if you eat eggs and drink milk.
Do you?
My point being that there's a lot of
fucking crazy people in this world and
this guy,
podesta guy being involved in this wacky
spirit cooking thing.
I'm not shocked.
This yoga guy,
this guy that you think of as being like
peace and sot nom and not my stay and
we're all going to flow together and
realize we're all want.
He's like,
I did pay $1,000,000 for one drop of my
spam.
He suck.
He's crazy and he's the head of this
yoga organization,
which we all think we immediately
associate yoga with peace and love and
happiness and he's talking about all
these women that accused them of being
human trash and pieces of shit and it's
like,
whoa.
Like think about how trump responded to
the allegations against him versus how
this yoga guy responded way worse.
He should have gone with a nickname
lying yoga hose,
what we call them,
but my point is that there's some crazy
people out there involved in all sorts
of weird stuff where you would never
imagine.
Well,
it also gets to the fact that I just tie
that together pretending I had a point,
but it kind of goes to the point where
we'll never have a nice person who is
president again.
Oh,
because it's true.
No,
it's because the only reason you thought
anybody was nice and he didn't know
enough about them,
but that's not true.
This is nice people,
right?
You're a nice guy.
Don't you run for president?
I'm a nice guy.
But if you were to dissect my entire
paSt,
I would look like,
you know,
satan incarnate by the time they got
done with me,
maybe now,
but I think within the next four years,
by the time trump is a on a second term,
if he decides to run again,
and if he wins,
right?
Which would be crazy.
Right?
To term trump who,
that's a shirt.
I see it.
I see a bumper sticker now to term
trump.
Trump,
trump,
trump.
Like if you guys start chanting that
shit,
I want credit.
Okay.
I came up with it,
but I,
I really could see that by that time it
will be way more difficult to just.
First of all,
we were going to have to acknowledge
that you can't just edit little pieces
of someone's life and make some sort of
a,
an absolute definitive statement on who
they are based on out of context
statements and things.
And also this idea that like something
you did in 2001 somehow defines you in
2016 and you're the same person,
right?
Isn't the point of life to improve 100
percent to say trump did terrible things
30 years ago and I think that what's he
doing,
he's trying to do things good for the
country.
Isn't that like the arc?
We're all supposed to be on where you
used to be kind of a,
you know,
not a good person,
but you're getting better.
Well,
we would hope they used to be a really
good person and now you're a god.
That's what I'm looking for.
No,
anybody like tHat.
I would.
I want someone who is perfect in the
nineties and is now transcended humanity
and is ready to lead because that's what
we need.
We can't have people leading anymore.
We need some,
a real guru.
You want to go the full cult?
Turn this nation into a cult?
Well,
we'll see.
We'll see what donald wanted.
The full.
I just.
I think we Haven't completely
unrealistic expectation as far as
someone who would put it like jfk,
right?
Perfect example that everyone always
uses.
If he was running today,
he'd be picked apart.
Clinton,
another perfect example.
If you look at him on paper as far as
policy,
take out the monica lewinsky scandal and
just look at what he's done with the
economy was like during this time and
make your arguments plus or minus that
he,
you know how much of it was because of
him,
how much of it was he was in a lucky
spot as far as being a president.
Right.
There's those Arguments,
but you look at him like that and you
go,
wow,
there's thIs guy who was a great guy,
but then either Jennifer Flowers in
Nepal on jones and the this and that and
all these different.
Then you have a totally different idea
of who this guy really is.
The truth is probably somewhere in the
middle,
right?
Yeah.
And and the technology for forming,
forming opinions that are incorrect
about your opponent is just better than
it's ever
been because now they can test that
stuff in real time.
They can put down several ads.
You clicks on what and test the
persuasion.
So,
so the best persuader of 20 fIve years
ago was an amateur compared to the best
persuader in 2016.
I wonder about that because I think that
jfk was a fucking magnificent persuader.
Have you ever seen jfk speech about
secret societies?
Uh,
no,
but I would agree.
he was great for television because he
was great on television.
Well,
he had an incredible speech about secret
societies and the importance of not
having secret societies and government
and uh,
it,
it was really like,
to this day,
it's one of those ones that conspiracy
theorists loved bring out and go,
this is why they killed him,
bro.
This is why they killed because I mean,
it may very well be that,
but you know,
he was talking about the importance of
transparency amongst the government and
amongst the people and how dangerous it
is to,
to hide secrets and have secret
societies.
And it's incredibly,
it's incredibly brilliant.
And it's,
it's amazing because you couldn't
imagine a president saying that today.
It's like,
do you remember,
I believe it was an eisenhower that had
the speech about the military industrial
complex before he left office,
right?
Yeah,
it was eisenhower,
right?
It's an amazing speech,
but it was a speech that he gave one
night that no one ever saw again until
the internet came around.
Like it wasn't something you were played
in school.
It wasn't something you even aware about
probably until youtube came along and
then you watched that thing on youtube
where eisenhower saying,
we must be fearful of the military
industrial complex.
You know,
he waS basically saying there's a whole
machine that wants to go to war and
they're looking for excuses to go to
war,
and he named it,
you know,
he called it this thing that you would
never fucking see that today.
You would never see that.
What kennedy did and what eisenhower
did.
It's almost like they've buttoned down
those holes.
They found out where those issues were
in the difference in the what,
the,
you know,
what the people that are actually
running the government want to direct
into project versus these mouthpieces.
These guys like eisenhower,
kennedy now it sort of the military,
industrial,
mainstream media conglomerates,
because they all seem to be on the same
side right now.
Sort of,
but aren't the.
And different sites like fox is
different than cnn.
Right?
Well fox Is sort of by itself.
Yeah.
I was watching fox and cnn back and
forth before the,
like before the election I was just
going to watch fox for like an hour and
then I'd switch over to cnn for an hour
and I was,
I was getting schizophrenia.
So if you seen how a reality as
bifurcated,
so if he switched between fox and cnn
and fox,
the trump transition team is doing a
terrific job picking real adults,
blah,
blah.
You go over to cnn,
it's chaos.
It's,
you know,
there's,
it's,
there's just this big cluster fog going
over there and everything's falling
apart of the country is going to fall
apart.
They have access to the same information
as far as I know.
Um,
and those are two completely different
views of reality.
Yeah.
There's two completely different views
of reality.
Also.
Um,
if I've gone to some liberal sites
websites that are urging people to
contact the electoral college and block
trump's rise to power,
like what is that even possible?
And how isn't that anti-democratic like
to,
to have a few people contact the
electoral college,
which is like you're talking about like
the representatives,
like every state picture representative,
that representative is supposed to
represent the state.
They almost always do,
but they have this sort of weird hidden
power where they could kind of change
the,
like if California voted for clinton,
but they said fuck that.
Trump.
Like if someone actually did decide to
do that,
some crazy delicate.
Yeah.
So apparently that power is
intentionally built in just to prevent a
monster from being,
you know,
didn't,
weren't elected,
they,
it didn't work,
didn't work.
Uh,
but that's what people are saying like
let's go.
But that would be,
there would be a revolt in this country
if they ever did that.
Good lord,
if they think it's bad now the
divisiveness and the,
the,
the angst and this fucking weird line in
the sand across.
I mean,
it's almost civil war style,
bitcoin between the right and the left
right now.
Well,
some of that might be exaggerated by the
media as well.
Could be accentuated.
Is,
is.
Yeah.
They're blowing on that fire with the
protesters.
Be out there.
If it wasn't an intellivision do you.
What?
Do you,
what is your opinion on the protest,
do you think?
I mean,
I've seen ads where they said they would
pay people 35 bucks an hour to protest.
Is that true or is that bullshit?
I don't know.
I would,
I would say low credibility.
I had heard that you can't snopes things
anymore because snopes leans towards
hillary.
Yeah,
I hear that too.
But where do you hear it though?
From snopes?
I didn't know either outright forums and
so I would say,
uh,
that one is grain of salt,
but there certainly are things that are
subject to interpretation for sure.
So you got to figure there's some bias
everywhere.
Yeah.
I wonder if people are really getting
paid to,
to,
to protest.
So it seems like a good gig if you're
broke.
Fuck,
I think it's just assumed to be true on
the right doors.
They think that this is proven and lots
of different ways.
Well,
when I was in New York,
I do,
it may be.
There was thousands and thousands of
oscar winning actors wandering the
streets,
but honestly,
to me it didn't seem like anybody was
acting.
It didn't seem like anybody was a paid
performer.
Well,
they wouldn't.
Most of them could be naturals,
but you need a core that gets everybody
excited.
You know,
there's gotta be a core of this shows up
and then other people can.
Or is it that the people that are
willing to take that 35 bucks an hour,
they hated trump anyway,
and this gives them an excuse to some
cash while they're hitting trump.
What is this here know someone wasn't
paid $3,500 to protest Donald Trump.
It's fake news,
uh,
created by paul horner who post fake
news and a variety of websites.
Oh,
how dare you.
He took credit for the fake news.
Well,
that makes sense.
He goes,
his followers don't fact check anything.
They'll post everything,
believe anything warner said,
referring to then trump's campaign
manager,
corey lewandowski,
horner said his campaign manager posted
my story about a protest getting paid
$3,500 as a fact.
Like I made that up.
I posted it in a fake ad on craig's
list.
Here's a screenshot of those since
deleted.
Tweet.
That's funny.
So I'm glad I said low credibility
before you showed that that makes.
That would have been really
embarrassing.
The amount of money you'd have to have
to pay thousands of people.
Thirty five bucks an hour.
Well,
that supports the.
George soros is behind everything,
which I'm pretty skeptical about.
Yeah.
Um,
what about that peter thiel billionaire
character that funded the lawsuit
against gawker?
Isn't he in some way,
shape or form a part of the team?
He's part of the trump transitions.
I don't know if he's technically on the
transition team.
Yeah,
it's all very interesting.
It's very.
Well there goes the anti gay thing.
Wherever you seen any evidence that he's
anti gay,
that trump's anti gay.
I am not sure what they're even looking
at except that he picked a pence as his
running mate in penn says stuff of this
history.
Yes,
he does.
He has some stuff that I tweeted the
other day that rachel maddow was
highlighting that he was saying that
instead of giving money to aids
research,
you should give money to educate gay
people about the risks of their
behavior.
Yeah,
so ears.
Here's what I think's going to happen.
If you want to put this in the positive
perspective,
the vice president will adopt the
president's policies,
at least in public by the time mike
pence,
he might run for president or something.
My guess is that it will be hard coded.
In other words,
this gives them an opportunity to evolve
to where the country you would find him
more acceptable.
Anyway.
Show do you want to do that?
And it's sort of a what I call the fake
because it gives them an excuse to do it
without being a hypocrite because people
say,
yeah,
you had to do that because he's your
president.
Oh,
now that's just your policy.
So my guess is that trump is moving a
lot of people to the middle because
that's where he is,
but that pence guys,
he's not very persuasive.
I don't.
I just really have a hard time seeing
him as being in god's going to run for
president some day.
I think he might really.
Yeah.
I,
I think as a pick,
you know,
all I'll say that I'm no fan of his
history with,
you know,
gay rights stuff and I'm not,
I'm on that team.
Um,
but as a personality on tv,
like he's really good at interviews.
He's really sticks and point and the
only had one thing you needed to do,
which was when a debate against the
other vice president,
tim kaine,
which he did.
He's trying to highs emails though.
Well
he's,
yeah,
I'm sure they would all like to be seen
that though.
That was the latest thing,
right?
Like they want access to his emails.
He's like,
fuck that,
you know,
we're waiting for that shoe to drop.
Who knows.
I mean,
it's going to come a time when I think
we're probably all going to have access
to all of our emails.
I mean,
I think you,
you're going to have to come to the
conclusion that when you're,
and you should now really,
you should think when you're sending an
email,
you should assume that this is not
really private.
I kind of do already,
first of all,
because someone on the other side who
gets the Scott Adams,
dick pic co,
we'll check this out and they just,
there's so many out there down and said,
well,
hey man,
already.
So like own it to you.
You know what I mean?
No,
no,
no.
Look what charlie sheen did.
Made a career to own it.
So I've,
uh,
I've speculated that the perfect world,
would it be no privacy if everybody knew
everything about everybody?
The worst world is where most people
have privacy,
but if people lose it because then
they're just victim so everybody could
but hear any of it.
But everybody knew everybody's shit.
Suddenly you'd be like,
really?
You're terrible.
I'm terrible too.
I think it would.
I think we would get used to each other
so quickly.
I think it would also force people to
evolve.
I mean,
we all know our best friends stuff,
you know,
and you know,
we know the,
the failures and that we all have
together collectively and we still love
each other,
but it's just like letting those other
people in on it,
letting those strangers in on the time
that you had did that bad thing,
but the reason you care is that they'll
think poorly of you and that that will
affect your life,
but if you have mutually assured
destruction,
which is that everybody's bad because
you know everything about everybody.
You know,
everybody's got something they're proud
of.
Everybody just thinks,
well,
I don't think I'll throw a stone because
it's going to come right back at my
house.
Well,
I think it's step one in this complete
and total assimilation.
I think losing privacy.
I agree with you 100 percent.
I think it's inevitable whether it's 30
years from now or 50 years from now.
I think essentially everything you do
from then on,
it's going to.
I think there's going to come some form
of technology that is a leap.
Very much like the internet is this
crazy leap,
right?
The internet provides us with this
incident,
tanium access to all the answers to all
the questions you've ever had,
which is just unprecedented in history.
There's never been a time where you say,
well,
what did happen on the native american
trail of tears?
Like,
why is it called that?
You can just fucking open your phone to
sit down for a few hours,
and then I came back to you.
What would he got for me,
Scott?
You could tell me like exactly wHat the
fuck went down.
This is like unprecedented stuff,
I think in that leap,
which I think we're in the middle of.
So it seems like it's not as big of a
deal as it really is.
Like there's going to be another leap
that's even more speCtacular than that
and that leap is going to integrate all
of our minds together.
It's going to integrate our memories.
It's going to integrate our ability to
communicate and we will literally are
going to become a technologically
technologically created hive mind.
I might've written a book that
has something to say about that.
I'm god's debris.
Um,
what was the idea behind your book?
if I told you it would ruin your book
reading experience,
but spoiler alert,
can you say that?
Uh,
but I will say that I've had this
thought using periscope because when I'm
using periscope,
unlike the conscious mind of this
gigantic brain,
which is all the people watching me,
so I can say things like,
hey,
I think this,
this law might go into effect.
No,
I don't know the answer to that.
Somebody tells me what the law is.
And within three seconds a period on my
screen in the periscope session will be
somebody who knows the answer that.
And there's almost nothing I can't throw
out there that there isn't someone under
the thousands of people who were alive
at that moment.
And it's the live part that's
interesting because you can,
you know,
the internet is kind of like one
person's alive and the others,
you know,
looking at data on the other side.
but when it's live,
people who are contributing to a thought
and you're watching a forum in real time
on periscope,
it is like a new intelligence has been
created by this technology that's
temporal.
You know,
as soon as I turned it off it turns off,
but it is a large freaking mind that
multiplies whatever I have going on by
the power of all the people watching.
It's really,
really thrilling.
But when it's spinning,
how come you have so many people that
are talking to you so often?
You get thousands of people on there.
How can you pay attention to those
comments?
Well,
I can't watch them all.
So if someone has a good answer,
well I usually,
if I,
I try to ask a question and then I look.
But otherwise if I'm talking and I'm
focusing on what I'm saying,
but when you're looking at their answer
d,
can you click on that answer?
Can you freeze your screen or something
like that.
So like,
because it's like I see how it works.
Like,
um,
usually what happens is something go
past so quickly.
I'll say I missed it,
I missed it.
Say that again.
And I look forward to it comes back.
Uh,
the reason why I asked,
because we did something similar
yesterday.
We have this tri caster that runs a
video stream on youtube,
that multicolored keyboard lit up,
christmas lights looking thing.
That fucking thing is crashed two days
in a row on us in the middle of
broadcast where it never crashed before.
Now jamie updated all the software and
we're hoping it doesn't do it again in
this show has been fine,
but I said,
well,
if anybody knows a better solution,
please let us know.
And so proud.
The comments were just filled on
instagram with all these really good
solutions and a few of them,
few the machines look pretty bad ass.
So I mean,
who knows what,
we'll have to research,
find out what's the best,
but that when have you ever been able to
do that before and you know some.
There's a bunch of dumb answers,
but somewhere in there is probably the
right answer.
You know,
in some person who's an expert.
Like if somebody asked a question and it
was on an insert,
a instagram forum or an instagram
picture and it had something to do with
being cartoonist,
well who better to ask than the guy who
created dilbert?
You would be able to answer and give
your your expert opinion on how this
works or that works.
I
think also our government is going to
run that way.
At least if trump is a transparent sort
of public president like I think he will
be.
I think there's going to be a lot of
policies that get created in this sort
of collective brain that is trump
leading the discussion and the entire
public weighing in through social media
and mainstream media in every other way.
I think he can do that and probably will
and it's going to be like this thrilling
experience of watching good thoughts
turn into better thoughts.
Boy,
that is the rose colored glasses view of
the trump presidency.
If I've ever heard one,
that Would be the best case scenario and
also that he wants.
Now that he's in the office once he's no
longer in contention,
now he's the president,
so now he's fighting with any way the
same way anymore.
But what people are worried about is
people that write things about him.
Like if people write poor reviews of his
presidency,
that they're going to be attacked.
They're worried about getting sued,
they're worried about being targeted.
They worry about the fact that he's in
control of the nsa and he can,
you know,
he could hire some edward snowden type
character to fuck up your life if you
write an article about them for the wall
street journal or something,
you know.
Uh,
well,
um,
I talk about this as well.
If you look at any individually thing,
he does like,
hey,
it's 3:00 AM and I'm tweeting about,
you know,
miss universe or something.
I always imagined them with the socks on
in the lazy chair,
right?
Yeah.
Like a boxer shorts with a boner angry,
no shirt,
red face screaming well on is doing
something with the kid and better yet
barefoot with yellow toenails.
I imagine he doesn't take care of his
feet.
uh,
but what he does is he a,
he praises and rewards people who are
good,
good to him especially.
And he attacks without,
without exception.
He just never makes an exception.
He will attack you if you go after him.
He doesn't start the fight,
but he likes to finish it.
I think bill burroughs one who said that
he would have those black socks on.
I might've.
I might've co-opted that.
I'm thinking of.
He might've said,
well,
we're drunk durinG the end of the world
podcast if you haven't heard that.
We get a podcast while the presidency
was being called and bill burr was on
fire.
It was on fire.
It was one of the funniest podcast ever,
but It was all like watching it all go
down.
At one time he got into an argument with
the other comedians,
sarah tiana,
because tiana was talking about how uh,
anybody who supports trump is a racist
and sexist and then.
And then bill made fun of it and it was
just,
it was perfect.
It was the perfect thing to see why it
was all going down.
It was like you were seeing in bill and
her.
You're seeing it in a physical form the
Way people are choosing to frame this
thing.
Fascinating.
I'll watch that.
yeah.
Anyway,
I was just saying trump likes to leave
the biggest gap between pleasing him,
end up pleasing him and it has nothing
to do with the thing he's fighting about
it at the moment.
It's about setting it up so that the
next who's thinking should
I fuck with him?
That didn't work for the last 700
people,
but if it had worked for some people to
fuck with him in the past,
you would be tempted.
You like,
well,
sometimes people get away with it.
This is a different thing though.
Once you're the president versus once
you're just some billionaire
real estate tycoon.
Because there was.
There was one guy that was writing about
it where he had been sued by trump and
when.
Because he wrote an article and when
they started examining the actual data
it got pretty ugly pretty quick and then
they abandoned the lawsuit and this guy
trump wound up getting him a seat for
the fights.
Like he got him a ticket and I think he
flew him out to atlantic city and maybe
someone with them as well for the fights
and that became like an issue.
Like,
yeah,
what,
how does that connect with the.
I'm missing the string there.
Well,
just you know that he's just a master
manipulator.
Like in the middle of this,
he has this lawsuit thing with this guy,
you know,
and the guy calls him a shithead or
whatever you called them and writes this
article about him.
Trump get some tickets to some fight.
Susan loses in court or loses the,
you know,
when they're going through all the data,
they abandoned the lawsuit.
Trump gets of tickets to the fight with
the whole thing is just crazy.
It's probably all part of rewarding
people and punishing people so that you.
Yes,
you feel there's a state game of thrones
type shit that came with us.
It doesn't look like.
I was just thinking of that in the
weirdly as I was doing something the
other day,
I was thinking that you could map all
these family dynasties unto the game of
thrones thing.
You could in some way.
I mean it is bizarre in to the extreme
that we've dealt with these family
dynasties like the bush family in.
We almost did it again with jeb.
You know,
I mean,
who knows if it wasn't for trump,
if trump wasn't around and he didn't
come up with that low energy jeb things
that,
what you called them?
YeAh,
low energy.
If he didn't see.
And also jeff just sucked.
I mean when,
when the pressure was on,
he just wasn't good.
This wasn't good.
It wasn't.
And when all that stuff was going down
or like rick perry,
like when remembering rick perry's in
debates,
you just didn't know what the fuck he
was talking about.
He's like,
what was I even saying?
Like that's it,
you're done.
But if it wasn't for that happening with
jeb bush,
he might have very well gotten the same
position that donald got into.
I mean,
when you looked at all the other people,
he least had that familiar name.
People might've been inclined.
He didn't have any real crazy like
horrible stories in the past that got
brought up immediately.
He could very well and they would have
continued that family dynasty.
The clinton family dynasties another
disturbing one.
You know,
that's a weird dynasty,
you know,
is a chelsea next is Michelle Obama
next.
Oh yeah,
I think she's definitely.
That's the question,
man.
That's the big question.
She would be excellent.
She would.
She's like a reallY good speaker.
She's very intelligent.
She's very articulate.
she's a very measured and composed and
stately and
as mcgregor said,
and the fight,
She has lots of attributes.
She has a lot of attributes.
Yeah.
I mean,
and she carrIed herself extremely well
for eight years in the white house under
some incredible pressure.
I mean,
I dunno what she,
what her,
you know,
her responsibilities were what our days
looked like,
but she's never made a misstep.
There was never,
never been an embarrassing interview.
Never important.
yeah.
Nothing much less controversial than
hillary clinton.
Much less,
you know,
because even before the,
uh,
like she tried to run for president,
there was always the whitewater thing
that she was connected through the vince
foster thing that she was connected to.
HAve you seen that meme?
You know,
they're doing all these joe biden memes.
Have you seen the recent joe biden meme
the one with and see if you could find
it?
I think I retweeted it.
I retweeted it yesterday.
Somebody tweeted it it to me,
um,
it was,
joe biden and obama laughing about,
uh,
about hillary having something in common
with monica lewinsky now.
Yeah.
Pull it up so you can say you could see
it.
I don't want to blow it.
Check this out.
Look at this.
Look joe.
Then it says joe.
Then I said,
hillary.
Now you and monica have something else
in common.
You blew it.
And then obama and he's laughing.
Throws his head back laughing and
obama's look at that and look with his
eyebrows raised and it says,
you know,
she kills people,
right?
These are fucking great.
Do you think she's killed anybody?
That kid that got shot outside of his
apartment at 4:00 in the morning or they
didn't take his cell phone.
they didn't take his wallet.
They didn't take his money and he,
according to wikileaks,
was the one that leaked all those
documents about the dnc and the dnc
favoring hillary clinton over bernie
sanders.
Who knows what else that guy knew.
If that was the guy,
if that is the case,
I don't know,
but it seem more likely that even if
they were murderers because of some
hillary clinton,
the connection that she wouldn't know
about it.
perhaps just somebody who thought,
well,
I'm going to change history.
You do a favor perhaps perhaps,
but this is also the woman who was
attributed in an email.
Whether or not it's correct.
She said about julian assan,
can't we just drone that guy?
This guy is some thumbing his nose that
America can't.
We just drone him so I don't want to
drone him because I think he's done a
great service.
But from the butts,
from the,
from the context of a government looking
at this situation,
if government secrets have been stolen
and It's your job to,
you know,
make sure this doesn't happen and you
know,
to get justice.
That's actually kind a fair question.
No,
I wouldn't want because you're saying
what are all our options?
Well,
it could be off the cuff,
flippant statement that she didn't
really take serious.
Like can we just drone him?
But she said some creepy shit.
Like one of the things that she said
about gadhafi,
you ever see that interview where she's
talking about.
She goes,
we came,
we saw he died.
Ha ha,
ha ha.
Yeah.
That was a startling and shocking is
after she hit her head.
Oh really?
Yes.
that would explain.
It wouldn't 100 percent.
Yeah,
very irrational to think that way and
I'm very impulsive to to say that out
loud because you're dealing with the
dissolving of a nation.
Libya is in complete total turmoil and
has become a breeding ground for isis
and a lot of that can be attributed to
it being completely destabilized by the
United States,
helping out all the people that wound up
killing gaddafi.
It doesn't mean good.
Naafi wasn't a huge piece of shit and
the world is in better because he's dead
probably is,
but Libya is not better right now.
Like olivia became completely unstable
after that so that he came,
we came,
we saw he died.
Ha ha,
ha ha.
That's like laughing in the face of
these poor unfortunate people who just
got a shit,
roll the dice and grew up in Libya and
now they're stuck there and then the
right side of the character from how
skilled the politician she is to say
something that's so clearly the wrong
thing to say at throwing.
Well,
wHen was the fall of Libya?
Was that 13 or 14?
When did a find out when gaddafi died?
When gaddafi was killed?
What?
I'll never forget it.
I'll tell you that that video is fucking
terrifying.
The video of the rebels capturing him
and they're sticking things up.
His assets.
Two thousand 11,
I believe the interview with her was in
2012 or 13.
See if you could find that out.
If it's in 2012 or 13,
it's entirely possible that this is
directly post concussion and a severe
bleeding.
Apparently on her brain,
she had some serious problems.
She's fucked up for like 12 months.
I don't think people realize that that
can permanently change your personality
permanently.
The the average person doesn't thInk
that's a thing,
but I've seen it.
You know,
I have as well,
I've seen it many,
many,
many times because I'm in the head
trauma business in a lot of ways because
of my experience with the ufc.
Um,
but I know people that have been hitting
the head outside of the ufc and have
never been the same.
Um,
that is one of the things that I've
always said about sam kinison.
Sam kennison had a great book written
about him by his brother called my
brother sam or brother sam.
It's a great book,
especially for me,
huge kennison fan,
but he basically says sam was one person
and then he got hit by a truck when he
was a little kid and became a completely
different person.
Became reckless and wild and it came out
of a head injury.
Oh yeah.
The lack of control didn't give a fuck.
That's where it came from.
Well,
yeah,
like literally from brain trauma.
What is it?
Yes.
This video that's got a million and a
half to 2011 was uploaded the exact same
day.
It says he died.
Oh,
okay.
Possible.
That she already interviewed and was
recorded and put.
This was up on,
I mean It may be possible.
It happened like that morning.
That doesn't seem right.
Yeah.
Especially if you're saying that this
same day as.
Maybe that's why she's giddy,
but if that is the case,
well why don't you find out because this
is just one.
It says 1 million,
542,000 cbs news interview with hillary
clinton.
There it goes.
Laughed about killing gaddafi.
Go to that.
That's for 2016 and let's see when it
says it says flash back.
Maybe it was like right after and she
was so giddy.
But if that's the case,
the link to that video I just pulled up.
Okay,
so if that's the.
But what does it say in that article and
that article that you're reading before
you click on it,
see flashlIght right there.
You like,
what does it say there?
Well he died in 2011 and she supposedly
had the big head injury in 2012.
So you can't even blame It on that.
Then I'll look into it.
If that's the case,
you can't really blame it on that
because that means that she hit her head
after this.
She's laughing probably about gaddafi
died and she fell.
Maybe when you laugh really hard and
you're not that healthy,
she was drinking or or do you think she
loses it up but were saying Scott Adams?
Well,
you can't rule that out.
Definitely can't.
She doesn't look too healthy.
She's definitely not eating the best
foods.
You know?
I was saying that no matter how much she
drinks,
if she is a social drinker and you know,
people were just social drinkers who
have had two drinks,
let's say you don't want them driving.
Right?
So why isn't that disqualifying for
somebody who's going to be in control of
the nuclear arsenal?
Who admits?
Yes,
I'm a social drinker now.
In the past you never had to ask that
question because it was too social
drinkers running against each other.
So you're going to get a social drinker
no matter who got elected.
But trump's the first time you had a non
drinker.
He doesn't drink at all.
No,
no,
no.
He hasn't had a sip of alcohol in his
life really,
or a drug.
He claims I'd like to get them drunk and
high.
How about that?
This issue was being interviewed in
Afghanistan on that day and news hit so
that,
I guess that video was not being taped
or it wasn't a supposed to be taped,
but it was like an unfair kind of
record.
Yeah,
it was definitely an unfair recording,
but so,
so that was like right when it happened,
but she was laughing about it right when
it happened,
but that explains why she was out of
character for her normal.
Yes.
That does make sense.
She was giddy.
It was off camera that they just killed
this guy and she was off camera.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
That's a lot more logical.
I'm glad that we solve this.
We solved it.
We should be detective Scott Adams.
Um,
we solved a lot of things today I think.
I think we cleared up a lot of people's
misconceptions about you that not only
did not vote for trump,
you don't vote.
You were essentially just looking at
this thing as a,
a person who knows a lot about
persuasion and knows a lot about public
speaking and what you were looking at
this and you were going,
this is,
um,
you're almost like watching a game.
You're watching a game play out,
and if you say,
look,
the raiders are going to slaughter the
dolphins.
It doesn't mean you hate the dolphins,
means you're looking at the actual law,
that defensive line,
the offense,
the quarterback.
I see where this game is going to go.
I thought when this whole thing started
developing the trump candidacy,
that would open a crack in the universe
where I could talk about this persuasion
stuff and be believed and in order to be
believed,
my technique for that was last year I
predicted so that when the day came,
when I was right,
I would have enough credibility to say,
okay,
so the other things I said,
maybe you should pay attention to them
too.
So it was sort of a long game.
I was playing for credibility.
And um,
I thought that persuasion would be the
most important variable.
It's certainly a huge variable in this
world,
um,
as is what we discussed earlier,
the ability to speak publicly with
confidence,
not just persuasion,
but just to not look rattled.
you know,
even if you're not persuaded like you
don't,
he's not getting defeated even when he's
losing.
and I would see like these debates and I
would say,
well,
she made some salient points.
She seemed more articulate.
she seemed smoother with her words.
She seemed more stately,
but he never felt like he lost.
He didn't act like he lost.
That's giant
to.
Yeah.
People.
People are,
you know,
they pick up their feelings for other
people.
We just look at them and say,
hey,
he's happy.
So happy.
Just picking that up.
People walk in the room and they're
downers and your energy goes down as
soon as they enter.
Watching someone super uncomfortable or
unsuccessful is very.
It's hard to do like watching someone
bomb on stage.
Very hard
do.
Uh,
one of,
one of my great moments when I started
to understand the world better is the
first time I smoked pot in college.
And for most of my college experience,
I found,
I found this weird pattern that people
were nicer to me if I had just gotten
high and it was years before I realized
that I was causing them to be nice
because you were nicer to them.
I was just relaxed and you were given a
better vibe out.
Gave anthony died.
And I realized that I can,
I can control how they act simply by my
emotional state.
Well definitely we control how people
react to us based on what kind of.
And I've given off the wrong energy
before and you see it in people,
you know,
like,
ah fuck,
you know,
like maybe you're too caught up in what
you're doing and you don't want to be
bothered or whatever it is.
We've all been there before.
And then we've all been on the opposite
where maybe someone's like,
this guy's a dick.
And I'm like,
really?
I just had a wonderful,
pleasant conversation with him because
you interface with them in the perfect
way,
at the right time with respect.
And the guy lord his guard and you know,
and gave a little back to you and you
gave more to him and everybody's good.
We,
I've seen,
I think we've all experienced both of
those things and I think that's one of
the problems with one person accounts of
any bad thing that went on.
Like can I.
And I've looked at some of this trump
stuff and I'm like,
man,
what?
What really did happen?
What really did happen with the clinton
accusations?
What was really going down between these
two people because one of them is
talking about and the other one isn't
and we don't know what the fuck the
answer is.
And I think that that's often the case.
It's like the actual reaction that
people have.
They want to think that the other person
was being a dick,
but maybe you were being something
negative too,
and they're reacted to that.
Then it compounded.
But maybe as Scott Adams was talking to
the guy and use the exact same words,
none of the disagreement would have
taken place in the first place.
The messenger is always,
you know,
the message.
Well,
we're both,
we're,
we are more than one thing and when
human beings are interacting with each
other,
we're,
we're doing,
it's almost like we're putting on a
combined effort.
We're,
and we're,
we're piecing together a conversation
and this conversation is a joint effort.
It's like we're both contributing to it
and it might come out terrible.
Um,
but it might not be your fault.
It might be 100 percent my fault or it
might be 100 percent your fault.
Like,
but the way it comes out is because the
two of us together didn't sync up,
you know,
and oftentimes they say,
I met Scott Adams.
He's a fucking piece of shit,
but it's not really you.
It might just be the way I hear that a
lot.
How dare you.
But it might be the way this person talk
to you.
Like they might've started out right off
the bat trying to joke around and,
and you know,
said something rude or said something
they thought was funny and you didn't or
caught you at a bad time or,
you know.
Yeah.
I just try to be aware that I'm causing
people to be the way they are more often
than you imagine why.
I also got to think that being the
president has got to be.
I mean,
you want to look at yourself the way the
world looks at you,
the harshness of the view of the people
on the outside looking in.
There's no better way than to be the
president.
I mean,
he's got people walking down,
wilshire blocking traffic,
screaming.
They fucking hate him like that.
If anything is going to cause you a
narcissist,
clearly obviously he's the guy has a
great love for himself,
which is part of his success.
Part of why puts his name on the
buildings is a great love for himself.
That takes a hit when you see thousands
of americans,
hundreds of thousands,
in fact wandering down the street with
signs saying they hate you.
I don't know.
You don't think so?
I'm not sure it does because you
probably have your critics as well and
they're not blocking traffic.
Imagine if the fucking people that hated
you were blocking traffic.
Fuck dilbert,
and they just had this gigantic stream
of people would chance donald champ,
k,
and the screaming and you know that this
things a true.
I just imagined myself in the oval
office looking out the window.
I'm the president and they see the
protesters
and I'm thinking,
I'm not having a bad day.
I'm the president of the United States.
So I think it gets lost in the noise
after you get elected.
I mean if civilization breaks that
you're talking about a guy that if
Someone tweets something negative about
it,
he's got a tweet back.
You're talking about A guy.
If somebody writes an article about him
in the wall street journal,
he'll go on his twitter page and call
that magazine or that newspaper a piece
of shit.
The failed New York times still won't
stop lying about me.
He's not a guy who was immune to the
impact of criticism against him.
So if that criticism is coming in the
form of hundreds of thousands of people
protesting the idea that he's going to
suddenly become enlightened enough to
ignore that.
Totally,
but don't.
I don't miss the pattern.
He,
he attacks professionals,
so he,
he goes after people who were in the
cage.
If you're not in the cage,
you're cool.
so those people on the street that are
just screaming and what is he said about
the protesters?
I think what he said is kind of
interesting because I think what he did
say is that it's great that they have
these rights to protests and he likes
the fact that they're all getting
together and voice their opinion,
but we're all going to work this out
together and he likes her energy or
something.
Yeah,
something like that.
So,
so that's,
that's my point.
Yeah.
If any of the,
if the,
if the parade had been led by,
you know,
a reporter for the New York times,
he would have eviscerated the
professional and he wouldn't have
touched anybody behind him because
they're there.
The citizens.
No,
that's a good point.
It,
you,
you make a very convincing argument for
this all being a positive event.
And I think one of the best arguments
for it being a positive event.
This is the first time ever,
we've had someone who has no,
no political background or aspirations
and they're already famous and
successful and they become the
president,
so we're going to get to see,
and it was a guy who wants to dismantle
a system,
like one of the things he said about
passing bills.
See,
when you pass a new bill,
you got to get rid of two old ones.
And I was like,
well,
regulations,
regulation,
excuse me by my first reaction to that
was,
oh,
that is a stupid oversimplification,
but I'll bet there are enough old laws
that they want to get rid of any way
that for a long time you could get rid
of two for one.
Yeah,
there might be some ridiculous ones that
we could get rid of it.
It's entirely possible you can't do that
rule forever.
And of course dr.
Deregulation,
um,
when it comes to environmental efforts
is one thing that terrifies people.
And this,
um,
climate denier a concern.
That's a real issue.
That's something that could affect us.
Let's talk about that.
Sure.
Please.
Because people have been begging me
please to give any argument that doesn't
make Donald Trump look like a science
retarded.
I'm soRry I shouldn't use that word.
I apollo use it.
It doesn't have any bearing on science.
It's not a medical term.
Retard is people that are retarded with
their.
They're slow to catch on.
And we're not talking aBout mental
illness.
We're talking about retards.
Alright?
But I apologize if anybody was offended
or you're going to do that.
They don't let you do it.
Um,
so here's,
here's my best argument.
Let's say I'll just play lawyer for a
second and I'm going to defend donald
trump's climate change position,
which disagrees with all of science was.
So you're starting from a deep hole,
right?
So you acknowledged that they've got a
tough task year to what's state his
opinion for what is his position first?
His opinion is that we don't need to
actively work on climate change.
Rather he would rather work actively on
cleaning the air and the water and I
think he thinks that gets us to the same
place.
Um,
and it might,
uh,
here's my argument.
I believe,
and again,
I'm going to speculate a little bit here
so I don't want to put too many words
into the president's mouth,
but I think that he's separating the
data collection part of the science,
which is you measure things and sure
enough temperatures seems to be changing
and historically significant ways and
sure enough,
humans seem to be behind some part of
that change.
I think trump accepts that part of it.
The second part of it is not the data
collection is the complicated models
that predict what happens with all this
data.
I think the trump things that those
models are unreliable and not credible
and probably bullshit,
just like he thought the polls were
inaccurate,
right?
Remember you just watched him defy every
expert in the world.
One hundred percent of pollsters said,
no,
Donald Trump.
Look at our numbers.
This could not be more clear.
It's independent people.
These are legitimate professionals.
There's no freaking way that you win
with these numbers,
and Donald Trump said,
I don't believe the polls,
and it was right.
Donald trump was right,
but there's a big difference between
poles and scientific measurements of our
carbon footprint.
No,
I'm not saying that the same thing,
so I'm not gonna I'm not going to leap
and say case closed based on it.
I'm just going to say that through our
history.
If you try to find the context,
how many times have we built a
complicated model on that scale and got
it right?
All right,
so there's nobody who's doing a good job
of predicting where the economy will be
next year.
Those are very similar in the sense that
there's lots of variables and different
models and stuff,
um,
that,
that turns out to be just random.
If the economy's largely based on
confidence,
it's,
there's a bunch of factors involved in
the economy.
How much is involved in the atmosphere.
I mean,
if you can,
their models figuring out that there was
a volcano over here,
there's something happened in the ocean
that you didn't expect.
Some,
some seaweed,
hobo.
Do you don't think they have accounted
for that when they're talking about the
models of the earth being warmer every
year?
I the past decade and scientists being
incredibly concerned that have been
studying this their whole lives,
seeing unprecedented levels of change.
You don't think that that's.
I think that.
Here's where the analogy to the,
the polling
is similar.
We all thought the pilot polling was
reliable because it's sort of math and
you know,
the science seems to work.
What you realized later is that there
was a whole bunch of judgment that went
into which variable to include and you
know,
who,
um,
assumptions about who's going to show up
on polling day and nobody could have any
good idea what was going to happen.
So the most important part of the models
was literally just people sit in the
room say,
I don't know.
I think it would be like last time these
case with science though,
and climate change.
That doesn't make sense to me.
I think that it seems likely,
and again,
this would be subject to smarter people
correcting me and I,
I could easily be corrected on this.
Um,
I think that when you have big
complicated models and lots of people
working on it,
there are probably places in which
people are using judgment.
For example,
in this just be a,
you know,
just to make the point,
there may be two sets of data and you
could say,
well this one seems more reliable than
that one because of whatever.
So I would think they're probably
different scientists could get wildly
different projections and all of them
tapping the same source of data just
like the pollsters got the wrong
answers,
but they're all looking at the same
data.
I see what you're saying kind of.
But I really don't see the connection
between that and the polls because
everybody knows the polls is based on a
very small group of people.
Whereas the vast majority of the problem
of the population is largely uncounted.
Like we really weren't.
We were guessing and gauging but their
opinion.
But that wasn't the problem because
polling is scientific enough that it can
capture it in some way.
But they're,
the conceit is,
I mean you,
you have to admit that there's a certain
percentage that we absolutely know.
We're not measuring those people when
you're talking about the temperature of
the earth.
He or you're absolutely measuring.
So we're measuring the climate all over
the globe.
You're actually measuring,
measuring the sheer heart numbers.
There's no opinion based on there's no
fluctuation of opinion.
I'm agreeing with you that the data
collection is probably pretty solid
because there's an extra.
The interpretation of the data is what
you're disagreeing with.
By the time you put it into an economic
model,
there's almost certainly some fuckery,
a judgment call that somebody who
doesn't think as a judgment call that's
almost guaranteed to be part of the
model building procedure.
Now,
I would love for somebody to educate me
on this because I've never talked to
somebody whose job it is to build a
climate model.
Like,
I'd love to sit in a room and say,
is there any part of this where two
people who are both experts could have
picked a different variable and I'm
almost certain that's the case because
it's a lot of variables in this
complicated and so he's going to be the
case,
right?
But when you have a mass consensus,
when it comes to scientists,
you're not talking about politicians,
you're not talking about cnn versus fox
news,
you're talking about scientists,
right?
When you have a vast consensus that
believe that we have a real issue with
our carbon footprint and that we really
need to slow down the amount of
pollutants and the particulates we put
into the air.
So is that a word?
Particulants particles.
What's the word?
What's the word with like the thing that
people worry about a lot of is not just
the,
like the carbon in the air,
but also the fucking dirt,
the dust,
the,
the actual pollution being.
So.
So here's the third leg of my,
uh,
particulates.
Yeah,
it was right.
Okay.
Thank you.
I love my defense.
So trump's thing is clean the water,
clean the air,
good move,
but it seems like that's going to get
you to the same place right now.
Let me give you another,
maybe give you another really hot.
No,
let me give you another analogy.
Um,
I put solar panels on my house when I
built it nine years ago.
Um,
what those solar panels have saved me
enough electricity and I can predict
forward that I'll definitely get my
money back from putting on solar panels.
Question.
Was it a good economic idea to put those
solar panels on?
Knowing what you know,
that the cost will more than be made up
in my savings.
Was that a good idea for me to do?
It seems like it wrong.
It was a terrible,
terrible idea wrong.
And I knew it at the time.
But by the way,
I have a background in economics.
That's my,
my degree mba from berkeley.
So why is it terrible idea?
Because I knew,
and this is what happened to the cost of
solar cells,
dropped so quickly,
that if I had simply waited three years
and bought it,
then I would have only you know,
three years of savings,
but I would have gotten it as such as a
lower price that I would pay it back
much faster and then it'd be gravy from
there on if you only wanted to look at
it that way,
but if you didn't take into
consideration the variable of you
affecting the carbon footprint of the
earth by gathering up your electricity
for three years due to convention.
That's actually why I did it and so I
made made a bad economic decision
because the,
what we call these stupid rich have to
go first.
Okay.
But it wasn't a terrible idea.
It just wasn't a good idea.
Economically.
It was a very good idea.
It wasn't a good idea economically,
the economically.
Okay.
So I'm sure you can't consider all sorts
of other variables.
All right,
well all,
all analogies breakdown ultimately.
So I tell you,
but they're good for.
They're good for explaining.
Okay.
If they're not good for proving a point
to say that.
So here's the analogy.
Odds are that technology is going to
save us from climate change.
Really?
Yeah.
They're there already,
um,
you know,
on the drawing board,
ideas for putting like a giant hose into
the upper atmosphere and in somehow
sucking bad things that will suck all
the clouds out to
but yet.
But chances are,
chances are,
and again,
you might not want to take this risk.
I'm not even saying you should,
but she has this are if you waited five
or 10 years and then got serious about
it,
you'd probably be in a better position
because we'd have better technology.
And,
and starting from that point,
we just be in a better place or no,
I'm not saying we should do that.
I'm just saying that you can't know this
starting now is the
smart thing because like my solar
panels,
the technology's changing so fast,
that waiting a little bit until you
really can get some purchase with some
good technology and just go balls to the
wall and say,
all right,
fucking $500,000,000,000.
We're going to spend now because we've
got the solution,
maybe this is a convenient way that
you're interfacing with the software
simulation that we're all trapped in
your choosing to take this path of a
success based on technological
progression rather than based on taking
care of mother earth.
Well,
it doesn't.
Doesn't every model assume that
everything stays the same and there's
just more of it.
Right?
So here's one thing I can guarantee your
climate change model does not include,
okay fucking hose to the upper
atmosphere.
I never thought about until you brought
it up and isn't that going to be the
biggest factor?
It will be the technological change that
happens between now and that in fact,
that's the whole point of alarming us.
So we'll work hard on the technological
changes.
I thought they should make a skyscraper
sized air filter.
That's one of the plans there.
There is a,
something like that.
Then they could actually take that
carbon out of the atmosphere and use it
for fuel.
Right?
And Burn it,
burn it back.
I,
I've seen some amazing things in
headlines recently,
but I never trust any of them and it
totally makes sense that if we can clean
air in your house,
like you know we have that right behind
you right there for when people smoke
cigarettes,
we have that air filter and it's pretty
powerful.
If someone can sit in your seat and
smoke a cigarette and this room will be
bearable.
Well yeah you can.
You can do that.
And that's a very simple portable unit.
Some buildings have very sophisticated
units,
so I think the technology for scrubbing
the atmosphere already exists.
It's just not implementing it on a large
scale is not economical.
So just like my soldier pedals.
So the point is if you started now and
spend $500,000,000,000,
you might get a billion dollars with a
benefit because you don't have the right
technology.
If you waited,
they had the right technology and then
put your effort into it,
you might get it for cheap.
Okay.
We don't know that.
So that that's a risk.
That's a risk.
Everybody is got to assess that a is
much more comfortable than the idea of a
climate change denier perspective.
Like a climate change optimist,
like,
yeah,
I know it's kind of fucked up now,
but we've got some stuff in the works.
Don't worry folks.
We looked at the progressions that are
going to be fine.
Well I think trump is trying to have it
both ways.
You know,
he's got people he needs to satisfying
the right,
but he doesn't want to be a crazy man
and left.
so we've had testified in some story
that both people can find some comfort
in because this is such a big issue and
I think that middle ground is where he's
trying.
He's sort of ab testing it now by saying
let's clean the air,
you know,
clean the water because how do you do
that?
You can't,
you know,
you do all the same.
Don't you know,
but you really can't do that yet.
No,
I clean all the water and clean all the
air.
I mean you would have to woof.
Oh well,
but the technology is to get there,
right.
Are going to be at Least overlapping
with whatever you need to do with
climate change,
hopefully,
because you still want your electric car
either way.
It's just different way to get there.
You also gotta think that whatever
byproducts that are in the atmosphere
and in the water,
all that stuff could probably be used
for something.
I mean the,
the,
the whatever these.
Yeah.
I think.
I think there's already,
at least in the lab they've,
they've made it useful.
That will be really fascinating if we
figured out a way someday to get to a
zero emission state,
you know,
where everything we use gets recycled
and we keep the air pure and we just
figured out a way to be completely
efficient and how we burn things or how
we make things or how we recycle things
and that we all leave.
I mean it just seems like.
Well,
I think what you're saying economically,
once it becomes economically feasible,
there's becomes like this big financial
boom and taking whatever the particular
incident,
the,
the carbon or whatever it is,
out of the atmosphere and you make mass
amounts of money from doing that.
You know,
and people figure out a way to get
really rich doing it.
Yeah.
Somebody just got to figure out a way to
get rich.
Every solution has that.
Right.
And then somebody found out a way to get
rich.
Okay.
Problem solved.
Is this one of the first podcasts you've
done like this?
Um,
I've done other podcasts but sort of
prepared yourself for something like
this by doing periscopes.
Like you're really good at these like
long form things.
Have you ever thought about doing your
own podcast?
I have actually.
I'm curious about it.
Just tell people gonna be mad at me
right now.
They get fucking mad every time I tell
somebody to do a podcast because I'm
like,
dude,
everybody shouldn't do a vlog,
a blog post,
but I think you should do a podcast.
I really do.
I would be remiss if I did not bring it
up.
People have been asking me.
I can't tell you how many people just
begged me to come onto your show.
Really?
It's the single most requested thing of
my year.
Wow.
Holy shit.
You specifically.
Wow.
Well,
it was worth it for me.
I enjoyed it.
I enjoy.
I had a great time.
We do this again.
This is a peak experience.
Let's do it again.
I would definitely do it once a year.
Let's come.
Come back in here and we'll see how this
fucking crazy plans working out.
I'll do that.
Let's do it.
Sure.
Thank you scott.
I really appreciate it,
man.
Thank you very much.
Scott adams says on twitter,
your blog is dilbert.
Just go to [inaudible] dot com.
[inaudible] dot com.
My book,
how to fail at almost everything.
Still win big and look at my app when
hubdoc and what is the app when the hub.
What?
What is it?
Oh,
it's a imagine the uber app without the
uber car where You and your friends can
just see that you're meeting going
toward the same location.
Oh,
so if your friend says,
oh,
I'm stuck in traffic,
and you're like,
bitch,
you haven't even left your house fucking
house yet.
Ooh,
I like it.
Keep people responsible.
Thank you very much,
scott.
I really appreciate it.
I had a great time talking to you.
I likewise.
All right folks,
we'll be back on monday with shannon,
the canon briggs.
Let's go see thAt.