Okay.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight,
have you to go to Joe rogan.net and click
on the link for the flashlight and you
enter in the code name Rogan,
and you can get 15% off and
masturbate at a discount.
And we're also brought
to you by Onnit labs,
creators of Alpha brain and new mood,
cognitive enhancers,
vitamins for your dome bitches.
Get it together.
If you think it costs too much,
please duplicate the formula.
We don't mind.
We just want you to use it.
It's good shit.
Go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for on it and enter in
the code and a rug and you get 10% off
that to Brian counts in the house.
You dirty freak.
Ready to get shit.
[inaudible]
we're going to break it down.
It's all gonna make sense today.
Brian counts here.
My brother,
my brother,
happy to be here and my friends.
Thank you to whoever gave me this
this weekend at the icehouse.
Some dude gave me hunter s Thompson
is the rum diary a nice paper back.
Just one of the things I
got it is shared drugs.
Psychedelics,
have you done your share yet?
No,
not yet as mushrooms.
I took a four hour
shower on mushrooms once.
Nice.
And then I was hiking in big whiskey
mountain on mushrooms with my buddy.
We decided to take a back route,
which you never do.
I was climbing up a landslide.
That's smart.
And I was like,
to my buddy,
I go,
dude.
He goes,
what?
I go,
you got to move with the mountain.
You're not moving with the mountain.
He's like,
okay,
he's a real mountain mine.
So he's climbing.
I go,
still not more in the mountain.
Okay,
I'm gonna stay here and talk to this rock.
And I had to have a conversation with
the Rock and then as he tells it,
we're on top of whisky mountain,
which is a very big mountain.
Okay.
Luckily it was in the summer as well.
I was with,
I was dating Patrick back in the day
and they were waiting downstairs and he
turns back around and I'm
not wearing any clothes.
And I mean,
no clue.
And I'm,
I'm top of a mountain that you,
that takes a really long time
to climb up and I'm naked.
What'd you do with the clothes?
Oh,
we never found my clothes.
No,
but I did stop and eat
a lot of blueberries
and by the time we also took a shit,
um,
squatting.
And then as I was doing that naked,
my buddy moved some branches pretending
it was a bear jumped up and started to
run and uh,
that caused a problem.
And then I came back down the mountain,
all scratched up,
no clothes and I can't
stop and eat blueberries.
My buddy who's got you
stop eating blueberries.
I had a blue mouth.
Uh,
Shit.
You walked,
you walked barefoot.
That's right.
My phone.
I'll cut up.
My skills was going to take,
I don't know,
a day and a,
I literally,
literally,
literally probably four
hours or something,
like a five hours were up
at any point during the war.
When I finally got down,
I had a blue mouth from
eating blueberries and,
and I was all cut up and patty was like,
what you're doing?
I was like,
I need to did my ass in the lake.
I've shit ass cause I didn't have,
I couldn't walk wipe it.
So,
um,
yeah,
one another.
One of my shit stories.
Thank you.
So,
so she was like,
wow,
that's attractive.
You're a,
you're my man.
Well I'll take the skinny guy with the
Blue Mountain has shit in his assets.
It was coming down off mushrooms.
So that was my experience
with [inaudible].
How much did you take?
Did I heat?
My buddy gave me just a handful,
handful,
it goes eat them.
I was like,
okay,
I want to have an experience.
You got to get them on an empty stomach.
I hadn't eaten.
Of course.
That's really good.
And we're climbing man.
And I just started literally
just hallucinating.
I,
you're better off that
you didn't eat anything.
If you had eaten something,
you'd probably throw it really bad.
I took a shower one time,
I wouldn't get out of the shower.
Patty was banging on
the door and I was like,
I'll be there.
I'm trying to figure something out.
And then,
nope.
It's hard to explain.
But I believe I kept seeing my profile
and the first thing I was like,
cause I kept saying,
Oh fuck,
I wish I was barrel chested.
I'm not barrel chest,
my grandfather's barrel chested.
I know I have a sunken chest.
This is horse shit.
I was like,
that's a terrible profile.
So then I resolved,
resolved while I was in the shower to
just spend the entire summer on a bench
press.
I was going to hire a coach,
just a bench,
which that never happened.
And then I came out of the shower and
then I had this experience of somebody
standing like watching me and judging me.
And I felt like it was the devil
telling me that I was a phony.
So I was like,
oh,
I'm a phony.
I'm a skinny phony.
Why you think it was the devil?
I don't fucking know.
I just felt,
I saw this just felt like
that's what it was like.
It was just the truth.
And so me and I was so raw.
I came out fucking God.
Maybe,
maybe.
Or was it just felt like the
devil because he didn't want to,
didn't want to admit the truth.
Exactly.
That's what the badge that is,
bro.
I can always tell the people,
you can just see,
it's so interesting to watch how people,
like I was thinking
about this the other day,
how people basically as adults,
like I would call it to adulthood and
what they call maturity is the slow
acceptance of what you will never be.
That's kind of what it is.
So what happens is you so much things,
you see little girls
dressed like princesses,
right?
And and that's their ideal.
They grow up with these ideas.
We still,
we stick these ideals and children.
Like you're going to marry a prince and
he's going to be pimped prince charming
and that shit gets whittled away.
You start settling for
simulation and simulation.
It basically your life becomes,
I'll take what I can get until finally
you're dating some guy with on his ears
and a pot belly.
Well at least he pays a fucking bills,
which is when I like to get them.
By the way,
I like to get them when they're
just going through a divorce,
had their heartbroken to 300 times.
They're 40.
They work out way too much.
That anger and frustration is combined
into this fucking creates like a freaky
that I can really work with.
Hotel 39 year old.
Crazy wall.
Yes.
Look at my ass like work out all the time.
That's fantastic.
I like,
I'm old,
not even old old.
That's young for me.
So,
um,
you're coming down the hill,
you're totally naked.
You're high as a kite on mushrooms.
Do whatever.
Any point.
Realize like you starting to
sober up at any point in time.
Like what's,
what's happening as you're sobering up,
what was happening as I was sobering up
and because I'm such a freak because I
had read a lot about how when you
can be on a mountain in the summer,
winter storm can brew up,
right?
They can pick up,
you can get caught in hailstorms,
freeze to death actually sometimes,
you know?
And so,
uh,
I was like,
I got to get the phone
and I'd read about k two,
and I don't know if he ever
read about climbing k two.
It's one thing to climb Mount Everest.
It's quite another thing that can't climb.
K Two I believe there's only
one side of k two one can climb.
And for a while I believe in,
you can check this on fact
check one in four people,
uh,
wouldn't make it.
Uh,
uh,
on k two people died all the time
because people would make it.
Can you do fact check?
Cause I believe that was
the case for quite awhile.
She's cranky.
And so what happened was it was the holy
grail of mountains still is cause uh,
cause um,
what happens is storms whip
up really fucking fast.
Like really fast and a and you die.
Yeah.
So,
so what happened was I,
um,
I started thinking of storm might
whip up and I suck in the cold.
Whoa.
What does it say on fact check?
Um,
it's just talking about there was a,
there's been a bunch of disasters.
Oh,
a lot of people have died on Kaytoo.
You don't climb k,
two very few people.
Client.
When you meet a mountain
climber and they said,
I got to the top of k two that
dude is on the all star team.
Wow.
That's a very rare dude.
And you have to go through Pakistan,
I think on the Pakistan side.
Yeah.
No bodies and you,
you pass bodies all the time.
You know,
it's hilarious.
The United States just got word from
Afghanistan that if we go to war with
Pakistan,
Afghanistan is on Pax dead side.
What a surprise.
Out of all the fucking to
all the bullshit propaganda,
pretending that we're helping
those people were all,
come on,
we're on your side.
We're pride.
We're extracting minerals,
blah,
blah.
Taking heroin.
But we're here for you.
We're bribing fucking entire tribes
to have loyalty to like Kabul.
They're getting information on these guys.
You know the number one
method for these warlords?
No Viagra.
Oh,
that's right.
I read about that.
That's right.
Hey,
I know you,
I know you have all these loyalties
you want a hard on for a long time.
Oh,
of course.
Yeah.
Well these guys,
he's warlords.
They start hitting 50 and 60 and then
you're fucking hurt and goats all day.
You're tired,
man.
You can't take to those 20
wives that you've accumulated.
You got cocky when you were young.
When you're young,
you're young.
My blood is hot.
You could have 10 fucking wives,
but then when you're a 60 year old man,
you've got to fuck 10 of these bitches.
They started talking shit to him,
it's actually four in Islam,
you have to treat all of
them exactly the same.
So if they had four though and one
of them was getting all the deck,
that's I the other ones,
start complaining.
It's the craziest thing because
I've never met two women.
Two women,
like four women get along.
My friend cat watch.
When a girl girls were really good.
Here's the good news.
I'm marrying you.
Bad News.
We're all gonna share the same roof.
Fucking luck.
How are they doing it in
the Mormon communities?
All these crazy Mormon cults,
they don't.
It's always been very small subsets,
and if you look at who
those cult leaders are,
they're basically class Jeffrey's tops.
Again,
closet perverts,
sociopath,
pedophiles,
scumbags.
That Guy Warren Jeffs was a pedophile.
Totally right.
And that it is a sort
of part of the kinks,
right?
They always find out that
these guys are marrying,
these girls were like 14 and shit.
They keep finding that younger,
younger,
really nice guys.
Yeah.
It's just weird,
man.
A weird offshoot.
You know that it's just,
it's just so strange.
It's some people vibrate on a frequency
that low their bullshit detectors that
week that they get sucked into that kind
of a community perspective and context.
I mean,
when you get somebody who's young
and they've never been told anything
different,
you know,
we're just,
you look at children with people,
you're,
you are what you get.
What put what's put inside you.
You need,
you need.
That's why I always tell
young people fucking read,
but read the right things and what
you don't know it's going to hurt you.
You've got to read.
You just gotta you gotta.
Did you,
have you seen the Zike
guys to moving forward?
No,
I haven't either.
I haven't watched the whole thing,
but I watched a chunk of it.
People just constantly trying
to get me to see this thing.
It's one of those things where
people email me once a day,
dude,
have you seen Zike guys moving forward?
And I'm like,
Oh,
I saw the first Zeit geist and
although I thought it was very moving,
I also thought there was like,
there's this some stuff on
nine 11 that I was like,
this is,
you're just you,
you,
you know.
There was stuff about the twin towers,
like they couldn't have
possibly fallen like that.
And I'm like,
listen man,
this is not real science.
This is,
you don't know what the
fuck you're talking about.
This is the end to say this to state
that for sure that happened I think is
crazy.
Well,
you know,
here's the only way to find out,
build the same fucking thing.
I have another fucking plane fly into it.
Let's see if it falls down again.
If it does,
Ooh,
you just fucked up.
If you actually want a really
good a debunking of that.
Um,
popular mechanics got together a whole
bunch of mechanical engineering science
called debunking the nine one
one myths and they talk about,
for example,
how care,
um,
jet fuel burns at a certain
temperature and what,
and I believe it's 1600 degrees
iron melts at 900 degrees,
especially that kind of iron.
So it made sense that the iron would
start to melt and the building would
crumble.
But they had a whole bunch of different,
they actually took each and it's a really
interesting bullying that's annoying
when you read the arguments
against it because some of the,
the information that people
pull out is just flat out wrong.
Like they're talking about how there's
cuts to the beams and you want to say,
look folks,
they cut the beams when they needed to
break everything down because they were
clearing out the area.
There's a lot of photographs in that man.
You,
there's no evidence that they cut the
beams to bring the fucking building down
lanes.
A lot of,
a lot easier to believe that a group of,
of,
of young men who are fanatics said,
you know what?
Let's let's fly planes into a building
that seems more than some huge and
massive government
conspiracy.
Think how many people would have
to keep their mouth shut again,
something like that going not just that,
but that,
that's the only way of
building like that can fall.
I really don't think that they have,
uh,
a lot of data on what the fuck happens.
The skyscrapers and they get hit by giant.
She didn't say,
I didn't know you got your
degree in mechanical engineering,
my friend.
That's exactly,
every time I hear somebody,
people are full of medical advice as well.
I love this.
If you read a lot of stuff,
for example,
what,
what people will tell you there was a,
there's a good ted lecture by this,
a epidemiologist who's a scientist
and put actually does science,
does the science on,
for example,
when they said that up glass of red
wine a day can help you prevent breast
cancer.
The problem with that statement that
you read in the New York Times and
everywhere else is that the actual
experiment was they had cancer cells in a
petri dish.
They dropped red grape
extract onto the cancer cells.
Those cancer cells died.
You'd,
that doesn't mean,
yeah,
you don't is what it is a right,
right,
right.
But you don't,
that doesn't mean you infer
then that a glass of wine,
it's going to kill,
you know,
it's going to prevent
kinds of breast cancer by the way,
and cancer itself as an umbrella term
for essentially the irregular division of
cells,
all different kinds of cancer.
We don't know why some kick on
some happen when you're a child.
Others when you're an adult,
there are different theories about it.
Some are environmental summer genetic.
So you know,
and by the way,
when people say you got to
build your immune system,
then if you drink this,
it'll prevent cancer.
In fact,
uh,
I was reading that some,
some cancers don't actually grow as a
result of a stronger immune system because
they are,
they are aligned with your immune system.
When your immune system is strong for
whatever reason and cell start dividing in
a healthy way,
the unhealthy cells do as well.
So,
so,
so there are,
depending on the cancer,
which is why they use chemotherapy of
poisons your whole body and that's his off
the cancer cells right
before it kills off you.
That's right.
And you remember some,
some cancer intuitive to
the holistic approach.
There was like super healthy
Greens and stuff like that.
You want to be healthy.
I take all that stuff.
I do that.
But yeah,
I mean we don't forget what
western science has given us.
Look,
up until the 1970s,
late seventies,
I believe a testicular
cancer killed many young men.
When you had testicular cancer,
you were done.
Okay.
But because they came up with a
chemotherapy that ha that uses,
um,
yeah,
right.
That's probably,
that's what they used to do.
But you,
you had things called,
but there were,
there was,
um,
there's a platinum compound
in the chemotherapy.
It is,
it has made,
um,
testicular cancer,
highly curable.
Most,
almost always when you
get to stick a look,
cancer young men live
now budget they take,
they take chemo,
they're sick for a little bit and then
it just goes away and it's curative.
So you know,
you gotta be careful,
you're right with people,
have a lot of information and if you
actually start scratching the surface and
asking them questions,
it's like,
dude,
you don't,
where are you getting your information?
Do you know the genealogy of your idea?
Did you study?
Do you,
do you know what?
Too many people are just too quick to
just grab a hold of a yes or a no or this
side or that side.
And you've got to look at the whole thing.
You know the,
the only thing that puzzles me about
September 11th is that the sat that uh,
tower seven building,
and there's a lot of debate on that.
That's the one that the architects and
engineers from nine 11 truth have a
problem with.
They don't know why that building
collapse like that and it looks like a
controlled demolition.
That's really interesting.
I've seen a bunch of them.
It's,
it's very interesting because I'd never
seen a building fall into its base like
that.
Like give out in uniform and
come down a straight line.
But it doesn't mean that it can't happen.
Right.
It's gotta be real careful about that.
Yeah,
it looks like a controlled
demolition and you know,
you've hear that this Larry Silverstein
guy had all this money invested in it
and when the,
you know,
if the buildings went down,
he made billions of dollars and
you hear all this craziness online.
But the,
the real reality is,
again,
we don't know how a building like that
performs until something like that
happens.
You got to light it on fire.
You got to make big holes in it.
Yeah.
And the other thing is nobody ever
realizes that these are people,
right?
So if you look at,
like if you,
if you read like Bob Woodward's though,
are you looking at how like governments,
the CIA,
this defense intelligence and
the national security agency,
the White House,
if you,
if there's a crisis,
it's really interesting to see and if
you look at these memoirs now that are
coming up about,
about the Bush era,
it's really interesting to
see how they do arrive at,
at,
at conclusions and
decisions to take action.
It's fucking heated in those rooms.
And like human beings,
everybody's got a different point of view.
Everybody has their own group
of people they control and,
and it comes down ultimately to date.
Everybody presents their
case to the present,
biting their lip,
having testy arguments,
not talking to each other,
threatening to resign like
Condoleezza Rice did with,
with the Donald Rumsfeld cause she
just didn't get along with him.
She thought he was condescending,
et cetera.
And the president and
finally has to be like,
guys,
can you,
hey,
let's not stop fighting.
Stop it.
I'm the one who makes the decision,
ultimately present your idea to me.
Way Scarier is the idea that we actually
let a guy like Bush really be president
to me is way scarier than the idea that
there's some massive conspiracy amongst
globalist to control all the resources.
But my fact that a guy really could be
president and they really don't have it
locked down.
Totally.
It's true.
Like I know it's not pushing
to have a lot of wisdom.
He didn't have to,
he was there.
He's a puppet.
They obviously had Dick Cheney and Dick
Cheney was a guy who was the fucking CEO
of Halliburton,
uh,
a company that made untold billions of
dollars reconstruct and countries after
we blow them the fuck up.
It's not a coincidence at this guy would
be really fascinated with going to war.
I mean,
he owed own stock.
The president,
President Bush was a fucking
character on a sitcom for us.
Listen,
calm guy that spoke for us,
Condoleezza Rice had a huge
falling out with Dick Cheney and a huge,
huge arguments about the fact that
the guy believed in a extraordinary,
I think it's called
extraordinary rendition,
where we would kidnap people,
kidnap people,
and take them to undisclosed locations,
usually a country they didn't object
to torture and a and put them in these
detention cells,
the CIA prisons.
And she was like,
you can't just disappear
people you can't do that.
Can't you can't take somebody off the
streets of Italy and bring them to the
Turkey.
There's certain people
that have an unquestionable
character to certain people.
You hear him talk and you say,
that's a man of character.
That's amount of intelligence.
That's amount of experience.
Yeah.
Colin Powell is one of those people.
I hear that guy talk and I go,
that guy's legit.
That's the real also against the Iraq war.
Yes he was.
And he was like,
oh,
did anytime in uniform.
Yes.
And he was also,
you know,
disenchanted with the
entire administration and it
didn't really work out for
him.
And you know,
everybody was real excited when
he joined the Bush administration.
But you know,
there's a guide that really
is a real American hero.
He's the,
these,
the real fucking deal.
And he's with all these jackasses and
war criminals and fucking thieves and he
has to sit there and watch them pillage,
just pillage the world.
Those motherfuckers well
till too seriously.
But I think that it's worth
being serious about that.
You know,
it is,
but it isn't because it's
not helping anything.
No,
but,
but no,
like I have a joke about occupy Wall
Street and I totally support the movement,
but the joke is that those hippies
are just going to start living there.
Now what's going to happen
is you're going to go there,
everyone's just going to be shitting
all over the street and you just have to
just drive through that
all the way to work.
Hey Man,
will you doing is wrong man.
Well,
nothing ever changes ever.
And that's the thing I was talking to
Neil and Neil Brennan was telling kind of
like,
give me a hard time for not,
not.
Um,
I disagree with them.
On a lot of things.
But um,
he was,
he,
but I respect meal because he works very
hard at earning and opinion developing
an opinion.
We are,
we're on a bit,
I think we're on different
sides of the equation but,
but Neil,
Neil,
Neil was saying you should
be down there protesting.
And my problem with the protest movement,
the occupy Wall Street
movement is that I don't,
I don't know that that's the
only group to play there.
There are a lot of groups
to plan the government,
Wall Street,
irregular consumers that were buying
houses and knowing they couldn't afford
them.
Nobody ever talks about that.
And,
and,
and so there and so when
you occupy Wall Street,
what you're really talking
about Wall Street of course,
just a euphemism or just a kind of a name
for I very amorphous group of people.
Because what you're talking about
when you talk about Wall Street is the
investment community.
That's what you're talking about now.
Do you want to protest
the investment community?
If so,
let me ask some questions.
What aspect of the investment community,
cause I would remind everybody
they pay a lot in taxes.
They also produce a lot of wealth.
You wouldn't have startup companies
without venture capital for example.
You want to start taxing,
uh,
you know,
um,
the capital gains tax,
see what happens to your venture catalyst.
He's,
we'll see what happens to capital
that is invested in businesses.
So I don't know the answers.
These are complicated issues.
And you start following that
thread and start saying,
well,
let's occupy Wall Street.
Okay,
okay.
There are some unscrupulous
assholes and Wall Street.
There's no doubt.
But,
but what are we going to do about it?
I would,
I believe personally that you had an
incentive structure in place and incentive
structure and a system with holes in
it where smart people got together and
said,
hey,
you know what?
I got to tell you this.
There are some very big legal loopholes
here and we can make a lot of money.
You know,
why?
Because three other houses down the
way or making a shitload of money.
So what are we doing guys?
Cause we're not gonna be able to compete.
Here's another thing,
we may be out of a fucking
job if we don't do this.
So there were,
so when you're in that and
you start to realize it,
it's really an interesting
development where you go,
Gee,
what would I,
what would I do in that situation as well?
It was so,
it was so fucking murky and it seems to
me what you want to fix is the incentive
structure.
Do you want to fix,
you want to go back to two nuts and bolts,
nuts and bolts.
What are you producing?
What is the bottom line?
How do you produce wealth?
What does produce wealth in the past?
And,
and um,
she may have been making money off just
making money and moving money around,
passing risk along.
Remember,
remember even much bigger than the
actual size of the actual economy as he,
there's a bus of the derivatives,
right?
Yes.
And,
and,
and there's a very good
book that I'm about to read.
And I had two very big
bankers who are in this,
who were in this and had lived
through it and saw every bit,
every detail.
And they said,
the book to read is the
big short by Michael Lewis.
He wrote Liar's poker.
It's would like to read this
book called the big short,
really for anybody.
It'll explain the genesis and,
and this guy is,
and is not,
it doesn't have a grind to acts here.
He's,
uh,
he's,
he is a journalist who is a
outstanding FirstClass writer.
I read liar's poker.
He's a great writer.
I believe it's Michael Lewis is his name.
I might be wrong with the first name,
but the point is that
he wrote the big short,
and that is renowned,
that is,
that is widely respected as the book
and sort of the Bible on how the shit
happened and what happened.
And essentially who's to blame.
But you start going into that blame game.
It's really interesting.
It's really fucking interesting because
there are a lot of people and they're
not just republicans and
not just libertarians.
A lot of people can make a very strong
case for things like the equal lending,
housing lending act,
that the kinds of laws that
came out of government,
because it was very popular in the
Republican and democratic side to say,
Hey,
I'm going to pass legislation
that makes it easy for everyone.
Own a house.
That's the American way.
That's the American dream.
Uh,
they did a study that they that
listen to this really interesting.
The first,
the Federal Reserve Bank
of Boston did a study.
They found that even if
you're qualified for a loan,
if you're a minority,
if you're black or Latino,
and even if you're just as
qualified as a white person,
you're four times as
likely to be turned down,
turned down for that loan.
Okay?
So if you're black or you're Latino,
back in,
I think this was in 1996 or whatever,
I don't remember the date.
If you're black and Latino,
you have the
same credit as a white person.
You're still four times as likely
to be turned down for a loan.
Countrywide mortgage is all in the family.
Maybe you need it and
then everybody could,
but countrywide Morgan said,
fuck this.
Let's open a bunch of small offices
with minority people working in there.
Let's start giving loans to these people
if they had the same credit rating,
let's do that.
It's really interesting when you start
really listening to the shit and you're
like,
wow,
man,
this is,
this got this got fucking crazy
on top of the fact that Europe,
the rich countries,
we're buying our,
our mortgage back securities,
they were buying the housing
debt and so we could pass it on.
It's just so weird that people thought
that it was normal that you would buy a
house and then it would be worth
twice as much in two years.
That's what happened.
Like what happened to my house,
dude,
I,
everybody was telling me this dude,
I bought it for 500 I sold
it for a mill and I'm like,
what?
Yeah,
you,
you just made a half a million
dollars just like that.
How the fuck did you do that?
How's that happen?
How's that real?
My father,
who was a banker,
said,
my father looked at me and he goes,
uh,
not going to last because
I was to kind of buy it.
I was going to buy a piece of
property getting a real estate.
He goes,
you know anything about real estate?
And I go,
no.
He goes,
you're not how to make people laugh,
right?
I go,
yeah.
He goes,
stick to making people laugh
because you're going in real estate,
you will lose all your money,
all this route and well,
not only that,
right,
don't be cocky and think you can jump
into a game like that and not give it 100%
of your attention.
Like people saying they're
going to moonlight in MMA.
I'm going to have a couple
of fights on the side.
Good luck with the rest of your life.
Thinking out of that
shitty brain of yours,
cause someone's going wrap a fucking Shin
around your skull and you're not gonna
remember things too good after that.
And then the hardest,
I'm sorry,
but that is the hardest
way to earn a living.
So I walked up there,
I watch these guys fight and you know,
and I was watching,
I was watching baseball the other day.
I'm watching the world
series and you know,
baseball,
they're athletes,
they can hit a ball.
You know,
you've got to swing the bat perfectly.
You've got to throw,
you've got to feel the ball and it's,
you know,
there's a lot of skill
involved in baseball but,
but when it comes to fighting and you're
out there with gloves that are just
tiny and you and somebody else is trying
to knock your fucking head off and you
have to know how to kick punch and
Russell so much more difficult,
so much more as on lawn,
physically,
your,
your physical health,
your playing a game,
how much your courage or your mind,
you gotta stay loose but aggressive and
you're going to be exposed in front of
all these people.
You're gonna people are
gonna see you break,
what would you not,
you probably are not allowed
to even say this cause you,
you call the fights.
But if,
if you had to put,
I don't know if it's a fair question,
I was you about the stone and Anderson
Silva fight or are they gonna fight first
of all,
do we know?
Who knows?
I don't know.
I'm a,
Dana likes the fight.
It's a promotable fight for sure.
It's a very exciting fight.
Anderson kind of hesitant to fight him.
I don't believe so.
I believe his manager
has said some things,
but you know,
a lot of that is just a,
it's a,
it's a game.
You know,
you got to realize that promotion,
uh,
you know,
managing fighters and stuff,
there's a lot of publicity
involved and there's a lot of,
just keeping it in the
press is a good thing.
Saying the child doesn't
deserve it as a good thing.
Building up any sort of
animosity is a good thing.
And then sales people.
So yes,
she does deserve it.
Anderson's where he's
going to kick his ass.
Then you got,
you got a thread going,
man.
So you can't,
he can't be a rube.
You've got to look at
these things and go listen
and sores is a smart dude.
And Anderson Silva is a goddamn genius
and chill son and is the greatest
marketing mind that combat sports
has ever known by a long shot.
No one's funny than him.
No one wanted me to hear that in him.
He's a beast.
I watched him and I get depressed it,
I'm not helping what
he said to Brian Stann.
He said,
he is an American hero and he's going
to get a good old fashioned red,
white and blue ass kicking.
It was so great.
I saw,
I'm talking about the nuclear brothers.
He's on another level.
It's talking about the Nogueira brothers.
It's like they thought that's possible
that they thought it was a rocky
[inaudible] interview with a man.
He's,
he's saying give them a carrot.
I brought it up to him.
He goes,
that happened.
one of them pull this belt off
like he's going to take it home.
Come on little fella and
you know I'm white dude.
On top of that.
Then motherfucker could fight his ass off.
If he was just a shit talker,
I would still love him,
so I'd be lost.
Everything like Sean McCorkle has lost
a couple of times in the UFC and you
know,
or at least once in the o Sing Sha.
Sorry Sean for I said one,
but he's a great shit talker.
He's a hilarious shit talker.
I'm like,
I like to see the guy back just
to hear him talk some more shit.
You know,
Shell's son and talk shit.
Anybody funnier than I
am and I'm a comedian.
I'm like,
Hey,
this guy's got,
he's figured out how to finish guys
instead of just staying on top of guys and
punched him in the face.
You know,
you can win a fight like that,
but you know what else you can do.
You can lose a fight like that cause
the guy survives and catches you in a
submission when you're on top of a guy.
If you're a wrestler,
the kind of caliber of [inaudible]
and you're not going to get up,
man.
The only way you're going to get up as
he's going to make it subtle mistake it
probably late in the fight.
You know,
maybe he's trying to finish you
off and he gets cocky and you,
you get an under hook and
you get back up to your feet.
But for the most part a guy that can
keep you down and if he's got good
submissions,
fuck,
why would he have good submissions?
What?
Look at the elite level grappling he has.
All you have to do is just teach them
a few different positions and he'll be
elite in those positions as well.
And his triangle that he hit Brian Stann
with was a crusher dude because Brian
Stan was defending the right way.
The way to defend is called
like answering the phone,
you put your hand over your ear and
it relieves some of the pressure.
But chill,
squeeze is so fucking tight
that it didn't matter.
He did everything perfect.
He's he just positional a will,
Willa strong gorilla,
strong end,
mentally tough as fuck.
He's tough as fuck and has crack in the
past and it's tougher because of it.
How about that has quit in the past,
had,
has done things in the past that he's
not happy with and those things motivate
him in a fight and much
like George Saint Pierre,
I think losing and cracking under
pressure makes them more dangerous.
I really do.
When a guy's been humiliated a couple
of times and then he comes back and is a
fucking Badass.
There's a different level of
intensity that those guys have.
A guy's been humiliated
like a George Saint Pierre.
There's a,
there's an intensity that he brings to
the table where this is not going to
fucking happen again.
That's also on the menu on the
menu is I'm going to kick your ass.
I'm on.
On the menu is I'm going
to force you to fight my,
my fight,
but also on the [inaudible] menu is
that Matt Serra fight is not going to
fucking happen again.
Salesman caught by
Anderson and a triangle.
Paula filio caught him in an arm bar,
but he's a,
he's a better fighter than back then.
I don't know what's going on.
I don't know if its consistency,
intensity.
I know a lot of his strength resides in
his hair and they think sand delicious
here dude,
he's a,
he's a fucking most marketable guy ever.
He's a man.
He's just,
he should have his own right where you
can talk radio show when you're a man and
you're watching the guy,
you're like,
Aye.
He's definitely the silver
back and I'm a backbone.
I'll throw fruit from the tree
and he's entertaining as hell.
Man,
he said was saying,
Larry,
this is great.
I'm a big fan of that guy so
that's going to be a big fight.
The rematch,
those,
but Anderson right now is recovering
from a shoulder injury and that's tricky
man.
I mean they can take a long time.
I came to the last it depending on
the severity of Anderson's injury.
Cain Velasquez has been
out for a long time.
I mean he had to get surgery and
that's a good solid nine months.
It's a very complicated joint.
The shoulder.
I mean,
look at all the different moves that
the shoulder can do and think about how
loose the tissue has
to be inside of there.
And if something goes wrong,
if there's tears and soft tissue damage
or worse ligament rips and things that
need,
and you got to go back in there and stitch
everything up and put it together and
you know,
possibly even,
you know.
Yeah.
And possibly even have
more than one surgery.
Yeah.
I mean there's,
there's people that have
shoulder injuries and it's nine,
10 months.
Wow.
Yeah,
it's a long time.
So Kane still hasn't come back yet.
So he's his junior dos Santos fight is
his first fight back on Fox because he's
been out for Jesus.
It's been to,
it's got to be like a year.
He beat Brock Lesner over a year ago,
I believe.
I'm not,
I'm not exactly sure when the,
uh,
the fight took place.
He,
and my opinion is just,
he's the perfect size heavyweight
where he's not a giant guy,
so he doesn't require
all this amazing oxygen,
but he's still small.
So can move is always
that debate about what,
what's the perfect size?
Because when you got,
when you're to 60 you don't have the kind
of explosive speed with your punches.
He usually got a lot of weight in those
arms to when you fill up with blood man,
you lose the snap into the punches.
He's got great,
snapped his punches because
he's not muscle balance.
Right?
He's got a real athlete's body.
I mean his,
his body is exactly built that way
because of years of combat sports.
So it's built the exact way it needs to
be to perform at the level that he wants
to pour it.
And with him,
the big thing with that guy,
his volume,
he has the most ridiculous pace of any
heavyweight and they never seen a guy
with cardio.
His ability.
Yeah,
his cardios was insane.
It doesn't make any sense.
He's 240 pounds and Africa gives out
works Lightweights at the gym at Aka Aka
American Kickboxing Academy in San Jose.
One of the best gyms in the country,
filled with killers,
you know,
filled with John Fitch and
Josh Koscheck and Mike Switch.
And all these fucking animals up there
and this guy is outlasting them in in
conditioning drills.
That's unheard of.
You're talking about like a Josh
Thompson like well those kinds,
that's like an elite,
elite MMA athlete.
You know,
like as good a shape as you can get an as
athletic as you can get in and to have
this fucking freak heavyweight beating
them in,
in,
in exercise drills.
It's really kind of crazy.
Or at least getting close to them.
Heavyweights are traditionally way easier
to tire out and he just puts a pace on
these guys so you could see them
and just can't believe it's real.
They can't believe it's real.
Like a perfect example.
The Brock Lesnar fight was a good example.
That was a good example,
but there's been a couple of other
fights in earlier in his career where you
just see him hit guys with this pace.
I'm a big Ben Rothwell.
That's a perfect fight.
He hit Ben Rothwell with this
pace that was just ridiculous.
It was just ferocious.
Everything he did was perfect.
Every takedown was perfect.
Every side positioning was perfect.
Every Hammerfest was perfect
because he wasn't touch was perfect.
Yeah.
It just keeps going six feet,
six foot one and Sammy,
something like that.
It's not a giant guy.
Like I said,
he's only two 40.
Unbelievable.
He's not a,
he's not a,
might be a little,
it might be six foot one at the most.
I should,
I should actually look that up.
You can say,
uh,
he's Mexican,
you know his brown pride
tattooed on his chest.
Somebody.
That's how you know
he's a bad motherfucker.
I write ca and you in a yacht,
you know Google and it
says Cain Velasquez.
That's how you know you're
a bad mother fucker.
Okay.
Not even Canada or California are
castration or castration or cat cats
or cats.
That's what would come up.
Mine says catch.
I mean you guys,
I should just say it now.
I'm a cat free.
Six foot one six foot one two 44 perfect.
Size heavyweight.
Not,
not too big.
Not too small.
And if a guy like Brock
Lesnar can't out muscle you,
I'm so depressed.
I'm five 11 one 70 but you always say
this but you never do anything about it.
I lift weights,
dude.
Do you do heavyweights?
Like did you,
do you read Tim Ferriss's book?
Did you see all this to shut the shit
that he had about gaining weight?
Yeah,
but I really want to get bigger.
You wouldn't be as funny.
I know that's a problem.
I don't want to spend that much
time trying to like work on my body.
It's too embarrassing.
You would be just as funny.
That's ridiculous.
But I don't,
I don't want to spend somehow,
I don't want to spend a lot of time,
a lot of time trying to get big and
just swamp 10 pounds more muscular,
tired,
quick,
just embarrassing that
I don't get tired quick.
The real problem with the big muscles
is that you have to feed those bitches.
You don't realize what a
big difference it makes.
That's why like,
you know,
you look at the real elite UFC
athletes like Bj Penn and Nick Diaz,
they don't look like a darkness.
I was talking to him at
that premiere of warrior.
I was looking at Bj Penn,
I was like,
well,
you're about as threatening and a
buttoned down shirt as the ups guy.
You got those ears closed up.
I know what that means,
but I'm looking at him and go on,
I'm sorry I'm taller than you.
And frankly my shoulders are broader.
I,
that's all I was thinking the
whole time you're sizing them up.
People must do that to
Bj on a daily basis.
Nobody dummies.
He wants to have to talk to.
I just keep looking at him like,
I mean how were you one of the
baddest man on the planet yet?
He is,
oh,
he's an animal and then I met
Alistair Overeem who was white.
The opposite elsewhere.
Overeem is like someone
gave someone a super person pill.
I was going to say,
if you were a character in a comic book
and you know you found a pill was an
doctor,
laboratories are spinning
nail impersonator.
That's what he,
yeah.
Okay.
Adam Corolla would say about
women who are really hot,
female,
female impersonators.
He's a male male.
I was like looking at his back,
I was grabbing his arm.
I was basically doing everything
but making out with a guy.
I was like,
ah,
here's the thing about Alastar
know when since he's been that big,
no one's had to push him in an MMA fight.
You know his,
his fights that he's had while he's
been that big or really kickboxing,
he's done very well.
But I think there's something to that
size in kickbox and that's particularly
intimidating with the skill
of an ouster over him.
He's very good at covering up.
He has so much muscle and I think that
muscles also sorta like a padding.
It's like armor.
My friend Walter say that
when we were doing taekwondo,
he would say that muscles don't help
you learn that teach out of fight.
But where they do do no doubt
about it is offered protection.
He goes,
they protect you against
injuries and he goes in,
it's padding and you've
got to think of your,
if your body body's heavily muscled,
it's patty.
There's a certain point in time where
it's a point of diminishing returns.
But the question remains as to whether
Allister's hit that point of diminishing
returns because he's so
big and in kickboxing,
he's a fucking beast and he was a bad
motherfucker when he fought Alster or when
he fought on Brett Rogers.
But truth be told,
Brett Rogers is not at his level.
He's not nearly technical enough,
standing up to stand with
Allister and you're not going to,
he's not world class wrestler,
so he's not going to
take them on the ground.
He's basically a brawler who was in
there with one of the best precision
strikers in the world.
So that wasn't exhausting.
Allister,
Allister Allister's that
wrestling is not that good,
but he's got real good Jujitsu.
Wrestling is not good.
He's not,
he doesn't have the best takedown defense,
but it's good,
you know.
But the bottom line,
it says he's got a nasty guillotine choke.
He choked out.
Vito Belfort with it.
If he tore tapped,
yeah,
it caught [inaudible].
I mean that's how good.
He's a lot taller though.
Yeah.
Well back then he wasn't back then.
They were both fighting
around the same way.
Interesting.
Yeah,
he might have a eat some
good foods and you know,
got a lot of weight put on his body
and my friend people put 35 40 pounds.
Well he does work hard man.
His workouts are unbelievable.
There's,
there's videos of him online,
crazy dead lifts and all
this strength and shit.
But they're the true test of that.
Whether or not you could perform with
all that muscle on really is when you get
stuck under the bottom of
a guy like Brock Lesnar.
That's the true test.
You know,
because that big mother fucker will take
you down and he'll be on top of you and
you might be,
fuck son.
I think Bronx biggest challenge is
knowing how to a box with a guy like Cain
Valasquez cause that
takes forever to learn.
Well because king can wrestle.
See Cain is a nightmare
because cane can wrestle.
He started as an excellent wrestler.
So his technique is a wrestler too.
He's very technical.
Like even though he's like,
he does like a lot of shit.
Like he chains take downs,
does it in a way that
very few heavyweights do.
It's like the way he moves.
He's like the way a lighter weight guy
would wrestle and so brings this really
technical wrestling to it too.
So when Brock starts heaving
and hoeing just a little,
Kane's got under hook,
she's back up to his feet and boom and
cans all of a sudden kickbox with them,
lighten them up.
His,
his,
you know,
he's got the worst case
scenario for a guy like Brock.
He's got nasty standup,
knocked out Nogueira ridiculous flurry
the way that no one's able to do.
You know,
he's good man.
His standup as good
and he can take a shot.
He took two solid punches from
Czech Congo that dropped him.
Same kind of punches that knocked Pat
Barry unconscious and he took it right on.
The Chet dropped and then
he completes a takedown.
That's what's so sick
and amazing about it.
Cut like Frankie Edgar for example,
who is me right now,
the most impressive human being.
The fact that that guy can
take shots to the face.
There's a correlation
between both of them.
Neither one cut.
Wait.
I was going to say I was gonna.
I was gonna ask you about that
because when it seems to me,
if a fight's going to go three rounds,
it's one thing to cut weight.
When the fight's going to go five rounds,
cutting weight is,
is going to be a liability.
You know,
usually if the guy,
the other guy has not cut weight,
your,
your muscles and all those cells
are hydrated and you're not gonna,
you're not gonna get as tired.
So it's an interesting kind of,
well,
you know,
strategy,
they re uh,
they rehydrate with Ivs and it helps,
it's definitely better than the
way they used to do it guys.
The way they used to do it,
you started eating slowly and then
they would start slowly sipping water.
Yeah,
I know.
Try to get up in the middle of the night
and drink water and they would drink
water and pedialyte.
But now,
now that the smart way
to do it is with an ivy,
but there's been some studies
apparently that were done on soldiers.
Um,
and I need to get ahold of this.
My friend Dustin told me about it and
they were talking about how long it takes
to rehydrate your cerebral
spinal fluid and all that stuff.
And that is where it's scary because that
shit takes weeks when you get hit and
you're dehydrated.
Very bad for your brain,
very bad for your man.
You cannot take a shot nearly as well.
[inaudible] you're more likely to die.
What is gray Maynard?
Uh,
walk around.
That to me tells me he's a big guy.
Like one 90 or something.
I don't,
well I think he can probably get up to
one 90 of his eating whenever the fuck he
wants and power lifting and shit.
But he's most certainly
too big for one 55 I think.
I mean,
look,
he's a beast,
man.
Don't get me wrong.
If he catches you with,
with a big shot,
he'll put you away.
But I think he's so thick that,
you know,
for him it might be better if you're like
lifted last and just got just a little
bit more cardio into a system.
And I know he's got good cardio,
don't,
don't get me wrong,
but he doesn't have the same
cardio that a guy like Edgar does.
And I think one of the reasons for it
is a guy like Edgar has less body mass
period.
He has less,
less,
much small oxygen that has
to push through the muscles.
And I think again,
there's a point of diminishing returns.
Edgar is obviously not
as strong as as gray.
Maynard gray Maynard is
way stronger than him.
The way scarier a punch or two,
he can hurt you with like one of those
early punches that he hit and it with.
Holy Shit Dude,
his upper cut is nasty to Greg can punch,
but I think that's a mechanical thing,
man.
I think he would be able to punch
like a motherfucker no matter what.
I think he's just become a much better
boxer over the course of the time we've
seen him in the UFC.
I don't think him a
little bit of mass would would hurt that.
I really don't.
I think he would.
He would be,
you know,
I think he would benefit from just
having a little less mass on his body.
But this is just me talking shit.
If he knocked out Frankie
Edgar in the first round,
I'd be saying,
oh,
he improved and he came back and he's,
he's,
you know,
he's the best of the,
the division now.
And think about the thing about you UFC
now as these guys become better punchers
those little gloves becomes such
a liability for any kind of error.
You make any fucking mistake.
And you go out,
look at Eve Edwards,
he was a great fighter.
He was fighting really well.
But one shot to the jaw with those,
you're done the way eves went down.
Like a guy who has been knocked
out before though there's an,
I'm not saying that it wouldn't
have happened a long time.
Yeah.
I'm not saying that it
wouldn't have happened anyway
because it was an excellent
shot.
You know,
it could have put them out anyway.
But man,
it was disturbing how we went out
because I really like Eve Edwards.
He's a smart dude and he's a cool guy.
And he said very skilled guy too.
And you know,
it's been around for a long time.
You know it,
you spin around.
I watched him fight in the hook and shoot
days back when he fought Aaron Riley
and we were in,
we were in Pittsburgh together and
we were doing warrior and he was a,
he was,
it wasn't me and Nate Marquardt when we
were in my apartment and he was there,
we were all a little drunk.
And I start yapping off and I,
and I'm like,
you know,
well I don't know why you guys
don't just fucking go for a double.
I tag them that I'm just saying stupid
shit that he was trying to get his goat.
I'm like,
cause I know you're a boxer.
I know.
But then I was talking to us,
so my,
you want no part of my feet and my friend,
I'm doing all this shit.
He's like,
he's trying to say,
he's like really?
And they,
all of a sudden he grabs me and now he's
practicing moves on me as I'm trying to
fucking stay alive and on,
on the rug as he's
letting me choke them out.
He's like,
choke me and God,
I'm not gonna fucking choke you gods.
And he goes,
could try,
just try,
come on try.
Next thing I know,
I'm like,
I'm getting like twist it around.
It's so fun in a role with guys like that.
Just what they can do to you.
It's just fucking ridiculous.
So you just started training again though.
How long?
How many times?
Just once.
How many years off to Jeff years?
We had a weird situation.
How does Brian scared
the shit out of me when,
when he told me this,
this whole story is,
it's very disturbing.
Um,
you had a real,
real medical problem.
You,
I had,
I had a concussion and um,
I,
my hands for like three months felt
like I was holding a hot snowball and it
would come back all the time.
And I found out that,
that,
that is one of the case.
That's one of the effects of a severe
concussion because I had a 40 minute fight
with this guy named Pasqual,
this French guy,
and boom,
boom.
And Sini was watching and I,
and I,
it was at street sports
and I didn't want to lose,
I was like,
I'm not tapping in front of boom,
boom,
but how'd you get a concussion?
I think I didn't even,
you know,
when you're wrestling that hard,
you don't even realize you get,
you know,
you hit your head on the mat,
you've fallen,
you're doing all kinds
of crazy going crazy.
I just hit my head on the
mountain a drilled recently.
I was like,
whoa.
That was a hard one.
Yeah.
Head head injuries are no joke.
But you know,
I just,
uh,
and I'm back though.
I miss it.
So when you,
uh,
you didn't know what the injury was,
you couldn't pinpoint
that with brain tumor man?
Nobody.
I know,
but I mean,
when,
what had happened when we were rolling,
there's not one moment that
I don't remember any of it.
And I've been so,
you don't even know.
I've been knocked out.
I've been kicked in the head up and punt
I know wouldn't be being knocked out as
you know.
I know,
but um,
for this it was just,
I got,
I,
I guess,
I think what happened was at one point I,
I went,
I think I was standing and I came back
and hit my head on the mat and we just
kept,
you know,
who knows,
who knows.
You don't think about
what you're fighting.
Are we doing this?
Why are we as a grown man
while you're having this?
Because I still haven't let go
of the fact that I'm a pool is a
lack of some mole man.
Bill.
Like I want to be,
I want to,
I wish I had some small,
that's all I want.
Just a little,
give me a little fucking Simone.
I just want the hair and the dark skin.
No hair on my skin.
Good.
Look,
I can wear turquoise and be a bad ass.
Yeah.
I can't wear jewelry.
I looked like a fucking,
I look like a something that I tell
in who wears turquoise or jade.
Johnny Depp,
he gets away with all
that shit were awesome.
This something about when guys were like
large silver bracelets with big jade
ovals inside of them.
You're like,
okay dude,
what do you do?
You believe in channeling?
Oh,
is what I ask them like right away,
what's going on with you man?
He's spent some time with Sedona.
Exactly.
Do you know any healers?
Exactly why?
My ex wife's a healer.
I was in,
I went here,
I went to John Varvatos,
you know that,
that we're where it costs $1
million for a pair of shoes.
What does that,
it's a really cool clothing company
that actually loved their clothes,
actually look good in their clothes.
You know,
it makes them for guys who
were built exactly like me,
but it's like really
nice cashmere sweater,
shit you wear all the time.
That,
that it's like,
because guys have two criteria
when they dress right.
They don't want to look like a pussy
and they want to be comfortable.
That's it.
That's it for me.
I don't,
I'm not dressing,
I'm not wearing,
you know,
but,
um,
so I get in there and that dude,
that dude,
this guy is like just very phase,
just like,
hi,
how are you?
I'm like,
good.
He's like,
um,
well let's start.
I go,
I'm doing a one hour special for
showtime and I'm bullshitting.
I'm like,
you know,
I am by the way,
but I go,
I'm doing a special,
and I go,
um,
and I want to,
I need somebody,
I need to wear something on stage.
I don't know what I'm gonna wear.
We have some great stuff
and he brings me over at,
and before I know it,
I'm wearing like,
I got a vest on,
I gotta,
I got a fucking awesome fedora.
I got this,
he puts this,
this unbelievable,
this like chain around my,
I look,
I looked in the mirror and I was like,
I'm sorry,
but right now not to be a dick.
I'm the coolest looking
motherfucker on the planet.
This is,
this is,
I look them up.
I was so impressed with how good I look.
And I went,
I've never worn jewelry.
And he goes,
oh,
I mean if you don't wear jewelry
then all you're wearing his cloth.
That's our rule here.
I'm like,
well you have to wear jewelry.
Well it just looks,
I was surprised but then right.
But then I looked at him in the mirror
and I was looking at myself when I went
like this and I said
right in front of my goal.
Then again,
I do punch people for looking like,
you know,
you see guys who are like,
they walk in like,
you know intelligentsia coffee where they
charge you $6 for a cup of coffee and
their hair's just must,
just the right way.
They got a bracelet on this.
Awesome.
Don't hate the player Bro.
I hate the game cause that shit works.
It does.
We pull up in a late model Maserati,
you know you have a fine
[inaudible] that shit.
Reading,
reading,
perhaps the Wall Street Journal.
I want to keep up on.
The market's going to get my coffee.
Why me?
Yeah,
very successful financially when a man
typically not so much since the family
died in the fire,
I just can't find the right one.
If family died in the fire,
you don't introduce any tragedy until at
least the first couple of two or three
dates.
Got a biggest problem
when I'm not running,
not running orphanages.
I guess my biggest problem is what?
The sweat to spend all my money on.
You got to come off like a hippie pussy.
They don't,
you don't want that.
Don't talk to the orphanage.
She can.
She can find that out.
You're making grand plans.
You can't keep banging her for long.
You're at a one night pled.
If you want to keep a girl in the game,
you can't just make up orphanages.
I do.
I like,
I like the Oscars like
the Wall Street Journal.
That's good.
Yeah.
You've got to pretend like
you're a serious person.
I'm a man.
She's lost.
She's got a pair on fucking rent,
man.
It's hard.
It's hard out there.
You know she's not in,
she doesn't feel like a woman,
but yet she is who she is to just,
I just manage my investments.
I wear one of those book bags that
you could keep your dog in the back.
Have you seen those things
with the little book bags?
They met carrier dogs,
animals in the back.
Wouldn't you want it in the front?
So you dog nose bleed.
A little dogs are great chick magnets,
puppies.
But what's crazy about these book bags,
it's like if you look at the
reviews like on Amazon or whatever,
there's so many psychos that are like,
I could fit all three cats.
I love going to target
with my cats and my cat.
The reviews are hilarious.
Checking it on our podcast where somebody
was talking about walking their cat on
a leash.
Who was the,
maybe there's a guy that walks
his cat on a leash by my house.
Someone,
God,
I'm sorry.
Oh,
Someone on,
I believe,
I thought it was on our podcast was
talking about walking in cat and all that.
I might've said they had a
history teacher in college who uh,
who told me that his buddies dog,
his buddies lab had like
a litter of puppies.
Like get the fuck can we
do with these puppies.
There's like eight weeks they're weaned
and stuffs like nobody wanted puppies.
He's like,
fuck,
and they're like board
and go on to the beach.
And I was like,
I got to the,
so let me just feed the dogs.
And his buddy goes,
hold on,
I've got an idea.
It's like,
what do you mean?
He goes,
let's paint the puppies to
the peach and the guys like,
what do you mean being the fucking pub is?
He goes,
don't worry about it.
Next thing you know,
they got a box of puppies and they
have a sign that says rent a puppy and
they're renting puppies.
You can go take,
just take the puppy for an hour,
leave a credit card,
play with the puppy.
Of course everybody
wanted to fucking puppet.
They're like,
how much do I have the book?
But my buddies,
my history professor was like the girls,
the girls that ended up that everybody
ended up hooking up with were just
unbelievable.
You just surrounded by girls,
bring a bunch of puppies to
a fuck to the fucking beach.
Forget your gym.
You're working out for three
months trying to get your chest.
All right,
bullshit.
You don't have to work out.
Just show up with a bunch of puppies.
Girls will flock to you.
There you go,
ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you.
Rent a puppy.
Brian Collins,
a genius when it comes
to picking up chicks,
you don't really want to
up in the first place.
That's the problem.
Everybody is so starving to get laid.
Men are so starving.
The reason why there's so many bitches
pussies in the men department and this
world today is because of the commodity
of pussy is so goddamn powerful and it's
totally the,
the percentage of the market
devoted to pussy is like,
it's shit.
It's got to be like 40 or 50% of the
market is based on pussy acquiring it.
Right?
And pressing it
the,
when I,
when I think of the
conversations I've had,
the sincere conversations I've had with
girls just to get laid where my brow is
not.
And I'm like,
really?
That's amazing.
Say more stuff that we do when,
so tell me about this dream you had again.
Ooh,
wow.
And women to get angry at
us for this insincerity.
But this is what you have to understand.
Okay,
we're junkies and you're the dealer.
It's really that simple.
The Universe is set up fucked up because
we have the same bodies that we had
back when infant mortality rates
were through the fucking roof.
So you had the want to fuck all the
time so that you can have a reasonable
amount of people so that the
human race could survive.
You know,
it was really cool common like back
in the day for people to have 10 kids,
11 kids,
12 kids,
they just kids,
we're fucking dying,
man.
Kids didn't last.
Then people got crazy diseases and it
would wipe out entire villages and if
animals were eating
people on a regular basis,
you know,
so we have that same body and
we want to fuck all the time.
Our body has not reacted to the,
especially if you're athletic,
it's one thing if you're
unhealthy and if you,
if you're confined to a cubicle and
you know your body become sedentary,
you,
you'll lose a certain amount of that drive
as you get your 30s or forties but if
you're athletic,
if you're athletic person
and you have your personal,
just the wheel hard engineered
to like the hunt of it,
the same way,
you can't roll a ball of yarn in
front of a kitten if a girl walks by,
it doesn't even matter
if you want to fuck her.
If a girl walks by in high heels and a
bikini with a big ass and big floppy real
tits and she's hot and she looks at you,
you go,
oh,
you just have to find a reason why
you had to get out of the room.
Meanwhile,
we are in queer becoming increasingly
automated and computerized.
And so what happened?
Worse than that,
worse than that,
we are because they're changing.
Because the fact that pussy so powerful
men are doing a lot of shit that women
want them to,
right?
It's not normal.
But I would say that's
also because testosterone,
muscle aggression,
those things are becoming um,
uh,
tools.
We no longer need to survive.
Think about what it was like just
to get by and feed your family.
You had to work the
fucking land should split,
would bale hay catch around food,
all that shit.
That took a lot of weight.
And now what happens is you go to the
supermarket and you swipe your credit
card.
Okay,
so,
so it,
and I'm watching,
I was watching two shows in particular.
I watched Whitney and I
watched American horror story.
Okay.
I like American horror
story stories by the way.
It's scary,
but it has it.
He has an affair.
Oh,
crystal is my buddy.
But he has it.
He has a,
um,
a bad is fair on a Whitney.
I haven't,
I don't,
I mean,
I don't mind that it's a sitcoms,
actually not,
it's actually never lie to me.
Like this actually has terrible,
we go way back probably over a decade.
This thing's going to be gone.
I like the last topic,
honestly.
Like the laugh track.
It's my favorite part.
She's very pretty girl.
I personally really like
Whitney as personally I,
you know,
I'm biased,
but someone about those billboards
and made me feel like I was in a Coen
brothers movie.
I was like,
I think this is it.
I think this is the last piece of
evidence that life is a work of fiction.
It's like,
what the fuck is happening?
Just do not work for me anymore.
I can not do
that.
But if you locked into a good one,
if another Seinfeld,
I mean modern family's funny.
Yeah,
I heard that's very typical.
Sick on to backtrack studio audience
supposed to be pretty good at.
I was doing really well.
So that's what Chelsea's Chelsea handler.
This Whitney's as well.
She quit.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
It works her ass off.
Man.
That's crazy that she's got to show.
I'm happy for it,
man.
I love her.
I've known her forever and I knew her
back when she was doing open mics,
you know,
and she,
she worked her ass off man.
And you know what about,
we know what I love about Whitney Whitney.
He's always been fucking really
positive and really supportive.
That's awesome.
She's the girl.
Well,
I'd be on stage.
She'd be out there laughing her ass off.
Well,
you don't get that everybody.
How great.
I was successful.
You don't get that successful
without being positive.
It's impossible.
Positive person who worked
her ass off and guess what?
I read the pilot of Whitney and
and I was laughing and I was like,
she wrote it,
she wrote it.
Now you stopped blowing and stuff saying
it for a Sitcom and it might not be,
you know,
I'll just say it,
I'm saying,
but I'm proud of her.
I said,
thanks.
I think said it comes to
the point I was making this,
this is that w like Chris's character,
it looks at a girl and for
the whole episode she's
giving him a hard time and he
feels guilty and he can't admit that.
He was just looking at
for a girl and I was,
I was saying it like that.
I was like,
look,
the truth of the matter is we're fucking
genetically programmed to be that way
until they have an honest conversation
about about what that struggle is for a
guy,
then we're always going to die because
there's a struggle for a girl to,
it's a respect issue and that's why I
don't think that people looking at other
people while you're in a relationship
was cool while you're with someone,
it's,
it's the,
you know what you're doing.
You know,
when,
when a girl,
like I've seen girls do it to
dude's and it's very disturbing.
It's happened.
Especially,
it happens around a lot around fighters.
Like,
I'm not talking about that.
I'm just talking about when,
when it does happen,
instead of pretending it didn't,
or instead of saying that
I don't feel that way,
there is,
there is a dialogue to be had,
which is,
yeah.
You know what,
that's,
that's the way when you
get shit out in the open.
Yeah.
It takes the edge off.
It does,
but it's a disrespect
issue in the first place.
You shouldn't be doing it.
You shouldn't be staring at some chicks
ass when you're in front of your wife.
You know what the fuck it is.
Just you know it's,
it's easy to not do,
you know it's easy to take it
in for a second goat chase.
I surprised and then don't say it don't,
but don't fucking stair blatantly at some
chick because you're just doing it to
create conflict.
You're doing it to make that girl feel
bad and we've all seen guys do that.
Sure.
We've all seen guys do that.
Or it might even actually say something,
you know that makes everybody,
I'm so lucky I get the elbow to me like,
Hey Brian,
look at that girl's ass
like it's backwards for me.
What else we want to see before.
But again,
no,
his girl does.
She does lesbian motion,
like seating box.
That's fantastic.
Don't have kids where they
are but that's fantastic.
Well you never know.
You never know is riding on a grill.
Give up on her pussy.
They don't though.
They just take a break and then when the
40 they kick you out of the house and
move in with their horse trainer.
Yeah.
That's what's going to happen,
Bro.
They'll tell you a couple of years off,
you'll have kids with them and then when
they're like 20 the kids or be like 20
if you do it with your eyes wide open,
it might be a risk,
but fuck it.
Take it anyway and she's like,
got a pass and she's all fucked up,
but you liked her dater.
We'll see.
You might lose your house,
but fuck it.
You'll get another house.
I don't know if he necessarily
should be having children right now,
but I see your point.
There's no guarantee they'll guarantee,
well,
not only that,
people do evolve.
They do change.
He,
you can't judge everyone based
on their earliest fuck up.
We'd all be losing disaster.
Compassion.
Yeah.
There's some sort of a time in between
your fuck ups and who you are today that
we have to accept.
I don't know what that number is.
What a time machine.
I'd go back and just meet me when I was
23 and slap my face with an open hand.
Why would you do that?
But it's perfect.
What'd you've gotten through
is absolutely perfect.
You've gotten through
it all with humility.
It everyone's afraid of making those big
colossal mistakes because they somehow
know that define you.
I say they don't.
I say you're not your past.
I say your accumulation accumulation
of your experiences and what you've
observed and learned in groove from
your experiences and because of that you
know,
or how you've grown from your experiences.
Because of that,
you're better because
of all your fuck ups.
You should embrace them.
If you,
as long as you learn from your fuck ups,
you're better because of them.
I am unquestionably,
I would not change a single thing
about anything I've ever done ever.
I mean,
I definitely feel bad for,
I've ever hurt anyone's feelings
at any point in time in my life.
That's the number one thing.
If anything I ever regret,
it's like maybe I shouldn't
have been so mean to that dude.
Or maybe I shouldn't have yelled
at this check or maybe I shouldn't.
Maybe I should have like ate it before.
I was just taking a look at
where they're coming from.
Perspective.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Or you know,
instead of just said,
shut the fuck up.
I don't want to hear you.
You know,
those type of things but isn't,
that isn't on what I chose to do.
My regret is I didn't work
hard enough and some things,
you know,
really.
Yeah.
A little bit.
Well,
like,
I know what I don't know.
I don't know.
I don't think there should be because
you've had a very enjoyable life and yet
you have to realize is,
you know,
you,
there's a certain amount of
whimsy to your personality and to,
uh,
to what makes you a fun guy.
And part of what makes you a fun guy is
that you're never really truly satisfied
with your current position in life.
You know?
But that's an interesting point.
But like you like that,
and I've never had anybody
use the word whimsy.
That's a ran of whimsy.
I had a barrel chest.
Oh,
like think of yourself
on top of a fucking all day
long boat with a broad sword.
Whatever special is coming out in June.
My one hour special on the cover
of the DVD as me hold my eye.
They made my muscles really big.
I'm holding the Mike over man.
And two girls are clutching.
He's looking up at me and
I'm on a mountain top.
You fucking eyes.
That's what I want to be.
And there's a horse rearing off in
the distance and a hawk in the air.
I'm like,
that's,
that's what I want to be.
Yes,
it's true.
I've always wanted to be,
uh,
you know,
I've always wanted to be everybody.
Everything.
I'm not,
but you know,
in that sense,
I kind of like who I am at the same time,
that is who I am.
But it is who you,
why it's not true though.
It's not,
it's not a real need.
It's a whimsical fantastic is again,
it is.
If it is,
it's,
it's like he's like,
he's being silly about it all.
If you really truly wanted it,
you would do it.
It's like never take that motion
that you have as a father.
I see the devotion that you have for,
for your work.
When you're actually
concentrating on something,
when you actually want to do something,
you're very focused on doing it.
So it's kind of a fake.
It is.
It's almost an admiration for extreme
examples of certain individuals and how
inspiring.
Like you meet a guy like Alister overing.
You don't necessarily
want to get that big,
but God,
Dan was inspiring.
Oh,
grab his fund.
Giant Anaconda arm goes Gulf coast stuff.
David off coast you,
you're grabbing the guy's fucking arms.
You don't even know the guy.
You're grabbing his shoulders.
I was Scott,
who's out,
who's grabbing,
I'm putting [inaudible] and I was like,
wow.
I was asking him about Brock Brock.
I had to touch his body.
I was like,
well,
look at this guy who
made these people don't,
you know,
that's a,
it's an interesting fight thing else.
There's one of the best
fighters in the world,
but I think Brock is big as
fuck in a serious restaurant,
had a lot of respect for Brock.
He says,
you know,
he says he's not ready for the fight,
but I have a lot of respect for Brock.
He's a great fighter,
and I was like,
whoa.
He said that without cameras.
It was just the fact that you can just
go up to a guy like that and grab them,
shows you where you're coming from
because if you are weird in any way,
you wouldn't be able to get that off.
Now you can get that off because you're
trying to make it happen every 10
minutes.
I get,
same thing with mayhem.
I'm always like trying to
under hook them and he's like,
you're crazy to think that you would ever
want to do anything different because
whatever you've done has made you,
you,
I,
you know,
I'm sorry for anybody that
ever hurt their feelings,
but I'm so happy everything
turned out the way it,
I guess you're right,
man.
I never thought of that,
but I really liked that.
As I was thinking,
as you were talking,
I went,
I spent a lot of time
wishing I was somebody else.
That's why I'm an actor.
That's my,
I'm a comic,
and by the way,
that is who I am,
isn't it?
We don't want a guy who wishes he was,
who spends a lot of time
wishing it was somebody else.
That's my identity.
Every guy wants an undefeated record.
Okay,
but I'm telling you,
that shit ain't good for you.
You have to understand
what it's like to lose.
Of course,
you have to understand failure.
You have to,
you have to be able to look back in
your past at a moment where you fuck
something up and feel
uncomfortable about it,
and that should provide you with a certain
amount of humility and they're just
trying to understand it.
I think a man is,
is the product of what,
partially a large but
largely a product product of,
of how of the actions he chose
to take as a response to failure.
You know?
Yeah,
for sure.
I don't know how you learn
anything other than the hard way.
I don't,
you don't,
you don't
really look,
we're,
we're a strange animal that's
dealing with infinite variables.
And the only way to truly find a
focused way through this path is to have
accumulated a massive amount
of experiences and forged
positive information and
game plans from these experiences
and be able to move forward.
You cannot know it all
right away from the get go.
That's right.
You know,
just you,
all you can do is control how you,
how you respond to failure,
what you choose to do differently,
uh,
readjusting your approach.
And by the way,
although the one thing for me
is I've learned just to enjoy,
enjoy that and allow the frustration,
uh,
what,
how would you be able to make
fun of yourself when you fuck up?
How many,
so you guys can do that.
So huge.
There was a guy,
do you remember?
It's so big and you're great at it.
There.
There was a guy recently,
I say recently,
it was in,
within the last couple of years.
It was back when,
uh,
legends was at the,
the old bomb squad on Santa Monica
Boulevard where the two Jimmys to,
yeah.
Anyway,
this guy picked up a hooker.
I came back from Iraq,
picked up a hooker.
Turns out the hooker was a dude.
The guy had sucked this deck for,
I don't think I was a guy,
shot him.
Oh No.
Dump the body in an alleyway
and an alleyway like a movie.
So the cops apparently see
this guy dumped the body,
the high speed,
chase and sues.
They chased them all the
way up to the desert,
gets out of the car with
his gun suicide by cop.
They shoot him dash wow.
And all I'm thinking of
is this motherfucker,
if he could just make fun of himself,
would have the best story ever.
So true.
The idea of the stubble and
this guy did it really quiet.
Suddenly.
You don't know that story?
No.
Interesting.
Well,
if I may,
if you play,
can't believe,
I've never told you this story.
I can't believe you haven't eaten it.
And you might have,
I met,
I'm a club USA
in New York City.
How many years ago?
Oh,
I dunno.
20.
Whoa.
I don't know.
I'm,
I'm 63 now.
You know,
I've just had a lot of work done,
but,
um,
uh,
yeah,
I'm,
I'm a Ahmed USA.
I'm a young man and,
uh,
I'm dancing and,
with my buddy and I meet this,
I have a weakness for Latina girls,
right?
A little fatigue,
curvy.
I see this beautiful Latino girl.
She's got this black pony tail.
She's got,
she's got that debt,
caramel skin,
this cute little ass.
They're just getting hard.
And I know,
and this title,
stop touching.
She's dancing,
she's dancing,
she's dancing.
She's,
he said,
stop,
don't touch again.
Sorry.
She's dancing and she's dancing and she
locks eyes with me with the eyes of a
fighter.
I mean,
just looking at me and I'm like,
all right,
well that's my wife.
That's my wife right there.
I start dancing with her and
we would dance one moment.
She smells like fucking apricots.
I don't remember what smells like,
we're for the story.
She smells like fucking apricots.
And I'm just,
um,
does this,
uh,
we started making out and I mean Bob
slapping on the dance floor and you know,
sometimes
when you're that attracted,
everything else melts away.
You just see that one person.
I'm a little drunk and I'm
kissing her and romantic.
I mean deep.
Oh God.
So there are these booths,
there were these peak booths at Club USA
where you could go in and there was a
glass thing where other
people can watch you.
So I take this girl into the Pete booths
and I didn't give a fuck as a glass so
other people can watch and they
want to come into the booth.
They can watch.
But nobody took care of freaky 20.
No,
23.
I didn't do what the fuck.
I was like,
I'll take my,
I'm fucking fucking right here.
Condom shot off.
So I'm literally like,
I'm going to fuck this girl right
here in this club and you know,
so you cuff me,
go fuck yourself.
I was just in love.
I'm going to get hurt.
This is my girlfriend as well
as my girlfriend forever.
So I'm kissing and I'm making out.
And I'm feeling a bodies,
guys,
little dance.
I'm like,
these are smaller.
It doesn't matter.
That waste so hard enough.
The ask was on another level.
I,
yeah,
she had a beautiful ass and
I reached down and I go for,
well I grab a grab a branch,
I grab a fucking branch branch
that had been talked under and she,
he goes up and pulls my hand away and
I immediately realize that was a cop.
I've been,
I've been deep kissing,
deep kissing for two hours,
so I'm definitely a little gay.
I mean deep kissing and
I just grabbed the cock.
You ever thought or do you not
know about the cock and tight?
How did I not know,
dude?
Because she was,
she was taking hormones obviously.
Secondly,
she was already like,
had that skin,
Latino or Filipino,
whatever she was where she just
didn't have hair on her body.
She was petite.
He,
I keep saying she's such
a girl and you know,
but here's this here,
ready,
here's the,
here's why I'm a good guy.
Here's why I'm a really fucking nice guy.
Nope.
I,
I looked in her eyes.
She was so hurt his eyes.
He was so like,
he was just like,
please,
you know,
let this big and I'm such a fucking shit.
Oh,
I felt so bad that I go,
I go back in to kiss her,
I kiss her him for
another like two seconds,
three seconds.
When I go on the lips,
of course food.
You fuckers now listen.
Oh,
I'm not ready.
Ready,
ready?
I go,
I go like this.
oh.
I go,
oh fuck.
I have an old sir.
I have an ulcer in.
My stomach is killing me.
And she goes,
you do?
I go,
yes.
She goes,
do you have to go to the bathroom?
I go,
no,
no.
I just have to.
I have a very bad old sir.
Sometimes it just keeps,
so I want to protect her feelings.
I felt bad him.
His shit is and,
and that's how I got out
and I left and I never,
I did not come back to that quote.
I can't believe you went
back in and you gotta be,
I didn't want to be rude.
No,
wait a minute.
Wait,
a,
I would have been the person,
some person pretended to be a girl
and tricked you into kissing him.
Never even told you something that for
a lot of guys would make them violence.
I would've gave back for a lot of guys.
I know,
I know.
I would've been mad if,
if,
if this person [inaudible] guys,
it's an experience.
It's an experience.
Well okay for you.
But for a lot of guys it's an experience
that they don't want to have and
someone tricked them into doing it and
they could get violent and I don't,
I don't justify it.
But I'm saying a lot of guys
that would be the reaction.
The fact that you felt bad.
It's very strange.
He went back.
And then what are a poem?
Did you ever the tongue after that?
Uh,
I don't believe a kissed with tongue,
but if I tell the story again
I'll definitely use that.
I know.
Isn't it funny how Lego a
memory from that far back.
It's almost bullshit anyway cause
it's so like fragmented and odd.
It's like I can recite the facts
of a lot of details of my life,
but do it truly recall them.
And if I didn't have a language,
they wouldn't even exist in my memory.
But I'm tempted to tell you another story.
I can do it.
Yes,
yes,
please do this.
That was pulled.
Did I tell you that Jimmy Burke story?
Which one?
No,
a million Jimmy Burke stories.
The one where where we were both
together with two girls on my bed.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
All right,
that's good.
Okay,
so I had my best friend's thumb in my ass.
All right.
Uh,
but that's a whole different story,
Joe.
What you put your thumb?
No.
Did I tell him?
I'll say my thumb.
Let's be clear about it because we
refer to each other as best friends.
And I tell my thumb was never
anywhere near the punchline away,
but there's a very,
very good excuse for it.
Oh,
well,
should I tell him the podcast?
It's a little late because
you already gave away.
The punchline is if you can tell
the story somehow or another make it
entertaining.
Even though the punchline was already,
I used to have ice date,
I two girlfriends for a long time that
I had sex with 10 years after the fact.
They were just my two girls.
Loved them,
loved them.
I had texted those girls,
I,
you know that we dated in
college and then I dated them.
We want to add right after college
and and for the next 10 years,
maybe longer.
They were always a booty
call and I was kind of,
relationships are so strange,
so weird.
Even through their boyfriends to
girlfriends and we would always get crazy.
Paul,
how many,
how many girls like that have a guy like
that somewhere in their life where they
just have some arrangements
and they can always up places
dirty.
How can you tell?
What do you cause they're there.
They talk about him a lot because he's
still in their life because he's still
really important to them
because they had a long time.
I can always tell him,
whoa,
you're saying you could sniff
it if a girl's doing it to you?
You can tell.
I mean,
I know.
And it doesn't give you like
a nice green light though.
You're like,
okay,
yeah,
yeah.
You should be friends.
You're automatically goes to,
can assume that she's doing that.
Just horr rampage
was
that with this one girl,
right.
Sorry about the training,
but I was that with this one girl and she,
um,
hold on
one second is it's getting hot in here.
I'm going to continue the story.
I'm sorry for,
I'll go slower Joe.
So,
so she um,
she basically was,
uh,
she,
she was the girl.
Both of them were,
you know,
my girls for a long time.
They are down at a restaurant in
New York City called [inaudible],
which is a great restaurant by the way.
And I get a call from one of them,
which is essentially like,
Hey Brian,
it's such and such and such and such,
and we're hanging out and we
really wish you were here.
And we were talking about
you and we were talking,
telling dirty stories,
whatever they were saying and I,
I couldn't call back fast and I was like,
where are you?
Like where are the Il Buco I'm like,
I'll be there.
I'll be there now.
I mean I was literally like 20 minutes
away and I got down there and five
minutes I was,
I was at his hand at the capitol.
I drive faster drive factor.
I get there.
Long story short,
because I'm a team player,
I call my best friend Jimmy Burke.
I saw Jimmy,
that's it.
I called Jimmy Burke.
I say,
get down here.
That by the way is always the code for
fuck and there's something about to go
down and it always involves pussy.
Get down here.
He goes,
be right there guy.
He's there in two seconds
we'll drink and wine.
I'm fucking getting them all
applied up talking about it.
I could see the two of them,
the two girls are,
are,
are all over each other and I'm like,
Oh,
you want to use me as a bridge to
have an experience with each other.
How interesting.
My two old girlfriends who subsequently
asked me to have children with them,
by the way,
just to use my sperm,
which was very flattering,
but I had to say no.
But anyway,
so,
okay,
so I'm like that Jimmy Burke goes,
hey guys,
let's go back to my,
I call him the maestro.
He goes,
let's go back to my place.
Let's go back to my place.
I'll pull the fire,
got some weed,
I'll make some fucking
chocolate chip cookies.
How's that sound?
We'd fireplace chocolates or cookies.
They're like,
uh,
yeah.
Okay,
sounds good.
We get to the place,
he goes to the kitchen to get like to
start whipping up chocolate chip cookies.
He's bringing out some weed.
He goes to,
cause we bring brings out we'd,
it brings out a joint.
By that time,
I'm already naked on the bed with the,
with the girls.
I'm already naked and he's like,
what the fuck is this is?
And I'm like,
oh my God,
you no longer working my balls.
I'm like,
oh my look at you.
look at him.
I go to,
I go to Jamaica.
I'd rather be nowhere else
in the world right now,
brother.
This is the place to be.
This is the greatest
experience of my life.
Literally like I'm living a
porn right now and I love them.
They're both my girls.
So Jimmy's like,
well,
let me take my clothes off.
He takes it.
He looks like a red,
bumpy pickled.
By the way,
he's fucking hairless.
Got a piece on him and I'm like,
that's just not attractive to me,
but whatever.
So he's trying to get
this girl's pants down.
He's getting it.
He's trying to,
and he's got a tongue
literally that goes literally.
He could catch fucking flies.
He's like one of those frogs.
Like people don't know
what a entertaining dude,
this guy he's got.
No,
he's one of these guys.
Like there's certain people that it you,
you,
they go from cradle to the grave.
They never become famous.
And it's a national disaster.
It's a tragedy we call national tragic,
calm,
the national treasure.
He's the greatest.
He's hilarious.
He's incredible.
He's a Joey Diaz type character
is one of those dudes.
It's just fucking hilarious.
Like you're so happy.
You know him cause you're always laugh
when you're around him because he,
because he rides around
because it's Christmas time.
He goes,
come outside.
I go,
well he's driving down fucking 57th street
with a cowboy hat on of down fest in
the middle of winter
with no fucking pants on.
And I hear him go,
that goes with bowls of holiday.
Oh and this woman goes and
screams because he's driving,
standing up on the pedals and it's God
is going on 57th street in the middle of
the,
I used to,
I was like,
you're the craziest motherfucker.
He was three blocks away from his house.
There was a restaurant that we stopped.
I stopped going to,
I'm going to stop going to this restaurant
because the last time I went was with
you and Jimmy and the fucking waiter
kept interrupting Jimmy Stories with some
newer bullshit plate that they're bringing
over with some fucking description of
where the olives came from
and how the cheese is cured.
And Jimmy's telling some crazy
fucking post nine 11 horror story.
You know about like hearing the bodies
hit the ground and this motherfucker
comes over with a plate of cheese.
This cheese is a book too
from South America and it's,
it's a type of cheat to
see what that Yak milking.
Get the fuck out of here,
man.
Put the stuff down and
let's be done with this.
There's nobody who tells
better stories neck.
So entertaining.
It was just bums me out.
Well,
the,
that a guy like that sort of,
well,
you know what though?
He always says that he goes
to life is my tapestry.
He just has such a blast.
He does always makes it a good time
no matter where that fucking guys,
he's,
he's taken this girl's pants down.
He's trying to get as
taste frog tongue in there.
She's cheese trying to
go down the other girl.
So she's more than the
other girl as I'll Megan.
Oh yeah,
go on.
I'm like,
Oh,
is that my cock glare?
As you know,
I'm just a fucking,
I'm sorry to be graphic,
but the point is,
it was just a fucking craziness.
Okay.
So,
so he,
he's trying to get a sense and she stops.
She goes,
wait,
hold on.
I don't like this.
You guys need to,
you guys need to get,
do something together.
I,
I don't,
I don't like to say I
look at Jim and we'd go,
oh,
we don't do that.
I don't do that.
See,
I don't fuck around with guys
because it's not that I'm homophobic,
just not attracted to guys.
And I definitely have a hard on right now.
And so it was my buddy and there's
no fucking way that's bad enough.
We're about two feet away from each other.
I'm not doing anything with my buddy.
And this is the girl that
Jimmy was trying to eat out,
right?
Like in Jimmy,
No,
she wanted to really,
she was more into the girl she was into,
you know,
so,
um,
so she says,
so she says to Jimmy,
she goes,
and Jimmy could give a fuck.
He,
he,
he doesn't give a shit.
He's down to go.
And if he has to fuck me
in the ass to get to this,
he's going to,
he's like this.
I can see the look in his
eyes and he's fucking like,
let's go.
Let's go.
What the fuck do you need me to do?
I want you guys to make out
that we had done a play.
We wrote a sketch where we,
where we make guys,
Joe.
And I go,
no,
no.
I don't make out with guys.
It's disgusting.
Can't do.
I can't do it.
I had to do it.
There was,
you said you wrote a plate that you guys,
I wrote this player.
We can make out.
I can't,
I can't make out with doers.
But I did write this play where
I make out with every letter.
And it's unfortunate that
it had to be that way.
They had to make out with a guy.
But I mean that's just,
that's what I wrote that I wrote.
It's called kissing a boy.
But the point is this,
um,
skills,
one of my dick hard.
Why am I crying?
Okay,
let's call.
Why am I crying your wife?
Anyway,
so,
uh,
so before I can even do it,
Jimmy goes,
I'll fucking kiss him.
Good Kick Egos.
Get over here.
You fucking pussy.
I don't know Jada.
Oh Man.
He goes,
he pulls me away.
You happy?
She goes,
yeah,
oh it goes down.
And I'm like that.
So now I'm back to my girl,
I'm back to my girl and where we're locked
in and we're making out and all of a
sudden I feel the other girls,
I feel the other girl's ass hand
around my ass cause he feel good,
Brian.
I'm like,
I feel fucking good.
All of a sudden I feel like I'm not a,
I'm not an ass play guy
to be honest with you,
but I feel like my
finger go on and my mom,
my mom was so let you will,
if I can general chip you,
but,
and I'm looking at,
I'm going to sue a pickle up there,
you know what I mean?
So,
yeah.
So I'm like,
I'm like,
uh,
okay that,
oh well the book,
she goes,
I feel good.
I go,
Oh,
I guess,
oh,
you're a girl.
I wouldn't go,
well,
you know it went in Rome.
I'm like,
AH,
fuck off.
And I'm just so on.
And then,
and then I find,
then I feel what feels like
a greyhound bus in my ass.
You understand a greyhound
bus in my ass to which I go,
oh,
like that.
Exactly what I went,
oh like that.
And I turn around like this.
I'm stuck.
I all,
I can do this on my back.
I turned,
I go,
oh,
I like that.
And my buddy's got his thumb and my ass,
and he goes like this.
He goes,
you fucking pussy.
Oh,
you know what had me style.
Let me explain.
Let me explain why and how she said
the ham.
I'm not going to do any more.
I will fuck you,
but you have to stick
your finger in his ass.
Do you don't have the balls.
And Jimmy goes,
what?
I don't know.
Fuck the fuck you shut the fuck.
Yay.
She give a shit.
It's like,
hey guys,
I mean a little something here.
I understand wanting to get laid,
but the stick your finger
in my fucking house.
I go,
here's the problem.
I got to tell them otherwise we're gay.
I tell all your friends and
tell everyone in the world,
I sold a half a million
people on the podcast.
Hey,
you know what?
There it is.
I told,
I was told my friends in New York,
we told the story,
they went like this,
my buddy like German fat and they,
they,
they had their hands in their pocket.
They are listening.
They just went,
fuck this.
You wouldn't have talked to me
shaking their head in a bad mood.
Can I fly Jimmy out here?
Yeah.
Has Him on the podcast?
Yes.
Okay.
The next time
you do the podcast,
let's,
let's schedule it in like
three or four weeks from now,
somewhere before thanksgiving.
You come out to do the podcast.
We'll fly Jimmy out from New York.
If he can do it.
Great idea.
I'll put them up in a hotel.
The whole deal.
You stay out here for a few days.
Okay,
beautiful.
Perfect.
I remember the first time I met Calvin,
I was sucking his Dick and uh,
wait a minute.
But you were wearing a blonde,
right?
Don't you think it,
this shows me the gay enough
wage.
You want to,
what made you want to take it deeper?
It was these brain alpha
brain shit works son.
Hey,
I'm,
have you heard about Trey Parker
and Matt Stone being investigated by
Scientology for the last five years?
Have you heard of those?
For what?
No,
I haven't heard anything about it.
Yeah.
Well you know,
they made fun of the whole
Tony I believe is crap.
Yeah.
Has a really big article about it.
You know,
and in some way,
and this is,
this is going to sound weird because
I'm a huge south park fan and I,
I'm on their side 100% but there's
a thing about having a gang,
like the Scientologists behind you.
The must be pretty fucking bad ass.
I mean,
you think about it.
Look,
I don't,
I don't buy into any ideology.
I don't believe anything
that you can't show me.
I will entertain almost any offer
except religions made by science fiction
authors.
There's a certain,
and a certain point in
time I step away and I go,
wait,
what?
But it has a,
as a group and as a clan,
let's call them a clan of people.
Yeah.
I respect that.
They fucking stick together like that.
People love being in solidarity
with other groups of people,
whether it's occupied Wall Street,
whether it's,
you know,
I mean,
I respect people don't
respect is when people use,
um,
what,
when people use lawsuits,
abuse,
use litigious behavior to try it,
intimidate and,
and,
and
scare people from taking
a look at them and that,
that's what I am.
I don't know.
I don't know if that's what
they're doing inside and talk to,
well,
you know,
look,
Matt stone and Trey
Parker or they're too big.
You know what?
I know Scientology can shut down some,
some shitty writers or some,
some unknown people or some people that
haven't been established by the media,
but those guys have a voice.
You can't silence,
then you're just not going
to make it way worse.
You start picking on those guys,
make it way worse.
I know buddy.
Fuck you up like they do like
what are they doing to treasure?
Like what's this like?
Are they just pointing
magnets towards their house?
They're like,
you know,
I actually know a lot Scientologists
cause I took class at the
Beverly Hills Play House and uh,
for a while there,
there were a lot of them in it and some
of the teachers and one of the teachers
that I've said something really cool,
he goes,
somebody asks me if I was assigned to us
and he had been for 23 years and he had
a good answer.
He said,
have I taken classes there and gotten
immense benefit from some of them.
Yes.
Have I taken classes there
and got nothing out of them?
Yes.
He goes,
if that makes me a scientologist,
whatever has ra Elouan Hubbards dianetics
and different philosophies helped me a
great deal of my life in some ways.
Yeah.
And it was kind of a good answer.
He goes,
it's a,
that helps me a lot.
But when he did in creating his own
religion is used a lot of excellent
principals from a bunch of different
ideology takes responsibility for yourself
as a lot of it is good.
All the positive thinking and you know,
and there's something to be said for
his way of thinking about reprogramming
your psyche and reprogramming
your reward system,
attitude and belief and you know,
and,
and just just moving forward
in a positive direction.
Very strong,
very important aspects of life.
I think so 100% I think that w,
you know,
one of the things is just
looking at yourself and saying,
okay,
whatever happens,
you can always make an excuse.
Whatever happens,
I'm responsible for
every condition on him.
It's a better way to go through
your life even if you're not.
So what?
It doesn't matter.
Just move on to the carrots,
move off to get my shit.
What,
what the excuse is.
You can have the best cause Houston world.
The problem is the world goes,
I know.
That's terrible.
Next,
next.
Well,
some people just need an
ideology and that ideology works,
you know?
And I,
I like I had a next door
neighbor who was a scientologist.
It was a nice fucking guy.
They were really nice family.
I always enjoy talking to them.
I know a lot of them,
I've met a lot of them and,
and uh,
I've never had a problem with them.
But I absolutely agree with you when
it comes to them lawsuits and people
critiquing them or criticizing
them and them going after people,
you know,
I gotta let that shit go,
man.
That's probably,
you know,
they're bullies.
They're the powerful
few people in power who,
who,
who are doing these kinds of things.
It doesn't necessarily
mean that everybody,
you know,
it's not,
it's not an indictment by the,
you know,
by a few.
Right,
right.
Well,
you know,
I don't know.
I don't know the real numbers,
but it is a fascinating thing to me that,
that it is possible to
do something like that.
But it also is very Coen brothers ask,
you know,
it's also very much like another piece
of evidence appointment to the idea that
the entire world that we
live in is a work of fiction.
It's not real.
It's a part of my imagination
because otherwise,
why would this really exist?
Why would actress be so vapid?
I mean,
if you ever met actors when you,
you're on the senior working with
them and you'd go into and go,
this isn't even real.
There's no you guys,
you went too far.
This is not believable.
What Daniel Day Lewis,
there's a great interview where he said,
Dan Daly was said the funniest thing
because I think he's an incredible actor,
right?
So I started like kind of like
researching them and stuff.
I just,
he's amazing.
We've talked about on the podcast,
so a thousand times he said,
you know,
you guys want to know about my process.
He said,
you know,
I stuck flowers at my jacket,
did cartwheels.
It wouldn't really matter.
The bottom line is this.
I sit around all day wearing
somebody else's clothing,
having somebody else's thoughts,
saying somebody else's words and trying
to believe all of it basically because I
am at heart,
a boring Middleclass Englishman,
I think he said because I'm ashamed of
being basically a boring middle classes.
It was a great answer because he just,
he,
he looked at the absurdity Christian Bale.
They were like,
why do you lose weight so much since then?
He goes,
because I'm a man and I put makeup on
and I make believe for a living and I got
to make it.
I gotta make it feel like real work,
you know?
I got it so I can close to
dying when he did the machine.
That's ridiculous.
I've never seen a
transformation like that.
You know,
a lot of people like were,
I remember back in the day when
people were first starting to do that,
Robert Deniro was one of the first guys
to put on weight for a movie for raging
bull and I was like,
wow,
he really got fat for that movie.
Like that's crazy.
And I read about his diet.
It was just eating like a regular Italian,
just fucking meatballs and Pasta all day.
And um,
you know,
and everybody was like,
wow,
that's amazing.
But with Christian Bale did
was a thousand times harder.
He literally almost
starved himself to death.
Credible.
That guy is fucking incredible.
Yeah.
It's like,
you remember that that below out when
he was on were they kept playing in our
radio stations where he was
yelling at some guy on the set.
It's cause it kind of
sets a fucking idiot.
He's right.
If you're operating on that level of
frequency where you need to really believe
that you're in this scene and
some asshole keeps walking around,
tweaking things in,
in,
in your,
in your line of sight.
But that's not supposed to be there.
It's maddening.
And everybody knows that one pastory
motherfucker that you can work with the
whole fucking anywhere his
face for the rest of his life.
But it's hilarious that
they released that.
They're,
they're released that and look,
yeah,
he was going crazy.
But one of the things what he was saying,
it's you,
you're not fucking professional.
He goes,
you're a nice guy.
You're a nice guy,
but you're not fucking professional man.
He's right.
You know,
you,
you reach a certain level of intensity,
emotional intensity.
When you do a role like that.
Again,
I'm just totally talking out of my ass.
I was just as a zookeeper,
I was at a child or your various,
my big,
my big park.
But there's a certain intensity
that you reach when you're,
you're putting yourself into a part
like that and you see some guy walking
around in the background,
tweaking the fucking lights
right in front of your eyes.
Like,
come on dude.
Really?
I could the fuck are you doing Bob?
Put the lights down.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Yeah.
If you're trying to be great,
what he's trying to do is that
somebody is fucking buzzing around.
You can understand it,
but we allow them to
do like a Batman movie.
You're allowed to do those piece of shit
when it was needed to make that money.
Son,
I'm going to come back and
do something else crazy.
He's fucking amazing.
So this is only a few of those guys.
You know,
there's a few of those Russell Crowe's
out there that really become a different
guy.
You're like Russell Crowe and the insider,
so one of my favorite movies because
movie scary fucking movie man.
When you find out how much
of it is based on reality,
how terrifying it is,
how much power that
tobacco companies have,
and that's sort of like what's going on.
My thoughts about this whole
occupy Wall Street thing,
when you look at banks and hedge fund
companies and all these is this corruption
and the financial situation
that we have right now.
You look at it and you're like,
man,
these people have been getting
away with so much for so long.
It's like telling them that
everything has to be fair now.
They're like,
fuck you.
Like I made him get into this.
To be fair,
I got into this because I met my friend
Tim at school and he was two years ahead
of me and he brought me out in a limo
with coke and hookers and they said,
listen bro,
we're trading stocks
were shortened things.
We're making millions.
We got this fucking town
wired and you're like,
mmm,
I want in.
And then you'll all get
together in the 80s,
Gordon Gekko style and start
fucking raping the financial system.
That's why the day in the first place,
they're there to make
as fuck tons of money through
every possible loophole.
Did you read about one of the CEO's wives,
um,
who uh,
got some of the government bailout
money to start a new business like $250
million in loans from some fucking guy.
He's got like billions of dollars.
It's amazing.
His wife,
he had his wife do a twosome snazzy
loophole that they engineered into the
system.
You start to feel invincible on it.
So amazing.
Well,
look,
when the old,
the president,
the United States,
when you know how much they own shit,
when the president of
the United States says,
ladies and gentlemen,
poor suffering people of our country,
I am going to take billions of dollars
of your tax money and I'm going to give
it to these cunts that ruined these banks.
And I'm real sorry about this.
But they get bonuses and their bonuses
are going to be roughly half of what
you're going to make in your entire life.
It's going to be a half a
million dollars is what?
We're going to put a cap on it.
That's the cap he was trying to put on it.
It was like when to put a half a million
dollar cap that's there's no buddy.
Your bank is done.
You can't give a bonus
if there's no money.
You don't have a bank anymore.
The reason why you have a big is cause
you took our fucking taxes and you throw
it back into your system and
now everything's spinning
and you want to shit out.
Bonuses.
What kind of contract do you have where
you have a bonus when the bank breaks,
right.
It literally breaks.
I will say it,
but how old?
I mean what,
what message are they telling us?
When the president tells all the
poor people of this country with the
middleclass is falling apart.
Poverty is an all time level high.
Exactly four 47% of all of Detroit.
You're literate.
I mean literally the infrastructure,
everything's falling apart and he's like,
I'm going to limit it to
a half a million dollars.
Like,
but first of all,
first of all,
you can't,
you can't eliminate it.
Thing on.
The other thing is that,
the other thing is that,
um,
I think at the end of the day,
the,
the um,
I went to occupy Los Angeles last night.
What do you mean you can't limit anything?
Well,
well,
w w well,
the,
when you,
what,
what banks will say is
when you give that money,
when you give that tarp money to a bank
and they're going to use it for various
things there,
they're using it to
operate their business,
to keep their business afloat.
And the PR,
the biggest problem was that these banks
came to that to someone like Obama.
Well,
actually not to Obama and Bush,
he's the fucking president.
He goes to them and says,
listen,
no bonuses.
You fuck you still wait.
He's not allowed to
get away with it.
In other words,
[inaudible] who is the fucking president?
Know what I'm saying?
Was running shit.
That's tells you the banks.
Yeah.
The Bay from the banks were too big to
fail and that's the biggest problem.
When you have a bag that's a
philosophy esophageal it maybe,
but when you have a bank,
when you have,
when you have a situation where most
economists are saying that the president
look,
the central nervous system of this
economy is going to collapse if you don't,
I'm not saying this is good.
I understand the arguments for the bail.
His problem is that these fucking,
these banks weren't dealing
with their own money there.
We did.
They were taking risks with your money.
That is a huge problem
and it is a huge problem,
but that's not my point.
My point is that you have
these giant bail them out
and they were still giving them bonuses.
Exactly.
Doling out bonuses,
how blatant it is.
The way they justified it was this.
They said,
if we don't give bonuses and those guys
will go to other corporations and we'll
go under suck my cock.
I will say that the banks have
paid back all that money though,
which is pretty impressive.
That is pretty crazy.
It just shows you how quickly
they've been stealing left and right.
Good deal.
Good government made a
lot of interest on that.
So every bank has paid back.
The money has been paid back and
they made a lot of interests.
So why is the economy fixed?
The economy is not fixed.
I think primarily because it was fake.
No,
I think that I think that the U S is
having to compete with China and India and
a lot of other countries and we are truly
becoming a global economy and I don't
think in a lot of ways to u
s has gotten ready for that,
but we're not making anything
other than Corvettes.
What else do we make this about?
As we made Corvettes and catalogs still
our economy actually still is run on
ideas.
Although I have a Mustang,
I have to say it's pretty fucking bad ass.
Do you us the US exports ideas.
The U s is an ideal kind of economy
and that's good thing to be.
We remember it most.
Most innovation by leaving shot comes out
of the United States in the Mustang is
an idea.
I have a gt 500 it's paper.
It's a stupid car.
It's got a manual transmission
with a cue ball for a shifter.
It's got a 540 horsepower engine.
Oh my tires slide all over the place.
Whenever you hit the gas tile tire
slide in second year all the time.
It's a ridiculous car,
but it's fun as fuck and
it's it truly American car,
like you hear it,
the engine,
the ridiculousness of excessive nature,
all of it and the end,
the fun of it.
It's got a lot of low end torque.
You know,
you hit that low end torque on a big
fucking eight with a supercharger and hear
the whine.
The U s exports,
a lot of of ideas there.
I'd and fun.
They're culture is fun.
Rock and roll is not the only reason why
our culture is fucked up or rather our
financial systems fucked up.
It's fucked up because of corruption
and greed and what you said earlier,
which I always say as well,
it should be real clear.
One piece of gold eagles,
one donkey.
That's my standard way of when you start
getting into derivatives and shorting
and gambling.
I mean what does that is the Vegas,
you're,
you're going Vegas,
gambling.
But then there's also but there is room,
there is room to levers,
there is room for borrowing,
borrowing and credit.
Yes but why is there room for things
like derivatives and shorting and why are
they allow
relatives and stuff?
What back when it was working a lot of
those derivatives and things like that
allowed people well allow people,
allow people to minimize risk so that
banks would lend money cause they could
minimize risk was distributed and and
as long as that was self contained,
they drew it know,
put a lot of,
put a lot of our wealth
back into the system.
I think what happened ultimately was
a lot of economists and historians are
starting to talk about this was also
a function of the rise the east.
It was also a function of the fact
that other countries were buying and
investing in the US housing market.
Think about it.
If you have big,
big central banks who are saying,
we want to buy your housing debt,
what happens?
That means I can bundle bundle
mortgages and sell them at a profit.
Guess what?
It makes it a lot cheaper now.
Now when people get a mortgage,
it's worth something.
Of course I'm going to lend
you a mortgage for no money.
I can make money on the mortgage,
I can serve with Germany,
and a lot of it was that a lot
of it was people in this country,
a lot of whom you and I know who said,
I'm going to start treating my
house like it's a commodity.
Not,
not like it's a place to live,
but rather a plate,
a way to make money,
and that was pretty fucking rampant.
So a lot of this was human overreaction
to a new set of rules to a new world
and just fucking human nature,
human nature.
When they find holes in the system,
the Brian's,
you were saying that you
went to occupy Wall Street.
What was that?
Yeah,
it was.
It was exactly what I
thought I was going to be.
What was crazy is that I,
I have these combat boots,
like these,
those a safari combat boots.
I bought it at a surplus store.
So I did they think you are a government
decided to wear them because of that
reason?
Really the,
I don't know,
just for fun government issue boots.
So I would think that you're a bad guy.
Yeah.
Just to see what would happen.
And uh,
so I parked and amazingly I got a parking
spot right across the street from it.
Yeah.
None of them have cars.
Yeah,
no,
no.
It was like this cop car pulled
out right when I got there.
And so like all these people were kind of,
you know,
like boards sitting on the line staring
at me so I could come up in her is like
people getting their tits
painted and I'm like,
this is awesome.
Good.
Yeah,
that's good.
And then immediately I pull out my phone
and this guy comes up right up to me
and goes,
hey man,
can I have a cigarette?
Like right in my face?
Like,
like,
uh,
he looked like Charles
Manson and I was like,
Oh shit.
This is a yeah,
sure.
Got,
get out of my face,
you know,
and then I keep on walking.
I'm looking at my phone now,
I'm kind of freaking out a little
because I'm by myself and it's,
it is a little,
I mean,
I don't know if you've ever
been downtown Los Angeles,
it's kind of scary down.
Yeah.
We've come a lot of fear
factor episodes down there.
Yeah.
So there was kind of like this
element around that area that's like,
hey,
there's a new apartment complex opening
up for the homeless people type thing.
You know,
it was,
cause it was like a village.
They had,
first day they had libraries,
they had a,
you know,
they had donate,
there's donations coming in that feed
like this whole entire like block,
uh,
you know,
of the State Capitol building or whatever.
Right.
And,
uh,
then this other guy kind of staring
at me and he comes up to me and goes,
hey man,
can you check the score for me?
And I'm like a square for wet.
And he goes,
Pittsburgh.
And I'm like,
uh,
I have no idea what he's talking about.
Like,
I'm like,
ah,
so he's asking you check it on your phone.
Yeah.
You're asking people
to Google shit for it.
Can I get a cigarette's not good enough.
Now can Google me the score.
I have a cell phone and the whole
time he's like staring my phone down.
So I think maybe some high government
issued boots and it was like trying to
figure out,
cause I had like a shaved head,
like a military haircut.
Oh.
And wearing the coat from
taxi driver or whatever.
You know,
obviously we had Kevin Pereira from attack
of the show on here the other day and
we were talking about agent provocateurs,
government people who were sent in to
break up calm protests and turn them into
violent protests.
They can bring him in fucking arrest her.
But it's common tactic.
It's smart.
Really.
They get tired.
All these fucking hippies in their banjos.
So this guy's kind of
frequently to look out for them.
Uh,
I've been impressed with how,
um,
when I hear the occupy Wall Street people,
a lot of them are people who are actually
educated w who just can't find a job.
Yeah.
And I'm trying to find the answer in the
case as much as I thought it wouldn't
be.
This was mostly,
by the way,
we're not in Wall Street.
No,
it doesn't really have a financial,
I mean it's just a small
financial district,
but it smelled like,
I don't even know where he would
occupy downtown law by Los Angeles.
He's got clothing companies
and the government buildings.
So this guy is like
kind of freaking me out.
Like it's like checking me up
and down and stuff like that.
And I'm like,
all right,
this is kind of sad.
You get for trolling.
I fuck.
I know,
I know.
But then my friend who's running like the,
the live stream and all the media
coverage of the whole place,
he called me over and
so kind of rescue me.
And so I go through was like my friend,
see,
hang,
he's a c hung on a Twitter.
Uh,
so,
uh,
there was a rap battle going on up on
stage because there's entertainment
throughout the day.
There's speakers,
there's like local musicians and comics,
you know,
like Jeffrey Ross,
Jeff,
yeah.
And so,
uh,
it was fine.
I sat there and watched this
rap concert for why were they,
people are handing off the mic and this
homeless guy was like looking guy with
like balancing like pop cans
on his head while rapping.
I was like,
wow,
you don't see this everyday.
You know.
So it was like the entertainment value,
it's pretty sweet.
Smelled like boo though like crazy.
And then they took me through the
media event where they do all the live
interviews and all the media stuff
and it's all like generators and solar
collectors.
And then there's tons of computers and
then there's this girl is just out of
nowhere comes up to my
friends see and was like,
Hey,
I want to donate these laptops
and gave him like three laptops.
And I was like,
wow,
this is really bad ass.
I need to start occupying Burbank
outside of best buy or something,
you know,
and get some shit.
Uh Oh Brian,
silly.
But then they took me through the
whole thing and there was like drums,
drum circles.
There was like it,
it seemed pretty cool.
And I guess that I've never
seen a good drum circle.
Never been there.
Well I fucked this.
Is this PLO drums and if anything it
seems like the more I walked around I,
I did see like the people trying
to sit down and come up with,
with solutions and ideas.
So you did see the good part of what's,
but the majority of it was just like,
it looked like a bunch of deadheads.
I don't think there's
anything wrong with that.
I think that's just going to be the
case no matter what with any sort of a
movement.
But this was a very exciting time,
man.
There's never been a time where this
many people have got together and had a
peaceful demonstration.
It was pooping in a shit.
Shitting in the street is
not exactly a peaceful,
he's a little bit of
violence involved in that.
But you know the,
they're shitting all
over the fucking street.
You go anywhere near Wall Street.
Yeah,
the shitting.
Oh God.
It smells like human shit everywhere.
I felt like such an ass,
cause I had a tin can and there was this,
there's three different
colors of trash cans.
Like the green trash.
It's black and the blue.
Oh,
I'm sitting here going,
which one is it?
Green is green as grass blue.
What's blue?
That's waiting.
It's like water bottles.
And this is a can is a black.
I just throw it.
So I'm like trying to figure it coated.
They didn't have
like,
it didn't save her.
It was a green trashcan of blue.
Oh,
that's ridiculous.
I think it's supposed to be.
You're supposed to know the colors.
Human Shit still bothering.
Yeah,
they shit everywhere man.
Well they have to,
you know,
there's a lot of people sleeping there,
but people have their
kids there and everything.
Port-A-Potties this is,
yeah.
Then sometimes
they can't.
Okay.
But this again,
we're talking about the Los Angeles.
Los Angeles one is a different animal
than the write up one New York one man,
the videos in New York one
is there really a shocking,
and here's what's really crazy.
The Wall Street,
uh,
has a,
not only have they donated four
point $6 million to the police,
but they also started hiring the police.
It's something that
most people don't know.
You can hire a police officer
for roughly $37 an hour.
So all of these Wall Street firms are
hiring tons of cops off duty cops to do,
uh,
you know,
paid work there.
And they work as a police officer with
a real badge and a real gun and the real
ability ability to arrest.
But they're working for the bank.
So the,
they,
it's a,
it's a loophole where
these are police officers,
but they are doing the
bidding of the bank.
They are doing that.
They're working for the bank.
They're not like the bank says,
Hey,
uh,
police officers,
can you organize your own police
presence around this area?
And,
you know,
put as many police officers you see fit
and I guess you guys work for the state
and you know,
maybe we'll,
uh,
we'll,
we'll throw in a picnic for ya and we'll
help generate some money to pay for all
this extra revenue that's going to cost.
They're paying,
but
they're paying the cops so
they tell the cops where to go.
I didn't know it.
It's,
it's fucking crazy.
I was legal.
It's,
yes,
you should think it shouldn't be,
but it was a I,
I think a Koch Mayor
Koch came up with that.
I think it was in the
90s that they had that.
Yeah,
I think the biggest,
you know,
and people have always had it.
I think the biggest threat facing all
of us is as far as this whole situation
talking about this,
I think the real enemy is that we are
slowly or maybe very quickly losing our
representative government.
And what I mean by that is that this,
this government and James
Madison warned warned about this.
He said,
the one thing you have to be careful
of in a democracy like this is special
interests because,
because the constitution says you are
allowed to petition your government,
that's a constitutional right.
It should be a constitutional right.
The problem is that our country now
is being run by small bands of very
energetic,
well-financed fanatics.
And,
and when you are a representative
in the House of Representatives,
if you are a congressman,
if you are even a senator,
but especially in Congress,
you don't do a goddamn thing unless
you check what that lobby and checking
unless you check with the people that
finance your campaign and the people that
have real power in Washington,
our fundraisers and lobbying groups.
Now,
James Madison said,
what's going to happen is these lobbyists,
lobbyists will offset each
other with their different,
and it'll be competing interests
and stuff hasn't happened.
In fact,
what seems to be happening is that some
of these groups have so much fucking
money.
And if you look at Potomac
where they're all live,
or just Washington area,
that is,
that is the highest per
capita income in the country.
Why do they produce.