All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
we are here and I'm here with Jocko
willink of extreme ownership,
how us navy seals lead and win.
I'm really excited to read this because
I really enjoyed your podcast with Tim
Ferriss and I've seen you around the UFC
a bunch of times,
but uh,
I didn't know much about you,
but you're one of those dudes,
you know where I look at this guy.
I'm like,
that guy probably knows some shit.
This is,
this says something about you,
like when I see you,
you know,
you're hanging around with lister.
I saw you a few times at the UFC in
line.
Like I probably know some shit or he's
seen some shit and then I saw or
listened to the Tim Ferriss podcast.
I go,
oh,
okay,
well that makes a lot of sense.
Now if you haven't heard that podcast,
it is excellent and you're the one of
the first guy ever to come with your own
notepad in your own pen too.
I just want to point that out.
Just trying to be prepared.
Well,
that's your whole thing,
man.
I'm a big fan of your social media posts
too because,
uh,
I like feeling like a lazy fuck whenever
I look at your social media posts and
you have a picture of your watch for 45
in the mornings.
Dudes out there working out.
I like it.
Yeah.
It's interesting because,
uh,
you know,
obviously they had zero social media
presence like three months ago or
whatever the case may be.
And Tim Ferriss was,
you know,
basically said,
hey,
you need to get on this social media
stuff.
And I said,
okay,
can you kind of show me what to do?
And he says,
yeah,
sign up.
So then I signed up and then he dropped
that podcast that gets listened to by a
bunch of people and all of a sudden I
was engulfed in the social media world
and I found twitter to be the one that,
uh,
was the easiest to use and you don't
have to write a lot.
So,
you know,
I don't like people that talk a whole
bunch without saying anything.
So I figured that one's pretty cool.
Yeah,
that was the thing that I was thinking
when he was encouraging you to use
social media was like a guy like you,
you're not a peacock,
you know,
and there's something about social media
as a person who's an avid social media
user,
there's some peacocking to it,
you know,
and I try to do it with humor and I try
to,
because it's,
it's an important aspect of promoting
comedy shows and podcasts and things
along those lines.
But,
um,
you were much more of a,
keep it to yourself.
One of the things that I loved about the
Ferris podcast you were talking about,
um,
how you would have a commanders would
come to a various leaders and ask them,
what do you need,
what do you need a and guys would have
all these requests and all these things.
We need Wifi and we need this.
And you were like,
we're good sir.
We're good sir.
And the idea behind that is when you did
need something,
if you really did need something,
someone would come to you,
you would get it quickly.
Absolutely.
When I,
when I needed something and I spoke up
and said,
hey,
hey boss,
this is what I need and this is why I
need it.
They would instantly give it to me
because they knew that I was telling the
truth that it wasn't some,
you know,
halfassed requests that wasn't real.
It was something that we legit needed
and they'd give it to me.
Well,
this is the value
of someone who keeps their words short
and means what they say and says what
they mean and doesn't have a lot of
bullshit involved in their vocabulary.
Or,
and this is coming from a professional
bullshitter.
I mean,
this is what I do.
I bullshit.
I talk,
you know,
fill a lot of hours of just shooting the
shit about nonsense.
And I mean I have to look in the mirror
at myself.
I mean,
I just wrote with my partner Leif Babin,
who I served with,
you know,
we just wrote a 300 page book about us,
for all practical purposes.
Now of course it's about our team and
it's about what we learned,
what we experienced.
But there's no doubt that there's some
level of,
you know,
self promotion when you're writing a
book that's got your name on the cover
of it,
and now I'm sitting here talking to you
and I guess that puts me in the same
league,
maybe not the same league,
but at least I'm playing the same sport.
Yeah,
we're definitely playing the same sport
but that.
But there's benefit to that because I
think what you have to say and
especially what you had to say in the
Tim Ferriss podcast is,
is very important.
It's,
um,
it's not just important.
It's unique.
And because your perspective is of one
who was involved in the most intense
activity,
a human being can participate in today's
world.
You were involved in combat in Iraq
during the worst time of the war and you
came through it with some pretty intense
lessons and you can.
I think anybody listening to that
podcast can get a lot out of it.
There's inspiration to be gotten from
that podcast for sure.
But there's also an understanding that
can only be.
I don't think anybody else can relay
what you experienced,
but you,
you know,
you can have all these guys that write
these movies and they could write
screenplays and television shows about
it or guys can write books about it.
Embedded journalists can write about it.
It's not the same.
I got a sense from just you talking
about it on Tim Ferriss' podcast.
Literally a shift in my perspective of
what it's like to be there.
Yeah,
it is.
For me,
it was my,
and I know this might sound weird,
but it was my lifelong dream to be in
combat and to be in a leadership
position in combat.
Ever since I could remember wanting to
do anything of any substance with my
life,
I wanted to be some kind of a commando
and so I really felt and the battle of
Ramadi was,
you know,
like you said it was 2006.
There was Ramadi,
Iraq.
It was the worst place in the world at
the time and I knew that and I felt like
my whole life had sort of been preparing
me to be there in that position.
Taking care of those guys to the best of
my ability and going out and sending
them out to go and kill the enemy and
supporting the conventional forces that
were there that were unbelievably brave
and humble and just miraculously
patriotic and we formed a brotherhood
that,
you know,
to this day I don't think it'll ever be
replaced and you can see why,
you know,
these stories of war stand the test of
time and when we talk about the
Peloponnesian wars,
we talk about war for all time because
there's,
there's something there and I think it's
what you began with because it is the
ultimate human test.
You know,
it's the ultimate.
It is other people are trying to kill
you and you're trying to kill them and
that's just the ultimate test and not
that it's a great test or a test that
everyone should want to have happen
because it's awful and horrible and
wretched in many ways,
but at the same time it's there and it's
present and there is no avoiding it.
There is no avoiding it.
War is part of the world.
It's part of human nature.
I know Dana White says fighting's in our
DNA,
well you don't have to go,
but one or two degrees further from fist
fighting to where you know,
tribes of human beings are trying to
kill each other.
Yeah.
It's one of the subjects that have
talked about with my friend Duncan.
We were,
we were going over this and we,
we essentially came to the conclusion
that the history of the human race is a
history of military warfare.
I mean,
when are you talking about the human
ways race?
You talk about the civil war,
he talk about World War One,
world war two,
Korea,
Vietnam.
You talk about wars and in between those
wars,
people preparing for more war or trying
to avoid war,
the cold war in between wars,
you know,
you talk about the various conflicts
throughout history,
whether it's [inaudible] or whether it's
Napoleon,
whether you're talking about war.
I mean almost all of our history has
been trying to keep people from fucking
with us and trying to take things that
we think will help our people.
That's essentially the history of the
human race.
Yeah,
and I think what really strikes people
and why there's a an almost sick
fascination with it in some ways is
because there it's,
you know,
we say that a combat is like life but
amplified and intensified.
So it's similar to regular life except
for the consequences are obviously
everything you know,
you,
you can die,
that can be the end of you and so when
you're in that moment and when you read
about that and when people read these
books or watch these movies,
they get some sense of what that must be
like.
And I think that's why there's,
like I said,
some attraction to it.
I mean that's why there's hundreds and
hundreds of war movies and hundreds and
hundreds of war books because people try
and understand what that
emotional content really means.
Well,
there's no higher stakes,
so anytime you're,
you're involved in an activity that
literally there are no higher stakes
other than the loss of your loved ones
and the grief that you would suffer
because of that.
The loss of your own life is about the
highest state possible.
And when I talked to people like you or
many of the other guys that have talked
to that have served and been involved in
combat,
one of the craziest aspects of it is
many want to be back there.
Many experience that life tuned up to 11
and they recall it like it's the best
time of their life.
There's no doubt about it.
Best time of my life,
crazy,
no doubt about it.
Feeling that pressure,
um,
knowing what was at stake.
And again,
for me in a leadership position,
you know,
everyone feels a little bit different
from me in a leadership position.
You're not worried about yourself
getting hurt or killed.
You're worried about your guys getting
hurt or killed.
And that's the most important thing.
And the thing that's keeping you awake
at night and the thing that's driving
you.
And so there's an intensity there,
but having so much pressure and so much
at stake when it goes away,
it's definitely leaves a hollow,
empty space inside.
There's no doubt about it.
Well,
you see it with fighters,
with boxers,
MMA fighters when they retire,
they have a real hard time finding
regular life to be fulfilling and I can
only imagine it would be way more
intense because of war,
because the thing about fighting is it's
such a solitary sport.
You know you have your team behind you,
you have coaches,
you have guys that you prepare with that
you train with,
but once you're locked up inside that
cage or you step inside that ring,
it's really all just about you.
The experience is yours.
When you're a war,
you're experience is protecting all
those around you as well as staying
alive and losing friends and thinking
that you could have done something
differently and maybe someone would
still be here.
That's,
that's a completely different kind of
thing.
To leave and to come back to regular
civilization and then to watch all the
shit that you did in Iraq go to pieces
now.
You watched just fucking chaos over
there.
Now everyday in the news that the.
Whether it's the civil war between the
Sunni and the Shia or whether it's
what's going on with Isis and it just
seems like whatever gains that you guys
made there are slowly being eroded
everyday.
Does that also like pull at you?
Oh yeah.
Yeah,
absolutely.
So we don't,
like I said,
we fought and when I say we,
I'm talking about a giant group of five
or 6,000
Americans with the one.
One had just a huge group of awesome
guys,
soldiers and marines and we were a part
of them and so they,
they,
we all fought very hard for the city of
Ramadi.
I mean this is,
it's a city,
it's a city like a city in America.
It's a,
you know,
it's got roads and it's got houses and
Scott building and it's got a government
center.
It's got a soccer stadium.
It's a city like what we have in
America.
And we went in there and fought to take
the city back from these savages that
owned it at the time.
And why do I call them savages?
It's because they
tortured people.
They skinned people alive.
They beheaded people.
They raped little girls and little boys.
That was just disgusting and so we went
in there and fought against them and
beat them and what we did in doing that
is the people that actually lived there.
Again,
this is a city with human beings in it
and I always have to tell this story or
at least relate to people that you'd be
running down the street.
There'll be and firing around you,
kick open the door to a compound to
somebody's house and you'd get in there
and there'd be,
you know,
a guy,
a dad working on a car and there'd be
two kids kicking a soccer ball and
there'll be a mom cooking lunch.
And so there's people there and those
people wanted us to be there and wanted
us to defeat the insurgents that were
terrorizing them.
And we did.
And they were joyous about that.
And so when you talk about what do I
think now when I see isis,
the black flag of Isis,
I mean,
is there any other more dramatic image?
Then I can tell you then that the black
flag of Isis now flies at the government
center Amati.
It's,
it's,
it's horrible and it's sickening.
And they went around and anybody that
had anything to do with the coalition
there,
they went around with a list of names
and they murdered all of them and all
their families and you know,
we,
we as a country,
we kind of left them hanging and it's,
it's horrible to see that
we left them hanging and we instigated a
lot of crazy shit when we took Saddam
Hussein out of power,
which was probably ultimately a good
thing to get rid of that guy.
And it was no question that he was a
psychopath and his sons were evil fucks.
But in creating that vacuum,
like when the leadership has gone,
you,
you kind of have a responsibility to
manage that area.
Now.
As crazy as that sounds like people want
to say,
we're not in the building.
We're not in the business of nation
building.
We're not,
we're not in the building process or
the,
uh,
the business of organizing or
structuring a nation,
building a democracy out of one,
which did not have
one ever,
but you kind of have to,
we'll look what we did in Germany and
Japan.
Yeah,
we're still in both those countries.
We stayed there.
And guess what?
The two,
you know,
what are the two economic superpowers
behind America?
You know,
I know those two are both in the top
five.
Germany is definitely the head of
Europe,
you know,
besides China,
but Japan,
those are economic superpowers.
They're very successful countries and we
formulated their new structure.
Now there's a lot of resistance in this
country.
There always was a lot of resistance to
going to Iraq in the first place because
people didn't understand the connection
between nine slash 11 and Iraq and it
seemed like it was manufactured.
It seemed like two people on this side
that,
you know,
we're looking at it and we're looking at
Dick Cheney and Donald Rumsfeld and all
these chicken hawks that wanted us to go
over there and why.
But once you're there,
you kind of have to have a different
approach,
don't.
Yeah.
Well,
there's no doubt.
You have to have a different approach.
You have to believe in what you're
doing.
And again,
when you're number one and,
and every,
every soldier or marine or service
member will tell you that when they're
in combat,
they're not thinking about,
you know,
the strategic mission of the United
States of America.
They're thinking about the guy that's
next to them and what they're going to
do to keep that,
keep their buddies alive.
And that's,
that's all there is to.
And that's true in anyone will tell you
that.
But that being said,
when you come back from that operation
and you have time to think about what
you're doing there,
then you've got to believe in what
you're doing.
And if you don't believe in what you're
doing,
then you're going to have some serious
issues.
And so for me,
you know,
it was pretty obvious that what we were
doing was,
was absolutely the right thing.
I mean,
you've got insurgents there that were
foreign fighters that want to kill
everyone in America.
They hate us,
they want to destroy us,
they want to do nine slash 11 over and
over again in this country.
They want to kill us all and so for us
to be there fighting them,
I am totally on board and was on board
and remain that way today.
Now these insurgents that came in to
these places like Ramadi and we're
taking over the city and killing all
these people and torturing all these
people.
Why were they doing that?
To them it's the same.
It's the same thing that isis did when
they went back.
I mean they want to have a chunk of
land.
At the time they.
They'd said that Ramadi was going to be
the seat of their caliphate.
It's going to be the capital city of
their caliphate,
that that's what they were trying to do.
So in a sense like once war started over
there,
it became a holy war.
Yes,
and it's a holy war.
But it's interesting because the people
of Iraq,
there's people in Iraq,
most people in Iraq,
when you talk to them,
they're normal people that want to have
a job,
you know,
build a new addition on their house,
fixed the roof,
uh,
get some good food for dinner that
night,
raised their kids so that they can take
over the family business or that's what
they want.
They're not a bunch of people running
around doing what Isis is doing.
But who is the powerful force in Iraq
right now?
Now everyone's scared of Isis.
And,
and one thing about this is there,
you know,
because Iraq is,
they don't have this kind of patriotic
feeling that we have in America,
which I know,
I know it may be dying in many cases,
but there's a lot of Americans still
believe America's the greatest country
on earth and that.
And even if you don't believe it's
greatest country on earth,
and even if you see it for all its
faults that it's has.
You appreciate the fact that in this
country you have freedom.
And so you can kind of fight for that no
matter what you're thinking about,
you're,
you're fighting for freedom,
you're fighting to protect your family.
Well,
in Iraq,
they're like,
okay,
um,
I'll,
I'll fight for whoever,
I'll fight for whoever or support
whoever is just gonna allow me to live
the.
They don't have the same attitude.
That's why when Isis came into Ramadi
and the,
the Iraqi troops kind of ran away.
They're like,
well,
we don't know what's going to happen.
We don't really don't have that core
belief that they're fighting for.
And so I think that's where some of the
challenges come in and as they grow that
they will,
they will perform better.
But it's definitely gonna take quite a
bit of time.
Well,
I think patriotism in America was at its
all time high around September 11th.
Right?
Right after that happened,
you never saw more flags.
I mean,
I remember driving down the street and
every car had a flag hanging from it.
No doubt about it.
I mean,
it was a buddy of mine,
Jay London sold flags.
That's what he used to do,
sell car flags,
flags that you put on cars.
Man,
I had a good business going on for
awhile,
but like a lot of things,
people got accustomed to it.
They got it settled in and everything
got back down to its normal level,
so so was this big buzz of patriotism
will.
There's a big buzz of patriotism when
you feel threatened and we never feel
threatened.
In America.
Everyone is driving around in a nice big
suv that gets eight miles to the gallon
with big air conditioning blasting.
They're looking at their iphone,
texting people socially interacting
through the,
through the Wifi,
and they're not concerned about their
safety.
And so when you're not concerned about
your safety,
what is there left to be patriotic?
When you don't understand what it means
to live in fear.
So yeah,
September 11th comes and you get
attacked and you feel that fear.
Guess what?
You rally around this,
this thing America that's protected you
and your family,
but you didn't even think about it
before,
but now you're thinking about it and you
go,
you know what?
I'm going to put a flag up on my up on
my vehicle.
This vehicle that I drive around in
complete luxury,
which is what America is like,
America is unbelievably luxurious
compared to the rest of the world.
There's also unquestionable evil
involved in flying planes into buildings
and killing civilians just randomly,
haphazardly suicide bombing essentially
with a plane right into a building or a
goal that was so evil that everybody
just.
There was no.
There's no gray area in that.
It was pretty clear.
It was about as clear as any event ever
in human history.
Agree.
Now when you found out,
I mean you already involved in the
military when all this was going on you,
you signed up like long before they like
you.
If there's anybody that I've ever met
that I've ever heard,
talk about it.
That was.
Doesn't mean this is how you feel.
You're born for this.
This is.
This is your,
your,
your goal,
your post in life?
Yes.
What put.
What pulled you into them?
You grew up in New England?
I did what?
Part of Connecticut and Maine.
Okay,
so it was just sticks on a dirt road,
you know,
just kind of a general American,
general American.
What was it,
the true you to it?
Like where did you develop this sense of
patriotism?
Well,
I would say prior to the,
the feeling of patriotism,
you know,
I,
like I said,
I always wanted to be some kind of a
commando and I would say that you,
when you joined the military,
I'd say people that are somewhat
patriotic join the military,
but when you travel around the world and
you're in the military,
that kind of confirms your patriotism
more than anything else because you see
what the rest of the world is like and
how unbelievably amazing America is.
And again,
how does America have faults?
Yeah,
America's got all kinds of faults.
There's all kinds of things that we
could do better and there's things that
we've done in the past that we shouldn't
have done and there's things that we'll
do in the future that we shouldn't have
done,
but when you compare that with the rest
of the world and how the rest of the
world lives and what it means to be in
an oppressed society,
you know,
you,
you're extremely thankful to be in
America.
This is once you've already been in the
military and already started trout.
So this is just,
you just had this draw towards it almost
like your destiny to be in the military.
Yes,
that's a,
it's strange that it just came out of
nowhere.
Like there was no like event in your
life.
It just seemed like this was just
something that it was always,
you were always attracted to.
I mean,
running around the woods as a little kid
with bb guns,
shooting each other.
And that seemed like a good job.
And it's funny.
You don't seal teams,
you don't,
you don't grow up,
you know,
you don't,
you continue with your childhood.
Uh,
you know,
play time for your whole adult life and
it's awesome,
you know,
that's the best thing about the seal
teams is you,
you get to do what you always wanted to
do and they pay you money and you get
unlimited ammunition,
unbelievably types of weapons,
bombs,
explosives,
no grenades,
and they just give it all to you.
And they say,
well,
they get excited when they find a guy
like you.
We've got here,
we got a smart guy who was born to do
this,
who's really looking forward to it.
It's perfect,
I guess.
So I'm sure the recruiter was pretty
fired up when he met.
I would be,
if I was recruited out of the way,
let me sign the paper,
got one check,
check the boxes.
And um,
but it's,
it's Kinda,
it's even more intense because it's not
just you get to play,
but only the strong get to play.
The week Oregon we weeded out.
And what's left is people have similar
character.
That's what I've found most fascinating.
I think that's one of the things that's
so romantic in the public's eye about
the idea of the seals or green berets
are rangers people that it's very
difficult to get in there and only a
select few have the intestinal
fortitude,
the willpower and the ability to lock
onto a task and a goal and get through
it.
Yeah,
and then when you're in the seal teams,
none of that means anything and like all
the training and all that selection
process is just doesn't mean anything
because you all.
That's just a baseline of where
everyone's at.
And so when people talk about this
intense training,
when you're in the seal teams,
you don't talk about that training that
you go through to get an it.
That's just the baseline for everybody.
So it's just to make sure that you're
not a pussy just exactly.
Exactly.
And here you are,
44 years old.
You're still getting up at 4:00
in the morning doing dead lifts.
It never left you.
It did not leave me.
It's not going to.
His aid is not going.
So you get through.
Once you get through the,
the intensity of buds and you get
through,
you know,
all the people that are going to quit
and you get through all the training,
what is life like from there on out,
like how structured is like training and
physical activity and things like that
from there on out,
you know,
again,
being in the seal teams is,
is awesome.
It's such a,
such a
fun job that I literally didn't consider
it a job except for maybe 13 months out
of my career,
13 months I worked for,
uh,
the directly for the animal that was in
charge of all the seals and it,
he's a great guy and I learned a ton
from him and from having that job,
but it wasn't a fun job.
And even he would tell you it's not a
fun job.
You know,
you've got to uh,
you know,
you're wearing a uniform every day and
in the regular seal teams you're,
you're wearing a pair of shorts and
you're barely wearing a shirt because
you're out there in the field or you
know,
getting ready to go in the field.
So it's a,
it's a great life and you're constantly
training,
you're hanging out with a bunch of guys
that are pretty much have the same
attitude as you for the most part.
There's a couple guys that don't cut it
and there's some guys that are super
studs and you're,
you're doing your best to emulate them,
but you're hanging out with a bunch of
great guys.
And you know,
when I was a young seal,
well we'd get to Friday and we'd,
you know,
go out,
have a beer,
we'd get done Saturday,
we'd still go to work Sunday,
we'd still go to work,
we go work out,
we'd hang out,
we'd work on our gear,
we'd get ready and there was even not
even a war going on.
We were just into it,
you know,
we were just fired up for the seal teams
and that was so it's,
it's a great life.
And then once the war
started,
the intensity definitely picked up
because you know,
everybody knew that we were going into
combat and everyone pushed that much
harder.
That being said,
back in the nineties,
we used to train really,
really hard because it was an unknown
element,
you know,
there was an unknown element where you
didn't know what was really going to.
You didn't know what combat was really
like.
So you trained as hard as you possibly
could.
Figure out how to train.
We trained and then once combat started
and we were like,
okay,
well we kind of know what we're dealing
with now.
It'd be like a fight or go into a camp
if he's never fought in the UFC before,
he's going to train super hard to make
his debut.
Well,
maybe after he wins really easily as
first couple of fights,
maybe he backs off on that train and
capital.
Not that we did that,
but it definitely mentally was there,
uh,
to,
to push hard even before combat.
So you just essentially saying that even
before you were going to war,
you were gonna be ready.
You,
you were,
you were going to make sure that you had
all your boxes checked,
you get all your ducks in a row,
100 percent.
How much physical training is there?
Once you're actually deployed it,
it depends on where you are and what
you're doing,
you know,
it depends on what type of missions
you're going on,
but you know,
being in the seal teams is a very
physical job and again,
you know what it is,
it's a baseline.
Everyone expects it.
You're gonna be able to put on your
rucksack and your gear and go out and
move and shoot and communicate.
That's the baseline.
Everyone's expected to do it and
whatever you have to do to make that
happen is,
is kind of on you.
Although we do do,
you know team,
what we call pt,
physical training,
but we do team pet,
but a lot of it is on you as an
individual or your smaller element,
you know,
group of guys and that's how you,
you to,
you got to stay in shape.
You do not want to be the guy that can't
carry as can't carry his weight.
That's just,
you'll,
you'll get,
you'll get kicked out.
So it's.
But it's not structured.
It's not organized like say if you're
deployed in Iraq.
What I was getting at was I always
wondered,
like I would imagine that the type of
workouts that you do,
they're exhausting,
right?
You know,
you're dead lifting,
you doing cleans and presses and all
this crazy shit and chin ups and running
up hills.
If you had to go to war,
right after a hard workout like that,
it's going to take something out of you.
Yeah.
You've gotta use you gotta use common
sense.
Right?
So how do you know like when to stay in
shape or what to do?
Yeah,
you're,
you're not going to do like a massive
squat workout while you're on
deployment.
That's going to put you in there for
three or four days.
It's just not smart.
You know,
you're gonna.
It's like a pavel,
you know the pavel.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
You know,
he kind of.
I heard that from him years and years
ago,
you know,
because he was trained in some swat guys
up in La and I talked to some of those
guys and they said,
you know,
well,
don't,
you don't need to go to exhaustion to
get stronger.
Says,
okay cool.
Let's try that.
And so,
you know,
you've got to be ready to operate,
that's your primary mission.
You got to be ready to go out on the
battlefield and get after it so you're
not going to crush yourself so hard that
you're incapacitated.
Yeah.
He's not a guy that believes in to
failure.
Right.
He's got some interesting.
He doesn't ideas and I'm not like some,
uh,
some follower from just one of those
things I heard along the way.
Yeah.
I mean,
look,
there's a lot of different philosophies
when it comes to training.
Um,
but when you,
so when you're deployed,
it's essentially all entirely on you
other than the group organized pt
trainings just about.
Yeah,
just about.
So do you guys get together and say,
hey,
we're going to go running or we're going
to live today,
or we're gonna go do some pull ups.
What about martial arts training?
How much martial arts training is
involved?
Again,
that depends on what the situation is
and who you're working with.
You know,
if,
if you were a junior officer that was
working for me,
then you are going to be trained Jujitsu
all the time.
If they're working for you.
So it depends on who they're working
for.
Yeah.
Uh,
you know,
I needed training partners and so I got
them.
So when you did that,
would you take guys and teach them some
basic stuff and then just choked the
shit out of him?
Is that the move?
Pretty much.
Do you talk them through it while you're
doing it?
Like defend,
get your arm here.
But,
you know,
I actually,
I would actually improve,
you know,
I'd go on deployment and come back and
some guy that maybe I was having good
battles with before I left to come back
and be better because all of a sudden
you go and work on really good offense
against a bunch of strong,
you know,
psycho seals that don't want to tap and
you've got to make it work.
So,
you know,
I'd come back and,
and be better.
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't get worse on deployment.
That's for sure.
Was that Sadie Bravo's theory?
He believed that the real way to get
better is not to train with people
better than you,
but to train with people that aren't as
good as you and just constantly drill
finishes over and over and over again,
sharpen them up like a Samurai sword,
and then when you do spar with people
that are your level or better,
you'll be much better just because
you're constantly used to finishing.
Yeah,
and I think there's a combination of
both.
You've got to train with people that are
better than you and you got to train
with people that are worse than you and
you know,
we do that in seal training to where
because the seal training that I ran
before I got out was not like the seal
training where you see with the guys
with the the logs carrying those around
or boats on the head that like I said,
that's the basic training in and no one
really cares too much about that.
Once you get in the seal teams because
it's just over,
it's just a smash you in the beginning
smash.
You make sure,
like you said,
make sure that you.
You're not opposed to exactly have the
intestinal fortitude to bring it,
but once you get in the seal teams,
then you go through something called a
workup and that's when you've got seal
platoons that are trying to work
together and we do crazy simulated
combat on these guys.
That is awesome.
I mean,
it's,
it's devastating.
And we have a paint ball.
Again,
this is like little kid stuff,
right?
You get,
you get awesome.
Paintball,
guns,
unlimited paintball rounds.
We had this,
this,
uh,
like the best laser tag system that
anyone could ever imagine.
This crazy expensive laser tag system
where you could go out and fight each
other with laser tag and when you were
getting at,
if the
rounds weren't theoretically hitting
you,
then there was a little speaker on your
shoulder that would make noises as if
rounds.
We're going over your head so that you
would know to get down and there'd be
explosions going off on these little
speakers.
And then when you get back from these
training operations,
the,
all the,
they have little embedded gpss in them.
So you'd put it out on Google earth and
you could watch the whole battle unfold
and watch what people did right and
wrong.
And my point in this is that sometimes
many times,
especially in the beginning when the
seals weren't quite up to speed yet and
they didn't know how to work together
that well,
three or four or five opposing for seal.
So these are guys that are pretending to
be bad guys.
They would kill them all.
They would just go out there and murder
them all.
And as these guys got better and started
to work together and the leadership
started to step up and take command and,
and do a better job of leading,
then all of a sudden they,
the seals would start to beat the
opposing force and annihilate them.
What an incredible tool to learn how to
organize and to,
to stay together and work together as a
team.
What did they used to do in the past?
Well that's,
that's a very interesting topic because
it's very similar to,
you know,
what the UFC did to martial arts because
as you know,
in 1991,
you know,
you and I could sit here and talk it,
you could be a Kung Fu guy and I could
be an Aikido guy and we could be like,
no,
my martial arts better and you can be
saying the same thing and we could
theoretically debated all day long but
we'd never actually do it.
And it's different.
So in combat,
obviously you can't,
you know,
we can't say,
okay,
let's find out which one's better and
we're on the same team,
we're just going to kill each other to
find out you can't do that.
So the first thing that happened was
simunition and that's,
you know,
they basically started paintball but
it's high speed paintball that fits in
your real gun fits in a real,
a real gun.
So you take your,
you put a new barrel on your,
your standard,
you know,
issue weapon and now you're shooting
paint balls out of your real gun.
You have 30 rounds.
He changed magazines like very,
very similar to real combat and all of a
sudden just like a punching bag,
you know,
when people say,
oh,
the punching bag doesn't punch back
what?
When you go into a,
into a house and you shoot a bunch of
paper targets,
they don't move,
they don't shoot back.
So it's,
you know,
guess what,
you win every single time and you can
get pretty confident with your tactics.
Your tactics aren't getting tested.
And so when,
when these great technologies come came
out,
ammunition,
paint ball and these laser type systems,
it was a,
it was a complete change and we
definitely changed our tactics.
Our tactics evolved,
just like fight tactics evolved with
the,
with the advent of the UFC.
And people said,
oh,
this doesn't work the way we thought it
did.
And you know,
this idea of,
oh,
we're just going to go running into a
room and no one's going to stop no
matter what.
No,
actually if there's a machine gun just
lay in paint into you as you go in,
you're stupid if you go running into
that room.
So we made these simple adjustments but
it was an interesting progression and it
definitely imprinted the fact that you
have to make your training as realistic
as possible.
And it also,
it also shows you how people,
humans have a tendency to believe in
what they're doing just because it's
kind of what they believe in.
And you know,
again,
I think those,
those traditional martial arts that were
so popular back in the day,
people truly believed that like,
no,
I will actually stop you with,
you know,
with my ci,
my Ci will stop you.
And they,
they really thought that I had one of my
Jujitsu buddies was,
you know,
had some ci guy in 1995,
like,
you cannot take me down.
And he said,
well,
what do you mean?
And he said,
no,
I,
once I settle my ci,
you cannot take me down.
And he said,
well,
okay,
settle your,
do you want to try it?
And the guy's like,
sure,
you can try all you want.
So the guy you know,
stands there and settles,
is she out?
And my buddy goes,
are you ready?
And he says,
yeah.
And he just like double legs and slammed
him on the ground,
but the guy believed it.
That's what's crazy.
And that's what,
that's what people get get lured into,
you know,
the,
our egos listen into a lot of stuff that
we need to watch out for.
Well
the belief is based on being taught by
people who also believe it too.
And it's so confusing because no one's
experienced it in,
in real life,
which was why the initial question was
when they used to prepare like back in
Vietnam or you know,
during the,
uh,
the,
well,
when was this stuff invented?
Like we did,
they had it during the first Gulf War.
Barely,
barely.
Very small groups had it,
you know,
not,
not as many as should they have the
laser setup and everything.
No,
we didn't get the good.
they had that.
They had a worse laser system.
You know,
they've been trying to do it for years,
but what did they used to do like during
the Vietnam era,
go off of the experience of guys that
had been in world war two and Korea to
try and pass that on.
And Luckily,
and honestly,
you know,
being in combat,
the basic principles of combat are not
the super crazy complex things,
you know,
the most basic principle that we talk
about is cover and move,
which is if you and I are going to go
assault a building over there,
I'm going to,
I'm going to take cover.
I'm going to engage that building so
that the enemy can't put their heads up
and while I'm shooting at the building,
shooting where we think the enemy are,
you're going to get up and maneuver into
a better position.
Once you get into a better position and
you get some cover,
you're going to start shooting at the
enemy and that's going to allow me to
move.
Once I get to a better position,
I'll start shooting again and we'll
continue to do that.
Supporting each other as we move to
retarget.
And then once we get there,
we'll kill the bad guys and there'll be,
it'll be done.
That's the most basic principle.
But there's times where before,
you know,
in between Vietnam,
which is where we had major combat and
people learned that cover moving guys
that were in Vietnam were the people
that taught me covering move in between
that time and the time when we started
using this ammunition and the and the
lasers,
the better products.
We actually forgot some of those
lessons.
As crazy as that might seem.
We actually forgot some of these very
simple basic lessons of,
of gun fighting.
And so it was great to have it back and
it was when we were,
when we went to combat finally,
we were more prepared for
it.
Yeah,
I would imagine that kind of simulation
you,
you're calling it simunition.
That's a,
that's an actual name brand.
And it's a name brand it,
that's the paint.
Yep.
So send me an issue is the paint and the
laser.
What is the name brand of that stuff?
One that we used was called debts and it
was made by sob and I don't know,
I don't,
I don't even know if they still make it
or if that contracts don't go in,
but it was awesome.
Yeah,
I like your analogy to martial arts,
like testing it in,
in the,
in the actual competition because it
would seem that that would be the only
way that anybody would ever actually
learn what mistakes not to make and how
they could easily be replicated in
combat and then the repeated actions of
doing those over and over again and
ingraining them in your mind is probably
the only thing that could really,
you could draw upon when you're in those
intense situations of an actual
firefighter.
Yeah,
and there's another good comparison.
I don't know if you've ever heard
somebody say this,
but you know,
they'll say like,
let's say I train some Kung Fu stuff
where I'm and I attacker and I rip your
throat out and all that stuff and you
train,
you know,
Jujitsu,
Muay Thai,
wrestling and boxing.
Right?
So people will say that you're not ready
for the fact that I'm going to poke your
eyes out or you're not ready for the
fact that I'm going to try and grab your
throat or whatever and therefore I have
an advantage and a and that you have
some kind of a training scar because you
aren't used to doing that.
You see what I'm saying?
So if like I said,
if all I do is train to grab your eyes
and poke your throat or whatever
pressure point type attack,
then that means that I'm better prepared
for a street conflict.
And as you and I both know,
like a guy that does that versus a guy
that trains in mixed martial arts,
boxing,
wrestling,
Moitai,
Jujitsu,
that guy's going to destroy this other
person in the street fight and the guy
will grab for Xyz and then he's gonna
get his arm broken off and is going to
get punched in at 47 times.
But my point in telling them that that
is that this.
We had the same type of people in inside
the seal teams that said,
Oh,
if you get used to training with paint
ball,
then you're going to develop training
scars from it so you're not going to be
used to your regular weapon.
You're not going to be used to the
recoil of a real gun and you're going to
have more courage because it's only
going against paint and wall.
That while there's some small piece of
truth to that,
just like there's some small piece of
the truth to the fact that if,
if you never think about what it's like
to be punched while you're doing
Jujitsu,
well then it's going to be a surprise
for you.
The first time you you are in guard with
someone and they crack you in the face.
There.
Some small truth who,
but it's not a reason to throw out,
you know,
that type of training.
It just doesn't make sense.
And the other thing that's good about it
is,
you know,
in Jujitsu and boxing and wrestling,
you're going live against another human
being that's a maneuvering on you and
trying to defeat you.
And when you have paint ball or laser,
you're going against another human being
that's trying to maneuver on you and
defeat you.
So therefore it's very effective in
teaching and what real combat is going
to be like.
What was it like the first time you were
deployed and when was that?
The first time I was deployed in 2003
and deployed to Baghdad,
Iraq.
And it was great.
That's not what most people would think
of.
It wouldn't never think of that word.
It's very it.
What was interesting about my first
deployment to Iraq was that again,
I was so happy to be in a position where
I was a platoon commander and we were
doing real missions and I was excited
and happy about that.
And you know,
that doesn't mean I was running around
smile on my face and we had a legit job
and we had to get it done.
It was also a time where the,
the insurgents,
there wasn't an insurgency yet.
We hadn't even really heard that word in
2003.
And so the operations that we did were
relatively simple and our tactical
advantage over the enemy was good enough
that we just annihilated them,
you know,
it was like,
it was like an unfair fight,
which is how you want it to be.
You want to have an unfair fight in
combat.
And so we would go in,
you know,
2:00
in the morning,
we'd find out what a bad guy was in some
house or some officer,
some building,
and we'd load up our vehicles and go in
the middle of the night,
blast their door open with big explosive
breaching charge,
clear their house in about 30 seconds,
grab them,
grab their buddies,
bring them all back,
interrogate them,
find out where their friends are and go
out and do it again.
And it was awesome and it was awesome.
And it was like a rockstar deployment.
We'd come home at 3:00
in the morning and be done and debrief
the operation and get ready to do it the
next day.
We probably were in four or five
firefights during that whole deployment.
Couple ambushes and I had one guy get,
get wounded,
not very bad.
So it was,
it was,
it was funny,
it was good and we were ready for it.
Um,
and the contrast comes when you go to my
next deployment,
the next deployment to Ramadi,
which was completely different.
So and on that deployment,
everything bad that can happen too.
A guy in a leadership position or an
element happened to us,
everything bad that could happen,
happened.
And so it was,
it was radically different than my first
deployment.
So your first deployment was a in a
sense a like what people
expected the war to go,
like after we had experienced Desert
Storm,
Desert Storm,
which was just an overwhelming success.
Just the only casualties were when that
one Scud missile had hid a barracks and
it was just,
that was what America thought war was
like,
well this is how good we are at it right
now.
We just go over there and we kill
everybody and we lose a couple people.
And real sad about that.
But
we wrapped it up tight.
So your second deployment,
what was that like and how did it begin?
Well,
it began with our deployment orders
changing,
so we were literally two weeks from
going on deployment.
So now my first deployment to Iraq,
I was what's called a platoon commander.
I had 15 or 20 guys underneath me
depending on what time during the
deployment it was.
And we were an assault force.
We were like,
we jokingly called ourselves Baghdad
Swat because that's what we did.
I just kind of describe what those
missions were like.
My second deployment now I was what's
called a task unit commander and I had
two of those seal platoons with 15 to 20
guys that were underneath me and then we
had another 70,
60 or 70 support personnel.
So these are people that do Intel
people,
that man the radios,
people that clean and repair our weapons
and people that keep the camera running
and all that.
So it's,
it's,
it's about 100 guys,
but there's only 35 or 40 seals.
And we found out about two weeks before
we went on deployment,
our deployment changed instead of going
to Baghdad.
And really doing more bag that swat
operations we went,
we were told we were going to Ramadi and
I was again,
and people always say,
you know,
I can't believe you fought that and I
can't believe how twisted you are and
all,
I can't believe what a sick individual
you are and et Cetera,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
But yes,
I was extremely happy and motivated that
we're going to Ramadi because it was the
worst place in Iraq and that is exactly
where I wanted to be my whole life.
So yes,
I was fired up to go there.
Just so
crazy.
I mean,
it's so counterintuitive to the way most
people think.
I guess so.
And I hung around with a bunch of guys
that thought the same damn thing is me.
Let's go get these guys.
Let's get after it.
Well,
that's why you are who you are.
I mean,
that's,
that's why it's important to have people
like you in the world like this.
Like there's a spectrum of human beings.
There is a spectrum of human being and
you're,
you're on the extreme edge of exactly
what you want.
When you have an army,
have you put together a military force?
You want a guy like you that has that
attitude.
You don't want a guy who's going to the
worst place in the world saying,
Oh,
why me?
What the fuck?
Why didn't I become a Baker like
my dad?
I could be making cupcakes right now.
Instead I'm shooting people.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
you,
uh,
and,
and the seal teams and the Rangers and
the special forces does a very good job
of attracting the type of people that
you're talking about,
the type of people that are fired up to
do that job and not encouraging it and
growing it like you did.
It seems like the amount of camaraderie
and the intensity of the friendships and
the bond,
that brotherhood that you developed with
those people just intensifies it all.
Yeah.
It's a big gang.
It's a big,
it's a big awesome gang that you're a
part of that's bad ass.
And you're part of this fraternity is
brotherhood.
So yeah,
they definitely fuel the fire and,
and I should say,
I shouldn't say they fuel the fire,
we fueled the fire.
We're,
we are the fire,
you know,
the guys that are there,
the guys that I worked with,
they're fired up guys that are
completely ready to do this job.
So you get over there,
you're in Ramadi,
totally different situation than banked
at totally different situation in
Baghdad.
And he immediately realizes immediately,
immediately we were going.
I mean I think,
I think we went to the first memorial
service for an American within,
you know,
24 hours of being on the ground there.
We,
my,
my camp got attacked the,
I dunno,
maybe the third or fourth night that we
were there,
every guy was on the roof of our
building,
shooting back at bad guys that were
shooting at us.
It was.
And then,
and then we started conducting
operations almost immediately.
And the operations were just,
just radically different.
I mean the enemy owned the downtown area
from Audi.
They,
they were the dominant force down there.
So whereas before you'd be going through
kind of semi permissive environment in
Baghdad,
meaning that,
you know,
it's a,
it's a bunch of civilians and they just
wanted to get out of your way and then
you'd go and find this bad guy,
well in Ramadi,
the bad guys,
we're going to find you.
And it was different and they were
everywhere.
They were who had trained them.
Some of them were former regime
elements,
so some of them were.
Ramadi was a,
was an Iraqi military city as well.
So there's some of them leftover,
actually a bunch of them leftover.
And then you had Syrians coming in,
foreign fighters,
uh,
people coming in from all over Saudi
Arabia,
Jordan,
I mean,
they'd come in from all over the place
to come and engage and get their Jihad
on.
And with a motivated because America was
now occupying Iraq because that,
what was,
was driving them,
I think more than the fact that that
America was occupying Iraq,
is that they wanted to take that land.
I mean,
America was no longer occupying Iraq
when they went in and took Ramadi this
time.
We were going,
we'd been gone for four years,
so the occupation of Iraq was not the
driving force behind this.
So once you get there,
once you realize right away,
it's different.
You're experiencing casualties at a
level that was unheard of in Baghdad and
you are engaging with an enemy that's
very prepared and overwhelming.
They're everywhere.
And they did.
They were similar to us,
meaning they did like a first world
country type stuff.
They had met a medical evacuation.
Plans are one of their guys would get
wounded.
You'd see them get evacuated,
you know,
you could watch on,
on the screens,
you could watch what was happening.
A vehicle would come in and gathered
them up and take one of the guys away.
They'd bring in reinforcements.
They had communications,
they did fire maneuver.
They did the same basic tactics that I
was talking about.
They did those tactics as well.
And so it was a real well trained and
well coordinated and determined enemy.
Was this expected?
Well,
we knew what Ramadi was like.
Um,
but I would say it was expected,
but it's hard to mentally picture what
that's going to be like when you,
when you're going to go up against guys
that are that prepared.
So this was tactically and as far as
like the strategy that was involved to
try to take a city like that.
This was a fairly new experience for the
United States military,
right?
We,
we'd never had what other being other
what Somalia,
like what other urban war had a,
the United States engaged in like this
where you're in a city.
Well,
I mean obviously World War Two had all
kinds of conflict and in Vietnam there
was portions,
you know,
the battle of waste,
waste city was a huge urban conflict.
Somalia was definitely urban combat,
but you're right in the fact that we
weren't going in there to try and stay.
And that was one of the biggest
differences or changes in strategies
that the US military had that turned the
war around.
And that was as the,
as the insurgence grew and it's 2004,
2005,
the insurgency started getting more and
more unified and better and more well
trained and more organized and America.
What we did was kind of go back to our
strong basis.
So there's basis.
You got to understand this in Iraq,
2005,
2006,
if you went to a base in let's say
Baghdad International Airport,
there was a huge US military base.
There was a subway,
the sandwich shop,
subway,
starbucks.
These places have become little little
outcroppings of America.
And so what we did when the insurgency
got worse and worse and worse,
and also the public opinion of the war
went down and down and,
and all of a sudden we're sitting here
going,
wow,
we're not going to want to minimize
casualties as much as possible.
So what does that mean?
You do?
You go back to your base.
And we,
we did that as a country.
We kind of said,
okay,
we're not going to take huge risks
anymore.
We're going to pull back to our basis.
We're going to try and support the
Iraqis as much as we can and let them go
out and try and accomplish missions and
we still did do missions,
but we definitely had strong and move
back to these big basis.
There was a guy a there.
There were several people and one of
them was general Patraeus.
He wrote this,
you know the counterinsurgency manual
now.
Now.
Now what you had was you went from this
idea of we're fighting kind of
terrorists and all of a sudden you're
fighting an organized insurgency,
and that was a huge strategy,
strategic shift,
and so now instead of going out and
grabbing a bad guy and then coming back
the the,
the new strategy,
and it was implemented in Ramadi by a
guy named Colonel Sean Mcfarland was c's
clear hold and build,
which means you're going to go into
these enemy controlled neighborhoods.
You're going to take buildings,
you're going to hold those buildings.
You're going to build them into your own
fortes and you're going to have American
and Iraqi soldiers live in those enemy
controlled territory's until the enemy
was gone.
Had that ever been implemented before?
It had been implemented in [inaudible]
in northern Iraq by a guy named h Dot h
Dot r dot mcmaster was another kind of
legendary,
a military army colonel at the time.
All these guys are generals now because
they're awesome guys.
He'd implemented up there.
He actually turned that plan over.
Two Gentlemen,
Farlane and gentlemen.
Foreman came down to Ramadi and
implemented the plan there,
but what was,
what was hard to understand is no one
really knew about this.
No one understood it all.
They all they said was,
oh my God,
wait a second.
You're saying we're going to go into
these enemy controlled neighborhoods
where were there haven't been American
or coalition forces for a year,
year and a half,
two years.
You're saying we're going to go in
there.
Right before we arrived in Ramadi,
there was a road that the marine corps
tried to penetrate down.
They hit 13 ids and 500 meters,
so 1330 $500.
So essentially what is 500 meters is
like,
it's every 50 meters or so,
a little less than 50 meters.
What does that football fields,
how much I foot five football fields.
Yeah,
that's insane.
That is.
Wow.
So,
so this new strategy to go in there and
pushing there was considered to be by
many people was considered to be too
risky,
too dangerous and,
and really in some cases crazy.
Like this is a crazy strategy.
We haven't been able to get down there
and now you're saying we're gonna go
down there and live there.
So it was a,
it was a very dynamic change.
So this is a gigantic,
gritty boots on the ground approach to
taking over a city,
like one step at a time,
but one building at a time.
That's it.
Wow.
That had to be insane.
Yeah.
Is there any documentary footage of
this?
Were there any embedded journalists
embedded journalists?
You know,
you can go on youtube and just Google
Ramadi,
2006 and you'll,
you'll see some good stuff.
There is a documentary that came out,
I think it was on the history channel.
It's called a chance in hell,
the battle for Ramadi and that.
What's good about that one is it
interviews.
A lot of guys that we worked with while
we were there and what I was just trying
to convey to you about the fact that a
lot of people were saying this was a
suicidal operation.
You can hear these guys that were
officers in charge of battalions and
companies.
They're saying the same thing there.
They were getting told by their peers
like,
this is a crazy idea and you guys are
all going to die if you go in there.
Wow.
Now what is morale like when something
like that gets brought down,
when these are the orders and this is
what you have to do and everyone's
telling you it's a suicide mission.
Well that's,
that's where leadership comes in because
you know,
one of the,
one of the toughest things that I ever
had to convey to my guys was this fact
that we were going to be working
alongside Iraqi soldiers,
conventional Iraqi soldier.
So you picture this.
We have that first appointment I talked
about.
We were,
we were only working with seals,
seals.
The guy to your left was a sealed.
The guy to your right was the CEO.
The guy behind you as a seal,
the guy who you can trust and who you
can trust them,
you knew them.
They were,
they were your brothers.
So now we get to Ramadi,
and the mission changed coming down from
the special operations forces that were
in charge of,
of all special operations in Iraq,
and the new,
the new mission was to the new mission.
I'm trying to think of the exact,
uh,
was to train and fight company and
platoon sized elements of Iraqi
soldiers.
Train and fight company,
platoon size elements of Iraqi soldiers.
And when they say fight,
that means like that's a verb saying
we're going to fight with them.
So all of a sudden I'm telling my guys,
hey,
you know how you're used to working with
a bunch of seals.
You're going to.
Now when you go out,
the majority of the guys,
you're going to be with our Iraqi
soldiers.
That's the majority of guys now Iraqi
soldiers are,
they're,
they're barely even military.
I mean people.
They're just unmotivated,
poorly trained.
In fact,
in many cases their loyalty is
questionable.
I mean,
these are guys that would shoot
Americans in the back.
So now I'm telling my guys,
okay,
you're gonna,
go out there and do this.
And obviously the first reaction I got
was a,
this is,
this is crap,
this garbage.
Why would we ever do that?
This is the worst battlefield seals have
fought on since Vietnam.
And you want us to go out there with a
bunch of a bunch of Iraqi soldiers
watching our back.
That's crazy.
And,
and when I heard it,
I thought it was crazy too.
So what do you do?
Then what?
What do you do?
Then you're going to send your guys into
harm's way in a much more vulnerable way
and you got to get them to do it.
So first of all,
I had to understand what we're doing on,
in my own mind.
I had to understand why.
I understand,
why would somebody be telling us to do
this?
Because it seems freaking crazy to me.
So as I sat there and thought about it,
I realized,
you know,
okay,
why is,
why is the president making us do this?
Why is the general the,
why is the Pentagon making us do this?
Why are the generals and colonels on the
battlefield here in Iraq?
Why in God's name would they be making
us go out with Iraqi soldiers?
It's crazy,
and then I thought to myself,
well,
okay,
why?
Let's answer that question.
Oh,
news flash,
if we don't do it,
if we don't get the Iraqi soldiers
trained up and ready to maintain the
security in their own country than who's
going to do it,
who's going to do it?
Who's going to train them?
And furthermore,
who's gonna hold the security and our
country?
And the answer was nobody in the answer
was us.
The answer was we would be here forever
because these Iraqis need to be able to
get up and stand on their own two feet.
And so when I explained that to my guys
like,
Hey,
I know you don't want to work with Iraqi
soldiers.
I understand.
I understand there's more risk.
Here's why we're doing it.
We're doing it because if we don't do
it,
if we don't get these guys up to speed,
if we don't teach them how to defend
themselves and how to defeat this enemy,
they're never going to be able to do it
and we'll be mired in this conflict
forever.
And once,
once they understood that strategic
picture,
they were able to get their head around
it and then slowly accepted what we were
doing.
How common were there complications from
dealing with the Iraqi soldiers and did
you guys have to take steps in order to,
to watch over them to make sure when
you're talking about guys shooting guys
in the back shooting Americans in the
back,
did you have plans in place to make sure
that someone was watching them at all
times?
Yeah.
So you didn't,
you couldn't treat them like,
did some,
did they speak English?
Uh,
no.
We had interpreters and oh yeah,
it's a nightmare.
Um,
and,
and we would have some of the Iraqi
soldiers,
some of them,
some of the leadership of the Iraqi
soldiers would be very good.
Some of the grunts would be very good.
And someone will just disastrous.
And did we have to change?
Yeah,
they didn't.
We had to change our tactics so that we
didn't use the terms left and right
because they didn't understand left and
right or no numbers.
A lot of them couldn't count.
I mean,
it was.
They couldn't count.
Yeah.
So they're totally on educated,
totally uneducated.
Wow.
Can't count.
Holy Shit.
Go four doors down.
[inaudible]
something you can tell a five year old.
Yes.
Whoa.
Yeah.
So,
so that was,
that was definitely challenging.
I think allowed to call them savages
when they can't count.
Is that,
is that the rule?
If you don't count the four I reserve,
I reserve the term savage for somebody
that carb commits,
you know,
atrocities against human beings.
You know,
somebody that rapes an eight year old
girl,
like they're doing wholesale doing that.
And Isis is doing that right now.
That's part of their gig.
Uh,
yeah.
I,
I reserve the term savages for them.
So what steps did you guys have to take
to ensure that the seals and the other
American soldiers were protected in
working with these people?
I mean,
you just have to keep your eye on him.
and honestly at this point,
the,
you saw this,
this,
uh,
happen a lot more than Afghanistan,
which was the,
what do they call it,
the color,
I forget what they,
they have a term for it,
but when the,
when the friendly allegedly friendly
Afghan soldier turns in,
shoots everyone in the back that
happened more later in Afghanistan and
when we were in Iraq it was pretty
seldom that it happened,
but we just had to be aware of it and we
had to,
you know,
you always had a guy that was standing
off the firing line and making sure that
no one was,
you know,
pulling their weapon out and aiming at
Americans.
So that was a job.
Yeah.
I would just,
you gotta keep an eye on these guys.
You absolutely crazy added element and
the other,
I mean it just again,
because there's dichotomy and everything
at the same time,
you'd have some guy that was,
you know,
some Iraqi soldier that was willing to
take a bullet for your buddy.
And so it's,
that's what makes war so complex.
And confusing is it's not cut and dry
and it never is.
So how did it start panning out once you
started this cs?
Clear hold and build.
It was a tough fight.
Basically with every one of these combat
outposts,
that's what we ended up.
Uh,
what they ended up calling these combat
outposts.
Every one of them was a pretty,
a pretty tough fight to the revit.
Their buildings,
they're calling them combat APA,
combat outposts.
What kind of the 10 stories,
like how many stories are these
buildings?
Most of them were two or three stories,
two or three stories.
And so you set up a perimeter around the
building.
Key people stationed in them,
guns at the windows,
looking out constantly.
And it would be it.
We take the building down and then they
would do a massive construction project
in the middle of a combat zone.
So these army engineers,
God bless them all would roll down there
with their bulldozers and there they put
these big concrete barriers up and they
put sand bags and all the windows and
they build machine gun nests on top.
And again,
they're doing this in the middle of like
mayhem.
Wow.
And then you'd have this secure combat
outpost and while they were doing that,
this is sort of was our,
our addition to this type of operation
was while they were doing this big
construction progress project,
obviously the situation was very
vulnerable for the American forces and
so what we would do is I would push our
seals out into perimeter buildings that
were maybe 200 or 300 yards.
And so when the enemy would come to
attack,
we'd kill them.
What a crazy scene that must've been to
be taking these buildings and then
reinforcing them and turning them into
military bases.
And then one after another.
You doing this to.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it was,
it was an awesome effort.
And I think a good number.
We put in one combat outposts and there
was the,
the uh,
army engineers put in 30,000
sandbags in one combat outpost,
like three buildings.
Just all good things.
A lot of sand out there.
Yeah.
No,
no doubt about it.
Wow.
And so how many buildings did you guys
wind up taking overall?
Uh,
probably probably a total of like 10
combat outposts,
each one having to three or four
buildings.
And again,
let me clarify when I say we,
I'm talking about this massive effort of
the one one aed,
which is the First Brigade,
First Armored Division and all the
battalions that were underneath them,
including one Marine Corps Battalion.
And the reason I'm pointing that out,
Joe,
is a,
those guys were just unbelievable years.
They really were.
They were awesome.
You choked up.
Yeah,
these guys were,
these guys were awesome.
They really were.
Yeah.
I can only imagine the emotional
attachment that you have to that.
Yeah.
And you know,
they,
you know,
you can look,
you can google navy seals and find,
you know,
$20,
million new stories about them.
Um,
and that's great.
But these guys,
you know,
to,
to have seen them,
uh,
kids,
you know,
because,
you're talking about earlier how the
seals,
you know,
guys like me,
this is what we want to do.
Well,
these guys didn't all necessarily have
that attitude.
And as a matter of fact,
the guys that were in Ramadi with us
when we first got there,
they were reserve unit out of
Pennsylvania,
the two to eight iron soldiers.
They were reservists.
These guys were teachers that like,
like what you see when they talk about
these reserves.
These guys were teachers and professors
and you know,
bakers and they had real jobs and real
world and wanting to get home to their
family.
And yet they were there grinding it out
against a hardened enemy.
And so,
uh,
yeah,
it's,
it's a,
it's a crazy thing to see and it's,
it's very humbling to be around people
like that.
It really is.
How long did this battle go on the
battle for Ramada?
Well,
we got there,
you know,
the,
like I said,
the two to eight had been there for 14
months.
Fourteen months on the ground.
Last around 100 guys,
I think 94.
Um,
and then the [inaudible] came in in May
and implemented c's clear hold and build
in by the time,
uh,
when I left October 20,
first 2006.
And by the,
by January of 2007,
the battle was for most,
for the most part over and these enemy
attacks that had been,
uh,
when we were there,
30 to 50 a day,
went down to like one a day and then one
week and then one a month and,
and,
and you know,
I have pictures of probably about six to
nine months after we left,
we got pictures that guy sent back to
us.
So they were running road races down the
worst.
What were the worst areas?
Ramadi,
they were playing soccer games.
There was people out in the streets,
there was guys,
seals or not seals,
but soldiers with no body armor on,
just walking around meeting people.
It was a,
it was a miraculous turnaround and the
people of Ramadi that we had fought to
support and help or were joyous and
we're had a stable city to live in and
we're ready to carry on with their
lives.
See,
I think stories like this get left out
of the mainstream narrative.
Of course they do.
The most people,
me included,
just don't know about it,
aren't aware of it.
Have a very insulated idea of what this
war was about,
what happened over there and what are
the pros and cons of this war and what
are the pros and cons of taking a city
like this and turning it into a
relatively safe place.
Relatively.
It was definitely a safe place.
There was less murders there.
The nerves and Detroit.
Wow.
I mean it was,
it was a complete turnaround and again,
you do,
you can do that because the people there
wanted to be stable.
They wanted that.
They wanted peace and they wanted
freedom and they wanted the insurgents
out.
They absolutely wanted the insurgents
Do you think that most people in America
have a distorted perception of,
of the military in general and of the
Iraq war in particular?
I think it's hard for me to give a
perspective of what civilians think,
you know,
it's,
it's very difficult because,
you know,
it's really easy to slip into like just
a straight John j Rambo,
you know,
there are no friendly civilians.
It's really easy to get there.
Uh,
but definitely when I hear various
people talking and you go,
this person has no idea,
this person has no idea the,
it's weird because they'll clump the
people of Iraq,
they'll clump those people together as a
group and it's the wrong.
They have the wrong impression of what
those people are like,
you know,
and,
and guys that have been to Iraq and have
gone into houses and talk to the local
populace there and broke bread with them
and drank their tea.
You're like,
oh that these people,
these people definitely wanted us there.
Like when I hear this thing about,
you know,
that they didn't want us there and we
were occupying.
It's like,
oh no,
they,
there was,
there was times where the weed kill an
insurgent and they would cheer.
They would cheer.
Like thank you,
thank you for killing that person.
He was a terrorist and he was,
you know,
trying to,
trying to rape my daughter.
They were happy we were there.
What is Ramadi like now?
It's been overrun by Isis.
There.
They keep saying now that there's going
to be an effort by the Iraqi military to
take it back and God blessed them and
good luck.
They would have to do the exact same
thing.
They're going to have to do the exact
same thing.
It's gonna be it's gonna be tough.
It's going to be really tough and
without the United States military force
backing them up and leading something
like that,
do you think that's even possible?
It's going to be difficult.
It is possible,
but is absolutely going to be difficult.
It's gonna be very difficult.
That's one of the things that again,
you know and leadership and leadership
is such an important thing.
It's such an important thing because it
really does change.
It changes every variable in a situation
and so when you have good leaders,
you you can win and I don't know who in
particular is in charge of this Iraqi
force that's going in there.
The Iraqis have some very strong
leadership and if they've got the right
person in position,
they will be able to take it back.
Now America has absolutely has
incredible military leaders,
some incredible military leaders,
and when you,
when you have to step up and lead of an
assault like that on a city,
I mean American leadership would be,
would absolutely make a change and would
be extremely positive for the situation
on the ground.
Do you think that America should go back
into Iraq?
Well,
first of all,
we're already back in Iraq were on the
ground.
We got 3,500
troops there.
This is a,
and I hate to answer your question with
a philosophical answer,
but war is very difficult and very
tragic and very evil in its own right,
and so you should be very,
very cautious about pulling that trigger
and initiating a war because horrible
things are going to happen.
Horrible things are gonna happen.
Enemy are going to be killed,
friendly are going to be killed.
Americans are gonna be killed.
Civilians are going to be killed.
This idea that we're going to go into a,
a worn urban environment and we're not
going to kill any civilians.
No civilians are going to die and you
have to understand that.
And I,
I talk about this when people ask me
this question,
there is two types of will that you have
to have if you're going to go to war to
types of will,
one is the will to kill people and like
I said,
it's going to be enemy and you're going
to focus as much as you can on killing
the enemy in some civilians are going to
die there.
That is what is going to happen.
And you have to understand that that is
part of what you are getting into.
So you have to have,
you have to have the will to kill and
you also have to have the will to die
because Americans are going to die and
young men are going to come home in
coffins and that's a horrible thing.
And so if you're going to go to war,
you should be going to war
with a clear vision to win,
to win.
And I think if we have the will and we
have a plan on,
on winning,
then we should.
We should execute that plan.
But if we're hesitant and if we don't
have the will,
then we should stand by until we develop
that will and we can sit outside and we
can shape and we can.
We can try and shape events which we
should.
We should have a leadership role in the
world.
We should be looking out for American
interests.
I know that sounds like taboo language
in this day and age,
but we're America and we should look out
for American interests around the world.
That's what we should be doing.
And there's nothing wrong with that.
That's what other countries are doing.
They're looking out for their interests
and when,
when we're all looking out for our own
interests,
there's a balance and things can move
forward.
So do you think right now with the
limited amount of troops that are in
Iraq,
it's a,
you said 3,500
now at one.
What was it at the height?
I don't know.
Over $100,000.
I mean at the hightest,
probably even close to 200,000.
What would it take to develop that will
that you talk of?
Do you think that the United States
needs to see some other Paris like
event?
I mean we already had September 11th,
they killed 3000 of our
people on our home soil.
Um,
but that was 14 years ago and for a lot
of people that might as well be another
world.
True,
true.
Um,
I,
I got to ask the other day about the
warning signs,
you know,
to do.
Are we paying enough attention to the
warning signs or are there enough
warning signs in it?
I just,
I kind of shake my head.
I mean,
what more warning signs do you need?
Then go watch youtube videos and they're
like,
we are coming to kill you.
We are going to destroy you all that.
What?
That's the warning right there.
The warning has been issued.
Standby for people like me that are
completely on the outside of the
military.
It seems like isis came out of nowhere.
It seems like once Arab spring started
happening,
we started pulling out of Iraq.
All of a sudden you started hearing
about the isl or Isi or isis varies.
They use the term Isi,
which was,
which was ice Islamic state Iraq.
They use that and I think 2007 was the
first time they use that as they started
to take a area over in Syria.
They threw the l on the end of it,
which is Lavonne,
which is the historical name for that,
that region and the other one is Syria.
The SS is so it's the same people.
It's the same people that were there and
will continue to be there until we route
them out.
What the.
What I was getting at was that it wasn't
something that anybody here had heard
about as an organized thing.
We had heard about insurgents in Iraq,
but we had never heard of it in in a
like with a name like like Isis.
Now that it's a name,
it's like an identifiable enemy and when
you're in a war against terrorism,
one of the things that I think kind of
freaks Americans out,
especially those that don't have a
connection with the military,
is this idea of a war against terrorism
is,
is this open ended proposition?
There is no enemy,
you know,
like the Er,
there's no,
there's no definitive end to this.
Like when Japan surrendered,
World War II was over,
people were kissing in the streets,
that iconic image of the sailor kissing
his girlfriend in the street that we
didn't,
none of that happened for us in this
country.
There was no definitive ending and when
we've pulled out of Iraq and we're
planning on pulling out of Afghanistan
and then we see isis build up and get
bigger and stronger and scarier and we
see what happened in Paris and we see
what happened in Lebanon and in Nigeria
and we see these terrorist attacks and
we're like,
well wait,
when is this?
Is there ever going to be a point where
we have a soldier and his girlfriend
kissing in the street is they're going
to be an end.
Is there going to be a confetti
billowing in the main street?
And a parade doesn't
seem like it.
I would say that that's an accurate
assessment that it doesn't seem like it.
Yeah.
We got a long fight,
you know,
and,
and you asked where did isis,
how do we start hearing about them?
Well,
the same thing we were talking about
earlier.
Social media.
Yeah.
They've got social media.
They're aiming it at,
you know,
a disenchanted people all around the
world that can cling onto something that
will give them some sort of a identity.
Yeah.
That's one of the most bizarre things
about this.
When you see people like these young
girls from the UK joining Isis and you
know,
they're escaping their country and going
over there and joining isis.
Like what,
what is happening here?
Like how disenchanted do you have to be
where that looks attractive to you?
The two girls,
I'm sure you saw this in the two poster
girls for Isis,
uh,
one of them died three to six months ago
and they just got the latest report on
the other one that was trying to escape
Isis and they beat her to death.
Yeah.
Did me
unquestionably.
It seems to be a growing force in a more
dangerous force.
Every day I got,
again,
I think it was on twitter,
someone hit me the other day on twitter,
um,
you know,
this is an idea and you can't bomb ideas
was the,
was the statement to me and you know,
I try and avoid getting into these
massive sort of political debates or
whatever,
um,
especially with 140 characters.
And that being said,
um,
Nazi-ism was an idea that was defeated
through military force.
Slavery in America was an idea that was
defeated by military force.
Imperial Japan was an idea and to
religion that was defeated by military
force and none of those ideas would have
stopped without military force.
And this is an idea that can be defeated
with bombs.
And this is also an idea that
unfortunately in this country gets
connected to all Muslims.
The idea behind what these people are do
or doing gets connected to all Muslims.
When in reality,
most of the Muslims in the world,
they don't want something like isis to
be in control.
They don't want to be in a perpetual
state of war.
They don't want to have to worry about
these quote unquote savages.
And what they're doing,
yeah,
I mean the isis has killed hundreds of
thousands of.
Well,
I dunno,
I dunno what the number is,
but we know that isis has killed
thousands and thousands and thousands of
Muslims,
you know,
they went into Ramadi and killed
hundreds and hundreds of Muslims that
had worked in some way with the
coalition forces that they could have a
peaceful city.
They murdered them all.
So let's say Donald Trump becomes
president and uh,
he listens to your podcast with Tim
Ferriss and he read your book and he
goes,
Jocko,
I'm coming to you for advice.
What do I do?
I don't know why I said Donald Trump for
president.
I'm hoping that that's our own isis.
Let's whatever.
Fill in the blank.
New President person becomes a known
size head person.
I didn't even go with woman or man.
Uh,
what,
what would you do if you were,
if you were in a leadership position,
if you were in a position to make a
decision or to,
uh,
to start a process,
what would you do?
We would destroy them.
You would just go right back in.
We would destroy them and you think that
that's what America should do right now?
Yes.
It is a cancer that is growing.
It is malignant and it needs to be
destroyed.
So what steps would you take?
Like what?
What would you do if you were in a
position of power right now?
You know,
it's interesting.
People get this idea that this is some
crazy complex situation and it's going
to be all hard and all this.
I could pull together like two first
lieutenants from the Marine Corps,
which is like the junior officer in the
marine corps and say come up with a plan
to defeat isis.
You got two hours and they do it and
it'd be a good plan.
This is not a complex situation.
How many people you're dealing with when
you talking about Isis?
I don't know.
Twenty thousand,
10,000?
4,000.
100,000
stuff to tell it.
Yeah.
It's tough to tell.
It doesn't matter.
You assess it,
you make you,
you bring what you need to the table and
you defeat them.
So what do you think is holding back
from us doing something like,
I have no idea.
Is it frustrating to you?
Yes.
Because if you got kids and you see the,
again,
a malignant cancer on humanity that is
growing unchecked when we have,
we're,
we're like the master surgeons that have
the ability to go in and eradicate this
disease and instead of doing that we're
just,
we're just not doing anything.
So do you blame this,
the current administration?
Do you blame the,
the climate of the American public right
now?
The political climate where people just
don't want to be involved in another war
or enter into another prolonged
interaction?
I think people are always looking for
the easiest way out and going in as a
hard decision to make.
It's a very hard decision to make and
it's be very unpopular decision and it
would be the short term pain that
everyone's afraid of.
That's what one of the things that's so
disconcerting to me about drones because
it seems to me that what drones are is a
way
that we can avoid American casualties so
people don't complain about it as much.
So we send this robot in there to fly in
and then launch missiles and the good
thing is it doesn't create American
casualties,
but the bad thing is it doesn't seem to
be nearly as effective.
It's sort of a wishy washy attempt in
some ways at war it seems almost like it
would be something that would,
you would use in a supplement as,
as well as a military attack.
Like they would be a part of it instead
of being the only thing that you used to
try to combat these people.
Does that make sense?
I don't know if we have enough drones to
get the job done and they're effective,
but I mean a drone is going to take out.
I Dunno.
Twenty,
20 bad guys.
So that'd be a lot of drones in action.
I don't know if we have that kind of
capability yet,
but we will someday.
You know,
someday we'll have a robot army and
we'll be dealing with some terminator
type situation,
right?
Yes.
But right now it's almost like a,
we need to get smacked.
Like something needs to happen before we
hit back and I can't,
I cannot in good conscience agree with
you because I don't even want to say
those words.
Yeah.
You know,
it's just a horrible thing.
You don't want to put it out.
It's a horrible thought.
Yeah.
Especially when you start talking about
a dirty bomb,
you know,
and like,
Oh,
here's a sector of America that no one
can live in anymore because it's been
contaminated.
It's radioactive now mean.
That's real.
And again,
for some reason the warning signs which
can be seen,
you know,
anywhere you look,
we're ignoring them.
I think people mean speaking for myself
and speaking for the people that I come
in contact with,
I think people are becoming more and
more concerned about isis on a pretty
much daily basis.
I think one thing that Paris did do is
it woke a lot of people up as two
possibilities that something like this
can happen and that this isn't the end
and this is,
this is ramping up and if they have the
kind of resources to pull off something
like the Paris attacks,
who knows where this is going.
Totally agree with you.
It is a very scary time.
What do you think is going to happen if
you had to guess,
what do I think is going to happen in
terms of the terrorist attack in
America?
No,
no.
In terms of our approach to dealing with
something like Isis.
Yeah.
I think it's very difficult to predict
the future,
but not not to be just a big cop out
over here.
I'm not trying to do that to you,
but there's so many different ways that
this could go and you know,
now you've thrown Russia into the mix
because they took down the Russian
airline.
You've got a guy like Putin who is a
gangster.
You know,
and I say that in both contexts of have
negative and positive.
I mean,
the guy
in a negative way,
he's a gangster that's,
that's like scary with his thought
process and at the same time like props,
the guy's a gangster and he's going to
smash them people you've got now,
Turkey in the mix.
I mean,
it's just a very,
it's a complex situation that's getting
more complex all the time.
And the scariest part about it is that
America is not in a leadership position.
We are not influencing the world the way
we once did.
We are not.
People are not looking to us as the,
as the leaders there were in the
backseat.
And that's scary.
We should be in a leadership position.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Is Not bad to have a benevolent country
and,
and I know people are going to go crazy.
But uh,
uh,
generally benevolent country that's
sitting here,
you know,
given billions of dollars of aid around
the world,
never taken any soil and kept it.
I mean,
we've,
you know,
I guess in modern times we've never
taken any soil and kept it.
We've given Germany back to Jeremy.
We gave Japan back to Japan.
You know,
we've,
we're,
we're a fairly benevolent country.
Again,
I know we've got faults,
I know we've done things wrong in the
past.
I'm sure we'll do things wrong in the
future,
but to have us not in a leadership
position is a very disturbing time.
And when you say that we're not in a
leadership position,
what do you think the shift is and where
do you think had happened?
I think it's been happening and I think,
you know,
I think the current administration is
definitely not,
um,
as experienced as you would hope and I
think there's a lot of,
a lot of naive attitudes about what the
rest of the world is like.
So this administration you think was the
beginning of the shift away from America
being in a leadership position?
Yes.
What do you,
what kind of a president do you think
would change that?
Somebody that has a better understanding
of the nature of the world,
like a John McCain type guy?
Yeah.
Maybe like a,
like,
you know,
again,
I'm not going to sit here and try and
think of who the best presidential
candidate would be.
I mean,
we have a hard time figuring that out in
America as a whole,
but again,
you look at a guy like,
you look at a guy like Putin and you
look at a guy like Obama.
Putin's
whole existence has been geared towards
this,
you know what I mean?
A KGB guy.
I mean,
he's been a player on the world stage
and a part of it for his whole life and
he's got an acute understanding of it
and he's a black belt,
you know,
he's a legit black belt and you just see
these other,
um,
uh,
you see the,
the naivete of,
of this administration.
And it's,
it's,
it's really hard to.
It's hard to understand.
It was one thing that Obama said it was
yesterday or today that just drove me
crazy.
He was talking about the attack on
planned parenthood in Colorado Springs
and he said things like,
this don't happen in other countries.
It's like,
how the fuck do you say that?
Just days after what happened in Paris,
I was reading that just today before we
started the podcast.
I was reading it.
I was like,
that is one of the craziest things that
someone could say after hundreds of
people were killed in Paris because he's
talking about it in terms of gun
violence from a religious perspective
that what the fuck happened in Paris?
What it.
Because it's not about babies.
It's different.
Like.
Yeah,
and he,
I mean,
he said something the other day too was
I'm not interested in some notion of
America leading and winning.
What does that mean exactly?
That's.
Yeah,
it's very,
uh,
it's just,
it's an,
it's,
it's very disturbing.
What does that mean?
What did anybody ask him to qualify that
or knows one of bands kind of speaking?
Yeah,
that's a weird statement for the guy
who's the commander and chief of the
greatest army the world has ever known,
interested in staying,
number one.
I think the,
the,
the concept of a benevolent leader,
the of a benevolent nation,
you know,
if you,
if you do concede that the world,
we're always being chaos and there will
always be at least in terms of like
foreseeable future,
you know,
the next one,
hundred years or whatever we're,
we're in until something crazy happens.
I mean it would have to be something
monumental life changing that,
that stops conflict all around the
world.
You'd have to,
if you were rational,
pragmatic person and you're looking at
the future,
you'd have to say,
well,
we're going to have conflict.
Especially if you look at places like
the Congo or parts of the Middle East
where people don't count and there's
places where like you would have to
educate them to the point where the
future would look radically different
than the present.
Right?
So if that's the case,
if,
if conflict will be something that we're
going to have to mitigate,
no matter what,
wouldn't you want to be the one that
gets to decide?
Wouldn't you want to be the person in a
position of power?
Yes.
You would be.
It's like the is a much smaller scale,
but this is what I've always tried to
tell people when they say,
why would you want to learn martial
arts?
And what I always say is you don't want
to learn martial arts because you want
to go beat somebody up.
You want to learn martial arts for two
things,
one,
because you want to learn how to
overcome incredibly difficult things,
and in martial arts you're going to
encountered times where you want to
quit.
You're gonna get your ass kicked.
It's going to be difficult and it's
extremely difficult to get good at it
too.
If you do get into a situation,
you want to be the one who gets to
choose whether or not someone gets hurt.
You don't want to be helpless because
being helpless is a terrible place to
be,
but it doesn't necessarily mean that
you're going to go out and fuck people
up and that's sort of the same idea on a
macro scale that you would look at the
concept of America being a benevolent
entity or benevolent superpower.
Absolutely.
One hundred percent,
right?
You know,
I mean,
you know,
it's,
it goes with everything that we do and
when I say we,
I'm talking about you,
you know,
you train,
you work out,
you try to be strong,
you know,
you keep yourself aware of what's
happening.
It's not because you want to go around
kicking people's asses,
it's because you don't want to have to
kick everyone's ass.
You know,
people are not looking at Joe Rogan be
like,
Oh,
I'm going to beat him up right now.
Now they're going out of that guy.
I know he trains all the time and if
someone gets in your face,
they're going to know that immediately.
You know that when you can tell,
you can tell by the way someone carries
themselves what,
you know,
what they have and what they know,
what they understand.
Uh,
you know,
I got asked the other day,
if you were president,
you know,
you asked me if I was got advice.
They said if you were president,
what would you do with Isis?
And I said if I was president,
Isis would not exist.
President Jocko happen.
They would not exist because
we would have a presence in the world
that would prevent the growth of this
kind of ideology,
but what kind of a reaction do you think
you would have from the American public?
From the insulated American public?
I mean,
we're with,
this is probably one of the most
sensitive times ever in terms of they
throw around the term Islamophobia.
If you even criticize anyone that just
happens to be Muslim.
I mean we're.
We're in a strange time when it comes to
incredibly sensitive,
maybe hypersensitive people that maybe
don't have a good grip on reality.
Well,
what would you do?
Take them over there and buses.
Yeah,
that'd be one thing.
That'd be the way.
It's interesting because I've already
talked about this
Islamophobia.
I mean I fought alongside these Muslims.
I fought alongside them to help them.
My friends did and America did.
We fought alongside these people to try
and help them and we did.
So how that gets twisted in some world
to where you know,
we're,
we're not,
we're evil is completely beyond me.
Well,
I think because there is legit
Islamophobia out there in the world,
just like there's a.
there's a legit hatred of Christians.
There's legit hatred of Mormons.
I mean,
you're going to find groups of people
that are hated and there's also people
that aren't willing to look deeper,
deeper into some some global issue.
If you have a global issue that there's
these people that call themselves isis
or al or whatever they call themselves
and you know,
they call themselves the Islamic state.
You Owe Islam.
Oh,
Islams bad.
Muslims are bad.
Muslims are evil.
I was watching some thing.
There was A.
Sam Harris had posted up on twitter.
There was this guy who is,
I believe it was in Virginia.
He was a at a like county,
one of those meetings where you're
talking about building something in the
town and he was.
He was talking about putting up a mosque
and these people were screaming at him
that Muslims are evil and you're evil.
Cult is not going to come into our town
and you're trying to invade our town and
get out of here with your evil called.
I'm like,
okay.
That's Islamophobia.
That's right there.
I mean,
you're talking about a peaceful guy who
just wants to be able to worship his,
you know,
his ideas,
his religion in peace in this place.
He wants to build a mosque and people
want to,
you know,
they're furious at this guy.
That's real Islamophobia.
Right.
But there's a big difference between
something like that and what's going on
in other parts of the world with Isis.
A giant,
giant difference.
And I think that when people want to
throw around that term Islamophobia,
I think a lot of times what they're
doing is they're just trying to be
correct.
They're trying to be politically correct
socially correct,
that trying to be sensitive and they're
trying to let everybody know that
they're not racist,
xenophobic,
Islamophobic or whatever,
that they're open minded and
progressive.
So they're throwing around these terms
and it kind of clouds the water.
Okay.
I mean these are the,
these people are running around calling,
you know,
Islamophobia.
I don't know.
No one's ever called me that.
Not yet.
I'm sure they will get already today on
twitter.
Yeah.
I don't see them happening right now.
I don't,
I don't see how he could,
I don't see how they could do that.
You know,
again,
we,
we fought alongside Muslim people,
we ate with them,
we put our lives in their hands and they
put their hand,
their lives in our hands and you know,
America and my friends were killed
trying to help them.
So how I'm a person that could be called
an Islamophobia is,
is kind of a stretch I think.
Yeah.
Well it rationally,
but you're talking about people that
aren't necessarily rational.
Well,
you know,
people paint their own layers onto
things and make them into what they're
not.
Well,
I think it's symptomatic of what's going
on with,
with our culture too,
is that this,
these hypersensitive oversimplistic
ideas and,
and people that that would say these
things like this don't have a real grip
like you have of what it's like over
there and I don't think anybody does
other than people like you that have
been over there and had been in combat.
I don't think it's possible.
I think that's one of the problems that
we have.
We're behaving like children and a lot
of ways because we really have never had
to live on our own.
Yeah.
And it's,
it's,
it's actually very similar to what we
were talking about earlier with the
traditional martial arts where you can
sit there in your fantasy world and
think that your ci is going to protect
you and that as long as you spread love,
you're going to be protected because
your ci is strong and until you've been
in a fistfight,
you're gonna believe that.
And so that,
that's Kinda like what you're saying.
Do we need to get spanked or do we need
to get into a fistfight before America
realizes like,
oh no,
there's real problems in the world that
need to be handled.
This is one of the weirdest times
everybody have been in my act about,
um,
this is the first time ever where
someone broke into the White House or if
you know that in 2014 was the first time
anybody had gained access and there was
a woman guardian,
front door was unarmed woman caught in
the front door and a woman who's in
charge of secret service because
diversity and one of my favorite parts
was,
there was an article written about when
the guy knocked the chick over,
ran inside and they said it was reviewed
and gender wasn't an issue.
Well,
we're okay.
Yeah,
that makes lot of sense.
Like Brock Lesnar was guarding the door.
The same thing would've happened.
The guy would've knocked him over and he
would have.
No one would have ever caught the guy
you just want to ran by and that's
fucking ridiculous.
But it's that same kind of crazy
thinking politically correct,
asinine thinking.
You should have a fucking team if you're
going to make the president sleep in a
house that's in the park,
should probably have a team of fucking
assassins surrounding that building at
all times and you should keep a lookout
for dudes that are sprinting across the
lawn,
knocking over chicks that are guardian
the front door.
There's no doubt about it,
but it's the same thing.
It's like we're so soft and we're so
used to being in this insulated world
that we have here,
this nice sweet bubble where we drive
our eight mile per hour or eight mile
per gallon suv.
I don't know how you would ever really
illuminates all these problems that
you're bringing up.
I don't know how you get get these.
I mean to the hand of the average
citizen,
like in World War II that you and me,
if we were 13 years old,
we weren't old enough to serve.
We still knew that there was a war going
on because we couldn't eat steak.
We couldn't use any metal.
We were gardening at night.
We were shutting off the lights like we
were impacted.
All of America was impacted at the
height of the battle of Ramadi,
the height of it,
at the height of the war of Iraq at the
height of the war of Afghanistan,
America,
Americans at the mall.
We're not impacted at all at all,
at all.
Not only that,
they weren't even allowed to show
photographs of coffins,
so the first time ever in the history of
the United States,
a history of the United States taking
pictures during war time where they made
it illegal to show photos of coffins,
which is just absolutely insane.
Like,
how,
how are you going to let people
understand what's happening if you don't
even allow journalists to show
photographs of coffins?
It's the,
it's the bubble.
You're talking about the same situation.
What made you decide to leave the
military?
Well,
a bunch of things.
I mean,
it wasn't like one day I woke up and
said,
all right,
I'm done.
Uh,
you know,
obviously if,
if you haven't caught this up to this
point,
I loved.
I loved the seal teams.
Yeah.
I loved being in the military.
I'm at the 20 year mark.
I had a bunch of different things that
kind of weighed in,
you know,
I had a family that I hadn't seen or
didn't know pretty much.
So you start thinking,
well,
you know,
maybe I should pay attention to them a
little bit.
I had completed sort of my last real job
operational job in the seal teams and it
was going to be a long time before I was
in command again,
have a seal team or have something that
was important and from a war fighting
perspective.
So that was kind of kind of another
thing that I looked at that was tough.
And,
and yeah,
I just,
I guess I,
that's it.
That's it really.
So what was your transition?
How long ago did you begin to get out?
I got out in 2010.
Wow.
So this is five years ago.
Five years.
Yep.
And what was your transition was?
We uh,
started this company where we go and
work with civilian companies doing
leadership and management and you know,
my,
my buddy life that I was talking about
earlier,
who was one of the platoon commanders
that was with me and Ramadi and you
know,
he,
he had run into a company I had run into
a company and they asked us to do some
stuff and the next thing you know,
you know,
I gave one,
one kind of leadership training to
accompany and then they said,
come back and train all of our
divisions.
And then the parent company of that
company watched me and said,
hey,
can you come to our CEO Summit?
And then went to the CEO Summit and then
a bunch of those ceos said,
Hey,
can you come?
And then the next thing you know,
I'm doing this.
So what is the,
what is the process like when you're,
when you're doing these,
uh,
these speeches are,
you're setting things up,
how do you organize them and what you,
you obviously your lifetime was in the
military,
right?
So what was it about you and about what
you brought to the table that was so
attractive to them?
I think it's because the principles of
leadership and that's where we,
that's what we talk about and that's
what we teach is leadership.
The principals leadership do change
whether you're,
whether your mission is to capture kill
bad guys or whether your mission is to
manufacture something or sell something
or produce something.
You're trying to.
You got a group of people,
group of individuals and they're going
to be diverse.
They're going to be different.
They're going to have different
intelligence levels.
They're gonna,
have different personalities,
they're gonna,
have different goals,
are gonna have different motivations and
you got to take all those people and
unify them and try and get them to
accomplish a mission in the most
effective and efficient manner.
And that's leadership and it does it.
Like I said,
that those principles that we used in
combat don't change regardless of what
the mission is and what,
what's good.
You know,
and I said this earlier,
life is like combat but amplified and
intensified or combat is combat is like
life.
But amplified and intensified and,
and that means when we tell a story,
like a leadership story about combat,
it,
it's so obvious what the,
what the principal was.
Whereas in the business world,
they might take six months or a year or
maybe you barely even notice what the
failure was,
you know?
And when we sit,
when we,
when we make those stark examples from
combat,
people go,
oh,
I see how we're failing in this too.
And that's,
that's why I think people really took
hold of,
of what we did and how we put it across.
So this was something that you were
approached to do.
This wasn't an idea that you had had and
you thought about this will be my new
thing.
Yeah.
And I mean,
regardless of all this garbage that I
talk in my life and I've always telling
people to like plan and be prepared.
Yeah.
I,
I almost completely fell into this with
the fact that,
you know,
someone said,
hey,
can you come and talk to my people about
leadership?
And I said,
well,
yeah,
I've been talking about leadership for
last several years in the seal teams and
I've been in leadership position in some
pretty tough situations and you know,
that's just,
that's just happened.
Now,
do you teach a course or is this a,
is this like a one time seminar type of
a thing?
We do both.
Well,
so sometimes we go in,
you know,
and we'll do like a keynote speech and
those are good.
Those are good.
Those are great,
you know,
we get a lot of positive feedback about
those,
but then sometimes we'll go in with
company and we've done like two year
contracts with companies where we've
trained everybody that they have and we
get all their leadership aligned on the
same page and,
and we'll,
we'll go in for maybe a couple of an
assessment,
we'll look and see what,
learn about what business they're in,
will learn about what they're doing,
how they're doing it,
we'll see what areas they can improve
on.
We'll formulate a plan around that and
it will come back and we'll train
leadership.
That's fascinating.
So you have to kind of construct a
course.
Yes,
yes.
I mean the,
the basic,
like I said,
the basic principles are always the
same,
but some organizations have different
problems than other organizations.
They all,
they all have the same,
you know,
five,
seven problems,
you know,
whatever that number is.
Some of them were
really bad at this are really good at
this or they're failing here,
but they're winning here.
So we got to go in and check them out,
see what,
see what the issue is,
and then we get it turned around.
Is this for warding for you d,
do you enjoy doing this?
Yeah,
absolutely.
I mean,
I,
well,
number one,
I can talk about combat all day long and
I can talk about.
And even more than that,
I can talk about leadership all day long
because it's,
it's,
it's the,
it's the most challenging thing.
The most challenging thing about being
in combat in a leadership position is
not,
you know,
trying to figure out what the enemy's
going to do and trying to,
trying to organize a good plan.
The most challenging thing is dealing
with all these human beings that that's
the challenging thing is getting these
guys and girls to do what they need to
do,
what you need them to do,
to get them to believe in it.
That's what's challenging.
And we definitely learned lessons
positive and negative.
You know,
that's one thing about our book that
people have gotten a lot of feedback is
this book isn't like,
Hey,
look what we did.
Look how awesome we are.
No,
this book is.
A lot of those chapters in that book
are,
Hey,
this is what we screwed up.
Here's the failure that happened.
This was a horrible situation and it was
my fault.
That's where we learn the lessons.
And I think that's what's made people
relate to it more because we're not just
saying,
hey,
we're the greatest thing in the world.
No,
we were,
uh,
we were humbled by combat.
We were,
we were humbled by the enemy.
We were humbled by our own guys that did
amazing things when we were around.
So I think that's a little bit different
as well.
And again,
I think that's one of the things that
makes peep that appeals to the people is
they look at this and they go,
oh,
I can relate to that.
I can understand it.
I've failed to.
I made a mistake.
Oh,
how did they handle it?
they did this.
Okay,
got it.
When you're talking about combat,
you're talking about people organizing
and staying together and figuring out
how to lead.
You're talking about these extreme
consequences,
the most extreme ever.
And when you have these extreme
consequences,
obviously when there's a lot on the
line,
people are going to focus and some
people are going to fall apart and some
people are going to pull together,
but you're gonna,
you're gonna.
Get people that understand the gravity
of the situation.
It would seem to me that it would be
much harder to impart that into people
in the business world.
Amplified and intensified.
So in combat lives are at stake.
Absolutely.
In business world,
have you ever had to fire anyone before?
No.
It sucks.
Have you ever had people lose their job
and couldn't pay their mortgage and feed
their kids because you screwed up as a
boss?
No.
That's pressure.
That is mass.
Have you ever lost hundreds of millions
of dollars worth of capital because you
made a bad decision?
No,
but you know why?
It's because I'm not a leader.
See,
so there's good things and not being a
leader is the,
the benefits of non-leadership.
So,
so you know,
we,
when people asked me that question is to
ask that question all the time.
I'm like,
Hey,
it's not about,
it's not about lives,
but it's about livelihoods,
right?
You've got people that are relying on
you to succeed and win and again,
sure you get killed in combat.
That's obviously the worst thing that
can happen,
but if you lose your job or you know
your,
your people lose their jobs.
Many people killed themselves all the
time.
When they make bad business decisions,
it's that much pressure.
It's that much pressure for sure.
And so that's why it does translate
because business people relate to that
amount of pressure and they understand
how it feels to,
to have that bearing down on them.
It just seems to me for a guy like you
that maybe you will be even more
attracted to going into business then
you would be to teaching people how to
lead their businesses better.
Yeah.
And I'm in,
it is a business where you a business
and it is definitely what we're doing.
Um,
and that being said,
for me to now go into business,
I'd have to learn some new business.
Well,
why not just take the skills that I do
have,
which is,
you know,
we know about leadership.
So let's just help other people.
And that is rewarding.
It's very rewarding to talk to someone
and have them go,
I did what you told me to do and this is
the result.
This is the outcome that's very
rewarding.
And,
and another piece of it is,
you know,
everything always ties to me back to
America.
The,
the,
the businesses in this country are the
economic power of this nation.
And our economic power is the backbone
of our authority in the world.
And so to help businesses grow and
achieve is,
is very rewarding because I know that
it's a,
it's a very patriotic thing to do.
Capitalism is,
is,
is a very patriotic piece of America.
That's an interesting perspective.
That's an interesting way to look at the
big picture.
And I agree with you.
I'm going to say something that people
hate me saying,
but I'm gonna say it because I need to
say it to you.
You should have a podcast.
People always get mad at me because I
say this all the time to interesting
guests,
but this is not something that's
difficult to do and you'd be fucking
great at it.
And I think that your perspective on the
military and your perspective on our,
our,
our situation overseas I think would be
very unusual,
very unusual and very educated.
And I just think there's,
there's no one out there that's doing it
like,
like you could do it.
Well we definitely,
I've,
you're not.
The first person said that to me.
As a matter of fact,
when Tim Ferriss,
like we got done with the podcast and he
pressed stop on the thing and he just
looked up at me and said,
you need to do your own podcast for him.
I've talked to.
I've talked to some of my,
some of my,
some of my buddies about it.
And uh,
we're,
we're working.
You have to do man.
Get a fucking phone.
Yeah.
Phone.
Press record,
you know,
sit down with people.
It's not hard to do.
It's easy.
Trust me.
No,
it's,
uh,
it's interesting too,
and I'm getting over the fact of,
uh,
like I told you earlier,
I'm like,
I,
like I said on the Tim Ferriss program,
you know,
people that just talk for no reason and
it's hard for me to get used to like the
fact that somebody wants to hear
what I have to say that's not,
you know,
a seal or you know,
a direct businessperson.
But,
uh,
I'm definitely,
you know what,
I'll probably end up doing something
with it.
Well,
I think you know,
great military leaders,
whether it's Zau,
it's sung sue,
the art of war,
whether it's me,
a motive Musashi from the book of five
rings,
Great Warriors from the past have
written books that civilians have gotten
a lot out of and I think that someone
like you instead of writing a book and
your book,
I'm sure it's great and I'm sure there's
a lot of lessons in that,
but on a daily basis to be able to do
something like this.
Anytime you want,
just fire up your podcast anytime.
Something like Paris,
like the Paris attack happens.
You could give your perspective
instantaneously uploaded onto the
Internet and it's just never been a time
like that.
It's wonderful that we could sit down
and read what [inaudible] Musashi wrote
hundreds of years ago.
I mean,
it's.
It's amazing.
It's interesting you should say,
to try to peer into the mind of one of
the greatest swordsman that ever lived
and see his philosophies on life,
but I think that today with the advent
of the Internet and with the ability to
broadcast yourself virtually
instantaneously,
I think you could.
You could make a gigantic impact in
sharing that perspective and taking
those experiences that you have so
deserved and so earned and,
and giving people this insight that
there's just,
they're just not going to get it.
You know,
I'm getting it from you.
Like I said,
I got it from you from that Tim Ferriss
episode and I'm getting it even more
from you now.
It's a perspective.
You're just not going to get from
someone who wasn't there.
You're just not going to get it.
You're going to get these fuzzy,
but it's like two people sit.
You ever heard two people talk about
martial arts?
Don't know shit about martial arts,
you know,
that's what it's like to hear someone
like me talk about the military.
Really?
Yeah.
And it's,
it's again,
it's another thing that,
that is a,
I'm
sorting out in my own head,
which is this idea of broadcasting
myself.
Uh,
it's just,
it's just weird.
I mean,
you grew up,
you were into this,
you know,
I think you,
you've been a comedian for your pretty
much your whole adult life for 26 years,
so 26 years you were getting on stage.
That's what you wanted to do.
And honestly,
when I first joined the seal teams,
that was the most frowned upon thing was
to be broadcasting yourself that you
were a seal,
that you were at what you did and it.
And it took me a long time.
I mean,
right.
Writing this book was a,
was a,
it's,
it's a really hard thing to do because
you sit there and you,
you know,
you,
you're,
you're supposed to be humble,
right?
You're a warrior.
You're supposed to be humble.
Okay,
well I'm going to write a big book about
myself.
I mean that just did,
that just doesn't work.
And so it was really hard and,
and Lafe and I,
that was one of the biggest things that
we did as we edited it and edited it and
edited it.
We went through it just to just to make
sure that we were coming across and
saying things in a manner that really
reflected that humility,
which again,
it's very hard to do because it's a
dichotomy.
It's a dichotomy because you're saying,
hey,
you got to be humble as a leader,
but I'm gonna read a big book about
myself.
You know what I mean?
It's just crazy.
And so when you're sitting here like,
oh,
you should have a podcast and I'm
thinking,
you know,
you should broadcast yourself.
And again,
with the way I was raised because you
spent your whole adult life in comedy,
I spent my whole adult life in the seal
teams and I was raised by these old
Vietnam guys that were bad asses and
they were like,
oh,
you don't talk about this.
Right?
And so I'm kind of going against this
the way I was raised and,
and so again I'm,
I'm getting over it,
I'm trying to get over it,
but at the same time I don't want to get
completely over it because that's part
of,
you know,
that's part of the way I was raised and
what I believe in.
Even
I see their point of view.
I,
I totally understand why they would say
you don't talk about it,
but what I think the benefit of talking
about it today as opposed to their time
is through the Internet.
You can broadcast in a way that would be
like,
look,
no one's going to take a navy seal back
in the day and give them a gigantic
television show where they could say
whatever the fuck they wanted,
broadcast anytime they wanted.
But if you have a successful podcast,
you can reach hundreds of thousands of
people with each episode,
which is just like a successful
television show.
And because of that,
you have the ability to educate people
and give people this perspective that I
said that I got from you that are just
not getting.
I'm not getting from anybody else unless
they've been there,
but I get it from you.
I get it from Tim Kennedy.
I get it from Brian Stann.
I get it from Andy.
Stop.
I get it from people that have been
there and you.
You get a different perspective than
you're ever going to get from someone
who's just pontificating or guessing
waxing poetically on the nature of man
and war.
It's all bullshit.
Until you talk to someone who's actually
been there,
you don't really understand what they're
saying.
I think that I think it would be
gigantic.
I really think you should do it.
I really.
I really think it would help a lot of
people.
I think it would help a lot of people
understand from the perspective of
someone who actually knows what they're
talking about and there's not a lot of
that in the world.
I think this is also what you're talking
about when you're talking about the
leadership in this country.
It's.
I don't.
I don't know if you should be someone
who has served in the military in order
to qualify for being the president,
but I don't think it's a bad idea to
throw it out there to to say that at the
very least you should spend some time
living in these environments where we're
involved in massive conflict.
At the very least you should visit them,
spend a lot of time with the people who
have lived and served and fought in
these countries.
So you understand
clearly with no fuzziness at all.
What the fuck is going on in the world?
Well,
there's no doubt that I think military
service.
I mean
it was so good for me.
It was so good for me.
And would it be good for everybody would
have been about Jamie over there?
Look at him.
I don't know either.
So you just said,
I don't know.
I'm not 100 percent sure.
I guarantee Jamie would get it all out
of.
I'm sure he wouldn't get it.
I guarantee you.
But he might wind up like that dude and
full metal jacket with a rifle in the
bathroom.
Private Kyle.
Yet.
So,
uh,
yeah,
um,
I,
I did,
you know,
in the military,
did the military was great for me and,
and,
but again,
you,
you were born for this.
I mean this is like something you were
drawn to,
like a magnet to metal filings.
Yeah,
no,
I was,
I was drawn to it,
but
I was still like,
when I joined my dad,
my dad said to me,
uh,
you're going to hate it because you hate
authority.
That's what my dad said to me.
I was like,
okay,
uh,
and,
you know,
that gives you an indication as to what
kind of kid I was.
I was completely out of control and
didn't listen to anybody and I was
probably similar to what you were like,
I'm guessing,
um,
you know,
I was just now to control kid that just
did whatever.
And so joining the military it put it,
put the structure around me and all of a
sudden I could take all this energy that
I had.
And,
and what's really nice about is you get
this clean slate where they're like,
okay,
if you do this,
you'll be successful.
Here's what you do.
Check these boxes and I was like,
okay,
I'm ready to do those things,
and you just do them and you develop the
discipline.
The discipline,
and I talk about that all the time.
You know,
the,
the fact that discipline equals freedom
and the more discipline you have as a
human,
the more freedom you're going to have,
which is completely counterintuitive.
You know,
people think,
oh,
you're living this discipline lifestyle,
so that means you,
you,
you don't have any freedom.
And it's actually the exact opposite.
I have freedom because I have
discipline,
I have,
you know,
financial freedom because I have
financial discipline,
I have more time,
I have more time because I have the
discipline to get up in the morning
before most normal people get up.
Those are the kinds of disciplines that
you put in place.
And those definitely get instilled
through the military.
Well,
I think the one thing that disciplined
definitely does help you with is it
helps you get things done and when you
get things done,
when you,
you actually do things,
you,
you have more success.
If you have more success and sometimes a
big part of success is just not being
fucking lazy and just doing it,
just get.
That's like 90 percent of it is just
showing up,
get there and start working like you're
not going to feel perfect every day.
If I felt,
if I only worked out when I felt good,
I'd be a fat fuck because there's a lot
of days I don't want to do it.
I've been pretty much the same with
everybody that that actually gets good
at something that you get.
There's got to be those days you pushed
through and they're probably going to be
more numerous than the days you don't.
And so the benefit of discipline in my
eyes has always been that through
discipline I get things done.
I always tell them,
I always say that I'm like the most lazy
disciplined person I know because I
don't want to do it,
but I always do.
And I'd be interesting to get your
perspective on this,
this statement.
So I also think that discipline is,
is a pathway to creativity.
And I'll tell you when I talk about
creativity is another misconception
about the military when you're on the
battlefield is an absolute exercise in
creativity.
Okay?
I already talked about how you're going
to lead these people.
What are you going to do?
How you're going to influence them,
how you going to talk to them?
How are you going to say the right
things?
That's creativity.
Now you throw on top of that,
what am I going to do?
The enemy,
how are we going to attack them?
How are we going to disorganize them?
How are we going to get in their heads?
That's all just massive creativity.
And when I look at people that are
artists like yourself,
because you're a standup comedian,
you are,
I would imagine that the more
disciplined you are the,
you know,
you got to get up and write,
you gotta write stuff down.
You got to read and find out about
what's going on in the world so you have
more things that you can jab baton and
make fun of.
You got to increase your vocabulary.
So that you are quicker and sharper so
that when people are saying things that
you have more words to battle back at
them,
all those things,
all that freedom that you get on stage,
it comes from the discipline that you
study.
You learn,
you read,
you write,
you talk,
you go through things.
Is that an accurate state?
Absolutely accurate.
There's a great book on it.
Steven Pressfield wrote a book called
the war of art and press field was
essentially like a ne'er do well until
he was 40 years old.
He was kind of a fuck up and then
figured it out.
Somewhere along the line I figured it
out.
I used to keep a stack of them in my old
studio,
not hand them out to guests if I thought
they needed it.
Take this because trust me,
read this,
because a lot of artists in comics,
I bet musicians as well,
but writers for sure.
One of the big problems is sitting down
and doing the work and you,
you gotta and Pressfield talks about
that in the most concise and beautiful
way and he labels it like an enemy.
He calls it resistance,
you know,
and that you have to sit down and you
have to overcome resistance and that the
pro goes to work and he doesn't matter
if you're sick.
It doesn't matter if you have kids.
It doesn't matter what you,
you're a pro and you go to work and that
just it puts it in your head that this
is what I do and this is what.
And you have pride in that.
And then when you are in front of that
keyboard and you look down the count,
it says I fucking thousand words today,
I put a thousand more than you,
you,
you're doing the work and out of that
work,
gems,
blossom,
little things.
But you might have a day where you just
write nothing but dog shit.
So show up again tomorrow and tomorrow
out of that dark shit,
a flower emerge you never know.
And that's the only way to develop.
Real,
like to,
to really develop your potential.
One hundred percent in anything.
Whether it's as an author or even as a
martial artist.
There's a lot of creativity in martial
arts to be a great striker.
You have to be creative because you have
to.
You have to develop patterns or execute
patterns that are aren't going to be
perceived like if a guy has a real
simple one,
two,
one,
you're going to time that shit and you
were talking before the podcast about
Holly Holmes victory over Rhonda Rousey
and one of the things that we were
talking about was that Rhonda had this
very linear,
straightforward attack.
You knew she was coming and holly is a
master at at countering,
so all she had to do was wait and move
and Rhonda was coming in one direction.
There was no.
There was.
There was no variation.
There was no creativity.
It was a mad bull dog rush that had
worked on everybody else before,
but she found one person who was a
virtuoso at movement and she needed
creativity and it wasn't there and she
needed that experience.
That came with having faced someone who
knew that position and new new had a
deep understanding of that movement and
she didn't have that in their
repertoire.
And so that's the result that we saw.
Like a striker,
like Anderson Silva,
he's extremely creative.
If you watch,
he's got a fight versus Tony Frequent in
cage warriors,
cage warriors.
What the fuck was it called?
In England,
small organization in England where he
practiced this step in upper cut elbow,
like a sideways elbow and his coach was
going,
you're fucking crazy.
Stop practicing that,
and he would make his wife hold a pillow
because it's his coach didn't want him
to practice anymore because he thought
he was wasting his time,
so he practiced stepping.
His wife would hold a pillow for him and
he'd step in and throw this uppercut
elbow.
That's when he knocked out Franklin with
and obviously the Franklin was
outclassed in that fight,
but he wanted to make a point and like
the front kick that he landed the face
of Vito Belfort.
Vito,
I never saw that check coming because
nobody had done that to him before
because nobody had done that in the
history of the UFC.
Nobody had ever knocked anybody out.
With the first kick you learn in martial
arts,
but the creativity to try something like
that,
he would throw punches to your thigh
from standing.
He would throw a jab to your thigh.
He would throw a crescent kick,
an inside crescent kick to your face,
like what the fuck it was.
It was part of what made him such an
effective stryker is that he through
these things that you just didn't expect
him to do.
There's a lot of creativity in Jujitsu.
You know that?
Yeah.
Well,
I got,
you know,
Dean lister and Jeff Glover,
or my guys.
Jeff Glover is one of the most creative
guys in Jujitsu today.
He's one of my favorite.
He does this thing for folks who don't
understand Jujitsu,
don't know what we're talking about.
He does this thing called
a donkey guard.
He's so fucking crazy.
This guy,
he gets on literally,
he faces you with his butt to you and he
launches himself backwards like a donkey
kicking and wraps you up and it looks so
preposterous while he's doing it that so
many guys,
especially when he first started
executing,
it just had no idea what the fuck to do
it.
There is right there.
Got Crazy.
He is,
he's out of his mind.
He so uh,
he so comfortable in every,
like,
you know,
he trains everyday.
We're the same gym and he trains
everyday with whoever and he puts
himself in the most ridiculously
horrible positions.
I'm talking like,
okay,
he'll let people get a rear naked choke
on him.
I mean he all watching them,
like what in God's name,
how was he going?
And he will escape.
He just put himself in horrible
positions all the time just to organize,
just to work on his defense and just to
be in a bad way.
How does he avoid getting hurt?
Because he's not a big guy.
He's super,
super,
super flexible.
I'm like crazy flexible and you know,
he gets dinged up,
but he just is very flexible and he
knows where to put his body,
you know,
he's just a,
he's kind of a freak because I knew that
he had trained with you.
I was gonna ask you like the idea of you
and him training together for folks
listening to this was the majority of
our podcast is audio probably 90 percent
year.
About what to 40 or something like that
to 35.
Yeah.
And Jeff's like,
well,
1:50.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
What the fuck?
That's a big.
I don't want to try.
I weigh 200 pounds.
I don't want to trade with anybody who's
to 10.
The fact that he's 150 pounds and he's
training with gorillas,
know how the fuck he does it.
He does it.
He's just super relaxed and he just
moves and moves really well.
It's amazing.
And you know,
back problems.
He's,
he's all right.
No neck problems.
He is 100 percent at all times.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
Dean's getting little more dinged up.
Do you know Dean looks like he ate a
dean.
I saw him the other day.
I'm like,
what are you,
a 300 fucking pounds and I don't mean it
in a fat way either.
He's huge.
He looks gigantic.
He's,
he's pretty big.
Yeah,
because he'd just been power lifting or
something.
Like what is he doing?
Uh,
I think he just eats a lot,
but it's definitely lifting too because
like food doesn't go right to your neck,
his neck.
He's a genetic,
a genetic mutant.
Another using genetic mutant and yeah,
he's both,
those guys are,
are mutants,
their actual grappling mutants where if
you and I were to like concoct some
weird,
you know,
like potion and create beings,
you'd make like a Jeff Glover because
he's weird.
Flexible,
wirey and you'd be really good.
And then you'd make a dean lister who's
just a big mutant.
Who you,
you when you,
when you catch dean you have to like do
everything perfect.
Because he's,
his defense is really good and he just
doesn't.
It's
really hard to tap him with stuff,
you know,
like he,
like he'll just give people,
you know,
his foot and be like,
yeah,
go for it.
And it takes me like three days.
I'll have to soften his foot up with
like nine foot locks,
then just crank it,
granted grandkids and then,
you know,
on the third day I'll get a deep one and
it'll already be like hurt.
So.
So,
you know,
so you have to soften them up overseas.
Tenderizing meat.
Yeah.
Well that was why it was so shocking
when Josh Barnett tapped him because
Josh Barnett tapped him and like old
school side like headlock joke,
which is a very rare.
It's very rare that you see like a high
level guy that executes that choke.
Like the way Josh did.
Josh has got that old school catch
wrestling knowledge too,
which is just such a different approach
and you get used to a certain approaches
and Josh has a very different approach
and he's a very physically strong guys.
Well yeah,
and I mean Dean is just a dean is a
mutant and he is a gifted,
incredibly gifted grappler.
But his,
you know,
his training methodology and lifestyle
is not really conducive to a competing
like that,
you know,
unfortunately,
that's a nice way of saying he's kind of
lazy.
Let's just make those noises.
Hey,
he,
he could definitely train harder and uh,
you know,
I've,
I've trained with all kinds of guys in
the world,
a world class,
guys all over the place and dean is
absolutely,
you know,
one of those guys that is up there with
like,
you know,
a Hickson who have trained with
Marcello,
but he's like that crazy
good.
Really?
Wow.
Well,
I know he was one of the first real leg
lock masters.
Really understood like,
and,
and um,
uh,
who brought him in to.
I'm into where someone brought him into
adcc pride.
No,
I know he a fuck.
Why am I blanking?
Alan Belcher belcher brought him in when
he fought a WHO's smart,
who's the best leg locker in mma.
And in that fight Alan just stopped
everything Paul Harris threw at him and
literally meet every single movement
that I saw.
I was like,
oh,
that,
that's,
you know,
like I knew exactly what dean had showed
him and exactly what those movements
were.
That's amazing.
What does Dean doing these days?
Is he going to still compete or he's,
you know,
he's teaching Jujitsu
and,
you know,
hanging out.
I'm getting after it,
you know.
Uh,
I would love to see him just like get
completely refocused and make a,
make a run at when an atcc or whatever.
Uh,
one more time before he,
before he hangs it up.
But when you say is dinged up,
like what kind of Shit?
Just normal old,
you know,
Jujitsu Guy,
he's,
his neck will be sore shoulder,
will be heard,
uh,
just that kind of stuff,
you know.
But,
but,
you know,
he is a mutant.
He is a mutant that could,
you know,
if I think,
uh,
he,
he in adcc his last,
I think it was in China,
his match against Buccella when we
churches just a complete beast and you
know,
they went at it and that was a very
close match.
And again,
if you watch training videos of
[inaudible] getting ready for ADCC,
he's training like a complete savage.
I mean,
he's bringing wrestlers in,
he's clean and jerk,
he's flipping tires,
he's doing everything that one does to
prepare for a situation like that.
And,
and dean does not do those types of
things,
you know,
okay,
we'll come in and train a little bit and
go on his natural ability as a mutant
human being to get it done.
It's always frustrating when you see a
guy who is so naturally gifted who kind
of like lays back.
But that's,
it seems to be,
that's a lot of what happens is the
people that are naturally gifted don't
have to work as hard so they don't work
as hard.
It's also part of,
you know,
when I talk about Jeff and dean,
both those guys,
they're both and you know,
you could throw Eddie and then you can
throw all kinds of people into this
category who are,
who are,
uh,
kind of game changers.
You know what I mean?
Well,
you know,
I don't know Eddie that well have hung
out a couple of times,
but I definitely know Jeff and dean and
there they got some,
they got some,
some weird stuff about them,
right?
I mean they got some weird personality
stuff and from my perspective that is,
you know,
know if you didn't have that weird
personality thing than how are you going
to be,
you know,
a 15 year old Jeff Glover and be like,
Oh,
you know what I'm going to do all day.
I'm just going to train Jujitsu all day.
Every day.
I'm going to sit there.
I'm gonna watch the youtube videos.
I'm just going to get good at this.
I'm going to train everyday.
I'm going to compete all over the
country.
I'm just,
that's what I'm going to do.
That's,
you know,
if you're not some.
If you don't have some,
if you're normal,
you're not going to do that on normal
person's like,
oh cool,
I'm going to get a job at Walmart and
then I'm going to do it.
You know,
I'll train it.
I'll train for an hour and half night.
These guys were like,
oh no,
no,
I'm just going to train all day everyday
and I'm going to live in,
you know,
on the mat and dean,
same way.
Like if he didn't have that weird like
spark that made him,
that makes him.
I mean,
he's got some weird like knowledge.
What's weird about him is if you ask
Eddie Bravo about,
you know,
the rubber guard,
he knows all this details about it,
but if you ask them about a full lock or
what,
something that he doesn't know that
well,
he'd be like,
Oh yeah,
a little bit.
You'll ask Dean about something that he
knows nothing like you've never seen him
do before.
And he'll know all these detailed of the
moves and I don't know if he,
I seriously don't know if he goes and
watches it on youtube or if he like
studies or write it down,
but he's got this weird little almost
rain man.
I'm,
you know,
idiot savant type.
Weird thing in his head.
He was one of those guys that had a
really hard time transitioning into mma.
Absolutely.
His striking just never seemed
fluid.
Like,
and he,
I know he worked hard at it.
He just,
for whatever his body is designed for
trap things.
Yeah.
And you see that with everybody because
everyone's got strengths and weaknesses
and everyone's going to be good at
something and bad at something else.
Uh,
you know,
you and I know all of these examples of
people that are like this.
Every fighter,
you know,
he's got some weak area and then you get
occasionally get a guy that liked gsp
that's just like,
well rounded.
Um,
but you know,
everyone,
even even things,
physical things,
physical attributes,
you know,
some people are just super mutant strong
and some people are just super crazy
flexible and some people have
unbelievable natural cardio and some
people don't.
And so it's the people.
Then there's some people that are really
good at grappling.
There's some people are really good at
striking.
There are some people that are good at
putting all those things together,
which I always thought fader was very
natural at combining his striking with
his grappling and kind of making it all
fit together better than most people
could.
Um,
yeah,
I agree with you on that.
I think that was one of the things that
really stood out about him was that he
didn't fall into that trap that a lot of
people do where if you're a really good
wrestler but you have knockout power,
you just knock everybody out fade or he
would be.
You'd be stunned and he would see your
arm and he would dive into Kimora,
you know,
he would.
He would always take the opportunity
that presented itself,
whether it was a grappling situation
where there was a striking situation and
his well-roundedness was one of the
things that made him special on top of
his knockout power and his aggression,
his.
He was so well rounded who was his
ability to flow with whatever was
happening and he also had that Hump
Humility and he had that calm like you,
like you saw holly had the other day and
I actually,
again talking about social media.
I posted,
I haven't posted much on facebook the
facebook before,
but there's a video of holly talking
about.
She got beat by Sophia Mathias in
kickboxing.
It was a vicious fight.
Watch it,
laser kickboxing and boxing,
kickboxing.
It's,
it's,
it's insane.
I mean,
she gets destroyed.
Holly gets completely destroyed hanging
on the ropes,
getting punched in the head.
It's awful.
Then you watch the post fight interview
with her and it,
it.
It's unbelievable because everything she
says she takes complete ownership of the
loss.
She's like,
I had a great training camp.
I,
my coaches were telling me to do the
right things,
but I wasn't doing what I was supposed
to do.
I wasn't fighting the way I was supposed
to fight.
The reason I last night is my fault.
I did this and I will have to change
things if I'm going to beat her and
hearing someone.
And the other part that was cool about
it was she was getting emotional,
like you could see like she wanted to
cry.
I mean she was crushed,
but she,
she kept control of her emotions and was
another one.
I saw that video.
I'm like,
man,
this girl is,
is
going to do going to do well in this
fight.
I mean,
I,
I had a pretty good feeling about it.
Well,
she's,
she is incredibly solid,
that's for sure.
And that is so admirable when someone
does take ownership of their mistakes.
So important,
so important.
That's like we wrote the book,
the book is called extreme ownership,
that that's literally the time ladies
and gentlemen right there.
But,
but that's,
that is like the key though.
The reason it's called that is because
when we made mistakes,
we owned up to him and furthermore when
both Lafe and I ended up in positions
where we were teaching leadership,
lead life was teaching the junior
officers that were coming out of the
seal training,
putting them through the junior officer
training course and I was teaching,
like I said,
the advanced guys and so you'd get to
seal officers and like I said,
we put these guys through horrible
training scenarios where everyone was
getting killed and blown up and they'd
be bought buddy carrying people through
the desert and just,
it's just awful.
And you come back from these situations
and you talked to one of the,
let's say one of the good leaders and
you'd say,
Hey,
what went wrong?
And the guides say,
well,
number one,
I didn't give a clear enough plan.
No one really understood what my vision
was.
They didn't execute because I obviously
didn't give them a good enough briefing
and you'd be like,
okay,
fair enough,
and that guy would go and fix that
problem.
Then you get a guy that was would not
take ownership of stuff that would come
in and say,
a user say,
well,
what went wrong?
That training that was,
you guys did a terrible job.
What happened?
He said,
well,
you know,
my,
my assault force commander didn't wait
for my command before he left and he
screwed up and my platoon chief wasn't
heads up about where our casualties were
being taken and my Lpo and they'd make
all these excuses.
And it really was the difference between
like who would be successful and who
wouldn't be.
Because the guy that takes ownership of
the problems,
what do you think the rest of his team
does?
Just just,
if,
if that person takes ownership of the
problems,
everybody on that team does the same
thing.
They don't say,
yeah,
you're right boss.
It is your fault.
No,
they go,
hey boss,
you know what,
I actually could have done a better job
and and that spreads through everybody.
Whereas when someone says it wasn't my
fault,
it was joe's fault,
what does Joe do?
Joe Goes,
no,
that wasn't mine because I'm not getting
no blame each other,
and guess what?
The problem never gets lost.
Exactly.
So to hear holly talking about that
after the fight and taking complete
ownership of a loss was very impressive
to me and then she went on to beat her
like six months later.
Unbelief.
Yeah.
It's one of the most important things in
getting good at anything is recognizing
when you're not good.
Recognizing when you make mistakes.
It seems so simple.
Right?
But you know why?
Because Ego.
No,
he goes,
everybody's ego.
It's like even even me,
because I sit here,
in fact I teach people about,
you know,
you've got to keep your ego and there's
a chapter in there like you've got to
keep your ego in check.
When,
when,
when somebody,
I'll ask somebody,
I'll be like,
hey,
is there anything I could have done
better in that,
in that speech or in that class?
And they'll be like,
well,
you know,
one thing that you could do,
and I'm like,
immediately I'm like for wrestling,
wrestling,
like my ego.
I'm like,
God,
I'm such a loser.
I'm sitting here telling them about
their ego in check.
And so everybody does that.
Everybody does it all the time.
No one can take criticism and you know,
part of that biggest step of moving
forward is a is,
is learning how to take ownership of
stuff and when it goes sideways and it
definitely will.
Well you need some form,
some amount of pride and some amount of
ego to get good at things in the first
place because it's such a cow
counterintuitive notion because you have
to have a belief in yourself.
You have to be able,
like when you,
when you first,
when you start out at Jujitsu,
your white belt.
I remember being a white belt and being
like,
oh my God,
I am fucking never going to get good at
this.
I'm going to suck forever,
but to to to look at people who are
better than you and no,
they had to have sucked at one point in
time.
Okay.
There's gotta be somewhere along the end
of this tunnel.
There's got to be a light.
I just gotTa keep going and Tigo Ego was
going to say,
I mean,
ego drives you to be successful me to be
successful.
Egos.
What's driving you?
The problem is when you let ego go too
far and you know everything,
you know,
everything takes balance.
This is a dichotomy and everything,
every part of you has a dichotomy.
You know,
you can get so into the physical aspects
of things that you end up like doing a
bunch of steroids and going crazy and
ruining your health.
That's not good.
The other end of the spectrum,
you know,
you can sit around and play video games
and turned into A.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well,
there,
there's,
yeah.
Bodybuilding is the best example of
that,
right?
Because yeah,
that's kind of dying out though,
isn't it?
Kind of bonded.
Building out their stuff to you and I.
It is,
but I think there's a giant culture of
people out there that want to look like
huge mutant still.
It's,
I think,
I mean I'm not in that world,
but when.
I mean a bodybuilding is a great example
of that because when you start lifting
weights like,
God,
I'd like to be stronger and you start
getting a little bit bigger.
You're like,
oh look at that.
I got a muscle,
Ooh,
this is cool,
and then you keep going and then you
keep going.
But some guys get so fucking crazy.
They won't stop until they have 22 inch
arms and they want to have thighs that
are so big.
They have to walk like they're,
they've got a barrel in between their
legs and you know,
and they,
they just can't help but they just take
it to some completely unhealthy place.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's rough.
Yeah.
Well,
it's just the nature of trying to get
good at something.
You've got to recognize what's good and
what is just fucking insane.
Yeah.
And it happens in training camps with
fighters all the time to retrain.
So bad,
big part of the problem with a mixed
martial arts,
so obvious too,
when you're overtraining somebody
because all of the sudden like one night
they'll just fall apart and they just
won't be able to do anything.
Right.
And I'm always like,
all right,
go eat two steaks and take two off
because they will get to a point.
You just feel them.
You'll just feel and fall apart.
Yeah,
but you have to monitor your heart rate.
That's a big thing that a lot of
fighters don't do.
Monitor your resting heart rate in the
morning and if it goes up more than five
beats in a day or two,
most likely year overtrained or you're
sick or you're struggling with something
that would make.
Steve Maxwell taught me that trick.
He's like,
every fighter should do that.
And none of them do.
They should monitor their heart rate and
every morning his heart rate is like
seven.
Steve Maxwell can fucking.
He can deal with anything.
He's just one of those dudes,
but he's just.
He's another guy I want to talk about.
A guy who's got a lifetime of wisdom
comes to strength and conditioning and
what he calls physical culture and the
culture of taking care of your body.
Guys.
Sixty two or 63 years old,
fit as a fiddle,
travels all around the world,
training people.
That's all he does.
It doesn't have a house,
doesn't.
He has a.
A bag that he brings with him when he
travels around.
All of this stuff's in that bag.
I ran into her in San Diego because he's
been downsizing and when I.
The first time I ran into him in San
Diego,
he was down to living in an rv.
That's when I first met him.
I hear him on a podcast,
whatever,
you know,
a year later or two years later and he's
not have all my worldly possessions in a
backpack.
Yeah.
He sold his rv and he's like,
fuck it.
I don't even know if he has a bank
account.
I mean,
just.
He's a strange cat man.
He really is a strange cat,
but a very at peace guy for sure.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's very interesting.
I wouldn't want to live like that.
I don't like living like that,
but he's also been the guy that's lived
the other way.
He's had the house and needs that.
The family and his son Zack is a very
successful Jujitsu competitor and you
know,
got divorced and gave up the gym.
He had the,
all the,
all the trappings.
He had everything.
He was like,
Ooh,
I like it better.
Like this backpack.
Maybe the key word there was trapping.
Maybe he somehow built all these things
around them that felt.
Ended up making them feel trapped.
Yeah.
For him it's just he would.
He figured out what he enjoys.
He enjoys training,
still doing Jujitsu to this day and he
teaches a course,
a Jujitsu for lifetime and it's all
about maintaining your health while you
train and you know,
he's written articles on training,
smart to avoid injuries as you get older
and you know how to pick the right
training partners and make sure you
know,
you know,
nobody's trying to hurt you,
but you could keep a,
an active martial arts lifestyle deep
into your sixties like he is.
Yeah.
You got to be thankful that you started
Jujitsu a little bit younger because you
got to get in.
Even today,
if you start.
Jujitsu is an older thing.
We have all kinds of older guys come
into the gym and it's that first like
year where they just don't know where to
put their body yet and they don't
notice.
They don't know to say no to that 21
year old juiced up marine that's like in
there to get after it.
Like they smack hands to roll in.
This guy's gonna tear them apart and
that's,
that's how guys get hurt.
If they're,
if they're older and you know they need
to ease into it a little bit.
Pick training partners carefully.
Got To pick your training partners
carefully and there's always gonna be
the guy that hurts people.
There was just this giant German dude
that used to roll it.
Our gym is to always get everybody in
leg locks and blow their knees out and
he's just never rolled with that guy.
I'm like,
I've,
I've been leg locked by dean on.
You know,
how many times,
like,
I mean,
we might be talking thousands of times a
heel hook,
knee locked,
but you know,
I've never been hurt,
you know,
and I've,
I've gotten him,
you know,
not thousand signs with plenty of times
and we've never heard each other,
you know,
because we,
we know what we're doing.
Yeah,
I'd way rather roll with a black belt
for sure.
Then some fucking psycho blue belt.
It's just too dangerous.
Sometimes they just,
they spazz out and they head,
but you accidentally and weird shit
happens.
It's,
um,
I'm.
One of the things that I think is
amazing is a,
that Anthony Bourdain has gotten crazy
into Jujitsu over the last,
I think two years now.
He just earned his blue belt.
He's 59.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
What's,
it's amazing.
He,
he lifetime of smoking cigarettes,
doing heroin,
like never,
never was fit,
never exercise at all when I first met
him.
Uh,
like he would laugh about fitness.
He just wanted to drink beer and you
know,
he,
the first time we did my podcast,
we got so high,
I don't even know how we talk.
And then,
uh,
I just did a TV show like a couple of
weeks ago.
We're in Montana.
All he wanted to talk about Jujitsu.
He's obsessed.
I'm showing them some techniques.
We're talking about different guys that
liked to do different things at
different approaches and gay versus no
gay.
And John Donner,
her and you know,
Gary Tone in an Eddy Commons and all
these different.
I'm like,
this is amazing.
I can't believe what a transformation.
This guy's overtaken Jujitsu.
Definitely.
I mean,
people can get into all kinds of weird
stuff,
right?
People get into surfing,
people get into skiing,
people get into rock climbing.
There's definitely something.
I'm more in Jujitsu that gets into
people's heads.
And it definitely happened to me.
I mean,
I was completely and I still am.
I mean I still cannot stop a youtube
video of a cool move.
I mean I just,
I just have to watch it.
Yeah.
And I think it's because there's such a
cerebral part of it,
there's something about it.
And I see this,
we know we teach kids and you'll see
the,
the knucklehead kids that kind of
knuckle dragging kids are kind of big.
They don't really get it.
But then you get this kid,
some smart kid,
you can tell they're smart and those are
the kids that get really into Jujitsu
because they realize like,
Oh,
if I learned this,
I can beat that big kid.
Yeah.
And that's where it starts.
But yeah,
Jujitsu can definitely be addictive.
Well,
Jujitsu's the only martial art where it
really works,
like in the Bruce Lee movie where the
little guy really can beat the big guy
because the reality is like if you watch
the old k one days where Bob Sapp was
fighting when Bob Sapp was 375 pounds
with ABS.
Oh,
you've never seen anything like it.
He was he on steroids.
He was steroids.
There was nothing human left.
And he beat or Nesto hoost twice who is
arguably one of the top two or three
greatest kickboxers ever.
And Bob Sapp just bum rushed him and
donkey Kong dumb.
Just beat them down with clubbing
punches because he was so much bigger
than him.
He was more than 150 pounds bigger than
him probably.
I think he used it at his biggest.
It's probably like 2:30.
Maybe to your point,
I was in Japan.
I was with dean.
As a matter of fact,
when Nogueira submitted sap,
that was insane.
That was insane.
That was a perfect example.
For example,
a boy,
it had to be Nogueira though because
sap,
sap dropped him on his head.
Pile drived him on his head.
I saw him the next day.
No Gira,
like after the fight and he was hurt.
I mean he was up bad.
Oh my God.
It looks.
I'm a big neck.
Was fucked up apparently forever.
After that I,
he hit his neck essentially.
Never recovered after that fight,
you know,
that was one of the fights that fate or
passed on fader wouldn't fight Bob's
out.
It was like,
Eh,
you can take your fucking clown show,
take your circus act and no heroes.
Okay.
Fader was like,
no thanks on the freak show.
But then again,
he went and fought troy who's a giant
guy too,
but giant actually gigantism giant,
not giant like juice to the gills giant.
But look,
Bob Sat,
I mean all power to them.
They didn't have a law against it and he
went in there and they were paying them
and that's how he made a ton of money
doing that.
But the point is that in Jujitsu,
like maybe an MMA,
it's a little bit different because you
know,
obviously Bob Sapp Drop Nogueira on his
head and most people would have been
done then,
but Nogueira was legendarily tough,
but a small man can tap out a much
larger,
stronger man on a regular basis.
I watched Rigo Rodriguez in Abu Dhabi go
against Marcello Garcia.
I was there and were either in La and
when Rico threw them on his bed,
when Marcel took Rico's back,
so rico through himself backwards and
slammed on top of Martin,
like Marcel was like a backpack on
Rico's back.
Rico's like 2:40
something maybe even heavier through
himself backwards and landed all his
weight on Marcello ourselves.
Shook it off and leg lock them.
They're incredible,
incredible.
I mean Marcella was like 160 pounds,
maybe one 70 maybe,
but just so skilled and so dangerous
with his Jujitsu that he was the
favorite in that,
which is incredible.
And that's,
that's where I think that addiction
comes in because I think it's just a
cerebral thing where people realize that
it's like you said,
it's this real force.
We're now one
of my,
uh,
my,
my kid asked me,
you know,
that movie the incredibles.
Yes,
there's kid.
These people have superpowers.
And My,
uh,
my son asked me a data,
is there really such a thing as
superpowers?
And I'm like,
Jujitsu is definitely a super power.
You know,
if you remember the days before anybody
knew it,
if you need a little tiny bit,
you were just get viewed.
No one can stop you.
It was awesome.
What's also amazing to see the
progression of Jujitsu in comparison in
1993 because the Jujitsu of 1993 was so
primitive in comparison to what you have
today.
Like the guys who are winning with
Jujitsu.
God though the setups were so obvious,
you could see the arm bars a mile away.
There was nothing crazy or weird about
it.
And you look at that in comparison to
today,
like Jacques Array,
like when Jocko array gets armbars,
it's like a work of art.
I mean,
you,
you watch his setups,
you look good,
Lord.
Like he tapped Chris Kamozi with an arm
bar and I've watched the transition,
the way he controlled them on the ground
and the scrambled to arm bar.
I probably watched it 40 times in a row.
I just played it back and forth and
went,
fuck one more time.
Fuck.
I needed perfect placement of the Shin,
the knee that pressure,
the hips,
everything's in place.
The control of the arm.
And it was a,
it was a done deal from the moment he
started his movements.
Now that to me is like,
that's just as beautiful as any painting
than anybody's ever made.
There's no doubt.
One hundred percent is an art to that.
No doubt about it.
What year did you start?
Uh,
[inaudible]?
Ninety two or 93.
Damn.
You got an early,
got an early.
Luckily I had a pre UFC.
Yep.
We,
we knew when we launched that first UFC,
we all knew while there were stairs,
three or four of us that knew that
hoists,
that release Gracie was going to rise.
That's amazing.
We have this old seal master chief old
Vietnam era,
seal master chief named Steve Bailey.
And he was,
he was like a high level white belt and
he had trained with flooring,
gracie up in the garage,
open torrents.
And so he knew he knew Jujitsu garage,
the infamous garage,
like the epicenter.
No kid in America.
But this Guy Steve Bailey had trained
there and you know,
one day we were over on deployment over
in Guam and he said,
hey,
who here wants to learn how to fight?
And I'm like,
Hey,
I want to learn how to fight.
And he just took us all and just choked
us all out,
you know,
I mean like,
okay,
you,
you attack me and just chokes on.
I'm like,
okay,
I'll listen to whatever this guy is
saying.
So.
So he taught us,
you know,
the basic,
like the rear naked choke and the arm
lock and like the American or something
like,
you know,
we're talking like four or five
different moves and with those moves,
like I never,
I,
I every scrap I'd get into,
you know,
I just force someone into the rear naked
choke or force them,
but they had no idea what was happening.
So it was actually amazing.
But,
uh,
but again,
I thought at that time that,
that,
that was Jujitsu like was this finite
thing a lot of people did.
Yeah.
And then you realize,
you know,
that it's completely unending and it
changes every day.
John John Machado had a guy that moved
to black belt and uh,
he was a very good martial artist.
He was very physically strong.
This guy,
he was a big bulky dude,
like a naturally big bone,
strong guy that gave people a lot of
problems and then decided like,
didn't just decide this,
but set it publicly.
I've learned all I could learn about
Jujitsu and now I'm going to learn all I
can learn about Moitai.
And everybody just went,
oh dude,
we're done with you.
Oh,
it was like,
it was so ridiculed in the community and
in the people in school that everybody.
Like I was like a blue belt at the time
and I was like,
what the fuck is this guy on?
Like you learned everything.
How can you learn every.
There's no end.
Jujitsu doesn't end.
It goes on forever.
Like you can't get.
You can always get better.
It's not,
it's not something until you achieve the
speed of light.
And that's another,
another great thing about Jujitsu is
because it like combat,
it reflects life.
End of the day.
You start saying that you're good to go.
Like in a leadership position or
whatever task you're working on the day
you say,
I've learned everything there is to
learn about.
This is the day you start to lose.
And I know that humility is something
that you have to keep yourself in check.
Because again,
I got asked the other day,
you know,
when were you,
when was your high point of leadership?
And I'm like,
no,
I never had high point of leadership.
I was always trying to learn,
I was always trying to figure out what I
was doing wrong and what mistakes I was
making because if you don't do that,
that's.
That's something I learned from Jujitsu
or you know,
if you don't do that then that you're
going to get passed by and other people
are going to figure something new way of
doing it and you're going to be left in
the dark.
Yeah.
Is much as I like to use,
like the term that was perfect.
There really is nothing perfect in human
beings.
There's always room for improvement.
There's always a shorter path is always
a quicker victory.
There's always,
there's always new things to learn and
as soon as you start thinking that
you've mastered something to the point
of,
of an end,
like if you kinda missed out what it's
all about in the first place,
it's all.
You're constantly uncomfortable.
You're supposed to be constantly
uncomfortable,
and then in these little victories that
you get,
the good thing about when people tap,
oh,
I get a little nice feeling right here.
Then they're like,
let's go again,
and then I'm like,
oh fuck.
Back to being uncomfortable and there's
no getting around and then he taps you
and you're like,
oh shit should have quit while I was
ahead.
No,
no,
because you're missing the point.
The point is that it's a,
it's a long path,
a long arduous path and I think anything
that's worth doing is probably like
that.
There's no doubt about it.
And,
and that's another,
another piece again,
another place where Jujitsu is like
is eat.
You think at some point you think you
know,
like you think you're good,
you think you're doing pretty good and
then you just get smacked or you get
smacked with something.
And like now like when you were 25,
you were like,
I'm pretty,
I'm pretty good to go,
you know,
I'm pretty,
I pretty much know what's up.
And then when you're 30 you're like,
I didn't know anything.
I was idiot.
And it's true like even.
And so I think one of the,
one of the things that provide some
small portion of like maturity as a
human being and as a man is when you get
to the point where you actually realize
that you don't know everything and
you're like looking at yourself like I'm
44,
and I'm like,
yeah,
I'm going to learn so much in the next
three years,
five years,
I'm going to look at myself at 44 and
go,
you have to see how stupid you were
then.
And when you come to that realization,
I think that's a pretty positive thing
because it takes a while to figure out
that hey,
you don't have everything figured out.
You're,
you're pretty stupid right now even
though you don't think.
So.
Another thing that things like Jujitsu
teach you,
and I say Jujitsu,
but it's really an all martial arts
thing.
The problem with the other martial arts
other than Jujitsu is at a certain point
in time,
you can't really practice them 100
percent.
Yeah,
like striking.
You really can't practice striking 100
percent for very long or your brain
starts to give out just the fact and
Jujitsu,
you can Jujitsu,
you can do it deep,
deep into your fifties.
I mean there's like a.
we're Anthony Bourdain,
he's pushing 60,
still doing it and you know it's not
that he's going to be a world beater,
but he can get the most out of it the
most that he can get out of it.
It's that stays the same like what you
get out of it stays the same regardless
of your were regardless of the success,
like what you're getting out of it.
Even if you're getting tapped,
what you're getting out of is doing your
best and overcoming and improving upon
what your best is every day and doing so
in a situation where there is extreme
consequences,
you're going to get strangled.
You know you're going to get your arm
broken.
If you don't tap,
you're going to get your leg fucked up.
there's.
It's not as extreme as combat obviously,
but it is extreme.
You can get in a sport that you're
participating in an activity that you're
participating in voluntarily in America
at 5:30
on a Tuesday,
where are you going to get 30 people
that are going to show up,
slap hands together and then hug it out
after it's over and go,
you're gonna be here tomorrow.
Yeah,
RLC man.
And then you know,
back again tomorrow.
Same thing.
That's
another kind of primal piece that makes
Jujitsu so intense is if you and me role
like and I get you or you get me and I
tap in my heart.
I know that if you and I were fighting
for survival,
I just lost and you woulda killed me and
I see this with little kids.
When kids compete,
you tell them,
listen,
just go out there.
Have Fun.
It's going to be fun.
You know?
Just go out there and do your best.
I don't care if you win or lose,
just go out and have a good time.
You tell them that.
You tell them that,
tell them that if they get tapped date,
they start crying.
It's so emotional.
And why is that?
Because a part of them inside their head
that they don't even know exists,
knows that that person had they been in
a mortal struggle.
They got beat.
They got their ass kicked.
Yeah.
It's not like someone.
This is what I always say like somebody
dunks a basketball on you.
It sucks,
but it doesn't mean anything unless you
decide it means something.
What does basketball escalate into?
We'll do all sports.
All sports escalate into finance.
So if you,
let's get rid of the bat.
Whatever else.
Let's just fight.
Let's just,
that's why it's,
you know,
that's why the,
I think that UFC has been so highly
successful because it is,
it's what it's,
it's the ultimate,
you know,
in combat sport again,
barring combat itself.
Well it's also why the dorks and pencil
next hate it so much because they think
it's a regression.
Back to the primal days of caveman
combat.
Like what are we supporting some fat
fuck wrote an article for the New Yorker
or New York Post or something like that,
about the Ronda Rousey loss,
about how barbaric and disgusting it was
and what,
uh,
what,
what bullshit that we were fed and that,
you know,
were made out that she was this
unconquerable in to watch her beaten
unconscious was disgusting.
And you don't get it man.
Like you don't get it like what you're
doing with your fat face,
like shoving cheeseburgers down your mug
is way worse than anything that she did
inside that octagon.
It's interesting because that
kind of attitude can,
can cross borders into other things.
And you know,
I,
I end up talking to people you know,
through,
through our company,
people that are smart.
You mean every like I'll be in a room
with everyone's,
went to an Ivy League college,
had been super successful in their worth
millions and millions if not hundreds of
millions of dollars.
And I was given one of these talks the
other day and we do,
you know,
of course they ended up asking me about
Isis and all that.
And as I'm sitting there looking and I'm
thinking to myself like,
these people are all looking at me and
thinking I'm just a savage,
right?
I'm just like,
Hey,
I'm a knuckle dragger.
We just need to go kill everyone.
And so I tried to explain to them,
I'm like,
listen,
I almost,
I almost feel ashamed to say this to
everyone here because everyone here is
an intellectual and is very,
very smart.
But there are some problems in the world
that there is not an academic solution
to.
And sometimes violence is the solution.
And again,
there can be a million arguments against
that.
But the reality of it is in the world,
it's like you were talking about earlier
in the world,
there are evil people that do evil
things and the only way to stop them is
to confront them and destroy them.
And unfortunately we,
we are so disconnected from that,
that it makes people look at UFC and go,
oh my God,
how could that happen?
And it makes people look at,
you know,
a military attack and say,
oh my God,
how could that happen?
It can happen because we're human beings
and we're imperfect and there are.
There are evil people in the world.
Well,
the people that think there's no ever.
There's no excuse for a violence
solution.
Take those people,
bring them to Ramadi right now,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
how do you deal with evil
when it exists?
How do you deal with it?
Do you,
do you hug them?
Do you knock on their door with flowers?
What do you do?
I mean,
what is the solution?
They don't have an answer.
They have an aunt.
The only reason why they even have that
attitude is because they live here in
this sheltered environment,
in our beautiful bubble we call the
United States of America
that many brave men and women have
provided and will continue to provide
regardless of what is said about them.
And uh,
God bless those folks out there on the
wire.
Yes sir.
And with that extreme ownership,
that was three hours,
man,
we just banged out three hours a day on
crazy right here,
Jocko willink and Leif,
Leif,
Leif Lafe,
Lafe Babin extreme ownership,
how us navy seals lead and win.
And Jocko is on twitter,
Jocko willink on twitter.
Is that what is Jocko willink and uh,
what is it on?
Do you have anything else?
Website?
Well,
yeah,
we have,
we have a facebook for extreme
ownership.
We have an extreme ownership.
Twitter.
Yeah.
We're out there in the social media
world broadcasting ourselves and soon a
podcast.
Right.
And I will,
I will do a podcast that.
See,
I knew I will do it.
Going to happen.
Echo Charles,
be ready to record a podcast.
Brother.
Thank you very much.
Sorry,
this was awesome.
I really,
really appreciate it and I will put up a
link on Amazon after the podcast,
so go out and buy this book folks.
Thank you very much,
John.
I appreciate it,
brother.
Thanks for having me on.