Sure.
Hello,
free people of the world.
This episode of the podcast is brought
to you by [inaudible] dot com that's o n
n I t on it is a human
optimization website.
What that means is that we sell
you or we sell. You might not,
it might not be to you, you might
just be a dude listening going next.
But we sell shit that makes
your body work better.
Shit that makes your mind work better.
Strength and conditioning equipment,
supplement that, improve
cognitive function, function,
supplements that can improve your
endurance and strength. All the,
the different various aspects of these
things are explained@onnit.com far better
than I'm going to be able to
do in a simple commercial.
But our goal is just to provide you
with all the different shit that we use.
Um, all the different things that I use
as far as like strength and conditioning
equipment like kettlebells, things that
can improve athletic performance, um,
steel, maces and steel clubs. All
these different things are all, again,
explain far better at [inaudible] dot
com if you're a person who doesn't
exercise and you've never tried
anything like this before,
I cannot stress enough to take it lightly.
Start slow,
hire a trainer if you can
afford one and you just,
you don't need to do like
every workout with a trainer.
Just have somebody show you the
correct emotions, the correct way,
the correct form to do like various
physical exercises so that you don't hurt
yourself.
Because a,
the whole goal of exercise obviously
is to improve the way your body works.
And if you break it along the way, that
shit ain't improve and nothing. That said,
we sell a wide variety of
weights, um, of kettle bells.
We sell packages from like beginner
Kettlebell packages, which uh, have, uh,
three different weight sizes, 20
kilograms, 16 kilograms and 12 kilograms,
which are um, what is
20. He was at 35 out,
50 pounds to 44,
46 pounds.
Yeah. Um, I don't know
why we doing kilograms.
This is something that because they were
created in Russia, it's a would kill.
Kettle bells are, is an ancient
Russian method of lifting weights.
It's like a cannon ball with a handle on
it and and using momentum and swinging
these things that the goal
of the Kettlebell is to
strengthen the entire body as
one individual unit. Like a lot of times
when you see people lifting weights,
they do things like if you go
to the standard gym set up,
a lot of times people are doing what you
call isolation exercises like curls or
things along those lines.
Tricep extensions that are
really just working one,
one body muscle group.
Um,
and the idea behind something like
kettle is to work the entire body as one
individual thing.
So it strengthens the body all is
one unit and also enhances athletic
performance because of that, because if
you just get developed strong biceps,
like you're only working your bicep,
you're not working your legs and
your back at the same time, you're,
you're kind of doing yourself a disservice
because you're going to create an
imbalance. It's not natural to just
have really strong biceps for no reason.
It looks sexy while some
fucking guns with a beach kid,
but you're going to get hurt.
Um,
but we carry all the way up
to a very heavy cattle bells.
We just started getting some really
big ones. Then, um, we have, um,
the strong man kettle bells that just
came in, uh, which I think go up to 90,
48 kilograms. What the fuck is that?
It's over a hundred pounds. Yeah,
it's a lot of weight, bitch. It's too
much for you. Start slow workout. Uh,
just, just do it smart
please. Whatever you do.
I hear hearing people are just to build
because you should her fucking tore my
shoulder report.
Don't do that extra size.
Eat correctly.
Get your fucking shit together people
and start it all at Onnit Dotcom.
There's a wide variety of things
including workout DVDs. Uh, the,
I can't stress this one enough.
I talk about it all the time,
but it's just because it's so good.
The extreme kettlebell cardio workout
DVD by man named Keith Webber.
Keith will be here in October.
We're working out the dates right now.
I'm very psyched to sit
down and talk to him.
He's a good dude and he has a great
workout regimen that you can follow.
A also strength and conditioning. Besides
strength and conditioning equipment,
we have a massive amounts of supplements,
healthy foods including the hemp force
protein bar, a hem force protein bar,
which contains the finest quality
hemp protein, very delicious,
very low in fats. It's got healthy
fats, minerals, fiber, protein,
all pressed into a shape that's perfect
to just stuff in your pocket or your bag
and get the fuck out of there and have
healthy protein and have something that
fills your stomach up.
It doesn't make you feel like an asshole
for doing it on a Dotcom o. N n I.
T use the Codeword Rogan
and save yourself 10% off.
We're also brought to you by a new
sponsor and it's called me undies.
Why did they decide to call their
company? Me undies? I don't know man.
I don't know,
but the idea behind it is they have the
finest underwear that you can buy and
they will deliver it to you.
Order it online and have it sent to you.
I personally do not like
going to a store and shopping.
I don't like going shopping. Why
is that? Um, I dunno. It's just me.
I hate it too. It's not
fun. It's a chick thing.
Chicks like chopping chicks like going
places and trying things on and I don't
know. What do you think? And
then they step out station.
I do almost all my shopping online now if
I can. I love it. Love shopping online.
And um,
me undies is a,
a company now that has the most
comfortable underwear you have ever tried.
They're fantastic underwear.
Does that, what does that mean?
If you ever had bad underwear?
Yes I have.
I've had weird underwear where you
cannot keep your balls from coming out of
that hole in the front.
Like what is that man figure that shit up.
That's wack underwear and black underwear,
really annoying.
But the me undies brand, they just
sent me a box of them two weeks ago.
They fit great.
They don't ride up on you and they
actually literally pull moisture away from
your skin so that your cool all day long.
Um,
so they've designed these
things like actually sat down
and thought about it. Um,
they're all working out of
a small warehouse in La.
They're not a bunch of
pretentious designers.
They don't take themselves too seriously
and they make their big great underwear,
great underwear. That looks great. If you
go to the [inaudible] a website though,
it'll confuse the shit out of you
as to what exactly they're doing.
If you go to the me on the website,
first of all,
everything is people in their underwear
walking around the street doing normal
things. Uh, which I don't recommend.
Like this one with these two guys
and their underwear with guns. Yeah.
What, what are you guys doing? Fuck.
Why are you guys in your underwear
with guns? What are you planning?
Wow. Fasten. Yeah. And
they also, not only,
it's so homoerotic they're not
just in their underwear with guns,
but the two guys have their shoulders,
like their elbows on the shoulder
of this other guy who has a gun.
You know,
if I was a psychologist and I was like
really deep into reading into shit,
I could go off on that.
Just one photograph.
Like what kind of a gang bang or
are you guys planning? You know,
it seems like one guy
has ear plugs on too.
I don't know what is Cammo Andy's on to.
Yeah.
And what are the things around their
necks? I was going to say something.
Those are your plugs for guns.
Big Guns. Okay. So they're just,
they're firing off guns in their
underwear. I don't recommend that ever.
I don't think you should shoot guns in
your underwear unless someone's breaking
into your house and you happen
to be in your underwear.
But it seems like these
dudes plan this shit out. Um,
I guess they just trying to let you
know that these are super comfortable
underwear and you can use them to
do anything. Uh, I support them.
I think they are excellent underwear
and a, if you go to meet undies.com,
forward slash Rogan before September 1st
you will get 20% off your first order.
That's 20% off your first order.
When you go to me undies.com
forward slash Rogen um,
excellent underwear.
And here's a,
here's a statistic that's going to disturb
the shit out of you. Most guys, uh,
when they were surveyed,
how long does it take before you change
your underwear or before you buy new
underwear?
How long do your underwear's last?
How long would you think I saw it on
seven years due to keep drawers for seven
fucking years.
Seven years of farts and Dick drippage.
Yeah,
rotate your underwear son.
Just go to me undies.com to take
care of it very easily. It's,
it's super easy to do. And for the u s
and Canada, shipping is absolutely free.
So me undies.com forward slash
Rogen save 20% off your first order.
We're also brought to you by audible.com
last and not least because audible is
awesome.
I'm a huge fan of a audio podcast and
I'm also a huge fan of audio books.
I'm a huge fan of taking time that would
ordinarily be wasted time and actually
making it very enjoyable. And that's
what a book on tape can do for you.
Audible has over 150,000 titles,
fantastic books that you can choose from,
including Bert Kreischer,
our pal Burke crushers,
the life of the party. Uh,
Bert did a fantastic job on audio a
on the audio book version of it and it
actually sells better than the book
book version, which is really rare.
But if you're a fan of Bert Kreischer,
it totally makes sense cause he's such
an entertaining guy and he's a fun guy to
listen to. Um, so if you go to
audible.com forward slash Joe,
you will get one free audio book
and 30 free days of audible service.
Audible is the leading provider of audio
entertainment on the Internet on a,
I can't stress enough how
much I liked that company.
They've been around for a long time and
uh, I've been a fan for a long time.
They have so many different
titles to choose from and uh,
you literally can never run out of,
uh,
excellent books to listen to and it
makes a commute so much more interesting.
And again, if you go to
audible.com forward slash Joe,
you will get a free audio book.
And I recommend my friend Bert crusher
book the life of the Party. So go there,
get a free book, audio audible.com
forward slash Joe. All right,
shooter Jennings is here.
Why fuck around.
Play the music and let's start the show.
Willigan experience. Try my day.
Joe Rogan podcast by night. All Day.
All right, shooter Jennings. First
of all, thanks for doing this man.
I really appreciate it.
Yeah, that's cool as fuck.
It's cool as fuck having you in here.
I mean,
I love hearing about a guy online
listening to the music and go,
Oh shit, I got a new guy I'm
into, right? So, uh, I'm,
I've been a tweeting about your shit over
the last couple of months. I'm a, I'm a,
I'm a huge fan. I love all that. You say
hero fan. Is that what you call it here?
Offense. I love that stuff.
I love, uh, I love that.
A southern comfort songs. One
of my favorites, man. Listen,
I want all the time tweeting about it.
That's good.
See I grew up the house I grew up and
was named southern comfort real quick
while we're on the audible thing,
by the way, I wanted, I just was a,
I'm huge audio book fan.
I will tell you a a hilariously awesome
and creepy experience is at the highly
recommend if anyone has like an hour
and they're, they're your buddies thing.
They have listened to that book. Get
dianetics the audit. I'm serious, man.
It's so creepy. It's like being
a fucking Philip k Dick Movie.
It's like being in total
recall or is it really, oh man.
The way that the guy who reads it, the
whole thing and like the whole package.
It's so cool man. You're like, oh,
and then you know the read
the book commercials like
my whole life I had always
heard that shit and I was like, I'm
going to get the audio book of dianetics.
I bet that shit's wack and
highly recommended just for
wackiness for wackiness,
but by the end of it you're like,
hmm. That's what's fucked up about it.
It's like the,
the concept of what,
because I guess dianetics like I kind
of assessed the Scientology because it's
so fucking retarded and in one sense
to me, but in the other sense like,
because it's so serious and
all the craziness you hear
about, so I've like read,
I've like really looked into it.
I'll Ron Hubbard and if you know about
Excalibur, do you know about that?
What does Excalibur, okay, he wrote,
he wrote a book called the Excalibur.
Supposedly the big rumor is,
is that this book,
there was like the foreshadowing
for Scientology and uh, and that,
that like he tried to get it published
and like three or four people that read
it committed suicide. So he locked
it and evolved and there's like,
I see of it and no one would
ever knows where that is.
But that was like where
Scientology was born from. So like,
I'm so fascinated by it. So like dianetics
was his new book like that he wrote,
he's like, wait, I've got
it figured out. Like it's,
it's more like this and kind of like,
it's a dianetics was kind of like the
way of introducing what was in the
Excalibur book too, like the mass
population. It's pretty fascinating.
That sounds like one of those, uh,
in the mouth of madness. Totally.
It's like the John Carpenter book where
love that the movie where the guy wrote
a book and a bunch of people were
killing themselves and going crazy and
murdering people. Sam Neil. Neil was
in it, right? Yeah, that was exactly,
that's what the whole rumor about it
is. And if you've seen the master, uh,
with uh, Phillip Seymour Hoffman when
he played like the l Ron Hubbard Guy,
he had a book in that it was called
like the sword or something instead of
Excalibur. But, but like, uh, yeah,
supposedly he like showed it to a bunch
of people and they like went crazy.
And apparently what the book is about,
and I don't mean to derail our entire
conversation in this direction,
but don't worry,
there's no derailing the conversation.
This is the kind of Shit I like
to talk about. I say like two man,
this supposedly there's, um,
what the whole concept was,
was about the mob mentality and
breaking that apart. So like that,
that no matter what everyone is,
is really always alone,
no matter if they're in a group,
but when they're in a group,
they act a certain way that's different.
So there's like, there's, there's,
it's supposedly there's a guy being hung,
there's a scene in it where there's a
guy being hung and then there's the mob
that wants him hung and
it goes and like analyzes,
like the people in the mob and the
analyzes the executioner analyzes the guy.
He's getting hung. Like, I dunno, you
know, I'm very fascinated with that,
that kind of like psychology and it's
one that's why the whole, you know,
uh, Scientology thing to me is
so fascinating because I'm like,
how do these people,
they pay money to join this fucking
club that's like, you know, real.
It's real like Aa and all that stuff in
the sense that it's like you know your
new friends and your old friends and they
have like they assigned people to you
and then eventually you kind of
weed out all those other people.
But the whole concept of it is,
is taking the whole concept of dianetics
is taking like when you're a little kid
and a dog bites you and then for the
rest of your life you're scared of dogs.
Like the whole concept behind dianetics
is that they can take the memory,
what they call a reactive memory,
which is like the dog thing,
and they can turn it into a like a regular
memory so that you won't like the get
rid,
get rid of all of those kind of little
things that fucked you up through life.
That's what the concept of Cleary is.
So that when those things become,
you're not reactive anymore.
So if like you're,
you hate your dad and then for that reason
you like react certain way to people
your whole life. Like you cannot
even get that out of there.
So you'll never like act and calm,
you know what I mean?
But then you have to pay them a lot of
money to have an auditor to go through
your life and figure all
that shit out for you.
That's where they make all their cash.
Well the give you give them a certain
percentage of your income. Right.
It's just like tithing,
tithing in a regular church.
I think you give them 10% especially
at the highest levels. Really.
I didn't even know that timing is a big
one. That's a big one with religion.
That's the way they get shy. Well, I knew
that, I knew that when the other ones,
but I didn't know that there was a, there
was like a tithing process. I, I didn't,
I know that they do a lot of things.
Like I used to rehearse, I've been here,
I wouldn't live in here for 15 years.
And my old band,
we used to rehearse on Hollywood and vine
in this place and there was a daycare
next door and someone told us later,
Hollywood and vine. Yeah, right.
Oh Shit. Right. And it was
like, do you remember? Well,
you know it's right across the street
from the l Ron Hubbard exhibit and all
that. And uh, and somebody was like, yeah,
that's a Scientology daycare. They're
like real hush hush about it. But it's,
it's Scientology. So like, you know, like
there are a lot of that shit going down.
I'm probably gonna get murdered tonight.
Scientology's becomes such a joke.
I know, I know. Last few years, if this
was 20 years ago, you'd have an issue,
but the internet is sort of expose
them in a way that's made them seem so
preposterous. Like seriously
preposterous. It's funny though,
they have that big, a psychiatry
kills thing to that big exhibit.
Is that on sunset too? Or is it,
where are the fuck is that hey,
is that what that is? Yeah, that's
exactly what that is. It's, it's on,
is it unsensitive or Hollywood?
Because there was a mock store that I buy
hard drives and I saw that it must the
street. I didn't know that was a, wow,
I've got to go in there and check that
out because they don't believe in that.
And they don't believe a lot of medicines,
but in in certain ways like I can sign it.
I kind of see their point in certain
ways. Like, I mean I've been,
I've talked to psychologists
before in my life.
I mean I went to one for like
relationship counseling and,
and of course like it becomes like they
want to talk about you and I'm like,
I'm the kind of guy,
he's like,
I don't like whatever problems
and issues I've had in my life.
I worked through them. I
got, I've never need it.
I've never seen the need to really
kind of, I don't know. I'm not,
I'm like an angry guy. There's not shit
I'm angry at from when I was little.
I've kind of dealt with all that,
you know what I mean?
So sometimes when I see Scientology,
like Tom Cruise being like,
screw all that stuff, I'm like, yeah,
Tom Cruise is like, that's cool.
Even though you're weird, you know, you
invited him to your show yesterday. To me,
we're right in line. It's
like you, you do come on down,
come on down. Tom Cruise. Don't want to
talk to you about your fucking magic.
I was like Joe Rogan and I was
real serious about the other three.
Billy Ray Cyrus and Marilyn Manson.
It's like come on down like Tom Cruise.
That would be odd if he showed up.
It would have been awesome. And he
had talked to him. Stop being so Glib.
Have you seen the guy on and I'm,
I'm supposed to not like
this guy because he did.
He did dis my best friend and manager,
which is not cool. But besides that,
previous to that, when before it got
sticky, there's a guy on Twitter named,
not Tom Cruise. Do you know this kind
of no dude, he's hilarious. He can.
He just talks about,
he's like blowing rails.
Was Britney Spears all
day long and drive down.
He just talking about being on coked
out his phone and like how he's like
Scientology rules and he's like looking
for bitches and like hanging out with,
you know, Travolta and doing rails and
shit. He keeps graduating. He's like,
I think that their stance
against psychiatry, it's,
they've got some good points,
but there's,
it's like all things this probably,
it's not a complete black and white issue.
It's not like psychiatric drugs are all
bad or that antidepressants are all bad
because I personally know people that
were like close to suicide. Yes. Oh yeah,
I agree. I agree with that too. I
think that that, that stuff is good.
It can be good, can be bad. It can also
be a crutch, you know, in that way.
And I think a lot of times, man, here's
the, here's the thing, I have it,
like one of my dearest
friends guy work for me,
I'm not trying to be a downer with this,
but his brother has got fair in
Miller who actually co right.
One of the songs on this
George record and dude,
I walked out of my house without my
vinyls. I have a stack of vinyls for you.
So we've got this means we
have to hang out. Oh, hang
out man. To be happy too. Um,
but, uh, Faron Miller cowrote
uh, living in a minor key,
which was on the George record and,
and Ferran worked for me for nine years.
Still does, but he's in a band
now and he's doing awesome.
His brother was on those,
those medicines and stopped
hard like cold Turkey Woo.
Cause it went just crazy. You know
what I mean? So like you have to like,
you have to really,
really be responsible with psych.
Like those kinds of drugs that
change your mental, you know,
and sometimes like you said,
sometimes it does wonders for people
and it changes their life and then
sometimes it can be really damaging.
So, you know, you have to be careful.
But at the same time, Scientology,
they're like no drug stance. Like,
I don't know. Yeah, I don't
think that's responsible either.
I think there's a reason why they've come
up with a lot of these drugs and some
people have benefited tremendously.
There's people that just have natural
chemical imbalances in their brain.
And the idea that someone who doesn't
know how your brain works can say,
you know, Oh, you don't need
it because I don't need it.
You don't need it because Mike doesn't
need a Tom cruise doesn't need it.
So you know, John, fuck over here. He
doesn't need it either. That's crazy.
Some people benefit from tremendously
and sometimes they can use,
you can use those things as a bridge.
He got really tough times in your life.
You can use the psychiatric drugs as a
bridge and then get to a healthy place
and then wean yourself off.
Get your life in order.
I've read stuff about
people doing that too.
I don't necessarily think they're all bad,
but I think that there's a lot of people
that don't take care of themselves and
then just to get depressed and just
take a pill and then now they're better.
Well maybe not.
Maybe you would have been better off if
you start eating better and maybe stop
drinking as much and doing a little
bit of exercise every now and then and
probably you'd feel better.
It would help. You know? So I,
and also the t the Scientology thing,
like we see a guy like Tom Cruise who
is undeniably wacky but also undeniably
successful. The guy is,
uh, always positive.
Like he does his interviews, he's got a
lot of great energy and it's like, man,
there's a benefit to that.
There's definitely something to that.
I ended,
there's definitely something to that.
And especially when you get a guy who was
in that much, I mean, that much power.
And has that, has that had that
much success? You know, an,
it has that much influence. Like, I
mean, you know, either they're like,
I know that they treat him like,
like he's the, he's the, you know, l,
Ron Hubbard junior or something. So I'm
sure he, he's loving that side of it.
But the reality is, is like he, for
him to have stuck by it, I mean,
there's gotta be something
to, I mean, like I said,
that [inaudible] the audio book of
Dianetics as funny as that is, it is,
it is so fascinating because it explains
why he's always a fucking good mood all
the time. He's like, he's like, I'm
really good at this clear thing. You know?
He's like,
he's really figured it out and he's like
really happy all the time and nothing,
you know,
who knows?
He might be or you know,
he might just shut the door when the
day is done and it's fucking whale cream
and fucking fish all over the ground,
flopping around like a fucking animal.
I mean, you know guys like that. Right?
I have a couple of friends where I'm
like somebody getting beat somewhere on
this guy because they're so nice,
you know,
somewhere he's gone on pack
a punch in Soda, lights out.
Well there's people that you can tell
they're holding back and you could tell.
Yeah, okay. All right, fine. You know, and
you'd tell as soon as this guy gets away,
he's going to fucking do something crazy.
There's some people that are actually
calm and then there's some people you can
tell they're keeping it together,
but there's a monster inside
just raging at the cage. No,
fucking get out. Yeah.
That's uncomfortable when
you, you like, you know,
if you tried to explain to
someone, you're like, well listen,
everything you said was good. He, uh, he
used all the right words. He was very,
but I knew this motherfucker was hating
it inside side and they'd be like, oh,
that's just your perception, sir. I
mean, you can't prove that. No you can't.
But everybody knows that one dude
that's like that. Yeah, of course, man.
It's like, yeah, that's so
funny. It's true though.
My next door neighbor in my old house
was a scientologist. He's a nice guy.
Super Nice Guy. Why be a scientologist
when you're just some guy?
Like that's what I want to know. Cause
they worship actors and they worship.
So why I think they worship to actors
and they worship artists because that
influences others to become
Scientologists. I think
that's the strategy, right?
I mean, yeah, and they, and they,
you know, they kinda deify like,
like anyone who does any kind of art
has kind of a superior being. Well,
in a way, look, listen, okay.
I'm a shooter Jennings Fan. If a,
if I found out that shooter Jennings
is really into Scientology, I go, oh,
well that guy is cool, man, man,
the fuck is up with this. That'd be,
then he started reading into
it and you'd go, oh, I see.
So it keeps him positive and that keeps
putting out badass music. Oh, okay.
Okay. Maybe I'm fucking try
this. And that's all you
need. Like Scientology, man,
look, Tom Cruise is a bad motherfucker.
Okay. Tom Cruise doesn't take any drugs.
Tom Cruise drinks water every day.
Tom Cruise runs marathons.
Tom Cruise is a fucking beast.
I want to be like Tom Cruise.
And next thing you know,
you're fucking holding onto these
Campbell soup cans that are attached with
little wires and they're
honoring you. Yes. Have you
ever done that? No, I got it.
Yeah, I did it really well. I'll do it
with you. I would love to do it and I, I,
I'll do it in a heartbeat. I don't know
if they would take me and now, I mean,
you'd have to have someone who doesn't
know who you are and, right, right.
I definitely found a
dude who didn't know why,
who the guy was in his late fifties.
You just walk in and I was the
one that was on in um, San Diego.
I was down there filming for this TV
show that I was doing on CBS called the
game show in my head when we put these
little earpieces in someone so I could
talk to them. And then I gave them
like tasks that they had to go do.
Like they had a sell water to
people that came out of a hose.
Like they had to do a bunch of, like when
I did it convince people to, to tell, uh,
they had to play a fake news reporter
and convince people to tell them they'd
been abducted by aliens and all this
different Shit. But why we were there,
we're filming,
they had this dinette set up because it
was in this outside public place or a
lot of foot traffic was,
so they had the dinette set up and they
had their ear meteor or whatever they
call it. Is that what they call
it? And it's like two cans.
It looks like to like things that you
look like a Campbell soup can that you
took the wrapper off and it's connected
with these strings and so to really,
yeah, we'll soup can with
the yarn, hold onto this.
And so I did it and the guy wasn't very
compelling. He wasn't that good at it.
But, uh, I,
I got to ask him all sorts of questions
and read into it and it gave me some
brochures or something like that. Tried
to get me to go down there. What, what,
what, when he did the auditing though?
I mean, do they w how far did they,
they don't really,
I'm sure because they're
trying to convince somebody
to come back that they're
not going to start delving into like
real personal shit. But I'm sure like,
like what do you do? What kind
of questions they don't remember.
Cause it was very unremarkable.
I remember it was big,
which is part of the problem,
which is why I was willing to do it in
the first place because otherwise I would
have probably just hovered and watch other
people do it. But, uh, I just, you know,
it was dumb questions,
like dumb questions about your childhood
or you're happy with your career,
you know, you're happy in your
relationship. Right. You know,
and they just get a reading
on you allegedly from this nonscientific,
you know,
measuring instrument.
It's just so wacky, wacky.
So I see we could spend the whole thing
talking about this because it's so,
it's one of those things where like,
there's a bunch of people in on a joke,
you know, and you're like, just wanting
someone to say, okay, we're just fucking,
but no one does. You know what I
mean? Well, those belief systems,
the thing about having
those belief systems is that
they're very empowering for
people who believe in him. Like if you,
if you look at it and go, wait a minute,
wait a minute. Fucking planet. Xenu
really? Yeah. You know, Shit's insane.
Like I'm reading about this after you
brought up Excalibur while you're talking
about, and I pulled up that website,
that mock Scientology's you new.net. Oh,
I've never been there. But
this, oh my favorite site.
They have everything they have.
They have the entire Scientology like,
like Whoa, everything about what they
believe. All of the operating things,
male wiki leaks and was looking at that
is operating the operating Payton's
manual like level three,
which is apparently where I guess Tom
Cruise is like four or five or six or
something. But he was three a couple of
years. Like they have different manuals,
you know. So he was three a
couple of years ago and now
he's four or five or six.
I don't know where he's at and I haven't
been keeping up with his level what
rank he is at, but I know he's
ranked up because they've given him,
they made up some new award for him.
Did you ever see that video that leaked
when he's like using all this stuff that
was like they made up this one, they made
up this thing they'd never had before.
It was a guardian of the galaxy. Can
they like gave it to him and he was like,
he's like saying all that shit that made
no sense and using all their words and
stuff. Yeah, the Internet and people
put music to it and she had gorgeous,
it's so good to work of art. It is. It
is, man. I mean almost, it is almost like,
like something that you would,
you'd see from some artists who's doing
so I'm like fucking piece where he's
going on, man, that'd be so brilliant.
It's like he just all of a sudden
flipped and told everybody I've been just
listening.
It helps my acting.
If I can pretend to really be
into Scientology for this long.
It's like the dumb dumber me,
the new one coming out.
It'd be seen the preview for, oh my
god, it's genius. But there's like a,
there's like a whole thing where
Jim Carey character's care. Carrie,
Carrie's character is like in an insane
asylum. Go over this over that chick,
the Mary Samsonite as they called him
from the first one and then it turns out
he was like joking like for like
20 years and yet Lloyd Lloyd,
you mean to tell me that you've been,
you've been faking for 20 years,
all for a gag. And he's like, Yep.
It's like, that would be amazing.
If he did that, that's the only
way a good politician would work.
The only way that you could
have a president in this
country that was actually
going to care about the people is
they'd have to lie their way from the
beginning to the amendment.
They get an office and they didn't have
to flip and then you would have to also
have a cabinet that was in on the lie.
Like you don't have to have everybody
with you that was working with you. Like,
okay,
we're just fucking around.
We're going to get in there and
we're going to change and say that
would never,
you'd never be able to get it.
You'll never be able to
trust another person. Yeah.
I think the system is so far rig
though that it doesn't matter. Oh yeah.
Yeah. Obviously because it's the same.
People are like just, we're running it.
I mean it's, it's like, you
know, it's like whoever's
who, you know, when they had,
when windows 95 had the fucking start me
up and the rolling stones and now like
whatever their commercials are like
now it's the same fucking company.
It just looks different and
everything, you know? Right. Yeah.
I think it's silly when people are like,
I think voting is silly.
This is, this is my whole thing
with that. Because it's like,
what is the fucking difference? Like first
of all, there's people who are like, so,
I mean I, I may be going against a
lot of people's opinions of this, but,
but like people who are so gung Ho on
these certain politicians and lobbying for
this person and they're like so excited
that Obama is going to like fucking
change everything. And it's
such, I mean, yeah, it's awesome.
Like our first black president.
That's awesome. But otherwise,
like it's the same fucking game.
Same Shit over and over.
So I look at people who are like
really gung ho about one guy. I'm like,
are you fucking crazy? Like
you're buying this? I mean, I,
nobody's bought anything for, so I mean
like, you know, like Bill Clinton goes on,
you know, Arsenio Hall like that change,
like, did you watch that nineties thing?
That, that has been unnatural
geographic recently. There's,
there's a series called the 90s and it's
like six hours the whole thing and I
sat and watched it one day
and it's awesome, but it, it,
it really reminds you how much shit you
weren't paying attention to in the 90s
and how rigged it all was like everything.
Like it was solid wood bin Ladin was on,
like they did an interview with him
and like 98 or 96 when was Oj 94 yeah,
it was right around there. I don't
remember if it was, if it was Oj,
I don't remember if it
was Oj or Monica Lewinsky,
but one of those things was going on at
the moment and 400,000 people watch this
interview with sound in line and he's
like, he says on the interview, he's like,
we're going to fuck you and you're going
to watch it on TV and you're going to
be crying when it happens. And in like
400 people watched it and nobody cared.
And like at the exact moment they were
airing it is when like Monica Lewinsky or,
or Oj was like in the prime and everyone's
like looking over here while like
this guy over here,
I know Sam has just as fucking bull
shitty is fucking the presidents and
everything. Like, like yeah, right,
like Osama did not fly that plane.
I mean there's some people that did that
shit and there are people involved and
we will never know the truth about
any of it. So I mean, no matter how,
how hard we dig, you know
what I mean? So it's like,
to me it all seems so silly when
people get so riled up. Like they,
they believe they have to believe.
So it's like satanism you have to
believe in God to be a satanist.
That seems so stupid to me.
Like you have to be Christian.
If you want to be in this Church of Satan,
you have to be a Christian first.
Cause then you have to believe that whole
thing to believe that there is a Satan
to join the Church of say it. And that's
a silly it. Is that true? Yeah. Well,
I mean,
I thought though that satanism like
really in its finest form was really just
about hedonism.
Well, yeah, that's true pleasure
of like of see,
I mean there's like Sally the Crowley
Church and there's like the kind of like
the [inaudible] church, which is
what you're kind of talking about,
which is just essentially like,
like do anything you hedonism
essentially. Yes, but,
but like the writings and the teachings
and the in the things that that where
they reference Satan as an,
you know,
and they all those kind of like rituals
and shit or silly because it's like
you've got to be in the frame of reference
of Christianity and the Bible and all
that. You know what I mean?
If it was really scary,
it'd be something you've never heard of
and some creature you've ever heard of
and you're like, be terrified. You know?
It's not the same bad guy from the Bible,
which is going to make it into a thing,
you know?
That's why it all seemed so silly.
It's just you got to believe in magic
and fairy tales and shit to make it all
happen. Well, you kind of do have
to believe in magic and fairytales.
We believe a guy like Obama was
kind of fix the country. Yes.
This system is so beyond rigged.
It's,
and it's so transparently rigged. Yes.
You have to end if to fix the system,
you have to end banking,
you have to end the Federal Reserve,
you have to get the corporations out
of control of the media and everything.
I mean,
and representative government and the
influence of representative government by
special interest groups and lobbyists.
Yeah.
You'd have to completely revamp everything
system that's just completely broken.
There's nothing working about it.
And it's so,
there's so many like fucked up pieces
of it that as it trickles down from the
top to the bottom, it's just,
you know how like I'm one water,
like water goes through, uh, when you,
when you see springs like
natural springs that come out,
that water's going through all this
rock and all this, this ground.
And in doing so,
it filters everything out.
So the water comes out really
pure and delicious to drink.
But it could start out, you
know, really fucked up. And
then it all gets true. Well,
the opposite is true with politics.
Like you could have a great idea and
you could have someone who, you know,
have someone who has great intentions,
but by the time they get through
the filter of corporations
and special interest
groups and lobbyists and this and
that and put it comes out empty,
it's like there's nothing left.
It's always going to do that because
it was all they want it to be that way.
You know that to me, like you said,
it's, it's so fucked up and it really is.
It's really because of that that night,
you know,
the 99% or the one percenters thing,
it's, I mean because you just had these,
you just, the corporations have
too much control and they've,
they're like the net neutrality thing and
trying to cut that out and that's like
their tribe. They're literally giving all
the power to like know Viacom and shit.
Like not only that Viacom is the,
any time you look at a
corporation as an individual,
which is what they keep trying to do.
They're doing that as far as their ability
to donate to political campaigns are
doing it as far as like
their responsibilities. Like
they're, they look at their,
they're trying to look at corporations
as if these entities should
be a given rights, like a,
an individual given rights,
like a human being. But that's,
that's crazy because in
doing so you're also doing,
when you have a corporation is you
dissolve the responsibility of each
individual for the actions of the group,
right?
If you're going to give corporations the
responsibilities or if you're going to
give corporations the
rights of an individual,
you should also be able to charge every
individual in the corporation as if they
were guilty for anything that the
corporation is in trouble for. Right?
And if you did that,
then it would change the actions entirely
of the corporation. Because right now,
like say if you,
you are part of a corporation.
This corporation likes to go to Guatemala
and build cell phones and in the
meantime you fucking shoot rabbits and
fucking poisoned the wells and you know
who knows what kind of horrible and anti
human shit they're doing in these third
world countries and
pollution and genocide and,
and it does have a group of people
that doesn't want them to clear cuts.
So they fucking gone these people down.
Then you find out about it all later
and everyone involved in the corporation
should be responsible for it and that's
the only way you would ever stop any of
that shit from going on. If you, if
you looked at BP perfect example,
the, the, the, the, the
oil spill in the Gulf,
which just fucked up
so many people's lives.
I mean there's so many people
that don't have a voice.
You're not hearing from the fishermen,
you're not healing.
Hearing from the people that had to clean
that shit up and not healing from the
people that lived in the
towns and close to the water,
they got really sick because of the
dispersants. There's so many individuals.
If everyone in BP was prosecuted as
fully responsible for the actions of BP,
I mean man, shit could get crazy. Yeah.
Like literally every single executive,
every single war,
everybody.
I think that's part of a corporate that
you can think of. Phrases subsidize.
That's what's even crazier. Oil
is subsidized, you know, the, the,
the amount of fuckery that's involved
when you get heavy duty money involved in,
in corporations and those corporations
have influence on politics and they have
influence on the way laws are formed
and structured the way our society
functions. It's just, it's
madness. It's madness.
And I don't know what the solution is,
but until you,
until you figure out a way to,
to not have these big groups of people
that have this disk diffusion of
responsibility. And now
because of your, you know,
shooter Jennings is a part of BP and BP
does something fucked up and you're like,
man, that's fucked up. I can't
believe my company did that.
But oh well I got a raise.
I didn't do anything.
You can sleep tight knowing that
you didn't do anything personally,
but you're a part of a machine that did
something that they really fight was
held accountable for that. I'd be
so pissed. I'd be like, you know,
like it'd be beyond that. I mean,
exactly. That's, that's fascinating.
That's fascinating point.
I mean,
right that all of these companies that
the courts are in the favor of the
corporations usually
and it's like the like I can't believe
three companies own 80% of them of all
television or something like that.
And in the 80s it was like 60 companies
and now it's three and it's like just,
and you just look at the way that the
world is, the way that we react to, to,
to the media, the way we react to this
shit like that, you know? I Dunno. It's,
it's amazing and feels,
it did feel like when we were younger
that like with things like the BP oil
spill happened and stuff like I think if
that happened now that we wouldn't hear
about it.
What do you mean? I mean oil
spill happened was how long ago?
EAP was just a couple of years ago.
That was like 10 years ago. No,
yeah, it was four years
ago. Was thought. Nevermind.
The big one was a,
the Exxon Valdez that happened in
1988 one we heard it was a big one.
That was a big one, which is by
the way, that area is still fucked.
Of course it is 1988 and they killed
off a massive amount of salmon and the
battery is about to come out of there.
The best rate.
But then there's people like you and I
that drive cars and you know need gas and
you know, you buy an iPhone and how's it
going to fucking get to the apple store?
Someone's got to put that bitch in a
truck and it's got to drive it over there.
No other way.
You know the whole system has just,
it's been set up without a whole lot
of foresight. Like they, you know,
it was set up to deal with
what's available right now
and no one sort of saw the
future of how things are
going to get ugly and where,
where it could become problems and the
fast how much carbon he can get into the
air until it starts fucking
with the weather. And you know,
it's just so much and then there's so
much momentum also once like the thing
about like politics and the thing
about the influence of corporations and
special interests groups is that it's
sort of been this way for so long that to
come in now and try,
it's almost like there's a train running
through your neighborhood. John, John,
John, John, John, John, John, Matt,
and it's just training like we've got
to stop this train. Do you grab it?
Like how do you hold onto it? Well we
need to do is put some stuff on the track.
What's going to run over that stuff?
Well how the fuck do you stop the train
when you got to grab the back and put a
lot of weight on it?
Is that gonna work? No.
Well that all the things that we're
doing to try to like to reform politics,
like from an individual point of view,
whether it's complaining about it
online or writing blogs or doing this,
and it's akin to trying to grab a
hold of the back of the train, dig
your heels. I mean, yes, I agree.
The only way to deal with his move where
though Iceland or somewhere, I don't,
I don't mean like moving to USA. I mean
in a metaphor. I mean kind of like,
like don't you feel like,
I mean,
I feel like the only out of the people
that I've kind of read and research that
are kind of like this
antiestablishment shit,
it seems to be that if they tell
you, you know, you've gotta,
you've gotta do this now you've
got to wear a blue shirt every day.
And the only way, the way to, to, to
fight any of it is just by not doing it.
You know what I mean?
Like just, just whatever.
But at this point in time that they've
convinced this entire country and they've
convinced the entire world,
this is how things work.
And you'd have to go along with it,
like jump jobs and you know,
they liked the fact they keep,
they liked the fact that
everyone is freaking out about
money all the time. They,
they squeezed the middle and lower
class out of that, you know, it was the,
they're freaked out all the time that
the both parents are having to work all
the time. The kids are in Shitty
daycares with education is terrible.
And it's like they, that's how they keep
that and control, you know what I mean?
But most people just walk through life
and accept that and just say that's the
way it is. And, and you know, it's,
it's very few people that actually stand
up and try and figure something else
out, but there's not really
a solution, especially that,
that someone like me can give
anyone. But, but at the same time,
like I can sit back and look at it and
comment on it because like with the black
ribbons record, that was
my way, you know, my,
my getting like it was right when the,
uh,
the economy fell in
2009 the very beginning.
And it had gone to 2008 2009 and George
Bush was missing and Obama was looking
real glorious at the time.
And,
but nobody was doing anything
about the collapse of the economy.
And then the bank bailouts were
happening and it was just like, man,
this is insane. It was like the
scariest little point of time, you know?
And that's kind of where
that album came out of. And,
and for me it was really my comment on
the whole thing and by having Steven King
be the Dj and do all that Shit.
Like,
like what hit his character was
really what the record was about.
And it was kind of like keeping
hope and in hanging, you know,
small communities and the
family and, and you know, the,
those kind of like friendships
and things like that,
that level is the only way that
people like unions, you know,
were started because it was like people
were like, I can't take this shit,
we can't take this shit anymore. And they
start like that connection, that level.
That's where you can grab the train and
you can end, you know when enough people,
it's like that occupy
thing. Man. When I was,
I was in New York living at the time when
the occupy Wall Street thing happened
and, and my daughter was going to
a school in the financial district.
So like when I drop her
off at school and I,
me and my buddy would walk over to the,
to the occupy Wall Street and just hang
out in the middle of the whole thing,
you know? And it got a bad rap and
it had all these different things,
but those motherfuckers were standing up
to the man and the man was like fucking
shooting the beanbags, Adam and shit.
And do you know it was really crazy.
Like there they had books and the cops
were burning the books and shit. It was,
it was like some scene.
I like Nazi Germany when we walked
out of there is pouring rain.
There are people in the trees
like every 10 or 20 minutes,
like a whole bunch of cops with
those fucking guard things.
Would run through the fucking place and
knock some guy over a shields. Yeah,
the big sheet. Yeah, like the riot shit.
Like they're cops weren't right, but uh,
uh,
greatest scene.
I think someone filmed it
and I was there for it.
I've sitting in the middle of that thing,
that encampment,
the occupy Wall Street thing with my
friend Lincoln and we'd turn around,
man in this fucking cop comes running
with that fucking shield and just slips
because it's raining and he
just eat shit falls down man.
And it's like three or four
of these fucking hippies
are like, hey, you okay man.
You know, even though the rest of them
were like, fuck you pig, you know,
it was pretty funny,
man.
This motherfucker just ate shit running
into that thing and everybody is just
laughing about it. All
that occupies stuff. To me,
it signals that this possibility,
like it wasn't entirely successful,
sort of awaken people to the
idea of protesting. You know,
that you could protest in a mass scale
to get a lot of attention and that people
are willing to get involved because
a lot of people did get involved.
But what it also said to me is
if things got real squirrely,
like remember when we almost invaded
Syria? Yeah. You know, and then the,
the response was so strong against it
that you don't hear a peep about invading
Syria. I mean, when Obama came on
television and gave that speech,
it was almost like invading Syria is
inevitable. And everybody was like,
fuck you man, fuck you.
And then it stopped.
There was silence in the news.
Like you literally don't hear a peep
out of the government talking about the
inevitable invasion of Syria. It just
doesn't exist anymore because the writer,
black [inaudible] or his wife or something
on television, hunger every, he's like,
Ooh, look over here.
This things happening.
And on the right and the
left were against it.
And if they had gone forward,
I think that an action like that,
and I think they're calculated in that
response that like when you have a
million people, like, like a Sha
saying, there was a one of those,
one of the dictators, I forget which
one it was, it was ousted. He just,
I forget which one it was,
was it a long time ago?
But it was because he had said that if
there was more than three people that
were, uh, together that were
protesting together as a group,
they would be shot on sight.
I forget which dictator it was.
And within two days,
3 million people were in front of
his castle calling for his head.
And it was like,
Oh shit.
Like when you have a million people in
the streets that are calling for your
head, the fucking, the Gig is
up. And the, the real, the,
the numbers when you deal with the,
the president and the secret service,
and then the government and the military,
the actual numbers of those people that
you would need to protect against a mob
of 5 million Americans
that have had enough.
And then come with rifles and guns
and just storm the gates like everyone
worries I people say, well, what do you
do? The fruit of the Second Amendment,
what do you need a gun for? What? Why
do you need a gun? You don't need a gun.
Like that was that was written
back when there was muskets.
Let me tell you something. If this shit
thing ever, if the shit hits the fan,
if the shit hits the fan like that,
and all of a sudden you've got three or
4 million people that are showing up on
the White House lawn and then they start
storming in mass and they literally
call for the president's head and
rip him apart on national television.
That's not outside the
realm of possibility.
Given a few terrible decisions,
a natural disaster or a nuclear
bomb goes off somewhere in Chicago,
the fucking shit hits the fan.
And then next thing you know,
there's a million people with
guns. We'll buy as Jesus, you know,
anything can happen.
Any literally anything.
And that's what I got out
of occupy Wall Street.
I got out of like this
is this kind of descent.
It's manifesting itself in this form
right now where there's a bunch of people
with fucking drum circles and they're
saying enough is enough. And that was,
it was too hippy. It wasn't that.
It was the one issue was it was too.
It was too too like Koombaya.
Yeah, it was. I mean they,
even though it got rowdy there at the end,
it's like it wasn't enough.
You know what I mean?
That's what happens when when liberals
go like go protest and, and then there's,
when the right wing is protest, they have
a whole different ritual. But it's like,
I feel like when you look at all of that,
like you said,
it's the power of it man. I mean the
Edward Snowden Shit, we get into that,
you know, you could get into the
power of like how that's changed.
Remember that everyone
was like, Ooh, the cloud,
the cloud is so fucking cool
that's going to do everything.
And then Snowden comes out
and they're like, shit,
we don't want our shit on
the cloud. Like, I mean,
they start changing like rebranding
the concept of the word of the cloud.
You know, like you go to Europe and it's
still the cloud, the cloud, the cloud.
But here I think everyone
started getting a little like,
well it doesn't matter if it's the cloud
because they're going right in your God
damn. And they know they're going into
your hard drive put. They're their,
they're hacking your hard drive and they
are going right in there pulling out
all your data, pulling all your credit
card information and putting out all your,
your contacts.
You know,
if you are a person that involved
in some controversial activity,
every one that you call everyone that
you talk to, they get monitored. Now,
like if you,
if you start talking crazy shit about
the government on this podcast and then
you make a phone call,
if the NSA decides to monitor you,
they're gonna Monitor your buddies.
They're going to monitor people
you fucking play pool with,
they're gonna monitor a
guy you go drinking with.
Like everybody gets monitored and you
all become suspects. You all got on?
I got started getting monitored
after I went on this show. Oh,
it be before you even decided to go on
the show, when I was tweeting about you,
you probably started getting
monetarily immediate.
Probably already monitored before that.
Probably. Probably. I wouldn't doubt that.
It's ridiculous. I mean it's like, look,
we're not criminals. There's not no ones.
These aren't criminals.
The idea that you're monitoring 99% of
the country or whatever the fuck the
numbers are, what does everybody
at criminal and then they're,
they're monitoring each other
like the Senate. They fucking,
the NSA was spying on
the Goddamn Senate man.
Did you read the thing about the world
Warcraft with one of the documents?
You know that game, the, the world of
Warcraft? It's like a, it's like an online
role playing game with like
1 million millions of players
go on around the world.
And they had,
they had NSA agents in there because
they were saying that that terrorists
groups were,
we're meeting in those games.
They would go in the game and they'd
meet and they had to talk in there.
So they said that they had so many in
essay agents in world of Warcraft that
they had to assign other NSA agents to
watch those NSA just inside of world war.
I mean,
can't you see these mother fuckers
playing like he's like a level
50 wizard. He's like, yeah man,
we're going to bust some fucking terrorist
today. Fuck yeah, and kill it. Drag it.
And you know,
while they're busting other people who
are pretending to be terrorists so that
you bust other terrorists. And I was like,
yes, that's awesome. What a great idea.
I'm going to go and I'm going to go on
an online game and I wonder how many
times there have been undercover sting
operations where an undercover drug
dealer was selling drugs to an undercover
DEA h and posing as a god by drugs to
movie. It's a movie should write that.
Totally just write it into a movie.
They want to kill each other and then
everyone tries to cover it up and it
becomes some crazy story. It's kind of,
it must have happened before. It has to.
If it had happened like 21 jump street,
the end of the movie with the Cameo
with uh, what's his name? Johnny Depp.
Maybe she was, did you see the new 21
jump street? No. No. That's great. Is it,
does a great cameo of Johnny Depp though,
just blew that for you then?
Well, similar to that, spoiler
alert, I think I'll be okay.
The undercover guy blowing it for the
other undercover guy kind of thing.
It's just when these guys start
spying on each other, it's like,
this is the CIA think that the Senate
is a bunch of criminals is that's what's
going on or do you just have carte blanche
to just spy on people? So you're like,
fuck it. Let's buy on these guys. Let's
buy and everybody, I don't trust him.
Fuck that guy. Let's spy on him. Let's,
let's find out where his dick
pictures are hiding in his hard drive.
They said they pass those around the
office about chips they did in these and
stuff. They did it also. They like spied
the people that were in the office.
I spied on ex girlfriends.
They look fine. Ex girlfriend.
That's the smartest thing they probably
did. You know what I mean? Man,
you could really, I'm going,
you know what? After that girl,
I'm going to join the NSA and I'm gonna
work my way all the way to the top just
so I can fuck her for
the rest of her life.
It's just when the CIA
spies on the Senate,
I really think that they should bring
everybody involved and lock them up.
Just like you guys.
You not only did you violate everything
that you're supposed to be standing for,
you guys are supposed to
be looking out for us.
The way you're looking at is by spying
on the fucking Senate. Looking in. Yeah.
Do you think that the Senate is bad?
Do you think that they're involved in,
are they terrorists?
Are they the enemy?
Are they working for the fucking Russians?
Like what do you toe in the fuck
are you doing wasting money?
Like you should go to jail just for
wasting tax dollars just for fraud.
Pretending that you're
here resolving democracy
or that you're here
protecting and serving.
You should go to jail just for
misrepresenting what your job is.
Cause you guys are gotten to him.
Crux.
Yeah. I mean a bunch of them, you
know, and that's why I love like I,
I'm on the Edward Snowden team
because it's just like fuck yeah,
that's what we work.
That's the kind of Shit,
you know that like movies were
made up like that we wanted,
we wanted to happen and we
want some guy to be like, Yo,
you all are getting
fucked and I'm going to,
I'm willing to die over this shit
and tell you about it, you know?
Yeah. And before Obama was
in office, that whole hoping,
fucking hope and change his website was
all about protecting whistle blowers.
All that shit was removed once all this
stuff started going down with Edward
Snowden and with Julian Assan.
But before that he was all about
protecting whistleblowers who are exposing
illegal activity. Guess what?
That's exactly what Snowden did.
Everything he did is protecting people
who are being exposed to dangerous
elements of attic control government.
I mean that's,
that's really what's going
on. I didn't, I didn't
realize that was on the, the Obama pay.
I mean, I never went to the Obama page,
but at the same time, like I never,
I never knew that, that he said that.
What a crock of shit. Jesus Christ. I
mean they were like, we had to say, Hey,
snow didn't come back here where we
promise we're not going to kill you.
Like when we, when America
has to say that, you know
what I mean? It's like fuck,
we're fucked. It's like Howard Stern
says, man, you know, he's like,
we're like the last, you know, we,
we are like the like people to
say we shouldn't police the world,
but the reality is, is like 90% of the
world were like murdering their own.
People are like stoning women death.
Like there's all these other countries,
like there's not many countries that
that says, Hey, fucking stop. Right.
That is what we want from
America is what we hope for.
But when you look at it and you look at
the NSA shit and all that, it's like,
you know, it's, it's just hard to get
all hyped up and excited about it.
I mean our world changed so much. Man,
I was talking to, I was talking to for,
I'm 35 and it's talking to
a friend of mine about this,
about how are my generation.
It was like our world is so
fucked compared to everybody
else's because I mean
it's probably just getting worse
for the other kids. But you know,
we saw like when we were 14 Kurt Cobain,
I was 14 curriculum and blew his
brains out. So like by that time,
like you're just kind of,
I was just kind of,
everybody's kind of hopeful
and then when that happens,
that's the first time that's
ever happened. It was so dark.
It was so like there was
photographs floating around
in my high school of it and
shit. And I remember kind of
being like, man, this is dark,
but it kind of like threw me,
I was really into nine inch nails and
Manson and shit like that and like threw
me into that world even more. And you
know, I, everybody loved the dark,
love the dark and then fucking nine
11 happens when we were like 20,
21 and it's like, holy fuck, like
everything changed after that point.
Like everyone, everyone is a lot
darker. Everyone is like, realizes that.
Yeah. You know, that might
just, these massive assaults
can happen here. You know,
there was always kind of
like dreamy. It's, you know,
it's America thing.
It's like we always kind of,
even though there was a lot of corruption
with like, from Nixon to like the, the,
you know, the Kennedy assassination and
shit, which was kind of the start of like,
like televise or, or public
or, uh, you know, uh,
broadcast in certain ways and newspapers
like death, mass death and weird,
crazy shit like that.
But you look at a,
there was always this kind of hopefulness
and I think like after nine 11 and
after kind of everything that's gone,
like people are really like
disillusioned to it. You know, they,
we don't have that same,
that same kind of feeling that that was
going on in the eighties and nineties
you know what you're saying,
like the perception of what
America stands for. Yeah.
You used to be that. We wouldn't
know where else, you know,
everybody used to say it's the land of the
free. Like there's, they still, I mean,
you know, you still got to New
York and the cab driver guy who's,
who's by the way only driven for two
weeks because he got here two weeks ago.
Like he'll still tell you like, I'm God
damn so happy to be in America of course,
because you're in New York City and it's
beautiful and there is a beauty to that
and, and what we offer the rest of the
world and people that are in these fucking
terrible countries and they escape
and they come here and it's like that.
That's great. But like in comparison
to the Congo were awesome. Yeah, yeah.
Compares the Congo. We are awesome. But
at the same time we're also like, we've,
we're like kids that,
you know,
like I think the couple of
generations before as it was like,
the parents stayed together and it
was like great. Like we're the kids.
The mom shot the dad and got away
with it and we're like, all right.
You know what I mean? Like, like
our, our, our vision of, of, uh,
America is kind of like, yeah, we
really kind of hate our parents,
but where I see what you're saying, you
know what I mean? Like, like I, yeah,
that sounded weird when I said
it, but what I'm, what am,
I know what you're saying though.
Like I just feel like we kind of are
this weird w this world that we're in and
the three of us and everybody that we
know kind of now, it's like we have this,
this kind of just disdain for things.
Like you look at this fucking sandy hook
and all these terrible things that are
happening and,
and everyone wants to focus on the gun
rights thing when there's mental health
issues that need to be dealt with.
There's all kinds of stuff,
but there have been crazy people forever.
There have been murders forever.
It's like, but changing the
system and trying to get ready,
just everything just seems so
fucked. You know, you're like,
you wake up and you just want to
watch cartoons. You don't want to be,
definitely don't want to watch the
news and you definitely don't want like
reasons why things are so fucked in in
as far as our perceptions is because
we're getting more information about
the real dealings of our government now
than ever before because of guys like
joining a songs and because of guys like
Edward Snowden, one of the things that
people don't like about it is like, well,
you know, they're exposing
American secrets. They're
putting Americans at risk.
Well,
maybe what Americans are doing is putting
Americans at risk because what they're
doing is exposing truth,
exposing things that we don't like.
I remember after September 11th,
one of the things that I found like the
most shocking about it all was how many
American flags were on people's cars.
Like I would drive to work.
And that was crazy fucking madness, man.
Every car had an American flag on it.
It was nuts. My friend Jay London, Jay
Lund had started selling American flags.
Well, he was smart. He made a ton
because it was insane when that happened.
You remember, he, it's like
exposing secrets, you know,
Geraldo exposes secrets has put guys
in lives in danger, not Edward Snowden.
And that's like telling you yeah, but
the, the fucking, uh, the flags, man,
that was insane. It was like this,
there was like a sense of, you know,
but who knows if that was real, like the,
I mean, you know what I mean? It was real.
People were buying the flags. That sense
of, of, of nationalism was real obviously,
but at the same time,
like there was a side of it.
It was just like there was marketing and
there was all these things and there,
there was like the magic trick going
on in the right hand while there's shit
going over here on the left hand.
And then you have like the Fahrenheit
nine 11 movie and you're like, well,
looking at that and everybody's
looking at in this loose change.
And some people were saying it
wasn't a plane that hit the Pentagon.
It was a missile and you got fucking
a, the wrestler. What's his name?
It's got to tell you've been to her chair.
Uh,
I feel like talking about they
got bombed paint, you know?
Did you ever watch the nine 11
episode of that conspiracy theory?
Here's the problem with
that conspiracy theory.
I work with those very same people.
When I did the sci fi show Joe
Rogan questions, everything.
I loved that shit there.
That was a killer shoe.
Thanks man. W W we still might
do it. We were still talking.
I just don't want to do it the
way we did it because they,
there's a lot of fuckery
involved in those shows.
Turn the plane around, Alex Jones. Wants
to talk and it's like, wait a minute,
what? There's just, they
use those shows. They like,
they gravitate towards the
fantastic and avoid simplicity,
employ and avoid, what would it be? Boring
TV, which is really the juice. Yeah.
I want to also avoid like other
possible scenarios that aren't as sexy.
You know,
there's a lot of incompetence involved
in government and sometimes people,
they misconstrue conspiracy,
they think of it's conspiracy.
It was really just a bunch of idiots that
did a shitty job of protecting people.
And then you know,
the,
the scramble afterwards and then people
that have capitalized on the scramble
and made money.
And then people look at the people
that capitalized on the event and say,
oh well this is clear evidence that there
was a conspiracy and these people that
were the ones that profited off of it.
Maybe not.
Maybe there was a fucking horrible event.
And some people look at horrible events
as an opportunity to make money and they
did and they didn't have
anything to do with it happening.
But they did have something to do
with profiting off of it. You know?
So there's a lot of like,
and you,
you people get involved in
these conspiracy discussions.
And unfortunately what happens is when
you start labeling a bunch of shit
conspiracies that aren't
really conspiracies,
you throw the whole thing into a tizzy
because now no one knows what the fuck to
believe.
And if I find out that you're wrong
about a bunch of ridiculous conspiracy
assumptions,
if you're wrong about
those, what, what else? What
am I supposed to think about?
All the other shit that you're
saying like I very right about that.
And that's a real problem with conspiracy
theories is that the people who find
them,
they're sexy to find.
So people go looking for them and fucking
everything and they're not willing to
abandon them once they have sort of
called them out once they've called that a
conspiracy theory,
they stick with it and they ride that
fucker right into the rocks. You know?
And a lot of these nine 11 guys are
like that and he's a is nine 11 guys.
There's photos that people said,
look,
it's clear that thermite it cut this
steel and the steel, that asshole,
they cut that steel so they can move
it like this is all after the fucking
buildings went down and you guys are
touting this as evidence that thermite was
used. They cut the fucking girders so
that they can move that shit out of there.
Well, you wanted to get rid of all
that waste and ship it over to China.
What did you want him to do?
You want him to hang on to it?
What do you want him to do?
Put it in a pile so that you can go and
send your independent investigators that
are going to go over and scan for
thermite. Yeah. Fuck man. See,
I know you,
you started talking about that in the
first thing to think about is the biggest
one is what happened was I bin Ladin
whole we dumped his body whenever that
whole story.
Yeah.
Everybody talks about that and it's
like people say he was not there.
That had nothing to do with.
There was never a situation there.
He was been dead for a long time.
A lot of people,
special ops people say that he's been
dead forever. Yeah. Yeah. Say that he,
that he died ages ago and they just
did this to pull that dude out of the
freezer and chucked them into the ocean.
I don't know man. Who the fuck
knows? You're right though, man.
People were ride that shit down and
it's like you end up kind of like,
he's more confusion. It is. It's like
white noise and static, you know,
around all the time. It's almost just
as bad as the is the is the media is,
you know, while it, and it helps them,
it helps anyone in government because
it also shows that anytime there's any
sort of a cataclysmic disaster,
anytime there's any sort of an event,
like a nine 11 there's so much scrambling
and there's so much chaos afterwards
that it's impossible to get a clear
story on what exactly happened. Yeah.
They love that. Yeah.
Especially if, you know,
it's like when they're
involved in something.
That's why Edward Snowden and people
like that really terrifying because they
tried to, you know, they planted fakes
node in stories that were like, there was,
there was a Ufo one that they were trying
to plant them so he would look like a
Kook and they weren't real real like it.
It'd be like an article and then you know,
some European magazine saying that
it's noted papers say that the,
the government knew about Ufos and he's
had them for a long time and all this,
those are a perfect one. Right? She
wanted to learn to cook. Perfect one man.
I mean, I've never you, it's like I'm
obsessed with all this shit. You know,
I'm obsessed with all of it. But the
reality is is like I've never seen,
I would love to see a ghost.
Babies never fucking seen a fucking ghost.
I've never seen a fucking alien. I've
never seen any of it. I've tried.
I've slept in haunted houses. I met
people that have, I've seen goat.
Like anytime somebody tells
me ghost story, the first
thing I think it was like,
you're fucking crazy. Like,
that's the first thing I think,
because I've never seen one.
Have you ever had an experience
with it goes or anything? No.
I've gone to the comedy store really
late at night at the comedy store.
Y'all heard about all that? I've heard
about all this shit about the murder,
the killing room they had
up there or whatever. Well,
the comedy store used to be Ciro's
nightclub and it was owned by Bugsy Siegel
and many people were murdered there
and Ciro's nightclub, you know,
this was back in the 1930s, I guess
in the 1940s, like whenever it was,
there were the early 20th century and
that was a place where it Dean Martin and
Jerry Lewis would perform.
And the comedy store's
original form was like,
essentially a mob club.
It was a mob run nightclub and a
lot of people were killed there.
There was a tunnel from the back
of the comedy store, main room,
the green room in the main room where
you would go and take this tunnel up and
do a house that was up in the hills like
they had it during the, uh, illegal, uh,
bootlegging error. Wow. Yeah.
There was a lot of wacky
shit that happened in that
place. And because of that,
I've heard too many stories about a
person that sits in the audience or
something. There's some lady that,
yeah, I've heard mostly bullshit.
Mostly bullshit. I was there, I performed
at the comedy store for 13 years.
Wow. And, uh, I never saw
shit. Yeah. I looked around.
I went there late at night.
I would,
I would sit in the main room when the
lights were out and everyone was gone and
just wait for shit to happen. Wow. Yeah.
Nothing happened it. See, that's what,
that doesn't mean that
something couldn't be there.
I just want to see some
fucking day, man. I mean,
these people like these fucking books
and he'd go on these talk shows and say
this shit. I'm like, I don't believe
a fucking word you're saying.
I just can't believe it because I
can't, I've never seen it, man. I mean,
but imagine if you did
and what you saw was, uh,
a brief but unique moment and in
that brief unique moment you saw.
Yeah. And then it's gone and you're like,
what the fuck? But you saw it. Yeah.
There's no way to measure it.
There's no way to become a cook,
I guess you may be right. Talk shows and
be like, and then his face was, I mean,
I don't know man.
It's,
I haven't completely ruled it out
because somebody brought out ghosts.
I just want to see some proof. I
just want to see something. I mean,
it just seems so nuts.
Like I got abducted by aliens and
my ass got probed and all this shit.
Like I see these people and you're like,
these poor people are so lonely
and they got nothing going on.
And they either dream this shit up or
they're taken ambien walking around in
their front yard, asleep, you know,
have this thing or whatever it is. Like,
I just don't know.
It's like I want to man,
me and my dad went to cause the
fire in the sky when I was a kid.
When that movie came out, you know, it
was just touching into mainstream all,
it's like alien abduction Shit,
you know?
And I used to watch x
files every fucking week.
I think that Travis Walton guys been
kind of called out as being a bullshit.
Right. It turned out, it turned out to,
there was some kind of thing
where there was fraud to it.
It's like it always is going to,
it's like that. Have you seen
that movie? It was so well done.
The well I mean the movies. Okay,
but the fourth close,
the fourth kind. Oh yeah,
no I didn't you see it cause it was like,
yeah cause they had like this lady who's
supposed to be the real lady and they
have her interviews with Mila Jovovich
and the scenes, but it was all fake.
Like they set up this whole
thing. I mean, you know Blair,
which was the first to do this kind
of shit, but eventually like it's all,
it's all coming down is fake.
I would think,
well that's just entertainment,
you know? I mean it's,
the real problem is
when you deal with the,
the people that are involved in
the quote unquote Ufo community.
Like I've interviewed a ton of those
for that television show and I sat down,
we had the show.
Each episode was only an hour long,
but in that hour long episode
I had several hour plus
long conversations with a
lot of different people that
were involved in these things.
And one thing that you get out of them
is that these mother fuckers only have
one option. That option in
their head is at you for real,
even if they haven't seen shit themselves.
And what they're not taking into account
is how many people are liars. How many,
like I've told this story before,
I was in the woods once
and I thought I saw a wolf.
I thought it was a wolf for
about four seconds at the most.
It was a squirrel saw a
squirrel. I was like, I said,
Wolf Squirrel. What the fuck is wrong
with me? Like it was literally like that.
Like I thought it was a wolf.
It was a squirrel and it was the woods.
And I'm saying, and I'm also, I'm con,
I constantly check myself. I, I'm,
I'm a very objective like that what,
but most like what are you doing dummy?
I'm always like saying that
to myself to make sure that,
but some people don't ever say,
what are you doing dummy?
Say I know what I saw. They're not
the joke with no punchline thing.
You know what I mean? It's like there's
no punch line to get you out of it.
So you're stuck in a joke forever.
It's like,
I know exactly you're talking about like
the other day my wife came home and I
was drunk with a knife because
I, because I had um, I had this,
our doorbell fell off right at our door
bells, like, like stuck to our front door.
It's not like wired in some kind of
little wireless thing and it said it had
fallen off.
So I put it inside the house and my wife
was gone and I was working and I was
drunk.
I was just drinking and hanging out and
like playing a video game that me and my
buddies play and stuff and I had been
drinking and all of a sudden the doorbell
rings and I'm like doorbells inside,
you know,
like I'm like Holy Shit and
I'll get a knife out. You know?
Cause it's like if someone's a bad
guy to get a ring the doorbell first,
where they get you, oh yeah, I'm old.
But they're in the house
and ringing the doorbell,
letting me know they're in the
house. You know what, I'm not a guy.
I'm not like a scaredy cat.
Like I'm always the guy that
goes downstairs to check it out.
I'm got no problem with that.
I got no problems walking down the stairs.
There may be somebody down that you know,
but at this moment I was like,
I'm alone and the doorbell's ringing on
the inside of the house and this fucking
sucks and I'm hammered. So I'm like
getting the knife out, you know? But,
but like I, again, same kind of thing.
Like, I think I'll see something,
I think I'll hear and my mind goes
to these places, but at the end of the
day, I know it's ridiculous, you know,
and unless it's a home
invasion of tweakers.
That's the only thing I'm worried about.
Tweaker home invasion,
which was rampant here when I first
moved into town in the flatlands.
But yeah tweaker home invasions are real.
It's tweets tweakers need money.
Bad.
They,
they come up with wacky plans and that's
the number one thing that happens to
meth heads as they lose their ability
to make good decisions. Yeah. Yeah.
Cause it's like after a couple
of days and shit, you know,
you're been for like nine days, get
more. Yeah. Well they also like,
they don't see how, it's almost
like their judgment gets cut off.
Like they can only see like
a couple steps forward.
They can't see like the
whole future. So they, they,
they see a co I know what I'll do,
I'll just store all the math in my ass,
you know,
and no one's going to check there.
And then they get arrested and they're
pulling math out of the rest. What,
what are you doing back there man?
I just find it like high as I find it.
Do you know that people
store things in their ass?
Guys have stored guns in their ass.
So there's this one article in Gq about
this guy who was a lawyer and he was
representing um, meth heads and
somewhat thing was juke vanity fair.
Gq One of those.
And uh,
along the way start doing meth and
then he started selling meth. Wow.
And then he kind of,
yeah, he had his basement,
had like buckets of meth.
Like he had like made it and like was
storing it in his basement, if you like.
Are you out of your fucking mind? Yeah,
he was. Yeah. He was out of his mind.
That's insane. He was a
lawyer representing meth
heads who became Heisenberg,
like full went full retard did that.
So it's saying what a great story and
now I've got to find that article.
Yeah. I wish that it was
many years ago. I wish.
But I remember reading that one of the
experts that we're interviewing was
talking about you're a lack of ability
to make critical decisions and that it
goes out the window. It's one of
the first symptoms of a Matthews.
As people start doing like rational
people started doing really irrational
things and don't seem to understand the
consequences of it. It's like they can't,
there's just so they don't see, you
know, you see several steps ahead.
Like you say like, well, you know, um,
if I go outside and
light that car on fire,
well if it explodes and then what are
the tree catches on fire and then the
building catches on fire. Fuck
man, I could start a big fire.
Meth heads don't think that.
All they think is I'm going to
like that fucking car on fire.
Nothing's gonna happen.
You know? That's, it's, so,
I know I have known plenty of people
who have gone down that path and I mean,
I've tried this shit if you've tried math.
Yeah, because it like, it's just like,
it's like really powerful coke. It's
like if you got like I've been, I had,
there have been times in places where
someone is, is it had that shit like,
I mean it's,
I'm not a big,
I'm not like fucking dude in
blow all day long or anything,
but there've been times I've done shows
and shit and there's me around and be
like, hey man, you want a party? And
I'm like, yeah, fuck it man. Yeah,
that's the guy you like think the guy's
going to chop up some glow or something.
Right. And then it was, it'll be like a,
it's meth but I mean it's
funny to call it because it's
crank or speed.
Like when I first moved
here I was partying a bunch
and there was this guy that
had like this yellow dog speed. It
was like yellowish powder. It wasn't,
and it's the same kind of effect.
Like it like one line of it,
we'll keep you up for like 10 hours.
Like with coke you want to do more
every hour or every 30 minutes.
And with math, like you do a line and
you're like, Ooh, like for fucking,
you can stay on for like 10
hours, you know, if you want to.
And then those guys like that's why Matt,
like you don't need as much of it and
they'll just do some or they'll smoke it
and do that. And you know, it's like,
that's what it is. It's like really,
really powerful coke.
So like I can't stay up all night and
coke and I have stayed up all night one
time on math.
Just one line of it of just being up
and you just like play the guitar and
you're like seeing and you're just so
into singing, you know. But like in the,
in the southeast where we play a lot,
it's, it's so big down there. I mean,
I mean every,
like my buddies that live in Kentucky
and stuff like it's everywhere and that
their buddies, I'll do it and they'll,
you know, fall, they'll do it.
Sometimes they'll do it occasionally and
then one of the guys will start doing
it too much and he'll fucking like,
you know,
there's tons of sad stories guys with
kids and shit that are just doing it and
staying over eight and nine days and the
kids have no idea and they're fucking
just wired and get, you know, so
I mean it's, it's just insane.
It's not, it's, it, it burns like
a motherfucker too. When you do it,
like when you take,
when you do it,
if you do a why I did it like
burns your nose like insane.
Like burns the inside of your nose.
Yeah. I mean, but it's kind of awesome.
The burn, the burn is kind
of the addictive thing
cause it's like, it's like,
then you're like eating Jalapenos.
Yeah. It's like snorting Jalapenos.
So how many times he'd done meth?
Ah,
probably going to sound like a
lot. Five. Five, Eh, don't worry.
The worry that people have is that you
do it once and then you're gone. No,
it's not like heroin in that way.
I've never done heroin, but it's,
but I know people have been on heroin.
I know it's like the,
there's that immediate like euphoria
thing and, and with, with, with math,
the reason why it's so cheap, it's
so cheap. It's so much more potent.
And I think that's why it's such a big,
and it's like, it's such a big deal,
you know,
it's,
it's easy to make with weird shit and
Draino and all this fucking shit in it.
And then in Sudafed and all that,
you know,
I mean they got to in the south where
they had to move sudafed behind the
counter because people were
coming in and buy and like six,
seven packs of sudafed.
If you buy it on here,
you have to give you your drivers on
it. Yeah, that's, yeah, that's true.
We did in the south where they were
like real fast. But I mean, you know,
I mean I probably, there's
probably been times, I mean,
there's probably been times
I've may have done it,
like where I thought I was doing something
else and then I'm like, oh, that's,
that's definitely, that's definitely
crank. You know what I mean?
But it's like my brothers
and sisters and cousins,
I mean they probably hate me for saying
this, but I mean where they come from,
that's common. It's common that
people have done crank or, or do it.
I mean it's not, it's not like weird and
it's, it's definitely not addictive. Like,
I mean,
if you're the type person who's never
done cocaine and you do cocaine and all of
a sudden you're like, fuck, I gotta do
more cocaine all the fucking time. Like I,
I know certain people that are into coke
like that, but I could never do that.
Like if I do have done coke, I can't do
it for another couple of days. I'm not,
I'm not the guy who stays up all night
and does the whole bag and does, I'll,
I'll do like, you know,
bump or something like that.
But it's been a long time since
I've done it. But if I did do it,
I would just do small amounts
of it, you know, here or there.
But there are people that if you have
that personality where you're going to be
the guy who does,
he locks himself in a hotel room
for three days and it does blow.
It doesn't show up for your job and all
that shit because just because you got a
bag of blow at, uh, at a party, you know,
then you're going to have
a problem with crank.
But I think it's the same kind of thing
though. It's just hardcore mandate.
It's not my style. Like some
certain people prefer crank to coke,
then I would like,
or you know,
some people were for Adderall and do
all that and it's like kind of like,
I mean none of it excites me that much,
but I would definitely,
anything that lasts a really long time
I can't do, I've got kids and shit.
You know what I mean? Like
if I'm in a party, I'm like,
weed is like right down my
alley. That's, I love weed.
I can fucking do it in the studio.
I do it at night after kids are asleep
to go to bed like it. It's kind of you.
It's never going to fuck you up so much.
You can't snap out of it and fucking
make a good decision at times.
You know you can like, man, I shouldn't
have fucking ate that old pizza,
but you know that it's not like,
you know,
I went and robbed my mom's house and I
woke up two days later in a ditch and I'm
like, fuck, probably shouldn't done that
crank. Yeah, it's still speedy ones.
They accelerate you and they, they cut
out a lot of decision making process.
They definitely do. They
definitely, I mean it just in an,
there's no two ways about it.
After you've been up an entire day,
you just start fucking,
I mean you start seeing stuff like I,
I've done that it without drugs.
You know what I mean?
I've stayed up days and you just start
getting delirious in like when you're
using something that's fueling your
heart rate and keeping you there,
your brain is still acting as if you are
not on the drugs and you've been up for
five days and you're seeing she had,
but yet you're just wired from that shit.
That's what they do. The home
invasion thing, like there was a, um,
I used to live on a, what I've
lived all of this town, but uh,
Santa Monica and gardener, there's
a astro burger right there. Yeah.
I lived right there behind the fat burger
and there was a house there that were
notoriously,
had been like tweakers like kick the door
down and came in and were just fucking
like tied the whole family
up and Shit and money.
Cause that's all they want is they want
money to buy more crank, essentially the,
the,
the deal.
But they ended up fucking killing people
and all kinds of shit over, you know?
Yeah, yeah. Well, you know the
thing, we're going to get caught.
Kelly's people will fuck it. We'll never
get caught that way. Yeah. You know,
they're not seeing a bunch of
steps ahead. Yeah. For sure.
People are terrified of crank their,
they're terrified of math are terrified
of anything that makes people maniacs.
You know, that's the big fear.
Yeah. Over the bath salts craze.
Then guy who like chewed the dude's face
off and it turns out he wasn't on bath
salts like well he was,
here's the thing,
they they say, oh we, all they
found in his system was marijuana.
The real problem is they don't
have tasks for bath bath salts,
so when they say huge issue in Kentucky,
my friend because he crank is now getting
to where it's like too expensive and
the coal miners, the coal mine, the,
you know the tests for amphetamines show
up in their systems to the coal miners
one and that.
That's why they,
that that bath salts things started
because the, from what I heard,
one of one of the regions I guess was
that the coal miners are doing that and it
wouldn't show up on the test.
They'd go,
they'd fucking smoke or snort a bunch
of that shit and go down in the fucking
coal mines and fucking work for like
three days straight. It makes sense there.
They don't. What they do
apparently was they take a drug,
whether it's math or
something along those lines,
and then they alter it slightly so
that it doesn't show up in a task.
But it still has some pretty significant
response. Yeah. And the human body.
And then they sell it as not for
human consumption. Bath salts.
Like I didn't understand it.
I thought it was just like people have
figured out that bath salts make you high
when you, you do, I'm like,
there's something weird about the vast
salts you snoring, but no, they just,
they're selling them as bad, bad faults
because that's the way he could sell it.
Yeah. There's fake pot too that they
sell. It's like something like that.
And I tried to back on that one time
and it was terrible. It was like,
just give me a headache
instantly. You know, you're,
you could've smoked a cookie and
probably done less damage. You know,
I have to say like I'm,
I'm a foodie too and all this and I just,
while we're on this,
I don't know when I punched in my head,
but there was a tweet you sent out that
I saved the photograph and I look at it
is that when you had like seven eggs and
it was like clearly a little butter in
the, in the pantry. And I
cook too. And I was like,
I was looking at this fucking
thing and I was like, God,
I could eat that all day and all night.
But the fact that you had that photograph,
the seven eggs,
I have it in my phone right now.
I have 24 chickens. Really? Yeah.
So those are all fresh eggs from my yard.
Yeah.
It's so great when you can get out and
jump into that. No, no, no worries man.
And it was like the eggs
are, you know, I'm getting,
I'm like the day they come out,
come out of the chicken boom,
I'm frying them and it's a dark,
like an orange yolk. So dear.
Like if I go to a restaurant, a
diner in our order, some eggs,
and you look at the Yolk, you're like,
what did you guys feed your chickens?
Like paper?
Nothing that there's nothing in this yoke.
I think I have the fucking
photographs. I did. I did.
I know I saved it.
It's in here so,
well I've been eating
nothing but farm fresh eggs.
Like we're for the past year.
My goal is by the end of this year,
to have all the meat in my house.
Be Wild game that I've killed our eggs.
Be the Chicco hunting La.
Yeah. It's funny. I've never been hunting.
Really? Yeah. I'm a computer nerd.
Like was as a kid. Like my
dad. We went, we went out
shooting. One time I did quail.
I did quail hunting with my buddy
when I was a kid. I mean, you know,
if they go out in the field
and everybody's shooting
at the fucking birds and
shit, but I never, I've never
even been hunting. I mean,
I've just never been my, my,
it's never been my thing.
Like I like
guns. I've, I've, I've gone shooting guns
and things like that but, but I've never,
I've just never really
done it. I mean I, I,
I can tell you like I can,
there are people around and be like,
I can never fucking blow his brains
out or whatever. But I mean I,
I would go with you. I would
definitely go. I'm not like,
I'm not opposed to going.
So you wouldn't go,
but you wouldn't pull the trigger.
I don't know if I would pull the trigger.
I never killed an animal with a gun.
Have you ever had venison? Oh, I love it.
I love it only comes from killing deer.
You got to kill. No, I know, I know that.
I'm just saying, you know what I mean?
But there are certain people
that are like, I like,
and I mean my wife would never kill it.
You never know.
Go hunting or like I that I have lots
of friends. I'd probably be like,
I don't know if I could do it, I would
go, got no problem with it. I've, I've,
I think that there's so many good
things that come from haunting,
like whether it be,
and I love that when people say that
they hunt their own their own meat and,
and eat it and all that. I'm just
saying I've never done, I mean people,
people think that I'm
like a Harley riding.
Like they think I'm tall first of all.
Then second of all,
they think that I'm like into hunting and,
and like all this redneck
shit and I've been like,
I have a computer geek that
moved to La when I was 29 I said,
well you sing country music.
Your Dad is one of the great
country icons of all time. I know,
but he didn't really hunt or do anything
like that either. He was that he had,
he had a gun collection of like civil war
era guns and stuff. And he's into, into,
into that kind of stuff, very into history
and stuff, which I was real good. He,
you know, in his own way,
he was kind of Nerdy,
forgot from being from Texas
and being who he was, you know?
But he was just kind of in into
history and things like that.
But we went hunting with Hank jr one
time and neither one of us hit nothing.
Like we would go fishing
every once in a while. Uh,
Toni Jo White was a great artist
who used to take us fishing.
My Dad had said he had a curse,
like you can never catch anything.
And I went fishing the Johnny Cash one
time too. Wow. Was just kind funny.
But as a kid and we went fishing
with Johnny Cash. Holy Shit.
Johnny had like a bunch of fish that he'd
already caught and he had them rigged
somewhere that,
so they,
so he was gonna try and make
it where my dad would actually,
does he think he caught something?
Cause he couldn't ever go like we were,
we were rural out, outdoorsy
people. Let's just hit that way.
Like I watch way more
horror movies with my dad.
Like he's to wake me up in the
middle of the night. It's eight.
There's a scary movie on TV and I go
downstairs. I was like six or seven.
I got onto it and proceed to like it
petrified by some horrible movie that
actually six year old
shouldn't lodge malaria.
So I was kind of more our activity,
listened to music and watch movies.
It's funny isn't it,
that country music is inexorably connected
to like hunting and fishing? Yeah,
well I mean naturally I guess
you know, because the, the,
the era and the like, you know,
if you go back a little bit,
I mean not very far from
my dad's generation, me and
him growing up and all the,
all of the grand old Opry and all that
hit, I mean all those guys were into that.
They all lived in the woods,
like the tea,
the Nashville and less
time and say Nashville,
like even all of the southeast was far,
far more undeveloped.
So like back then it was really
country folks and they were in like
country music.
They would roll their windows up when
they listen to it because it was frowned
upon. It was like a poor
people's music, you know?
So a lot of the people
in the south and stuff,
it's inevitably tied into that of course.
But I mean,
you know it's funny because
now it's like someone,
if they're critical of I like I don't
represent myself pretending to be like
anything.
I'm not,
but if someone was ever critical of the
fact that I live in La and I'm not like
a country boy and I play
like country style of music,
it's like do you guys really think that?
You know Jason Aldeen and these fucking,
these new country guys that are so big,
like you really think those guys at daily
existence is like tailgate parties and
hunting and things like that.
You guys are fucking retarded because
they're shopping for shoes on Melrose.
Getting caught cheating
at the Cabo Cantina.
I say shopping for shoes.
Oh man, he's making it look
country man. These pre,
these genes are perfectly
pre, pre torn, right?
Perfectly Praetorian is the worst.
God. It's so fucking stupid.
There's nothing stupider than wearing
jeans that are already have holes in a
builtin. It's so dumb. No,
of course it's so dumb,
but it's something that everybody wants.
They want to like already be worn in,
you know, they want to pretend
that you're like, this is,
I'm at ease that they've,
they've been, you know,
really really wearing it out for them.
They don't even look
remotely like uniform.
We worn like when people have those
genes that have holes in the knees,
like it's obvious you didn't get those
holes working all the rest of the genes.
Perfect.
You just got to snap.
And I'm like what a weird
thing to become a style. Yeah.
Holes in your clothes is a style. Yeah,
I know. It's like seeing my jeans.
Like I don't, I'm the worst.
Like I don't wash my jeans.
Like I wear them for months
and like they literally get holes warning
them like because of, because of that,
like I'll get them in the knees sometimes
I d I walk on the back of them so like
the backs of them are like ripped,
you know what I mean?
And so I eventually get holes in them
because they're just old and shitty.
But it's so funny man.
It's like there's,
but there's like all these weird
styles right now that are just like,
what is happening? Like
those, um, affliction kind
of thing that was going on.
Like all those national guys were
wearing all the tribally looking shit,
all the skulls and, yeah.
But not like cool looking
shirts, like your shirt, like,
you know, that's a monkey either. Well,
that's a chimp with a mushroom in his
mouth. That's my own one, actually.
This primate.com.
This is all,
this shirt is based on Terence
Mckenna stoned ape theory. Ooh.
That a lower hominids ate mushrooms and
then they have this ideal of a nuclear
power and spirituality. Yeah. That's
what the shirt represents. Interesting.
Yeah. Kinda had this bizarre
a idea that's, it's an
interesting idea that his, uh,
his brother actually, his brother
Dennis Mckenna was still alive.
It was a fascinating guy himself actually
substantiated with science in a way
that's way better than I ever could.
If you want to listen to the first podcast
that I did with Dennis Mckenna and,
um,
he explains the actual effect that
silicide been has on the mind and why it
would, uh, why he would facilitate
the construction of language and that,
what would he would McKenna's theory was,
was that what happened to lower
primates is that somewhere around,
you know,
a million plus whatever years ago
when over a period of 2 million years,
the, uh, the size of the
human brain doubled and a,
that's like a very substantial
event in biology and they,
they really have no idea what caused
human beings to become so much more
intelligent than they were previous.
And his theory is that this
is at the same time that the,
um,
these tropical rainforest receded into
grasslands climate change forced these
tropical rain forest,
uh, to become grasslands.
And these monkeys climb down off
trees and started experimenting with,
uh, various food sources,
different things.
And one thing that they do is they start
flipping over cow patties and they find
bugs and worms and shit
to eat underneath them.
But there was also things growing on
the cow patties and those things were
psilocybin mushrooms,
pals in the jungle though this is like
they've grassland robbed and they've got
this, the seeded into grasslands over
the, the climate had changed. Right.
And rain forests had become grasslands
fascinate and so these monkeys ate
mushrooms. Exactly. And
then got smarter. Yeah.
And there's a bunch of
different reasons why,
besides the facilitation of
language, which is, uh, the,
the very specific reaction to psilocybin
has on the human mind and why Dennis
Mckenna described it very well.
I can't really repeat what he said.
I'm not smart enough.
I don't remember it either.
But what Mckenna also
said was the silicide in,
in low doses increases visual
acuity. It's a, it sharpens edges.
It makes you be able to see things better.
It makes you hornier so it would make
you see better and make you horny or,
so it would make you,
if you see better,
you'd probably be more
aware of things about you.
A better hunter if you're horny or
you'd fuck more. So the, the mush,
the mushroom meaning monkeys would have
a biological advantage over the non
mushroom meeting.
Montrez well you do know if a bunch of
monkeys are walking around and one of
them eats mushrooms and all the sudden
he's like no, there he'd be like, dude,
you guys got to try this shit.
It's like that at all the
things that make sense.
As far as looking at the effect
of a substance, the, the,
the effects of a
substance has on the body,
what would cause massive consumption of
the substance over a long period of time,
like 2 million years. What would cause
direct changes to the human body?
What would cause direct changes to the,
the, the actual function of the mind.
Psilocybins like number one,
it's so common. It's everywhere.
It grows out of a cow. Shit.
It's totally edible. You, you're,
you're hungry. You can eat it. You eat
it, you trip balls, you trip balls,
you think about things, you
develop language, you develop.
Have you done DMT? Oh yeah. I've never
done it and I'm dying to try it. Uh,
do you Sturgill Simpson is, no, he, you
should check out his record. Accurate.
It's new. And he has a song
called turtles all the way down,
which I heard about this DMT, right? Well,
he apparently he did a bunch of DMT
who's doing the record and was just like,
yeah, there's this, that song itself
talks about DMT and silicide but,
and stuff in it. But Eh, but
it's like really old school
country. It's got tattoos,
a DMT molecule. Really. I didn't know
this about you see, you know, see,
I've never experienced it and I'm sorry,
I'm so into all that too. Oh my God.
Let's get together and duty. Do teach.
Don't say it on the radio on the,
I promise I won't bring any crank.
Well,
DMT is one of the weirdest ones too,
because you can never be tested for it.
I mean, really they would
have to catch this one alone,
that kind of an experience with anything.
I've done mushrooms before and
I laughed a lot. I've done acid,
I didn't really see anything but,
but I'm very fascinated with like the
payout he kind of experience and all that.
And I've never, I've never, never had
it. Stirs was like you gotta try it dude.
He's like Dmt is mushrooms times
a million plus aliens. Wow. Yeah.
What's the deal with the aliens of DMT?
Well, there's something that happens
when you take DMT, where you, you,
you pass through visually or spiritually,
whether it's real or mentioned.
You pass through into some new space
and when you're in some new space, the,
what's weird about BMC all in your
head with your eyes shut or is this,
your eyes are shot,
but if you open your eyes,
you're gonna see some crazy shit too.
You'll see some crazy shit though.
That's also, you're better off
keeping your eyes closed though.
Cause then you'll get sort of
a full representation of what,
what's going on and what you're seeing.
When your eyes are open,
your eyes are taking
in the physical world,
like what you're seeing in front of you
and you're trying to combine the two of
them and it's very baffling, is
better. Just shut your silent darkness,
close your eyes,
take it,
and then just close your eyes and lay
back and you go on the craziest trip.
It's, it's impossible to it
for anything to be stronger.
It's impossible for anything to be a more
potent hallucination because it seems
more real than reality itself.
Like once you, once you do DMT,
the weirdest thing about it is
coming back like regular realities,
so dry and doll. It's like
that's more real. Like it's more,
you feel it. You also feel,
if this makes any sense,
you feel the experience in your,
in your essence and your in your essence
as a human and it sticks with you after.
Fuck man,
I've had trips that stuck with me for
five or six years where every day I would
think about that trip for five or
six years. Wow Man. This, that's,
I'm very fascinated by this
man. Well, it's the very,
the very components of your,
the brain itself, the very,
the very human neural transmitters,
that power thinking that,
that work inside your mind mean
these are endogenous chemicals.
These aren't like,
it's not like something that's alien to
the human body that you put in and it
has this crazy effect. No DMT is
actually produced by your body itself.
So when you add it,
when you take it and smoke it,
like your body already knows what it is.
It's one of the reasons why
it's so transient. Like,
um, it's when you take it,
you have this extreme high,
you have this wild ride of hallucinations
and experiences or whatever it is and
how long dimensions.
That's the crazy thing.
15 minutes Max you do at time,
which goes like a short thing.
But that's more if you do it
intravenously, if you do it intravenously,
can last like a half hour or more.
Really? Yeah. Like Rick Strassman,
who was the guy who, um, he was one
of the first guys to get federal.
Um, he got, um, federal permission,
the Da's permission to do these
research studies on dimethyltryptamine
intravenously and patients.
He did it out of the University of New
Mexico and they did a, several of these.
And then they did it.
He wrote a book on it called DMT,
the spirit molecule where these
people at these incredible,
incredible experiences while on this
intravenous diamond field tryptamine and a
repeatable experiences, they
would go to these and very, very,
very much mirrored the alien abduction
experiences that people would talk about,
like being taken the board
alien spacecrafts and being
brought to alien places
and alien lands, like very,
very similar reb tiles. Yeah.
So he started connecting uh,
dimethyltryptamine and endogenous dumps
of dimethyltryptamine to alien abduction
experiences. And that's what
he thinks that's all about.
He thinks all of these
people that have these,
like I woke up the middle of the night
and I was on a space ship. You just,
your brain just dumped a bunch of DMT
in and somehow or another you got caught
in the middle of this world
of being awake and dreaming.
So your body when you're dreaming is
essentially producing something that's
causing you to hallucinate. The
speculation is that that's DMT as well.
They haven't totally proven that yet,
but they're pretty sure they've already
proven that DMT is produced by the
pineal gland. That's, that was a
long time for, that was speculation,
but they proved that that in live rats
that live rats actually produce DMT in
that glance. That's really,
yeah, it's all pretty trippy,
trippy, trippy shit. That's,
that is very fascinating. I mean,
like I said, I honestly haven't,
uh, I haven't, I haven't, I've
just never, I've guided to do it.
I've just never done it. I, I'm just
into that man. I'm into that experience.
I'm into that like go into
the next level US wheat.
So yeah, this is one of the, it's
one of the weirdest ones because a,
it's in so many different plants.
It's not like a,
you have to go and get a
pomegranate from Brazil.
And that's the only way you
get this. What's the walkout?
Iowaska. Iowaska. Yeah.
IOWASCA is essentially the way they
get out all that shit. Like, yeah,
like the movie.
Yeah.
Well what Iowasca is an orally
active form of DMT because DMT,
when you smoke it, it goes directly
into your breads, your blood supply.
But DMT is in so many different plants
that if you got it from eating it,
you would be tripping your balls.
That every time you have a salad
because grass has it in it.
A lot of different thousands of different
plants evidence. So because of that,
your,
your body produces chemicals that mitigate
that and one of them is called Mano
Amy and Oxidase and Mano Aiming
Oxidase is produced in your gut.
So when the Amazon,
uh,
schamens figure out how to give people
DMT with a sleek and modern like in
today, and you know, United
States and modern chemical world,
there's scientists that have figured
out how to synthesize pure DMT.
So they'd take it from plants or you know,
from various chemicals.
And they synthesize pure DMT. You smoke,
it goes right into your bloodstream.
It's pure DMT.
But you can't do that in the Amazon.
So what they figured out how to do is
make an orally active version of it.
So what it is is they combined the leaves
of one plant with the roots of another
and one of them being harming,
which is a natural Mao inhibitor.
So it's a mano Amy and oxidase
inhibitor that they mix in.
So it's a like a DMT trip,
but it's not quite as intense.
It's s it's a slow release,
longer version that's very hallucinogenic,
very spiritual, a lot of ways.
But I've only done the big one.
The big one is the DMT.
The smoking DMT is you get shot
through a cannon to the center,
the fucking universe.
The way I describe it as
you're communicating with
complex geometric patterns
that are made out of love and
understanding. Man, that's so funny.
Cause I've heard that. I've heard the
geometrics thing and, and you know I'm a,
I'm a big study of like safe, sacred
geometry and all these kinds of things.
I'm very fascinated by this.
I'm very fascinated. Oh,
I'm so fascinated by geometry,
sacred geometry and fractals and
all those different, when you,
when you look at that,
just the nature of the universe itself,
it's just the nature of cellular life,
subatomic particles.
Adam's becoming individuals,
individuals being a part of a group
of individuals that live in a planet,
the planet being a part of the galaxy,
the galaxy being a part of the universe
on and on and on. I don't know.
I'm not like,
like it seems like there's a,
there's a fractal geometric
nature to life itself.
The FIBONACCI sequence that
describes like, you know,
like the way sunflower seeds or
develop the way a nautilus shell looks,
the way so many different plants grow.
There's all this weird sort of really
don't mathematical nature to the world
itself and like the tree
of life 33 you know,
it's just, there's so many things like
that. I'm so fascinated with that.
I feel like when you,
when you unlock those kinds of things
in your mind and your end of that stuff,
like there's a great book called
gateway to the Gods that I ran.
I don't know how I ran across this
book. It's, it's about this guy.
It's about a lot of sacred geometry. It
talks about, uh, it really deals with the,
the in the Bible, like the watchers and
the Nephilim and the concept of that.
Angels w that we're actually like
interdimensional travel and it deal,
it touches a little bit on
the DMT ish kind of thing.
And it touches on some of that
kind of travel, mine travel.
But I'm very fascinated by
it, man. I just, I, you know,
I think if your mind's open to it
and you do do something that I DMT,
it probably, it probably
enhances your, if you're like,
you being so knowledgeable
on so much of this,
probably has it enhanced your trip
when you do it because you're, I mean,
I don't know how it probably,
I mean, are you like,
are you able to focus on what you're
looking at or wherever you're super hard,
so hard.
It's so crazy and it changes every second.
Every second you look at it,
it becomes something even more impossible.
That's the weirdest thing about it.
It's just you can't believe you're
seeing something that's like this.
Like how is this possible or there aren't
there like enter beings that more than
one person that I've seen
and they're all the same.
They all described them as the same.
See, it's hard to do that. I've seen,
see my trips have been different
every time I've done it.
That's one of the weirdest things about
it is like someone saying that they've
seen the same things that I've seen. I'm
not even sure I can tell you what I saw.
Like I can tell you what I
can remember about what I saw,
but one of the weirdest aspects
of it is that it's impossible.
Like when you're seeing it,
like this isn't real.
This can't be possible that I can
actually see this. And then like one,
one of the things that one of my trips,
one of the most profound ones, um,
there was like these like
almost like children that
were in this, this dimension,
children that were like infinitely
more intelligent than me,
but behave like children and communicated
like children. And they would say,
I love you.
600 million,
500,000 times like something like a kid
would say like, I love you infinity,
I love you. 50 million south
700,015 like you know, like shit.
They would say that. And then they would
go look at this. And they kept saying,
look at this. And every time
they would say, look at this,
they would show you something
that was so impossibly beautiful.
Like tears were like flowing down my
face because I was conscious. I was,
I had my eyes closed and I was
seeing this and I was conscious,
but I was crying because it
was so beautiful. And then
they would say it again.
I love you. 600 million,
500,000 times, look at this.
And then they would show you
something even more insane,
like a million times more insane.
What? She didn't make any sense.
It was just,
you can't describe it.
It just the fractal nature of
the universe embodied in imagery,
which also had meaning and love connected
to it. So when you were seeing it,
you weren't just seeing something
beautiful but you were feeling it.
And it was like almost like it
was running through your soul,
like it was cleansing you as you saw it.
Like everything that I saw
made me every time I saw it,
every new thing made me love people more.
May me Love Life,
may be more appreciative,
made me want to hug more.
And then I thought that was over it and
it would it go look at this and then
you'd get hit with a new wave and it
was just overwhelming. I'm just crying.
I couldn't, couldn't hold it in. It
was just so unbelievably intense.
It had a negative experience.
No, not on DMT now.
I've had never had negative
experiences in that. Um,
DMT is sort of exposed that I was maybe
a little out of control of my life,
like maybe too stressed out or maybe uh,
you know,
taking too much time, devoted too much
time to work and bullshit related things.
It really didn't matter in the long,
like,
like the negative aspect was it like
after it was over, it's like, hey,
I need to just fucking chill out.
Like I need to just smelled the daisies.
I need to just enjoy this
experience, you know? And this, wow.
Not 15 minutes. Yeah, but wasn't,
I've never had a negative experience in
that. Like while it was in, it was like,
this is negative, but I've seen it.
I've seen people freak out. You have,
have you been with
someone that freaked out?
My friend Eddie freaked the fuck
out the first time he did it,
but I think it was because he was trying
to control it. You can't control it.
You can't,
you can't like saying,
I'm going to pull myself out of this and
sober up. Good luck. You have to give in.
You have to be willing to give in.
But I mean, I'm, that's the thing
is man, it's like I'm, I'm that,
I think you and I are a lot alike in that
way. That it's like, like I, you know,
I want something more out of this
experience. Like I love, I love life.
Like I'm a positive guy. I've got two kids
who I love. I love the time with them,
you know, everything like
that. And that's why it's like,
I'm so fascinated with like the,
hey,
I don't believe all the bullshit on
the media and I don't believe all the
fucking, you know, all the shit that
we've been talking about this whole show.
Like that's why I'm into the bitcoin
thing, which we didn't even gotten into.
And I'm, I'm mind those things. I'm into
the technology of it. Am I am. Yeah, I do.
I mean, I'm just into the
technology of it. I'm into the,
to the programming side of it, in the,
in the cryptology and all that. But,
uh,
but like I,
I am into understanding the full
aspect of life while I'm here and,
and it's like I'm fascinated by religions
and I, my mom, I was raised Christian,
my mom's that way. Like I, I, you
know, it's hard for me to say that I'm,
that I'm like, uh, I'm not a church
going Kinda guy, but, but it's like,
I believe when you're here,
you're supposed to be you.
If you could leave being good, you
know, and I haven't been a good guy,
that's the thing.
But I'm into the knowledge I'm into like
discovering where things come from and
you know,
studying like the Egyptians and studying
the fucking artwork that they're always,
you know, I'm just into it. So
that's why like semantic DMT, like,
like if I could travel to other dimensions
and party with reptiles I was doing
right now.
You can.
Yeah. Well you can with DMT.
I don't know about reptiles,
I've never seen a reptile while on it,
but I've seen things that are somehow
or another consciousness or appear to be
conscious or are representations of your
own consciousness and some sort of a
much have much, a much
greater form. But you know,
who else was in a church going person.
Jesus.
See Jesus didn't have a fucking church.
Churches are human creations and humans.
The problem with any sort
of power structure, um,
any top down power structure is that
people want to contain that once,
once they have power,
they want to retain that power.
They want to contain the
people that contained the
ideologies of the people that
are involved in that group. And then
you know, to have a, an open minded,
completely open situation where you have
a group but there's no structure to it
and everyone's just loving and
able to do whatever they want.
There's no one person that's the leader.
No, that's not what we do. Human beings.
Everything sort of falls into that
weird Alpha male monkey category where
there's one person that talks
and everyone else listens.
And that's what you find in churches.
That's what you find at political rallies.
That's what you find when the
president gives a speech on television,
there's the one and then there's the
listeners and is, it's not a dialogue,
it's one person talks and there's a, you
know, everyone comes in and sits down,
open up to page three 24 we're going to
read from the Gospel. And then it was,
but this was one person that's doing this.
It's one person that's guiding this whole
thing and that's sort of contrary to
the very like nature of like a
cooperative and open group of humans.
A a community.
And that's also the best way to control
people to ensure that this one person
disseminates the rules.
It's one person gets to talk and this one
person keeps everybody in a control of
the preachers here. Everyone all rise.
The honorable judge is here, you know,
all the, I mean, court court itself,
you have to stand up when this
asshole who's wearing robes,
like why you wearing
robes, man, you can't,
you can't give the law out
with a tee shirt and jeans on.
You have to wear like
special fancy clothes.
And in order to to understand the law,
the way the powdered wigs better way
crazy curly white wigs, you know,
people are mad,
they're mad,
and they're also running on momentum of
an ignorant past running on the momentum
essentially of people that we used
to write shit down on animal skins.
That same momentum is still
propelling society. So, yeah.
Yeah. And it's, yeah, you're
right. You're right. It's, I mean,
we could get into that forever because
I've, you know, just conceptually,
the way that the control
is, is, is, you know,
doled out, it's pretty pretty. I mean,
it's pretty easy. It's pretty math,
mathematical one plus one equals two.
Like you just like I was saying,
you keep the, keep, keep everybody pour,
keep everybody uneducated
and then convinced them that
if they don't do what we
want them to do,
they're going to burn in hell.
Yeah. Even better than poor. Now they have
a new thing. It's called being in debt.
Yeah.
Everyone's in debt.
It's way better than poor because poor
you could just deal with being poor,
but debt you never going to have, you
can't stop working. You owe money.
You're not even, yeah, that's
true. That's exactly it, man. Man.
It's like, you know, separate
the family. Have you, uh,
you're getting the bright eyes that
man pride eyes know Conor Oberst.
Have you heard of him? No.
You know that those guys,
they have a great record called the
people's key, but the, uh, the opening,
the opening La, the opening thing is this
guy, I don't even know who it is. He's,
he's talking about exactly what
we're talking about it and how they,
how they control the masses and stuff.
Man,
it's a great speech in the beginning
of this thing. But you know,
it's like keeping like keeping the mom
and dad separate because they both have
to work.
Like,
can you make it so hard for a normal
like lower income family to even be
together so that you can disseminate
information to each one of them? Exactly.
Like you want it and they don't have
a lot of time together. You know,
that's a big part of it and it's, it's
so insane. It's just, it just is insane.
It just like the wages and the way they
control that and the people who make the
money. It's like, like the banking thing.
This is why the bitcoin thing is so
brilliant. I mean, you know, I mean,
you talked to the, to uh, Andrea's
who's like, he's like the man,
but um,
Andreas Antonopoulos who we were talking
about this before the podcast left that
bitcoin foundation. Yeah. I don't,
we need to have him on again.
Find out what that was all,
what that is.
See that the foundation has never been
needed. This is what's weird about it,
because they've, they're, you know,
the bitcoin itself is the protocol.
So it's like,
that's what's brilliant.
The foundation was created as something
that was supposed to kind of drive the
development of it, but it's become,
it's become a corporation essentially.
You know, it's, it's got a, had
a lot of negative, uh, but the,
the people who were in charge of
it now, or even more, more so,
people are like,
they're kind of crooks and shady and,
but there's really no need for it.
There's no need. There's not like,
there's a bit coin company that
people work for. You know, the thing,
it's like more like a virus that was set
into the world and then just like the
Internet was, you know,
there's not like the,
they're an internet company that there's
the president of the Internet who can
decide like that today.
But you know what I mean?
That's a beautiful thing about the
internet, isn't it? It is amazing,
but that's why they're trying to do this,
this,
this net neutrality thing is such a
big issue because they're trying to,
they're trying to can't, like right
now time Warner cable can already,
like if they don't like
the Joe Rogan show,
they can slow down when
people go to your site,
they can slow it down on purpose, but,
but that's, that's shitty enough already.
But like with the net neutrality
thing they're trying to get rid of,
then then time Warner can say, hey, um,
Google, we're, Shit's going to be
real slow unless you pay us money.
And so then they're going to start
extorting money out of, do you know,
to go back into their own
pocket to actually do,
to alter what sites and even
blocking sites and that and when,
when Time Warner owns all the internet,
I mean there's a giant portion
of the Internet. I mean,
I don't know what the actual numbers are,
but it's over 50% of the,
of the service provider and the service
provider can then charge companies and
decide what people can see.
Then that's like the Internet is the,
the purpose of it is, is you're getting
fucked big time. You know what I mean?
They're trying to corporatize it.
They're trying to control it the same
way they've controlled the airwaves.
Like CBS chipped and they cut,
they cut the internet, you know,
and shit like that. That's what we're
like three steps away from happening.
And that's, that's the Internet.
The Internet is decentralized.
There is no one in charge of it.
And they know that, you know,
and the reality is is like if they,
if you know,
if time Warner becomes that big of a deal,
somebody will come out there and run
their own wires and fucking set up their
own fucking statewide wifi and
it'll be fine, you know? But it, it,
it's just tough man.
But you know that like,
did you ever get into discussion about
bitcoin? About how you can use the in a,
in a,
if I send you money you can attach a
message to it or you could actually like
attach a deed or I could write a song
and it would be in the blockchain
copyrighted, but you can actually
embed a message in the transaction.
And that the first,
the first transaction ever done
by the guy who made it had the,
the like Washington, like the Washington
Post or like Wall Street Journal.
The headline was like the government
approves second bailout for banks.
Like that was encoded in the first
transit transmission cause it was like
they're saying like enough,
like this shit is so fucked.
The banking, the Federal Reserve,
the government, everything.
Like we've got a solution that way
you don't need a banks anymore.
You know what I mean? You don't, I mean
it would change. It changes the escrow.
It changes everything like it.
Yeah.
You don't need banks if
you have digital currency.
I mean that's the most party is, is
the mining community. So like it's,
there's no need, there's no way to rig
it, you know? Yeah. I think that if,
if it can continue and
it can grow and evolve,
I think it can be definitely,
well definitely I think it will as well.
I think there's definitely powers that
are trying to solve or Horace Mann of
course, because can you imagine?
But, but here's the reality, man.
Banks are record stores and our big
record companies and Bitcoin is Napster.
That's it. That's what it is. When
you, what would the tower records, man,
I used to fucking go there
at all the fucking time.
It's not there anymore and the,
and all of these fucking city national
banks on every corner that's going to
happen. Mark my words, they
will not be there anymore.
That would be the same fate as tower
because people will figure out how to send
their money around, you know? Yeah.
And once you get used to
buying things with your phone,
which is probably the future, and I do
it all, I bought a fucking computer.
Like I'm such a nerd that I buy old.
I bought an old four 86 PC with like a
disk drive in it because I just wanted to
play my old games that I liked. I bought
one on my phone on the way in here. Wow.
I need on Ebay though.
I bet.
But like that's paypal and you're like
paying all kinds of money for that.
But like if you know,
I can go on right now.
I could go to anywhere and PR.
I mean right now,
like with Dell,
like start accepting bitcoin.
Like I bought my manager a computer like
with some bitcoin than I had and it was
fucking cheap and it was like
I sent Alex upset. Now Dell,
it started accepting it just
recently. Wow. You know,
overstock.com was the first one and now,
now Wiki Wikipedia takes it for donations
and it's slowly becoming adopted.
And I think it's, you know,
back in [inaudible] 94 93
when the Internet was out,
people were like,
no one's ever going to do this.
www.somethingorother.com they're going
to have to come up with some easier way
to do it. No one's going to ever, this
will never become normal. And you know,
it's like,
here we are 20 years later and it's
like there's no way that anyone could
function. Any of our devices
could function without the
Internet being involved.
Everyone would prefer to go to
a website then call the number.
It's like people download their music,
they don't buy it. Really. I mean they do.
But you know, I mean it's
like, so I think that the,
all the talk around bitcoin right now is
the same kind of talk that we're having
around the internet then.
But I don't think it will be,
there's like messaging programs, uh, where
you can send money in the, in the text,
like a on, on an iPhone.
So like if I was like,
hey can you go pick up this and you know,
here's 40 bucks worth of it or whatever,
or you know, whatever it costs,
I can just send it to you
instantly and not being,
so you could just like say if I'm,
say if we were living together and you
wanted me to go pick up a steak, yeah.
Hey Man, your store. And go get some
food and here's the money. Yeah,
just like that. I mean there'd be
no, there's like a couple cents,
maybe a charge for the transaction fee,
but there's,
I mean such an if there is one, it's such
a small amount and that money goes to,
it's like a four o one k plan for
the mining system cause it's going to
eventually hit the mark
where it can't make anymore,
can't generate any more bitcoin.
And then after that there'll be living
off the transaction fees. But um,
it's kind of interesting to
see like the mining thing, man,
it's like some people
think of and they're like,
oh it's like people who want to just
like make free money, which is not,
is not the way it works.
It's like what it actually is is,
and this is the nerd part of me. Like I
also run a full node, a bitcoin at home,
which,
which means like I'm part of the
network of transactions that happen.
It's kind of complicated, but at
the same time like the, the, the,
the technology behind the whole
transaction confirming process,
which is the Aka the mining is what
is so fascinating to me. And I like,
I mean I'll go on the Internet and uh,
an IRC and hang out and talk to the
developers and shit cause I'm just,
I think that someone has to in is going
to use this technology in the way that
bitcoin is and make finally
a decentralized entertainment
distribution platform
because eventually like iTunes takes
30% like they've been good to me in
different moments.
But here's the reality.
You make something that costs nothing
to duplicate because digital and they're
taking 30% of it plus a
company like tune core,
like jabs you in Rob's you to get eat to
even get your shit on iTunes if you're
just a new band. You know, he was like
I, how do I get measured on iTunes?
Somebody going to collect some money
for them to just email your song over to
iTunes in the correct format and then
iTunes takes 30% like if you got rid of
that and you've got it where I was like
I say I gave you a David Bowie song.
If there was a way to just have a
proof of ownership and have like,
like a transaction fee like
there is in bitcoin where I've,
I just gave you an album that would like
somehow pay David belly when you get
it. You know they're not there doesn't
need to be the, the, the Itunes,
the store you go to to get it.
It's like really if I'm
sending you a song via email,
there should be a way to like build it,
build a decentralized
distribution platform like that.
It's crazy that Amazon takes that
much or if it takes that much,
yeah. How can they do that? I'll
tell you why, because there was,
everyone said the Internet is never going
to be a way that people buy music and
iTunes said,
we're here and we're putting our flag
down and you guys are going to be sorry.
And that's what happened.
They jumped in when nobody cared.
There were meetings that were,
they said, we don't care.
Don't talk to us about
MP3. He's like, Sony said,
don't talk to us about mp3s
until it's 30% of the market.
And by the time it was 30% of the market,
iTunes was fucking,
Wa had iPods and it was weighed 30% seems
like a lot of money because it's not
even like they're storing it on their
website and then you download it from
their servers. Like they need all the
bandwidth. And so you're, you know,
because your album is, you know,
x amount of gigs that, I mean,
that's not what's going on.
They're not doing it. Well. I mean,
you have to have a host. They do store
it. I mean, well, they don't do it with,
for podcasts,
for podcasts.
Podcast gets downloaded from
a host like a torrent. Yeah,
I have a of a company called the
company's called Libsyn and Libsyn's.
Tunecore is,
so that's what tune core.
That's the way tune core or like
reverb nation and all those things.
Work is you can get yourself,
I mean that's essentially yet,
but I believe that it goes
into the back end and iTunes.
I think a lot of those companies,
like,
like if I don't pay tune core,
after five years they're going to,
in my music will go off iTunes.
So like they have the control over that.
But I've also seen labels
go directly to iTunes,
not be those things and go use the
backend there. I mean, I, I dunno,
I thought they did store the
shit, but you know, I mean,
I should probably know that and I don't
know that, but the reality is 30%,
I don't care what you call it. [inaudible]
it's a duplicate of a digital file.
Yeah. It cost nothing to replicate.
That is, it is kinda crazy.
Yeah. That's why so many artists held
out for so long on it, but then they had,
they just buckled and went.
But I know that there's dirty deals and
went down in the back room where like,
like certain people got better cuts off
that. Like the Beatles, I bet you money,
they're not taking 30% of the vehicles,
but they would never admit to that.
But dude, everything's a dirty
deal. Listen to this shit.
Bilborough billboard charts. You
think about it, you're like, oh,
this album number one on billboard.
There are certain artists that I've
heard about where they've had that like
sponsorships with like say
Coors light and the red,
they're weak,
the record comes out.
Coors light buys 300,000 copies of
the record so that it goes number one.
I mean it's all rigged financially.
It's all rigged by money,
so it's like none of it's real. The
Grammy's aren't real, you know, it just,
it's to me it's all sister the Gig.
The Grammy's aren't real. Yeah,
none of that's real. Do you think any of
that's real? Do you know what way Paul?
There are people that charge that are
services that are people that were at one
point worked for the Grammy Organization
and they have the email addresses of
all the people that they know that vote.
So there are people that will charge you
like five grand to bombard these people
with emails all year so that by the time
they see the voting sheet they're like,
oh that fucking person, I'll
vote for that. Like there's,
there's things like that,
but besides that dude,
it's like the Grammy's are a self
contained operation of like the old media.
Like it's, it's like Clive Davis and all
those people and they're all like, like,
like a random band from
nowhere who nobody's ever
heard of is never going to win
a grammy and less they've got money
behind them. Do you know what I mean?
So like the whole show,
like what I mean like the billboards
are fake and all that shit.
All that Shit's not real.
It's not like,
it's not like the 50s were like muddy
waters puts out something and it goes
straight to the top of the charts and
all of a sudden like race music becomes
like this big thing.
It's not that way anymore.
It's all corporate controlled by
the 1% it's controlled by the,
by coms of the world who are putting
it on the television, who are,
who are deciding who's going to win.
Like arcade fire wins a fucking grammy
because they think that that like,
you know, everyone feels like
it's been two pop away in it,
so let's give one to arcade
fire this year. And it's like,
as much as I want to
believe that there are,
like the fans are in any way
involved in these kinds of processes.
They're totally not, it's just
all the marketing. There's,
there's fucking five people calling all
the radio station programming for the
year. There's, you know,
people buying their way to the top of the
buying grammys and buying their way to
the top of the billboard.
It's like if everybody's,
if rich people are the only people that
have the ability to buy their way in top,
like why would, why would some,
why would muddy waters even care?
Do you know what I mean? But it's just
the system has changed so much like,
but that isn't that just the system as
far as like the awards and award shows
and Samsung and all those kinds of things
that the accolades that that go along
with being a musician, like the, you know,
going out and playing a show
and having a grassroots thing.
Like that's one thing that's real,
but like all the accolades that the
billboards and the awards and all that,
all that stuff is just for show
and it's highly manipulated so,
well it makes sense. I mean
it totally makes sense. Move.
Why wouldn't they manipulate
it if they could manipulate it?
If it led to financial gain? Of course,
if they're scratching each other's backs,
like,
you know,
kind of Davis is going to make a record
and he's going to give it to the, to the,
when they go to their Bohemian Grove
little party that they do or whatever,
they're going to fucking,
he's going to say, Hey, I'm
going to send you the new, uh,
you know,
Kanye record or whatever,
miss any of the new Alicia Keyes record
and it's radio stations are going to
fucking, you know, they're gonna get,
you know, they're not getting Pale love,
but they're fucking getting free trips
to Disneyland for their whole family and
like five of the people you know,
don't fucking play like this record
that sound says invested in. So
to me it's all a kind of a joke.
And that's probably why I'm not,
why I'm not a rich man is
because I fucking, I mount,
I spout off about this shit all the time
on my radio show too. And I'm like, like,
fucking, where's your, what's
your radio show on Sirius?
On Sirius Xm on a outlaw
country? A channel 60. I'm on.
Is that the xxx channels? I would, it
is, oh, let's call it electric Rodeo.
The triple x thing was something
where I was trying to actually, uh,
it's kind of defunct in a way now. I
mean, I still play all those bands,
but there's this whole like underground
country underground kind of roots blues
thing that was happening and it was
getting boxed into this Americana Shit.
It was getting real, like Americana
and contrary and everything.
There was this real big gap in the
middle and there was all these bands that
were falling in the gap.
So I was like,
I started a website with that and it was
kind of just a play on triple a radio.
And I was like, I don't know. I
got more heat over it. I mean,
it helped a lot of artists
and I know it did because,
because I'm friends with
them and it definitely, I, I,
I've now started producing a lot of
other people and started working in the
studio with them more as
opposed to promoting them,
which has been really good.
But,
um,
it was just a way of trying to promote
all these really great bands that really
just weren't getting any chance.
But I still play.
All those bands were ready to show,
but it's called electric Rodeo.
I've been doing like nine years now,
which is kind of insane.
But I don't do it like this. I
do it on the fly. I was like,
looking at this then I'm like,
man,
I think I've been doing my show
for nine years. I was like that.
I would actually have
something to show for it.
You guys are smarter than I am as a,
you know,
I do mine on the fly on my laptop,
like wherever I'm at.
Sometimes I've done it on the
airplane when I'm flying, you know,
just when I got to get it in by the end
of the week. So. Well this thing is just,
I mean, we need other people here.
This is like a location to do it from,
but fucking what a great location when
the fucking wolf and Predator and fucking
lava lamps and fucking antlers
at this place is insane.
Well, we've turned it into this. We
first moved in here. It was the opposite.
It was like a board room or something.
It was just a regular or even the
covers over the fluorescent lights.
I've never seen that shit before.
Oh, their space. Yeah. Yeah man.
I mean it's the vibe in this room.
It's like I would never, if I were you,
I would just stay in
this room all the time.
Just narrowing the pool table
outside of that. It's a good spot.
Great Spot, man. Yeah, I, uh,
I think it's important to have a space
where you feel comfortable. You know,
you feel like you could just chill out.
It doesn't feel corporate.
I think it enhances the conversations and
a lot of ways for sure, man. You know,
and also it just,
it's a creepy secret spot.
It feels like a creepy spot. It's
great man. It's great. I love it.
So you think that you doing your radio
show and being honest about all these
things that held you back?
Yeah, I dunno. I mean,
I do know like one time I said that
thing about, about the billboard and I,
I had evidence of this and I'm not gonna
say what artist it was cause I'm not in
the business to doing that.
But there was this big name artists,
we had this new record
coming out in his sponsor.
Companies bought 300,000
copies of it first week.
So they would make sure
that it went number one.
And I said that on the radio and, and my
boss says any, they've teased, told me,
I've gotten a lot of calls that they'd
call him and they say he's saying this
shit and it's irresponsible because it's
not true. And I'm like, yes it is true.
I know it's true.
I've seen the paper that said it was true,
but I mean I think they'd get
pissed that I said, but I,
a lot of people don't like me.
They blackballed me a long time ago
anyway because I was just always,
I've always been that way,
man.
I'm at to my disadvantage a lot of ways.
But like if someone's a phony, I hate
that more than anything in the world, man.
And you know,
there've been times in my life when I was
a phony growing up they girls and with
things like, you know, we
tried to try to get into that.
But as you get older and as
I've gotten older, it's just,
there's so much insincerity in,
especially in the music business
that I have such a disdain for it.
It's just like,
like the way that the writers were.
Cause I mean what's happened to country
music is, is directly responsible.
I mean directly related
to like the exact same,
you know what we're talking
about corporate America,
it's like the same kind of shit.
It's just,
it's just gotten to where
these corporations are in
so much power and they have
so much money that it's really hard for
like the little man to beat it, you know?
And so I just get really,
I see people who pretend to be
for the little man and, or they,
but yet they're playing this
fucking ballgame over here.
And it like to talking out of both sides
of her mouth. And it just kills me,
you know what I mean? So I'm the halt.
Say It, I'll happily say it all day long,
you know, but uh, but yeah,
like I definitely think that it,
there, there are groups I just found
out about a group in Nashville,
but there are groups,
much like the Bilderberg group where they
are in music and in movies and things.
I mean, I know that everybody knows they
kind of had that kind of thing, but,
but there are actual groups where they,
where they orchestrate kind
of who they're going to,
who they're going to lend their
support too. I mean, they,
they never played me on the radio thought
like that are going to have a meeting
and they'll say, we're not wearing
it. I purposely keep shooter out.
It's not like that. Not that
paranoid, but, uh, but I, I'm,
I do know that they have meetings about,
uh,
where the studio heads and the local
community and the congress and city
planners and developers and certain
record labels, mostly independent.
The independence of kind of choke, hold
it out. The corporate ones a little bit.
They've in a weird way,
especially in in Nashville,
but in the songwriters and the radio
people and they have these retreats that
they go on together and it's like,
Duh.
Like of course they're all
scratching each other's backs.
And then of course like the little guy,
they have to pay like 15 grand to join
this group to go on these retreats,
you know, and keep paying.
And it's like, like, uh,
it's fascinating to me.
You know, like when people,
like that's the dumbest thing I've
ever heard. That doesn't happen.
It's like if you think that
doesn't happen, then you are dumb.
Because of course these people want,
they want the keep their job,
they want to stay in there, they want
to keep making the money they're making.
So they'll do anything it takes to keep
that position. Yeah. It's unfortunate,
right? The people that are
in that sort of a position,
they're making a shitload of
money don't realize like, man,
this is kind of bad for the
art form itself to do this.
Like the very art form that we
need. Sellen. Yeah, they wouldn't.
It's the short term victory that
they want and it's like the longterm,
like people like us, you know, like I'm
a movie Fan, like I'm a blade runners,
my favorite movie of all time, but I raise
the, Oh man, I watched it the other day.
Watch. How many times have you
watched it? I mean hundreds at least.
I mean I just bought all these prints,
these posters.
Is that all fulfill Philip k
Dick Novel? Yes. Yeah, I do.
Androids dream of electric
sheep is if the book,
what a great fucking moving man,
great movie and stands up stands
up at the end of the movie.
The original version was Harrison Ford.
Ford supposed to find out that he's
a robot to, well that's the kind of,
that's kind of the point of the
divide. It's like the, the kind of,
the point of the movie a little bit is,
is that, I mean it's implied in that,
especially when at the very end of the
movie, Edward James Almost as character,
like he's been leaving these
origami all over the place,
but he leaves the Unicorn.
But see in the original one,
I just watched the theatrical one for
the first time. I had never seen it.
The one where, um, Harrison Ford
narrates the film. Oh that's the,
the original director's cut. No, the
director's cut is when he does not.
They took his voice off and then they
took the last scene out of the movie where
they drive away. That's the only
one you've seen the one till now.
Which one's the director's cut. Yeah.
Cause that's the only one you can buy.
They would, they would, the minute it was
available on DVD, I don't know about VHS,
but like the minute the DVDs came out,
the director's cut saturated the market.
So like I on, um, Voodoo, I bought it.
I was like trying to figure out a way
when I was traveling on the road and a car
and to venue to venue,
I was trying to figure out a way to,
I don't have enough space on my fucking
iPhone cause the fucking iCloud and the
pictures and all this
shit and it's always full.
And I don't want to throw it against
the fucking wall, you know. But I, uh,
the Voodoo app lets me watch
movies. So I was like, oh,
I'm going to watch blade runner.
And then I pulled it up and it was that,
that version,
which I had never seen there.
Then there was a final cut that was
made about seven or eight years ago.
They came out and that one has
the deleted Unicorn scene in it.
And what, what, what that
is, is that I guess that,
that uh, Harrison Ford's
character has some kind of a,
like there's a unicorn thing
in his past and his memory,
he has a memory of a Unicorn and
there's this scene where in the movie,
in the final cut where he shoots that
chick that had the snake around her neck
when he shoots her,
there's this shot of this Unicorn because
it reminded him of this thing and it
is kind of like connecting the dots that
he has this weird memory of a unicorn
in the woods.
And at the very end of the film,
Edward James Almost makes a unicorn.
He walks out the front door of his house
and there's a unicorn out of origami
sitting in there. And that's like Edward
James almost saying, hey, you know, we,
you're actually one too.
So that was kind of the implied,
but the whole thing is like, you know,
if she's one, if he's wanting, you know,
anyone could be one. And that
was the kind of, you know,
I robot or we all robots. Like, you know,
that's kind of the, the ultimate story,
but it never confirms that.
But in the, in the book,
they run away together and she ends up
dying and it's like a love story. And,
and he, he, it, it ends up not mattering
if he has one or not. Because you know,
well, in the real world
that we live in right now,
that seems like much more likely and
possibility than it ever did when blade
runner came out. Yeah,
man. Like back then,
like the idea of a robot that
looks exactly like a person,
like, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Might as well be traveling to the moon.
Might as well be fucking, you know,
Battlestar Galactica or something
like Xenu. Yeah. But now you,
when you see the artificial bodies
that they're able to create now,
like these robot faces that move and
articulate just like a human face,
like really similar though.
Some of those Japanese ones,
they're so similar and you just imagine
what's a hundred years from now I'm
going to be like, and like, it's uh,
the company that Hologram the company
that made the Tupac Hologram and then they
reached
out to me and I met the guy yesterday.
It's got Gary and that he, I'm, I'm,
I may be going there,
I have to go get my kids from here and I
made to be taking them to this guy. He,
cause he's contacted me about
wanting to do like a Whalen holiday.
Like I think that they're trying to talk
about getting a bunch of the guys and
making a Hologram of like cash and La,
who knows.
But like he wants to give
me the demonstration, but
I was talking to him about,
and he said, man, you know the shit on TV.
Like when it's not lit a certain way.
Like he didn't like the lighting
on the Michael Jackson one.
He said it wasn't right,
but he said that when they
do it correctly that that,
see,
it's like with Michael Jackson,
they have a body double and then they
had this face technology that like that
does the face on top of someone
else's face. So it, it looks like,
right. But like you don't really have
to do that. Like it's not CGI people.
So they have the ability right now they
have the ability to do the help me,
Obi wan like I can,
they can,
they have one thing that's got these
three d cameras and I can be in that room.
He was telling me a story about an
Indian guy in India who's running for
president or whatever their fucking thing
is over there and that, that he, he,
he told people he was really rich and
he had like 3% of the vote and he set up
these,
the hologram things and like every town
and he paid for them to all be over
there and said like, hey,
come see me. I'm going to,
I'm going to talk your town and he and
he likes stood at home in this thing and
he appeared in like 50 towns and they
didn't even know it was a hologram.
He thought he was really there and he
never told them so they thought he really
came to their fucking shit
town and there's nothing to do.
Like you know they're little village
and it was like this guy and like he's a
right now like I could go over there and
they can have like a hologram thing set
up in Japan and I could like literally
walk in front of the cameras and I'd be
in Japan and I'd be talking
to motherfuckers and
totally like help me Obi wan
and say we all we want or like the fucking
sit lord guy appearing like talking
about it.
But it doesn't even look like that.
He said when it's in a normal room it
looks like you can't tell the difference
from a Hologram.
I will report to you on this after
I go to it if after I go see this
demonstration.
Yeah.
Do you remember when they had that on
television for CNN when they were covering
the news and Wolf Blitzer would like
stand the CNN hologram. The holodeck?
No. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. They uh,
they experimented with it during
elections. You got a video of a Jamie,
he's got a good guy. Let's see
the Indian guy. Oh, you found it?
Yeah,
that sounds
long. It's like 45 minutes. So
that dude right there as a hologram
so he's not really there. I got
it. It got so hot in the last, wow.
How's, he appeared dope. If he fucking
appeared out of smoke coming out of that.
They're saying and demonstration.
They gave that guy, he was like,
I don't like presenting an award.
And he was standing in the room and this
whole family walked in the room and uh,
and he was standing there and he talked
to them and they were like talking to
him back and everything and then he just
busted into flames and they were like
all freaked out because they
thought he was real. Look at it.
This looking at weed comes
in, first of all, how strange.
Let them walk in and get Jamie back it
up a little again because that guy's got
the fakest hand wave ever.
I would never vote for that motherfucker.
Just by the way, maybe this is like
an Indian thing, but I understand.
We'll look at it. They're
introducing homeboy. Look,
first of all, he's wearing a
dress. What's that all about?
Are you a school teacher?
Your Old Lady school teacher.
He's got a theme song to look.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
Just fucking waving his hands.
He's wearing white tights and address.
This guy's a freak.
He's a Hologram.
He's wearing white tights and addressing
is going to sit down in a chair.
White tights. So bizarre.
Man. That's so bizarre.
It man, isn't it? Isn't it crazy? I mean
the technology that you can, that pot,
the fact that you can do that.
It's just like, it's so amazing.
Like I would love to not have to
ever do a show like travel to do.
Should I just stand in my fucking
people want you to be there
though. They want you to be there
physically. They didn't know. Yeah,
but isn't it something about actually
no one that's the guy there? Yeah,
of course. It's like, did you ever
hear that band man or astro man? No
band. Like in the like early two
thousands late nineties but they'd had,
they had cloned bands, they had
wore masks, they wear these hoods.
So they had like five clone bands and
they'd send them out on the road and you
would never know if it was the real
band or not because they always had the
hoods on and shit, but they would
have like five different bands.
They would just send up
touring. Oh, that's silly. Yeah.
You know people didn't know it.
I know, but isn't that like half
the thing if the pay to see,
do you want the guy to be right
there? You know, like yeah,
your reputation will be really damaged
if they found that you were actually in
your living room and the shit
it like started fucking up while
you're doing it, man. That'd be,
that would be righteous though. If I was
watching fucking, I'm like, you know,
nails, CNN, the CNN thing that they
did during the wolf blitzer. Yeah.
They only did it during the elections.
And it's like, everybody's like, Ooh,
they're busting out the fucking hologram.
This is crazy. Wow. And he wouldn't,
you know, be in another location and
they, you know, they would appear,
started it with a will.
I am the guy from the black eyed peas.
They started with him and
then they used it with him.
They use it. It was it an
Obama event. It wasn't it.
A John will know and pull out the,
see the CNN reporters did it
see like there is a beautiful time
in Los Angeles. My mom texted me,
telling me how proud she is of me and
pull it back so you could see him appear.
That's fascinating. You a brand
new day and applied in Grand Park.
Let's see if he came
me and now here we go.
Let's make it look as much like star
trek is, we can be appearing process. Oh,
this is great. You know, we're at an
eve of a, a brand new day in America.
How weird is that being here in Chicago?
Uh,
former and Obama supporters
basically like exactly like in a,
in star trek when they
would be and people down.
That's what it looks like right here.
Yeah. But yeah, but this is, it's a,
it's a beautiful time here.
Um, in Chicago. It's a
beautiful time in Los Angeles.
My mom,
the purpose of this just to show
up, show up the technology, well,
to just didn't add an element.
They did it with Wolf Blitzer and
remember he was a, he was a hologram too.
Isn't it funny though to listen to
that guy? It's a beautiful time.
Everything's amazing. Cut to
everybody. Fucking hates him.
Six years later you fucking piece of shit.
All of you.
You fuck heads even will I am right.
Didn't you like run for a,
he was going to be the president of
Haiti or some shit like that? No, no.
That was the other guy. The
guy from a will. I am with,
what's his name? Wyclef Sean.
The same guy to me. Yeah, it's,
I was about to make that joke when he said
that about it being like my John and then
he said it. Yeah, there was this broad,
we're going to be
another one.
She's some chicken where I am was
paying like 20 minutes before.
Did you hear the, did you, you're the guy,
do you know all the controversy about
the dude who bubba buoyed or no, no,
no, he didn't [inaudible] he
quit the MSN BC thing recently.
The Howard stern thing.
No, what happened? MSNBC.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
There's this guy, there was a guy who, uh,
I kept trying to remember
his whack pack name on there,
but like he had gone into retirement
from doing prank calls. Well,
one day recently on,
they were talking about the Malaysia air
thing and this guy calls in and they're
like, we've got this soldier from the
war on the phone. And he goes, yes,
I believe I saw something.
I, you know, I saw it.
I was driving and I
looked out of my passion,
which I saw something I believe it was a
giant burst of wind from Howard Stern's
ass that hit Malaysia plane and all of a
sudden like the lady's like, excuse me.
She's like, so can you tell me what you
like? She starts to it and he goes, well,
you're fucking dumb,
aren't you the girl?
And they like cut the transmission
and there was like he,
and he turns out he wrote an email
to Howard Stern, his people. He said,
this is how I got in there. He said,
he called and he said that he was a,
he was a soldier in the air force or
something and they put him on the phone
with a guy, another guy who then
like it was trying to quiz him on,
on him being legit. Totally
said he bullshitted his
way all the way through it.
The guy let him through, they let
him on fucking MSNBC in this moment.
And this chick,
her name was crystal ball,
was the name of the check as I can
reason why I can remember it that.
And she was just like, you know, I
had no idea what to do with that.
When the guy said fucking high
burst of wind from Harrison,
his ass is what hit it. Like, you know
Msnbc like is that all this trouble?
Cause like no one was paying attention
while it went down for so long for a
couple of minutes. And then they
cut it and it was like, man,
everyone got fired because it was like,
I mean they, not only did he get through,
but they didn't even catch that. He said,
Howard Stern's asked for a long time.
When you're doing those
things and those remotes,
you have an ear piece in and a lot of
times it's hard to understand what the
fuck anybody saying.
And there's a bit of a delay and
them saying it and you hearing
crystal ball, I can, I
can, I can forgive her.
But the guy sitting over there watching
the fucking broadcast or supposedly
watching the broadcast when it goes down
and in editing on the fly and all that,
that guy should have been
like, uh, cut it. You know,
cut it now. But I don't remember
the some ting long when the,
when the plane crashed. Oh
yeah. That was another one.
Four different names and they all got
fired cause some editor fucked up and yes
it is something Wong.
Did she think that? Yeah,
there was something recently the,
the New York Daily News.
Let some fake story go through and uh,
didn't do any checking.
It
was all over the news.
I forget what New York Daily News.
Hoaxed daily.
That's funny man.
They all are, it happens all the
time. People were trying so hard,
you know,
it's with fake news comes through.
That's like the most real
thing we're getting. Yeah.
Well you know we live in strange times
where anybody can get information out.
You can. But especially with these
legacy media, places like that,
like, like news, like we're,
we're getting someone who's live on the
scene and like that's like those are
targets for people fucking
with people. Yeah. It's like,
cause you know that
everyone's looking at this,
everyone's paying attention to this. If
you can get on there and Baba booey yet.
He'll definitely get like
some play on the radio show.
People will do things like that.
I don't know. Gosh, turns pain is,
yeah, it's uh, we're, we're in
weird times when it comes to that.
We're also weird times when it comes
to those things being relevant at all
because at a certain point
in time you've got people,
they're realizing that more people are
paying attention to online sources than
they are. Yeah. Facebook,
Twitter, all of the above.
There's so many different things. The
nightly news, like who, I mean I'll watch,
I do, I will say like if, if I,
if I'm cruising the channels and I'm home
and like the five, six o'clock news on,
I'll turn it on because
I cause it locally de la,
like if there's anything going on
I'll kind of be interested in that.
But otherwise like who watches the
news on like Channel Two? Yeah,
I mean who are just fucking scene.
The only reason why they watch
CNN is because of, you know,
it'll be something massive has happened
and people want to tune in and like
watch it 24 seven otherwise it's like
you don't really, it's going away.
It's going away slowly but surely.
And also the format is so bizarre.
The like the, the evening news,
like the Los Angeles Evening News,
those are the fakeness
broadcast in the world.
The way that everyone talks is fake. You
don't get, you don't see any personality,
you don't have any connection
to those people. You know,
if you had someone like shooter
Jennings reads the news, like Dan,
this some shit went down
today, you know, and you start,
people would connect to
that in a way like, oh,
this is a real guy and he's
telling me about some real stuff.
But if you watch the average broadcast,
it's on the local news show.
There's so it's so fake and, yeah,
and so like uptight and, and weird.
Yeah. And it's just the same garbage
duct to you. Like it's not updated.
That's why people like,
you know, I don't like,
I look at my Twitter feed for that.
Like if I hear something's
going on or if I like, you know,
if I see something like,
it's like the culmination
of all the people I follow
kind of provide the correct
information. Do you know what I mean?
That seems more effective to me. Yeah.
And even then you still have to process
stuff. There's so much bullshit.
It's so difficult to figure out
what's right, what's wrong and,
and then when you have this information
thrown into the mix, I mean,
it's been proven that
government organizations will,
when there's something bad goes down,
they'll throw a bunch
of wacky shit into the news as
well to sort of counter balance.
Like there's a lot of people out there
that believe that a lot of the conspiracy
theorists that like say the most
ridiculous shit that they're,
they're being hired to say ridiculous
shit because it makes all conspiracies.
Conspiracies sound silly. Yeah.
Yeah, of course. I believe that 100%.
I believe that their misinformation
agents all over the place.
He Hall was one who only manly p hall
famous writer and wrote a lot of books
about a lot of conspiracy type thing and
he was a straight up a disinformation
agent for the masons.
Really? Yeah. He was like,
he was out there trying to cloud up
the religion side of things but for the
Masons Bay via the conspiracy
where I'll mainly be all,
it's like famous and a lot of people swear
by his shit but he was really a mason
and he was like in bed with that. What
did they ever figure that William? Uh,
what's the guy who wrote behold a pale
horse man and we could talk about this
guy a lot. Have you Cooper
Cooper man. I love his shit dude.
[inaudible] really nutty shit about
like alien bases on the moon and yeah.
Yeah, he got into some shit like
that in there. But man, if you,
did you ever listen to his radio show?
You can download every episode of it.
I've been trying,
I've been in contact with is a estate,
because I'm trying to take the hour of
the time is the name of the show and
every, every single episode, you know,
he was killed in the 5th
of November in 2001, Waze,
he was in the UFC fight or a gunfight.
He sat on the air,
he was like, look, because it,
Bill Clinton is labeled in
the most dangerous person
on a radio. And he said it,
he said, they're going to
come after me. And he goes,
and I bet you money that they're
going to use the IRS is the reason.
And so they did.
They had it.
So he moved his family away and then
they came after her for tax evasion and,
and when he wouldn't comply,
they sent the US
Marshall's in there and uh,
and they shot at him and he shot one of
them and they killed him. Really? Yeah.
But he's, man, that story,
that dude is very fascinating because he
is the real life. Like, like, like dude,
I mean the,
in my than black ribbons where I could,
the Stephen King character gets
killed and everything in the end.
I mean he's the real
life character of that.
Like this guy was out there and his radio
show is awesome and he was just like
telling you, it's like the first person
talking about the Bilderberg group,
the first person talking about all these
people and just laying it out there no
matter what it,
who had pissed off.
And eventually it pissed off enough people
to get him killed. But he, but he, uh,
he's very fascinating and the hour of
the time I wanted to take the first
episode of it and print it on a 12
inch vinyl cause it's just long enough.
I wanted to put music under it and, and,
and, and make a record on a record label.
And I was trying to get the family to
let me do that, but they were interested.
But then they kind of disappeared on me.
But have you ever looked into
William Cooper debunked? I have.
I've looked into some of that
stuff, but I mean it, it,
it seemed to me William Cooper,
I mean obviously he was hitting
on some pretty harsh things if,
if he was killed by the United States
government.
I mean they didn't,
maybe he owed a lot of taxes and he got
in a shoot out with the federal marshals
who came to arrest him. Is
that possible too? Yeah,
but I bet if you got,
if you listened to his show,
he's very saying he's not, he doesn't,
he's, he seems, he's very collected.
He's very smart, very educated.
Like it'd be one thing.
It was like full of shit,
but he's not like his, if you
listen to his show, he's, he was,
he was very wise to things and he was,
and he was saying a lot of shit
that would piss a lot of people off.
And I know for a fact a lot of it,
I read his book and halfway
in the book I was like, Bitch.
And I tossed it across the room. Yeah.
There was some wacky shit in there.
If you go to rational Wiki,
yeah. You got a rational wiki.
He believed that Ufo people
were controlling the world
that UFL technology had
been used in Vietnam. He became, uh,
one of the stars in the Ufo lecture
circuit writing books that alleged that
space aliens were part
of the new world order.
He later believed that he had been tricked
into believing in aliens and it was
all part of an Illuminati plot,
including the JFK assassination and
the fake moon landings. Uh, yeah,
he,
you know about the Cooper
and landing thing. Right. What about
it, but about how the, there's a,
there's a theory that, that uh, that
the u s government wanted the, the,
the technology that he developed during
doctor strange love and he used it in
2001 for the monkeys and
in the backgrounds and the
way he shot that stuff,
that they came to him to film the,
to fake the moon landings. Yeah.
I've heard that they would fund, they
would give him on unlimited access to the,
to NASA and everything for 2001
and fund every film forever.
I said that supposedly like he was
hinting at a lot of it in 2001 and an eyes
wide shut,
especially in eyes wide shut that he was
hinting to like what he'd done in the
movie a lot.
Well there's documentaries
that show all the secrets,
symbolism that he put
him into the shining.
That movie's terrible because see
I had studied all that shit man.
And it's so true. There's such cool
shit in it. And that movie was like,
they were like review.
They were like interviewing the craziest
people on the planet earth with no
frame of reference to what
they were talking about.
And like when you watch that
movie it's like why didn't,
it sounds like they're crazy.
It's not like everything about that movie
is bullshit because these people who
are talking are clearly insane and,
but the people who who like actually did
the research before those Kooks are the
people that it was kind of fascinating
about. But I'm big Kubrick nerd anyway,
so like Kubrick was definitely a
genius and definitely fascinating guy.
If anybody was capable of faking anything,
which is a website reality sandwich.
There's an article I read that I
read the Atlantic. I'm not convinced,
I'm fascinated. I'm not convinced, you
know, I'm not convinced about any of it.
To me, honestly, I'm not convinced about
the Midland. I'm not convinced about this.
So it'd be not,
I don't know.
You ever heard Bill Clinton's taken the
moon landing? No. This is one of the best.
Bill Clinton wrote this book
called my life. And, uh,
in his book my life, he had
a whole quote about, um,
about the moon here. I'll pull it
up. Oh, I know that my life book, uh,
this is,
uh,
this is the quote he wrote in his quote
he wrote about when he was young, um,
uh, and he had seen the moon landing. He
goes, this is a, I forget what page it is,
or it's just says, just a
month before Apollo, uh,
11 astronauts buzz Aldrin and Neil
Armstrong had left their colleague Michael
Collins above a board starship Colombia
and walked on the moon beating by five
months.
President Kennedy's goal of putting them
on a man on the moon before the end of
the decade. Um, the old carpenter asked
me if I believe that it happened. I said,
sure. I saw it on
television. He disagreed.
He said that he didn't believe it for a
minute and that them television fellers
in quote could make things look
real that weren't back then.
I thought he was a crank during
my eight years in Washington.
I saw some things on TV that made me
wonder if he wasn't ahead of his time.
That's fucking crazy.
That's crazy that a president would say
that of the United States would say,
I saw some things on television during
my time in Washington that made me wonder
if he wasn't ahead of his
time specifically talking
about a guy claiming the
moon, that the moon landings
were fake. See, I could
totally buy it too,
because of the fact that especially in
the in then and we're technology is,
I mean, look at us now, like we
haven't gone back and we're trying,
we've sent a rover to Mars,
but we have not yet.
The rovers are easy. Here's the real
thing is biological life in space.
That's the really difficult
thing because of the radiation,
because of the solar flares,
because of all sorts of micro meteors,
there's all sorts of things that can
happen to someone when they're outside.
Yeah. You know, you're,
you're out there in space.
You're not protected by the environment.
You're not protected by the atmosphere.
So there's no,
no protection from like micro meteors
asteroidal impacts like all the different
things like when you see shooting stars,
those are fucking rocks that were in
space then made their way down to earth.
But they get eaten up in the
atmosphere and they burn out. Yeah,
I mean the radiation is the big one.
Here's the thing,
I think that will Willard we're going to
know and I tell you when we're going to
know is, is these independent
contractors or trying to get to the moon,
Google and being one of them.
When someone else asks someone else
besides the government goes to the moon,
I don't mean the Russian government and
the bread around the same time. Like,
if someone,
someone independent goes to the moon and
it looks way different than it did when
they did it in the 60s you know,
and it's like, oh, like really,
you don't float when we walk in here. You
know what I mean? Like then we'll know.
You know, there's, there's a lot of
fucking things about that. There's,
if you know on that one website with the
Kubrick thing and they're like, dude,
this contrast thing where it kind
of compares the 2001 monkey scenes.
Yeah. Well that was the word
comparing a style of filming, calling,
I think it was called front screen
projection. Yeah. Something along
those lines.
That's exactly what it is.
That front screen rear screen or
whatever it is, it's he, he had a,
it's like a two way mirror and there's
these certain kinds of beads and there's
the projection coming from a
different angle and is able to like,
you're able to film the actors on the
stage at the same time as the background.
Is that adding it later?
So that's why it looks real.
Yeah. The Reality Sandwich, uh,
title is how Kubrick faked
the moon landing. Yeah. Uh,
you know, I think, I don't
know if this is this,
I believe in it wholeheartedly
for a long time. And, uh,
this reality sandwich article shows,
um,
the use of this front screen projection
method and how it, it mimics,
I think that's what it's called,
how it mimics what the shots
looked like from the moon landings.
The real issue with the moon
landing says how few, if you,
if you stop and think
about between 1969 in 1972,
that's when all these took place and
that no one has been more than 400 miles
above the earth's surface since then.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying. That's
what I'm saying. That's what seems so,
so ridiculous to me
knowing that. How about
when Neil Armstrong, he's a,
there's a 20th anniversary
of the moon landing, uh,
for NASA and uh, he, he gives a speech or
25th anniversary, I think it was. Yeah.
That's what it was.
And he gives this speech at the
White House and his words were,
there are great ideas,
undiscovered breakthroughs available
to those who can remove one of truth
protective layers. That's, that's
the quote that he gives. He's,
he's speaking to America's
a honor students,
like all the,
uh,
the high school students that get the
best grades and science and math and all
these different things and they're all
there listening to this guy was the first
man on the moon talk. And this is the
thing he says, there are great ideas,
undiscovered breakthroughs available
to those who can remove one,
a truth protective layers.
Yeah.
But the fuck does that mean like
that's between him and Clinton.
It's almost like if the
moon landings were real,
like they're clearly fucking
with everybody begging for
people to read into it.
Yeah. But if it wasn't real,
it's almost like poetic how,
how they're dropping these truths.
Yeah. That was how the, with Kubrick,
like they said that they didn't,
a lot of the films, like he was
dropping the guilt of the fact that he,
that he'd lied, that he did this
thing and that it's a, you know,
that he was trying to,
trying to admit it and a lot of the films,
it is pretty crazy with the last
time people went, it was 1972 yeah.
Like fucking clothes since then.
And not only have we not come close,
we've never gone further than 400 miles.
That's,
that's the thing about every single space
shuttle mission, every space station,
mission,
everything is inside of 400 miles from
the earth's surface except the Apollo
missions.
All those were 260,000 miles and back,
you know, so it's hard to believe
it is hard to believe in. I mean,
it's like you're like cad.
No one's ever gonna make it to the middle.
They're never going to prove it.
And we'll be,
I'll be dead by the time they do
anyway. So who cares? The big mind fuck
for me is when you look
at the moon itself,
like you're sitting at home and you look
up, you see the moon and you're like,
bitch,
nobody went there.
Yeah. I feel like you did not
no way. Look at that shit.
That's bullshit. But we know that they
did go to space, so if they go to, I mean,
I couldn't believe that they
could go to space and a fuck.
I just went around from 1960 9:00 PM
yeah, I dunno. I Dunno. I would look,
I love sexy ideas and the big
sexy idea is that they didn't go,
that they faked it all and they somehow
or another captain for the American
people. That's the big sexy idea. That's
the fun one. That's, you know, it's also,
that time was just so
filled with bullshit.
That was the time of the Nixon
administration, Watergate fucking,
I mean that was just lying. The Gulf of
Tonkin incident, they'd already faked.
They got us into Vietnam with
a fake fucking attack. Yeah.
I mean that's wild.
Widely accepted now that the Gulf of
Tonkin incident [inaudible] didn't really
happen and that's, that caused more than
a million deaths. Yeah, they got us into,
I mean that's way crazier than the
idea of just faking a trip. Yeah.
Nearby it's planet. You're so right
man. And you know, as time goes on,
like these things do get exposed.
That would be a motherfucker
of a mind fuck though.
If they did find out that it really was
all bullshit that no one did land on the
moon. Yeah. Or like, or like what if
everything was true. All the conspiracy
shit was true. You know what I mean?
Like you just start finding that shit
out. I mean, look man, if, if, if,
what's his name,
Virgin Galactic,
you can pay in Bitcoin to get on
a fucking trip to space right now.
Like take me to the moon. Yeah, that's
too far. They can't really do that.
Did you ever hear about the fake moon
rock that was given to Holland by Neil
Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin? No.
It was fake. Yeah, pull it up.
It's kind of interesting,
Jamie. It was, wait a minute,
it was a moon rock that was giving to
the Dutch prime minister by the Apollo 11
astronauts. Um, and, uh, once
they examined it, like many,
many years later, they were,
um, they were doing it for,
I believe it was for an
insurance investigation.
And it was actually just
petrified wood. Yeah. It was,
it was attached to a, you know, a whole,
a plaque that said it was there from,
you know,
Apollo 11 and Neil Armstrong and buzz
Aldrin and taking this from the moon.
And this is,
and they, and they said in Buzz
Aldrin and Neil said, yeah,
this is really for the man. Oh yeah,
that's what it said on the plaid.
Well, you know, whoever gave
them the rock, I mean, it's,
I don't know if the actual rock was
handed to them by Neil Armstrong and buzz
Aldrin,
but it was supposedly a rock that was
given to the Dutch prime minister from the
Apollo ever. And astronauts
1969. And uh, it was fake.
Wow. Yeah, it was,
it was during a global tour then.
It was, it was given to them.
Um, 50 years. Uh, okay.
It says the Rock was
given to William Drees,
a former Dutch leader during a
global tour by Neil Armstrong.
Michael Collins and Buzz Aldrin
following their moon mission.
Yeah.
The Rock was then donated to a museum,
uh,
after the Dutch prime minister,
his death in 1988. And so then, uh,
after that, I guess, uh, they had decided
to test it and when they tested it,
they found out that it was
actually just petrified wood.
Yeah.
I mean, who knows. I mean, maybe
it's just like they're like,
fuck this guy's giving. Maybe we did
go to the moon, but it's, you know,
rocks are valuable.
Sky's the Dutch prime minister given
we got some shit that looks like a moon
rock. Yeah. It's a symbolic gesture
either way that either way,
if buzz Aldrin and Neil Armstrong were
in the know than the men landings faked.
I mean,
who knows if they were in the know,
but if they weren't in the know then, then
even further, if they were like, dude,
have you and I walked on the moon together
and it was just the two of us and we
came back. We were the only two
humans that walked on the fucking man,
first of all, when you think that we
would like look around and be like, man,
look at this shit. I mean you don't think
we would've been like, wow, whatever.
Some man, just what? Another place.
So by the time you get to this,
if somebody hands you a fucking piece
of wood is petrified wood and says, Hey,
this is from your moon trip,
first of all,
neither one of you picked
it up and brought it back
because you know that second
of all like wouldn't do anything.
We would know that it's not.
Especially if our whole life was meant
to get to this point and somebody hands
you this rock that you're supposed to
give to someone that has a moon rock.
Don't you think that?
I don't know.
I'm not a geologist,
so I could never even speculate is that
whether or not it'd be able to tell
where rock came from.
Well, you'd know for sure that you
didn't pick it up and bring it back.
Maybe,
but maybe it looks a lot like a rock
that you brought back and you'd think it
was,
you know,
I don't know what the Fuck I'm moon rock
actually looks pull up a real moon rock.
Let's, we just saw that
image is a real moon rock.
Well they definitely got moon rocks that
came from asteroidal impacts and that
was actually one of the big points of
contention because Wernher von Braun who
was a Nazi, a straight up
Nazi, ladies and gentlemen,
that's a real moon rock. Wow.
It looks like an asteroid.
It looks like it came from,
uh, from space. It's, that's
the, the thing about, um,
uh,
the Werner Herzog thing.
Wernher von Braun rather a Wernher von
Braun was in Antarctica in 1969 before
the actual or 67, one of
those, um, before the actual,
um, Moon landings took
place collecting asteroids.
They had gone to Antarctica because
Antarctica is one of the places where they
could be assured that a lot of the
asteroids that had landed there,
for whatever reason they knew were still
there, were from the moon themselves.
So they, uh, they collected a lot of
these to examine them. Interesting. Yeah.
There's pictures are Wernher
von Braun in Antarctica.
He had a broken arm at the time.
I don't know what happened to him.
Maybe he's thinking about
not faking the moon. They,
huh?
There's missing moon rocks and they're
worth a lot of money on the black market.
Yeah, I would imagine. Fucking
moon rocket will moon rocks.
This is what it's called. You're going
to have a moon rock in your house.
People come over, they be fucking,
they'd think you're the shit you do then.
Well that's,
there's a,
there's a whole black market for stolen
art because there's a lot of people that
just, they don't give a fuck.
They just want that art,
whether it's stolen or not stolen, you
know, they just, they just want that art.
They could hide it and you know,
have people come over and bring
them to their secret layer and look,
this is from Egypt. This is some shit
they stole during the, yeah, Iraq.
Oh, that's a sudden. It's
like Reagan, Reagan and the
wolf up there. That was fun.
We're uh, we're running out of time here
in 10 minutes we turn into a pumpkin.
Oh yeah, yeah. We just did three
hours and not fast man. It's,
it's great doing this.
I see why it zooms by.
It's just fun just to talk and yeah,
I mean that's it.
You've got the skill of being,
being like it. Your mind is alive.
So it's like when you talk to you,
it's like, it just, it just rolls.
It's like seamless information flying
all over the place from, you know,
back and forth.
Think we started talking about Scientology
and did not take one breath and got
all the way to the fake moon
landing and well, there's so much
to talk about. You know, that's the thing,
the beautiful thing about this world
today is there's so much God damn
information. Yes. It's
constantly coming at you.
And you can't pay attention to all of
it. If you do, you'll go mad. Like I,
the one thing I've get done to myself
lately is forced myself to stay offline
for like many,
many hours.
He's at a time nothing to do it. I W I
mean, I mean I would be happy not to.
I'm happy to throw my phone aside
cause I like, I run my own business,
I run the record label that we
do with my manager and like,
like I was packing like Sunday night,
me and my wife,
we're literally packing all the preorders
of like our vinyl that we did in boxes
and shipping them and shit.
And we've set up a warehouse
and we've done all this shit.
So like I'm stressed out all the fucking
time and I'm in the studio all the time
and I've got my kids autistic,
like when I get my kids
loved her on my phone inside.
But I would be real bummed if I
didn't have like didn't have, no,
if I wasn't able to get on the Internet
because it's like part of my favorite,
my non stress time is, is uh,
there's a game called combat arms.
It's like a free,
like first person shooter game that like
online only that me and my manager and
buddies,
we go in there and play and kill each
other and like do that kind of stuff or
like said on IRC and talk about shit or
like IRC dude, you're a serious game.
I'm on IRC all the time. I'm on there.
Right. I mean, I'm just, you know,
sit on there all the time and I go on.
Yeah.
Late at night I'll go in the bitcoin
channels, uh, on the freenode thing,
which is there,
there is some kind of communication server
and talked to a lot of developer guys
and stuff. Like, I like a man. It's like,
that's my favorite thing to do. You know,
I don't do Facebook. Nah. I mean I have a,
I have an official page,
but I don't use it.
I don't like do it socially.
I'll do Twitter.
I always liked Twitter cause it's kind
of like a one way thing in a weird way.
And then I always liked
that communication better,
but then I got over a
little overwhelmed by it.
Like I used to be on all the time and
I used to like do shit all the time and
kind of like when I went through my
split up with my last ex or whatever and
there was a like I just
got really complicated.
There was a lot of sudden there was
like factions of people and there were
people commenting and there were things
that were just became kind of like weird
in public. And so after that I kind
of backed it off a little bit. But
yeah,
if you go through something in public
and everything like is subject to other
people's criticisms and evaluations with
or without any information whatsoever
and then you watch it all play out,
you're like, why? Yeah, I see it.
Right around that time I had just started
to creep into Facebook and started to
enjoy it and I was like posting pictures
of like skeletor and shit that I was
into.
You know,
my friends and I'm like keeping up with
my friends for the first time. I'm like,
oh this is kinda cool.
And then I'll like this wave of negativity
hit me and I'm like, fuck that thing.
And you know what I mean? So I've
never done Facebook. And then Twitter,
Twitter, I kinda, I backed off
a little bit on, but you know,
but I like it a lot better. Like
I think, I definitely think it's,
it's more my speed, but like, you know,
if I had it my way, everybody be an IRC,
what I like about Twitter is
retweeting shit like that.
People Send me interesting stuff,
then I can send it to other people and
that motivates people to send me more
interesting stuff.
And so then you,
you got this constant network of
interesting stories coming your way. Yes.
That's very true.
There's definitely a lot of dumb shit
and gossip and stuff that people get
caught up in it, but that's
just human beings, man. Pete,
human beings love stupid shit. Yeah.
Think like to be assholes, you know,
and just to fuck with you to see if they
could get a rise out of you and just to
get you to react just so that
they know that, you know,
shooter Jennings is a real person on
the other end of that. Yeah, that's,
that's why I like to keep it where they
think I'm not real. I'm just kidding.
Like I don't react now.
You know,
it's funny like Ricky Rachman has a
buddy of mine and he was telling me that
he's like,
it's funny that people write United shit
all day long and you never replied to
it. But like one guy says, fuck
you dude. That's why they do it.
You know? That's what people,
there's, there's many, many people.
Like sometimes someone will, I never
go back and forth with people. I just,
I used to, it's stupid.
It's a waste of energy.
But I will go online and read something.
If someone says something rude and then
I'll go look at their profile and I'll
see, even if they don't
say something rude to me,
I go to see if they say
rude things to other people.
And you find out that their whole
profile just, yeah, just, yeah.
Yeah. I found that out too. One time I
said something, I said that I'm a tweet,
this is actually, this is kind
of when I backed off of Twitter,
I tweeted something about John Mayer being
a giant Douche because I thought that
like he,
he like all of a sudden led was the all
Hollywood and he was all played out in
Hollywood and then all of a sudden he
buys his place in Montana and he got a
Poncho and starts growing his hair.
I'm wearing a cowboy hat and doing
all this shit. And I was like,
give me a fucking break.
But he's still hanging out at the fucking
Chateau Marmont but he's like putting
this image forward and I was like phony,
more of the phony shit.
So I just called him out on
it and like TMZ like put it,
I remember it was Halloween of 2012
I'll never forget it because TMZ fucking
puts that shit everywhere and all of
a sudden I'm getting calls from like,
like my,
like my brother and like my fan like
that they're seeing it on like the Yahoo
page,
like the TMZ,
like what says this thing
about how I called him a King
Douche and all that dude.
All of a sudden I had,
I'm looking at my Twitter and it says,
I've got like lots of mentions in the
number just keeps going up and like,
and like it was like 15,015 year olds
telling me what a piece of shit I was and
I was like, nobody and I was
doing this shit for attention.
I mean I've never seen.
So I just started retweeting all of them.
Like it was just constantly retweeting
all these people telling me what a piece
of Shit I was, you know? But
after that I was like, man,
I mean it just scared me to death.
I was like, I am as not worth it.
You know John Mayer? No, I've never met.
Is it possible that he just like found
out that like having a place of Montana?
It's pretty cool. Probably. Are you
friends with him? I don't know him. No.
I already,
he's a nice guy though.
He hangs out at the comedy store
sometimes I have done standup.
I mean I know it's easy to
call him a deuce first of all.
He's way too pretty well I know some
girls that are brought to mind that have
been real fucked by only town like,
like some guys like you know you're
like fuck their friend and then like the
Douche bag. So like I've kind of gotten
some wind of him that way and then,
but isn't that two sides of that too?
Like impossible. Those girls are,
is always saying and I hooked up with
him and he was like, you know what,
I can't deal with you anymore.
And then before you know the truth,
Fuck John Mayer, he's an asshole. But
meanwhile he just got bored. Yeah,
he doesn't like them. Maybe
they're annoying, you know?
The same type of girls would go on
ratting them out and saying these crazy
things about them.
Those are also the same type of girls.
That would be annoying if you were John
Mayer and you were dating that girl.
Right? Right. Yeah, it's, he
hasn't, I mean he's ready.
You can say that but you could also say
like, man, I really don't like his music.
That's true and I really didn't like it.
His version of free fall on which was
like all these like 12 year old kids think
John Mayer this song
and then and so I had,
I already had issues and I'm sure that
there are people that have the same kind
of issues with me,
but it is kind of a well fact that
the John Mayer is a Douche bag.
I mean I can guarantee that
and it's kind of not news.
I don't know the guy.
I don't either.
I will reserve judgment until I see that
makes you a better man than I and the
scenario, the situation, because I did
not reserve judgment. I got he, I read,
I'm reading this rolling saw article and
my blood is boiling because he bought a
ranch in Montana. Just cause he's like,
he's like putting forth this, like I'm,
he calls himself the new Neil young
in the article they, that he says,
he says, I'm this generation's Neil young
or something like that. And I was like,
that's what flipped the switch for me,
where I was like,
fuck you and your fucking body
is a wonderland. I, that's,
that's what it was. I mean, it's
like, you know, don't say that.
Don't say if he said,
if I'm this generation's Neil Neil Young,
the Nora Jones is this generation's
like, I don't know who he, Janis Joplin.
It was something, something.
So like that doesn't work.
It was like something even
worse that he said. But I mean,
just to say that just
rubbed me the wrong way.
I'm a huge Neil young fan and I was a lot
to learn before you're going to be new
young John Mayer.
Um,
I worked at a concert one
before I was a comedian.
I worked as a security
guard and great woods,
great woods is this place in Mansfield,
Massachusetts that has his concerts.
And uh, the Neil young show was the
last one I ever worked. It was like,
this is too fucking crazy.
I was like,
I got to get out because I thought I
thought it was going to get killed.
Like somebody who's going to get killed.
Yeah,
it was madness because the way
great woods works is there's um, uh,
a covered area and then there's a
back area that's like a lawn and uh,
all the security people were
assigned to, uh, you know,
stop people from bringing in booze.
Like they'd bring in bottles of wine
and stuff like that, bottles of Whiskey,
and also, uh, to keep, keep order, like
when shit would go haywire and we'll the,
the lawn, the thing about the lawn
was there's no assigned seating,
so everybody just sat wherever
they wanted to on the lawn. Well,
people just started fires and
during the Neil Young concert,
they had to shut the concert down
because the lawn was on fire.
Like people would just, and then
fights broke out. And I wound up,
I had a security jacket on and I covered
my security jacket or it turned it
inside out. I remember what I did, but
I was like, fuck this job, set it up.
And I'm like, I'm a normal person
now, and I got the fuck out of there.
I remember I go, I don't even know if
I got paid for the last day of work.
I don't know if I punched out.
I don't remember shit.
But I remember saying to myself,
very, I was probably 19 at the time.
It was a long time ago,
but I remember saying,
this is the last day I work as a security
guard and it was the Neil young show.
Wow.
Just so crazy.
There was fights breaking out and fucking
bottles were flying and fire and it
was like,
this is what was I going to pay,
like 10 bucks an hour or something
stupid back then it was like,
this is not worth it. Wow. That's funny.
But it was cool that it was Neil young.
Yeah. At least you go out with a bang,
go out with Neil young and
that's like, you know, yeah.
Neil Young's the shit. You know,
he lives up in northern California.
He's got a giant ranch ranch
up, makes his own diesel. Yeah.
And he's got like what he made that he
made that new iPod thing he's trying to
sell and he's got, yeah. What is it
like it's his own version of an MP,
three player. Right. I don't know how
you can jump in that game. That's,
that seems to me like it always seems
like a poor business decision to try it
because if he's not making a phone,
you're not going to beat the iPod.
Like nobody buys iPods. They buy
phones that have music on them now.
I mean there's no, it's called a Puyo
or uh, yeah, it's called Pono Pono.
It's like, yeah, I mean, look,
I think it's awesome technology that
he's got some shit where it's like the
audio quality is way better, but I mean,
you're jumping in, that's like saying,
is that what the idea is? If the
audio quality's a lot better? Yeah,
it's is it if you're trying to Jamie?
No,
I haven't tried it,
but I know that's the trying to sell
the audio files and that's, yeah,
but no one's listening
to music isn't made for
mastering for digital quality for Itunes,
so you have to breed master everything.
It's, it's, it's kind of weird. I mean
it seems like a losing game to jump into,
but yeah. Although you know,
got like him, like, I mean they,
they, they crowdfunded it. Yeah.
That's the weird thing, right?
He said it's Crowdfund,
but can you play stuff from your,
can you transfer stuff from your apple
from iTunes to that and will it sound
better? Will it play? Like how
much better will it sound though?
You a lot of time you're listening
to us through shitty ass. Fucking,
it's supposed to make an iTunes.
Tufts, I'm better. I don't believe that
that's what they've got some
crazy algorithm and that's
what is going on inside
really. But I mean, you
start getting into art.
This sounds better versus
just sounds better. Yeah, it
does. But I don't like it.
You like it. You like it.
I don't like it. Okay,
well let's just move on to tomorrow
because this is a silly argument.
Yeah,
but they're pointing out in this article
about it that it doesn't mean Jack Shit
if you don't have really good headphones
behind it, you know, it's kind,
kinda interesting. It will be. Well,
what's interesting is that like see if
people react to this and they up the
sound quality for phones. Video video
just died. Well we ran out of time. Yeah,
just a heads up. Oh, all right,
well that's it ladies and gentlemen,
podcasts over the people on iTunes
can get another couple of minutes. Uh,
thanks to our sponsors. Thanks
to uh, me undies me undies.
Go to [inaudible] dot com forward slash
Rogen and get 20% off your first order.
Uh,
do that by September 1st so me
undies.com forward slash Rogen.
Thanks also to audible.
Go to audible.com forward slash Joe get
one free audio book and 30 free days of
audible service. Thanks also
to onnit.com that is o, n n.
I t used the Codeword Rogan and save
yourself 10% off any and all supplements
shooter Jennings. This was fun, man. We
got to do this more often. You do it.
Do it again. Anytime you want to stack
of vitals for you that I forgot to.
Bring in the vinyls next time you
come and do whatever, man, we'll,
we'll figure something out.
Thank
you very much brother. I appreciate it.
Thank you so much for having me. You guys.
That was fun. Zoom by. I want to get,
I wanted to do DMT,
man.