Ready?
Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Larry Sharp.
How are you sir?
I am doing great.
Thanks for having me.
Uh,
before we get started,
I like you.
Oh,
that's good.
I like you a lot.
I like winning Ryan,
man.
I'm just telling you right now upfront,
I've been listening to a lot of
interviews,
watching a lot of your interviews.
You make sense.
It's almost like,
you know,
you can't win,
so you talking so logically you might
win the,
yeah.
The hope is that the people who actually
have given up who think it's so stupid,
they don't bother voting.
Right.
So the hope is I say something that
makes sense and I go,
oh,
maybe I should vote.
Oh my God,
If those people vote,
you win.
I win.
Yeah.
There's an untapped resource of
unmotivated people who are too fuck.
But how do we fix that?
Is it,
is it a matter of getting people,
I believe firmly that if we could get
people to register and vote online,
especially with their phones,
it changes the world.
Yes.
Are Really,
really,
really believe that.
And I think that this is also a concern
of the people that are in the Democratic
Party and the Republican Party and I
think they want that 100% look.
They have a lot.
They're relying on voter apathy.
There were also relying on people who
are committed to their parties and who
are politically active,
which is not the majority of the people.
It's the establishment.
Right.
Look,
you asked how we fixed this.
Bernie and trump actually told us this
in 2016 they told us two things.
Number one,
if you can get people to an event,
you can get them to the polling station.
Number one,
that's what they did.
A lot of events.
I do over 30 events every month.
I'm always doing events,
getting people to show up because if I
can get him to show up to my event,
I can get them to a polling booth,
right?
Cause to come to s to hear me speak.
You have a lot of choices out there.
You can be on Netflix,
you can have with your family and
friends.
You could be playing a video game.
You choose to come hear me speak,
you'll come to the polling station.
That's number one.
But how do I get into care in the first
place?
It's hope.
The average person who votes often,
right?
If you vote often you use the vote
because of fear.
The two party system installs fear,
right?
I don't really care about my guy or Gal,
but I'm so afraid of the other guy.
I'll go out and support my guy or gal
even don't even know his name.
I just know I don't like the red team.
So by blue,
I don't like the blue team,
so I vote red.
But to get someone who doesn't vote and
He York states really bad.
New York state,
about 70% of New Yorkers don't vote.
It's a huge chunk over 7 million New
Yorkers.
70% yeah,
70% yeah.
Last likes,
I think it was 67% so it helped us
around 70 to get those people out.
You have to give them hope.
Bernie gave the left hope.
Trump gave the right hope.
If the Democratic Party wasn't so broken
as a party,
Bernie would have been their nominee.
It would have been hope against hope.
It was hope against establishment hope.
One.
That's how it works.
I'm hope the other two guys who are
running in my,
in my,
um,
election,
that totally establishment.
Well you say some really logical things.
So one of the things that you've said
that nobody wants to touch you,
you were talking about gun violence and
you were talking about these mass
shootings.
Yep.
And you said there's two things that
they have in common.
One of them,
they don't have relationships.
They're,
they don't have girlfriends.
Boyfriends,
well,
it's almost always girl,
a guy that does it.
Usually it don't.
And boys tend to be more violent in a
tent.
Males tend to,
people get mad at me being sexist,
but I'm guessing are in stats.
That's just statistically males tend to
outwardly strike.
Women tend to him when the strikers,
the general statistically,
and there's exceptions,
obviously.
The only other,
the other factor is psychotropic drugs.
Yep.
And these are two things that no one
wants to talk about.
Correct.
And they're both real and they're both
facts.
And why is it that you think that these
are there obvious facts that people want
to ignore because they don't actually
want to fix the problem?
Right?
If you fix the problem,
then you don't have controversy.
If you know of controversy,
you don't have a left versus right
paradigm.
Do you realize that that's what it is?
Yes.
First off,
they don't want to touch the car.
They don't want to fix the problem.
If you want to fix the problem with
school shootings,
right?
There's two things.
Remember as I'm,
as you've heard me say before,
the school shooting,
while it is a murder at its core,
it's actually a public suicide and
people don't understand that at its
core,
most mass shootings are public suicides.
They would understand that show.
It's like death by cop,
right?
It's public suicide,
so you have to make sure you have
happier people,
right?
But then why did they school?
Why did they choose schools?
Several reasons.
One,
because that's where they're,
they're assumed enemies are right.
The insoles think that the guys,
the bad guys and the bad girls were
there.
But something else,
the soft targets.
The other thing you remember from all of
these school shootings is there planned,
and that's a critical aspect.
You want to stop school shooting in New
York state.
You don't have to pass one extra law at
all.
Have do one minor thing and one thing
only.
And that is say if you are a licensed,
uh,
if your license and you have a permit to
carry a firearm,
if you want to in school,
you may,
if you a teacher or administrator,
if you want to,
you may.
That's it.
You don't have to force a teacher to
carry,
you don't need a resource officer.
Why?
Because if you have a resource officer,
which is what most Republicans will say,
put an officer there,
they'll just shoot him first.
If you all democrats,
no guns,
they'll shoot everybody.
So if you instead say,
well,
I don't know who's armed.
Is it an administrator as a teacher?
Is everybody isn't nobody.
The planning goes away once there's no
planning available.
The school was no longer a soft target.
They stop choosing the school.
Okay,
Linda,
what's on practice?
So you're saying that if you have an
officer on the school that carries a gun
and this person knows that officer has a
gun,
they will shoot him first?
Correct.
And that if just teachers are carrying
guns,
there's no way this person knows and so
they're less likely to shoot people.
They're are less.
There's two things.
If you,
here's the core of it.
What's killing our children?
It's not firearms.
The the one of the,
I think it was the Texas shooting,
I think it was before he stole the guns.
He had put together and set up pipe
bombs and pressure cooker bombs in case
he couldn't steal the guns.
So if he couldn't get guns,
he was going to kill people.
Anyway.
The key thing here is what's killing
these kids?
Lack of community,
lack of purpose and loneliness.
That's what's killing our kids.
Those three things.
Take those three things away.
Kids don't do that.
You give a kid who's 16 1718 purpose,
he can't go off and kill people.
There's something to do.
Here's a reason to live.
Remember,
this is a public suicide.
If you have a reason to live and you
think the right answer is to go do
something,
you don't kill yourself.
If you don't kill yourself,
there's no public suicide,
mass shootings all of a sudden,
a tremendously reduced,
it's just how it works.
It's human nature.
You have to understand that,
but if you do that,
then there's no extra law.
Then there's no one to point a finger
at.
You can't restrict guns.
What I'm saying just makes actual sense.
This is where you and I brick company
because I don't agree with that.
I don't think that anyone is trying to
keep the school shootings in the same
state.
There are now.
I think that there's two things.
One,
no one wants to demonize psychotropic
drugs and especially politicians.
They have a really hard time with that
because they don't want to tell people
who are on psychotropic drugs that
they're either suspects or suspicious or
potential mass shooters.
It's incorrect.
We made the safe act and the safe act
literally says,
if you go on these drugs,
you lose your firearm.
So that's absolutely not true in New
York state.
It may be true in California,
I don't know your laws here,
but in New York state,
the opposite is true.
We've,
we've already done that.
We have made our medical personnel part
of our secret state police,
which means if you go in and say,
I'm,
you know,
I'm feeling depressed,
I need some drugs,
I'm thinking about suicide.
The state police might combine,
take your firearms that's already
happening in New York state and they now
want to create red flag laws,
which means a teacher can now do it.
So now a teacher says,
oh,
there's a student who I see drew a
firearm.
He a gun cops and robbers,
maybe a red flag.
Let me go to a judge and see if I can
have the cops go and take his father's
firearm.
I'd definitely want to talk about this,
but I want to bring it back to what you
said earlier.
You don't think they want to fix the
problem yet?
Yeah,
I don't think that's true.
I just don't think they have a viable
solution that they think is politically
viable perhaps.
But I think my solution seems bloke
avaiable people,
I,
I say everyone I say this too,
they go,
oh wow,
you're right.
Well,
you are definitely right that they're
lonely,
sad people that are lashing out.
And I think you're definitely right that
in many instances it's a public suicide.
Yup.
And I think you're definitely right that
the vast majority of them are on
psychotropic drugs,
which do have a disassociative,
uh,
aspect to them where they're not even
sure they're aware of what they're
doing.
This is,
if you've talked to him on those people
that have been on these things,
things don't mean anything anymore.
Like a car accident in front of them
doesn't mean anything.
People have various reactions to various
SSRS and the antidepressants.
But one thing that happens is you lose
the highs and lows and everything is
just flat.
You become numb.
Yes.
And you become numb to almost anything
good happens.
Absolutely.
And again,
it varies depending upon the individual
that's on these things.
Sure.
Part of that would allow someone to do
something horrific,
which they wouldn't be able to before.
Well,
there's two things to remember here.
One.
I'm
not concerned with being righteous.
I'm concerned with happy New Yorkers and
happy people.
That's what I want.
Righteousness is very low on my priority
of things.
So if that doesn't sound,
if what I'm saying sounds bad,
I'm okay.
I want to fix the problem.
The second thing is I'm not a
politician,
which means I don't have,
I don't have a uh,
a career I have to protect.
I don't have interests.
I have to serve.
The average donor is $75 so I don't have
a bunch of people who are,
I'm a huge checks,
so don't have that concern either.
So maybe in four years I'll be corrupt
and you can beat your corrupt,
I mean,
I'm not saying that at all.
[inaudible] they're corrupt.
I mean,
I'm sure many of them are,
but I think that they just,
there's things they don't feel like they
can discuss politically.
And I think one of those things is in
any way demonizing people who are on
antidepressants because a lot of people
along the highest percentage of people,
absolutely.
Our opiate crisis is,
is heavily based upon the idea that when
you have pain of any type physical,
mental,
the answer is not dealing with that
pain.
But the answer is a once a day pill,
right?
Yes.
That is the answer for all of our pain.
And because of that,
you have a lot of people who are on
drugs and you probably got a stat,
about 80% of all the people who are
currently heroin addicts,
uh,
somehow started on someone's that even
though it was theirs,
but someone's prescription legal,
legal drug,
I mean that was prescribed for the pain
medication or something like that.
Usually pain medication.
But other things too,
you're totally correct.
This is a problem.
But what I'm saying is this,
where I talk about often people say,
Larry,
you know,
why should I vote for you?
Why should I support you?
Here's the reason why,
whether you believe I can win or not,
it's actually irrelevant.
If you think I could win,
awesome.
I can win and to be forward with you.
If I went in New York as a libertarian,
the entire nation changes overnight.
And that's not exaggeration.
The entire nation changes overnight.
This is the most impactful election.
Hands down the entire nation.
2018.
Why?
Because it's New York.
That's correct.
New Mexico.
Mary Johnson won.
Yes.
If I would,
New York State was ranked 50th by Cato.
Uh,
when it comes to freedom,
it is,
we have the most people leaving over a
hundred thousand people leaving every
single year more than any other state.
We also,
on top of that,
we were ranked the least friendly to
retirees.
All of a sudden Larry Sharp libertarian
becomes governor.
I mean,
it's insane.
The advantages.
It's a five way race in a five way race.
30% could win.
This is actually winnable race.
How's it a five way race?
It's going to be his majesty who are
current king.
He will run,
um,
there'll be a republican slowmo cuomo.
Yes,
correct.
There'll be a republic home and His
Majesty,
cause he's thinks he's a king and he is
a king.
That's the reason when I'm in front of
him,
I'll call him your grace to you.
I met him one time in 2014.
It was,
yeah.
Um,
yes he was.
Yes,
he was.
He was,
he was very dismissive.
Yes,
he was.
I was,
I was actually with the libertarian
candidate.
Then in 2014 he was dismissive.
So His majesty will run a,
there'll be a republican sacrificial
lamb placeholder.
Who knows.
He'll come in second,
probably third to me because New York
has basically always been a left wing
state.
Not always.
Now I,
the last 16 years and the last 16 years
in New York state,
same thing happens in a state wide
election.
Blue team comes in first red team comes
in second.
Nothing changes,
nothing changes.
That's been the last 16 years.
But prior to that,
Republicans did when it did happen,
but it in citizens tubes in,
what is she running as a,
she won't be running in about a week or
so.
No.
She'll be finished.
Yeah,
she'll be fine.
Yeah.
How do you know?
Let,
let me,
let me give you the five people that
I'll cover her.
Right?
Those two,
then Stephanie minor will run.
She's a,
uh,
an independent who runs out of Syracuse.
There'll be a green party communist.
So run how we hawkins.
Communists,
yes.
And if you call communism,
he wouldn't be unhappy if I called them
that.
Really?
He's,
he's,
he would nod his head probably close.
Yeah.
Wow.
He'd be okay with that.
Um,
so him and then myself.
So five people running.
Okay.
With five people running New York
state's a plurality state.
So 30% in theory could actually win this
thing with people who know who I am.
I already pulled it 25% this is about
the Quinnipiac poll on Gravis marketing.
Paul both Poles,
I pulled about 25% of people who know
you will know who I am.
My problem is name recognition,
right?
If more people get to know who I am,
then that number of,
obviously we'll be going higher.
And how much time do we have here?
Two months.
Here's the reality.
I get $2 million.
I win because all in dollars is all text
because I just need to get my name out.
I already have infrastructure already
had the message.
All I needed to get my name out,
which takes what it takes is
advertisements on local news.
News on local stations,
get my name out.
That happens.
I win.
That's not an exaggeration.
How important are the debates?
Debates are important.
If I,
if I don't get that money,
I'll have to intubate so I have to do
it.
Jesse Ventura,
right.
Just even sure.
In Minnesota when he had the debates,
he won.
He handled the one in debates and that
really gave him the,
uh,
they gave him the election.
That will give me the election.
People were a big fan of that movie
Predator that yes,
because he didn't,
he didn't have time to bleed.
That's exactly right.
You Go,
yes.
But those are drawn fragments for those
of you old enough to remember that
movie.
Yes.
Jessie didn't have time to bleed,
so yes.
Um,
so that's,
that's what I'm saying with that we make
that happen.
We can actually win and change
everything because all I need is my name
to get out.
But you asked about it.
The next Nixon,
Cynthia Nixon made an error.
Cynthia Nixon is not a politician and
doesn't know politics and she thought
that her celebrity would get her a pass.
The the democratic machine which is run
by by Cuomo in our state,
so she ran a democrat.
Stephanie minor is also a Democrat,
but she chose not to run as a Democrat
because she knew that if she ran is that
Cuomo crusher as Comos crushing Nixon.
How was he crushing Nixon in the
Democratic convention?
If you are able to get 5% of the vote
from delegates and you get to speak on
stage,
cuomo controlled those delegates with an
iron fist so much.
He made sure Cynthia Nixon did not even
get 5% she couldn't even get on the
stage to speak and when to be clear said
the next one is a popular actor who
lives in New York City.
There is no way they were enough people
who would have,
if they wanted to hear out speak could,
would have voted 5% of course he made
sure it didn't happen.
She had to submit 65,000 signatures to
get on the actual ballot so she could be
in the primary.
There is no way that he allows her to.
When she doesn't win,
he debated her and because he thought,
let me just show people that that I
don't care.
I can just dismiss her and that's why he
debated her and he's going to win and
she's going to lose she and once she
loses,
I don't think she's going to stay in.
I doubt she will if she does better for
me because in the basics way race,
but I doubt she will,
she'll probably drop out in some way,
shape or form.
My odds.
All should run for Congress or something
like that.
In the working,
the working families party to do
something like that.
The Working Families Party?
Yes.
That's another party.
So the party,
New York State?
Yes.
How New York state runs New York states
has a,
is a fusion state,
which means you can run as multiple
parties if you want to.
You can have three or four or five lines
if you want to.
So what often happens is the big two
parties,
they use it as a way to have issue based
voters.
So they'll literally create parties to
their credit part that says,
I'm the working families party.
And then people go,
oh,
well it's not a democrat.
I'm a working family.
And they'll click that and it's the same
guy,
Como be on four or five lines happens
off the Republicans on three lines and
the Democrat.
I think we'll be on probably four lines.
It's a very complicated process.
No.
Is there any effort made or is there any
discussion whatsoever about potentially
moving voting to online and is that
something that you would not fail?
I'm not in New York state right now.
No,
I'm unsure.
Unsure of it.
I love the concept completely.
I do.
The only thing I don't know is it don't
have the technology behind it.
I don't know how safe it is and you
don't know,
but what about banking?
If you can bank online,
that's where all your money goes.
No,
I love the idea I missed.
I don't want to commit without knowing
that the technology,
if we,
New York state is a problem because New
York state throws out everything that is
new.
We've thrown up blockchain.
We don't want to do any open source.
Um,
we throw out a hemp and marijuana.
we were,
we,
we were trying to show the vaping
industry.
I mean,
anything that's new in New York state,
we try to get rid of,
we able to stick with beating up uber
now or taxing uber to pay for the MTA
because the corruption by established
bodies that are a hundred percent New
York state likes old money.
We're really happy with old money.
We do not like new money at all.
Which is another reason why the youth is
leaving.
We are the hardest time getting the UFC
and to New York because of yes,
absolutely.
I had to wait until they're one
politician was arrested.
What was that one guy that went to jail?
New York state.
There's so many at you.
Yeah.
I forget who it was,
but he was corrupt.
He was one of the main reasons that it
was,
they were trying to make an illegal.
Absolutely.
Um,
it's new,
which means by default,
hit it with a stick.
That's how New York thinks.
It's new.
Hit of a stick.
Don't like it.
It's new.
We want old stuff for a place called New
York.
Yes.
It's,
which is why my slogan is a new New
York.
That's the reason why.
My slogan is that because we are right
now an old New York and it's not helping
at all now as part is the Old New York
speaking of,
of the people who are older people are
retiring.
They can't stay in New York state
because it's too expensive,
too expensive.
So they pack up and go to a North
Carolina,
South Carolina,
Florida,
is it taxes?
The real estates?
Both its taxes and it's an opportunity.
It's both of those two things.
Right,
so it's so,
so they decided to head on down in North
Carolina,
South Carolina,
Florida,
Tennessee.
They actually have a name for us in the
Carolinas.
They call us halfbacks.
We went to Florida and halfway back.
That's true.
They call it halfbacks.
That's how many New Yorkers go there.
But he was the worst part.
Go to Florida.
Go,
ah,
this is a mistake.
There we go.
Say,
well,
the sad part here is though Florida
actually has more people than we have
and half of our budget and,
and Scott actually the governor Scott
actually thanked Cuomo for sending all
the people on that because 15% of New
York state's budget is actually
pensions.
And so many people who are pensions are
actually leaving New York state and
going someplace else.
So New York state people are paying for
the pensions and then they're being
spent in other states.
It's terrible idea.
We,
the state is broken.
It is so broken and people are talking
about if you're Democrat,
you're saying everything's still great.
If you're Republican,
you're saying,
well tweak this or tweak that.
I'm saying rebuild from scratch.
There are things you have to change.
You have to change the route so you can
make the branches actually die.
We keep clipping branches,
the weeds to keep growing.
Now we got way off track with this um,
school shooting thing.
And I wanted to get back to it because I
think it's a very complex issue and I
need is,
I don't know what the answer would be.
I think there is no one in town.
Right.
I think you've found problems and these
problems that you're willing to discuss
it.
Very few people are,
are these people are lonely and sad that
it's a public suicide and that they're
on psychotropic drugs?
Absolutely,
and I don't know why you don't think
that other people want to fix it.
I just don't think that they have a
solution that they can discuss that is
not so controversial that it overwhelms
the rest of their messages.
What could be done?
Sure.
I have a couple of answers.
Okay.
The issue is this is an issue that's
been going on literally for decades,
so there is no do this and it's done.
Right.
There are several things.
One of them is fixing education.
The other one is fixing family courts.
Is it two things?
You start slow.
How do you fix education?
Absolutely.
It is a complete reboot right now.
The first thing I'm gonna do with
education is you want to make sure there
is no standardized testing until high
school.
None whatsoever sounded nice.
Testing is bad for several reasons.
Number one,
it's an unfair way of grading teachers,
right?
Teachers are now graded by how their
students do on a standardized test,
which is silly.
That doesn't mean you're a good or a bad
teacher.
Next,
it makes a bunch of kids who are 10 11
1213 years old feel stupid because
they're not good test takers and you
create now a secondary class of student
for absolutely no reason because the
next reason is standardized testing is
no indication of success in life.
You could be a great test taker at 12 or
13 or terrible test taker,
and it does not mean you'll be
successful or not successful in life.
Last is how New York state,
often we'll decide how to fund schools.
So it's a way of funding schools.
That's also unfair.
There's no advantage to standardize
testing except it mean it means the
federal government now begins to control
our schools more.
So when you say the standardized testing
has an,
there's an effect on funding,
does that mean that if a school does
really well,
they get more money?
Yep.
Often.
It's part of a,
a very complex algorithm that New York
state has that almost no one can
actually find.
That seems like it should almost be the
opposite,
that if a school does poorly that they
should put more resources into that
school because it's not being effective
in theory.
That's true.
I'm not sure that's accurate either.
I mean,
we throw about $22,000 per student per
year in New York state and we'll even
than California and it doesn't work.
We have mediocre results at best dollars
isn't the answers.
It's revamping the system.
Right?
Funding is not the answer,
so how do you revamp the system?
There's more parts than that.
First one was just covering of that.
The second thing is we shouldn't even
have k through 12 k through 12 was an
anachronism in shouldn't exist because
the last two years she be k through 10
the last two years of high school for a
huge chunk of people.
Jim,
study hall,
Video Games and probably smoking weed,
just nothing but bad foot.
Too many students just sitting around
doing nothing.
They have no purpose.
There are no community.
They have.
They have no,
no reason to do anything.
They were unhappy.
Right.
Another reason why they're unhappy.
It's not a gross generalization that
they're unhappy and I know thing.
I mean,
there's probably a lot of kids listening
to this that are 16 and 17 they're
working their ass off right now and I
have a section for that future and I
have a solution for them.
That's even better.
I have a solution.
Again,
your limits moving,
right?
First thing is how do I know what I just
said is true,
right?
You just asked that question.
I'll tell you why.
What I just said.
Well,
I know it's true because for the vast
majority of students going to college
now,
the First Year of college is 13th grade
because they're not ready for school
because the last two years didn't
prepare them for college.
If it did,
we wouldn't require 13th grade,
I don't know.
It's 13th grade.
The adverse that now take six years to
graduate college,
so the results show me that I'm correct.
Right?
The results of what's happening and
here's the worst part.
Now we shift these kids off to college.
Who many of them don't even want to go
to college.
So we sent him anyway.
It takes them six years to graduate.
The 24 years old with at least 50 k in
debt,
if not more,
minimum decay.
Some a hundred k something,
200 k depending what it is.
And now there's no job for what they
want to do.
And now they're working at starbucks.
Wow.
What a disaster that is.
We wonder why our kids coming back home.
So how about this,
since that at 10th grade,
take a test.
You pass the test,
you get diploma with you,
a home school,
private school,
Public School,
diplomas,
yours.
Awesome.
Now you have five choices and this is
exactly to your point.
You have five choices.
Choice number one,
you're a kid who's hardcore.
You think that college is your answer?
Good.
Go to to get prep school.
Imagine that kid who right now you just
had is busting his ass.
He could be in,
in a prep school of his choice and,
and the people in that prep school are
all kids who want to be in that prep
school.
It would change his entire situation.
No more knucklehead who don't want to be
there,
who are forced to be there,
who will cut in class.
The kids would be,
there are those who want to be there,
the teachers and this,
no disciplinary issues.
They have more kids who want to be there
better for them.
They could hustle better now they're
ready for college.
When they get there,
they take advantage of incubators of,
of internships,
maybe even graduate in three years now.
The Rock and roll them less debt.
Better off life is good.
Better services,
better everything for less money.
I'm not done.
You're not that kid.
You're the kid who is super smart human.
Become a scientist.
You want to be,
get a phd.
Awesome.
Go right to an associate's degree.
Start right away.
16,
17,
18 your degree because you're that good.
Take your sats.
You're that smart.
You're Einstein.
Awesome.
Go do that.
Not,
you know,
one of those things.
No worries.
Could Trade School,
uh,
become a plumber or a carpenter,
Mason,
whatever the case.
Let me go do it.
New York state desperately needs
tradesmen desperately.
The average trade's person in New York
states about 50 years old.
Too old for an average should be 30
something for an average 35 and before
an average it's too high,
which means we have a lot of trades,
jobs that are not filled and a lot of
foreign labor that has to come to New
York state,
right in New York or kids aren't doing
it.
Why we've been told a lie and that lie
is the only way to success.
The only way is to do well in high
school.
Get a great for you degree and go get a
job and sit behind a computer all day.
That's a lie.
That is a way to success.
It is not the only way to success.
There are a lot of kids now,
and I'm sure you know people like this
who they spent the first five,
10 years of her life trying to make it
that way,
struggling through school.
Then at 28 years old they go,
it's going to build houses,
man.
The nigga build the house or that's what
I make.
It's going to be a computer guy and they
just make apps.
He's gonna do something.
Want to do.
They should have been doing that at 18
I'm still not done.
Most people though,
they don't know what they want to do.
This is a part and I get that.
The time don't have a passion.
They don't have a direction and they're
confused.
Yes.
I,
this is one of my biggest complaints I
got about this plan.
Right.
Because of the two ideas are cause he'll
get a job,
right.
Just go work or start a business.
And what you just said is what I get all
the time.
But Larry,
they're 16 they don't,
they're doing good.
Make Your mistake at 16 not 26 we're
making mistakes at 26 we have people who
are lost at 26 we have a generation now.
If you ask the people in their twenties
right now across this,
across this nation,
and you say,
do you feel like an adult over half will
say no over half,
say no 40 year olds also the not as
much,
but yes.
But not as much though.
It probably would be over half.
It won't be over half.
Okay.
You go to your 20,
somethings over,
half will say,
no,
I don't feel like an adult.
Right,
because they're making the same mistakes
that many people may 18,
1916 they're not making a 25,
26,
28 this was also not a rights of passage
things though thing that actually
happens.
This would actually be that.
They'd have to make that choice at 16
but here's the issue.
How do I pay for,
and this covers the entire sheet of what
you're talking about it.
That's the next question I get.
How you paid for it.
New York state says,
I have to pay for a full 12 years of
school.
Have to pay for it.
It's pay for it.
No worries.
I was a marine.
When I got in Marine Corps,
I got a Gi bill x dollars,
I think it was $100,000.
I forgot what it was back then.
This was in the 90s.
Um,
I think at $100,000,
like 10 years to use it,
we're going to give all of our kids
$20,000 and five years to use it.
They don't get the physical check,
but the state will pay a check to
whatever school they want to go to for
$20,000.
They have five years to use it.
Where does that mean?
You can at 16 slow experimenting.
You can say,
you know what?
I know college is for me.
I'm gonna go to prep school.
Here's what I promise you.
I promise you this,
the,
but any amount of money you want,
promise you this.
As soon as this comes into play,
you will find tons of all of a sudden
prep schools and trade schools the pop
up and guess how much they're going to
cost for two years,
$20,000 that's going to be a tuition.
You might say,
well,
wow.
[inaudible] a lot of money.
It isn't.
We're paying $44,000 now.
If each of those kids,
we're saving $24,000 per kid and giving
them better schooling,
more accurate actual choices,
they can learn something.
They make their mistakes at 1617 which
is way better than 26 or 27 and maybe
they figure out they want to do well.
Why is it so cheap?
Why are you going to be able to do that
for $20,000 when it costs so much more
now?
What's going to be different that people
can be choosing,
right?
Yeah,
so the people that are educating these
people,
yeah.
How are they going to get paid?
Oh,
where's the money gonna come from?
Great question.
Now,
a couple of things.
Remember teachers ask me all the time,
they say,
Larry,
how are you going to help us?
Here's what I tell you.
I'm going to get rid of a bunch of your
administrators in New York state.
We actually have school districts that
have more administrators than teachers.
What?
Yes,
that's correct.
Do you want homework?
What's the value of having
administrators?
Because you have to check boxes for
government.
You have to check boxes for coming.
Did you do x that you do?
Why did you do z?
These administers required,
that's what's going on.
That's correct.
There's,
there's about $60 billion in our budget.
New York state for education,
give or take about 4 billion comes from
the federal government.
About 35 billion comes from the state
and about 20 billion comes locally,
give or take it to it.
These are round numbers and they change
yearly depending on,
on,
on who you talked about.
It's about that.
Once we get rid of the federal
government,
being involved in,
in the,
uh,
in New York state for being [inaudible]
goes away.
People get afraid.
Oh my God,
we lose that money.
Good,
good.
Let it go away because all of the
ministers go away.
Also,
if you can give her a three,
four,
five,
six administrators for every one or two
teachers,
oh my God,
I'm not good nutritional educator,
but I would imagine that if I was a,
I would be upset at this.
I would say that there's a reason why
those administrators are there and we
need them to take some of the
administrative weight off of the
teachers.
The teachers are stressed out enough by
teaching students,
they don't have the time to be taken
care of.
All the formalities and the things that
these administrators too.
Um,
I have never heard that ever because
that's not true.
You're the first person that ever said
to me ever in over a year of me doing
this.
So,
and the reason is those with you?
No,
no,
no.
Not every teacher said,
I never heard it.
You never heard it.
Talked to a lot of,
lots of them.
Dozens of them does.
What did they say about administrating?
They say awesome.
Not In those words,
but yes,
because most of those administrators are
actually administrating teachers that
teach,
tell them how to teach,
what to teach,
when to teach,
grading them.
Even if they don't,
who will the parents?
Well,
the parents will,
yes.
You think the parents have the time or
the understanding of what an education
should comprise of to be able to direct
not just their,
their student,
what their child needs,
but you know,
a group of 50 or however large the
class.
Great question.
And generally speaking?
Probably not.
But teachers do.
Teachers too.
They're going to self police.
There'll be some administrators.
You're,
you're assuming that I'm going to get
rid of all administrators?
No,
no,
I'm not.
I'm not saying that.
I'm saying,
but you're definitely saying you went to
school though.
Hold on.
You went to school.
Do you remember how many vice principals
that were any of your schools you
remember?
No,
I don't.
Probably two or three that was normal
and met most schools when I was his
goal.
Often it was two or three.
I don't remember.
Now there's 12 1210 40 why?
Why is that?
Because their administrators and they're
making sure other things,
they're making sure boxes are checked.
So here's your alternative.
You're alternative is keep funding a
broken system and be afraid,
which is what you're saying.
No,
I'm not saying you're saying,
you're saying teachers will be afraid
because I'm afraid.
Yeah,
because then Hio Frey who educated our
kids.
No,
no.
Overwhelmed.
Okay.
Fear of,
of being overwhelmed.
Not just,
not just that,
but also like having a mandate,
like having,
Yup,
a very strict,
I'm with you.
Curriculum.
Yes.
See she's children and that is nothing
but a bad thing.
I'm going to give you real fast if you
don't mind.
Let me give you a list of all the time
centralized control has worked.
Finished centralized control doesn't
work in in education meaning what?
In anything when a centralized control
and make things better defined,
centralized control,
a strict mandate from Albany,
a strict mandate from DC.
I'll ask you a question.
I'm,
I'm assuming you're old enough that you
were in school at one point at 1980 or
older.
Oh yeah.
Or before I was,
yes.
Prior to 1980 basically the partner of
education didn't really exist as it does
now.
It did exist,
but it was basically as a repository for
information.
It didn't really do anything and I
didn't have any power since that's an 80
began to have power.
Do this and we'll give you money.
Don't do this.
We don't give you money.
Here are your rules.
Follow them up.
We punish you that that's what they are
now.
You learn to read and write.
You learn to function in society,
so die somehow.
Every American prior 1980 when the
school learn how to read and write,
learn how to function in society.
Somehow it worked.
Do I trust the administrator or a
teacher?
I would rather trust the teacher.
Now does that mean they'd be no
ministers?
Of course then there'll be a minister.
Of course they will be.
There'll be still principles and things
of that sort of course.
But the differences,
an administrator cares about checking a
box,
check a box.
Your cigarettes aren't better off
because boxes are checked.
You said it's a better off because these
students are getting better and because
the parents are happier.
Right,
but when you're saying boxes being
checked,
that means things being covered that
they feel the signet for a standardized
test.
Yes.
You two said that they feel
significance,
correct?
Yes.
Well,
that's someone,
I mean I would assume,
I don't know how curriculums are set up,
but I would imagine that people get
together and they decide that children
need to have a certain amount of
ability.
Yup.
And with grammar.
Yes.
Certain amount of understanding of
mathematics.
Yes,
I would agree.
Yes.
Who's going to do that?
How about
teachers and the local administrators
and how about the local PTA?
What's wrong?
So less administrators,
an elimination of administered.
I never said that,
so I didn't say you did,
but how do we decide how many
administrators are necessary and how
many can you cut out?
How much money can you save this and
this is even better.
You know that you're going to love my
libertarian ways on this one.
Right now what happens is there is a
convoluted way of deciding house.
What a convoluted way I thought he said
come loaded.
Did you hear that?
It could be,
but no,
I don't think it alluded and convoluted
way.
Like this is a new word and I don't
think it should be used.
Is that,
is that new?
No,
not convoluted.
The other ones I'm loaded.
I was like,
this is,
I'm sure as a fetish there somewhere.
I'm sure there is.
I just haven't heard of me there.
See you.
You're ready to go now.
So there's a calm that a way of actually
of funding these schools.
I don't want that.
I want to be very simple.
I want a flat fee to come from the state
here,
district,
depending on how many kids you have,
here's your money.
What does that mean?
Well,
the reality of it is there are about,
if I'm not mistaken,
about 700 school districts in New York
state.
A lot.
That's a lot.
It is a lot.
And so what happens now is there's your
money.
Most of them are going to make no
changes because they're gonna be afraid.
But it's like anything else.
There'll be early adopters and early
adopters are going to say,
wait a minute.
So the federal government isn't going to
do this.
The state government isn't telling us to
do that.
So we can change some things here.
So when you say,
here's your money,
they're going to get less money than
they're getting now.
It depends.
It depends on the school district.
So we'll somewhat there.
It's not like you'll have less jobs
there.
They're going to have to decide whether
or not minnis traitors.
You got it.
Exactly right.
Yes.
And you're saying,
oh my God,
that's scary.
Some of our school districts will fail.
Yes.
But in New York state,
they're all failing now.
So I don't care.
But the trailers in mass right now,
I'm okay,
let me finish.
Please go.
I don't want government to be what you
always hear,
which is,
you know,
elections have consequences.
So I,
when I now get to impose my will upon
all of you,
cause I won.
So what I say goes,
I'm supposed to know everything,
be everything,
create boards and make things happen.
I instead want to be the guy who when
you have trouble,
I can help.
So as school districts begin to have
trouble,
I will without question try to help
them.
Of course I wrote,
but there's 700 that's correct.
How would you have time to do that?
I won't personally.
I'll have people who would have,
right now there's already an
infrastructure to handle that already.
I don't have to create a new one already
exists,
but right now it's just,
it's making up reasons to punish people.
I don't want it to make it reasons to
punish people.
I want instead to say,
okay,
this school district is lost.
How do we help?
I only have one string attached to the
money.
I give only one,
and that is transparency.
As I told you before,
I'm a business guy and here's what I
know.
This is an actual equation that works
every single time.
Very simple,
simple equation,
personal freedom plus transparency,
plus accountability equals innovation.
If we do that,
the other doctors will come on.
They will find great ways of making
things work.
They will get rid of some
administrators,
they will get rid of some teachers,
they will hire new ones.
They will decide which one should be
given raises.
That will happen.
Okay,
those after you there,
please go ahead.
Because what you're saying may work in
the world of business because people
have incentive to succeed in business
and that extensive is monetary success
when he always monetary,
but yes.
Okay.
Not always,
but for the most part.
Yep,
sure.
When you're talking about a school,
yes.
And you cut the funding for the school
and say,
Hey,
figure it out.
You guys decide how many administrators
you want to keep art.
The administrators',
essentially the bosses,
aren't they the ones who are in control?
I mean they're not going to get rid of
their own jobs,
so what are they going to do?
You're going to pay the teachers last
and they going to get an inferior
teachers and it's a great question.
Ramp up their,
their control of the,
of the cashflow because they realize
that there's less of it.
It is a,
it's a great question and here's the
issue.
It's not going to happen overnight.
It's not like I went in November and go,
great.
All the money's gone to how it works.
I went in November.
People know what the plan is.
We start talking about it already.
We start bringing parents on board.
We said,
coming up with plans already,
the plans,
it's like,
uh,
it's like any other organization.
You're saying business.
I'm like,
oh,
this works in military.
This works in,
this works in business.
It doesn't matter.
Works and everything.
What's your family?
It doesn't matter if you knew that six
months from now you're going to have a
sniff and decrease in your income.
You would start to make change.
Typically,
if there was someone above you saying,
hey joe,
you're going to have a decrease in your
income.
How do we make this work?
What can we do?
If someone's there to guide you and you
already have infrastructure there,
you'll begin to fix it.
My fear would be that they would have
less teachers and then we have larger
classes.
Totally possible administrators because
they're in control.
People don't like to give up control and
control.
Well,
who's actually in control with the PTA?
Right?
The parent teachers association can and
have a lot to heat to the board to sign
boards would decide,
but they would have to agree with you.
Yes.
They want to get rid of administrators
and if they didn't universally,
if they didn't universally across the
board in this fails miserably and then
classes get larger and then kids get
less attention.
Yup,
and then the already Piss poor education
system sinks further into the abyss and
we have two choices.
Number one,
we can be afraid of that and stay a
hostage to a terrible system that's not
working as failing our kids and making
us in happiness.
Jordan estate.
That's option one or option to do that
and just watch over it.
Right.
Understanding that that could happen
because those were the only two options.
These other options.
The other option is yes,
funded more.
Ooh,
fuck a bad system.
Boom.
No.
Why is that?
If you had a 10 what's,
what's wrong with the system?
Let's go over that.
I just told you.
I don't know,
but no,
but I mean in terms of like how much
money are they making,
right,
and what would increasing that amount of
money enhance.
Okay.
Two things.
Remember the first thing is there's no
way in the world that a governor
should be deciding what every teacher
makes an estate.
Okay.
That's just philosophically wrong,
so I'm never going to do that.
That is simply philosophically wrong.
It's against who I am.
Centralize,
centralize.
Control was a bad idea.
Localized control is always a better
idea for,
so that's so that that premise,
I'm never going to even touch that.
What I'm trying to achieve here is to
make change.
I know that locally there will be people
who do it right because that always
happens.
That's just how it works.
You will see out of seven districts,
some of it decide to to,
you know,
get together and,
and,
and mix this together.
Some will decide not to.
Some will do different things.
You'll see it happen.
My point is this is a major overhaul.
I get it,
right?
Businesses there all the time.
Families do all the time.
If you're able to watch it,
I don't want to be the mother or the
father,
right?
Democrats won't be your mother.
They wouldn't to give you everything,
going to be a father and protect you
from everything.
I wonder,
your brother,
let me to get you love.
You don't want to live with them,
but you love him and when you need a
ride to the airport,
he's there for you and with the
firefighter,
the guy who comes to help when you need
me.
Now you're saying,
but Larry is good.
This will fail.
Yes.
I want them saying,
well,
okay,
some might fail.
That's you're saying some,
some.
I'm not even saying they might fail.
What I'm saying is that you're going to
put them in a compromised situation.
Yes.
You're going to give them less money and
you're going to say figure it out.
Yes,
but not just see.
You're assuming that it's just here's
money.
Good luck.
No,
here's less money.
Yes.
He's less money.
I think you have too many
administrators.
Yup.
And let's talk this out over a series of
several months.
When you talk to professional educators,
do they agree that they have too many
administrators do money?
Yes.
So far everything's your,
I've met everyone,
but they agree they do well with less
money if they didn't have to.
Miniaturize is yes.
And how much less money are we talking
about?
I'm not sure to be fair with you.
Not sure yet.
This is the one show you that you feel
like the way to fix the education system
is the cut funding that would like for
people like me who are on the outside,
you hear that and you go,
Ooh,
I already feel like teachers are
underappreciated.
And probably because of that unmotivated
because you decided to say the answer is
cut funding.
It's not what I saw on,
no,
no.
When I started this of what you were
saying.
Yup.
Regardless of what you're saying.
What I'm saying is currently,
Yup.
Even in California,
forget about New York.
Yup.
I feel like teachers are
underappreciated.
I would agree with that and I feel like
it's a noble profession that's
incredibly valuable and the people
should be able to make a decent living.
Agreed.
I don't know how.
The solution to that is to give less
money to the school.
You're missing a very valid,
very important point.
If you ask most teachers whether
underappreciated,
most of them,
they're not going to say that people
like you and I don't appreciate them,
they're going to say,
the system doesn't appreciate me.
That's why they're always fighting the
system.
Oklahoma,
they fought the system.
They always fighting the system.
What I'm saying is fix the system.
The system is heavily controlled in many
cases by the federal government.
$4 billion worth,
so we have to lose $4 billion unless we,
unless we want to keep the federal
government in our system,
but you don't want that.
Your fix is to let them figure it out.
Get the federal government out.
Hold on,
let them figure it out with less money.
I have to,
I have to push back here.
Okay.
You,
you keep saying,
let him figure it out as if I'm just
going to walk away and say,
oh well good luck.
I hope I'm going to go off and now you
know,
hang out in Puerto Rico for a while.
No,
I'm saying I'm gonna facilitate it
because you know what I do.
I trust teachers more than twice
administrators.
I trust the local people that if I give
them the right tools,
they'll do the right thing,
but more importantly they'll show others
as also transparent.
What's going to happen is they're going
to figure out the right way to deal with
teachers.
Should should school district one hire
more Spanish teachers versus going stick
to,
I don't know.
I'm not supposed to know that,
but they do and if they make a mistake
then they'll fix it.
And then other counties,
are you talking about the teachers
themselves or are you talking about
these administrators who you want to
eliminate?
I'm talking about the school boards,
the school board.
The school boards are going to be the
ones with the,
with the PTA.
If we make this work the right way,
it will be everyone talking together.
It will be school boards talking to
administrators,
talking to teachers,
talk with parents.
I don't want schools graded beat by
standardized tests.
We've been doing that for years and we
have very,
very unhappy people.
Unhappy Students,
unhappy parents.
I want parents to be happier.
I want students to be happier and you
might say,
but then Larry,
they won't learn certain things.
Is that a horrible thing?
I'd rather than be happy than learn ap
chemistry.
Yes.
If that means one school decides that ap
chemistry isn't that important in a
school district,
it's fine.
Those kids will learn it in the prep
school and some kids won't learn ap
chemistry.
If that makes your school district
happy,
I'm okay with that because it goes to
the next level,
which of course becomes kids with
special needs.
You have a special needs kid.
How do you make that kid happy?
How do you decide whether a kid kids
successful or not?
The standardized testing doesn't work.
What do you do?
These are doing check boxes.
Does that work?
Of course.
That's why you literally have hundreds
of parents every single year,
so in New York state,
because they were unhappy with their
kids getting services but not getting
better.
I want your kid getting better.
You're assuming that because the federal
government puts these standards in it
that makes them good or bad.
It doesn't.
If anything,
it makes them worse.
If kids,
if my kids are happy,
that's what I want.
Happy New Yorkers means they stay in New
York.
Happy New Yorkers means they grow their
businesses in New York.
Keep their families in there.
I get that,
but saying happy and saying that
solution and the key to happiness is
funding them less and getting rid of
administering goggling the Democrat Joe,
I'm the Democrat.
Yes you are.
Thank God you are so a Democrat.
How am I a democrat?
You got [inaudible] being the world's
ending less funding means the world's
anymore.
People that hear that you're going to
take money away from school.
The person who only hears that.
If the person says all he's going to do
is get rid of money from schools,
that's that person's never going to vote
for me.
That person's probably a democrat.
That problem's person's going to vote
for Cuomo and that's fine.
I'm not gonna win everybody.
I can't win everybody,
but I'm going to change a system that is
completely broken.
If you say this,
what you're talking about people talk
about with the MTA also in New York
City,
the MTA,
you got to keep funding the MTA.
I'm not going to be hostage to a shit
system,
period.
I don't care.
I'm not going to be hostage to a shit
system.
This is a terrible system that is
failing New Yorkers.
That is failing people in New York City.
When it comes to the MTA,
that's fairly big state.
That's mass transit.
I'm sorry.
Yes.
If those of you are not in New York,
it's a bad system.
I'm not going to be a hostile because of
fear.
No,
I will fight my jailer period and my
Jello is a system that is broken that
says if you,
if you,
you better give me more money.
Otherwise it'll happen.
You better give me more money.
Otherwise it will happen.
No,
no,
I'm going to fix that system.
I'm going to help facilitate fixing that
system.
Am I just to let them go away?
I'm not saying that.
What I'm saying is I'm going to help
facilitate that system and to do that we
can lose $4 billion and we'll get over
that.
We'll fix that,
we'll make it happen.
We'll make it work so by,
and if you get more people into this
state,
and this is the most important piece,
you can raise money through other ways
and just raising taxes on people and
this is the most critical piece when we
hear funding,
and this is why I'm,
I was teasing you in Konya Democrat
because we need to about funding.
You're talking about more taxes.
I'm not talking about that.
If you get more people to stay in New
York state,
you raise your revenue without having to
raise taxes on anybody.
But if you raise your revenue,
we're going to put more revenue into the
schools of course,
to be more people in the schools.
More reverent.
Yes,
absolutely.
Your money in the school,
there'll be more people in the schools
and more Morton.
Of course we would if we could.
Re of course we would.
Of course,
New York state has $170 billion budget
with about a $4 billion deficit and $300
billion in debt,
and the answer for every Democrat or
Republican is more funding.
There's going to be nothing left.
This state is going to go different.
It's gonna go.
It's going to,
it's going to go under in 10 years.
How do you get more people to come to
the stair right first thing by having a
really super court cases,
and I talked about super cool education
that'll get people to come back.
Are you going to hire someone to create
this super cool education system?
Are you going to let these teachers
figured it out on their own?
If we need teachers,
build me a super cool education system
so that we get more fun.
I already have the,
I already have the infrastructure for
the super cool system.
I just told you,
I've already told you what that,
what the instructor is done.
The concept or at a skeleton is already
there.
Now,
once I win in November,
we begin to build it out and yes,
it will be me and other people be clear.
It's not like New York doesn't have
enough.
New York's doesn't have enough workers.
We have tons of workers that we can
absolutely use to make this happen.
Tons of them that if I'm not mistaken,
the New York state has the most by
percentage,
uh,
government employees I think.
And I think in the nation,
I know we are the most unionized,
but I think we're the most,
uh,
government employees by percentage.
You're going to move their jobs.
Sure.
Love it.
Yes,
let's do that.
Love the idea.
You're asking details that are simple to
fix when the time comes and simple to
fix.
So you're going to take people out of
what professions move them
into fixing.
I actually it beside it for every person
in New York state where they're going to
do.
I don't know.
That's why I'm asking.
Of course not you.
This is a,
you're doing it like a show now.
I'm not doing a show.
Do you?
You're a democrat.
Look at you.
I'm not.
I'm giving,
I'm just asking you a real clean
questions here.
You four times said you're going to take
money away,
but you are right.
Yes.
You've said like four times because you
going on about these other things,
which is what matters more than losing
$4 billion from education.
Right?
But I just want to be clear about what
you're saying about what the actual
going to fix this system by creating a
good skeleton off the bat that people
are going to enjoy and like,
and then once I went in November,
we're going to fill that skeleton up to
make an amazing school system that
people can be proud of.
They're going to want to bring their
people,
they're gonna come back from North
Carolina that had come back from
Tennessee.
They're going to move from,
from Pennsylvania and Massachusetts and
want to be part of their system.
They're going to see schools that
actually work well.
They're going to see prep schools,
get kids into college.
They're going to see colleges that
actually educate kids and get them into
jobs.
When they see that happened,
that all start coming.
That's going to happen.
It doesn't happen by me saying,
how do I fund this?
being afraid of making a step.
You don't have to have the perfect plan
to move forward.
No plan is perfect anyway.
You want a good solid plan with
motivated people.
If you have motivated people to take up
a plan,
it'll wind up being successful again,
it's how it works.
So this grandiose plan is I like,
you're going to get rid of the last two
years of high school and you're going to
offer potential prep school for children
and you're going to,
for other kids,
offer them trade schools,
schools.
Sure you're going to get rid of $4
billion in federal funding.
You're going to let the schools figure
out how many administrators they should
have with help with help,
with help,
and who wants to help,
who are you going to hire it?
Oversee this whole thing.
We'll figure it out.
You figure that out.
Look,
I'm two months from the election away
from the election and then at least six
months reputation,
right?
At least if I met,
that's probably low,
but mark nine put anytime this is,
this is something to play until next
September,
right?
At earliest.
Right.
The earliest thing coming to play is
next September.
I hope it's that fast.
That'd be amazing.
I hope it is that fast,
but it isn't five minutes.
It's like up.
I'm not doing this so I can become king.
We already have a king and that's why
we're in trouble.
Right?
Right.
I want to give localized control many
more options.
I'm a,
I'm the crazy guy who actually means
what he says.
When I say let teachers teach,
I actually mean that most people say it
and then they and their response then
becomes give more administrators.
So you think what's stopping them now?
Standardized tests and administrators
and then funding.
That's based on the success of the test.
That's correct.
In the school district it's correct.
The answer is always more funding.
The is always more funding
and it isn't.
It is not that people always say we have
to fund fund fund.
That is not the answer there.
There are better answers out there.
Of course there are.
My main done,
let me go to the,
to another piece on how to raise money.
Okay.
The first thing is of course,
as I mentioned,
get more people.
If more people show up to the state,
New York state could,
in theory,
and this is theory,
easily hold 30 million people if they
the state could.
It's possible how many done the city?
Seven is about eight and a half in a
city to say right now,
but I didn't happen to see right now,
but that's a lot.
It is a lot.
It's the largest city in the country by
far.
It's,
it's over double a Los Angeles,
Los Angeles,
about three and a half,
not mistaken.
Went down sort of La.
There's no end to it.
Yes.
Well,
if about LSD,
look at the metro area of,
of New York state,
and New York City's had 16 million metro
areas,
60 million.
The actual city itself is a half.
So it's,
it's by far the largest city in the,
uh,
in the nation.
So yes.
So it could in theory,
take 30 million people.
It's possible if we get that amount of
people,
oh my God,
the,
the tax revenue would be insane.
Right?
But you can get people to move to New
York state by having a better state.
And one of the things I mentioned was
education,
but there are several other things you
can do.
First of all,
why aren't we supporting small
businesses?
And we don't know is that we punish
them,
right?
We punish them.
But with licensing,
we punished him.
In New York state,
there's actually a licensed to braid
hair.
There's a license to walk a dog.
There's all kind of license.
The license to walk her dog.
Correct?
Yes.
It's involved in that.
I don't know.
I'm not a dog walker.
No,
no.
There should be none here.
Here's my rule and licensing.
I got a good,
nice,
good general rule.
Would you ask your friend to do it?
If you were a,
a a woman who had lots of long hair,
would you ask your friend to braid your
hair?
You probably would when you probably,
Yep.
Probably would.
If you had a dog and if you have a dog,
but assuming you have a dog,
would you ask your friend to walk your
dog?
Sure,
sure.
Of course you would.
Why is their license for that?
Would you ask your friend to remove your
appendix?
But I think the idea would be that you
wouldn't want someone to screw it up,
so we'd want to make sure someone has
insurance so that the consumer doesn't
get ripped off.
Yes.
But the,
the appendix and you wouldn't let them.
Yeah.
Good license for that.
I'm fine.
Right.
Get a license for that.
But your point's a valid one.
How about instead?
There's a difference between licensing
and what you just said,
which is insurance difference.
Licensing says the government decides if
you can or can't do it and if you don't,
the government will find you and or jail
you.
That's a license.
So you don't have to have hair braiding
insurance or dog walker insurance.
You might want to have insurance.
I didn't say that.
I said license.
There is a difference.
Right?
The assumption is,
and you've made it by make that step.
You made the assumption which is
licensing is for safety.
It is not that.
It's full control.
It's all it's for.
The example I'll give you is vaping in
New York state,
many calories you have to have a license
for vaping.
So what does it likes his intestines to
sell?
Yes.
To sell that.
A vaping store?
Yes.
Have that because have to have a
license.
They have a vaping store similar to that
of having a tobacco store similar.
Right,
right.
They do that.
So you might say,
well,
vaping a licensed,
it's grades for safety.
Right?
Well does the person who has done the
vaping shit thought maybe,
I don't know,
learn CPR or understand the effects of
nicotine in the body?
No.
They have to write a check if a lot of
form.
That's it.
There's no safety involved that the
license is approved for license.
That's correct.
They can't be a felon with a history of
fraud.
I'm not sure if that's even the case in
[inaudible] the main thing,
I don't think that's true.
I think in vaping that's not true.
In certain cases there are.
That's true in certain,
but this is one tobacco controlled
substance.
It is.
So I would assume that they do have to
have a license based on not being a
felon for tobacco prep until about
vaping.
Vaping is,
no,
it is not.
It's not.
No,
not at all.
Not Tobacco,
right.
Some is.
Some is not.
So the stuffing is basically a is
though.
Isn't that a controlled substance?
No.
No,
no.
Nicotine.
I don't think it is.
Hmm.
Tobacco was,
I know that's hilarious.
If tobacco itself is the point,
active ingredient isn't.
The point of all of this is why is any
of it controlled and why is vaping
controlled?
If you're talking about safety and this,
let me go to safety.
I'm glad you brought this up.
Safety.
Everyone will tell me.
W W will tell me,
well,
licensing is for safety.
Regulations is a for safety.
They're not.
They're not,
they're not.
And then I'll give you the best example
I can give you.
Health food stores,
the healthiest people you know shop at
health food stores.
There is almost one is a health food
store.
It's a store like a store where you
might go and buy vitamins that are not,
that,
that's not GNC or store where you might
go and purchase organic things.
That's not a regular food.
Not a whole foods.
Whole foods is similar,
but the mom and pop health food store,
which generally speaking is usually
privately owned.
Usually it's kind of his thing from the
past,
isn't it?
Health food store.
Yeah.
I say that because most people
understand what I mean when I say that,
but if you did not,
I apologize.
But most people do understand.
When I say hopefully,
I mean basically a local store that was
some things like vitamins and it will
sell things like supplements.
It'll be,
it's like a GNC is often,
often it's a mix of like a GNC and
grocery store,
usually owned by an individual,
but not always our family,
but then kind of store.
Those stores are almost not regulated at
all.
I mean probably 90% of their products
have no FDA approval because of there's
no FDA approved for supplements.
Correct.
So there's just a stamp that says not
approved by FDA.
Right.
Most of their products are um,
most of their,
their,
their products are just out there.
Where are all the deaths from health
food stores?
There aren't what health,
food stores have our standards,
lots of standards,
tons of standards.
Now some people buy certain products
because they believe in them.
Some people buy certain bras because
they believe in the brand name up to
them.
Some maybe go to certain stores that
trust those stores.
It's fine.
It happens all time.
It's just,
it's a standard.
What would happen if,
say there was a health food store or
even a GNC or any place like that and
there was a supplement that if he took
that supplement and uh,
most people who took it will get
addicted and do crazy things.
And that came out to the news.
Look,
here it is.
If you take xyz product,
you'll probably go crazy or do something
not so whatever happened,
they removed them.
You know,
things like that's correct.
Fuel those away.
Yes,
that's exactly my point.
To kill you.
Thank you.
It goes away.
There's actually repercussions and it
goes away.
Right,
and maybe there's a lawsuit,
maybe not,
but it goes away.
What if it's FDA approved?
Nothing happens.
80% of all of our addicts,
FDA approved drugs,
nothing happens.
When it's a government monopoly from by
a government regulatory body,
there's no repercussions.
It just keeps killing us.
Well,
that's certainly still feel
pharmaceutical interest.
Yes.
Slowly.
It just keeps killing us on and on and
on and on.
If you want things to be safe,
then let's focus on safety.
Not Focus on control,
so I want products to be safe,
not controlled.
Controlled is useless,
so make them safe.
They're safe.
I'll use a health food store examples,
for example,
how about competing standards?
Standards that are competing.
I don't have a problem with the
government saying these are the
standards we believe have the
appropriate standards to be safe.
They should do that.
Absolutely.
A practice is a choice.
Take the stamp or not.
The the only exception is why they
punishing you.
If you choose not to see what it does.
It's of innovation with government
stamps.
Not at all,
but it has to be something that is
voluntary.
It's correct.
The person who owns the store and buy
the consumer.
Now,
how do what my example I give is this
water?
I would probably has it.
Yes,
it does.
It has that circle you the circle.
You.
Do you know what that means?
No.
It's the Orthodox Union,
right?
I'm live in New York.
City's a very high Jewish population,
New York City.
I'm in a Jewish friends,
and the Orthodox Union means it's a
kosher product.
Oh,
so their water's kosher.
This water's kosher?
Yes.
How does it become kosher to bless
blessing.
There's the issue.
I don't know the circle you on it.
You know?
So if,
if you're Jewish and you care about
keeping a kosher household,
you would buy this product because you
trust the circle.
You.
Is this kosher?
I don't know.
But the person that buys it believes it
and buys it.
And what if they found out this was the
water was not kosher then that'd be a
problem.
That'd be it.
Then there'd be some kind of backlash.
Well,
as a person who is a partner in a
supplement company and also someone who
works for the UFC who hasn't,
the UFC has giant issues with people
taking tinted supplement.
Sure.
There's third party independent
verification,
third independent testing.
Absolutely.
Really good supplement companies like on
it and many others use where you can
find out that you don't have tainted
supplement.
Absolutely.
I'd rather have that than how about we
had those stamps on.
Products are like that.
Yes,
I had the stamps and if you have a
government that have that and guess
what,
maybe you want 4 cents,
maybe want the government stamp plus
third party stamp plus authoritarian
stamp.
Well what I liked was the side business
does third party independent company
absolutely has their own personal
standards and you know when there
are really good company you can rely
upon them.
Yes.
And if you don't,
you could have competing standard
multiple companies because you trust one
company more than the other or you want
both.
Is that possible solution for education,
a third party,
independent verification of the
education system.
We've been here for what about an hour
or so?
And you already gave a good idea.
Yes,
exactly.
My point.
That seems like a good idea to me.
There we go.
Yeah,
there should be some effective school
system that works and then they take the
people that run that effective of school
system and they have a curriculum and a
way of doing things that they could
perhaps uh,
you know,
teach other other school systems.
That's the idea of transparency and
accountability.
That's the whole point.
So this is the deal with people that are
libertarian,
right?
The idea is that you are a free market
person and that you believe in the free
market and you believe in less
government.
I believe in the consumer,
right?
I believe in the consumer.
And then Jennifer,
the pool and things are consumer driven.
And this is not hundred percent role.
Government isn't always wrong.
It's often wrong.
But not always.
Right,
and the consumer isn't always right,
but often,
right.
So as a general role,
consumers tend to drive things better.
Like as I said,
kosher water like supplements.
If you don't allow the consumer to
decide,
you by default stifle innovation,
you just stifle innovation.
You stifle everything new because if it
can't get through the FDA that it can't,
it almost can't be done.
And you have centralized control that's
very difficult to get past.
You got it.
Exactly right.
Or not really motivated to improve or to
no end to the opposite.
They're,
they're actually incentivized to make
sure nothing goes wrong.
So always err on the side of no,
no.
It becomes the rule of no one meaning
everything is about,
no,
there's no one's job to make it work.
This is my point on the education
system.
The job there has to be someone who's,
who says,
we have to make this thing work.
I'm the guy who says that I want to make
it work.
Let's make this thing work.
Let's just not make sure things go bad.
Let's make sure that things actually
work.
Now,
you obviously know far more about New
York politics than I do.
I know very little about it,
but one thing that I do know is it's
almost universally regarded as being
insanely corrupt.
True.
You get to a position where you become
the governor.
Yup.
How do you clean up that fucking
hornets?
Yes.
The one thing people always say is,
Lara,
you got to clean it up.
Like you just said.
It's funny you use that.
I think I hear all the time.
You got to get these guys in jail.
You got to punish them.
Whatever I ran,
we talk about that and the reason is,
okay,
you put some guy in jail,
you punish him.
Whatever the case may be.
Great.
Who's family came back from North
Carolina?
Who's kick I that education?
Who got a better job?
Whose taxes went down?
Who's happier,
whose business didn't go under?
No one's helped by people going to jail.
We feel righteous and then we pack up
and move to North Carolina.
I mean,
this is not the right answer.
North Carolina is beautiful.
It is and that's another problem.
It is.
You go there,
it's all green and it is people,
it's grave or not to have it a little
Twang to the way they talk.
Barb can,
it's pretty fucking good to try to make
sure
a bunch of New Yorkers don't go there
and ruin it.
Say I understand.
I understand.
That's keeping New York,
keeping New York.
Um,
I want to keep them all in New York.
So my,
my point being,
um,
I forgot my point now.
Um,
I don't know.
Your point by point of corruption,
getting rid of the jail,
the goal is not to just put people in
jail.
The goals make a better system.
Right.
Well,
I'm not really even interested in
putting them in jail.
What I'm interested in is figuring out a
way to stop corruption.
Several things.
The first thing,
first of you can't stop corruption.
You can absolutely lessen it and you can
catch it fast that you can do,
you can make less corruption and catch
it fast.
Then you remember,
is the average person who is about to do
something which may or may not be
unethical or maybe corrupt?
Is it thinking,
I wonder if I'll get five years or 10
years?
They just thinking,
will I get caught?
It's all the thinking about will I get
caught and will my be over?
Right.
So several things.
The one I went less opportunity for
someone to be caught.
What does that mean in New York state?
Less money coming from Albany,
which is our capital less money.
The less money the governor has to give
out,
the less chance that there'll be
corruption.
That's number one.
But on top of that,
New York state is filled with boards and
committees and authorities and things
that the governor creates to make other
things happen.
We'll create this authority to make this
happen and this commission to make that
happen.
And then he appoints all of his cronies,
all of his buddies onto these,
onto these commissions and boards and
such.
Now he now has one step away,
but he is raised over $800,000 for his
campaign for people he's put on boards.
So he gets lots of money for these
people,
rewards them up,
putting on boards,
and then they become corrupt.
If you've noticed that your politics,
many people have been indicted,
arrested,
convicted,
almost every one of them is either on a
board or a commission or authority.
Trashing those is a huge part of getting
a corruption.
Getting me what we have in New York
state.
We have regional economic development
corporations.
These are basically with the government
decides where the money goes to develop
areas.
Yes.
The government decides where to develop
areas.
You mean any gap jump?
Yes.
Well,
we're going to put money into whether it
can be infrastructure,
building a hospital,
putting a new downtown in all these
types of things,
so who would then,
how about the local,
the local people,
the local government.
The mayor,
absolutely.
Why not?
Okay.
Need the government.
You have a be the local,
local and local less as something else.
How about just like bankers who want to
invest in things,
businessmen who think this is a good
idea.
How about the local woman who thinks
this is a great place for it opened up a
whole new business.
How about the guy or Gal who thinks this
is a great place for a new school as
opposed to what it is now,
which is we all that petition to the
government.
I'm not joking.
We think we should.
The government then agrees,
blesses it gives us a certificate of
need and then says here's the government
money to build this thing.
That is completely the wrong answer.
Right.
But then it's going to be some
regulation.
Like you don't really want a nightclub
opening up right next to us and we go,
there's gotta be some regulations gene,
that guy's,
there should be.
Yeah,
of course I did that.
At what point did I say destroy
everything?
Well,
I'm not saying you have ever said that,
but I'm asking you if there should be
some regulation based assays.
If I'm arguing to control,
not I based upon safety,
not control safety.
If it is based upon safety,
I'm in.
Right.
Like a scroll would be right next to a
strip club.
Is that safety right?
Is it?
Yeah,
I would think so.
Then I'm okay with it.
I'm not sure that's true.
I really,
I don't know enough about that,
but if that safety,
I'm okay.
It's not safe for those kids.
Then there we go.
Some of those girls then that,
then I'm fine with that and have,
I don't have a problem if it's based
upon safety,
but just because,
just because I decide I don't like this
thing here.
Right.
If someone was stability or the ability
that if the community doesn't want it
there as a general rule,
the community doesn't support it.
What's the main argument against
libertarian philosophy when you fear
fear.
Fear.
Fear of change.
Fear of not having big brother and
control.
Remember something in New York,
I mean New York.
In America in general,
as a general rule in America,
the government does not just take our
rights as a general rule,
we eagerly vote them away because we're
afraid.
I'm afraid take my rights,
I'm afraid.
Take my rights.
That's what usually happens.
Fears of problem,
which is why as you've said will,
there'll be no regulation.
There are a lot of libertarians who
probably heard that and went,
yeah,
Larry say no regulation.
I'm not going to,
and here's the reason why.
If I decided to pull the rug out from
people,
they will be afraid.
People who are afraid make bad decisions
all the time.
The word that I'd use more here,
and maybe it's not landing,
maybe this is my error for not making
this land better,
is facilitate.
I want to facilitate better options.
I would facilitate better answers.
I'm not just going to go to school.
Some may say take away the money,
go away.
That would create fear and bad
decisions.
What would you do instead?
I would say in x number of months,
the federal government regulations and
the federal government dollars are going
to go away,
which means by this time we're not going
to have it,
which means that only do you not have
the money,
but also you don't have these
restrictions.
How can we fix this system to win so you
don't have district restrictions
anymore?
What can you make to be better,
stronger,
faster?
How can we do this now let's talk this
thing out.
Some people will fight me.
Of course some people will not make a
change of course,
but some will go,
oh my God,
thank you so much.
Yes,
I would much rather not spend the money
here,
but I'd rather spend it here.
Okay,
let's try that.
Let's do that and before the others will
follow and then others will follow and
that might take a year or two.
It might take three years.
But what will happen,
we'll have a much better effective
system and when one fails,
but hopefully,
hopefully none yet because it hasn't
been done before.
Okay.
It's been done in everything.
We'll give you the best example I can
give you with education with,
I'll give you the best of,
I can give you.
Okay.
Um,
google,
Google.
Yes.
Google had a program and I think they
still have it.
I'm sure someone will let me know if
they don't,
but I believe they do to where you had
an um,
an employee could choose to take 20% of
their,
their work time and do it on any project
they wanted to,
any project,
whatever they want to do.
Did you work on if they want to do it
was voluntary.
You didn't have to just do your regular
workload if you want it to,
but if you wanted to be like 20% and
work on anything you want,
whatever you think is appropriate.
The only rule was you have to be
transparent and you're accountable to
your team what you did.
Again,
in uh,
freedom plus transparency plus
callability.
Right,
okay.
And was that many of the people did
things mindup up doing things that
didn't really work very well,
but when they did it,
they said,
hey joe,
I went and tried this thing.
It didn't work.
You might have tried it too.
You learn something,
figured things out,
made it better.
But a bunch of their most profitable
things,
profitable applications came from this.
Now what I actually want,
I'm happening also is some people that
20% some people weren't even more,
let's get more work out of some people.
They have more innovation out of people
because they were doing stuff they
wanted to do.
Now does everyone take it?
No.
Some people just did their own work and
we're happy with her work at their
salary moved on,
but what happened is you got innovation
and other people learn from it and it
became better and better and better.
That happens all the time.
All the time.
That is a very different system than
talking about the education system.
When you're talking about Google,
you're talking about people that are
hired to make money for a mega
corporation that makes billions and
billions of dollars and you give them a
chance because they're engineers and
techies,
you give them a chance to innovate.
They innovate,
but their financial incentive is
massive.
I mean,
I have differential instead of hasn't
changed,
and who's a big executive at Google?
They make a shitload of money.
Absolutely.
The people that work underneath them
have the potential to move up that
corporate ladder to show none of this
financial incentive in the school
systems.
That's not only that you're limiting
their amount of money.
You're not just offering them the
possibility to exchange creative ideas.
You're saying we're going to give you
less money and we're going to have the
administrators who are still going to be
in a position of power.
You're going to have that.
Everyone's going to have to figure this
out.
All right.
This is not,
this is not a parallel situation.
Absolutely is.
Let me tell you why.
Parallel situation a wide is the first
thing is the people who get into
teaching,
they don't get in because my God,
I'll make millions of dollars.
They don't do that.
They get into it because they think it's
a viable career path for them.
They have skill at it.
They enjoyed doing it and they want to
make a difference.
All those things.
Yes,
that's correct.
If you're lucky,
if you,
if,
if everyone's lucky,
that's what they do it for.
Well,
the same thing with Google,
right?
Does everyone go there?
Cause I'm gonna make tons of money.
No.
A lot of them didn't show.
And a lot of teachers go there because
they don't make a difference.
Yes.
So the incentive you women,
I don't think anybody's going to google
because they want to make a difference
in how teachers,
teachers,
yes,
while there,
but somehow they're parallel.
Something you want to go to muscle,
giant business.
How many,
how many?
One of the biggest businesses in the
world and the New York City in New York
state schools,
a system and say 60 billion odd
business,
still a bunch of money.
It's not profitable.
That's the same thing.
The same thing by any stretch of the
imagination and it's certainly not
profitable for the individuals that are
involved in this innovation that you
seek and I think you are wrong in many
ways.
How am I wrong that it's not profitable
for the individuals that you're asking?
You are assuming because we lose $4
billion.
You're assumption is that means teachers
don't get more money.
That's your assumption.
She was going to get more money.
If you're giving them less money.
I'm not keeping teachers less money.
You're giving the school last month.
That's correct.
School district class money.
Teacher's not going to get less money.
Schools get more less money.
Well,
what if you got rid of,
I don't know,
a bunch of administrators?
What if you got rid of,
you would have to,
who would decide that these
administrators are removed?
Don't know how many times I've got to
say this.
You never said anything clear.
That's why I'm asking you over and over
and over again.
This is not clear.
Okay?
You're saying it's going to work itself
out.
Yes,
we're going to facilitate it,
but then you comparing this to google
when you're giving people who are making
a fantastic salary.
Yep.
The ability to innovate for 20% of their
time.
Sure.
I don't think,
I don't think these are valid
comparison.
Humans are humans.
We want to have purpose.
We want to do better at whatever we're
doing.
We want tap accolades from those who
respect.
That's what humans want.
Okay?
I agree.
No matter what humans want that if
you're a teacher,
you want accolades from those you
respect.
You want to be good at what you do.
You also want to be able to feed your
family.
You also want to be able to make a
living.
So in most of them make piss poor money.
All right.
This is an Oklahoma,
it's New York state,
right?
So most of them are doing well enough to
not starve it down.
How much did I make?
How much show how my teacher makes it?
Didn't you just get done saying how
expensive it is to live in New York?
It is expense.
Taxes are outrageous.
It's outrageous.
Absolutely.
We're moving out in droves.
It's true.
And then there's going to be less money
for people that already get paid less
than they should.
That not saying that's true.
Your saying that's true,
but there's going to be less money that
goes to the school,
goes to a school district.
Yes.
So how was that not going to translate
into less money that goes to the
teachers and less.
I will try it again.
How?
No,
no,
no.
You've never said it.
Tell me what he wanted me to say.
No one has decided how this is going to
somehow know the benefit.
The teachers,
yes,
but you've,
you've,
you've not firing these administrators.
You're making everybody figured out on
their own.
The administrators will wind up being
fired.
They will by WHO,
by what?
The PTA.
I'm some PDA.
The at the school boards,
they will begin to it.
You're going to,
it's going to happen.
We're going to facilitate the way out.
It's going to happen.
You know,
if you,
if you want me to say there are 700
school districts and I'm going to fire
that guy,
and I'm literally two months out from
the election and then at least nine
months middle mentoring it.
You're simply asking too much of me just
asking too much of me.
The skeleton is built.
The idea is good.
It will work when we fill out,
of course we will.
Absolutely.
How am I going to which guide a fire and
I'm a year out from doing this,
basically asking much of me.
It's,
it's an unfair question.
It's an unfair question.
I'm not asking you which particular
human being defier.
I'm asking you how you're going to
facilitate paying less money to the
school districts and somehow or another
having them organize the right way to
make the school runs smoother and more
efficiently while you're comparing it to
people who work at a multibillion dollar
tech company where you're allowing
engineers who get paid substantial
amounts of money to innovate for 20% of
their time.
And I was saying that these,
this is not a valid comparison and I'm
saying you're incorrect cause they,
both human humans want to be good at
what they want to be.
The reality of it is,
as I said earlier,
a lot of school districts won't do much
different at all,
but there will always be early adopters
that happens in everything.
They will always be early adopters and
some people will jump in and go,
this is a wonderful idea.
Let's start working on this now.
And some will,
some sort just,
we'll do absolute nothing and they will
think Larry was going to fail.
Who Cares?
Let's change nothing.
Of course.
And probably most will do absolutely
nothing once I'm elected.
Nothing but a bunch of going to say,
oh my God,
what an awesome thing this is.
And they'll begin making changes right
away and as they do,
we'll start watching,
oh,
what do you,
what are you proposing?
What's the right way?
That sounds great.
What do you think?
As I said,
my business guy,
I go in,
I,
I've,
I've been an officer in a public company
for short periods.
I'm twice and in both cases when I went
in,
I didn't go and going,
ew,
ew.
That's TV show stuff.
It's not how it works.
How it works is you walk in,
you talk to people,
you begin to figure out what's going on.
You try new things until the right thing
works.
That's how you fix a business.
And if you know anyone who does it,
they'll tell you that's how you do it.
You don't walk and go,
I know everything.
So it works well.
Let me,
let me come at you from a position of
fear.
Please.
Let's pretend that I'm a parent and I'm
hearing this plan and I'm thinking,
this is not a plan.
You're eliminating money.
What if my school system doesn't figure
out a way to innovate?
Would if they cut funding,
would have the kids classes get bigger?
What if there's just a just a mass panic
throughout the organization because you
essentially gutted their infrastructure.
Wow.
I gutted their infrastructure.
I really hope they don't believe that.
But they might your right.
That would be if I was your opponent.
That's absolutely what I would argue.
Sure,
and I guess you could argue that if you
wanted to,
here's my response.
Okay.
Keep the same system,
keep paying your same taxes,
keep your kids unhappy,
sue the state,
and you can pack up and move to South
Carolina this time.
Is it North Carolina or Tennessee
instead of North Carolina,
Florida.
Cause your hat going move if you want
to.
That is an option for you.
If I was your opponent,
I would say that is a ridiculous
proposition.
So you're saying either we keep the
current system or we adopt your system.
These are the only two options.
We either leave or we take your option
and Nope,
you're would say,
why don't you throw more money at these
teachers?
Give them more incentive to succeed,
figure out a way to take money away from
something else and apply it to education
because we believe that it is the least
appreciated thing that is the most
important because we've been doing that
for 20 years and failing.
That's why.
Yes,
they've been paying teachers more.
Nobody had been throwing more money at
the system with for 20 years to hiring
administrators.
They've been throwing my,
we've been doing it for 20 years.
It hasn't worked yet.
When are you gonna stop?
That's my response.
We've been doing it for 20 years,
at least throwing.
We spend more money per kid than
California does and we have worse
results.
If you're happy with that system,
awesome Volk Cuomo,
you'll get it.
You'll keep it,
no worries.
But if you actually want change,
if you're unhappy with the system,
you got to change it.
And they said to my system with people
all the time,
what I'm doing right now,
I think the same thing.
Yeah,
but I haven't even prepared and I'm
finding all these problems with it.
Does he ever,
you haven't given me one prom at all.
I haven't given you any problem.
What have you heard me say?
Not One you just said,
I'm afraid.
I'm afraid not.
It's not what I said.
That's what I heard.
That's I haven't said it.
I'm afraid.
Never said that once.
You said,
but what if but what if but what if,
but one last what if questions.
It's not saying I would says I'm afraid.
I'm afraid.
That's what I hear.
But what if is asking you to define how
your system is going to succeed?
It's not saying I'm afraid that's
hyperbole.
Didn't you just say if I'm,
if maybe I'm,
maybe I didn't hear you correctly,
but then you just say,
but what if this bad thing happens?
What if it's my school district went,
what I did is I had an exercise where
I've made a parent who was scared.
I didn't say,
that's me.
And I'm telling you as a person who's
not debating you,
I'm just asking you questions about
this.
Please.
I'm curious,
but I see massive flaws in the logic
behind allowing these systems to figure
out how to eliminate administrators in
order to stay alive with less money.
I'll try it again.
I'm facilitating this to make it happen.
I'm going to oversee it.
Of course.
There's already administrators in,
in at Albany who can help to facilitate
these.
I understand what you've said and you
can repeat it at nauseum.
I'm just curious about it,
but it seems very loosely defined and
it's very,
would agree with you.
I don't think it's confusing at all.
Loosely defined is true.
It's a skeleton and it's a good
skeleton.
Well,
it's confusing in the fact that you have
these administrators and they're in this
position where you're going to eliminate
some of them,
but you don't know how many or which way
or how to do that and you're going to
allow the PTA and the teacher's unions
to figure this out or not the teachers
union,
but whoever would be just to be part of
it too.
Of course.
Look,
you used to be part of it.
PTSB part of it.
School boards be part of it.
Of course Albany's administrators to be
part of it.
Of course it you can't,
you can't do a long term solution for
any problem by just dictating what is
right and what is wrong.
I agree with you more worried about the
short term consequences are the ones
that are going to vote for you or not
vote for it?
Probably not though.
For me.
My assumption is not built for me.
Right.
Yeah.
I'm with you.
I think most,
most people who are afraid of that,
who think the way you're presenting to
me,
most of them are not gonna vote for me,
but you've got to play devil's with
yourself when
you're going over these things and is
what I know for sure.
There are a bunch of people who are not
going to vote for me.
I'm okay with that.
I'm still right.
It's the right answer.
Whether I win,
lose or draw,
everything I'm saying is true and right
and there is no better alternative in
New York state period.
No other,
every other person who's running is
saying we have to fund more fun,
more fun,
more.
That's not going to work.
That I'm sure of,
and anyone who knows the system also
knows that it is impossible that funding
more's going to work.
That's correct.
Why is that?
Because you're not changing the system
itself.
You still just have a bunch of teachers
being told you're goal is high test
scores in standardized testing.
That's your goal.
That's how you're funded.
That's how you're judged.
That's how you decide if you're going to
stay a teacher or not.
That's everything.
That's the current system.
And there's no opposition to that other
than you.
That is correct.
Yes.
So everyone else wants the people that
are doing the best to get more money.
The people that do school systems,
no,
no.
They judge them by standardized testing,
but they're doing the best and now
they're not doing the best.
Whoever's getting the best scores.
Thank you.
Those are the ones that are getting the
most money.
Correct.
The people that are doing the best.
Yes.
Now,
not to be the best,
best scores.
The scores don't mean to me.
Well,
they mean something.
You take a test,
so I mean,
it means something.
It means you're going to taste tech.
You're better at the test and the
publisher of the best tests.
Correct?
Yeah,
but,
but test taking standardized test taking
is no indication of success.
What is a good indication of success?
Emotional intelligence.
But you can't measure that.
And the emotional intelligence,
yes,
but that's not going to work for some of
his goals.
Right?
Um,
but if you're teaching kids,
how do you,
how do you judge whether or not you're
doing a good job,
you know,
other than tests,
how would you judge as an example,
how do you judge things when they're
hard to judge?
And I bring this up in my business
often,
right?
When you can't,
when it,
things aren't,
when it's not easy to find a win,
right?
If I don't know what a win is,
how do I figure out what a win is?
Sometimes can be challenging,
right?
Um,
if you're,
uh,
if you own a something a company,
you might judge it on sales,
which is a lot easier,
but you might not,
you might,
you might judge on or something like,
you know,
um,
how many of your competitors,
how many of your customers are a
professional athletes?
You might judge it or something like
that.
You could find another way of judging it
if you felt the appropriate,
depending upon what you thought was a
win or valuable the syndicate happen in
schools,
you could judge it by simply how many
parents are happy and you could judge
them by,
uh,
how many show up.
You could judge them by having an
actual,
a rating system similar to how Google
writes things or yelp rates things.
There's many ways you could jut getting
system to help.
Well,
you could in theory shorts,
another option of course.
But how would you be able to figure it
out?
Like fi spell this out for me but I
don't,
what's your question?
You're saying a rating system for kills.
You can,
it minute.
You could be a parent's judge.
The school could be the teachers do a
three 60 on themselves,
right,
and many businesses are three 60 I don't
know if you know if that means,
I'm sorry.
It's a business thing.
Sometimes what'll happen is in a,
in a business,
how you judge the individual is you do
what's called a three 60 and people who
are around that person will judge them,
usually anonymously.
So person may be has seven juniors,
seven peers and three or four seniors.
They'll pick a couple of juniors,
a couple of peers and a couple of
seniors who will then grade this person.
It's called a three 60 and now that
person gets graded every six months or
every year or depending upon the company
every quarter and now you know how the
person is doing because everyone around
them is judging him or her.
So the teachers are judging each other.
They could do that too.
Sure.
You're asking me for specific plan.
Could be,
I think these are all viable plants.
What I'm saying is can be a combination
of viable alternative to testing to find
out how well children are doing.
It could be only thing you should write.
How about graduation rate?
I like that too.
Graduation rate could work,
but it's a great way.
By what standard are they graduating if
they're not taking tests and I said,
I've taken tests.
They're not taking standardized tests.
We're going to take standards.
That's what I said.
So taking some tests of course.
So you're judging them by these tests?
It's correct.
And letting me teach standardize.
That is correct.
That's why I said difference between the
tests that you would judge them on.
And standardized test.
Standardized test is usually given by
federal or state authorities.
It's usually written someplace out of
state.
It's usually decided based upon the
company that bids the right bid and it
doesn't necessarily decide what's
important to the local kids.
Also the parents.
So what would be the difference and the
test teachers are,
these teachers would have their own
tests,
so there would be no standard that the
state would enforce.
They would all be up to the community.
Sure.
Love the idea.
I love the idea.
Let's let the school districts create
their own tests and the odds are they'll
wind up copying each other most of the
time anyway.
That's fine.
You see what works.
The issue is you're assuming that a
standardized test has value.
I don't,
I'm not gonna assume me.
A standardized test has value.
I'm just asking you what would the
alternative to a standardized test will
be?
Is is a,
is a district wide test district.
What's wrong with that?
Standardized for the district.
The district.
I'll take back.
Sure.
Much better.
Why would that be better than for the
state?
Because each,
each school district is different
because each,
because each county in New York state is
different.
Each region is different.
They're just physically,
socially,
they're just,
they're different regions.
So there's sort of different standards.
Sure.
In terms of how they graduated,
what an a is and what's a pass,
how you get through school and with
that,
would it be even across the board?
I mean,
would you,
would you know what you mean by that?
It wouldn't be better.
Would you have schools that will be be
worse and they would all have the same
grains?
Look,
if you wanted to,
I think you could easily create a system
to where at the end of the day,
meaning at the end,
at the end,
meaning 16 in this case where I'm
talking to k through 10 at a k through
10 where there is one statewide
standardized test,
which is why I said no standardized
testing until high school.
Right,
so prior to high school,
I don't want standardized testing at
high school.
I'm fine with it at that point,
the kids a bit more mature,
the kids kind of know where they're
going,
the Senate,
it have more value for them in that
regard because they'll know,
wait a minute,
I'm doing standardized testing because
I'm thinking do I want to go to college,
do I want to go to prep school?
Do I want it to trade school
standardized testing in high school.
This is where I said,
okay,
so for 14 to 16 basically just two
years.
That's correct.
Yes.
In those areas.
I'm totally happy with that because at
that point the kids are deciding where
they want to go and being a good test
taker in those years might make you
think,
you know what,
maybe I'm good for sciences,
maybe I'm good for math,
maybe I should be a plumber,
maybe I should be a truck driver.
Maybe I should be an insert thing here.
Right.
Maybe for a teacher.
So I'm totally happy in high school.
So I said until high school doing in the
youth doesn't do anything except make
things bad.
So once we get to the high school level,
yeah there's standardized testing at
that point.
But I'm saying before that,
but before that is when the kids are
building up who they are.
Right before that was when the kids are
building up who they are as,
as students,
as as who they think they are in their
life.
Are you familiar with other types of
teaching like wall door for some of the
other alternative forms of education and
have you ever looked at those models and
no,
I have not.
Not Teacher.
Yeah,
I have not.
But I'm happy to to look at those too.
I'm happy to look at them.
If those are,
if those are models that would give our
kids an upper hand and a better chance
of success,
I would happily take them.
If they are,
I'm happy to.
I'm happy to do that.
To be fair with you,
as I'm trying to tell you everything
you're saying right now in the
conversation we've had in the past,
hour and a half,
you've already come up with some
different ideas in such already you
have,
can you imagine what teachers were doing
was they had this,
the concepts and ideas they would come
up with.
We can facilitate things actually
working maybe even by region,
maybe even by county,
maybe even counties that would test.
Even test schools.
Schools have a test things out for a
year.
You imagine even that teachers have the
kind of freedom to innovate and I mean
in any foreseeable future like that,
yes.
Decide,
decide some of the things that we've
talked about now,
third party certifications and trying to
figure out.
Absolutely,
yes.
What you're hearing me say?
What you have so many people get afraid.
Not saying you are,
but many people do.
If some talking about an actual revamp,
a reboot of our education system where
you're talking about change,
radical change because my state is
collapsing and I understand that radical
change.
Yes.
Do you think it's collapsing or do you
think the current numbers are just
unsustainable?
Is there a difference?
Yeah,
the differences.
It will still maintain,
but there'll be less people.
It's not collapsing.
Collapsing to me seems like it's falling
apart.
Yes.
That's what I say.
I think there's a lot of people that are
in New York that are like,
Holy Shit,
this is too much.
I gotta Outta here.
Which in my eyes tells me that it's
cloud because you have situation where
you have counties that are one third
have Medicaid,
one third of Medicare with a,
a bunch of unfunded mandates that force
them to pay for certain things and with
people leaving you have a dwindling tax
base.
So at that point,
yeah,
that's collapsing.
At what point does it stop?
I don't see it stopping.
I just see larger chunks of Medicaid,
Medicare,
and at one point when it's Medicare,
even they pack up and head to Florida,
North Carolina or South Carolina,
right?
Families are keeping people in New York
state more than anything because their
relatives or close by.
Yes.
So now if they're not,
if so,
I see it's continuing education out of
the equation.
So if we've got education cured,
how do you make amazing,
be amazing.
How do you make it more attractive for
people to stay in New York that don't
have children,
Yadda,
you make it more attractive to
businesses?
Absolutely.
Several things.
Number one,
we,
as I said before,
we have to raise money through ways
other than taxation,
right?
We can still raise money.
We can find ways to fill gaps and if we
have to fill a gap,
say the 4 billion from the federal
government,
we have to fill the gap.
If we find that the first six months of
discussion,
there's no way we can do this without
the forebay Nelson,
the federal government,
let's say.
Let's say I'm wrong.
Let's say I'm wrong and the 4 billion
now is I want to get rid of from the
federal government is no,
we have to have it that we,
the plans you've come up with that we
think will work.
What card?
That money.
Okay.
Deal.
I got it.
We can still raise it some other way.
Now.
In the past we've done things very
poorly in New York state.
We've done things like,
let's have a lottery and a lottery.
We will pay for education.
Then it goes off to the general fund and
it goes away.
We can do,
is that something like this?
I talk often about using our
infrastructure in New York state.
As we of raising money,
we have bridges and tunnels and through
ways and the Erie canal,
which is about a 500 miles and about
three dozen locks and lots of stuff like
that.
Right?
Why in the world do we have a bridge
right now in New York state that's named
after one of our previous governors
called the Mario Cuomo bridge.
That's embarrassing.
We literally have an,
uh,
an imperial bridge.
Neva throw royal family.
That bridge should not be named that
there,
but she'd be the staples bridge,
the verizon bridge,
the a,
the three m bridge,
the Kellogg's bridge,
the Apple Bridge,
whatever.
We should be leasing the naming rights
out.
I'm a business guy.
Want to retain the asset.
We don't lose the asset.
Lisa naming rights out,
right?
These are companies that pay billions of
dollars every year in marketing.
Old Time,
they dropped $20 million for a a a a
stadium that gets used on the weekends.
Instead we have them pay a,
how'd it make dollars for bridge?
That's across by hundreds of thousands
of cars every single day.
So you call it the verizon,
the rise of rich.
Love it.
Perfect.
And it's mentioned hundreds of times
every single day during rush hour in a
16 million person metro area.
But here the next piece is on top of
that.
Once he has the money,
they're also responsible for the
maintenance.
We used to inspect the bridge,
right?
People say [inaudible] is responsible
for that is correct.
That's part of it.
Yes.
So they have to pay you and they have to
fix the bridge.
They can go,
yes.
That's all I know is I already have
already asking me about how long is the
lease?
What are we gonna do?
They already love it.
Yes.
People already tell him,
know that you want them to fix it to
correct.
Yes,
absolutely.
But be part of the contract again,
I don't have to.
And this is a common theme that you'll
find that people don't like and you
didn't,
you don't seem to like it either,
which is,
I don't have the answer for exactly what
the contract is.
I'm not saying I don't like and I'm just
saying,
man,
if I was verizon I'd be like,
Shit.
So Yang you guys just to put my name on
it.
Now I've got to fix this.
Yes,
there may be.
You know what,
if you don't want to,
maybe we negotiate.
You pay a little bit less pain,
90 million instead and fix the bridge.
But I want you fixing the bridge and
there's a reason why she fixing the
bridge right now across our country,
but just collapse concrete cancer.
They,
they all old time.
Right?
And,
and why?
Because the government has to run it and
the government runs out of money or drop
Rossi fails.
Right.
But in this case,
we would actually have someone who has
to fix it so we could actually check the
bridge and to say it's at at a b and an
a diesel.
Osa can get to as an example,
right.
Has to be,
verizon refuses to fix it.
It goes to see rice and fix it.
Now you lose a contract and I guess now
it's gonna be a sprint bridge.
Right?
They have to fix it.
The British who actually gets fixed,
that makes sense to not even know what
that is.
So yeah,
that's,
that's one.
Right?
So immediately at that point we're
getting money.
The bridge are actually getting fixed.
And here's the best part,
the need for tolls.
If you've been through New York state,
you know we are the toll monsters.
I mean we are horrible.
It's brutal.
Yes.
When a tree establish those tolls under
the false premise of once the bridge is
paid,
got it.
Correct.
Once they got addicted to that money,
he said,
well,
we're never paying this bitch off.
That is correct.
Yes.
So instead they now know it's creepy,
which means now those truckers that are
paying a hundred bucks every,
every time across that breaks,
they pay by the axle.
Those go away.
This isn't a $100 every time they cross
the bridge for a big truck.
A trailer.
Yeah.
Cause they paid per axle dirty.
Yes.
It's horrible.
That is so dirty.
They're paying tons of money every time
across that bridge.
And if that goes away to see if you
could do that,
you would when the governor,
I would hope so.
If you could figure out how to do that,
you would become governance.
It's already be this.
The idea is not crazy.
We already have a doppler.
They ever brought this up besides you
never,
we already have adopt a highway.
Fuck your education system.
This shit would work.
See that?
I got you on that one away.
So all right,
so I'll tell you what,
we're working on.
This one.
I said,
but here's a better,
but not even done yet.
Not only at their paying for
maintenance,
which means we have lower spending
because we're not paying for
maintenance.
And his even better part,
the less money I have to give out for
these contracts,
less corruption because I'm not giving
out the contracts anymore.
Verizon's given car.
How much money do they get though in the
tolls over a year.
I would imagine it'd be bigger than $100
million.
Um,
no it isn't.
It's not.
No.
Yes it is.
I'm sorry.
Yes,
the tolls.
I'm sorry.
I'm thinking of billions.
Yes,
because the New York state budget,
I was like a billions.
I apologize.
Yes,
it's not $100 billion,
but it's several days.
I think just New York City,
if I'm not mistaken,
there's over 2 billion,
2 billion a year in tolls.
Just know he's dead is so dirty.
But that may include people you can't
drive unless you give us money.
You want to cross this line?
Pay Attacks.
Pit Tariff.
Yes.
Oof.
That's so gross.
It's tons of money.
We're so lucky here in California,
so we could raise that money.
So to make you see,
I'll make your education unhappy.
I'll,
I'll take four being off of that.
I'll put it back in the teachers and the
money's the same.
Well how you're,
if you're taking that,
let me again and said I did not love
you.
I was just finding holes in your game.
Now when you're,
when you're talking about the holes,
don't be silly.
No holes there.
Don't be silly.
This isn't halls there.
No,
come on.
Come.
So when you take away all that money
that people are paying on the toll is $2
billion a year.
How do you replace that?
I they're paying $2 billion in young
hungry.
If we're getting $100 million from one
bridge,
that's just one bridge.
Okay.
How many bridges you got?
There's over a dozen just in New York
City,
Justin,
the MTA.
And I didn't even,
I didn't even count the Erie Canal.
That's 36 locks would get named each
lock,
repair the entire Erie Canal.
Make it commercially viable without
paying any tax payer dollars whatsoever.
And we had McDonald's could own one.
They put Mcdonald's on every single log
lock.
These are for,
um,
commercial boats.
Yeah.
Well,
we can make whatever we want.
Right now.
The Erie canal is run by the parks and
rec switch it.
It costs us about a hundred million
dollars every year,
including capital projects to maintain
the Erie Canal.
We make less than 5 million.
Have you crunched all the numbers on
putting different advertisers and
sponsors?
You can't.
Just different bridges.
And the issue,
I mean in theory you will absolutely
raise billions that I'm sure in theory,
but you will raise billions.
But the problem is you don't know which
one goes first,
which one is more valuable?
You don't know how long ago shades is.
We'll take.
You also don't know.
Will they take the throughways also what
bridge they'll take.
Some just may not be viable to be taken.
So I don't know each,
once I'm tunnels,
they may not want to take and then how
fast was catch on.
But the advantage is you could do this
with tunnels.
You can do this with roadways.
I mean nobody gives a shit what the
parkways called the Verrazano Parkway.
It's not making anybody any money by
calling it the Verrazano Parkway.
Right.
Unless there's another idea.
This is a,
there's an iad one in upstate New York,
which is falling apart.
So my idea for that is this thing,
how are we going to fund this interstate
Youporn youporn highway?
Well,
if they're willing to give you the most
money,
what I'd rather do with the highway,
um,
but I'd rather the highway is have
instead make it a google road.
Google road.
Jesus.
Save those fucking people.
Grip on your state.
Oh yeah.
Well look,
if they want to give me a road,
here's whole road here.
No,
here.
Here is how it works.
They get their own road,
they get their own road and they can
make it a driverless car road whenever
they want.
The rent for that is maintenance of the
regular road.
Okay.
That's the rent.
That's it.
You,
you maintained the road for free,
right?
You get to keep the next to it.
Google road.
Now people have an option.
You want to drive in a driverless car is
they come up with that.
A driverless buses or whatever they come
up with.
I don't care what they come up with you.
Then you take it if want to.
If you don't drive the regular road.
If Google says,
I don't want to pay for anymore,
they lose the,
someone else buys it.
Now it becomes an Amazon road or a
battlecat,
whatever road becomes apple road,
whatever.
It was so will and it's funny.
That makes sense to me and I liked that
because nobody really gives a shit what
a road that's correct.
It's called,
which is why you don't,
you don't name the road.
You give them a road next to it,
right,
right.
That they do.
They can,
but you can use that.
They can either what they want to just
to transfer their goods.
For Amazon,
it can be an amazon hub that just moves
Amazon products.
Fine.
I don't care.
As long as you maintain the regular
road,
do what you want with the other road.
What other road is this again,
it could be an Amazon road.
Where did,
the only thing is is the hub to move
Amazon products back and forth.
It's fine.
Again,
I don't have to know what this is.
It's not required.
Okay.
They will figure it out.
And what works for them.
That's an innovative way to generate
income.
Absolutely.
Bridges the roads.
Not even done.
The MTN is subway ride the subway plan
right now the answer is the same thing.
Just give them more money.
No,
I'm not going to be a hostage to the MTA
either.
The t-mobile subway.
No,
not that.
No.
Instead I don't want no,
no.
Instead.
Uh,
cause I think anybody would care about
that anyway.
The issue is this older airlines,
there are rail lines that the MTA
crosses about 11 I think or maybe even
12 different counter things.
11 different counties.
So it's all over.
So and not have these lines we at night
aren't used.
So why don't they freight lines that
Amazon move its product from upstate New
York into Manhattan on a freight line.
Is that being used at night?
What's the,
what's the fee for that?
Fix the lines,
fixed the lines,
fixed them and maintain them.
Is that a viable alternatives?
Absolutely.
Run this by people with a good sense for
them.
People really liked the idea.
Suppose.
Yes,
I live in,
I live in New York City,
right?
I live in Queens.
I work in Manhattan.
I know lots of bankers and I asked him
these questions and they all say,
yeah,
nice idea.
Sometimes they say no to some stuff I
say,
but these,
they say they actually asked how long
the lease would be on the bridge.
They went that far.
That's how I say like the bridge of
that.
You'd like to bridge it into a obviously
a good idea.
It's a good idea.
They like it very much.
Now the answer all your idea.
Of course she got a lock that shit down.
Why stealing?
Let Cynthia Nixon let let them,
Joe,
you just came out with the reason why
this is so important because win,
lose or draw everything I'm talking
about stays and we'll fix my state.
People say all the time like what
happens if everyone takes all your
ideas?
Good.
I'll go home and go back to work.
I can stop doing this.
So the reason why you're doing this,
it's just cause you want to affect
change in New York?
I don't.
There are three reasons why.
Number one,
I don't want to leave New York and I'm
noticing change.
Do you ever go to North Carolina?
I have.
I know.
I know that barbecue.
I get it and I don't and I don't want to
go.
So yes,
stop teasing me.
I don't want to go.
That's the number one reason is I want
to stay in New York.
Okay.
Number one.
But also I want to change the state for
better,
but even more,
I can change the nation for better.
When New York can be the place where we
will look and go,
wow,
you know what?
We can start doing these things.
I'm not even done.
Okay.
Talking about a small business,
right?
Wyoming has a law right now that says,
if you're a small farmer and you agree
to not sell outside of Wyoming,
that you're immune from federal
regulatory bodies helps the small
farmers,
they get a leg up.
There's something in New York,
but why can't they just for every
business,
every small business,
if you agree you will only sell locally.
Why are you being bothered by the
program and how does uh,
the commerce clause come into effect
here?
It doesn't.
So how about we make that happen?
So that applies to all restaurants.
Of course.
Absolutely.
But unless some border restaurants
actually deliver across the border.
Okay.
So you live across the border now that
won't work.
And what will get delivered?
That's great.
If you deliver across the board doesn't
work.
If you don't deliver or don't cross the
border,
you're fine.
What about if you used one of those
third party delivery services,
you know where they are using an app and
they order something and the APP would
be the people who are actually doing
delivery would be responsible.
You would not.
Okay.
As long as that.
As long as that company's based in New
York state.
So this keeps all the money in New York
state?
No,
it does give all the money in your
state.
Good amount of it.
It gives the small business owner a shot
at competing as large businesses,
which almost always cross borders.
Right.
Gives farmers a much greater incentive.
Yes.
And to be more farm to table less stuff.
Now I've gotta help my farmers out.
My New York state farmers are hurting
badly.
That's one idea.
But a second thing is you want to treat
farmers like small businesses and
they're not,
which means they don't get the SBA
loans,
they don't get help.
They'll get treated that way.
It does not work when you treat them
like small businesses.
But next I want to completely legalize a
hemp and cannabis.
And then whenever you're talking,
and I want to regulate them like onions,
onions,
like onions and my joking,
like onions,
onions.
He's the reason why a lot of onions come
out of New York.
That's right.
Yes.
So as my onions and no one cares.
Bingo.
Exactly correct.
And here's the issue.
There are three reasons why I want to
leave lives.
Hemp and cannabis and most of the things
you want to get high.
No,
the only drug I use is cannabis because
cannabis is a caffeine.
Oh,
buff cell.
This is the only drug.
Freud.
Yeah,
I like that.
And that's about cannabis.
I know.
But if I use cannabis,
I would happily tell you so I don't have
him to hide.
Why not happily tell you don't use it.
That my thing [inaudible] paranoid and
worried about the school system.
When you get hired.
I think I talk even more.
I don't want to talk even more,
do I?
Nobody.
I would have my grampy introspective.
You might sit back and go,
God,
I talk too much.
Yeah,
maybe then I could mushrooms.
Then I could do this.
I've never done mushrooms.
I never want to do mushrooms.
I feel like I talked too much,
so maybe,
maybe I should try them one day.
I've never done mushrooms and mushroom.
That makes me uncomfortable.
Yes.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm 50.
I'm 51 there we go.
You've never done mushrooms?
Never.
So somebody came up to you go,
Larry,
you want to do some mushrooms?
And you're like,
no man,
one day I want to be governor.
That's what I was thinking.
I was seven and I thought,
can I be governor went this says who's
bringing questions to a fucking seven
year old?
Oh,
that's what I'm was psycho.
Are you hanging around with it?
You got it.
You don't understand why?
Where I grew up,
when I grew up,
where I grew up now I grew up in south
bronx.
Oh,
even more crazy.
It was crazy.
And then Tim dog,
I didn't know who tim dog is.
Sorry,
I haven't been in the Bronx.
South Bronx.
Sorry.
I haven't been in the bronx in many
years.
I'll dress.
But anyway,
it wasn't obscure.
Reference Mushrooms and marijuana.
Yes.
Thank you.
All right.
You've never smoked pot?
I have not.
Nope.
Never.
Never have what I can't ever have behind
you,
bro.
Sorry.
Never had.
What kind of square are you?
Damn snow.
No Pie.
L Mushrooms.
Acid?
Nope.
Do you want to try it?
Maybe one day.
Live on right now.
No,
not now.
no,
no.
I'm running.
Can't pay my friend.
Oh,
maybe we'll help you then.
Odds are now talking to them as seventh.
Okay.
Did I'm a seventh to be forward.
I'm not against any of these things.
Right?
It's your body.
You owned your body.
Okay,
so if I,
if I tried cannabis now I don't drink
either.
You don't have her drink.
Not even a glass of wine with dinner.
If people are around drinking,
I'll drink,
but I don't,
I don't have any alcohol in my house.
I don't drink unless all those were
drinking.
Okay.
Um,
I'll socially drank again.
I'm,
I'm getting out of bed.
Theresa will drink.
You are focused for most of your life
has been what?
Business?
Uh,
first it was military.
I was a marine for seven years and then,
and then it was business.
Yes.
So you're just,
uh,
keep your nose to the grindstone kind of
guy.
Get this done.
How else could I do this?
Have you seen my campaign?
This is the last three gubernatorial
campaigns in New York state combined
didn't raise $10,000 combined.
I raised over a quarter million already.
The last three gubernatorial candidates
combined didn't do anywhere near the
amount of stops I've made and I slept
too much.
Like how much is Cynthia Nixon?
Raise a 1.7,
I think.
Male,
you know,
ain't,
that is crazy.
I think people are getting behind sex in
the city a lot.
There's a lot of that menopause money
out there,
bro.
I need some of that,
I guess.
I Dunno.
It's flickering around my point being
yes,
nose to the grindstone.
I'm doing this.
Of course.
I believe it.
Literally no mushrooms,
no mushrooms,
no.
Maybe later,
Wait till November 7th and then once you
hit then maybe we'll see maybe your
party with me.
Maybe if I win,
I can't do it while while I'm governor.
That would be,
that would be,
that would be not cool,
but marijuana,
isn't it legal in New York state?
No,
still not.
You have to have serious diseases,
right?
That's correct.
Medical and you fix that of course.
Why the point?
Yeah,
that seems really proposed to my whole
point on cannabis and hemp is heavily
because of farmers also,
right?
Right.
Small farmers right now,
yes.
Particularly has,
Hoadley,
uncontroversial and it's a fantastic
commodity.
It's good,
it's good for the soil,
it's good for the environment and the
best thing is if you treat small farmers
like small businesses,
they can now specialize,
meaning they can specialize in hip and
then also create products in their farm.
Then with specialized hemp products,
they can do that and create niche
industries.
Right,
right.
And we see that in New York state with
both coffee and um,
and breweries,
we said already happening in New York
state.
And you would have the same sort of
incentives for them to sell in New York.
Absolutely.
Yes.
So particularly hemp,
which would be incredibly beneficial
with zero controversy.
That's correct.
In terms of like psychoactive effects,
it doesn't have people,
people would be very happy to do that.
Right.
But cannabis too,
because I want you to be able to create
cannabis products,
but there's something else
and that is,
there are a lot of people in this
country,
but I'll tell about New York state
civically who have chronic pain.
And right now they have three choices,
one opioid and maybe get addicted to
suffer,
which I don't accept all three.
What people tell me,
and for some reason,
again,
it's only been women who have told me
this,
they walk up to me and say,
you know,
Laurie,
I hope we can legalize marijuana because
I smoke a little at night so I can go to
sleep.
What about cbd?
CBD is legal in your state?
I don't think so.
It's not,
I don't think it is fucking,
I don't,
you know,
that's a good question.
I don't think it is.
That's crazy.
My medicinal,
no,
I'm sorry.
It's probably medicinal cbd.
Probably minute.
That'd be my assumption.
But CBD has no psychoactive effect,
but it comes out of it.
It comes from cannabis,
right?
So I,
I think it is,
look it up real quick.
I think it's just,
I think it's medical in New York state
did some sort of a doctor's prescription
to get cbd.
So my point is if it's onion,
you can grow in your backyard,
right?
Great medicine.
Your backyard,
right?
If we heavily,
yes.
If we heavily regulate cannabis and or
hemp,
big business wins,
small business loses guaranteed,
it'll become big business cronyism.
The small farmers collapse.
It's the wrong answer.
Right?
So we need to make that happen.
And people already smoking it and maybe
you don't want to smoke it.
Why don't you have an edible?
Why don't Ya,
I have liquid.
Why don't you have whatever is your
thing.
You don't have to smell it.
If you want to smoke it,
please smoke it.
But there's many ways of,
of taking advantage of,
of both thc and cbd,
which you prefer.
And look at your body,
not mine.
And why in the world what I want you to
have to live with chronic pain if you
don't have to write.
Why do you see,
because cbd again is not psychoactive
isn't legal.
Yeah.
Okay.
It is legal in New York.
There we go.
It's,
it's pretty legal everywhere.
CBD because of the fact that it doesn't
have any psychoactive effects and it's
fantastic for people with arthritis.
And so we got older folks are,
I mean,
shit,
I got Ted nugent taken it.
How about like that?
He's never even touched anything tech
related does he likes my facebook stuff?
Well,
one of the things can be Ted likes.
Is that your second amendment proponent?
I am.
You know,
very true.
Uh,
you know,
there's an issue that I have with people
demonizing the National Rifle
Association.
And one big issue is they always point
to these school shootings and I'm like,
God damn it,
not a single NRA member has ever
committed.
One of these mass shootings.
This is not NRA members.
So you guys are going after people that
are fighting for the right for people to
have arms when there's people that are
taking these arms and they're using them
completely illegally.
Yeah.
None of them are in the NRA.
It doesn't make any sense.
Yup.
We find a boogie man.
Right.
But that boogeyman is culturally
accepted.
Yes.
And it's really confusing.
And then it's not helped by the fact
that a lot of people that are nra
proponents get,
you know,
they dig their heels in the sand and
they fight hard and very much
emotionally so against people who are
against the NRA.
And then it becomes this tribal thing.
It does.
And the tribal issues,
the biggest issue.
I totally agree.
It's a point where you're not even
listening to each other.
Yeah.
And this is why
I say the third party is the way,
look,
people ask Larry,
can you win this thing here?
And I hear it all the time.
And the biggest,
the biggest critique I get is you can't
win,
man.
What do you do when you can't play in
that too?
Particularly right now,
Republicans,
but some Democrats to,
they're heavily said you can't win.
You can't win.
But to answer,
there are some aren't win.
Yeah.
A lot of them are.
Some are,
some aren't.
But the two things,
remember that the first thing is I can
win.
And here's the reason why the Republican
cannot win because there's only about
two and a half million Republicans in
New York state and about 600 million
Democrats in New York state give or take
the,
the tribalism we have now,
if you're a Democrat,
you're not going to vote for Republican.
If you're a Republican,
you're not going to vote Democrat,
but you might vote for the material.
You might have up with somebody who is
not the other evil guy.
So I have the option of getting the
other things.
I can get the other guys and I can get
the setting percent of New Yorkers who
don't vote.
I can get those.
So there's a chance to win.
Add on top of that.
A five way race,
only getting 30% to win.
This is a winnable,
racist can be done.
But let's say I'm wrong.
I've been wrong.
Maybe all my ideas are wrong.
Maybe every hole you found is a is a
real hole and it can't be done.
And maybe they all destroy me and they
beat me up and I can't win.
Get rid of those poles and you win bro.
Get those fucking balls out.
Get those tolls.
Not polls rather tolls.
You mean you told us,
yes,
you can win the whole thing,
but say I'm wrong and I can't win.
Great.
If I just come in second,
I beat the Republican.
Only imagine what it does for the state.
The first thing it does is it shows them
that a third party can actually have
impact in New York state,
which changed the entire nation off the
bat.
People,
third parties without thinking,
wait a minute,
we can do something in a big state.
Yes.
And something else.
It'll make better republicans and better
Democrats.
Cause right now,
neither of them does anything for
anybody.
They don't care if nothing gets done.
But when there's a third party,
I become the referee.
I'm the one who says,
Democrats,
you're supposed to be about civil
liberties.
You're not what's wrong?
Republican's,
you're supposed to be about less
government and second amendment and
small business.
You're not what's wrong?
And now the media,
here's me now people hear me.
They have to become better because if
they're not,
they'll come to me instead and they'll
see it and had a fear.
They'll begin to change.
Now what do you think about this move
toward Democratic Socialism?
And you're seeing this a lot in young
kids in particular.
They seem to be abandoning this old
system and trying to adopt a,
a much more radical left wing system.
Yes.
And uh,
apparently there's some real problems.
That lady who won,
she's literally my congresswoman.
She wouldn't,
my counseling.
Yes.
Yeah.
AOC.
Alexandria ocasio Alexandria.
Um,
Bushy Cortez.
Was
it,
was that true or they smear on her?
Or is it true that she used to be a
Republican?
Antiabortion uh,
I have no idea.
Person.
I don't know.
And that she's really from Florida.
There's a lot of people are so terrified
of her and yet you know,
and attacking her and she's made some
missteps too.
You know,
on her
own.
We have to realize is socialism for most
Americans today till the young young
ones is just the newest ideology of
rebellion.
Bright.
It's all it is.
Most of them don't know.
Most of the people,
the youngsters particularly who actually
supported Bernie couldn't tell you any
of his policies.
Right.
They just knew he wasn't the
establishment.
Disabled trump though.
There are a lot of people swear trump
who would,
couldn't tell you one policy,
but there's things he was in rebellion.
The Bernie says that that resonate with
people.
Yes.
One of them is that there's income
inequality in this country.
Very true.
That's a big one.
And so people say,
Oh,
well the game is rigged and Bernie is
going to fix it.
Yes.
Well,
the game is rigged.
That's true.
And it didn't quality.
It's having,
that's true,
but it's rick,
because of corruption,
because of the two party system.
It's rigged because of crony capitalism.
Right.
That's why it's rigged,
but it is rigged.
The problem is you have a system where
people keep saying it's the free market,
right?
This happened with Obamacare,
by the way,
with obamacare.
They said,
well,
we have,
we have markets,
right?
We have the market place where you can
go buy insurance.
And what people that heard was,
oh,
it's a free market.
It's not a free market.
But that's what they heard.
It was a free market.
So then when obamacare fails in certain
states,
what do they say?
The market didn't work.
See,
we need single payer.
The market didn't work.
We need single payer.
That's how it's spun.
And single payer is,
oh,
single payer.
What's the right answer?
It's Medicare for all.
Well,
that sounds amazing,
but it won't be what it will be as va
for all and the va to disaster.
It'd be a two tiered system.
And I said disaster.
And what most we don't realize is
socialism actually equals a two tiered
system.
The reason why so many people who are
wealthy will will be fine with obamacare
or socialism.
Is it because they're not gonna use it?
They're not using it.
I see him Manhattan,
right?
Where we're,
I'm in Manhattan,
it's already happening because of how
New York state works and how bad the
system is.
You have less and less options for
insurance.
And only like one or two insurers and I
left the New York state,
they leave and they're walking away with
them.
It can't make any money.
So what's happening now is all the best
doctors shouldn't say all,
most of the best doctors don't take
insurance anymore.
Really?
Don't.
They just don't think it.
Really.
Yes.
So what you have to do,
just doctors have enough patients that
are wealthy,
that want the best medical care there
can go,
look,
you're going to have to pay me.
Yes.
And,
and it's actually a better,
I know,
cause in my own family.
Right?
That's crazy.
I'm a business owner,
so I have to pay for my own obamacare.
Right.
But my wife phone going obamacare.
So my wife takes private doctors and I
take obamacare doctors.
That's how I spoke to my actual family.
So when we go to a doctor's office and
you can see a difference,
right?
If it's,
if a doctor takes insurance,
two doctorates in a doctor's office,
five people who are administrators and
they care more about photocopying your
documents,
then you,
you're in the way that the,
the,
the rooms bad.
No one cares.
Whatever your appointment's at two
o'clock,
you can see that three 45 now change it.
Now it's a doctor who does,
who does not take insurance when I was
five doctors and that office two
administrators,
you show up to that,
hey,
how are you?
What's going on?
Please have a seat.
Whatever.
They take your credit card or your
check,
whatever,
boom,
you're good to go.
You want me to two o'clock.
He sent two oh five.
While the comparison of valid comparison
is the Canada's healthcare system versus
Americans.
I have friends from Canada to come to
America to get healthcare because the
healthcare system over there,
although it's free,
it's not as good.
That's correct.
Many aspects and the waiting lists are
massive.
And the wealthy come someplace else.
A two tiered system.
Exactly.
Correct.
Right,
right.
They live out of a thing now where you
go go on vacation and get your uh,
your,
your stuff done right.
I'll get my case.
I mean,
it's,
it's horrible,
right?
But let me finish the last piece in the,
if you have a,
uh,
an insurance,
the author takes insurance,
he'll talk to you for maybe five,
10,
15 minutes at most,
and it will always end with one or two
things,
a prescription or procedure.
It's how they get paid.
The bill Medicare,
right?
They build Medicaid,
they bill your insurance company,
prescription or procedure.
They always doing this.
I didn't make money private.
The person talks for 20 minutes,
30 minutes.
Ask you things that matter.
Like how are you eating?
How are you sleeping?
What's your stress level?
Things actually matter when it comes to
your health.
They asked those questions,
what's going on?
One of those things,
they begin to ask these questions to see
if it works.
Then it doesn't always end with that.
It ends with whatever's appropriate
because you're writing them a check
anyway,
right?
They're getting a 300 bucks for one
visit,
no matter what.
You write him a check where you swipe
your credit card and there's an
incentive for you to talk about what a
good doctor they are.
So correct.
More business that pays them the same
way you're paying.
That is exactly correct.
And they don't have to go through
paperwork.
You are the customer,
right?
Right.
When it comes to anyone takes insurance,
the insurance companies,
the customer,
no people that are listening to this
that don't have enough money to pay for
that are saying,
well I want that kind of care and I I
wanted to be federally funded.
Yup.
Is that possible?
The combination?
No.
Can you get good care?
Yes.
And how do I know this?
Again,
anything I'm saying is based on
something,
right?
Right.
And the best example I can give you is
non nonemergency or non critical care
things like Lasik,
eye surgery,
things like cosmetic dentistry,
all types of things.
Right.
Um,
getting breast enhancements,
things of that sort.
Any type of enhancement.
Yes.
Any of those things.
Right?
If you remember years ago,
you're as old as I am.
So you know when,
when Lasik first came out,
they should charge you per eye cause
it's so expensive.
It was so expensive as per eye.
Now you get both done for less than a
thousand bucks.
Right.
And I was a couple hundred bucks
depending on where you go.
So what's happened in every instance,
service level's going up,
price has gone down,
technology has gone up in every case
that's happened.
So why don't we follow the same model
and in this and can it work sort of
happening.
The Oklahoma Surgery Center right now,
right?
It's doing it right now.
Leading Lady,
they list other pricing,
right?
So you can,
you can actually like,
oh okay,
I can get this.
I know what the cost is cheaper than
anything.
House outside of insurance.
Correct?
No assurance.
Yes.
There's a motto popping up in certain
areas.
Now doctors that are coming out of is an
Oklahoma only that I know of.
There may be others,
but then that one I know of interests,
right?
So I think it's,
I think it's actually called the
Oklahoma Center for surgery or something
like surgery center or something like
that.
And so the ideal situation would be that
would be available for people that can
afford it.
And for people that can't afford it,
there's always going to be catastrophic
healthcare.
You break your leg,
you're going to be taken care of.
Well here's the hit the flu,
There's a bigger issue here and the
bigger issue is we in this country have
confused healthcare with healthcare
insurance.
They are two totally separate things.
I don't talk much about healthcare
insurance that much.
We like cam more about the healthcare
system itself.
The system itself is broken.
It's a cartel system,
right?
So it's literally a people in a room
getting ready,
get together and go,
Hey,
what do you think?
A aspirin,
85 bucks.
When do you think?
Yeah,
85 bucks it is for aspirin and it's not
based on how much it cost to make it.
No,
not at all.
Not at all.
It is a little bit and stuff like that.
Martin,
what does that little twats name,
that one up going to jail?
Just corralling.
Yes.
The Wu Tang clan album,
perfect example.
Jacked up the price of some heart,
some medication in a horrific way.
Perfect example.
Yes.
That of course is an extreme example,
right?
But that's actually happening.
If you've ever gone to a hospital or
going to a doctor's office and you see
the PA,
they give you the bill,
right?
Aspirin,
85 bucks in a bed for five minutes,
$3,000 right?
I mean they do that,
right?
Right.
And,
and that's a problem in itself.
And one of the reasons is this right
now,
healthcare system is the current
healthcare system.
All right,
Joe,
you decide you when I get a new job and
you want to get us a new clothes for
your job.
So you come to me,
the Clo there,
Larry,
and you say,
Hey,
I need some new clothes.
They go,
great.
Here's some new clothes and I tell you
what you going to do and I give you a
good hat and clothes and everything.
He got awesome.
You go,
thanks,
Larry is perfect.
Awesome.
How much it cost.
And I say,
I dunno.
You said,
wait a minute,
I came to your store,
you gave me the perfect outfit for my
new job.
You don't know how much costs.
That's correct.
I don't know what it's perfect.
I don't know how much it costs.
Here's what we're gonna do.
You go home,
take,
take the close.
It's great for you.
You can get a bill in the mail,
but a week or so,
whatever the bill is,
I don't know what it is you have to pay.
That's our current healthcare system.
Wow.
That is true.
Yes.
That's how it works.
And it's true.
It's only in our system,
right?
You don't do that for a car or clothes
or a computer thing.
Nothing else.
Only that it's true.
But here's the worst part.
Alright.
Um,
you decided you want to buy this water
from me,
right?
Um,
I'm sorry I missed your name.
Jamie.
Jamie decides he wants to buy this water
from you.
I'm calm young.
Jeremy,
if you want to be a young Jamie Young,
give him what he wants to buy this water
from you and you agree you want to sell
to them for a dollar.
He agrees with them by $4 I step in,
I'm insurance.
Nope,
you cannot have this.
I have deemed as the insurance company
at this.
This actually is worth 50 cents.
I've decided so.
So I give him the water so I can try to
sell the water for a dollar.
Insurance Company says fuck you.
That's correct.
And gives you this sense done.
That's a real problem with,
yes,
absolutely.
So up the next piece though,
now this guy here and he wants to buy
the water too.
He doesn't have insurance.
I can't get involved.
Will you want to sell the water to them?
How much you wanna sell a word to him
now a buck 50 now you gotta make up for
the sense of him.
So he's paying three times as much.
He's paying.
How do you fix that?
That's the current system.
How would you fix that?
Transparency.
Transparency,
transparency.
So number one thing trans parents
offers,
you broke your foot.
You say a broken foot costs this,
it costs $50 an hour for that.
It costs 15 cents per pill for this.
That kind of shit.
Amazing.
But just,
just doing one thing.
Just saying in New York state,
just saying this,
if you sell medical services like any
other service,
you must be transparent.
Right?
That's it.
So you can't just give someone a bill,
you have to show them why it costs what
it costs and you have to have a
standard.
Absolutely charged them for,
that's very reasonable.
It's like a car,
right?
You don't always know much.
It costs to fix the car.
They give an estimate so you feel like
it gives you,
the estimate was just been in place for
a long time and they've taken advantage
of it and they have power and so they're
just leaving it the way it is.
There's also a bunch of fear and then
you have,
this isn't enough,
right?
This concept of transparency is not
enough.
All these problems that we have,
people often say,
well why?
What's the answer?
It's not one thing.
It's many things.
Transparency is a huge piece,
but you also have to facilitate more
things.
As an example.
You want to facilitate an environment to
where if a,
okay,
the current system people are starting
to use now is what I call the costco
model,
which basically a membership model,
right?
So the doctor's office has all of us as
customers,
all of us decided to pay or they agree
with what the payment is,
400 bucks a month or you have a kid,
so you're 800 bucks a month or your
singles,
you're turning,
whatever the price,
whatever the price we all pay.
We now can go to that doctor's office
whenever need to and whoever's in the
office,
whatever they have,
we have access to it costs five bucks,
five bucks over it.
That's all.
They try this at zero just doing it
free.
But senior citizens,
we show up every day,
so they charged us that $5 five bucks,
shopify,
bucks and tomato.
What's the goal of the doctor's office?
The goal of the doctors' offices,
if you to be healthy.
If you didn't have a show up,
just pay you 400 bucks every month and
to never show up,
that'd be awesome.
Right?
Right.
Now that's happening already,
right.
The advantage is whatever they have,
we get to use.
So if they start making more money,
they will bring them more doctors.
They will bring them more everything so
that you will get more of your family
and friends to come and pay the monthly
fee.
Like a gym membership.
Same thing,
right?
As long as healthy,
you're fine.
Well,
what happened is as long as they can
help you,
they help you.
If they can't,
two things.
You have catastrophic insurance and they
would have some type of agreement with
another facility,
like a hospital or something like that
so that they will get a lower price
because you're going to them,
they're sending patients to you.
Right.
So if you had a bigger issue they can
handle.
They have to groom with other
facilities,
so you get a little price anyway,
but you'd have insurance for that
catastrophic insurance.
Of course,
we already have sunlight that we have
longterm care insurance.
Right.
Which insurance that when you get
something that will last a long time,
there are insurances that will help to
pay along.
But also,
but more importantly than that,
with that in mind,
we've take care of are,
are,
are people who are very poor.
So what can we do?
We can have a system to where you have a
take insurance normally if you want to
or this system and his an incentive.
If you decide,
say as an example,
and I'm making this up as an example,
only you know,
10% of your,
uh,
of your,
people,
um,
you will bring on for free.
And based upon how we decide that
they're poor,
I'm making this up as an idea.
So,
um,
uh,
they uh,
they,
uh,
they are eligible for free school lunch
in New York state.
That's how we as New York state will
define poor for the sake of argument,
sake of argument.
If Algebra that you take those people,
then we will give you a break on this
tax or this fee or this thing.
If you do this,
many of the smaller doctors,
the break probably won't be enough.
And they probably won't take it,
but large organizations probably will.
So larger companies will take on people
who can't afford to pay anything.
This is another idea or concept.
You start making this happen.
If facility in this and you will see
health care will get cheaper and when
health care gets cheaper now insurance
gets cheaper.
Now you have more people want to get
into insurance business,
you will have more options and choices
for insurance.
You know that people would just get
emergency room insurance.
Some people just get longterm care
insurance,
so maybe we'll just get x,
Y,
z insurance.
How could you reduce the number,
the amount of money rather than
pharmaceutical drugs cost cause that
would be a big issue,
right?
It would be.
Absolutely.
Now there are several things.
One of course is the FDA.
The FDA stifles so much,
I mean at the end to be completely
rebooted.
I can't really do that in New York
state.
That's the thing.
The government,
the state government we can't do much
of.
All I can do is make it forced them to
be transparent so that people see how
bad it is.
As a general rule,
and this isn't a hundred percent rule,
but general rule is when you shine a
light on bad behavior,
almost though what you can make the bad
behavior less so when it has to be
transparent and when you actually see
each pill costs all this money and
enough people go,
dude,
what are you doing right enough?
Go,
what are you doing?
I'm not doing this and it will force
them to change,
but that's a longterm solution.
That is really a federal issue.
Well,
listen,
Larry,
you got some really good ideas.
They're very revolutionary.
You're a bold motherfuckers.
The goal,
some chances.
Absolutely.
I like the fact that you're sticking
your neck out there with a lot of these
things and I hope we do well.
Let me wrap the last piece he's do.
If,
if,
if I don't win,
if you don't win,
if I win,
it changed this nation overnight.
100% because all the ideas pop up,
things will change.
You will see people who are independent.
Step Up.
You'll see libertarians change to be in
the debates.
I just be popular.
That's it.
How much do you have to be?
Probably what has to be decided and they
just decide who designs.
Is there a committee?
I think presidential thing is cuomo
decides if he wants to show up or not.
That's it.
Yes.
And when he does is he says,
follow my rules and I'll show up.
What does his rules,
whatever he feels it's appropriate.
Really?
Yes.
Him To do that.
Yeah.
Oh,
he won't show he did with Nixon.
He said it has to be sit down,
must be here,
must be there.
She said yes,
he showed up.
So he'll have his rules.
I'll say yes and I'll show up.
What will he do that with you?
I don't know.
I think he will in the last three,
last two times he did it.
He did all that.
All four people showed up last.
Well,
good for him.
Yes.
Last time we did it.
So probably,
well,
when would this possibly happen?
October.
October?
Yes.
And we could promote that.
We can tell people about.
Absolutely.
Um,
what would be the key things that you
and him would butt heads on?
Wow.
So much.
Um,
as a general rule,
the biggest thing is,
um,
the states collapsing and he doesn't say
that.
He says the states awesome because we
have great gun control.
It's what he says.
He's worried about fighting trump.
He thinks fighting trump has everything
because he's running for president 20,
20 a.
So his entire campaign is,
I'm the only one who can beat trump.
I'm the only one who can protect New
York state from trump.
And if he loses the governorship,
he's fucked.
Running for president.
I don't know.
It depends on Democrats think.
I mean,
you know,
it depends.
Some Democrats who depends on who wants
to fight trump in 2020.
If trump is very popular,
a lot of Democrats won't want to fight
them,
but Como,
well,
who else is going to run?
What do you mean?
For my twenties,
as a democrat?
Is Hillary running again?
I don't know.
It seems like she is right.
Maybe it seems like Bernie might run
again.
He might.
Yeah.
I don't know.
There's a lot of Mites,
so I don't really know.
It hit his loss.
Might mean that he,
uh,
that he doesn't run vote if you win
changes the entire nation,
not just that you will find people who
are liberty leaning all of a sudden
running the libertarian banner.
Because I'm,
I'm,
I'm right now the most popular guy
running who has an l buys name.
There are some libertarians who are
running who don't have els by their
name.
They're running a nonpartisan racist.
I'm running boldly with an elbow by my
name,
right?
So I'm trying to change the brand.
So it's a decent brand.
It's what I'm doing.
Are you putting the betraying all my
stuff?
I'm always libertarian,
so I'm trying to build the brand out to
be a better brand.
So if I win the brands better people
would do that,
will raise my money,
there'll be a real third party.
I mean,
there'll be a third party in the United
States,
which will make better democrats and
better republicans will literally be a
better nation,
a better pr.
A politic will be better in in America
if I actually win this damn thing.
But let's say I lose Sam wrong.
My things in my mind is a wrong
whatever.
People want gray,
I lose.
It doesn't matter.
The bold ideas are still out there.
What you heard,
what your audience hurt is still there.
Someone's going to pick this up,
some of us in a talk about it,
and if you're fine with that,
100% what?
Yes,
please.
I want to fix things I'm not concerned
with who gets the credit for it.
Let's fix it.
I want a better place to live.
This cutters in trouble.
Neil's gets a perfect example of where
we're going.
I don't want that to be the rest of this
nation.
We can fix,
steal all my stuff.
Please steal it all.
Awesome.
I hope you steal it.
I hope California copies me and does
everything I said it'd be amazing.
Please do that.
It'd be awesome,
but if people don't hear me,
if I don't get out there,
if I don't get debate stage and I don't
come in second or third,
then no one's going to hear me because
I'm going to be forgotten.
But if I come in second or a tight
third,
there'll be a microphone in my face for
the next two years and every time it's
out there,
I'd be saying stuff just like this again
and again and again,
and maybe my education system isn't
perfect,
but guess what?
Someone will figure out the right.
It won't be.
Just keep giving it money.
It won't be that.
It'll be something I'll actually work.
It'd be something brand new and exciting
and get people to come back to our
state.
What I don't want is what's happening
now is kids get educated,
they leave,
they don't come back with the edge here
someplace else and never come back.
It's the wrong answer.
Good luck to you,
Larry.
Larry Sharp,
ladies and gentlemen,
the revolution has just begun.