Well good already.
Damn.
I didn't even see a countdown.
Jamie,
you're so fast.
Uh,
thanks for doing this,
mark.
Appreciate it man.
Totally.
My pleasure.
I've enjoyed your tweets.
I've checked out your website and mark's
Daily Apple and,
uh,
all of your,
the different rules for the primal
blueprint.
And I found this really fascinating
because,
um,
it seems really straightforward.
It seems like,
oh,
well this makes like eat lots of
animals,
insects and plants move around a lot at
a slow pace,
lift heavy,
things run really fast.
But what you've done essentially is
created a guideline for optimizing your
health and your body.
Yeah.
Um,
you know,
I've always wanted to be healthy from a
really early age,
like 12 or 13 and a read a lot of books.
Uh,
wanted to do the right thing.
Um,
tried to figure out the,
the hacks,
uh,
before they were called hacks and got to
the point where I was,
you know,
I was doing a lot of running because
aerobics was supposedly going to make
you live longer.
I was eating complex carbohydrates and a
ton of them in order to fuel the
aerobics.
I became a pretty good a endurance
athlete,
but I fell apart,
uh,
as a result of the training and the
result it turns out of the Diet.
So the Diet was very proinflammatory as
we say.
So I started doing research into,
uh,
the ways in which I could re access this
health that I was seeking from the early
age,
uh,
and not fall apart and not be decrepit
and beat up.
Uh,
and this became my mantra is how can I
be strong,
lean,
and fit and healthy with the least
amount of pain,
suffering,
sacrifice,
discipline,
calorie counting,
portion control,
and everything else.
And where it led me was down this path
of looking at human evolution and how we
got to where we are today,
how we derived this genetic recipe that
we all have that wants us to be strong
and fit,
combining the research only in the last
10 or 15 years,
uh,
with the modern genome [inaudible]
sequencing the genome and figuring out
the actual mechanism of how lifestyle
behaviors and foods and sun exposure and
sleep turn genes on or off.
Uh,
and they can turn on genes that make us
a strong and build muscle.
They can turn on genes that burn fat
more efficiently,
then say glucose.
Uh,
they could turn off genes that caused us
to be moody and depressed,
turn off,
Geez,
it might predispose us to,
um,
to get cancer.
And when I arrived at was sort of a
simple set of guidelines.
He's 10 primal blueprint laws that not
ironically emulate a human nature and
human behavior for the first two and a
half million years of our existence.
So the genome was,
was forged in this crucible of eat
plants and animals,
uh,
avoid poisonous things,
move around a lot.
At a low level activity.
Sprint once in a while,
lift heavy things.
Every human that ever lived up until
10,000 years ago did that every single
day.
And that's how those genes got passed
along to the next generation to become
us.
Where we've screwed up is in the last,
certainly the last couple of hundred
years,
but starting 10,000 years ago with a
agriculture,
we went from being a hunter gatherers
and moving around a lot to being
sedentary and sitting in one place and
uh,
eating processed foods.
Um,
uh,
not terry,
not disposing of our waste.
Uh,
lots of,
lots of little things that sort of
conspired to make us a smaller and
weaker and more susceptible to disease.
So you were involved in triathletes and
endurance activities which kind of break
down your body.
That's one of the big issues that a lot
of people have with,
uh,
with that kind of training.
It's just constant and brutal and that's
catabolic.
It's,
it's,
uh,
you know,
it's a,
it's a great pursuit.
I wouldn't take back my years as an
endurance athlete.
I was a marathoner in the 70s,
and then it was a triathlete in the
early days of triathlon and the,
uh,
all throughout the 80s.
But the training was a,
it's devastating.
It really does tear you down.
And you,
the assumption was at the,
at the time that you had to put more
miles in than anyone else to be one of
the best.
You had to,
uh,
you know,
dial everything down.
You had to work harder.
You had to suffer more.
It had to struggle more to achieve
greatness or to,
or to win races.
Um,
what we've discovered in the last five
years is that it doesn't have to be that
way.
How crazy is that?
That it's only the last five years?
I mean,
we're talking 2010,
2011.
Yeah.
Um,
so you know,
a lot of this,
uh,
this new paradigm is based on science.
It's been brewing for 40 years,
but it wasn't the,
the findings weren't palatable to most
of the athletes who are training.
They certainly weren't palatable.
The coaches who'd had been invested in
training a certain way,
putting it a lot of miles,
eating lots of carbohydrates,
managing glycogen throughout an event,
uh,
which meant not only,
um,
carbohydrate loading the night before a
race,
but seeing how many gel packs you could
slam down in an hour to keep the sugar
burn throughput going.
Uh,
and that's certainly what my generation
of athletes,
uh,
wound up depending on.
And,
and we all trained that way and it,
and it was sort of,
um,
it was counterintuitive to think that
you could learn how to burn fat as much
more efficiently,
that you could possibly go faster by
going slower under certain circumstances
that you could spend time in the gym
doing heavyweights and have that
manifest itself in a,
in,
in better endurance.
So these,
these later sort of developments that
come out of the laboratory and come out
of the clinical studies,
you know,
they were sort of interesting to the
people who are reading them,
who knew how to read the studies,
but it didn't make it into the
mainstream a training mechanism.
What was the science based on where the,
where people had used carbo loading carb
loading
and using all those gel packs and eating
a lot of pastas and stuff.
Wait,
where did that come from?
Like what,
what was the,
the idea behind that?
Um,
it was,
that came from studies that they go back
into the 30s and forties,
but it was basically this notion that
the body needs to burn glucose to go
fast.
Uh,
that it,
it was assumed that you couldn't burn
fat at a high rate of throughput.
And if you couldn't burn fat,
then the only thing he could do was
manage your glycogen.
There's muscles can store four or 500
grams of glycogen Max,
which is only enough to run 20 miles,
let's say.
Um,
and uh,
if you couldn't,
so you,
you had to learn how to manage that
glycogen so he didn't deplete it in a,
in a marathon for instance.
So you'd hit the wall at 20 miles.
So how'd you get through the wall?
Well,
you start to learn how to,
I mean,
gatorade became out of the science.
The gatorade was the great first real
performance enhancing substance that
athletes used.
You could drink this sugary drink that
had salt in it in a race and um,
and then stave off that wall a couple of
more miles.
So for years,
for decades,
um,
the science revolved around a
continually try to continuing to try to
figure out how to manage glycogen.
So Tim noakes,
Professor Tim noakes out of South Africa
was the go to guy in this.
He wrote a book called the Lore of
running.
It's a 900 page tome.
He,
he was the,
um,
the source that everyone's cited for
decades when it came to carbohydrate
intake and glycogen management and all
of the things that had to do with fuel
partitioning during an endurance event.
And about five years ago,
he looked at the research partly because
he was,
he'd been a runner himself.
He'd been employing this same strategy
of carbohydrate intake and carbohydrate
management.
Uh,
but he was a type two diabetic.
He'd become,
he had become,
despite his training,
a type two diabetic.
Um,
I think his uncle and his father had
died as type two diabetics.
So he,
you know,
he got the fear of God put it in him and
he started to re evaluate the research
and he literally had an epiphany.
He goes,
Oh my God,
I've been,
I'm the guy that's been promoting this
way of training for decades and now I
have to completely change my,
my,
my opinion on it and say,
what I told you was wrong.
And the body is developed and was
designed to be a great fat burning
machine and not rely so much on
carbohydrate and not rely so much on
glycogen or glucose.
Um,
and the guy is taking so much shit for
it in South Africa.
They like trying to run him out of the
country.
There's a trial going on right now.
Oh yeah.
Here's a professor Tim noakes.
And in my mind,
that's the epitome of a heroic science,
a man of science.
He,
he's gone down a path.
He's dedicated his life to being the
guy.
And then he,
he looks at the research and he goes,
Holy Shit,
I,
I messed up.
This is terrible.
I,
you know,
I've been telling you the wrong thing
and I'm willing to,
to basically fall on my sword and tell
you that because it's this new
revelation is the truth.
Well,
that's how it's supposed to be,
right?
I mean,
that's what science is supposed to be.
It's not supposed to be relying on this
bad information just because you've
taught it to people.
It's supposed to be,
you find the new data,
the new data doesn't correspond with the
old data.
You have to let everybody know.
I sound that it's like,
you know,
that's like Unicorn farts.
I mean it's,
it's a really,
science is,
is kind of dirty and,
and uh,
and messy and there are no black and
whites in science.
There's no absolutes.
There no is no right or wrong answer.
They're just theories and opinions going
forward.
And if you're a scientist who's had an
investment in your life's work being one
way,
you're going to,
you're going to defend that position
even sometimes in the face of new new
information that that really becomes a
huge issue when they deny information
just because it's bad for their ego.
And just because it's bad for their
career and they can just,
I mean,
he can,
I'm sure have just kept his mouth shut
and just coasted and everything would've
been fine.
It,
uh,
well it would have been fine for awhile,
but they,
the coroner had been rounded.
I mean,
enough other scientists,
uh,
had,
had started to look at this and I,
you know,
he,
uh,
he cited me as one of his influences in,
in helping to turn that corner.
But here's a guy,
he was reading my blog posts and sort
of,
you know,
having,
uh,
a new perspective cast upon his
information and was willing to look at
some of the research that I,
and Rob Wolf and a number of other
bloggers in the new,
in the emerging Paleo sphere.
We're talking about that,
that we are,
um,
we're born to,
to excel at burning fat and we shouldn't
have to depend on sugar.
And in fact,
the less sugar we burn in a lifetime,
it probably the better off we are.
So for the longest time when people were
doing all this carbo loading and when
they were,
I'm just following the old methods,
they were creating extra inflammation
because of this food.
I mean this,
the,
when you're talking about simple
carbohydrates,
pasta and bread and such,
they cause inflammation.
Correct.
So sugar is proinflammatory if you have
high blood sugar levels that causes
inflammation.
And if you are,
when you say that to people,
like explain to me what,
what do you mean by inflammation mean?
Like joint inflammation?
So,
um,
good question.
So inflammation is a process in the body
that's designed to deal with an insult.
So he twisted ankle,
um,
and inflammatory process begins the,
uh,
the ankle swells up because a water
accumulates there.
The cells are being,
uh,
partly protected by the,
the water,
uh,
white blood cells rush to it to try and
assess the damage and fix it,
repair some of the damage.
Uh,
there's a a long process where the
temperature of the localized temperature
of the areas raised.
Um,
all of this is contemplated to deal with
a short term insult that hopefully over
time it repairs.
Um,
in many cases it repairs even stronger
than it was before.
You know,
you break a bone.
And sometimes that where it broke his
stronger,
um,
or a callous is an example of a,
you know,
a stronger skin from having been
irritated but the same.
And we can,
the same sort of process happens if you
get a bacterial insult.
If you get a microbial insult,
you know,
you get infected with somebody and
something and uh,
maybe by somebody and you get,
uh,
and there's a,
there's a reaction to that infection.
Um,
and it may happen in the bloodstream if,
if the,
if the bacteria goes into the
bloodstream,
then there's a,
there's a response to that which,
which is an inflammation and
inflammatory response.
Uh,
now if you,
uh,
and by the way,
a lot of this happens as a result of,
of genes within cells being turned on or
off based on signals they get from their
immediate environment.
So genes don't work in a vacuum.
Something has to turn the gene on or
off.
Something has to give the reason,
the gene reason to build a protein or
have whatever action.
It's going to have.
So when you've got,
um,
let's,
so now let's go back to the food
analogy.
You've got certain foods that you can
eat that cause the body to,
um,
to initiate an inflammatory us,
what we call a systemic inflammatory
response.
It just,
it just,
uh,
maybe emulate something that would've
happened in an infection,
but now it's caused by an over abundance
of a maaco sits omega six fatty acids.
So you're literally turning on genes
that are causing a systemic
inflammation.
Now,
over time,
um,
in,
in the short term,
not a big deal,
one meal here,
uh,
you know,
some,
uh,
temporary insult,
not a big deal,
but over time,
if your diet is such that you're
continuously,
um,
presenting these sorts of foods that
would prompt inflammatory genes to turn
on,
you get what,
what is known as an inflammatory
response.
Now,
um,
sugar has that response.
A refined grains can have that response.
Sometimes even whole grains because of
the,
uh,
there's portions of the grain that we
say are natural,
but they're actually,
um,
uh,
there,
there's slightly toxic to the body.
Uh,
the industrial seed oils that are
pervasive in our diet,
that would be,
you know,
corn oil,
soybean oil,
canola oil.
All of these can have the effect of
causing a systemic inflammation,
that systemic inflammatory response in
the body.
Uh,
when,
and a lot of times you'll see like
you'll see it,
you look at the biggest loser and you
go,
God,
that dude lost 25 pounds the first week.
That's unbelievable.
How do you do that?
How do you burn off that much fat?
They don't burn off that much fat.
They lose that much water because by re,
by eliminating the proinflammatory
foods,
the inflammation,
the systemic inflammation that was
causing them to carry literally 30 or 40
or 50 pounds of excess water,
that causes of inflammation goes away
and the water goes away.
The swelling goes down.
So you could look at the cause of heart
disease.
Heart disease isn't caused by
cholesterol or saturated fat.
It's the proximate cause of heart
disease as we know it today is systemic
inflammation.
It's an inflammatory response in the,
you know,
in the,
in the blood vessels.
So when you,
when you say someone looks puffy.
Yeah.
Like people who drink a lot of alcohol,
they start looking puffy.
That's lit.
That's actually literally,
they're,
they're inflamed.
We get water.
Yeah.
They're,
they're retaining water as a result of
an inflammatory response.
The body is having.
So,
um,
where we went to that from training,
I don't,
I don't know how we,
how we get down that road,
but the idea of,
of eliminating these proinflammatory
foods,
um,
oh,
so I'll tell you where it went.
I had arthritis in my feet at the age of
27,
28.
Uh,
I had to smile this hard running and
biking and from the Diet because I had
this systemic inflammation,
right?
I had this diet that was promoting an
inflammatory response throughout my
body,
not just in the ankle that I might have
just twisted or whatever.
Uh,
I had,
um,
uh,
I had arthritis in my hands when I was
even into my,
um,
even after I cleaned most of my diet up
into my forties,
I had arthritis in my hands or my
fingers that I thought was just a normal
artifact of getting old.
And the last thing that I eliminated
from my diet was grains,
which I found were causing,
were a huge cause of issue for me.
When I got rid of grains,
the arthritis in my fingers went away.
All grains,
sprouted grains as well at zeal bread.
Yeah,
I mean,
you know,
yes,
yes.
Let's,
for purposes of this conversation,
let's say all grains and then we'll talk
about what that means over time.
But I'm getting rid of all grains.
Uh,
I got rid of,
I had irritable bowel syndrome most of
my life that I thought was because I was
a type a stress ladened individual.
It couldn't handle it well.
Um,
and that literally that ibs had run my
life.
Um,
that went away.
The,
um,
the upper,
upper respiratory tract infections I
would get several times a year went
away.
Uh,
I had lingering sinus infections after
I'd have an upper respiratory tract
infections that those one way and I,
all these things I'd assumed were just a
normal artifact of being human and
getting older and part of life.
It doesn't everybody suffer these
things.
They went away.
And that was a real epiphany for me to,
to realize it.
If I had made,
um,
I'm basically a researcher and if I had
done all the research and still defended
my right to eat grains in the,
in the face of the research I was doing,
how many tens of millions of people you
know,
might be effected by this.
So,
and I don't want this to an anti grain
crusade today,
but I'm,
I'm,
I'm sort of suggesting that a lot of
what happens to us in a,
in life,
um,
certainly a lot of the root cause of
illness or the beginning etiology of
disease,
um,
has deep roots in what we eat or
sometimes more importantly,
what we don't eat.
One of the things you said,
I think this is really fascinating,
is turning genes on and off.
And for most people like me who don't
have background in medical science and
don't necessarily understand genes,
the idea of genes being turned on or off
by lifestyle,
by a dietary choices,
things along those lines.
It just doesn't make any sense to
people.
They go,
well,
no,
you got your genes so you don't got your
jeans.
You know,
he gave the got red hair or you got big
feet and that's genetic and that's it.
No,
exactly right.
So,
so yeah,
there is a huge assumption that the
genes are finished when we're born.
Right.
You know,
and then we just grow and we have our
eyes and we're,
we're,
we're doomed to be 50 pounds overweight
because our parents are,
or we're doomed to get breast cancer
because her mother did.
Or,
um,
genes are at work every second of every
day.
Uh,
rebuilding,
renewing,
regenerating,
recreating us based on the signals that
they get.
So jeans are these little switches,
it that cause the production of proteins
that actually run our body.
So it's a proteins.
They make a that run our body,
whether it's muscle protein being built
or whether its enzymes to cause certain
reactions to take place.
And um,
and the jeans,
uh,
are basically not doing anything until
they get a signal from the environment.
Now,
the,
when I see the environment,
um,
it might start from what we perceive as
the outside environment,
but eventually it's a biochemical
signal,
uh,
or some sensation,
some transmission of information that
gets through the cell to the genes
themselves and causes a gene to turn on
the switch to turn on the protein to be
built.
And that manifests itself in whatever
that gene is assigned to do.
Uh,
so the beauty of the primal blueprint
and the lifestyle that I've been
promoting for 10 or 15 years is this
notion that we can discover these hidden
genetic switches that we all have.
And we can make choices in our lives
that direct us in a,
in a direction of health versus down
this slippery slope of illness and
disease and,
and falling apart.
Um,
they're,
uh,
they're not right or wrong.
They're not good or bad.
They're not black or white.
They're just choices.
And I'm not going to criticize you for
making whatever choices you make.
My job as a blogger and certainly a
running mark's daily apple and writing
the books that I write is to offer you
some,
uh,
educated choices that you might elect to
undertake based on what you tell me your
goals are.
So,
you know,
if you say,
well,
I want to lose weight and I'm want to
get stronger and I want to,
you know,
uh,
maybe participate in a five k we can
look at a number of different,
whether their dietary and I mean they,
the more the better because all of the
strategy will have some impact,
but there's certain foods you can eat
that will cause you to become better at
burning fat,
uh,
and will cause you to burn two to build
muscle,
uh,
more effectively.
Um,
there's an amount of sleep that you'll
get that will reduce the amount of
cortisol that you secrete.
Cortisol is an adrenal hormone,
uh,
that we secreted in response to stress.
Cortisol tends to make us carry a little
bit of extra weight,
some of us.
So if I can reduce,
if I can increase my sleep and improve
my sleep patterns,
uh,
and reduce cortisol,
it all has effect an effect back at the
gene level,
uh,
to,
to get me closer to where I want to get,
want to be.
How much do you sleep?
Um,
probably nine,
eight and a half to nine hours a night.
Wow.
Yeah.
They say wow,
because that's a lot or that's,
that's a lot.
Yeah.
Um,
you know,
I have friends who,
who brag about getting 10 and make no
apologies for it.
Um,
and,
and almost more,
more importantly is the consistency of
sleep.
So I don't like to stay up late because
I wake up early,
I wake up the same time every day.
So if I stay up late,
you wake up six 30,
you one of those,
get out of the house and go run around.
No,
no,
no.
I'm a no.
I,
I sort of Mosey on down to the coffee
pot,
make a pot of coffee and read the paper
and you know,
I ease into the day and I typically hit
the gym around nine 30 or or go paddle
or whatever it is I'm going to do for
the day.
I don't do it first thing in the
morning.
I want to be kind of refresh for it and
ready for it.
Um,
but then we can talk about sun exposure
and we can say,
well,
you know,
so many people are Vitamin d deficient
and uh,
they've been that way because
conventional wisdom has suggested that
they stay out of the sun,
that the sun is bad for you.
That any amount of sun exposure is,
you know,
is going to cause you to get or
predispose you to getting cancer.
Well,
what we say in the Paleo community is
they're probably more people who have
gotten cancer from having avoided the
sun than ever got cancer from too much
sun.
And the reason I say that is because sun
exposure,
uvb light is what?
That's the stimulus that causes
cholesterol in the skin to convert to
vitamin D.
And vitamin D is one of the most
important vitamins that she actually
should be a hormone.
It's a,
but at one of the,
one of the implications is that vitamin
D is,
is strongly involved in cancer
prevention.
So the more vitamin D you have,
the more,
the less risk,
the lower risk you have for most
cancers.
Isn't the issue with people sun damage
though?
The issue is no,
exactly.
So if you go out and get sun burned,
and I've never advocated that,
but,
but there's a difference between
spending a little,
a little bit of time in the sun
unprotected and going in and putting on
a shirt or even if you want to stay out
putting on some sunscreen at that point
versus,
you know,
just uh,
rubbing baby oil and us and a,
what was it?
Iodine.
We used to put back in New England and
there was very little sons.
They had to get a cram for that.
Suntan.
I had dine.
Huh?
I didn't know that.
No,
I did baby oil.
Baby oil with iodine was even,
it was like a,
it turbocharge.
It was like,
it was like the,
it was like the buttered coffee of
Suntan Lotion.
That's what that stuff is.
Yeah.
What's the mechanism behind iodine?
Like how does that show?
I don't even know.
But that was the,
again,
that was the old wives' tale.
Conventional.
Okay.
I went,
I was worst burn I ever got.
Um,
uh,
it was a winter break or spring break.
I went to Williams college in Western
mass.
We drove from Williamstown to Fort
Lauderdale,
straight through,
uh,
in a BMW 2002.
There wasn't great little car,
great car.
Four of us smell like a goat farm by the
time he got down there and,
uh,
fell asleep on the beach at nine o'clock
in the morning and then just burned to a
crawl from zero sun exposure,
you know,
all winter,
um,
all the way down to Florida,
all the way down the beach barbecue.
There you go.
Wow.
Yeah.
That doesn't sound like it's
recommended.
Nope.
Um,
now just just to clarify a inflammatory
response.
So when you're eating grains,
like say if you're reading a lot of
pastas and things along those lines,
what exactly is happening that's causing
an inflammatory response?
Your body's processing the,
the gains.
And so pasta,
bread,
um,
a lot of cereals,
especially the processed cereals,
sugars,
they,
well,
so,
so those grains turn into sugar.
I mean,
they turned to glucose like really
rapidly.
As soon as they hit your,
your gut and the body doesn't really
know which glucose,
it doesn't know the difference,
whether it doesn't know the difference
in a bowl of skittles producing the
glucose and a loaf of bread,
it's just,
it's just glucose to the body.
So if you raise that level high enough,
um,
you will have some issues.
Now,
if you,
if you introduce high fructose corn
Syrup,
which is,
uh,
you know,
frankenfood created in the 70s to um,
to provide sweetness at a lower cost,
uh,
typically coming from corn,
now you've,
you're introducing yet another variable,
another agent,
because a fruit toast in and of itself
is,
is a somewhat inflammatory.
So this is,
uh,
that's the,
the glucose portion of what we're
talking about here.
But then some of the grains have what we
call these anti nutrients in them,
uh,
that may cause issues with some people
in their gut may open the gut wall and
cause it to literally leak fecal matter
into the bloodstream.
Whoa.
Yeah.
So if you've heard of leaky gut
syndrome,
um,
that's probably a reason why a lot of
people,
uh,
have autoimmune diseases or at the very
least a systemic inflammation.
That's fascinating.
And that's caused by your body
processing too much glucose.
It's not caused by your body processing
too much glucose as it is.
Uh,
it's a side effect of it.
Yeah.
There's a,
um,
because it's not the glucose it's
causing that in that case is now we
moved on from sugar and glucose being a,
a cause of inflammation to,
um,
uh,
certain elements in Ho let's say whole
grains that turn on certain genes that
cause certain responses,
one of which may be in some people to
open the junction between the cells
lining the gut and allow undigested food
particles,
shall we say.
Uh,
to,
to enter the bloodstream.
Now the body sees those undigested food
particles,
which the gut is only supposed to really
allow in a free fatty acid,
simple sugars.
Um,
and,
uh,
you know,
amino acids,
single peptides die,
peptides may be,
but if you get a large undigested food
particle in the bloodstream,
sometimes the body goes,
hey,
that's a,
that looks like a bacteria.
We better go get that thing and set up
an or an immune response to it.
So you get an initial form of
inflammation where the body's just
saying,
look,
there's some foreign matter in the
bloodstream.
We don't recognize it.
We're going to kill it.
And that's sort of bad enough in it,
in and of itself.
But if you,
if you,
um,
if that continues long enough for some
people,
sometimes that,
uh,
inflammatory response that,
that immune response,
now it goes to look for similar
molecules and it might see,
uh,
a,
a Beta cell and the pancreas and go,
oh,
that looks just like that other thing.
I just set up a response for let's go
kill this.
Or it might do it with,
um,
the,
in cells and the joint,
the chondracytes in the joint.
And you may get rheumatoid arthritis as
a result of it.
That's an autoimmune response to body
set up,
setting up an immune response to itself.
So when you hear people talk about
gluten sensitivity and you know,
people are trying to go gluten free,
do you think that a lot of,
a lot of what that is,
is the body responding to an excess of
this glucose in the body,
uh,
excess of focus in the two different
things.
So the glucose is one thing that the
sugar is,
is what it is that from breaking down
breads and Pastas or,
or candy or cakes or pies or um,
you know,
um,
snickers,
whatever it is,
our soft drinks,
which is a huge issue,
um,
cause softdrinks or,
or a large part of the problem.
But gluten is a different,
an entirely different mechanism.
Now we're talking about,
uh,
a protein,
a protein.
It's a plant protein is folded so
densely that there,
the theory is that humans haven't had
enough.
Most humans haven't had enough time to
adapt to,
uh,
the digestion of that type of a
molecule.
And as a result,
uh,
there,
it causes problems within the lining of
the gut.
Right.
But what I was getting at was the p
people always talk about having gluten
sensitivity,
but really what you're saying is that a
lot of what people are having issues
with is these simple carbohydrates is
like breads and pastas against,
sorry.
Sorry to be,
that's just,
there's like two parts to this equation,
right.
And
either part is kind of bad,
um,
and together they're kind of like,
why would you do that?
So,
so on the,
on the glucose side,
and it's just unfortunate.
Gluten and glucose have the first glu
but they're not related.
So,
so on the Gluco side,
that's the sugar,
that's the,
that's the thing you want to avoid.
Partly because the,
one of the other things that happens is
even if you don't have an inflammatory
response,
it raises insulin.
Insulin is a,
is a storage hormone that tends to take
every calorie you ate at the last meal
in excessive what you needed and store
it as fat.
Now,
if you're a skinny,
uh,
east African marathoner,
then you're going to burn it off.
But if you're a typical American eating
couple hundred extra calories a day in
the form of this sugar,
you tend to store it as body fat.
And if you haven't built a mechanism to
burn off the body fat that causes
problems over time,
that increases your risk for cancel,
that,
that increases your risk for heart
disease.
That increases your risk for type two
diabetes.
I don't think I have gluten sensitivity,
but I do know that when I went,
when I decided to go gluten free,
I kind of quit it after a while,
but I did it for about six months.
My face got thinner,
a lost body fat.
I had more energy,
I felt better.
And uh,
I attributed it.
I was trying to figure out what it was,
but I tried.
I don't think I have a gluten
sensitivity.
I just attributed to the fact that
eating all that pasta and breads and all
those things was just giving me all this
extra sugar,
eliminating that from my diet made a
difference and that,
so that is the sort of the first line of
defense for a lot of people who want to
lose weight.
It's just just by getting rid of those,
those foods,
and I want to say limiting yourself,
but you know,
including meat,
fish,
fowl,
eggs,
nuts,
seeds,
all the vegetables,
a little bit of fruit,
healthy fats,
oils and nuts.
Um,
you know,
that's a pretty nice plate of food that
you can offer yourself up.
Um,
as long as you get rid of the,
the,
the carbohydrates,
the simple carbohydrates,
you're well on your way to re reducing
the,
the excess body weight,
which includes the excess retain water
in the fullness and the face and all the
things that we talk about.
Now if you give those up and you find
that you,
that your joints work better or that you
have,
uh,
you know that your immune system works
better,
you don't get sick as often,
which is what a lot of people notice.
Now we probably are looking at the fact
that you might have some,
some level of sensitivity to gluten and
gluten sensitivity exists on a spectrum
of no problem at all to I'll die if I
eat it.
And you could be anywhere in the middle
anywhere on that spectrum.
I mean this again sort of the operative,
a mantra here,
no,
no right or wrong,
no black or white,
no,
no good or bad,
just choices.
But if you're a person who really wants
to dig deep and kind of make those,
those changes that are going to get you
closer to your goal quicker,
that might be a choice that you might
look into.
So there's no right or wrong,
but there is a spectrum in terms of
tolerance.
Your tolerance might be much better than
mine and some people just really
shouldn't have it in the Diet at all.
Whether some people can have a fairly
good amount of it and really not have
too many issues.
Yeah.
We say what,
you know,
what can I get away with?
And that's,
that's sort of an interesting concept in
and of itself because people,
humans,
you know,
we tend to see what we can get away
with.
You know,
you might save saves,
this is,
this is really good for me and,
um,
or this is really bad for me.
I'm never going to do it again.
But if I don't die from it and it,
there's no consequences,
then I'm going to take it right up to
the edge and sometimes a little bit past
the edge.
So there are a lot of people who can get
away with eating a lot more
carbohydrates than others,
even though they don't train hard and
maybe not gained that much weight.
There are a lot of people who can get
away with,
uh,
with consuming,
um,
you know,
Omega six oils and not get into that
proinflammatory state as readily or as,
or as quickly.
You just,
you know,
as,
as Ronald Reagan said,
you know,
man's got to know his limitations or it
was that dirty Harry,
one of the both.
But I think it was dirty Harry.
Yeah,
I think,
I think Reagan restated it later on,
but yeah,
so,
uh,
I was reading this article yesterday and
I talked about this yesterday in the
podcast about this woman who,
uh,
she wrote this article about she's in
her seventies and how her whole life
people have been shaming her for being
fat and she was sort of like trying to
promote fat acceptance.
And you know,
and I,
when I,
when I see articles like that,
there's two reactions.
One reaction as,
as,
as a human being.
I look at her and I say,
oh,
this poor lady,
you know what a fucking shitty roll the
dice.
She's gotten life and she's been
overweight her whole life feeling fat
and gross and she's trying to get people
to lay off her,
leave me alone.
And she sort of,
it's a very biased account and not
science or exercise physiology based
where she sort of describing all the
various times in her life where people
have said she's unhealthy.
But meanwhile she's been very active and
she like lists all the different things.
She did tree climbing and hiking and all
this different stuff.
Right?
Which obviously to a guy like you or
someone like me who knows a lot about
competitive athletics and like the uh,
the amount of calories she's actually
burning out versus putting in,
it's probably skewed.
It's probably fucked up.
And I don't,
she didn't really discuss the actual,
what she was actually eating.
She was talking about very bland foods
and a thousand cars a day the doctors
are trying to put her on,
which is the wrong approach.
Right?
Absolutely.
And it's really,
when I,
when I see things like that,
I don't see a woman who's like 70 years
old who's coming to accept the fact that
she's overweight and it's no big deal.
And who,
you know,
everybody's got these,
ideas about body image that they're
based on skinny supermodels that are
actually anorexic.
And yeah,
I usually just leave me alone and I'm
plump and I'm healthy and everything's
fine.
I don't buy it.
I,
I look at that and I say,
this poor lady has been given a bad set
of directives.
She's been getting given bad information
as far as her diet.
And you don't have to be fat like you
can,
you can eat healthy foods and,
and you know,
and live a healthy life and your body
would lose a lot of weight
just eating healthy foods.
That's absolutely true.
And so that,
that brings us back to this,
you know,
this idea of,
um,
good or bad and,
and judgment because you know,
people self judge,
people judge other people.
Um,
I have to be very careful,
uh,
when I look at people not to make that
judgment.
I mean,
my tendency is to,
is to say to myself,
Holy Shit,
I could,
I could fix that person or I could help
that person.
You know what I mean?
And people resist that.
Well,
and I don't do it.
I mean,
I say it to myself because it's,
it's pretty clear that,
um,
you know,
you have to want to change.
And,
and we,
we talked about what,
you know,
what can I get away with?
Well,
if I can get away with being fat and
people still reasonably like me,
then I don't have to do the work and
therefore not motivated to do what it's
going to take to get to that point.
Um,
but it's,
uh,
it's a,
it's a slippery slope with,
with talking with people about,
you know,
like what's the ideal body composition,
right?
It's,
um,
the ideal body composition is where your
body says back to you,
Joe,
man,
I love what you've done with the place.
This is phenomenal.
You know,
you've lost 50 pounds,
not you,
but you know,
you're,
you don't get sick as often.
You've got all the energy you want,
you maintain it.
Uh,
without a lot of,
uh,
you know,
dieting or anything like that.
You eat pretty much,
you know,
how you know you're supposed to eat,
but you're never hungry.
That's your ideal body composition,
man.
And if it doesn't look like the cover of
muscle and fitness or shape magazine,
so be it.
Um,
by the way,
I can get you to that point for a lot of
people where you are on the cover of
shape magazine or muscle and fitness,
but it's going to cost and it's going to
cost not in money,
but it's going to cost and sacrifice and
discipline and pain and,
and hating life.
So,
you know,
the science can get us there,
but is it worth the life?
The,
the main thing we do at the primal
blueprint is we try to live an awesome
life.
So,
so in fact,
my tagline is primal blueprint live
awesome.
Living awesome means enjoying as much of
every moment,
every day as you can extract and the
greatest amount of pleasure,
whether it's movement,
whether it's with friends,
whether it's food,
um,
again,
with the least amount of pain,
but in a way that's sustainable.
So it,
it,
it not only benefits you right now and
today,
but over the long haul,
you're going to live longer.
You can be happier.
Um,
you won't get sick,
you won't tap into your 401k to pay for
a $200,000,
whatever,
uh,
operation.
Um,
it's about,
it's about how can I enjoy life right
now today,
now back to the overweight person who's
trying to,
trying to get to that point.
And I,
I see a lot of,
you know,
overweight people are quite happy I
guess.
Um,
but I see a lot of others who are maybe
hiding it and going,
you know,
I'm,
I'm the jolly,
you know,
fat person.
But inside I'm,
you know,
I'm,
I'm the sad,
whatever the sad clown.
Um,
you got to deal with that,
that,
you know,
there's a lot of,
and there's a lot of baggage.
So some of this stuff comes from the,
the changes you make in your diet.
So there's a lot of easy things that we
do.
I can,
I can write anybody a program that
they'll love that,
that says,
um,
you know,
we're gonna,
we're gonna have a buttered coffee for
breakfast.
We're going to have a two eggs and a
little bit of Bacon.
We'll have a salad with some salmon on
it for lunch,
we'll have whatever and they'll never be
hungry and you'll start to burn fat and
life will be wonderful.
And um,
and sometimes they'll get to a plateau
and they'll go,
what happened mark?
I did everything right.
Well,
you know,
you went from,
you're a woman,
you went from two 25 to one 75.
You know,
you still have some work to do,
but for right now you're at your ideal
body composition because in terms of
your body,
the body,
it's a survival mechanism.
You know,
if you,
if we get to this,
you know,
this sort of,
um,
uh,
secular,
or you know,
discussion about life and what we're,
what we're,
what we're after.
The human body is a vessel designed to
carry two strands of RNA DNA into the,
into the future.
And it's a bizarre permutation of
several hundred million years of
evolution.
But the bottom line is the body is,
is designed to survive long enough to
procreate.
And that's,
that's the reality of human and
evolution and the fact that we live
longer and we enjoy life.
This is all wonderful in icing on the
cake.
But from the body's perspective,
your ideal body composition is that
composition at which again,
you don't get sick,
you move around,
great.
Um,
you,
uh,
you know,
you can meet a mate,
uh,
you have all the energy you want.
You're not hungry.
So that's it.
If it's,
if you're a woman and that's one 75 for
now,
you get,
you got to go.
This is fabulous.
I embrace this.
I feel good at,
you know,
whatever.
Now,
if you want to get dropped the next 25
pounds,
okay,
now we got to look at refiguring that
the diet out and adding some sprints in
there and doing some,
some little tweaks in there and we'll,
we'll,
we'll get down there,
but it requires number one,
um,
I identifying an appreciation for what
you've done so far to get to where you
are.
A number two,
it requires acknowledging any past
insults in your,
in your life.
And there's a lot of stuff going on in
the mind and the brain that wants to
keep people a protected with armor.
Um,
whether it's,
um,
sexual abuse,
whether it's,
uh,
you know,
verbal abuse,
uh,
some,
you know,
scenario that happened in childhood.
There are a lot of people carrying a lot
of emotional baggage around with them
that in some cases,
if you dealt with it,
you know,
in an inappropriate manner that might
free you up to lose a little bit more
weight.
And I've seen this happen.
So when you're saying armor,
do you mean in terms of like emotional
armor or is it the body fat that they
keep on top of them?
Is it almost like a distraction or is it
the food that distracts them?
The overconsuming of food to sort of
nullify the effects of the abuse or
whatever trauma.
It could be any of those,
any of those and all those.
Um,
but it's,
I see it fairly,
um,
where people will,
you know,
do everything right and then hit a
plateau and wonder what I need to get to
the next level.
And do you got to,
sometimes you need to really do the deep
work.
Yeah.
Why,
why?
I tried to explain to someone when they
try to gain weight when people are
carrying,
I want to,
I want to put some muscle on.
Um,
I tried to explain to people that like
that that is not an easy thing to do.
And matter of fact,
your body doesn't want to do that.
Your body has a limited amount of
resources and it does not want to spend
resources created on this extra muscle.
And in order to do that you have to be
uncomfortable.
Like this is the only way.
And people say,
Oh,
I've been doing all this lift and I'm
not getting any weight.
Well you probably lifting not enough
weight.
You're not putting in enough intensity.
You're not a,
you're not eating enough.
I mean in order you have to get your
body to say,
all right,
this has hall wants to do dead four days
a week now or squats or you know,
he,
he's doing all this heavy stuff.
We have to adjust accordingly because
the,
the environment in which we're existing
in obviously changed and now we are
going to need a lot more muscle.
No,
I mean,
that's again,
the nature of the human body is to
preserve itself,
to pass the genetic material along to
the next generation.
Part of that preservation is,
I don't want to waste precious resources
building something that I won't need,
right?
So,
um,
in,
in a lot of people,
how that manifests itself is if you
don't lift weights,
you don't have any muscle.
So you have this lack of muscle,
this lack of,
of,
of um,
uh,
of muscle mass.
And you know,
he said,
well,
what,
what's wrong with that?
I'm skinny.
Well,
you know,
you could be skinny,
but you could be what we call skinny
fat,
no muscle.
You got a little bit of excess fat,
you're memory,
more prone to getting type two diabetes.
But almost more importantly,
if you don't train,
and as you get older,
it becomes more and more important to
maintain muscle mass.
Um,
people don't die of old age.
They die of organ failure because they
just,
you know,
something wasn't keeping up with the
body.
But the concept of dying of old age is
kind of ridiculous when you think about
it.
So the typical old age scenario is you
got a 75,
85 year old man or woman,
hasn't done anything active for years.
So there's no muscle mass.
Um,
and because there's no muscle mass and
they haven't done anything active,
the bones,
there's no bone density.
So the bones go,
hey,
I don't,
I don't want to,
I don't need to build a structure
because this clown isn't going to the
gym and doing anything to require it.
So I'm going to,
um,
save resources,
not build bone density.
The muscles are not building bone mass.
Now the heart's going,
this is easy.
I can pump blood all day at at 5% of my
volume or maybe 15% of my volume.
The lungs go,
Hey,
I,
you know,
there's no,
no requirement for excess oxygen.
This,
this clown's just sitting around in a
chair all day or you know,
watching tv or doing minimal activity.
So the lungs,
they sort of ceased to function at full
capacity.
Same with the liver,
same with the kidneys.
And as,
as you go down this path,
then one night you get up to take a leak
and you trip over the cat and you fall
and you break your hip cause of bone
density sucks.
And now you wind up in the hospital and
you get pneumonia and you die because
the lungs can't expel the sputum for the
pneumonia and,
and the heart can't keep up.
So you maybe you die of congestive heart
failure.
I mean,
this is a very typical scenario for a
lot of people and it all goes back to
creating a need for the body to want to
change that.
Great.
Um,
Vince Vaughn and Jennifer Aniston movie
where,
how dare you say that there you say that
great.
Vince Vaughn,
Jennifer Aniston movie gnosis things
ever.
Sorry.
There was a great line in,
uh,
in a mediocre Vince Vaughn,
but you're the one I'm talking about
where she,
they're,
they're having a fight and uh,
and she says,
honey,
come help me do the dishes.
He goes,
no,
that's all right.
I'm going to watch the game.
And she goes,
no,
help me do the dishes.
He goes,
Nah,
I'm just,
that's all right.
I'm going to be over here watching the
game.
I just watched the game.
She goes,
come help me do the dishes.
He goes,
all right.
All right.
I'll come help you do the dishes.
She goes,
nevermind.
I don't want you sh.
He says,
why?
I don't want you to help me do the
dishes.
I want you to want to help me do the
Oh,
Christ.
Right,
so get a new chick.
The so the body,
the body,
sorry about that was an arcane movie
reference,
but the boss,
you got to give the body the body needs
to want to change and you do that by
using your,
your brain to elect to go to the gym and
lift weights or to embark on a,
on a,
a more rigorous and strenuous regimen
than you had previously encountered.
Well,
changing patterns is very difficult for
people.
That's why New Year's resolutions are
always such a joke because everybody,
I mean,
the amount of people that stick to those
things that they prescribed on January
1st like this is it.
I'm going to write it down.
I'm going to January 1st from here on
out.
It's all salads and salmon and running
up hills and then come February 13th for
lucky fucking over.
So over your right,
back to the same thing.
So sustainability is a huge part of
this,
uh,
of any program like that and that
changing patterns.
And that's what we like about the primal
blueprint is that the foods are
sustainable.
So I mean literally and figuratively,
the Diet,
the eating strategy is a sustainable
strategy.
Rule number one is you never let
yourself go hungry.
You just,
instead of eating a Bagel in the middle
of the afternoon,
you know,
you eat a spoonful of coconut butter or
something that's got fat in it that
satisfies and you scoop coconut butter
for a snack.
Coconut butter,
just butter.
You know,
like the peanut butter.
Oh hell yeah.
You just take a scoop of that.
Not,
but not coconut people just checked out.
They're like,
this fucking guy's,
well,
should we talk about the same thing?
Coconut butter,
I like peanut butter.
That's the meat of a coconut.
It's like what's in an almond joy?
I want to fucking cook.
Like I don't want a candy bar.
I don't want a god Damn Colantoni man.
Okay.
So you have to suspend disbelief a
little bit here and a humor me,
go buy a jar of coconut butter and try
it instead of a cookie or whatever.
Do you participate in any sort of
intermittent fasting?
Not really.
And I'll,
I'll tell you why.
Um,
this is again about seeing what we can
get away with.
And I'm pretty lucky that I can,
I can get away eating what I eat.
Now I have,
on the other hand,
it compressed eating window.
So you could argue that I intermittently
fast every day.
So I,
I eat from 1231 o'clock to 7:00 PM and
then I don't eat again.
So you don't eat it all in the morning?
It's,
no,
there's no concept of the word breakfast
for me.
I have a cup of coffee and that's it.
So I'll go to the gym fasted,
I'll do whatever workout I'm doing,
whether it's a heavy weight workout or
whether it's,
I mean,
it could be a leg day,
could be,
you know,
uh,
intervals on a bike.
It could be a two hour paddle faster.
You find that when you do that,
that you have less energy than if you
have like some fruit.
The difference here is I'm really good
at burning fat,
so I derive my energy from stored body
fat better than a lot of people.
Not because I'm genetically gifted in
that way,
but because that's how I've lived my
life.
That's how I've orchestrated my eating
strategy over the past 15 or 20 years.
So I become,
I wake up,
I have all the energy I need.
I don't need to tap into the stored
glucose in the form of glycogen in my
liver or in my,
uh,
in my muscles.
So you essentially have you follow a
Ketogenic Diet?
Yeah,
but it's not ketogenic.
So it's,
it's a high fat,
moderate protein,
moderate carb diet.
But I have enough carbs.
I have maybe a hundred to 130 grams of
carbs a day.
Uh,
which would be in,
in,
in no one's estimation would that be
ketogenic?
But I'm good at burning fat because I've
spent enough time in that sort of low
carb area.
I've built the metabolic machinery to
burn fats really effectively.
So I'd probably,
you know,
I'm just going to suggest that I have a
lot more mitochondria in my muscle cells
then than other people do because of the
restricting the carbs and restricting
the sugars and forcing my body to become
good at burning fat.
How does that work?
So how does that pertain,
baby?
Please tell me.
So how does it promote more
mitochondria?
Well,
when it's called mitochondrial
biogenesis,
so when you are,
when you're born,
you're born again with this recipe that
wants you to become really good at
burning fat and it very quickly you
change the script.
So you,
the parents feed you grool and oatmeal
and why back and toast and whatever and
uh,
and pureed vegetables and you become
very dependent on,
on carbohydrate.
And the body says,
I don't need to burn fat because I'm
getting fed carbohydrate all the time.
And a couple of responses are,
um,
I got to get rid of this excess glucose
because,
uh,
if I don't,
it'll,
it's toxic body shouldn't have more
than,
you know,
90 to 100.
Uh,
your,
your blood sugar count should stay
between say 85 and 70 and a hundred Max.
Um,
what does the number of,
uh,
you know,
milliliters per desk deciliter?
I forget what the exact number is.
They're all over the place with
cholesterol and blood sugar.
But the point is that there's the entire
amount of sugar in your bloodstream
right now is probably the tablespoon,
you know,
five grams of sugar.
Um,
so it's not copious amounts.
And,
and if it rises above that,
you start to get into problems that
sugar can interact with,
with protein molecules and cause a
reactions that lead to a clogging of
arteries,
a destructive,
a destruction of,
of nerve tissue.
That's where the,
the diabetic damage comes from.
Just excessive amounts of sugar that are
in the bloodstream.
So you,
so the body wants to kind of keep that
level low.
Um,
and if you continuously feed it
carbohydrate a all day long,
if you're not burning it off,
if you're not running 20 miles a week,
there's a tendency for the body to store
it,
store the excess as,
as body fat,
uh,
and over time.
For some people that's a real problem.
For others who can get away with it,
not,
not so much a problem.
So we were,
many of us are at grow up depending on
uh,
this carbohydrate as a main source of
fuel.
Uh,
and you know,
you eat a carbohydrate meal,
a high carbohydrate meal causes a surge
of insulin because the insulin is there
to take the glucose out of the
bloodstream and store.
Cause again,
it's dangerous to have too much.
Um,
but the,
sometimes the insulin surge is so great
that it drops the blood sugar and then
you get hungry again a couple of hours
later.
That's why there's these swings
throughout the day.
If you are a sh what we call a sugar
burner.
Uh,
if you,
if you try and look at a way,
a different way to configure your
energy,
um,
uh,
sources.
If you restrict sugar and restrict
carbohydrate a little bit,
you don't have to,
you know,
be draconian about it,
but you start to create the need for the
body to,
to start to burn.
Some of it's stored body fat.
You say,
well,
the body goes well,
if I've,
I've got to save,
saw my glucose from my brain because at
the brain runs on glucose and ketones
and I'm going to,
um,
I'm going to learn how to burn fat more
efficiently.
And in order to do that,
I got to build more mitochondria cause
that's where the fat burns inside the
Mitochondria and explain to people what
Mitochondria.
So Mitochondria are the powerhouses of
the cell.
So every cell has,
most cells have mitochondria in the
muscle.
Cells have lots of Mitochondria that are
creating ATP,
which is the energy currency of the body
uses to move to,
to live,
to exist.
What does ATP sound for a and
triphosphate?
It's a very,
we're not going to get a biochem lesson
right now.
That's okay.
But ATP is,
this is this currency of the body and it
can be recycled using,
um,
certain different pathways,
a glycolytic pathway,
which,
which doesn't require oxygen.
And,
and,
and one of the pathways is,
is using oxygen in the Mitochondria.
So that's a very important place to not
only build more mitochondria,
but improve the efficiency of the
Mitochondria and how that happens.
And this is the elegance of this again,
is it certain signals that you give the
body by,
by cutting back on the amount of
exogenous carbohydrate you take in those
signals go directly to the cells that
say,
I've got to make more Mitochondria.
And then unique to every other organelle
in the body.
Mitochondria have their own DNA.
Um,
no other organelle within a cell has it,
but Mitochondria had their own DNA and
the DNA and the Mitochondria go,
well,
we better be more efficient at what we
do.
So you upregulate the mitochondrial
biogenesis,
the creation of more Mitochondria,
and you upregulate the efficiency of the
Mitochondria all done at the level of
gene.
All done through a signal that you gave
by in this case,
restricting carbohydrate.
And it could be increasing the amount
of,
uh,
um,
low level aerobic activity you do
theirs.
And it can be both.
And that we talk about that in,
in my new book,
primal endurance.
Read your new book and I want you to
mark down what he just said,
like the time on the podcast.
What time is it here?
Like,
uh,
an hour and 10 minutes in or something
like that.
Three minutes and 53.
That's it.
Okay.
Um,
that's very important.
I'd never heard that before.
I did not know that your body can change
the amount of Mitochondria.
Absolutely.
That's,
that's incredible.
That's just from restricting
carbohydrates.
Well,
it's,
it's from a comp.
There are a lot of things you can do it
a certain forms of,
uh,
of weightlifting.
You can do like what,
um,
you know,
you,
you could do,
um,
sustained a maximum power output stuff.
So you know,
you've got a dead lift.
What are you going to dead lift Max of
500,
which are dead lift Max jail,
somewhere around there.
Okay.
So a little heavier than that.
I'm Kinda Yo.
Um,
so you'd,
um,
you'd do a workout in the gym where you
do 80% of your,
of your Max,
a se to 400 pounds,
and you might do it four or five times
and then rest a few minutes and then do
it again,
four or five times and rest a few
minutes and do it again and do it
instead of doing three sets of 10 of
whatever it is you're going to do.
Um,
you,
you load this up,
you load deeper and deeper into the
fibers.
Uh,
to the extent that the workout's over
when you,
when you can only do one,
you know,
and,
and you know,
you can only do one.
You don't even try to get the next one.
The workout's over.
And maybe it's,
um,
maybe that winds up being 15 sets by the
time you're done,
but you've maximally overloaded so much
at a high,
not 100% Max because that's,
now we're talking about danger,
danger,
issue,
but you know,
you can do 80% Max and three or four.
So that's one example of,
of how we can,
and then that'll prompt those muscle
tissues to,
to want to build more Mitochondria.
Because if you probably heard,
you know,
a truly effective weight session causes
you to burn fat throughout the day.
Right?
Yeah.
Well,
it's one of the best ways to get lean.
And it's one thing that people sometimes
aren't aware of.
Most people when they want to get lean,
they think about cardio.
They start doing a lot of extra cardio.
I know
it's weightlifting that really makes you
lean.
Yeah.
No,
I mean,
um,
weightlifting and spreads nothing,
as I say,
nothing cuts you up like sprint hills.
Yeah,
yeah.
Hills really do it.
Um,
when you were talking about increasing
mitochondria,
like how,
how much of an increase are we talking
about?
Double.
Yeah.
I mean,
up to up to double.
Wow.
Yeah.
And what are the other effects of having
double the amount of Mitochondria?
What are the other positive benefits?
It's,
um,
you know,
more energy throughout the day because
now you're so good at burning fat and
you have all this machinery to burn the
fat,
um,
that,
uh,
you,
you're hungry less often.
And you know,
it's interesting when we look back at,
um,
how hunger runs our lives.
And again,
if you look at the carbohydrate sugar
burning paradigm,
you get up in the morning,
have the most important meal of the day.
It might be a bagels and toast.
Special K.
Yeah,
yeah.
Special K,
um,
a glass of juice.
Don't forget,
tell you,
you,
I have that instant sugar water hundred
and 50 grams of sugar before you,
you know,
before you head out the door and you're
not even supposed to have 150 grams of
sugar in a day.
That's what I'm saying.
Yeah,
it was.
Most people said what I'm saying,
I'm saying you're not supposed to have
more than I like one 50 is a max amount
of total carbohydrates that I have in a
day.
So sugar is as a minor minor subset of
that.
And then,
but then,
uh,
you know,
you get to work and 10 30 rolls around
and it's time for a break.
Don't break room,
don't at somebody brought donuts today,
shelly.
Uh,
and then,
you know,
where are we going for lunch?
Ah,
Skoda,
you know,
get a pizza or whatever.
And uh,
again,
another break in the afternoon,
they get home and you have dinner and
maybe you have some ice cream or
something watching tv.
And the next thing you know,
you've,
you know,
you've taken in six,
700 grams of carbs in that day.
Well,
if you're good at burning fat,
the first thing that happens,
you wake up in the morning,
go,
ah,
I don't need to eat.
Really.
I don't feel like I need to eat.
It's,
I'm not hungry.
And,
and one of the things we talk about in
the panel blueprint,
if,
if you're not hungry,
then don't eat.
That's,
these are the signals your body's giving
you.
And if you can get away with not eating,
and when I say don't eat it,
it's clear.
It's important that we have to say,
because I'm not hungry.
If you're hungry,
eat,
but if you're not hungry,
then Eh,
you know,
move on.
Um,
I did,
uh,
a thought experiment a while back and I
thought,
you know,
it's interesting cause when I was,
when I was in college,
um,
every one of my college buddies know me
as Arnold.
They don't even know me as mark.
They call me arnold because when we were
in college,
there was a TV show called green acres,
and there was a pig on the show called
Arnold Ziff.
And I could eat more than anybody in,
in the,
in the college I went to,
including the football team.
And so people would call me Arnold Ziff.
And so I became Ahrens,
Arnie Arnold for most of my life.
It's just because the amount of food,
just because the amount of food I could
eat.
And,
um,
did you have a contests or is this,
everybody knew.
It's like you're going to eat that
dessert.
You're going to eat those,
you're gonna eat that steak.
You can have that.
Um,
but I was running a hundred miles a
week.
I was a skinny shit have weighed 30
pounds less than I weigh now,
but I just,
the throughput was,
was where it was.
And because I had a leaky gut,
probably a lot of it just went right out
the button out the button.
So,
um,
uh,
the thought experiment was that my whole
life I sort of was guilty of this.
Like how much food can I eat and not
gain weight and not be uncomfortable.
You know,
that's,
and I think a lot of people look that
way.
It's like,
all right,
we're going to go eat lunch.
How much food can I eat and a,
and not gain weight or how much of that
cake or that pie can or whatever.
People I think tend to this is this is
the,
what can I get away with part of it?
Well,
what if you shifted that around and you
said,
what's the least amount of food I can
eat and maintain muscle mass and
maintain energy and,
and not get sick and most importantly
not be hungry.
And you find if you do this experiments
pretty interesting.
If you become good at burning fat,
your,
your appetite.
So self regulates and so mitigates that
you find yourself pushing a plate of
food away after a couple of bites or not
being hungry or eating just the right
amount of food to,
to,
to get you through the day.
What do you keep your body fat out?
You know,
so I'm 62 now and build.
Great.
Well thank you.
I mean my people would look at me and
go,
oh,
you must be six,
7%.
No,
probably nine,
maybe nine and a half,
maybe 10%.
Um,
a lot of people lie about their body
fat.
Uh,
you know,
you hear these stories of the wide
receiver that's,
you know,
two and a half,
3% body fat.
It's,
that's not even possible.
It's impossible.
Yeah.
And,
and even with the bodybuilders,
the ones that,
that get down that that lien are so
close to death,
you know,
that's a,
that's dieting down that the day before
the contest to get there and they
better,
they pack it right on afterwards.
So,
so,
um,
yeah,
so the body fat thing is,
uh,
I,
I've stayed at this same V v visible I
should say,
um,
you know,
body fat level
since I was in my twenties.
So this is a result of a lot of
strenuous exercise,
a lot of long distance running,
a lot of the,
the,
the different things that you
participate in as well as this body
burning fat primarily because you're
talking about if you've been in this
same body fat percentage,
most of your life do you haven't
adjusted what usually happens now?
So now forties when you adjusted your,
you're done in my forties.
So,
so what happens now is I,
I don't run at all.
I was a career runner for the first part
of my life and uh,
uh,
I haven't run a mile.
I have not run a mile in like 13 years.
What do you do now for exercise?
So I lift,
uh,
twice a week.
I do an upper body sort of full,
full routine.
I don't separate,
you know,
chest and Tris and back and buys and all
that stuff.
I just do a full routine.
That's a smart way to do it.
That's separating stuff kind of
malarkey.
Well,
it's at separating stuff as if you don't
have a job and it's good for a body
building to go to the gym every day and
do two hours and whatever.
But yeah.
Um,
I,
I try to get some long,
either a paddler a hike in once a week.
Um,
I do a pretty focused a interval ride on
a bike,
but half an hour once a week.
And then my big thing meaning like a
stationary bike,
stationary bike.
And then I,
and I go to the gym,
not to ride the bike,
but to catch up on our reading.
Oh,
okay.
I read while I'm on the bike and
whatever.
Um,
but uh,
then the,
the big workout for me is my Sunday
ultimate Frisbee game.
So you laugh like you get to some
images,
some pastoral hipsters barefoot.
I don't even know exactly what ultimate
Frisbee is.
The greatest game ever been fed.
Lucky you can always,
you've got to get you out.
Joe.
Whole demeanor changed.
Got his smile line.
Your eyes lit up.
What is all,
what are you doing?
Ultimate is just,
um,
it's a,
it's a very fast paced game.
It's played on a field like a football
field or a soccer field.
Two teams trying to advance the Frisbee
down the field by making completed
passes to their teammates.
When you're a pastor,
you can't,
you can't run,
but everybody else on your team is
trying to get open.
So they're running,
trying to get away from their defenders.
You complete a pass and eventually if
you complete a pass over the,
the end zone or the goal line at a point
and a,
but if at any point in time Jamie just
puts them on the board here.
Oh,
there he goes guys.
Yeah,
check that out.
So yeah.
So Watch,
here we go.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
you know any,
at any point in time,
well they need some black people on this
report because first of all,
no,
there's a white guy was running slow.
She definitely got to that anyway.
It's a pretty,
it's a pretty athletic game.
These are,
I don't know who this is.
This is a,
I'll tell you what,
they're not black.
There is a good layout right there.
Okay.
Um,
that was a good catch actually.
No and we,
but we have those every week that we
played a bunch of those.
So it's a very fast paced game.
And if you,
if you lose the Frisbee,
if it's turned over by your teammate,
either drop it or something,
it becomes the other teams,
a frisbee going in the opposite
direction and now you've got to get back
on defense and defend the same guy that
was defending you in most cases.
Okay.
So if you throw the Frisbee and the
other guy doesn't catch it,
then the other team gets it.
Correct.
And then it got to try and do the same
thing.
Interesting.
And so you're sprinting a lot.
A lot.
I mean we have,
you know,
soccer players come out and basketball
players come out and they go,
dude,
this is,
I couldn't walk on Monday after that
game.
That's,
that's just ridiculous.
So you know,
running except ultimate thing except you
know,
eight to ten second bursts.
And how that,
how that plays out for me is,
um,
you know,
some of the recent research is you go,
instead of doing intervals like the old
days,
we do 60 seconds or a minute and a half
interval as a marathon,
or I used to go to the track and do 16
times one half mile,
you know,
uh,
at race pace.
So now we're doing all out sprints,
10 seconds,
15 seconds,
maybe 20 seconds,
but your Max,
Max Max the whole way.
And then,
uh,
sufficient enough rest and come back and
do it again and do it six,
seven,
eight,
five,
six,
seven times and you're done.
That workout is over and you have
accrued the benefits probably at a
greater rate than would have had you
done
the old method of training,
which was to do,
you know,
again,
repeat quarters or 200 or whatever.
So do you think that a lot of what the
old methods were doing was just as,
as people getting through with mental
toughness and you're,
you're getting some benefit of it,
but you're also kind of breaking
yourself down too much?
Yeah.
So most of endurance athletics is,
is pain management and overtraining.
Yeah.
It's like half the races that I was,
I thought I was most prepared for.
Um,
I sucked in because I was overtrained I
left everything on the training field.
That's a big problem with fighters as
well.
With UFC fighters.
It's a gigantic issue.
I'm trying to figure out what is the
right amount of work you should do.
Yeah.
And especially with fighters because in
mixed martial arts or dealing with
different disciplines,
you have your grappling every striking
give,
putting them all together.
You have submissions,
you have takedowns,
you have a bunch of different things
that you have to train as well as
rigorous strength and conditioning
programs.
And there's a lot of debate as far as
what should you put,
uh,
most time and effort into and some of
the more successful people,
it's really an interesting,
have been going away from skill training
during camps when they prepare for a
fight and going almost exclusively to
strength and conditioning programs with
very minimal skill training where the
strength and conditioning program takes
precedent over everything else,
which I find very fascinating.
The idea behind that being you already
know how to fight.
So what they're going to do is get your
body to a place where it can function at
the highest work rate.
And a big factor in that is maintaining
a healthy heart rate and make sure,
making sure that you don't overtrain
making sure that you have enough
recovery time,
100% agree.
Um,
we,
we say that in,
in,
um,
training triathletes and runners here.
You know,
the amount of time you spend on the bike
after you've been doing it for a couple
of years,
you know,
how to ride.
So let's train the component.
Let's break the race down into its
component parts.
You know,
how can you,
how could you sustain your power over
the next three hills to where your
output on the third hill is essentially
the same as it was in the first hill
versus in the old days where you are
100% going over the first hill and at
90% over the second hill in 77% going
over the third hill because you didn't,
you hadn't trained that part of your,
of your,
um,
in your,
in your regimen that one of the things
we say to endurance athletes is how many
races have you finished where you were
out of breath and maybe you had to
sprint,
you know,
to,
because you were neck and neck with some
guy.
But most endurance athletes don't finish
a marathon out of breath because long
ago their form fell apart.
Um,
their,
their muscle tissue started to break
down because they hadn't trained for
sustained power.
And so the,
the,
the aerobic part of it was like,
feel we could do this all day long.
You're just going slow because you
didn't,
you didn't train appropriately.
So there's some strength training
components like even to something like
marathon running.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
So now we're,
we're saying that the next,
you know,
the next breakthroughs in in marathon
running will come from somebody who has,
who has trained Quito genically and,
and we didn't talk about that yet,
but you know,
has restricted carbs to the extent that
they,
um,
cyclical.
He,
they know how to access ketones,
which are a byproduct of fat metabolism
and they can use the ketones in place of
glucose or glycogen.
Uh,
they can use the ketones to fuel the
brain to,
to will them to continue the pace
they've done the work in the gym where
they can maintain a sustained power
output over 26 miles and not have it
fall apart and not have formed breakdown
22 miles into the race.
Uh,
and,
and if you put all of these,
these different component parts
together,
now you and do it with a,
with an elite,
a world class athlete,
you know,
now you look at,
at the next level of records being
broken,
the problem is it's so antithetical to
the way we trained for the last 40 years
that you take,
uh,
an elite,
um,
professional runner who's already had
some amount of success.
And you go,
dude,
uh,
we want to shift everything around.
It's going to cost you the next 18
months to adapt,
but there's a good chance that you'll be
better.
The guy's gonna go,
ah,
you know,
so hard for his.
Yeah.
And it's so hard.
Well,
it's so hard to,
to give up something and give up
something that's working right.
You know,
to,
to get to that.
Yeah.
Um,
I want to go back to something you said
while you were just explaining that,
that you,
you get someone to train ketogenic.
Yup.
And what do you mean by that?
So now you,
there are periods of time when you're
restricting carbs so much that you're,
you're creating a more ketones,
which are this byproduct of fat
metabolism.
So you've already become good at what we
call your become fat adapted.
As we say,
you become good at burning fat and now
you're building further metabolic
machinery.
That access is ketones better.
So now ketones,
which we we refer to as the fourth fuel.
So you'd have proteins,
fats,
carbohydrates,
ketones are the fourth fuel,
the body.
Uh,
we evolve to use ketones very
efficiently.
There was,
there were times throughout millions of
years of human evolution where it wasn't
like you skip lunch,
it's like you skipped last week eating
right and you had to maintain muscle
mass and maintain a thought capability
and maintain speed and health,
um,
despite not eating anything.
And the only way to do that was to
access was to access the stored body fat
that you'd stored from overeating or
eating slightly more than you needed be
at the last time there was actually food
present,
which is why we're all wired to overeat.
And this ability to,
uh,
to use the byproduct of the fabric
capitalism to fuel the brain.
So ketones actually the brain loves to
run on ketones.
Uh,
one of the things that happens in
particularly in endurance contest,
and I suspect that happens in mma fights
toward the end of the fight is,
um,
you know,
you,
you feel gassed and you run out,
you starting to,
to run low on glycogen and you're
starting to,
um,
to really feel like the wheels are
coming off.
More often than not,
it's a brain just is a lack of glucose
to the brain.
The brain isn't being powered enough and
the brain goes a timeout.
We gotta,
we gotta,
we gotta pull over the side of the road
and take a nap.
So it'll make you mentally exhausted
because your body's running on glycogen
and glucose rather than exactly.
Exactly.
So,
so when you run out of glycogen and
glucose,
the old theory was,
well,
the reason that you hit the wall in any
of these events are you bonk,
as they say,
uh,
is because you've depleted glycogen so
much.
The muscles can't function anymore.
Well,
the research now shows that you'd never
really deplete the glycogen in the
muscles.
If you go from 500 or 600 grams total in
the body,
you never get lower than one 50.
So there's always some glycogen laughed.
So what's going on?
Well,
it's the brain and its lack of access to
glucose that is shutting you down.
And Tim noakes,
the guy we talked about,
professor Tim noakes at the beginning
of,
of the show here,
um,
he coined a phrase that the central
governor theory of the brain,
and he said,
the reason a lot of people hit the wall
isn't because you're out of glycogen.
But it's because the brain as an
override mechanism says,
in order to prevent further damage,
we have to stop.
And,
and it,
it manifests itself as a system,
as a sensation of tiredness and
whatever.
Now,
if you could find a way to bypass that,
uh,
and,
and keep the brain going,
because remember,
it's,
it's the brain running on glucose,
uh,
that once it runs out of that fuel says,
um,
I'm sensing there's no fuel,
so we're going to pull over.
So that's what ketones do.
So when you become good at accessing
stored body fat in producing ketones,
and you've built the metabolic
machinery,
particularly in the brain,
to use those ketones,
and we know from history and from
genetics and from modern science that
that the brain runs really well on
ketones.
Now you founded a substitute fuel for
glucose,
so you can run out of glucose and yet
the ketones will keep the brain,
you know,
revving and uh,
and,
and guiding you at the same pace again,
provided you've done the,
the work in the gym to maintain the,
um,
the form and the power.
Uh,
and it's,
uh,
so you know,
this is all,
I'm going to say kind of theoretical now
because the real world records haven't
been broken yet.
Some are being broken in the ultra
events,
the hundred mile run.
There are a number of guys doing
ketogenic and low carb training who are
breaking records like crazy.
I'm Zack bitter is a guy who in the in
the lab has shown that he could derive
96% of his total energy running seven
minute miles from fat.
So,
in other words,
it's seven minute miles,
which is like race pace for,
I mean it's,
what am I saying,
race based sprint pace for most people.
It's not that fast for a marathoner or
even an elite runner and elite runner,
but it's a,
it's a substantial patient for,
for a guy running a hundred miles a,
it's a pretty good clip.
And to derive 95 to 96% of all energy
from your stored body fat or from
exaggerates Fathi or eating and just a
tiny bit required from glycogen or
glucose.
I mean I think 30 or 40 years ago we
would've said not only was that
impossible,
that was like twice as it twice times
impossible.
Well,
the benefit of that for athletes has got
to be incredible in terms of motivation,
in terms of enthusiasm towards the end
of the race or an end of a fight or
something along those lines where your
body would run out of the glycogen into
glucose and instead you have fat to
burn.
So your,
your mind doesn't drop off as much.
Your mind doesn't hit that wall.
Right.
That should be she,
I mean,
that alone should be motivation for
people to at least attempt to pursue
that.
Yup.
Now,
when it comes to highly glycolytic,
uh,
experiences like mma and you know,
you can't,
you can't derive a us a substantial part
of your energy from fat that's still has
to come from,
from glycogen.
Why is that?
Well,
because,
uh,
there's a point at which,
your,
your throughput of oxygen,
you know what I'm talking about,
endurance athletes,
they're measuring their output over two,
three,
seven hours.
You know,
now you're talking five,
five,
five minute,
uh,
now you've got a,
you know,
you got to that same output is
concentrated now and you're going,
um,
at a,
at a fairly high rate.
Although,
you know,
I,
you see them,
you know,
they're jumping around and dancing
around and you know,
moving back and forth.
So there's recovery periods in there,
but you still have to have that hundred
percent intense glycolytic output.
So when you're in a hold and trying to
escape or when you're,
you know,
you're trying to defend her and try to
come in for a barrage,
you have to be at 100% of,
of output,
but it's brief periods of time.
So conceivably you could train in the
gym to access that part of,
of your body that Burns fats that Burns
ketones.
Um,
you know,
almost the most important part would be
making weight.
You know,
if you,
if you're look,
especially in mma,
it's about power to weight ratios to a
certain extent.
I mean,
there's a lot of obviously skill,
but,
but a power to weight ratio.
If I'm,
if I'm,
you know,
142 pounds,
I don't know what the weight with the
divisions are,
but if I'm,
if I'm carrying around,
I'm at one 65 and I have to cut down to
one 42 to get to my division.
Um,
I'm going to lose power.
But if I maintain that power and I
never,
I never even get up to one 65 anymore
because I'm not gaining fat because I've
learned how to burn fat and I could stay
effective and functional at,
at,
at the weight that I'm at that has
benefit,
you know,
and it's a power to weight ratio
concept.
You would have to have some sort of a
hybrid diet then yes.
In,
in something like mma.
Yeah,
it was so,
so once you've built the metabolic
machinery to burn fat and to burn
ketones,
it doesn't go away when you start eating
carbohydrates.
So you can,
you can do what we call this cyclical
approach where you spend,
uh,
in,
in the early phases of your training,
you become really good at burning fat
and,
and you do stuff that's,
that's contemplated to,
to make you the best possible fat
burner.
You can pay a,
then you might introduce some
carbohydrates,
uh,
the day before a really hard glycolytic
workout.
It doesn't,
that doesn't turn off your fat burning.
That doesn't even really negatively
impact your ability to handle ketones if
you do it for six weeks.
And you do nothing but cars for six
weeks,
then it all shifts back again.
Upregulation and downregulation of of
enzymes based on gene input,
a gene expression.
But if you built the metabolic machinery
and you keep coming back to it,
then you can craft a strategy where you
say,
well,
tomorrow we're just going to do,
um,
100% glycolytic stuff.
It's gonna be be prepared to puke all
afternoon or whatever.
You have a,
you know,
150 grams of carbs and the sweet potato
that for dinner that night you topped
off your glycogen stores,
you're still good at burning fat.
You have all the glycogen that you even
could possibly have loaded if you'd just
been a carbohydrate based athlete ever
since.
You just pick the,
the times when you're going to up the
ante with,
with ex extra carb intake and you make
sure it's not sugar,
but it's,
you know,
a good,
um,
you know,
a starchy carb in this case,
something like a sweet potato or you
know,
yam or something like that.
So how do you regulate the amount of
sugars that are in your body?
Do you limit the amount of fruit that
you eat?
Do you uh,
or how do I,
can you eat as much fruit as you like or
is that not a good idea?
It's just not a good idea.
It's just,
it doesn't,
uh,
most fruit,
some amount of fruit is good.
But I think what,
what cracks me up is number of people to
say I'm on a,
I'm on a very healthy diet.
I'm eating a,
you know,
12 servings of fruit a day and I go to
Jamba juice and I get a big fruit
smoothie and I go,
dude,
you're taking it more sugar than,
you know,
the guy is drinking two,
six packs of coke.
So even sugar that comes from fruit is
not necessarily healthy.
Correct.
Now again,
all these things exist on a spectrum,
right?
I might have blueberries every day
because I love blueberries.
Grew up in Maine,
you know,
picking them wild.
So I love blueberries,
but they're low in sugar,
they're Tart,
they've got antioxidants in them,
and I don't overdo them,
but you know,
you will limit yourself to like a cop or
something like that.
I don't even limit at look at for 99 a
pack for organic blueberries.
I limit myself based on budget,
not on right on any other metric.
Um,
how many servings of fruit will you
allow yourself in a day?
Oh,
just because I don't feel the need to
eat fruit.
It doesn't,
it doesn't,
I don't have a craving for it.
Um,
maybe made a,
maybe two servings is the most elliot in
a day.
Some days.
None.
Um,
but I don't,
you know,
bananas,
um,
some of the citrus fruits,
some of these things can be way over
done pretty quickly.
And I'm not necessarily saying don't eat
fruit.
I'm just saying don't consider fruit the
healthiest possible alternative to,
you know,
bread and pasta and then replace all of
the calories you've got from bread and
pasta and cereal and whatever.
Don't replace that with fruit,
but figure out a way,
like vegetables for the most part are
the ideal source of carbohydrates in our
diet.
They're locked in his fibers matrix.
Um,
it's,
you know,
they're basically low glycemic index,
so they kind of drip into the
bloodstream at a,
at a reasonable pace.
Don't cause a huge surge in glucose.
So celery with coconut butter would be a
much healthier alternative than a
banana.
That's it.
Again,
not that healthy.
Healthier is the wrong term.
And we were making choices here based on
what we're trying to accomplish.
No good or bad,
no right or wrong,
but,
but in a,
in a,
you know,
like in a perfect world,
celebrate the coconut butter is a great
choice.
And a banana at the right time is maybe
a better choice,
like postworkout bananas,
good choice.
I mean,
it depends on who you are.
If I fast after the workout too,
because that's kind of interesting.
There's so much of,
of these little nuanced science bits
that you pick up.
And I've been in the supplement business
for 30 years designing supplements for
other companies.
And one of the supplements I made a
bunch of years ago,
um,
for a very large company today,
was a post workout drink and everybody
loved it and everybody thought it was
the greatest thing they'd ever tasted.
And it was in,
it had,
um,
uh,
you know,
had it had carbohydrates and it had some
protein.
It had some creatine and it was great
drink.
But the purpose of the drink was to
recover from the hard workout you did
today.
So you could do the bitch again
tomorrow.
And that's not how I train anymore.
So I don't do two hard days in a row.
So for that particular purpose,
if you're going to train hard every day
and you want to replace glycogen,
then that's a strategy.
And that's a choice.
If he say,
well,
we're going to do some hard glycolytic
work today,
we're going to,
for whatever reason,
going to do some hard glycolytic work
tomorrow,
then then let's have a post workout,
high carb,
relatively high carb,
um,
supplement because there's this window
in which the body manufacturers glycogen
refills glycogen stores at a higher
rate,
just workout.
That was the whole reason for the
postworkout meal.
That's why people like to drink
chocolate milk.
Exactly.
But if you are,
um,
you know,
so,
so if you're going to go,
uh,
from day to day,
then that's probably a good thing.
Now,
another strategy would be to go really,
really hard today.
Do a deep leg day and then fast.
Well,
what happens when you fast is you don't
replenish the glycogen but you preserve
the pulse of,
of growth hormone and testosterone that
happens as a result of the leg day,
which we you would otherwise blunt by
taking in a sugary drink.
Whoa.
Okay.
So again,
these are,
it's,
it's complex and yet it's pretty cool.
The science is pretty cool.
So,
uh,
insulin,
has an effect on growth hormone and
testosterone actually lowers it.
So if you are eating a,
were a,
a post workout meal that's high in carbs
because you want to refill the glycogen
stores so that you can do it again
tomorrow.
Um,
then the postworkout meal will cause a
rise in insulin,
which will blunt the glycogen,
excuse me,
the growth hormone and testosterone
pulse that you got from that workout.
But you'll have glycogen stores slightly
more ready for the hard work out again
tomorrow.
Now what are you trying to accomplish
here?
What what I'm saying is I'd rather just
do the workout really hard,
get all of the benefits,
the growth benefits then looking for and
not have to do it again tomorrow I want
to work as little as pot I want.
If I want to do a leg day and Puke,
you know because of it today I don't
want to do it again tomorrow.
I only working out to get the benefits.
I'm not working out for the sake of
working out.
I'm not working out every single day
because I just love to go to the gym and
some people do by the way,
and I'm not going to judge that,
but if I'm working out to get the most
amount of benefits I can from the work
that I've chosen to do and in this case
that includes my strategy post workout.
That makes sense.
It does,
but it's fascinating because I've never
heard that before.
There's a catch 22.
So refueling the glycogen levels
actually deplenishes though it blunt.
Blunt is the best word.
Yeah.
Deplenishes I sent even a word.
I like it.
You make it up.
Let's trade trade market right now to
plan it.
Just,
I said it like it was real too.
Um,
but I've never heard that before.
So there's,
there's gotta be catch 22 in there then
it seems like.
So is there a negative effect of having
those hard workouts more than one day in
a row?
And would you be better off in,
would you gain more if you went the way
you're doing it by not replenishing,
I'm saying you do.
Wow.
Now it's even for an elite athlete
that's competing in a sport like say
mixed martial arts or something along
those lines.
Yup.
Well,
it depends on what the game plan is for
the week and what the game plan is to
get you into the ring or to get you to
the starting line.
And in this case,
if,
if we say,
um,
you know,
you're doing,
um,
uh,
let's just use a leg day again,
you know,
you're doing hard legs,
you don't want to do it again tomorrow.
So there's no need to,
to take the post workout drink because
here's what else.
The other thing that happens is if you
have,
if you wait a couple of hours,
maybe you have an hour or two,
you have a meal,
but it's not even a high carb meal.
It's just a regular meal.
It's not high carb.
It's not contemplated to,
to increase glycogen stores,
but within that meal and within the next
meal and within the next meal,
your body will riff.
It'll replenish glycogen.
Eventually it'll,
it,
it wants to do that.
It's not,
you're not preventing it from
replenishing glycogen.
So there's no immediate urgency to do it
with a,
with a post workout drink.
If the meals for the rest of the day or
the next morning have some amount of
carbohydrate,
some of which will go to replenishing
glycogen.
So you might wind up instead of having
restored,
you know,
275 grams of glycogen.
Yeah.
Restore 230 big deal.
What about the benefits of forcing your
body to do more work to up your
conditioning level and would that be
mitigated or wood with some like what
you will your strategy being too,
not replenish the stores after the
workout and to not have those hard
workouts two days in a row?
If you,
if you instead had the hard workout
when,
through your idea of allowing your body
to have its natural,
uh,
uptake of testosterone and growth
hormone because of that hard workout,
then giving yourself adequate time to
recover before engaging in the next hard
work.
I would you in fact have more progress
then keeping slamming your head up
against the wall,
which is at least with like,
uh,
wrestlers and for mixed martial artists,
a lot of the time that's the standard
operational approach is to beat your
body down to be absolutely exhausted.
And you think that's in fact maybe
counterintuitive?
I totally think,
I totally think that is wow.
I mean,
the,
the notion that,
um,
and again this is during sports and,
and mixed martial arts are,
are very similar in it's about pain
management.
It's about,
it's about managing,
um,
literally a pain and perceive pain,
and a exertion over time.
Um,
so you know,
to the extent that you can,
um,
that you can train in the gym in
selective areas that all come together
in the fight.
That's a legitimate choice.
But another choice and the one for the
last 30 years is sort of the rocky
Balboa choice,
which is just go hard every single day
and build up the cause.
Maybe when it comes up,
maybe it's the,
you know,
the fifth round and mental toughness,
um,
really comes to play there and you're
able to dig deeper just because you know
how to beat yourself up.
So it's not to say that one's better
than the other,
they're just alternative strategies.
One of the greatest runners the country
ever produced.
Steve Prefontaine was fairly talented.
He was not the most talented runner in
the world.
And,
uh,
and he would,
he would go to the starting line and
he'd look at some guy who was,
who was clearly a more talented but
hadn't had,
they'd run the Sim similar times and
Prefontaine would look them in the face
and go,
dude,
he said,
you may be more fit and more talented
than me,
but I'm willing to die for this.
I'm willing to hurt more.
And,
and he was,
and that's,
he could dig,
dig deep.
And maybe it was a result of his hundred
and 20 mile weeks of training and,
and beating himself up every day.
I suppose there's value in that in a
sport where you know,
from the time that gun goes off till the
time you cross the finish line,
you never sang to yourself in a
marathon.
Fuck,
this is fun.
Let's do this again.
You know,
you never know if you're at the elite
level,
you never that,
right?
So it's about pain management.
And there's,
there's a legitimate strategy in maybe
having some days where you do what I
outlined and some days or some weeks
where you do what you outlined is,
are they mutually exclusive though?
Like,
here's the question.
do you have to beat yourself up in order
to be mentally tough?
Can't you be mentally tough just through
meditation?
I don't think you have to beat yourself
up to be mentally tough.
And the danger there is you literally
beat yourself up,
but the dangerous you overtrain and
maybe that,
maybe doing that and trying to force
yourself into these mentally tough
exercises is actually a form of weakness
because you're not able to look at your
body objectively.
You're not able to assess it.
And more of a scientific fashion.
I mean,
I'm telling you,
back in the,
back in the day when I was doing
training for marathons and triathlons,
I defined myself worth as based on the
previous workout I'd done,
you know,
and you skip a day and you feel like a
slacker and hoser and a loser.
Um,
and,
and yet,
um,
I,
oh,
I was chronically overtrained all the
time.
I wish I had those days back because,
you know,
I would have,
I would,
my career would have been extended.
On the other hand,
if I had him back,
I probably wouldn't have arrived at
where I am today through the pain and
the suffering and the sacrifice,
you know,
trying to figure out how to fix that.
Yeah.
Um,
my friend Steve Maxwell,
who's a strength conditioning coach,
says that you should monitor your heart
rate every morning and if your heart
rate is over a certain beats per minute,
it's over what?
It's naturally normal,
five plus beats per minute.
You just take the day off.
That's one.
That's one modality.
That's one protocol.
Um,
there's now heart rate variability,
which,
which looks beyond what the heart rate
is.
It looks at the,
at,
at the time between the beats and
suggest that if there's greater
variability,
if there's more time or there's,
there's you know,
0.8 seconds here and 1.1 second here and
0.7 and 1.1 that that's better than
having 0.9 0.9 0.9 0.9.
It's sort of counterintuitive because
you'd think the heart,
you'd want the heart to beat
metronomically.
Yeah.
But if it's beating metronomically it's
a sign of overtraining annually.
Yeah.
It's a sign of,
even if it's a low heartbeat.
Um,
so correct.
If you wake up and you got 40 beats per
minute,
but they're all the same equal beats.
Yeah.
That's not going to happen.
It's typically going to be higher with
if you've overtrained as well as having
a metronomic interval to it now.
Um,
but there are programs you can get so
you can wear your heart monitor and get
these hrv heart rate variability
programs and they'll literally tell you
what the score you for the day till he's
use those.
I don't,
um,
primarily because,
I have a premature ventricular
contractions,
so I'm,
I'm now at 62.
I've been doing this for 40 years.
Um,
actually 50.
I started running when I was 12 a to and
from school,
just like that nut brown African lad,
you know,
with my converse,
uh,
you know,
sneakers on.
And,
um,
so I've been doing this a long time and
I spent so much of my career,
stupidly,
foolishly,
my heart rate,
heart rate out every day.
So I've,
uh,
I've,
I've written about this for the last two
decades about how training for endurance
competition is somewhat antithetical to
health and certainly training the way we
used to,
which is accumulating miles and miles
and miles in,
in,
uh,
at a heart rate that we call the black
hole,
which is,
um,
it's too high to benefit,
uh,
on a regular basis,
but too low to,
um,
to create sort of the interval training
deal.
It's,
uh,
it again explain it in the book,
but we,
we spent years and years and years,
decades training a lot of athletes at
say anywhere from 75 to 85% of their max
heart rate for an hour,
two hours,
three hours at a time.
We'll,
over time the heart responds to that and
gets,
it gets thicker,
the heart muscle gets thicker and
thicker.
Um,
partly it's like the heart can't,
it doesn't have a say in it.
So your brain tells your legs to run
right in the heart goes,
shit,
I gotta I gotta keep up with this cat.
So the heart's pumping away in,
pumping away,
in pumping away.
And if you do this enough,
day in,
day out,
over years,
the heart starts to get damaged a little
bit.
And in some cases it gets thicker.
The ventricle gets thicker and thicker
because it's growing muscle.
Yeah.
But it's,
it's,
uh,
it's not necessarily a good kind of
thicker,
so it's,
um,
it may be stretched,
you know,
too much.
It may just not have,
it may not recover.
When you go to the gym and you say,
we're going to do,
uh,
you know,
200 preacher curls of 75 pounds,
you're,
you're going to say,
well,
you know,
my boss,
well maybe your biceps can handle that
Joe,
but my camp.
So,
um,
you know,
cause they'll,
they'll fry,
they'll shred,
but they feel it.
You feel it.
The pain is there.
Well,
the heart doesn't feel that kind of
pain.
So if you force the heart to calf to
keep up and it's a demand Oregon,
it just,
it just feeds whatever the demand is
from the body.
Uh,
and if that's held at too high a heart
rate for too long,
over decades,
it can manifest itself in problems.
There's item,
there's an epidemic of Afib,
atrial fibrillation in my generation of
runners from that very problem.
So anyway,
having said that,
so I have the occasional premature
ventricular contraction,
which is just a couple of cells in the
heart,
maybe a thickness in the ventricle that
misfire every once in a while.
It's not,
it's not life threatening.
it's just annoying.
But it,
it,
it makes my hrv look really good cause
because there's big interval between
beats sometimes,
you know,
but it's an,
it's a false positive.
Wow.
That's fascinating.
So you don't necessarily monitor your
heart rate because of that?
No.
So you kind of more go on the way you
feel.
Yeah.
And again,
as you know,
I'm at my,
at my age,
I just want to have fun.
I just want to play.
I,
I don't,
I'm not seeking to win any age group
competitions anymore.
Those days are long behind me.
It hurts too much.
It,
it's,
it's too much.
You know,
I'm,
I'm trying to extract the greatest
amount of pleasure out of my life.
So when I,
when I go to the gym,
it's pretty much contemplated to,
um,
to do as little as possible.
That keeps me looking good naked.
But also,
uh,
it keeps me somewhat immune from injury.
It's a very honest of your brother or
whatever,
you know,
a lot of,
I don't even care about that anymore.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
I still going to care about that until
the day I die.
But,
uh,
but,
but for the most part it's about,
um,
it's about avoiding injury when I'm
playing.
So if I'm playing Frisbee,
you know,
I'm,
I'm sprinting,
uh,
I'm,
I'm keeping up with 20 somethings on a,
on a long bomb run to the end zone a and
then have to come up,
turn around and come back and get them
on defense.
Um,
that,
that has some cost attached to it.
Some,
some metabolic costs for an old guy like
me.
So the stuff I do in the gym is trying,
is trying to keep me from getting
injured,
knock wood and uh,
and then I spent time on the paddle for
two hours and it's a best upper body
workout you'll ever get paddling.
Stand up paddling.
Yeah.
And uh,
um,
you know,
it's fun and I don't think,
Oh God,
when's he going to be over?
I'd think,
Oh shit,
I gotta get back cause I've got a
meeting,
you know,
I'm out hanging out with dolphins and
whales and looking down at fish and
catching the wave once in a while.
So I'm trying to,
I'm trying to have,
I'm trying to have fun.
When I,
when I moved,
when I workout,
I did some,
uh,
paddling a few years back.
I did a canoe trip down the Missouri
River and,
uh,
it was,
I was shocked at how tired my arms got.
I'm like,
this is like a legit workout.
Like I thought I was in pretty good
shape.
I'm like,
it's going to be nothing paddling St
Shit.
No,
no,
no.
It's hard.
It takes a good shots when w,
you know,
after paddling,
and that's how I tr I treated it as a
workout too.
Just decided like,
okay,
we're doing this for a couple hours a
day.
I'm going to go hard.
I'm going to just,
I'm going to leave it all out there on
the river,
you know?
And we were with some other guys who
were under the boat.
I was trying to kick their ass.
So I was just trying to stay ahead of
them the entire way and calling them
pussies and yelling at them.
Yeah.
But it's great.
It's lat work out.
It's Serratus,
you know,
it's deltoids,
it's everything.
One of the big issues with a Jujitsu
competitors and,
uh,
people just practice even as a hobby is,
um,
is a joint injuries,
inflammation in the joints and um,
and also spine injuries,
a lot of bulging discs,
a lot of things along those lines.
Do you think that some of that can be
mitigated by reducing the amount of
inflammatory foods?
You know,
you,
you've got such a trauma based sport,
um,
maybe a little,
you know,
if you're,
uh,
if you're 10% less prone to getting the
disc issue or um,
or the joint,
the joint pain as a result.
But a lot of that is just the brute,
just the brute force of the impact and,
and uh,
you know,
that's just,
that's a choice that you make to be in
those sports.
Well,
I'm not
even impact like with grappling,
a lot of it is just,
it's just twisting and twisting and
constant pressure and yeah,
just the day to day grind.
I think Jujitsu is one of those sports
where a lot of recreational
practitioners who get really addicted to
it because it's really fun.
You know,
you're essentially,
you're having a life or death struggle
with someone and you can tap out and
then go right back at it.
And it's,
it's very different than a lot of other,
other martial arts in that way that you
can,
you can kind of do it a full blast,
right.
Whereas sparring,
like kickboxing and things along,
you really can't do it full blast for
very long because the body just can't
take it.
The head can't take it.
Especially.
Yeah.
Um,
but with Jujitsu,
a lot of guys are injured then they,
they just wrap themselves up and kind of
go back in where they say,
oh,
I'm just going to roll light and my next
bother may just lay off my neck.
And I always wonder,
like,
is there maybe a dietary choice that
could perhaps limit the amount of
inflammation that you're experiencing
after these brutal workouts?
It depends.
I mean,
if the,
if the Diet is currently horrendous,
then just probably some amount of,
some amount of,
um,
of,
uh,
you know,
management of that,
that could,
that could be increased in pain
management.
Could be a little bit better and less
inflammation for sure.
But if the Diet's already good,
then um,
you're still,
you're still putting the body through
some unnatural torsions.
I'm just amazed that we were talking
about your hands and arthritis deep into
your forties,
that you were able to mitigate that just
by changing your diet.
It was so powerful.
It was a,
it was really,
actually the most powerful thing for me
was the ibs cause it,
it literally ruined my life or ruled my
life.
Um,
but,
but the arthritis thing was like,
I mean,
I play golf with friends and I was like,
I can't even grip the frig and club the
way I need to.
Yeah.
And now you have no bag.
I'd meet you and I go,
shit,
is joe going to try to out bro,
shake me,
you know,
and take roads,
take me to the ground with,
you know,
with a,
with a firm grip.
Have it when they get the tips here.
Oh Geez.
All silver.
Those tapes of the fingers guys were
shit.
I hate those fucks.
Yeah.
Um,
so that's,
that's very well,
I'm very careful.
Shaking hands too,
because I know a lot of people with
broken hands cause yeah,
fighters especially like after fights
you have to be real careful.
Like I give them like the most gentle
handshake possible.
Um,
what other,
um,
what other ways do you think there are
dietary ways to reduce information other
than a reduction of grains or,
or elimination of grains?
Know I say if you,
if you get rid of the industrial seed
oils,
so you replace the soybean oil,
the canola oil,
the corn oil,
and,
and look at the labels of the
ingredients because they're all over the
place.
The different,
what's the different mechanism in the
body as far as like the way your body
processes s soy or corn oil versus
coconut oil is the profile of fatty
acids.
These are polyunsaturated fatty acids.
Sometimes they're partially
hydrogenated,
sometimes they've got,
they've been processed with,
um,
sort of nasty processing agents like a
nickel.
And,
uh,
they've been,
they've undergone enough alteration that
maybe they contain some transfats.
Transfats are known to be
proinflammatory.
Um,
uh,
the Omega six,
by the way,
Omega six in and of themselves are not,
they're not bad.
They're,
there's Omega three,
there's or make a six or nine to seven.
There's 12.
There's all these,
but the three to six ratio is the one
that's gotten the most pressable s
decade omega three fatty acids that are
found in,
uh,
you know,
fish,
krill oil or fish oil,
things like that that just supplement
with fish oil a little bit.
Yeah.
Not a lot,
but a little bit,
um,
couple of capsules,
every other day.
Oh,
really?
Other day.
Yeah.
Uh,
and I,
and I manufactured them too.
I mean,
it's part of my,
my,
um,
my line of products,
but because my diet is pretty much based
on,
um,
uh,
an otherwise healthy intake of Omega
threes and more importantly,
a reduction of Omega six.
So it's,
it's not the Omega threes are by
themselves.
Antiinflammatories they are and Omega
six are proinflammatory,
but it's this ratio.
Um,
there's some requirement for Omega six
in the body,
but when the ratio gets way thrown off,
it tends to be a pro inflammatory
reaction.
Where do Omega six has come from?
That those are the industrial seed oils
that we talked about.
So there's a slight benefit to having
some industrial seed.
Well,
no,
there's a slight benefit to having omega
six from other sources.
So what are the other sources?
Um,
you know,
any,
any most,
uh,
fish.
We'll also have oh six.
Um,
you know,
they're,
they're everywhere.
They're in any kind of fatty food,
um,
nuts.
We'll have them.
Uh,
uh,
that's probably the source of most
people on the Paleo movement get the
Omega six from.
Um,
but yeah,
it's,
it's about sort of the totality of the
Diet,
not,
and,
and it's largely a result,
again,
of what you're not eating,
what you eliminate from the Diet that
has the greatest effect,
not what you're reading.
So when people say,
well,
Paleo Diet,
I mean,
I've had such great results on the Vegan
Diet,
or I've had great results on a,
you know,
in some Vegetarian Daddy,
oh,
well,
you know,
you're,
you're not eating the same shit we're
not eating.
So the fact that you get your protein
from plant sources,
I'm maybe gonna suggest you could have
more protein,
but it's not that big a deal.
It's really about what you've eliminated
that that has the greatest impact on
your health.
Yeah,
I
have conversations like that often with
people that are Vegan.
When they start talking about all the
different things they eat,
how much better they feel,
and then I tell them,
listen,
I eat all the same things you eat.
Like my diet is pretty vegan other than
meat.
Yeah.
I mean,
most of what I,
like this morning,
what I had,
I drink a Kale shake.
So I blend Kale with cucumbers and I
know it's gross,
but it makes me feel amazing.
I blend Kale with cucumbers,
garlic,
um,
celery,
ginger and pear.
I throw a pair in and a I that up.
Oh
and a half a beat.
I blend that all up and I had an elk
stake.
So the two things together,
that's,
that's what I eat.
That's my lunch,
you know,
that's what I had.
I didn't eat breakfast.
I just ate lunch today.
And how does it,
how does the Kale shake tastes like
shit.
Yeah,
it doesn't as good.
One of my rules is,
one of my rules is I don't put anything
in my mouth.
It doesn't taste awesome and it feels
good man.
I'm telling you,
I eat that.
I get this burst of nutrients I'm going
to,
I'm going to keep doing it.
All right,
well I'm not going to terrible with a
full pair in.
Yeah.
You know,
cause the full pair,
I mean so big Bartlett,
pear,
a little bit of garlic.
Very,
yeah,
it's very sweet.
Yeah.
But is that too much sugar?
That one pair?
It's,
it depends on how much,
what your sugar load is over the course
of a day.
If that's,
if that's the only sugar you get.
Pairs are pretty high and you know,
they're pretty high in sugar.
But um,
if the whole pair,
I don't think I eat a pear before yoga
class too.
That's what I was,
that that gets me through a yoga class
cause I got pairs.
Your favorite fruit or something like
pears.
Wow.
Is that okay for you?
It's totally good.
I just get the first,
first guy I've known it's favorite fruit
as a payer.
Really.
I mean I like a pair,
but I said,
ah,
I like mangoes.
Mangoes are my also favorite.
Those are awesome.
Yeah,
I,
I'd take sliced so I'll do that.
What would we be better?
Pears and mangoes,
I guess.
No difference.
Difference,
difference.
But fruit is what I usually choose
before I work out.
But now I'm thinking that maybe fruit is
a little too high in sugar listening to
you or I should limit the amount of it I
have in a day.
And again,
if you,
if,
if you like where you're at and
everything's good and life is wonderful
and you enjoy it,
then I'm not going to tell you to stop
doing it.
Well,
I'm all about optimize them.
I mean,
I,
um,
if I can chug down those Kale shakes,
I'm obviously willing to eat some
horrible shit to feel better.
Um,
this is not,
it's not that horrible.
I,
I kind of exaggerate a little bit how my
tolerance for gross food is pretty high.
I can,
I can eat it.
Jerry eat any of that shit on fear
factor?
Yeah,
I hit a bunch of good,
good.
I uh,
I balls,
sheeps,
eyeballs.
I super worms.
Those,
those worms,
they use a on cadavers cleanup bones.
Yeah.
I ate a tomato hornworms it was pretty
gross.
I ate a Madagascar hissing cockroaches.
That was the one that was at,
that's the one I think it would have
drawn the line in.
That one was the easiest to do.
Yup.
Yeah.
It's all psychological but that's chewy.
But it's very mild.
Like it has almost no flavor.
It was all just in your head.
That was no big deal at all.
The really hard things to eat.
It's really interesting.
The smells were probably the hardest
part and a big factor in the smell was
the um,
he would add this really expensive
cheese.
They would go to this beverly hills.
What is up for module?
What is it?
One of those fucking places called where
they sell the cheese for Masuri.
Anyway,
it was a very expensive type of French
cheese that just smells like fucking
death because cheese,
a big part of what makes a cheese
fragrant or interesting is the culture,
which is actually bacteria.
Yeah.
So we would buy this bacteria laden
cheese that smelled so fucking bad.
They would take it and they would open
the little cup,
the little plastic tub in front of me
and sticking from,
oh.
They'd be like,
dude,
that shit is expensive.
Really expensive.
And we would throw that into like a
blender full of maggots and that's what
would make it disgusting.
The maggots on the,
on their own.
That's really didn't have that much of a
smell or taste.
Yeah.
It's more psychological than it is
anything.
Yeah.
A lot of stuff on fear factor.
And then there was a lot of,
it was just the sheer volume.
Like they would have to drink,
you know,
a gigantic blender,
phil with his horrible shit.
And there's the amount of mass that
you're putting in your body and you have
like three minutes to do it or whatever
and keep it down and keep it down.
Yeah.
I think we gave them like they had to
keep it down for like 30 seconds or
something like that.
So that at the end of that 30 seconds
they would sprint towards everybody
hurl.
Oh yeah.
I saw more people.
I probably seen more people throw up
then like a very small percentage of the
population than most ers.
Right?
Yeah.
Well maybe ers would have me like
nightclub bouncers might have me,
if you,
if you put in 20 years as a nightclub
bouncer,
you'd probably see more people puke than
me because you're seeing it every night.
Maybe it was only one day a week.
Yeah.
But one day a week I'd watch it at least
two people just fucking hurl.
Just raw projectile vomit.
Yeah.
But,
uh,
again,
more psychological than anything,
you know,
the,
uh,
the actual taste of those things,
especially the roach was nothing.
It's like really no big deal.
Like if I was,
was,
I was starving somewhere and I found
like a,
a big batch of a hissing cockroaches,
those Madagascar ones,
I would definitely scoop those up and
eat them.
Well,
you know,
um,
uh,
there's a,
a bar company called Xo that makes their
bars out of cricket protein and I'm an
investor in their company there and I'm
fascinated by the concept that,
that uh,
you know,
billion and a half,
2 billion people around the world eat
insects all the time and think nothing
of it.
Yeah,
well that's what a lobster is.
One of the things that we found out when
we did fear factor was if you have an
allergy to shellfish,
you also have an allergy to roaches.
We found that out the hard way because a
guy who listed shellfish as an allergy,
eight,
a roach and got really sick and we had
to take him to the Er,
they got to give him an adrenaline shot,
the whole deal.
So the,
the enzymes apparently are very similar,
but you can eat those bugs and there's
the very high in protein and very good
for you.
And they can also be an excellent source
of protein for a inexpensive source of
protein.
For a lot of people it's the cricket
thing is very sustainable.
It's like 20 times less resources,
fewer resources to,
to an equivalent amount of,
uh,
of steak and also equivalent amount of
amino acids.
It's like a very good profile.
Yeah,
that's really fascinating to me that you
could get like really high quality
protein from,
yeah,
we're,
we're prejudice against bugs I guess.
I mean,
I'm trying not to be anymore.
Do you eat your bars?
Oh yeah.
Get all the time.
All the time.
Just because I don't,
I don't use those kinds of snacks.
I make my own bar,
but because they,
the guys who started expo are really
onto something and they're trying to,
they're trying to change the way the
world thinks about sourcing protein.
So the first hurdle you have to overcome
is making a bar tastes great and not
turn people off because it's cricket
because it's crickets and you know,
there's not like heads and antenna
sticking out of these bars.
It's a powder.
It's been ground down to a fine powder
and it basically looks and probably
taste the same as whey protein isolate
does.
Once it's ground down,
down,
down.
Um,
do you lose any of it when you're
dehydrating in or grinding it down or
turn away?
It's,
it's,
it retains its properties pretty nicely.
So there's no benefit whatsoever to
eating it fresh.
Um,
not necessarily.
No.
I mean,
if you can compact more into,
uh,
I mean that's the beauty of,
of I think insect protein powder is to
be able to fortify foods,
uh,
that,
that otherwise,
you know,
rather than having 40 crickets on a
stick,
you know,
to,
to have the powder equivalent in a bar
is kind of a neat way of doing it.
I've eaten crickets like that too.
Like roasted crickets.
You don't taste bad at all.
Not Bad.
It's all in the head.
Yeah,
it really is.
It's all in your mind.
Like you,
you,
you chew them,
they're crunchy and they're broasted
over a fire.
They're actually not bad at all.
I mean,
they're sold as delicacy in the streets
of sure.
You know,
in Bangkok and most of Asia.
Yeah.
Especially if you put some spices on
them or some point that they can
actually be quite tasting like maybe
some butter or some oil and some spices
on them.
Yeah.
We have these ideas about different
things that are good to eat and not good
to eat.
And since more based on custom than
anything and a lot of ways,
yeah.
I wonder how many people that are vegan
would be willing to eat bugs,
you know,
Vegan as far as I know it goes against
their religion,
which I don't even want to use honey.
No,
I it's,
it's crazy.
That's funny you say that because we've
got a bar that we just introduced with
grass fed whey protein isolate and,
and uh,
um,
it's got collagen in it.
It's a great bar.
Um,
and we tried to bake one for the Vegan
community and because it has honey in it
is as a suite near the Vegan said,
well we can't,
we can't eat cause it has honey,
it's bs,
you know,
that's there's are slaves,
man.
Yeah.
Whatever.
Okay.
Whatever they want.
You know,
you want to go that way.
Yeah.
Honeys.
Awesome.
It fucks.
Is there any like nutritional benefit to
being a Vegan or is it an deficits,
you know,
it's involved in it.
Um,
I think that's probably some foods that
you're not getting that would provide a
micro nutrients,
the micro nutrition that would be
beneficial to you in the long run.
And,
and yet the human body is so frigging,
uh,
adaptable to,
to any sort of dietary strategy.
I mean,
you know,
you see,
uh,
eight foot tall,
Africans,
you know,
the go play in the NBA that grew up on
a,
you know,
500 calories a day and cow patties.
Um,
you know,
during the Irish potato famine,
people live for six weeks on shoe
leather and seaweed.
I mean,
the human body is pretty adaptable.
So you on that one hand,
um,
you can't describe the perfect diet.
So if you're choosing to be Vegan and
that's what you want to do and,
and you're mindful about it,
um,
and you're not militant about it and not
trying to convince everybody else that
that's what they ought to do,
then then go for it.
Well,
that doesn't exist yet.
So few.
That's,
that was a requirement.
That's the Unicorn Fart.
A requirement of membership.
Yeah.
Um hmm.
What,
like what,
what are the,
there's a few plants that do have a
full,
complete amino acid profile,
right?
Like keen Wa is one of them.
Yeah.
I mean there's great plants.
I don't know,
I wouldn't say they have a full amino
acid profile.
It's what's lacking.
Well,
there's probably,
if there's nothing lacking,
it's the,
it's the relative amounts that make the
difference.
So it's a protein efficiency ratio,
right?
Uh,
the,
um,
the protein amino acid score that,
that,
uh,
really determines whether a protein is,
is exceptional and that's where the,
you know,
meat and eggs and,
and,
uh,
you know,
that dairy and things that someone was
trying to describe that to me,
the amount of Broccoli you would need to
get the same amount of protein and amino
acids as an eight ounce steak,
something insane.
It's like two pounds of Broccoli.
Yeah.
I still,
I don't think it's insane.
I just think it's a cause.
Ll those same people will argue that
there's,
um,
you know that it's a on a,
on a,
I think it's on a per pound basis.
It's almost like it has the same amount
of amino acids.
I forget where I,
where I heard that some,
some Vegan side of that to me and I,
I know that broccoli does have some
amino acids in it.
You just have to eat a big bowl of it
and if you're a Vegan,
that's what you do anyway.
So,
uh,
I'm not going to criticize that choice.
I just think that um,
if you're missing certain amino acids,
you better balance it with something
coming from lagoons or some other
source.
You have to figure out what amino acids
are lacking based on what plant protein
in the human diet was always based on a
wide variety of things that you were
taking it and just,
you know,
not,
not just one kind of thing,
but something off of this Shrub,
off of this Bush,
out of this ground and the tuber here
and some quail eggs here.
And,
you know,
it was always a 200 different choices,
uh,
within a five mile radius or whatever.
You can just get whatever you get your
hands on it.
And that's where the insects came in.
That's where the,
you know,
we don't talk about,
amphibians,
but imagine living on frogs and snakes
and,
and eggs and,
uh,
you know,
in wheat grass and just,
it's,
uh,
it's pretty amazing the variety of foods
that we can eat.
So typically you start your morning off
with butter,
coffee with mct oils,
which I don't just eat a regular coffee
and it's regular.
That's just,
I don't,
I'll have a buttered coffee every once
in a while,
but I don't,
I don't feel like I need the calories to
get my day going.
I just want the cup of coffee.
You just want the caffeine,
just want the caffeine.
And I actually don't want to,
um,
I don't want to interfere with burning
off my own body fat.
So,
uh,
not that it interferes with it,
but that's 500 calories that,
that or 250 calories coming out of the
coffee that otherwise just coming off
my,
you know,
my gut.
Interesting.
So when you wake up in the morning,
it's all dependent upon how hungry you
are.
Yeah.
So if you're hungry,
maybe then you'll have some butter
coffee.
And if you're not hungry,
it was her regular coffee,
black,
a nod,
a little bit of cream,
but just enough to color it and like,
uh,
your first meal of the day,
it's probably lunch.
Yup.
And what did,
what does that,
uh,
usually a salad.
I have a big ass salad,
I call it.
And uh,
it's um,
it's lots of Greens and some form of
protein might be salmon,
might be chicken from last night's
dinner,
might be a tuna.
Um,
well what size?
Like an eight ounce portion.
Now it's a bitch.
No,
I mean,
no,
not much protein.
I,
that's the other thing that I've
realized over the years is that we don't
need that much protein.
And even if you're doing work in the
gym,
you know,
you don't need 200 grams of protein a
day.
That's bullshit.
You just can't process that.
What is that from?
That's from a bodybuilding power lifting
my town that's from the muscle and
fitness days.
And that's from Dave draper and his
fricking,
you know,
blender full of stuff was dave draper.
Oh my God,
you don't.
So Dave draper's before your time,
man.
So he was on the original,
uh,
southern California blond bodybuilders.
He was in every ad for,
for shakes and,
and mass gainers and things like that.
Mass gain.
Yeah.
It's all sugar,
right?
Yeah.
Oh that does it.
That's nasty stuff.
That's just like cheap cheap ass protein
and high fructose corn.
Yeah.
They're,
yeah.
Stayed there.
Yeah.
On the beach.
Hello ladies.
So that guy,
uh,
would advocate massive amounts,
but I mean that guy,
you know,
when you,
when you can process,
when you take it in,
uh,
you know,
super human levels of steroids,
you can process all kinds of protein.
Look at them today.
So today,
Jamie,
yeah,
still looking pretty good.
He's probably about 70 their yolk.
60 what?
63 63 right there.
He's your age.
Yoked is fuck.
Look at them.
Maybe does a little steroids too when we
think,
do you think could be huh?
But a,
so people using needing protein,
it's,
you know,
maybe women probably need 50 to 75,
maybe 80 grams a day.
Um,
even guys,
you know,
training fairly hard,
don't no more than 113 hundred 40 grams
a day.
Now what is,
what's the muscle and fitness mentality
or the powerlifting mentality?
It's like there's a certain amount of
grams per pound of body weight.
Describe.
Well,
you know,
that's all over the place.
So it might've been one gram per pound
of body weight at 1.5 grams per pound of
body weight.
Well,
it's like 200 grams a day for me or,
yeah.
Yeah.
Graham,
I'm 200 pounds.
200 grams of protein.
That's a shitload of broke.
How much is a steak?
Like a 12 ounce steak?
50 60.
But Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
So I'd have to four fucking stakes in a
day.
Yeah.
I mean by the time you cook that down,
yeah.
It might be less.
Right.
What about eggs?
How much is it an egg?
Seven or eight per ticket.
Yeah.
That's why these guys would do a whole
dozen eggs in there,
shake.
Um,
you know,
that'd be 70 or 80,
or 80 or 90 or whatever grams of protein
plus some powder in there.
And,
but you know,
the,
what we learned a long time ago was a
body really can't handle more than 30,
35 grams of protein at a sitting.
So the rest of it turns into,
um,
you know,
the farts.
Yeah.
So if you're,
if you're eating,
that's one thing.
If you've ever been around people who
drink a lot of protein shakes and eat
protein bars,
they're farts are brutal like
bodybuilder type dudes.
And that's just,
they just,
there's too much protein,
right?
Yeah.
Among other things.
A lot of that is,
you know,
they haven't,
um,
who knows what's going on with their,
with their gut bacteria too.
That's a lot of protein to put in there.
They're probably,
if they're eating that much protein,
they're not eating much of the way of
vegetables and those muscle milk type
supplements,
although there are delicious,
there's a lot of sugar in those damn
thing.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
All those bars,
a lot of bars have a lot of sugar in
them.
This is a giant issue.
Yup.
Yeah.
Hmm.
So,
um,
you think that these guys,
these bodybuilder guys are power
powerlifter guys that are operating on
that inefficient method of one gram per
pound.
If they had reduced it,
they would still have the same amount of
gains and maybe their body would operate
more efficiently.
Are we talking on juice or off the
juice?
Oh,
okay.
That's a good point.
You know.
Yeah.
So back to your on steroids.
Back to your point about,
um,
you know,
I'm a hard gainer and you know,
putting on muscle is,
is,
is difficult.
Um,
most people are overweight,
don't want to hear this,
but putting on muscle is much more
difficult than losing body fat.
You know,
you take a 165 pound guy and you say,
oh,
he says,
I want to put on 20 pounds of muscle.
Ain't going to happen.
You know,
might put on 10 pounds of muscle,
might put on seven over a very focused
period of time.
It might have to work hard to keep it on
because that's the body also going.
If you don't create on a daily basis,
my requirement to continue to maintain
this muscle mass,
I'm going back down to where it was
right there.
It seems to me that there's a number of
days or years or whatever it is that you
maintain that body mass where it starts
to become normal.
Then your body says,
well this is what we way now.
Yeah,
and then you,
you maintain it,
but there's this touch and go period.
Say if you weigh one 65 and you put on
that 10 pounds like,
well you got to keep pushing for a long
time for your body to say,
listen,
this is what we way we need all this
power.
We needed all this horsepower and we
were going to be able to carry a lot of
heavy shit all the time.
Yup,
exactly.
Yeah.
Bring your own honey.
Is that what's going on with no,
no,
no.
Jamie,
what is that?
Oh that's you are honey.
I'm having some which just like to here.
This guy's serious.
This brings his own hunting.
No,
no,
but honey is good for you,
isn't it now?
Raw honey.
No.
How dare you.
I know.
Who are you?
It's not.
It's not good for you.
It's not going to kill you.
You know any that's one of those
moderation foods.
If you want to use it to like in this
case I put a couple of drops in the,
in the tea,
but I always hear it's really good.
Like raw honey.
Did you hear?
Who Do you hear it from?
Not The vegans money that people make,
honey.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's just a,
it's something that I've always heard is
it's not bad.
It's just all sugar.
It's a form of sugar.
And if you overdo it then it's probably
not as wise a decision as to cut it
back.
So we got to your launch your launch,
which a big ass out with a small amount
of protein.
So maybe like four ounces of protein or
something along those lines.
Yeah.
Okay.
What piece of chicken or a piece of fish
or something like that.
And then,
um,
what about dinner?
Um,
dinner.
I like to have a stake.
I got this Wagyu short rib that I get
you.
Like that stuff is so good,
but it's all fatty.
Yeah.
That's the point.
We like that.
That's the point,
ma'am.
Yeah.
And uh,
cause you liked fat.
Yeah,
no,
I,
my diet is probably 55% of my calories
come from fat,
but Wagyu is a lot of corn fed animal.
All right.
So I'm,
so I make a little bit of an exception
there.
Um,
I could get a grass fed when I,
you know,
when I,
when I look forward at a Pc Greens where
I shop in Malibu,
but um,
or at whole foods or whatever.
But this,
this Wagyu,
uh,
it's just such a delicious,
you like a nice tender juicy steak.
Yup.
Is there any benefit like what are the
health benefits of eating grass fed meat
and using grass fed cows?
Butter?
Yeah,
it's really interesting because,
um,
one of the things I,
I just kind of have to raise my eyebrows
add is I hear about grass fed whey
protein isolate,
right?
So you have grass fed whey protein.
It's whatever they put in the drink.
Well,
the reason you eat grass fed cows is
because the fatty acid profile is more,
um,
uh,
it's,
it's a more desirable fatty acid
profile.
The protein compliment is the exact same
in a corn fed steak or a grass fed
steak.
You just can't tell the difference in
the protein.
It's the fatty acid profile that's
different.
The other difference might be the
residual hormones and antibiotics.
So when they raise corn fed beef and
they start from an early age,
that's not the,
the cows native diet.
So they,
the cow tends to get sick,
get infected and so these antibiotics
and they have to use a in,
sometimes he use growth hormone just to
get them off the lot quicker.
So,
but,
but the,
the,
the reason to have grass fed beef is the
fatty acid profile is much more
desirable.
Uh,
and yet it's still,
it's still fat.
So it's just a couple of different
versions of stearic acid and,
and different versions of the saturated
fat that you're talking about.
So it's not even like this life or death
decision that you make.
Like if I have a wonderful cut of corn
fed steak,
I'm going to die.
If I have grass fed a live forever.
These are just choices.
And if,
if you,
if you can find a great tasting grass
fed steak,
by all means habit.
If you can have a great find a
relatively inexpensive,
you know,
lined line caught wild salmon,
that's a probably a better choice for
your stated goals.
Then some farm raised salmon.
So yeah,
the farm raised salmon is a,
it's problematic because of their diet,
right?
Yep.
But so back,
but just back to the,
the grasp of things.
So when you get to grass fed whey
protein isolate,
whey protein isolate is 90 to 95%
protein.
There's,
they took all the fat out of it so it
doesn't matter.
They all the good fatty acid profile
that was in it because it was grass fed
is now gone.
So it's like a marketing strategy to
call it grass fed whey protein isolate.
So it's not bad,
but it's not any better.
No,
it's,
it's definitely not bad.
It's,
it's not demonstrably better to have
grass fed whey protein isolate versus
just regular.
What about grass fed butter?
Grass fed butter?
Yeah,
yeah,
absolutely.
That's all fat.
So that there's,
and there's an example of,
that's the exact opposite.
Now they took all the protein out of it
and now just giving you fat.
So grass fed butter is a great choice.
And what is the difference in the
profile?
The,
the fatty profile of a grass fed butter
versus same as it is with the meat.
So it w when is that difference?
Um,
I can't,
I can't cite the research and I can't
cite to break down to the of the fatty
acids.
It's just that they're more appropriate
for a,
a cow that was raised on its native
diet.
Pop was the difference between the fact,
cause I've heard it but I can't cite it
when somebody wants to bring it up.
But I prefer the taste of a grass fed
meat.
Yeah.
Cause it's a leaner,
like more dense meat.
It's more like wild game.
Right.
Then um,
like uh,
a ribeye from a cow that's fed corn.
Right.
But you're saying that like health wise
had rib eyes pretty good.
Pretty good.
Yeah.
It's more of a fatty cut.
Um,
so,
but you're saying there's not that much
of a difference in terms of like the
health benefits.
If you can get a,
again,
a humanely raised a cow that was not
given antibiotics or hormones,
um,
you're pretty close to where you want to
be.
And so I'm suggesting that the fatty
acid profile isn't going to be hugely
different,
isn't the issue with cows that when you
give a cow grains,
their body isn't designed to process it.
So they develop a lot of infections and,
and that's,
that's why they use the antibiotics.
So isn't that,
I mean,
just automatically problematic if you
have a grain fed cow?
Not necessarily.
So a lot of times you'll have a cow that
was raised on grass and then finished
with grain.
Um,
and there's different types of grains.
So some it's not automatically
problematic.
Um,
it,
it could be,
but if you look for the cows that were,
uh,
pastured up until a certain point and
you know,
again,
they might've been grass finished,
sometimes they'll,
they'll say grass fed and they won't,
they won't tell you it was grain.
And when they say green finished,
how much time do they spend feeding them
grain?
It's a couple of weeks.
That's it.
Yep.
Okay.
So they just fatten up for the last
couple of weeks before the end.
Yup.
And so they don't have enough time to
develop a lot of the massive issues of
they might have if they were,
uh,
in Corinth the whole life in theory.
So,
um,
you'll,
you'll lead a little bit of steak and a
steam vegetables.
That's what I have my big plate of
Broccoli or Broccolini or partial spouts
or,
you know,
whatever.
And what about like drinks?
What do you drink mostly?
So I used to drink wine at meals.
I don't drink a lot of water.
I'm a soothing a throat today,
but um,
with this,
but normally I wouldn't drink much,
uh,
much water during the course of the day.
I let my thirst mechanism,
you know,
just sort of tell me what to do.
And I don't get thirsty that often.
I mean,
I used to go on 50 mile bike rides and
not get thirsty,
so I've got a real,
yeah.
Yeah.
Is that just weird?
Just you missed,
I know other people like that.
A lot of people are of the belief that
you should drink water all day,
so you have to pee all the time cause
you're flushing your body.
I don't,
I don't buy that at all.
No,
I think it's unnecessary.
It's probably,
yeah,
it's,
uh,
I definitely don't agree with that
concept.
Um,
but you might want to do it once in a
while just to,
you know,
do your own little cleanse or whatever.
But I don't think as a rule of thumb
that,
that there's any particular health
benefit to that put about the toxins,
the toxins out.
Man,
I didn't pay clear.
I need to drink more.
Yeah,
that's,
that's bullshit.
Um,
I think so.
Yeah.
Um,
I know a lot of people who still do it.
I know a lot of,
you know,
people at the gym bring their gallon jug
of distilled water in or whatever the
hell it is really bad.
Right.
Ros,
Ros water yet.
Yeah.
Because when you drink distilled water,
there's no minerals in it.
It actually robs your body of minerals
because they're like,
takes the minerals out.
Right?
Yeah.
Um,
so don't drink unless your Thursday.
I mean,
that's my rule of thumb and I,
and I don't,
so what do I drink with meals?
Um,
until recently I was drinking wine with
meals.
How come he stopped?
So,
uh,
I'd written a lot about wines over the
years and,
and how,
uh,
you know,
the research shows that wine drinkers
live longer than teetotallers,
resveratrol,
all that stuff.
And,
uh,
there's a lot of good,
compelling evidence to drink wine.
And yet at the root of the matter,
wine is still a source of ethanol.
Ethanol is toxic to the body.
So you're putting a toxin in your body
every time you drink wine.
I'm starting to look at that in my own
case and realized that I wasn't sleeping
as well as I want it to.
And sleep's a big thing for me.
So,
um,
but I was a two glass a night wine
drinker for 30 years.
I'm just,
it wasn't dinner if I didn't have wine.
And,
um,
so I went on a 30 day,
which I do often when a 30 day
experiment of one,
see what happened,
it cut out the wine,
um,
felt great,
uh,
slept better,
and that I was never really,
it never woke up hungover.
I mean,
I've never,
my kids have never seen me.
My kids are 22 and 25 they'd never seen
me drunk.
My wife has never seen me drunk.
It's not like I was abusing anything,
but I had this regular pattern of
drinking wine.
So I went off it and I realized that I
was benefiting from it.
Uh,
so for last year and a half,
I really cut back on the one I still
have a glass or two.
What was the benefit of that?
You watched?
I didn't wake up at three o'clock in the
morning and then not be able to get back
to sleep for an hour.
That was the big thing that I noticed
for myself was I would fall asleep
really easily and then I would wake up
two or three in the morning and have a
tough time getting back to sleep.
And that sort of subsided when I went
off the wine.
So the,
that's that's the result of the effect
of alcohol.
Your body processed to the alcohol.
The alcohol is a depressant and knocks
you out,
your body processes it,
and then once it's done processing it,
then your sleep cycles disturbed.
So you wake up,
is that what happened in Chinese
medicine says that that's when your
liver is working at at three,
three o'clock in the morning.
So maybe that's when the real processing
was starting to take take place or I
don't know.
You know what item,
not huge adherent of Chinese medicine.
I'm not suggesting that it's not an
important thing to look at,
but in my case the sleep benefited
tremendously.
So feel any better other than the sleep?
Yeah,
I mean I think so.
I mean,
I didn't really notice.
Like I say,
I never woke up hung over and I've
always felt refreshed waking up,
but I didn't like not getting that sleep
and,
and having to,
and then in my case,
because I'm a,
I'm not good at managing stress and I
have a fair amount of stress,
just business stuff in my life.
So that's,
you know,
when you can't sleep at three o'clock in
the morning and that's when all the
business shit kind of starts to
circulate in the brain,
you know,
and how's this going to happen and how
are we going to do that?
So,
so I didn't like that part of it.
Um,
so year and a half went without drinking
wine and I replaced it with,
I used to be a prodigious beer drinker
before I gave up the grains.
Um,
and uh,
and I started,
I found a couple of,
um,
nonalcoholic beers that I like.
And,
uh,
so again,
it was for me it was about the habit
that the ritual of dinner.
So I needed,
I couldn't just drink water.
I hate,
I hate drinking water with dinner.
So I wanted to find something to replace
the ritual part of the wine.
And I found these nonalcoholic beers
drink.
So I had one with dinner at night,
maybe one and a half.
These non grained made,
no,
they're,
they're made with grains,
but it's not,
they don't affect me,
uh,
to an extent.
And uh,
and so that's,
that's what I've been doing for the last
year and a half.
And then recently,
um,
I came across a guy who is looking at
Paleo wines and,
and I,
I'm going to do it if you coined a new
phrase,
this as a marketing ploy.
Now there's these wines are 300 wineries
in the world among the tens of
thousands,
uh,
that don't use additives or sulfites or
colorants or formaldehyde or any of the
shit that we put in wine in this
country.
So if you look at what,
how wines are made in the u s some of
the more,
um,
desirable wines from a nose perspective
have all kinds of crap in them.
And there's like 87 approved additives
that the government allows us wine
makers to put in their wines.
And that's the shit that causes you to
get the hangover and feel bad from
drinking the wine,
particularly red wines,
uh,
and wake up in the middle of the night
and not be able to sleep.
So,
um,
this guy approaches me one day actually
I met him at,
um,
at a conference and uh,
he started telling me a story and last
I'm not,
I'm not buying it.
You know,
you've got these wines that don't have,
that won't cause you to fall asleep or
don't,
won't cause you to wake up in the middle
of the night.
He goes,
I was like,
you mark.
I gave up drinking wine and I'm a,
I love wines,
but it gave him up because I didn't like
what it was doing to me.
And I found this new,
these new wines.
So he sources wines from around the
world that are made in wineries that
don't use any of these additives.
And I,
and I,
he gave me a case of them to try
different brands and different things
and none of them from the u s they're
all from Europe or South America or
whatever.
Um,
and these are wineries had been around
for 300 years.
They just never bought into the concept
of adding shit to wines.
Right.
And,
you know,
I realized I,
some of these wines I can drink and
enjoy and feel a little bit of,
uh,
taking the edge off and then go to bed
and have no ill effects at all.
So I'm sort of opening my mind to the
fact that there's some,
some Paleo type wines out there that
don't have the additives in them,
in them that,
um,
that consumed in moderation or probably
enjoyable and potentially helpful.
The term Paleo seems to be a loaded term
because people connect it with the idea
of the Paleolithic era and what people
ate at that time.
But it's not,
we're not talking about that when you're
talking about Paleo wine.
You know what I mean?
Like it seems a weird,
it's a weird term.
Yeah.
And he doesn't,
he doesn't really use the term he uses
natural.
Yeah.
Um,
but,
but it,
the market to which he was catering at
the time itself to Paleo communicates
the Paleo community.
Yeah.
It's almost like they need a better word
than Paleo because it's not necessarily
even what people ate during the
Paleolithic era.
You just reducing grains or eliminating
them and,
and concentrating on fats.
That's not necessarily what people ate
during the period.
I mean,
that's one of the great misnomers that
general public has about the Paleo Diet.
Is it,
if a caveman didn't need it,
then we should need it.
We'll,
none of this stuff existed in caveman.
It's time.
Nothing that we'd even,
even the stuff we get out of the ground
or off the trees didn't exist then.
It's all been manipulated by farming
and,
uh,
you know,
whether it was inserting gene,
it wasn't inserting genes,
but we still did genetic manipulation
of,
of foods to get them
sweeter and more protein or whatever.
Maybe it's a loaded term and we need a
new term,
something like primal maybe or,
right.
Well,
the primal blueprint.
Oh,
hey,
that's a good one.
Maybe you should run with that.
I thought I'll try.
It honestly is probably better than
Paleo,
right?
I thought from the beginning,
I s I started,
uh,
my project,
writing the blog in 2006 and I knew
early on wanted a brand that was sort of
unique and separate from Paleo.
I thought Paleo had too much baggage
from caveman on it.
And primal sort of has a primary,
you know,
first importance kind of thing as well
as,
um,
as well as going back to primal times
and primal urge or whatever.
So,
um,
hence the term primal blueprint and my
primal fuel and my food products,
primal kitchen,
they're all kind of based around that.
So these additives that they're putting
in wine,
it's just from an economic standpoint,
it allows the process to want to know.
It's from a consumer demand point of
view.
So you know when you get some of these,
um,
I don't want to name names,
but some of my favorite really expensive
California wines that I used to love
because of the way they taste them,
a thick and rich looking and you know,
Okie and all this just additives all
crap they're putting in there because
that's what the consumer thinks is going
to make for a sophisticated wine.
Wow.
And all that is chemical additives that
fuck with your body.
Yeah.
Not all.
I mean it enough that they all do.
Wow.
That's bizarre.
I never would have thought that.
And when I think of wine,
I thought wines,
just fermented grapes and they go
through a process and they store it and
yeah,
my friend Maynard makes one,
I need to contact him.
You know,
you know the band tool?
Yeah.
Maynard,
the lead singer tool.
He has a,
an awesome wine company.
Could do ceus.
Why did they make their own wine?
Or they somebody else's,
somebody won.
He grows his own grease.
Fucking crazy though.
He's,
yeah.
I mean,
I don't want people to grow grapes in
Malibu,
but none of them make their own wine.
They stayed,
they truck it out to some distillery
demand.
When they truck it out,
this guy takes it and throws a bunch of
shit.
Well,
whatever that the grower,
the grapes who's got his own label will
say,
I want it to have this,
these properties.
It's got to be,
you know,
this,
this color and this thick.
And sometimes if the grapes don't,
you know,
can't pr in and of themselves provide
that.
I mean,
a lot of the stuff comes from the,
a lot of the tannins in wine come from
the grape skin.
And uh,
to get the deep,
deep,
deep rich color,
you have to,
you have to mash the grapes up in the
skin up even more and more and more.
So more that Tannin to get the red,
the deep red colors in the wine date,
they have to provide more of the skin.
And that's what's causing a lot of the
tannins.
So for some people have issues with the,
that you hear about the histamines and
wine.
Again,
that's the,
that's the marketplace demanding a deep
red wine.
And so it's a color issue,
part of a color.
It could be color,
it could be,
again,
some of the,
you know,
adding sugar to the wines.
A lot of the u s wines have a lot of
sugar in them,
like a,
like a fairly high sugar content.
The Guy I'm talking about here who,
who led me down this this road and sort
of opened my eyes to this,
he's been in Ketosis for two years and
he couldn't drink wine because the sugar
would take him out of Ketosis,
the sugar and why.
So that's sort of one of the reasons he
got started on that.
He was a lifetime wine drinker,
grew up in wine country up in Sonoma,
and I'm an adult Delton the business and
sort of left it because he got
disenchanted and then came back when he
discovered that there were these wines
that have no sugar,
that have no self or,
you know,
minimal sulfite to me.
And I'll,
I'll,
uh,
natural,
fruits and vegetables have some amount
of sulfites but not added,
no added Sulfites,
um,
uh,
and,
and none of these 80 or so approved,
uh,
added ingredients that can affect the
color and the smell and the,
and the,
and the thickness.
That is really interesting.
That's something I never even consider.
I never even thought there was additives
and won.
I just thought it was just grapes.
I thought it was pretty simple.
Well,
these are American companies that do
this.
Is there anything local?
I don't know.
I mean he's,
the,
the things that he's given me are,
um,
uh,
all from,
from other countries.
That sounds so counter intelligent,
intuitive that we grow so much wine in
California.
But to get wine without any shit in it,
you'd have to get it from Europe because
we're so concentrated right now,
at least this part of the country is,
uh,
on,
you know,
natural foods and you know,
grass fed beef and organic vegetables.
The fact that we would have wines that
almost all primarily.
Yeah,
that's nuts.
Oh,
it is.
Um,
and it may be that I'm,
you know,
that he hasn't sent me any that are from
the u s but most of these are from,
from other,
uh,
and where would you order something like
that?
I want to try that now because I like
wine.
I love red wine.
A dry wine farms is the guys,
is the name of the company.
Dry wine farms dry.
Yup.
I always think of dry.
It's like a,
that's like the way that
kind of white wine that people like a
dry white wine.
Right?
Yup.
Hmm.
I just never would have believed that it
was the additives that are causing all
that.
Well,
so now we're back to that,
that initial discussion we had about
let's,
what you don't eat right.
That really affects you more than what
you do eat.
And,
and so if you're getting,
um,
you know,
uh,
you're eating appropriately grown cuts
of meat and organic vegetables and
you're cutting out the,
the organic,
I've,
excuse me,
cutting out the industrial seed oils,
cutting out the sugar,
cutting out the processed grains and
some of the other grains.
And in their place,
you're,
and you're cutting out,
in this case,
crappy wine and,
and,
and substituting fruits,
vegetables,
meat,
fish,
fowl,
eggs,
nuts,
seeds,
and hit.
Now we have,
you know,
again,
if we want to enjoy life,
and that's one of the things that we
might consider an enjoyable part of life
is,
is partaking of a glass of red or white
wine with dinner.
Now it's kind of back on the menu for
some people.
That's interesting.
That's really interesting.
So,
but it's not necessarily on the menu
for,
you know,
so,
uh,
and having said that,
um,
I'm not finding myself back in that
situation where I'm drinking wine with
dinner again because I've,
I've,
I still recognize for myself that it's
the ethanol that I'm not,
I just intuitively,
I don't like putting that amount of
ethanol in my body on a regular basis.
So once in a while as a hormetic,
you know,
uh,
insult,
if you will,
that's fine.
The body will adapt to it and use it as
to its benefit.
But on a regular basis,
probably.
So just the sheer alcohol content of
wine was causing an issue.
It wasn't just the additives.
No.
So,
so the,
the additives were probably causing the
issue because with,
with these wines,
I wasn't waking up in the middle of the
night and it was,
so I felt as if I hadn't had the wine.
So what's the ethanol ethanol is,
is that's the alcohol,
that's the form of alcohol in the wines.
Right.
But it's not the additives.
No,
no,
no that,
that's what you're trying to get at is,
is ethanol is the,
is the alcohol and the wine.
That's what gives you,
right.
That's not what's being added.
Right.
So,
but you had decided that it wasn't the
ethanol,
but I still didn't like the idea.
It's not about the issues as much as
it's just,
um,
it's like I can,
I can consume a fair amount of sugar
over the course of a day and not have
not gained weight and not have it affect
my blood sugar.
I just choose not to because I know it's
bad for me.
Right.
So you don't even like a glass of wine
once it happens,
fine.
Yeah.
Once in a while it's fine.
But it hasn't ever been,
has it been shown that there's some
longevity?
Right.
That's,
yeah.
So do you think that's the Rivera trial,
which is an antioxidant?
I don't,
I think,
I think I could be wrong,
but my interpretation of some of these
studies is that you take two cohorts of
people who have each of whom have a
shitty diet and are going to die of
heart disease in large numbers.
And you give one with the cohorts,
two glasses of wine a night and you give
the other glass or the other cohort
none.
And over time you look at the two groups
and you realize that the group that had
two glasses of wine tonight didn't have
as many cardiac events as probably cause
their blood was thin from it,
from the wine or something.
You know,
it's like,
it's not that it's bestowing longevity
on these people,
it's that they're not dying at the same
rate from their shitty diet.
Because some,
my guess is it's probably some
artificial blood thinning that's
happening or something like that.
Huh.
But why is it a,
it's sort of conventional wisdom that
it's resveratrol.
Well,
fair one of the components of why,
but,
but you,
you would have to drink,
you know,
750 glasses of wine to get the amount of
resveratrol that you can get in a
resveratrol capsule.
There's not a lot of resveratrol in
wine.
There is some,
and it's,
it's a,
it's a well studied,
um,
you know,
component of,
of wine.
Uh,
in fact,
there've been companies founded on just
providing resveratrol as an anti aging,
uh,
nutrient,
but it's not,
there's not a lot of risk virtual and
wine.
And I'm not,
and I don't think any of these studies
have ever pointed to the fact that it's
the resveratrol in the wine that you're
drinking,
that's conferring longevity on this
group versus that group.
Do you think there's any benefit and
consuming exogenous ketones?
Okay.
Uh,
no,
not on balance.
I think if you're an athlete and you're
looking to,
um,
to maximize performance,
there might be places in which you could
consume exogenous ketones.
First of all,
if you haven't,
if you're not keto adapted,
it's,
it's a joke.
There's no reason to take exogenous
ketones if,
if you're fat adapted in Quito adapted,
um,
there may be a reason to take exogenous
ketones in,
in an event,
um,
instead of sugar.
But
like,
say if you're going to run,
do some
amen.
And yet to my knowledge,
there aren't many great tasting
tone salts.
So now you've got a palatability issue
as well with a lot of these things.
Have you tried them?
No,
I haven't,
but I've been fascinated by ketogenic
diets over the last couple months.
I've been really considering trying.
Yeah.
I mean there's,
there's some potentially good science
there,
but I can't give you a practical
application right now,
uh,
where it would,
where it would work other than in some
elite event where,
where somebody was,
uh,
you know,
racing all out for hours and was
completely keto adapted prior to the
event.
And,
you know,
was,
was so good at,
um,
at,
uh,
using ketones in the brain that they
could,
they could hold off bonking for another
hour or two.
So they would take a,
some sort of a ketogenic supplement in
their water or something along those
lines.
Yeah,
yeah.
Or not,
not necessarily on water,
but some,
yes,
some drink would probably be the easiest
way to do it.
So if you were going to recommend to
someone to try to make your body more
fat,
adaptive,
um,
what would be the first step?
Just just to radically cut back on
sugar?
Should you do it slowly?
She to taper off.
Oh,
she just,
just give him up.
Um,
either way.
I mean,
it's easier.
I think if you,
if you just give it up,
he just,
you know,
go all in.
Um,
if you're somebody who's been depending
on sugar your whole life and you're,
you know,
you're doing four or 500,
600 grams a day of carbohydrate,
uh,
then,
um,
you know,
going down to a hundred or 120 is going
to be painful for the first couple of
weeks.
Now I say painful.
We have this thing called the low carb
flu.
So you go from your body,
your brain,
expecting to have you refuel every meal
for every couple of hours every day with
carbohydrate to then,
um,
uh,
reducing it down to 120,
150 grams a day.
The brain starts to go,
what?
What's going on here?
I mean,
the muscles haven't yet built the
metabolic machinery to burn fat.
They're working on it and they're
upregulating the,
the genes are turning on to create the
enzymes,
but they're not there yet.
It takes about 21 days to do this.
So in the process,
the body's expecting sugar,
and if you're trying to work out at the
same time,
you're going to be screwed because now
you have your sugar depleted and you
haven't learned how to burn fat yet and
the brain is depleted.
And so the brain goes,
fuck it.
I'm foggy.
I can't thank,
I've got a headache.
I'm dizzy.
This sucks.
I'm going to get a Bagel though.
It's a lot happened to me when I did the
Atkins Diet for,
yeah,
many,
many years ago.
A lot of people get derailed first or
second week.
Yeah.
So you have to not train during that
time or at least cut it way back.
Don't do any good look glycolytic
training.
So just ride the bike easy,
go for a hike or do some stuff like
that.
But you can't really train,
train hard when you're doing that
because how long does it take to adapt?
So f one or two weeks,
um,
people get through that fog and then
they'll,
they'll be good.
Um,
I have a book called the 21 day total
body transformation.
It's the 21 days is about how long it
takes to get 80% of the benefits of
becoming a fat burning beast is what we
call it.
A fat burning piece that,
I like that.
Yeah.
So you got to commit to it and you've
got to assume there's going to be an
adjustment period.
Yeah.
And,
and in that adjustment period,
it's not going to be,
I mean,
for some people it's minimal,
is that they just feel a little bit low
energy or whatever.
Other people get headaches and woozy
because that's the brain,
again,
recognizing that there's no glucose and
it hasn't yet built the metabolic
machinery to burn ketones.
Um,
even though the body may be producing
ketones and,
and when the body produces ketones,
um,
you can either burn them as fuel or you
can spill them out in the urine and the
breath.
And so a lot of people who have not yet
become keto adapted like a sugar burner.
Carbohydrate dependent person will still
produce ketones.
If you skip two meals,
you know,
you wake up in the morning,
you're basically fast and if you're a
sugar burner and you wake up and if you
don't eat breakfast,
you might smell ketones on that person's
breath.
Or they might,
you know,
pee on a strip and it shows a certain
amount of ketones in the blood,
in the,
in the urine because,
because the body's just getting rid of
the ketones because you can't burn them.
It doesn't have burn him yet.
So to consuming exonerations ketones
doesn't accentuate a ketogenic diet.
So I don't accelerate it.
I don't know.
I don't know enough about the clinical
trials are going on right now.
But my assumption would be that if you
take exogenous ketones and you're not
fat adapted to Quito adapted it,
it's not going to necessarily prompt you
to,
to become that unless you've done the
dietary manipulation as well.
Okay.
So there's no shortcuts to that
transitionary period between,
uh,
a glucose based diet and a of fat based
Diet.
There's just going to have to be a
transitionary period?
I think so.
Cause like I say,
I think,
I think if you skip a meal,
you're producing ketones.
So just,
and you're pissing them out.
So adding more ketones,
it's just going to piss out more
ketones.
So you've got to show,
by the way,
going to be a superstar when you piss on
the Strip because you got your ketones
plus the exogenous ketones.
But this all starts in great.
But this also,
but I feel like shit I'm doing,
but the Strip says I'm doing great.
Right?
Yeah.
Okay.
So this trip's not nearly as important
as the actual physical performance and
where you feel.
So no matter what,
you're going to have to go through a
tree.
So if you like they say it looks just
me,
Gal like me.
If you,
if I had a shitty diet,
I mean spaghetti all day,
um,
you would recommend that for a couple of
weeks.
I just take it real light and make this,
make a commitment to making the
adjustment and the Diet,
doing a fat based diet with very low
sugar,
very low carbohydrates,
cut out the grains entirely.
You get all your carbohydrates from
celery and lettuce and vegetables and
some fruits and just make a commitment
to it.
Yeah.
And part of that commitment is,
I'm not going to train like a banshee
for the first two weeks.
I'm just gonna I'll train,
but I'll do easy stuff.
And that's why the first chapter in our
book,
which should be about diet,
is about training and about low level
training.
And which book,
which the primal endurance book that
just came out a few weeks ago.
Um,
the first chapter should be about die
because that's clearly one of the most
important parts.
But we talk about training first because
we figured enough endurance athletes
would read the book that if they read
the diet part first,
they would continue training at the high
level and,
and,
and embrace the Diet and then fall
apart.
So we got to get the training dialed in
first for those people and say,
you've got to,
here's why you have to cut back.
Um,
here's why you can't exceed a heart rate
of one 80 minus your age for the first
couple of weeks,
uh,
training.
Uh,
when you're doing long distance stuff
and at that rate you'll be burning
mostly fat.
So you'll be accentuating what's going
on on the dietary side,
which is restricting carbohydrates and
providing more fat and more healthy fats
for your body and creating more
mitochondrial biogenesis upregulating
those mitochondria to become efficient
at burning fat.
How long does it take before your body
reaches the optimum level of
Mitochondria?
I mean,
um,
we,
we see,
um,
athletes who are still,
uh,
who get 80% of their benefit the first
three weeks and then s and then another
10% over the next six months.
And then the final,
the final benefits kick in the last six
months because it sometimes you lose
your,
your top end power diminishes as you
become fat adapted,
you got to get that top end power back.
But that's what we build in the gym.
Um,
so it's a,
it's a longer process,
but once it happens,
so it's like 80% and then six weeks
later,
another 10% and then six weeks later,
six could be six months later,
another,
another 10%.
So in the course of a full year,
you're still slowly adapting I think.
I think within a year,
maybe a little bit more than a year,
you can,
if you do everything right,
you can be this completely rebuilt
engine.
That's amazing.
So,
and then there's gotta be some benefits
in terms of longevity,
in terms of your ability to do work over
long periods of time,
like,
well,
one of the things that that's most
compelling is a,
again,
coming from an endurance community where
marriages fall apart because the guy
would rather go for a 100 mile ride on
Sunday morning and then stay in bed and
cuddle with a wife,
you know,
or would would rather Ameritas fall
class?
One of the reasons,
but I thought it was money.
Yeah.
Well it is money,
the $8,000 bike,
uh,
to go on the,
on the ride.
Um,
so,
um,
where are we going with that?
Uh,
longevity.
Yeah.
Marriages fall apart.
So,
so the longevity part,
um,
one of the things that happens is you,
you train less,
there's less total training time to get
the results that you wanted because
you're doing it methodically and you're
not just putting it all out there every
day and crossing your fingers and
saying,
well,
I'm training as much as this guy,
so I must,
I better be as fast or faster than he
is.
Right.
You're doing a,
an approach that's very scripted,
a detailed and methodical at one on one
end of the spectrum on the other end.
It's also sporadic and fractal.
It's like a wake up today and I don't
feel like doing what I had in my plan.
Take the day off.
Because if you've got,
if today's the day you're going to go
hard and you feel like shit,
do not go hard,
there's no magic,
there's no benefit.
There's no,
there's no points that you gain from
doing it.
In fact,
it'll,
it'll take you down the toilet.
So you,
you learn to become intuitive about your
training and period.
This city is one of the words we talk
about where you paradise,
you,
there's,
there's moments where you're,
there's times when you're going very
make your longer workouts longer and
slower and you're a hard workouts
shorter and harder.
Um,
and,
and in the B in the middle of these,
um,
you know,
be intuitive about,
about how you feel,
how much sleep did you get?
Are you fueled appropriately for today's
event?
Are you,
do you have,
uh,
is there a purpose to today's workout
other than just go accumulate miles?
Because I'll feel like shit,
I'll feel like a slob if I don't.
Uh,
and,
and if you could get around all that,
you can,
you can start to see some amazing
benefits with less pain and suffering
and sacrifice less being beat up,
less burnout,
less time.
And presumably if you do it right,
better results anyway than the old,
than the old paradigm.
So that's going to cause a real dilemma
with people that are obsessed with the
work rate.
Uh,
obsessed with just doing more than
anybody else,
obsessed with proving to themselves.
They push themselves,
they put in all those hours and
accumulate and looking at it.
They look at their,
you know,
a lot of people have apps on their
phone.
Yeah.
Measure how many I know.
Oh Shit,
it's nine o'clock at night.
We just finished dinner.
Honey,
I only have 16,000 steps.
I got to,
I'm going to walk back to the hotel or
the house cause I gotta get to 20.
It's bullshit.
That stuff is so ridiculous.
And yet,
you know,
I was there,
I was one of those people who,
um,
you know,
I lived my life based on the amount of
miles I accumulated and measured myself
worth a on whether or not it could hang
with everybody I ever raced or race with
in a workout,
you know,
and never let anybody half wheel me on a
bike ride,
uh,
in,
in any workout.
And it was,
it was fun I guess,
and it was part of my lifestyle,
but it's not,
you got to go back to the,
to the essence of why are you doing
this?
If you're doing it just to hang out.
People used to say,
hey mark,
you so disciplined,
man,
you're,
you're out there and you're riding 60
miles a hundred miles.
Some days you're running 10,
you are so disciplined and might,
the joke is,
I'm thinking to myself,
are you fucking kidding me?
I'm not disciplined.
Discipline is going to work and,
and you know,
putting in a full,
productive eight hours and then finding
a little bit of time to work out or
maybe hang out with a family.
It is,
it was so easy for me to get on a bike
and go put some miles in or go for a run
and shrug every other duty off.
Mm.
You know?
And that's the one of the dangers of
being an endurance athlete.
It's addictive.
It's a,
it's a,
it's a very addictive pursuit you are
creating,
especially if you're beating yourself up
every day.
You're creating endorphins,
endogenous morphine,
like substances that sit on those same
receptor sites,
the painkilling site and the pleasure
giving sites that you would inject
heroin to achieve.
Now you just doing it naturally and
you're doing it every single day and you
crave it every day.
And if you take five days off,
you feel like shit you go with through
withdrawal.
So there's that part of it as well that
we have to look at.
Why do people do this?
Yeah.
I'm the obsessive aspect of it,
the obsessive aspect of it and the
addictive aspect of it.
Yeah.
Hmm.
That's interesting man.
Well,
listen man,
this has been probably one of the most
informative and interesting podcast I've
ever done.
I really,
really appreciate you taking your time.
And coming here and sharing all this
information.
I'm going to have to listen to this
fucking thing three or four times to
work to get all of it and,
and your book.
So please tell us the book again,
the name and how we get,
is it Amazon?
It's primal endurance.
It's on Amazon.
Uh,
my website is mark's daily apple.com.
So a lot of the stuff we talk about here
has been broken down into blogs,
was 4,000 posts over the last 10 years.
Um,
yeah.
And um,
encourage anybody to,
to give it a go.
Well,
I'm giving it a go,
man.
I'm,
you've really convinced me.
I'm sold.
I'm,
I'm gonna radically reduced sugar.
I'm going to cut out all my grains and
a,
I'll keep everybody posted.
Cool.
I'll hold you to it,
man.
Please do.
I really,
really appreciate it.
Thank you very much,
mark.
All right folks.
We'll be back tomorrow with a Hannibal
burress.
See you then.
Bye.
I do.