Doo doo,
Doo Doo Doo.
Oh,
what's up hunter?
How are you doing?
Gel.
I'm doing good now that we're actually
live.
She feels more formal.
We're just talking about how crazy some
of the,
uh,
people in Brian Collins passed.
Then what is the like doing his show?
Man,
I knew you guys.
You're like cohos.
You keep them on the level.
Well,
yeah,
so I mean,
what,
what happened was,
is that a couple of years ago,
Brian and I were talking about books and
Brian had just started doing his podcast
at that point and uh,
you know,
he was sort of interviewing strippers,
a lot of strippers or like porn stars
are like,
you know,
mma guys and that was fine,
but you know,
I was like,
Brian,
if you enjoy these books so much,
why don't we get on some of these
professors?
And he was like,
really?
Like professors would talk to me and I
said,
well,
you know,
what are your download numbers and you
know,
he told me them and then I went off and
I liked the professors and like doubled
or tripled them to do it though.
And then,
you know,
as a result they were all like,
that's great because if you're a New
York Times best selling author,
you usually have an audience of three
and so have a chance to like actually
reach a decent number of people,
then yeah,
you're going to come on this weird
podcast.
You're like,
I've heard of podcasting,
what is that?
Why not?
Right.
And so we started getting all of these
professors and academics and scientists
and all that stuff on and um,
you know,
that's sort of been the journey and
we're now 200 plus episodes in.
Yeah,
that's Brian loves that kind of stuff.
But I wish that like,
how come you never talked about that on
stage?
He just,
he wants to be captain silly face Joe.
Are we willing to wander into the dark,
dark place?
That is Brian Collins mind dark place.
Yeah.
Are you ready to go there?
Yeah,
I've been there.
So,
I mean,
a lot of it comes down to Brian's own
personal insecurities.
Like he loves it,
but he doesn't feel confident engaging
with and breakout.
Disagree with that.
I would say that he's just his comedy,
he prefers it to be silly,
you know,
because there's a difference between
comedy and in Brian's mind,
especially between what's really funny
and what's really deep,
you know,
and he doesn't find deep things to be
very funny.
He's not,
he doesn't,
you know what I mean?
Like he's,
when he gets into deep subjects,
he kind of gets into them just for what
they are and not like tries to translate
those into comedy.
Does that make sense?
It does make sense.
I mean,
but part of what I've seen across the
course of these 200 episodes is I think
that Brian Kellen is growing up.
Oh Way.
Finally it like whatever age he is there
at 5:55
tomorrow.
Yeah.
There's starting to be an evolution and
part of it is just sort of having
actually talked to some of the smartest
people in the world.
He's like,
oh,
these are just people and you know,
they know certain ideas that I didn't
know and now I know them and you know,
maybe I can.
And he even started experimenting with
you particularly got really excited.
We had a guy called Joe Henrich on who
wrote this great book called the secret
of our success,
um,
which is all about cultural evolution,
cultural evolution works,
and one of the things he talks about in
there is,
you know,
why do we have black people in,
why do we have white people?
Um,
and,
you know,
it comes down to vitamin D and foliate
and all these sorts of things.
Determine where are you from?
Oh,
I spent a lot of time in England and I
got rid of most of my accent,
but there are weird words that come out
like vitamin and being.
Um,
and so sometimes people think I'm
Canadian,
which is hilarious because they
literally can't place it.
Side story,
uh,
when I was,
when I first went to college,
you know,
I wanted to major in linguistics for
awhile and I met with my linguistics
professor and he sits me down and we're
having a conversation just like this.
And then all of a sudden he stops me
just like you did.
And he says,
wait a minute.
And he proceeds to like ask me these
really fucking bizarre questions.
Like he's like,
if John and Jane are in a race and John
comes fifth and Jane comes in
afterwards,
what position does Jane come in?
And I was like sick and he goes,
British precedes to like do all of these
tests basically spot my accent.
Sixth,
sixth.
There's no ask.
It's not sixth.
Yeah,
it's super weird.
And then medicine is the other one.
They don't say medicine.
They say medicine.
Oh,
so by sick.
Wow,
that's interesting.
That's interesting because the Eq sound
is really a k and then an ass even
though we represented as an ax.
So he basically had all these tests and
he figured out pretty quickly that I was
trying to pass as an American and he's
like,
sorry,
white boy,
not so much.
How long did you live in England for?
Ten years.
Ten years until your 10.
A from the age of eight until 18.
So if you were in England,
so you started out without an English
accent?
Yep.
Right.
So you learned English here and then
when you started speaking in England,
did you sense that you were shifting
over to nick and I sort of fought it.
I fought it and it's because what
happens is,
is that people naturally sort of start
to,
you know,
you're in a tribe and you start to like
pick up the values and the speech
patterns and all that sort of stuff with
the tribe.
And you know,
I really thought of myself as American,
um,
in large part because I identified with
my mom more than my dad.
Um,
and so what happened was,
is that,
you know,
I was like,
Oh,
British accent creeping in.
And so I fought that with everything
that I could,
but in spite of fighting the accident
with everything,
I could these words that like being in
vitamin and medicine and sick that I
wasn't watching for,
that no ordinary person would watch for,
crept into my mind is always interesting
to me.
There's an added a insight that you get
from people that come from another
country and then live in America.
There's something different about like,
oh,
you guys don't know how weird this
fucking place.
Like I know,
you know,
I've been to Scotland,
I lived there.
You know,
like those people have a different
insight.
Very different insight and also I think
we're so established in America in so
far as thinking that this
is how people live in the world.
Like this is where you go,
you go to Byrd Gang,
it's right over there.
You get on the highway,
it's right over here.
And we see our landscape and we see our
cityscapes and we see it as being
normal.
If you don't go to another country,
you don't go,
oh,
this is normal to,
this is normal for them.
Oh,
Yup.
This is like,
you really need to be there.
Like I don't think that's.
I don't think that's absorbable from a
DVD.
No,
and part of it is,
I mean,
this is a large part of what we've been
doing and what Joe Henrich work is
about,
is the fact that,
you know,
when you're in a tribe,
whatever that tribe is,
whether that's America or Christianity
or mormonism or Islam or,
you know,
some Papa New Guinea,
Ian's in the foothills of,
you know,
Papa,
New Guinea,
whatever you do,
you're like,
that's our way.
That's just the way things are done.
You don't question it,
right.
The tribe creates the sense that this is
what normalcy is.
And then the second you go outside the
tribe,
whatever that tribe is,
you're suddenly like,
oh,
our tribe is fucking weird.
There are other ways of doing things.
And um,
that,
that's sort of been a large part of the
experience that Brian and I had growing
up because Brian's dad was my dad's
boss.
Uh,
so
I'm the first place that I went after I
was born in Saudi Arabia was Brian's
house.
Like at work.
I went to Brian's house.
Um,
and so for the last,
you know,
and then we moved around and we moved to
different places.
He did,
you know,
Philippines,
whatever,
whatever.
I did Saudi Arabia,
Greece,
Brazil,
England,
um,
and then my parents moved to France and
Libya and the UAE and then,
you know,
I came to the US.
So,
so moving constantly between tribes,
like that was a large part of my
experience growing up as a kid was I was
constantly like,
people are all the same and yet they're
fucking different.
And how does that work?
Um,
and because I come from the background
of science,
my first response was like,
oh,
well there must be science of this,
right?
Why not go and look at that science and
see what the science says about that?
Turns out there's a massive amount of
science all about it.
Yeah.
There's a massive amount of science all
about it.
And it's so fascinating when you stop
and think that there are some people on.
I'm sure you've seen the most recent
photos of that uncontacted tribe now
contacted obviously in the Amazon,
like really recently over the last
couple of weeks.
Oh,
it's amazing.
Yeah.
Really cool.
I mean,
these people were there.
They don't have American teacher,
like sometimes you'll see like these
tribes and they're deep in the Amazon,
but they have to tee shirts on and like
can't get there.
There's,
there's some sort of interaction with
these people.
There's none,
there's been no interaction with the
West.
They have stick bows they've made and
you know,
they're all barefoot and all wearing
leaves and shit.
You know,
these people,
they're here.
They aren't trucking along in 2017 and
you've got to think 50,
60,000
years ago.
They probably were living exactly the
same way.
Yep.
Yup.
And what's fascinating is just the
degree to which those people have so
much to teach us because you know,
a lot of what happened,
you know,
in the beginning of the enlightenment
is,
as you know,
if you look at Locke and Rousseau and
all these guys,
they're trying to imagine the state of
nature,
but they're a group of people who are
sitting around in Europe.
They've never met somebody from the
Amazon or someone from Papa New Guinea.
And now we really have a pretty good
idea of what,
what was life like before civilization?
Um,
and,
and it's,
I mean,
it's pretty damn fascinating.
I mean jared diamond has this great
book,
the world until yesterday,
um,
which is literally all about life before
civilization.
And what are the things that we can
learn as moderns from these people?
Um,
what are the things they get right that
we get wrong?
Like what was his examples?
Well,
he has,
there's a bunch of interesting ones.
One of my favorite ones is a
constructive paranoia.
Um,
so what happens is when you have tribes,
people and they go outside of their
village and they suddenly become
massively paranoid,
like incredibly paranoid and he's like,
you know,
these people are more paranoid than your
average New York Jew,
right?
Like suddenly,
like wandering around the forest and
they're like,
shit,
is this tree gonna fall down?
Where can we sleep?
Like they go and they check the trees,
they look for footprints.
Oh my God.
Are those the footprints of some other
tribe?
Like,
what's going on?
What does that sound?
And he's like,
what is this paranoia about?
And for a long time he thought this
paranoid paranoia was just misplaced,
that it was inappropriate.
But then he had this experience where he
had a couple of experiences,
one of which was around,
you know,
somebody,
some other tribe that was potentially
trying to kill him in Papa New Guinea.
And then the other one was around.
He basically was getting on this boat.
And you know,
if you're in the west and you get on a
boat at the New York Port Authority or
whatever,
you feel like,
oh yeah,
this boat safe.
Like there are safety rules.
Probably someone would check it,
whatever.
So he gets on this boat,
the boat goes out into the ocean and
like capsizes and sinks and he almost
drowned to death.
And it's basically because these kids
who were running the boat,
we're running it way too fast and the
water kept sloshing over the side and
the highways and a certain point.
There's so much water in the boat that
the boat goes down.
You know,
when you're in that kind of environment,
one of these societies that doesn't have
protections and doesn't have rules and
all that sort of stuff.
Being paranoid as super smart,
it's the most appropriate thing you can
do,
and he then talks about how,
you know,
he's in 70,
80 year old man.
He's like,
I need to be more paranoid because the
reality is if I go down,
it's probably because I slipped in the
shower.
There are all these things that can
actually kill me in my environment that
I sort of take for granted because my
world seems so safe.
And so one of the things you learned
from that is that paranoia is a tool and
rather than a lot of people have trouble
with paranoia where they're
indiscriminately paranoid,
but the key is figuring out what to be
paranoid about when to be paranoid so
that you're hyper alert,
alert to threats.
I would totally make sense.
Yeah.
I mean they're very vulnerable.
They're so soft and flushing.
Most of their body's exposed and there's
all sorts of different poisonous things
and things
and cats and fucking spiders and
whatever the hell is out there.
And if you break a leg in the gun,
you're done.
Yeah.
And that's the point is they don't have
the luxury of,
Oh,
I was,
you know,
not paying attention to in crossfit I
dropped a barbell on my foot.
Oh,
I go to the doctor.
I'm out for a few months.
Not a big deal.
Yeah.
It's a shorter life though.
It doesn't seem like nearly as fun.
It will be.
The interesting thing is that in many
ways that it's actually more fun because
they have such a strong,
like,
you know,
part of what we don't have.
And obviously part of what you're
creating with your podcast and what
we're trying to create on a smaller
level with our podcasts is tribe,
right?
Like we,
you know,
a strong sense of community,
a group of people that you belong with,
you know,
you're in it together,
all of that sort of stuff.
And you know,
America.
And he particularly talks about the
elderly,
you know,
he talks about what is the experience of
the elderly in a tribe and you know,
you're super valuable until death.
Everybody respects the shit out of you.
You always have things to contribute to
a tribe.
What do we do with the elderly here?
You stick them in a fucking old person's
home and leave him to rot.
You know,
they don't have that sense of belonging,
that sense of purpose late in life.
Do you think that's a sheer volume thing
that's almost like we don't value life
as much because we're overwhelmed by it.
When we're talking about the last
podcast about the number of people in
America today versus when I was a kid.
Yeah,
when I was 14 there was.
We figured there was 230 200,
what was it?
Twenty five.
Two hundred and $25 million.
Now there's a 100 million plus more.
Just the sheer volume.
It seems like if we lived in a small
town and there was some guy that we
really loved and he was starting to die,
we'd want to take care of them.
Right.
But if it's like crazy asshole that's
down the hallway in your apartment
building,
you never even talked to that dude
because there's a thousand people in
your apartment building that you never
talked to.
Right?
Well,
part part of it is like what are
neurological limits?
Right?
So in general there's what's called the
Dunbar number and the Dunbar number,
you know,
it's like one of the 50,
1:50
and then there are serious to explain
that what that is for people who haven't
heard of that,
it's pretty simple.
The easiest way to understand it is
facebook,
right?
Like you may have 4,000
friends on facebook,
but then you constantly find like who
the fuck are these people that I
friended?
And some sort of like friending for
instance,
like a song.
Yeah.
Well hopefully not.
I don't think that you were breaking up.
I don't think that's going to take off.
But you,
you find that like,
oh,
I only really know a few of these
people,
the majority of them my brain can't
track.
Right.
And you even get into that experience.
Like that's what I always find
fascinating is you run into someone you
haven't seen in a long time,
right on the street and you're kind of
avoiding the interaction.
This,
you're like,
oh,
where the fuck do I know this guy from?
Yeah.
And you also then if you like,
really get into it,
then you have to dust off the
relationship.
You have to invest time.
It's fucking exhausting.
Right?
So there's,
there's a real limit to like how many
people any one human brain can handle.
Isn't it more of like the top nine on my
space?
Remember,
wasn't
it nine?
Was it nine people?
Yeah.
When were you to have a top nine?
And like those,
those are the people that you were like
pretty tight with you to have your boys,
all your friends and the top nine.
Well there's a,
there's a series
Dunbar numbers,
right?
And there's like,
you know,
there's essentially like two or three
people who are like,
you would tell anything to.
Right.
And then there's sort of like your top
nine,
right?
You're sort of like,
oh we're cool,
we can all go hang out.
If I was going to have a bachelor party,
these are the people I would invite.
Right.
And then,
you know,
you sort of get out into larger and
larger circles.
One 50 is sort of the size of a tribe,
but then you know,
even though there's 1:50,
there's,
you know,
whatever,
4,000
people,
5,000
people who like,
you'd recognize their face,
but you're like,
I don't totally fucking know you.
So there's a series of all these things,
but whatever the numbers are,
it's not 7 billion.
Well that's what's interesting about
small towns is that there's a,
there's a feeling in small towns of an
invasion,
invasion of your privacy as much as
there is a feeling of comradery.
There's also like a nosiness yeah.
So like if there's 2000 people living in
an apartment building,
nobody wants to know shit about anybody.
Right?
Yeah.
But if it's 2000 people living in a
town,
that's the whole town and everybody
needs to know everything about everybody
else.
Yeah.
That.
But that hunter boy know what he's up
to.
And what about that Brian?
Oh,
he's a wacky one.
And everybody wants to gossip and
exchange information.
What gossip is what Dunbar his work is
really about.
Um,
so his big book is a grooming gossip and
the origins of language.
And so Dunbar,
his whole thesis is.
The big question has always been like,
why do we talk,
right?
Like why do humans have language,
what is the function of language?
And what Dunbar did was he basically
looked at what's the natural group size
of different primates,
right?
So,
you know,
there's a natural group size for a apes
for chimpanzees and you know,
orangutans and all this sort of stuff.
And what ends up happening is,
is that when you,
if you're chimps,
right?
You know,
you can groom all the members of your
team,
of your troop,
right?
That's not a big problem.
But if your trip is 150 people like it
is for humans,
there's no way you can physically groom
all of those people so it becomes too
many people to physically groom.
So essentially the idea is that language
is how we groom each other without
having to do it physically.
And that's what gossip is about.
It's really that we're like grooming
each other,
we're maintaining social relationships
and we're trading information about
who's trustworthy,
who's not trustworthy,
who did what to who,
and passing information around in the
tribe.
Totally makes sense.
I mean,
it seems also when you think about how
women are really into gossiping and
chatting,
whereas men really appreciate quiet and,
and,
and then get upset if people are too
flashy young.
It's about men going off into hunting
parties.
Right?
And the women's staying back and going,
you know,
this crazy motherfuckers doing when no
one's looking and they have to try to
assess what the dangers are in their
environments.
Yep.
And specifically men like what you're
saying about like making sure that
nobody's getting too flashy.
That's,
I mean,
you know,
that's the real function of teasing,
right?
The real function of teasing is this,
that,
you know,
if you look at these hunter gatherer
tribes,
they have all these mechanisms for
making sure that nobody's head gets too
big,
right?
So for example,
you know,
they'll do things where,
for example,
I'll give you my arrow and you'll go
hunt with my arrow.
So then even if you kill a deer,
it's actually not your kill because it
was done with my arrow.
It's everybody's,
it's everybody's killed.
So,
and then also,
you know,
when they,
for example,
they'll have all these rituals when
somebody is elected,
the big man of the tribe or whatever it
is,
they will.
Then all the group will get around and
make fun of him,
right?
And they'll sort of humiliate him and
it's a sort of democracy.
It's a way of keeping him his ego in
check.
So this is what Donald Trump is
avoiding.
The exact this is,
he's avoiding this inevitable reality of
being mocked me.
So mad at Alec Baldwin.
Well then he should,
he should embrace it.
I mean,
that's the shit,
right?
He should,
because I mean,
it's,
that's if for his social function,
right,
the leaders social function is to be
humble because we,
you know,
power corrupts,
like that's what it does to human
psychology.
That's not a function of Donald trump.
That's just a function of the human
brain.
Right?
Um,
and,
you know,
we,
we know that.
I mean,
that's,
you know,
that's been studied.
Now there's a guy at a bar at a UC
Berkeley,
dacher Keltner,
who's also awesome,
um,
who's studied power and specifically,
you know,
there's this old quote from Lord Acton,
power corrupts,
absolute power corrupts.
Absolutely.
He went and studied that and he got more
specific and he found out that power
does two things.
It makes people more impulsive and it
makes them less empathetic.
So it makes people good,
impulsive and bad.
Impulsive in the sense that you'll have
celebrities who will be like,
I'm giving away all my fucking money.
Right?
You're like,
oh,
that was fucking dumb.
Or like Wesley Snipes had that great
idea of like,
I'm just going to not pay taxes.
In his defense,
he just got one of those wacky attorney
convinced there's some loophole in the
constitution and they don't want this
constitution loopholes.
I'm gonna tell you something,
man.
They found out that no one has to pay.
Taxes goes down.
People.
There's a lot of people that actually
had that conversation with me telling me
that you don't have to pay taxes and
that the constitution says that the only
time we were supposed to pay taxes is
during war and that's when they came up
with federal taxes in the first place
and it's not legal and that's why they
can't really charge you with it.
If you just resist like bitch,
they will put you in a cage,
take all your money and we'll put you in
a cage.
Like it is a one time.
There's two really fascinating things
when it comes to money.
That's a really fascinating one and
said,
if you don't pay your taxes,
it's one of those debts were it doesn't
matter.
You go to fucking jail like you go to
jail.
They take everything you have the law,
even if you have no ability to pay it.
When you get out,
you still owe it and you go to jail.
That's fascinating because you can't
just pay it off.
It's not like,
Oh,
you owed $50,000
in back taxes.
No,
you fucking lied to us about paying
money.
So now you go to jail.
Like you weren't honest.
So it's not just you owe the money,
now you pay it,
now you're clean.
No,
no,
no.
You go to jail,
we take all your money and then you get
out and you hadn't made money in a long
time and now you've got to get back on
your feet and fuck you.
Fuck you.
And the other time the PS fuck you is
student loans.
So one thing that you can't fucking go
bankrupt.
Wealth,
that's horrible.
That is the worst idea ever.
Saddled down.
Young impulsive children who are just
getting out of their parents' grasp,
saddle them down with debt and then have
them enter into a diminishing job
market.
And if you start off something in 2016,
what are the fucking odds?
Especially if it's tech related,
that anything you learned is going to be
applicable in four years.
Well,
I mean if you want to talk about the
university system,
I mean,
you know,
there's a.
there's a ship that is sinking pretty
damn fast and a whole lot of stuff,
isn't it?
Having Jordan Peterson on your podcast.
You guys had them before I had them on
and I've been paying attention to his
work for a long time.
He's one of the few people that are out
standing out there in the river
screaming,
you know?
I mean,
that's what he's doing.
He's like,
this is.
You guys are.
This is madness.
You guys aren't being honest about
things here.
Did you see this recent thing with this
women's March?
It was in the New York Times.
They're separating the women by color
and white women are being told to check
their privilege in this March against
discrimination and privilege.
We're going to find that.
See,
I put that up on my twitter,
pulled it up because it's fucking
hilarious and this is not some fringe
newspaper.
This New York Times printing this and
Michael Shermer posted it,
women's march on Washington opens
contentious dialogues about race.
Well,
let's,
what is the,
uh,
what was the headline that was on my
twitter thing about it?
Because the headlines Hilarious.
Look at what,
what schirmer said.
Oh,
to protest racism now,
dividing women by skin color whites told
to check your privilege.
Get the fuck Outta here.
And that's what you were talking about
with power and power corrupting.
That is power.
That's one of the thing that's going on
with this social justice warrior
movement is not just people deciding
that some people should be more ethical
or kind or loving or open a progressive.
No,
no,
no.
It's exerting power over people to
enforce your standard of thinking and
driving on them.
That's a giant problem.
And that's what Jordan Peterson is
fighting.
Well,
and it's the power of a adjust cause,
right?
Okay.
You're fighting racism,
you're fighting sexism.
Like these are things to fight.
Like I'm,
I'm all down with you.
But the fact that you know,
if,
if you have any problem with it,
right?
Jordan Peterson takes issue with some of
that behavior there.
Then like,
so you're saying racism and sexism and
discrimination are okay.
Of course,
no one saying the stupid game that they
play.
Exactly.
They try to paint you into a corner
instantaneously with their opening
statement while you're a bigot.
So you know,
Oh,
I'm a bigot.
Is that what's really going on?
Just because we disagree on things.
I'm a bigot.
Yeah.
And,
and if you look at,
I mean the,
the argument I think particularly about
pronouns,
it really comes down to a linguistic one
in the sense that,
you know,
words are tools,
right?
And so if you look,
if you want to talk about pronouns,
look at English and the time of
Shakespeare,
right?
They had this,
this thing,
thou right,
it was another pronoun and then they got
the fuck rid of it.
Right.
And why did they get rid of it?
Because they were like,
man doesn't really add anything good.
When you say to that,
and it sounds fancy,
but it's not,
it doesn't practically add anything.
Right?
So it was,
it was.
It's the same thing as the romance
languages where it was a distinction
between formal and informal,
you and essentially we decided we didn't
need that distinction so that Pronoun
dropped away and in general that's what
has happened over time.
That's a big part of,
you know,
Joe Hendricks work is that language
simplifies over time the tools become
more and more powerful and more refined
and the same way that say a stone tools,
right?
You see the early stone tools,
their shit and then over time they get
more and more elegant and more refined.
The same thing as being happening with
language for the entirety of human
history.
They get whittled down.
So what the fuck do you think happens if
you introduced 70 gender pronouns?
Well you might get equality.
Fucking racist cisgendered piece of
shit.
You Shit.
That's a problem Joe,
is for guys like us,
we have so much privilege.
Like we're going to be there like
checking it in like half an hour,
an hour.
We have to even out the world.
That is true.
The world must be evened out,
so there's no more competition by the
way,
which is one of the more hilarious
things about people that actually think
that they're communist shut.
Just shut your fucking mouth,
but if you are and you really do
subscribe to that guarantee,
you're not contributing.
You're like one of those hippies that
always wants.
We'd never bring some,
you know,
come on man,
that's old shit about you bring your own
weed.
You they never have it.
Right?
And that's the communist people,
the people that are really into the idea
of communism on theory about everybody's
sharing and not worrying about money.
There'll be great.
There's only the three of us.
We were the only people in the world.
This is my example that I always love to
use.
If was the three of us and there was
like $3,000,000
in the world and we all said,
oh,
it's all just split it up like.
And then money won't be nothing.
It's just we'll just trade back and
forth and everything should be even
okay.
Cool.
And we'd be fine with that.
And then we go on about our merry way,
but there's too many fucking people and
there's inevitably going to be going to
be some form of competition and it's
some form of competition.
Some people are going to get out ahead
and it's going to be some people that
are upset that people were ahead and
it's gonna be all sorts of reasons.
Some people are going to be at the head
because they're assholes.
Some people are going to be head because
they get up at 5:00
in the morning while you sleep till
fucking noon.
That's true too.
These are all true.
There's some people that are totally
ethical and they just do a lot of work
and they do better.
They're going to do better.
They didn't steal from anybody,
they didn't rip anybody off.
But this narrative keeps getting
repeated by people who don't get up at
7:00
in the morning or don't have the same
kind of ambition or feel bad because
some people do want a fucking private
jet and fly all over the world and ball
like Dan Bilzerian.
It's all these things are true.
I mean,
it's both things,
it's like you can be an ethical person,
it'd be like a super ambitious,
crazy person and wants to succeed in
business for some reason.
They're not mutually exclusive.
Nope.
So when everybody says capitalism is
evil and it's the problem,
man.
No,
no,
no.
You saying that it's a problem.
It's not a problem.
The whole reason why you have a fucking
laptop to complain on is because of
capitalism.
And the point is is that the lesson of
2016 is that there are a lot of shit
ideas out there and there shit ideas
spread all around the political
spectrum.
Right?
And the.
I think the challenge of 2017 is how do
we kill those ideas,
but also in the defense of the people
that are anti corporate or Anti
Corporation,
there is an issue when these gigantic
groups get together and they're only.
They're only motivation is acquiring
more money every year.
Right?
That does become a problem and then
there's a diffusion of responsibility
when you're locked into that giant
system and you're just a middle manager
of some Exxon group that's fucking kill
and seals and you don't give a shit.
You know,
those poor seals.
What are they living in the Arctic
anyway?
Loyalists.
Stupid fucking seals covered up with
soil.
You know,
it becomes that,
right?
It becomes.
You're just a part of the thing.
But look,
I got a new BMW drives itself.
Hey guys,
we got a house in the hamptons.
Everybody's happy.
And that's a problem too.
So there's,
there's two problems.
There's,
well there's a million of them,
but that's,
that is a problem with money too.
It's like it might be the issue,
might be corporations in itself might be
a problem.
Like that is a power thing.
Like you're talking about.
Absolute power will look.
The problem is not power per se,
it's unchecked power.
Right?
And so,
I mean the founding fathers understood
that.
That's why you had checks and balances
and the problem is,
is that a lot of the checks and balances
on,
you know,
intellectuals,
right?
What's happening at universities have
broken down,
right?
And the checks on corporations,
which is government,
right,
is broken down and the check on
government is the people and that's
broken down.
And so what's happened is in a lot of
the checks and balances have failed and
the ultimate check and balance is the
people.
But the problem is,
is that you can't get the wisdom of
crowds if the crowd isn't wise and it's
not a real big fucking problem.
One and so good statement.
And the,
the problem is,
is that a large part of this is these
are large historical forces,
namely specialization.
So you know,
if we get,
you know,
the 300 million people in America,
it's not that everybody's an idiot,
right?
It's that,
oh,
you're a lawyer and you know the law and
you know nothing else,
right?
Or you are a teacher and you know your
subject,
you know,
history,
whatever.
Right?
Or if you go into academia and you talk
to a bunch of scientists,
you'll find,
oh,
you know,
your sub discipline of psychology,
of biology and chemistry of and
literally nothing else that is happening
in science.
So the problem is,
is that what that happens is if you look
at the founding fathers,
they,
they read really,
really widely.
Um,
and you know,
I was recently involved in a
intellectual dispute with some
libertarians.
Right?
And so I went to libertarianism.org
where it's just run by the Cato
Institute.
What was the intellectual dispute
regarding.
So my big beef that I've been taking is
with fundamentalists and across the
board,
across the board,
I don't really have a car.
I don't really care what kind of
fundamentalist you are.
I have an issue with fundamentalism in
general and if you look at what you were
just doing,
Joe,
is that you were able to hold two
contradictory thoughts in your mind.
Right?
I think it's important.
It's incredibly important.
You were able to say there's a problem
with people who oppose capitalism and
there's a problem with much of what
corporations are doing.
And then that's how you know,
you start to figure out reality is
you're like,
oh fuck,
there are these two opposing things.
How do I reconcile them?
And you have to go around,
you have to think,
you have to read,
you have to talk to people,
you have to do all that sort of stuff.
Fundamentalists aren't burdened with
that problem.
They have a much easier time because
they know that they are the good guys.
They know that there is one thing that
is the answer to all of our problems and
that there is one thing that is bad and
whatever that bad thing is,
we can just get rid of that bad thing.
Then all of our problems will be solved.
And then they go about figuring out how
to strip away more and more and more of
that bad thing.
Right?
So you look at the obvious example is
Islamic fundamentalism.
They're like,
it's the way of the profit.
We just have to live the way of the
Prophet Mohammed.
And so then we have to strip out
anything that interferes with that,
like toothbrushes and kites and you
know,
women's education.
We're driving around all these really
problematic things.
Right.
And you know,
it's not that the prophet Mohammed
didn't have a toothbrush,
it was just a stick toothbrush and you
know,
I'm not a dentist,
but I think that an oral b is better
than a stick toothbrush.
Dick.
He,
they had like sticks that were like
bristled at the end or something.
Like they would break up the stick.
Then you just get that stick in there
and.
Yeah.
So you're supposed to use that today to
this day.
Well,
if you listen to some of Moms,
yeah.
Wow.
If you want to go super,
super deep.
Yeah.
Well,
exactly.
That's the point that it's always about
going super,
super deep.
It's not the case with Christianity and
all religions,
right?
That's,
there's people that are just,
you know,
kind of like casual Christians just like
us.
People that are casual Muslims and then
there's people that go whole hog.
That's right.
I think that the reckoning is coming.
Jesus is on his way and that's better
pack your bags because you're going to
need clothes and having people that are
packed and ready for Jesus to take them
away
and those people give the rest of
Christianity or the rest of Islam.
Yes,
bad name,
but they also give us amazing movies
left behind and left behind too.
I don't know if you've seen them,
but they're Kirk Cameron's greatest
word,
a ratable work of comedy that he didn't
know his comedy while he was making.
Oh dude,
it's so bad.
Have you seen it?
Left behind and left behind too.
It's so good.
I bought it on vhs.
I saw it at Walmart and I snatched it up
like a greet each child.
I'm going to write this down.
Left,
right and left behind too.
I'm sure you can probably get it on
itunes or something.
It's on itunes or Netflix and find out
where people can watch it because it's
fucking unbelievably bad.
Somebody a youtube Amazon video or
google play and it was based on these
cataclysmic books that were written by
these.
A loony tune dudes.
Is it one loony toon dude or two loony
toon dudes that wrote the left behind
series.
He's a Christian guys,
and by the way,
they've sold like 100 million copies of
this fucking shit bag.
It's so dumb,
but it's amazing.
What's that?
Two guys.
Two guys can each other off in between.
I made that up.
Gay.
Don't get mad.
Don't sue me.
I'm sure your books.
Amazing books the best,
but my.
Take it back,
take it back.
I'm going to be a.
I'm going to never forget some of Kirk
Cameron's best work that growing pains
as best work is avoiding Dick's.
Oh,
is this it?
Oh Wow.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
It's just for us.
Yeah.
This is for the cinematography and the
fact that this is made in 2000 and
that's the cinematography.
Like,
that's really impressive.
So adorable.
He's adorable.
He religious.
Have you ever seen the one where uh,
ray comfort,
who's his buddy and all these videos
describes how a banana is an atheist
work.
Worst nightmare.
How wonderful is that?
Amazing.
So what's wonderful video and that's his
right hand man.
Like he's like,
God designed a banana specific purpose.
Like what?
Okay,
well what is it?
Coconut fuckhead coconuts are more
nutritious it bananas.
Guess what?
Phase?
Really Shitty.
Beating bananas.
She like one of them in a day.
They're high in sugar.
Okay.
You really shouldn't be bananas Ray.
But wouldn't that be amazing if you
managed to convince Christians that
like,
you know,
actually instead of the Eucharist,
you should be eating bananas.
Some people that believe bananas are
like super good.
Well then your potassium,
there's something to them but the
coconuts better for you and you got to
break that fucking thing open.
You got to get through that husk like
somebody had to figure out that husk.
Yeah.
And then the hard part,
you have to be so hungry.
You're banging on a brock and then
luckily for you there's meat and water
inside.
Like wow,
what are the odds?
You had to do a lot of work.
I bet it was probably somebody who's
loved.
One was killed by a falling coconut and
got fucking pissed as smashed that
coconut with a rock thinking that
coconut and killed their mom or somebody
who killed their mom with that fucking
coconut.
That to 150.
People die every year because coconuts
fall in their head.
What a way to go.
Twenty one people in America are killed
by armed toddlers every year.
I think I would.
What would you rather go buy coconut or
toddler coconut all day?
I'll God dropping a rock on my head all
day to be in shot by a one year old.
A one year old.
You like what?
I mean?
I know you're tired.
Why'd you leave a loaded gun in your
purse and crazy bitch?
No,
you get mom.
Bernice,
maybe you should fucking keep that gun
on your hip.
Yeah.
They leave guns and purses and they
leave the kids with the guns and the
kids pull it.
Oh,
I see now on TV and they shoot mommy 21
people a year.
Think of that.
That's not a good way to go,
but in general,
I mean that's two a month.
Yeah,
Bang.
One just probably happened right now.
It's like there's a timer that's going
off like we're waiting.
It's like the slowest national debt
clock.
We should have a arm toddler where you
get a notification every time an rm
toddler kills a person because it's 21 a
year just in this country.
Well,
I think probably primarily in this
country.
Folks.
Get on that.
Who?
I'll promote your APP.
Please send it to me.
Tag Me on instagram.
Make that APP.
Will promoted the arm.
Toddler APP,
toddlers shootings in 2015.
Oh,
1:13
says they killed more.
Oh my God is so that's 13 had
inadvertently killed themselves.
Oh,
13 kids had killed themselves with
firearms.
13 more injured themselves.
10 injured other people and to killed.
Oh,
so there's only two.
This is this statement.
It was looking up.
The toddlers killed more Americans and
terrorists in 2015.
But what?
How many do they kill?
It says they only killed two to have
killed other people to killed other
people.
So toddlers,
they were suicide bombers who killed
themselves.
That's the point.
Okay,
so when you're saying that they killed
15 people,
13 of those 15 were the baby themselves?
Yeah.
Oh,
well that's not the same.
Right?
That's not that,
but I've read.
Where is this?
Where are you getting this from?
On snopes.
I just typed indoor arm,
toddlers.
Do you know what?
Didn't we talk about snobs?
About the.
The Guy Married a hooker?
Yeah.
The guy who owned snopes left,
his wife,
married a hooker,
a who had a website that's an act of
escort website with reviews as recently
as 2015 people reviewing.
So nothing wrong with being a hooker.
No,
that's cool.
But it's the oldest profession,
but when I think about a dude marrying a
hooker,
I figured about a dude who's off the
rails.
When you think about a dude in his
fifties who marries an escort,
I'm like,
oh,
he might.
There's a 50 slash 50 chance that guy
might be out of his fucking mind.
So like one of the criticisms of snopes
during this election was that it wasn't.
There was a pro hillary bias to some of
the information that snopes was
reporting on and apparently she had been
involved in some sort of an anti Bush
anti anti Republican website in the past
and you know,
leans left the whole deal,
so snobs might be a little wacky or not.
Maybe beside all those things,
they still stick to the science thing.
I mean,
you know,
wouldn't that be nice if people actually
stuck to the statistics,
the facts,
reality.
I would way rather have someone who goes
off and married some crazy escort lady
and they pull up to ecstasy every night,
but when it comes down to the work,
they do solid works because I'm a big
old.
Oh Wow.
I was all her husband and wife now
married and that's the old.
There you go.
Happy couple.
Maybe they have a good time.
The guy smiling.
It gives a shit if she got paid for sex,
people are so god damn prudish.
That's when she was at our best.
But presumably it's also like the weird
thing always with fundamentalists and
like wanting to marry a virgin.
Like don't you want somebody who has
some experience with the old wife
though?
She's mad dude.
Yeah,
she mad.
There should be like a meme just as.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I guess.
you'd want someone who was experienced
for sure.
You want someone who's worked at all the
toothy blow jobs so that when they get
to you,
they know what they're doing.
Right.
And is there much of a difference
between a woman who gets paid for each
individual sexual encounter versus a
woman who marries a guy for money,
which is pretty much same thing.
It's kind of the same thing.
Yeah.
I mean you just have one John for life
or at least until you run out.
Yeah.
Until the Castillo's.
Exactly.
Until they upgrade seat number for that.
Those guys like that's a,
that's the trump move.
You know,
those super rich dudes,
they keep getting smaller and more
baller or wife's like.
The new one is like God damn.
Little bit at a certain point like it.
That's a problem.
He can't really.
He can't replace Melania.
Not while he's president.
Uh,
with a hotter one.
Yeah.
Yes.
Again,
you think you can fuck,
yeah.
Yeah.
He's the king of dance halls.
How many people have come out of the
closet as assholes now?
You know,
I mean,
this is a rare time where it's not just
that he doesn't,
doesn't represent a lot of people that
wanted to lean more.
Right.
And you're also represents a lot of men
that are kind of dicks.
Yeah.
Right.
And they get excited about this.
This is,
there's,
there's definitely more overt asshole
behavior in the name of trump.
Yup.
You know,
like he's tapped into that vein,
which I didn't really see.
I don't remember seeing that from any
other candidate ever.
Well,
I think,
uh,
you know,
that frustration has been building a lot
for a long time with those guys.
They didn't get that representation to
get kicked his wife out.
If she said something stupid,
she said,
I'm tired of his breath.
Yeah.
Fuck him.
And he kicks it to the curb and I mean,
people would be like,
get rid of her donald.
Get a new one.
Probably.
It'd be like a gigantic,
like nationwide woman hunt to find the
perfect person who just knows to do what
she's told and to just to,
just to obey the and just
to take care of them.
And as long as she doesn't look too much
like Ivanka.
Right.
Just got to look hot as fuck for sure.
I mean,
he's the God damn president of the
United States and his wife is hot as
fuck.
He's going to go down.
No,
he's not going to get a less.
He's only going to go down in age.
Yeah,
because he keeps going up.
Right.
He went with his first wife,
then with Marla Maples,
maples.
She was super hot and then this one is
even more super hot.
This one's off the charts.
Well,
Eastern European women.
Yeah.
What's that all about?
Uh,
well,
I think actually like a large part of it
is I think also cultural,
right?
There's a certain like arrogance that
eastern European women have where
they're sort of like,
who are you?
Like,
are you good enough for me?
There's a certain hottiness right.
And a certain skepticism,
like an unavailability emotionally.
Are you a racist?
What do you know?
I'm,
I'm thinking about generalist.
No,
but I'm speaking about culture.
This is outrageous.
Well,
do you want to have outrageous
conversations?
Yeah,
I mean,
he seemed like a guy who likes them,
right?
I do.
Yeah,
But yeah.
Do you think that's because of the war?
A lot of those Russian men died in the
war.
I mean,
there was a mass calling of males.
Right?
And that's part of a much,
much older phenomenon than the war.
Right?
So in terms of cultural evolution,
the way that cultural evolution works is
we all have certain mindsets,
right?
So every human has optimism and
pessimism.
Right?
But for example,
we talked about Americans earlier,
right?
And how outsiders see Americans and
Americans are,
you know,
historically massively optimistic that
even Alexis de Tocqueville when he came
here,
right?
A French guy comes here,
he's like,
Americans are so optimistic.
What is up with that?
Right?
That's why we kicked ass on.
Well,
but it is,
I mean honestly,
like the,
because their optimism has certain
benefits,
which is that it makes you super
productive.
Right?
Super happy.
And these have always been a large part
of what American success is about,
but optimism doesn't have a problem,
which is an optimism has a tendency to
make you delusional.
Right?
Ah,
that's a problem.
That's a problem.
And so if you look at what is the most
optimistic group of humans on the
planet,
it's actors in Los Angeles,
right?
Are they really the most optimistic you
think?
Well,
I think the people who are to move to
La,
right?
You have to really believe that out of
all the people in the world that somehow
you're going to make it.
Right?
So optimism is what attracts people out
here.
But then what happens is that a lot of
them end up sort of sitting in optimism,
right?
They're always sitting there and being
like,
I'm going to get discovered.
I'm going to win the lottery.
Right?
Essentially,
it's that sort of mindset and then
they're just waiting for things to
happen.
They don't have an actual plan for going
about it.
That's obviously not true of all actors.
Some people are like,
man,
okay,
I'm out here now.
If I'm going to make it,
I need to hustle,
I need to do things,
I need to do all that sort of stuff,
but there is that trajectory for actors
who come out here hoping they're going
to get discovered,
you know,
are waiting to be discovered for 40,
50 years and then like,
Oh shit,
I'm 70,
and then they crash and then,
you know,
they become the super depressed,
cynical actors who sit around like,
you know,
being like,
fuck the industry.
The industry is the fucking worst.
Exactly.
Because people are rough to be around.
They are rough to be around.
I'm just spit it out.
It's all negative.
It's like coming out of them like a
sprinkler system and that is where a lot
of middle America is right now because
they've had this hope of the American
dream,
the American dream,
the American dream.
And then there's,
those hopes have been crushed,
right?
It hasn't delivered.
It hasn't panned out the way that it was
supposed to.
And so you're seeing a lot of pessimism
and you know,
which is the opposite side.
And pessimism has certain strengths and
the strengths of pessimism.
It's that constructive paranoia we
talked about that they practice in Papa
New Guinea,
which is that you're super alive to
threats,
but you're actually so alive to threats
that you see threats that aren't even
there.
Right?
You're paranoid,
right?
Um,
but the problem is,
is that it also comes with substance
abuse.
Um,
so you find that,
you know,
for example,
what's happening in middle America,
there's a lot of substance abuse going
on,
on all of these opioid addictions,
all that sort of stuff.
Right?
But don't you think that's a function of
being exposed to those things as much as
it's a function of the society that we
live in,
it's those things are super dangerous to
be exposed to.
And because of these corporations that
we were talking about,
the concept want to up their bottom
line,
they're selling these things and pushing
them on doctor.
So it's,
I mean,
that could be as much as the cause of
despair as a symptom of the issue.
Well,
right,
of course,
of course that's a factor.
But at the same time,
look at Russia right?
Russia is a place that is famous for
substance abuse,
right?
Thirty point five percent of Russians
die from alcohol related causes and
that's as compared to say three percent
in America,
right?
So 10 times as many Russians are dying
from alcohol related causes and they
drank fucking anything,
right?
Like they pioneer weird fucking drugs
like Krokodil that are just like fucking
gnarly.
It's either exposed bones and they're
there periodically.
There's all this weird stuff that
happens in Russia where,
for example,
they'll drink like,
you know,
some weird detergent,
some glade plug in or something like
that because there's a tiny bit of
alcohol in it,
right?
So there's a certain psychology that
comes with that massive pessimism and
that massive pessimism evolve because of
the context of Russian history,
right?
So Russian history,
if you ever want to truly be depressed,
just read some Russian history,
right?
That'll do it for you.
And you find that like,
I mean,
Russia has always been a meat grinder,
right?
It just chews people up and spits them
out.
And so the way that you survive in that
environment is being massively paranoid,
right?
The winter will kill you,
The leadership will kill you.
There all sorts of things that will kill
you.
And so the Eastern European mindset
tends towards this massive,
massive pessimism and the pessimism is
useful in the same way that it is for
the Papa New Guinea.
Ian's where you're massively alive to
possible threats,
but it sets up these problems and the
problems that it sets up our substance
abuse.
And it also sets up the problem of sort
of anticipating threats that aren't
actually there and just overall despair.
Yep.
And so what ends up happening is,
is that there's then the problem that
pessimists and optimists misunderstand
each other,
right?
They don't get each other right.
The optimist is like,
you're just fucking depressing and you
know,
sort of see threats that aren't there
and like,
your life sucks and the pessimists looks
at the optimists and it's like,
you're fucking delusional dude.
Like you got to get real.
You've got to understand how things
really work.
So if you look at what happens in
Russian and American relations,
what happens is that you'll have to the
same situation but interpreted in two
totally different ways.
So after the fall of the Berlin Wall,
the United States made some sort of
promise or some sort of intimation that
it would not expand NATO any further
east and the Russians were took that as,
okay,
you're not expanding NATO any further
east.
Right?
But in fact,
what ended up happening is the United
States and the West,
and it's sort of oblivious hopefulness.
It's like,
let's keep expanding NATO,
right?
They didn't take this comment very
seriously,
and they moved NATO all the way to
Estonia all the way to the Russian
border.
Now the Russian sitting on their site
interpret that as a violation of the
promise.
So sitting there as the pessimists that
they are,
they're tracking each of these moves.
They're like,
oh,
okay,
you're moving to another country over.
You're moving in another country over.
We see what you're doing.
And that's a lot of what the tension
that boiled up between Russia and
America was about.
Well,
don't you think right now?
Rushes in the weirdest place ever with
Putin because he's essentially a
dictator is a dictator,
right?
Right out in front of you as a dictator
and all of his.
All of the people that are opposing him,
they weren't getting murdered really
publicly yet,
but that's because the dictators are
godfathers.
That's what they're.
They are.
And you,
you know,
father's household well on the sentiment
in Russian culture that.
No,
just to dictators in general who is
Kadafi?
Who is Saddam Hussein?
Who are any of these guys?
They,
they functioned as the godfather of
their society.
So there's basically,
you know what you want the,
there's an I should clarify just so that
people know.
Where is this all coming from?
This is all coming from books and
interviewing academics and if you are
curious about anything,
tweet me,
let me know.
And if there's any comments that you're
curious about,
I'll direct you to the book and you can
go read it and you can work your way up
the science chain and figure it out.
There's an onslaught of Dick pics to be
tweeted to.
Exactly.
Or,
or Dick Pics.
I don't know what I'll do with those,
but you know,
when you want to send them back for
gifting.
So I'm a Russian civilization.
Where were we?
So,
so there's,
there's essentially,
if you look at,
if we talk about those hunter gatherers,
right?
They have a two big problems,
One big problem is band level genocide.
So what'll happen is,
is that periodically one tribal just go
and wipe the other fucking tribe out,
right?
They'll kill them down to the last man,
they'll kill the babies,
they'll do all that sort of stuff.
And this can happen super,
super quickly.
So what'll jared diamond when we had him
on the podcast,
he told this great story about,
you know,
there's these two tribes in Papa New
Guinea.
They've been living side by side for
years and years and years,
perfectly happily.
They love each other,
they get along,
they cooperate,
all this sort of stuff.
And then resources get scarce,
right?
There's some change in the environment.
Suddenly there's not as much food around
and as people start to get hungry,
one of the tribes goes off and for in
the course of half an hour,
they tell each other,
made up stories that get increasingly
fantastic and by the end of the half an
hour they have convinced themselves that
the other tribe are vermin that they
need to be exterminated,
that they are a scourge on the land,
that they're not really human and they
go and wipe them the fuck out.
And that is one of the dangerous
potentials in human psychology is the
fact that when resources get scared
scarce,
we like identify some sort of threat in
the environment,
some sort of group of humans and we go
home,
we wipe them the fuck out.
So if you look at,
for example,
what happened in Germany in 1933,
right?
There's the great depression,
there's hyperinflation,
there are all these problems and you
know,
that old psychology that hasn't changed
and tens of thousands of years is still
there.
And so naturally people start looking
around for a scapegoat and the
antisemitism that is sort of already
lingering in.
You know,
the German cultural environment,
you know,
suddenly that becomes the target group
and you know,
Hitler,
the political opportunist comes along
and says,
oh,
you can blame it on them.
That's the source of all your problems.
It's almost like there's a death mode
locked in the human consciousness that
when things get scared and like,
Oh,
you might die,
we're now on death mode.
That's right.
Death mode means you kill other people
quickly.
That's right.
And,
and that's,
and you have to understand,
I mean,
this is the brutal reality of evolution,
is that in that hunter gatherer context,
that's fucking useful.
It's really useful if,
if resources get scarce,
to be the one who acts first,
who wipes out the other tribe first.
What's interesting that we even think
that this is unusual or bizarre when we
look at nature,
when you look at all the different
systems in nature that are set up,
like how many times lions will kill cubs
to make sure that those males don't grow
up to dominate.
That's right.
Especially cubs that aren't theirs.
Um,
and that's,
I mean,
that's a big problem of sort of what's
happening on college campuses is that
there are a lot of unpleasant things in
human psychology and unpleasant things
in human nature and you know,
for humanity,
really the good things come from being
realistic.
When we're realistic about how disease
works,
we get to control it.
When we're realistic about how electrons
work,
we get to control them.
Let me ask you this,
because this is really important to this
subject,
this issue with Marxism spreading across
universities.
What do you think is the cause of that?
Like why is that so attractive to
people?
Why are people so confident to openly
proclaim,
proclaim themselves as Marxists without
understanding how ridiculous that is?
Well,
it's,
you know,
so John Height,
who um,
you know,
is uh,
is at Nyu,
he has what's called moral foundations
theory and essentially it's that we
have,
we all have these sort of basic impulses
of morality.
So for example,
fairness,
right?
So you know,
you can watch little kids and they're
like our tracking fairness,
what's fair,
who got more,
who got to play with the toy more and
all that sort of stuff.
That doesn't change,
right?
But we have these notions of fairness
play out in different ways as we're
adults,
but different political groups and
different tribes favor these other
notions of fairness more than some
others.
So let's take for example,
the issue of pro life versus pro choice.
Right?
Okay.
So you have,
let's just,
here's the question.
Are liberals pro life or are liberals
pro choice?
They're more pro choice on the issue of
abortion.
So on abortion it's about freedom,
right?
Okay.
Uh,
well it's very much about women's
rights,
women's freedom.
It's a big,
uh,
it's not,
it's not even thought of it like as a
human freedom because,
uh,
it's,
it's about the woman,
not about the child.
That's right.
So it's about the woman's freedom,
right?
So they've hooked up to that idea of
freedom,
right?
Yes.
And then,
you know,
conservatives are pro life.
This is about caring and protecting from
harm and all that sort of stuff.
Okay.
Unless you're talking about war,
unless you're talking about war and
that's exactly the point.
Is this that you know,
are all humans hypocrites or is it that
we selectively use these same intuitions
that we all have for different causes?
So if you look at,
for example,
gun control,
are liberals pro choice or pro life?
They're definitely pro life.
Ah Ha.
So what you see is that on abortion
they're pro choice and on gun control
they're pro life,
but then when it comes the other way,
exactly lichens are pro choice when it
comes to guns.
So we all have these same intuitions,
but we use them in different ways to
justify our political arguments.
Well,
what's interesting too is that there's
two positions that are taking place in
the American psyche at least,
that were almost reluctantly agreeing to
and is that the Republicans are,
or the Conservatives are more realistic,
more hardcore ready to kick ass ready to
fight for what's right.
Yeah.
Whereas liberals are bunch of whiny
crybabies looking to give away their
money and they're creating welfare
babies.
Well,
that's certainly.
If it wasn't for.
If it wasn't for the conservatives,
these fucking people would be speaking
German living in Vietnam actually write
well at all tribes.
The nature of tribes.
You tell something that makes your tribe
look like the good guys.
Right?
So each tribe has.
That's,
that's the conservative story.
And then the liberal story is like we're
fighting racism and sexism because you
see the Golden Globes.
Uh,
I did see the golden.
She's a meryl streep,
Meryl Streep's speech.
God bless her.
God bless marrow.
What she was talking about,
mixed martial arts people get so mad.
And I was like,
of course she doesn't watch cage fighter
when she's talking out of her ass for
sure.
But she did say that some people aren't
artists.
Martial artists aren't artists.
Well that's completely open to
interpretation.
Like what do you think is
beautiful?
You think that fucking stupid movie.
When you played that Rockstar,
what was that one that nobody went to?
St Ricky get your gun or whatever the
fuck that is.
Listen,
that wasn't art.
That was an art.
And Anderson Silva Front kick to the
face is a thousand times more beautiful
than that piece of shit movie put out
lady.
I'm sure she's a very nice person and
she probably thinks that she's.
She's standing up for what's right.
Get ready for ricky.
That's ricky flash.
Get the fuck out of here.
Three people saw that when we are all
related to her.
He saw that movie and you see that movie
even heard of it.
It was like,
what are they doing?
She's an 80 year old lady,
is going to be a rockstar.
Ricky's coming back.
And.
But it's also like such weird casting
for her too because she does like these
emotionally difficult.
Like Sophie's choice movies.
She's like trying to do like a poppy
rockstar movie.
Well she was interested in it.
You know,
she's an amazing actress.
She's an amazing artist in her realm.
And I just think it's the.
You could,
you could sort of say that without
disparaging what other people enjoy and
including disparaging with a lot of
women.
Enjoy like and foreigners.
One of the things you were saying is
that Hollywood is crawling with
foreigners.
If you take them out,
all you have left is mma and football,
MMA,
mixed martial arts,
not the arts,
but you wouldn't.
That's not true because like 80 percent
of the fighters in the UFC or from other
countries,
they're from Ireland,
like conor Mcgregor,
they're from Brazil.
Like Amanda Nunez.
I mean this is the good,
incredibly diverse lineup of people from
all over the world.
So for her to say that is like so silly,
but I can understand saying that you
don't think it's an art by your
interpretation.
I understand that,
but the larger point is that humans are
silly.
Yes,
general are silly and we're not
individually that smart.
I think performance arts,
like as far as dance,
I mean dance is clearly an art,
right?
If you watch Mikhail Baryshnikov,
that's clearly art and I think in many
ways competition in performance,
like gymnastics is also an art.
We don't think of it as an art.
We think of it as a sport,
but when you look at the ability to
execute these spectacular moves,
yeah,
maybe that doing it to a concerto,
but it's still art.
You know,
like you see some amazing gymnast,
fly through the air and nail a landing.
It's beautiful.
It's glorious.
Well,
that's art in competition,
but it's not one on one competition.
Now art in one on one competition is
Edson Barboza.
We'll kicking Terry Adam.
I know it doesn't look like art to some
people,
but to me it does well and it's a
technically extremely difficult move in
clinic and a lot of time to practice and
get good at it.
So it's just the fact that when he does
his beautiful pair of wet,
it just lands in someone's face.
Well,
someone has to suffer because someone
has to suffer and perhaps sometimes both
people have to suffer in terms of a very
brutal fight.
Right.
But if you look at like Amanda Nunez
knockout out of Ronda Rousey,
if you're an Amanda Nunez Fan,
that is a beautiful
work of art.
Yeah,
because she didn't get any promotion for
that fight.
She was looked at like cannon fodder to
go in there and fight rousy.
A lot of people were predicting a first
round victory and she went out there and
fucked her up in 48 seconds.
That's art too.
To some people it might not be to her,
but.
Well,
but also,
I mean this comes down to,
you know,
liberals,
right?
So in general,
liberals massively over favor the notion
of caring.
That's like their big,
big moral intuition,
right?
So they care about the environment,
They care about protecting children,
toddlers from dangerous guns,
right?
They just sort of.
Everything is interpreted through caring
and wanting to protect.
So understandably,
when they look at an MMA fight,
they're like,
oh,
that's bad because there's not caring
and people are getting hurt,
right?
They're getting their feelings hurt.
And so when Jordan Peterson is on here
and he's talking about how it's this
very sort of maternal thing,
it is a very maternal thing and the
problem is,
is that,
you know,
what ends up happening is,
is that when you have an echo chamber
like college campuses,
which are incredibly liberal with very
few outside opinions,
that that's the rabbit hole that they go
down,
they go down the caring rabbit hole and
when you go down the caring rabbit hole,
you end up at Marxism and you know,
when you're surrounded by people who
essentially think like you,
there's no one to like sit you down and
be like,
that's fucking nuts.
Like let's talk about though the,
that is why do you think going down the
caring rabbit hole lead you to Marxism?
Well,
because you know you don't want anyone's
feelings to get hurt.
You want everybody to have enough.
You know,
you want to share.
And it's important to realize back to
your point where you said like,
you know,
if it was the three of us,
communism might work,
right?
It comes back to the Dunbar number.
If you actually look at hunter gatherer
tribes,
they're communists right there,
really,
really socialist.
And what they do is,
for example,
they have these behaviors where,
they'll drag.
If you go and kill a deer,
we drag it into the middle of the
village so everybody can see the deer
and then we divided up and then you make
sure that you give it to everybody else
first.
And then you take the last piece and you
take the smallest piece.
So it's,
you know,
what you do with birthday cake,
you're trying to show everybody like I'm
being Super Sherry here.
Isn't this great?
I'm not thinking about myself and at the
level of a tribe,
you and I can track all of the
interactions we can attract.
We can track the fact that,
you know,
oh,
a fucking hung over there is not pulling
his weight.
Such a,
such a piece of shit.
And that's the point we go and we talk
about,
um,
we talk shit about 'em.
And then we go and we go and we confront
them.
We say among you fucking piece of shit.
Like we go out all hunting all day and
then you sit around and you know,
there's always going to be an honest.
There is always going to be an along and
if you have enough people for sure
you're going to have 100 people.
There's going to be one and that's just
evolution.
It's a strategy that works.
Oh,
fat sack of Shit.
You come back and all guava,
like you ate all of it.
Right.
And there's.
Then you have to plot to kill ung.
Well.
Or to get him to pull his weight for
him.
No,
you just say kill him.
Take them on.
Take them hunting and have him have an
accident.
Come over the fucking place.
Exactly.
Look over there dude.
Looking at waterfall or get them to hang
out with a toddler with a gun.
Yeah.
They don't have that as though the
second word.
Tyler with little kids can't even
stretch that far.
Talking to now you have a zero worry
about being shot by a bone marrow from a
toddler.
Another reason why arrows are superior.
I'm so.
I'm so,
but Marxism,
Marxism being like a communist ideology
of Marxism,
being that you know,
everyone should be more equal sharing
more,
but as Jordan Peterson pointed out so
eloquently on your podcast and on my
podcast,
that doesn't really work.
It doesn't work at 7 billion people,
more 300 million people,
50.
It works at 50 or $150 because that's
what our brain can track.
The problem is is that I can't track all
the ungs.
It works great without technology.
It works great without access to people
all over the world.
That works great in a consolidated
environment,
a small controlled,
contained environment,
but it doesn't work when a,
essentially there's,
you know,
you're in an apartment building,
have 2000 people and you don't want to
fucking talk to anybody,
right?
But what do people say?
Well,
it should work and we can make it work.
It's just this old outdated mindset that
you fuckers grew up.
You guys grew up way back in the day
before the influence of the Internet.
Now we understand thatZ is a very
respectable pronoun and we need to be
using.
How do you say that?
Zero.
Zero,
zero.
I think so know there's 75 options.
Whatever the fuck they are,
you know.
Well,
I mean I think the experts making people
use it.
Well,
Oxford is again also gone down the
rabbit hole,
but the,
these,
you know,
colleges and academia are not going to
go back out of the rabbit hole.
They're just getting.
They're going to keep going down the
rabbit hole until the larger community
holds them accountable.
So do you think that that's happening at
all now?
I mean there was the president of
Chicago University that said,
hey listen,
there's going to be a safe space is this
year.
It's not going to be any trigger
warnings to shut the fuck up and go to
work and learn.
This is the marketplace of ideas.
That's right.
Express yourself,
get your ideas challenged,
debate these ideas.
Let's find out what's right rather than
what's safe.
Well,
and I think a large part of how you do
that faster.
I mean firstly people already doing it.
There's the,
there's the guy in Chicago,
there's Jordan Peterson,
you know,
the larger community is having a
conversation about this,
but the faster way to do this is
science,
right?
You confront people with science and
then you force people to either are you
either accepting reality,
are you denying reality and if you're
denying reality,
then you got a real problem because now
you look like a fool.
Well,
you,
when you talk about science,
you have,
you run into a real issue when it comes
to gender.
Yeah.
Gender and science,
like gender as is discussed
on campuses today,
things that gets things get real weird
thing.
It gets real sort of loose and open to
interpretation and even though you're
biologically a male,
you can identify as a woman and the
correct way to treat you as to treat you
as a woman.
So we're,
we're gone.
We're outside the realm of science now.
Well,
we're in into the world of social
constructs and agreed upon behavior,
but the science exists.
It's just in journals and it hasn't been
brought and made accessible to these
children and there are ways to do it
very simply.
So for example,
do you know the story of David Reimer?
No.
Okay.
So this was a kid in the sixties,
um,
who I think it was Canadian and for some
bizarre reason right at the hospital,
the surgeon decides to use an
electrocautery needle to circumcise him
and basically there's a huge botch up
and he manages to,
he manages to chop off most of his dick.
Right.
And so the parents are like,
okay,
can't put that back on,
what do we do?
And so they end up going to the world's
leading specialist in the 19 sixties or
whatever it was,
50 sixties on gender identity and all
this stuff,
which is this guy Dr.
money.
And they go and see Dr Munday and Dr Dr.
money convinces them to castrate their
penis lists son and to raise him as a
girl.
And so they have to go and,
you know,
take their son in and,
David who is now going to be raised as
Brenda,
um,
is,
you know,
Dr Money is showing pictures of naked
men to Brenda and saying like,
this is what girls like and all this
sort of stuff and you know,
uh,
is forcing him to wear women's clothing
and they're going to do hormone therapy
and all this sort of stuff.
Now Dr Money is meanwhile publishing
papers that is saying,
oh,
this is a tremendous success.
It's amazing.
Like gender is all a construct,
you know,
blah,
perfectly adjusting to life as a girl.
All this stuff.
And the plan is,
is that,
you know,
they're going to do surgery and give him
a vagina and all this sort of stuff.
Not some.
Now.
Meanwhile,
what is Brenda doing?
Brenda's hitting things with sticks.
Brenda has no interest in playing with
her sewing machine except for the one
time that she takes a screwdriver and
picks it apart to figure out how it
works and doesn't want to hang out with
girls.
Only wants to hang out with boys only
wants to play with her brothers toys,
you know,
so all these sorts of things.
And at some point,
you know,
and when the kid is like 13,
14,
the Jig is up,
they figure out that they better tell
Brenda the truth and Brenda finds out
the truth and proceeds to essentially,
you know,
have a mastectomy to remove her breasts,
switches to male hormones and you know,
instantly goes to living as a boy.
Now what happens is,
is that,
you know,
Brenda,
now David grows up,
marries woman,
um,
and you know,
has a relationship,
but unsurprisingly has a whole bunch of
psychological issues and ultimately goes
into a supermarket,
a grow a parking lot and blows his
brains out.
Now,
the point is,
is that I think that if you really want
to talk about gender,
you should force anybody who wants to
deny gender to talk about David Reimer.
You Make David Reimer household name,
and we're all going to talk about what
lessons can we learn from the tragedy of
j Dot David Reimer.
And if you get,
for example,
you know,
how many listeners do you have at this
point?
Yeah,
it's a lot Joe.
And if you get your tens of millions of
listeners,
$30,
million plus listeners talking about
David Reimer and you're like,
we're going to make David Reimer
household name.
We're going to make sure that the
tragedy of David Reimer is something
that everybody knows about and learns
about and everybody's tweeting and
talking about David Reimer.
Then suddenly it becomes very hard for
anybody to say that gender is purely a
construct.
There may be spectrums and there may be
like,
you know,
weird in between areas,
but the reality is that a lot of gender
is genetic and the sciences there,
and you're not going to get a bunch of
social justice warriors to read science
because most people don't actually read
science,
but you will get them to engage with the
story of David Slash Brenda Reimer.
Well,
there's most certainly as a spectrum,
but there's also a high percentage of
people that operate in a very specific
area of that spectrum and you're going
to get some kids that are convinced that
they are boys,
but guess what?
Some of those kids grow up and they
changed their mind as they get older and
that's something that really deserves
the shit out of me.
When I see nine year olds that are on
hormones,
I'm like,
this seems crazy.
Like this kid really thinks he's a girl.
Let him think he's a girl.
Like as is like,
why are you adding hormones to the mix?
Why?
Right.
Why are you suggesting surgery when he
turns 15 or whatever the fuck the ages.
Like this seems like something that
should be worked out by a grown adult
with a fully developed frontal cortex.
That's right.
It doesn't see.
And also like the influence of the
parents to change how this kid.
Like if you have a kid and you have a
daughter and your daughter just wants to
cut all her hair off and climb trees and
like let her do that.
Like if she wants to be a boy letter,
thinks she's a boy and and work it all
out one day.
That's right.
But to work it all out and to encourage
that behavior or to say we're going to
bring you to a transgender specialist
right away and they're going to
prescribe this and that.
Like how many of these people are going
to be like Brenda reimers original
doctor?
Well there was a male name was a male
named David,
David Reimer,
David Reimer's original doctor who,
who were,
you know,
proclaiming it was such a success when
the tour shit
in general,
raw reality,
denial leads to tragedy.
That's,
and you know,
so what we have to be engaged with is
what is reality and you know,
it's not that I sit here and have read
literally all of the science I can't
like,
it's,
it's far too vast to project and science
isn't supposed to be an individual
project.
Supposed to be a collective project.
We're all trying to really figure out
what is this bitch known as reality that
has evaded us for millions of years or
tens,
hundreds of thousands of years.
And you know,
the,
the point is,
is that if you want to talk about like
gender for example,
let's talk about people who are
Intersex.
There are some people who are born and
it's not,
you know,
their genitalia at birth aren't clearly
male or female and what they now do,
you know,
the medical community is that you
basically find out what are they
genetically,
are they x,
y,
or are they xx?
And then you raise them as that,
but you don't do hormones and you don't
do surgery precisely because you're
going to let them decide.
Right?
And if you are,
I mean,
you know how much better.
Okay,
so why is this surgeon using an
electrocautery,
neil needle to do circumcision?
Who the fuck knows,
right?
Like it's a dumb choice by a surgeon.
But imagine if they'd said,
okay,
that fuck up happened.
We can't unfuck that up,
but we're not going to now make it worse
by chopping off his balls.
Well,
this was what year?
This is in the sixties,
fifties,
sixties.
The amount of data they had back then
was so limited and we've now,
we've now got a lot more data and you
know,
David,
Brenda Reimer is not an isolated
incident.
There've been other incidents like that.
Um,
and you know,
they,
they very like,
it's not,
it's not that everything turns out
David,
Brenda Reimer,
right?
But if you really care about children
and you really care about people,
which is the sort of the big liberal
value,
then you know,
if the hippocratic oath,
the whole point of being a doctor is
their first responsibility is do no
harm,
right?
You're not supposed to make things
worse,
right?
If you can make things better without,
you know,
really possibly making things worse,
then that's great.
And so again,
again,
you would,
we don't let children vote.
We don't let children drive.
Why would we let them make such a huge
decision at such a young age?
Um,
and I think whatever the decision ends
up being,
you know,
people are going to make their own
individual decisions,
so be it.
But you want to make sure that the
decision is an informed decision.
And
there's also,
um,
there's forbidden territory when it
comes to gender and gender identity as
far as like what you are allowed to
debate or not allowed to debate.
There's a lot of forbidden territory.
It becomes a pretty obvious that the
origin of that forbidden behavior,
forbidden thinking is that people that
are transgender or gay or marginalized
in any way have been discriminated
against and treated poorly.
And we recognize that.
So we are,
we automatically stop any critical
thinking when it comes to those people.
Like they can't be crazy.
They must be,
you know,
it's just a transgender issue.
It couldn't be that they're crazy and
transgender.
Well that's never discussed.
It can't be.
He's gay and stupid as fuck.
No,
no,
no.
Gay People are wonderful.
They're all amazing.
Yeah.
Because they've all been discriminated
against.
Right.
And the point is you don't,
I mean,
you know,
human beings are human.
And so for example,
when
we had Jordan Peterson on,
one of the questions that I asked him,
which I think is a super important
question,
is Jordan's a psychologist.
Right?
And I asked him,
okay,
so let's imagine you had a patient who
came here and said,
you know,
I want to be called by one of the 70
pronouns,
right?
What as your patient would you then do?
And he said,
well,
if you came to me and said to me that
you were Jesus Christ,
I would have to as a responsible doctor
first decide that it was in my best
interest to call you Jesus Christ.
So I have to figure out really what is
that about and is it going to serve your
outcome to be able to do that.
And again,
you know,
there's unaccountability for any human,
whether it's a celebrity or a sports
star or a rapper or a gay person or a
transgender person or a politician or a
scientist is bad.
Like humans need accountability.
Like that's just the reality.
Otherwise we go fucking nut balls.
So if for any reason a human is denied
accountability to other humans,
you've got a problem,
right?
Yeah.
You're doing them a disservice by
thinking that your in somehow or another
helping them or you know,
like that stupid article earlier today
that we were talking about,
about these people showing up with a
racist and a conference and then the
white people being forced to check their
privilege.
Like this is your,
you're ruining the whole thing with this
kind of short sighted shitty thinking.
I want to really go down the rabbit
hole.
No,
let's do it.
Let's do it.
So do you know Thomas Soul?
I know that name.
Why don't we do that name?
Thomas soul is a big,
famous conservative.
He's at Stanford.
Um,
he's at the Hoover Institute,
I think.
Anyway.
So,
you know,
within this,
I mean,
first just to set all this up,
we should set up briefly how does
culture work,
right?
And the way culture works is that it
like genetic evolution.
It works based on blind copying.
So what ends up happening is that you
are in all of people,
right?
You look up to people and so you blindly
copied the things they do and
specifically you start by blindly
copying from the outside.
And then you work in,
so the first thing you do is you see
someone and you're like,
oh,
that person's fucking amazing.
That rockstar,
that sports star or whatever,
and you start dressing like them.
You start walking like them and all of
that sort of stuff.
Now in a hunter gatherer context,
that would be somebody who is a hunter
or a gatherer and you're like,
man,
you know,
she finds all the best guavas how does
she do that?
And then among fucking eats them.
Yeah.
Um,
and so,
you know,
you would,
you would like hang out with her.
You'd sort of Shimmy up to her.
You'd be seeing what she'd be doing.
She's like,
oh,
okay.
That she looks for a very particular
color of guava.
She squeezes them in a certain way and
over time you learn what she's doing.
And then ultimately you even learn how
she's thinking.
But in a large scale society like ours,
I don't meet Michael Jordan,
right?
Michael Jordan just becomes this sort of
distant person that I idolized.
And so advertisers have figured out how
to hijack these mechanisms and they know
if you a burger next to Michael Jordan's
face that I'm like,
oh,
I want to be like Michael Jordan,
so I'm going to eat a big Mac.
Right?
And little children are dumb and so they
blindly copy that,
or Oh,
I want to be like James Dean,
he has a cigarette in his mouth and I
want to blindly copy that and we don't
understand that the burger or the
cigarette is not actually the key to
being as successful or as cool as or as
good at basketball as Michael Jordan or
James Deane.
Right.
We don't understand that.
That's where that comes from.
So we have this tendency to blindly copy
anything we can.
Right.
So it makes sense.
Yeah.
And in,
in a mass society,
we never work our way in.
We never learn the mastery,
right.
We just sort of remained at this sort of
very superficial level.
So what that means is that we're.
Where did this all start?
A good question.
Yeah.
Where were you going with this?
Well,
we're starting at culture,
how culture works,
how culture works.
Okay,
so now we're going to talk about black
people.
Okay?
Jesus Christ.
So Thomas Thomas,
Thomas Soul is a black guy,
right?
And Thomas Soul has for years and years
and years being trying to fight racism,
but he's been trying to fight racism by
having a conversation about culture,
right?
And the fact that there are essentially
two different sort of,
uh,
you know,
we're speaking broadly here,
right?
But this is for the purposes of
communication.
Um,
we're going to tell a simple story to
start off with,
right?
So broadly speaking,
he puts two different cultures of people
with dark skin next to each other,
and one culture is these people from the
West indies.
And one culture is this group of people
who grew up in the south with slavery
and all that sort of stuff.
Now,
what one group,
the West indies group does really well.
So I'll,
a lot of the successful black people,
people like Colin Powell are originally
from that cultural heritage.
The other group is the group that you
find in ghettos and African American
communities.
And all of that sort of stuff,
they don't do well,
right?
They don't get good education,
they shoot each other,
they're all these sorts of things.
And the reason why soul has been telling
this story is because he's been trying
to say,
you know,
when liberals look at the people in
Ghettos,
they say,
oh,
racism.
That's why they're not succeeding.
And Soul is saying,
no,
it's not.
Because if you look at this group from
the West indies,
they also came from the experience of
slavery.
There was slavery in the West indies.
They are also black.
So they also faced racism and yet they
do well.
So it has to be something else.
And that other thing is the fact that
these black people who were in the
south,
there's always been a big question.
We're black people robbed of their
culture or did they preserve their
authentic African culture?
And what soul is saying is that they
were robbed of their culture.
And so they picked up the culture of the
people around them and the people around
them were rednecks.
And if you look at the white redneck
culture and the black redneck culture,
they have a lot of the same values.
They don't particularly respect
education.
They love Jesus,
they use violence in their conflicts and
um,
they,
you know,
there's,
there's just,
you know,
a lot of the same values and a lot of
the same outcomes.
And even at bonaire,
which is black English is actually all
from the west of England.
So it's actually,
this is from the west of England.
So for example,
if you go to places like Cornwall,
um,
there used to be this amazing,
uh,
these amazing ads on British TV,
right for this,
uh,
this Devin custard or whatever.
And they would always say,
Devin News,
oh,
they make it so creamy and they all talk
like this.
Right?
And so it doesn't sound like black
English,
but they do say things like,
oh,
you be doing that and we be doing this
and you be doing that.
And they be doing that.
And so there's the use of that Copula be
right where instead of saying,
I am,
you are,
he is,
she is,
they are.
They just say I bub,
we be.
They be,
which is the classic feature of Black
English,
African American vernacular English
right?
Now the point is,
is that how I'm blower mindblower now
let's imagine that.
How do you think that Thomas Soul has
been received by Liberal America?
Not Well,
not well,
and so for example,
soul has a book called black rednecks,
white liberals.
Okay.
And his whole point is that,
you know,
if you actually,
and you know,
again like soul is,
you know,
he researches the shit out of this
stuff.
He really does this work.
Now,
if you,
if you look at the experience of African
Americans after slavery after slavery,
they do really,
they,
they start to make real progress,
right?
And a large part of the reason why they
make progress is because you start to
get a lot of people from New England
either you know,
black people from New England or white
people from New England who come down
and sort of reshape the culture.
They create these schools and they're
teaching those New England values,
right?
It's those puritan values of hard work,
tenacity,
all of that sort of stuff.
And so there's all this progress and you
have people like booker t Washington and
booker t dot Washington was an actual
slave and then after he got his freedom,
he got to go work in a salt mine,
which is literally the worst job ever.
And in booker t Washington's up from
slavery,
he tells this great story about seeing a
school house right and that he thought
that going into a school house was about
as close to heaven on earth as you could
get.
Like this is a dude who wanted an
education really,
really badly,
and that's a lot of what you find in the
early black experience in,
you know,
the post slavery period.
And in fact,
you know,
blacks,
before sort of world war two actually
had higher rates of marriage than
whites.
All of these sorts of things that you
know are now supposedly a problem.
And then there's this turnaround,
right?
The black experience starts to go south,
It starts to get worse.
And what year is this around?
This is post World War Two,
right?
So,
um,
so post slavery,
black people experience a rebounding,
they're starting to make some progress.
There is ambition and I mean,
you know,
if in terms of books to read like,
just because a large,
you know,
a large part of what I'm trying to do in
general is really let's move to the
place of all people are created equal.
Like let's remove all these stupid
distinctions,
right?
And really live that principle.
And the problem is,
is that in order to really live that
principle,
you need a new narrative that beat
slavery.
So,
you know,
it's not.
If you go and talk to racist,
you can't just say racism is bad.
Like that doesn't destroy racism,
right?
What destroys racism is when you make
sense of the things that they know,
right?
They see people who are violent in the
ghettos or they see crime or they see a
lack of education or they see that
Africa is poor and you're able to tell a
better story that makes sense of the
things that they know,
but also comes out with the conclusion,
oh,
we actually all have the same potential.
Right?
But if you have this issue with people
imitating their atmosphere in retaining
their environment and this southern
style talk with,
uh,
the southern redneck influence on the
African American slaves,
former slaves,
how do you,
how do you stop that and how do you turn
that around?
Well,
in general for humanity,
I mean,
this is sort of a big problem for
humanity in general is that there's not
a culture alive today that is well
suited to the world that we're living
in.
And that's because,
you know,
culture is adapted to environment in the
same way as any evolutionary thing.
Right?
So for example,
you know,
if you look at a like,
let's talk about these hunter gatherers,
right?
The Anam Amo or something like that.
So there's a great story in the lost
city ofZ ,
um,
where,
you know,
a Percy Fawcett who was an explorer
comes across,
you know,
all these tribes in the Amazon,
and one of the examples that the author
gives him there is a David Grann,
he talks about how,
um,
you know,
there's this group of tribesmen in the
Amazon and what they'll do is there's
this special leaf and they go and they
squeeze this leaf,
right?
They crush it up and this milky
substance runs into the water and then
all of a sudden the fish float up to the
surface upside down,
right?
They've been anesthetized by this.
Whatever substance in the leaf.
And this little boy goes into the river
and he plucks out all the fattest fish.
And then as the milky cloud dissipates,
the others fish swim away,
right?
Impressive as fuck.
Like,
how the fuck did these tribesmen who
don't have science,
don't have any of these things,
figure this thing out.
And it's cultural evolution.
That's what happens is,
is that,
that's the nature of evolution.
That's the nature of markets.
Because markets are an evolutionary
process,
you know,
intelligent answers and intelligent
solutions can emerge from just sort of
competing forces and so all of these
cultures are well adapted to a
particular environment.
So if,
you know,
if you,
like we talked about American culture
and we talked about Russian culture,
Russian culture selects for pessimism,
American culture because you had to move
all the way across the ocean,
right?
If you've got villages in Italy,
you know,
Vietnam,
whatever it is,
who is the person in that village who
says,
I'm going to go across the ocean to a
country I know nothing about and you
know,
make a fortune,
right?
It's the most optimistic individual.
And so it's basically a magnet for all
the most optimistic individuals in the
world.
The analogy,
I always use this,
you ever see American tale,
the like old animated movie from like
the must be the nineties or whatever.
Probably.
I don't think I saw that.
Well,
it's about a group of animated.
It's animated.
Yeah.
Um,
who,
who made it?
I don't know.
I'm trying to remember.
Um,
it's not Disney.
That's it.
No,
I don't think I saw that students,
Spielberg will.
Anyway,
it's,
it's sort of about the,
it's about the immigrant experience more
generally and then specifically sort of
about the Russian Jewish experience.
Um,
and it's about this family,
the mouse Kevitsa is and right there on
that,
on that trunk,
there's a 500 miles Kovitz and five old
mouse Kovitz,
um,
you know,
in the first part there in Russia and
the,
they're all being persecuted by cats,
right?
Because there might be 500 miles of it's
sings a song with all of the other
Moskovitz is called.
There are no cats in America,
which is so much of what the American
immigrant experiences about.
Right.
You're like,
oh,
it's all going to be perfect land of
opportunity.
The streets are paved with gold excepted
an American tale.
The streets are paved with cheese,
American t a L.
exactly.
Or Til t a.
yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
Um,
so,
so the,
these different environments,
right?
Just as you have different environments,
select for different,
uh,
different beaks or wings or whatever it
is,
select for different mindsets,
different ways of thinking,
different cultural traits.
Right?
And what ends up happening is we become
well adapted to a particular
environment.
So what happens to the point of the lost
city of z is what happened to all of
these European explorers who went into
the Amazon?
Well,
a lot of them fucking tide and that's
because they're doing things that are
well suited to England,
like walking around in wool suits and
eating cans of chipped beef,
but suddenly when you're in the hundred
degree heat of the Amazon and there's
all these animals you don't understand
and you don't know how to use the plants
that you squeeze and have the anesthetic
in them and all that sort of stuff,
you can't survive.
Right?
And what they called in velocity of CSI,
all the explorers,
they called it the Amazon UK counterfeit
paradise.
It looked like a paradise was so lush.
It was so tropical,
but there were like,
there's nothing to fucking eat except
clearly there was because Amazonian
people had been living there for tens of
thousands of years.
They just did.
The Westerners didn't have the cultural
software that was well suited to
surviving in that environment.
So how does this translate into
African-american's?
So what is the environment that created
that southern redneck culture and the
environment it turns out is right?
So raising sheep,
raising goats and all that stuff.
Because most of the people who are in
the south,
I'm originally came from the Scots.
Irish.
And when you look at hurting cultures
around the world,
they all have certain traits in common,
right?
So if you're a herder where you have a
big,
big problem,
and that big big problem is property
rights.
So if you're a farmer,
there are clear boundaries on my land.
Now there are ways you can try and fuck
me.
You can try and move the boundary stones
on my land slowly into your field,
over,
over.
But what we usually have is we have some
sort of government,
there's a local town official that we go
to and he is responsible for policing
the boundaries.
And so towns would do things where you
know,
you would essentially all get together
and we go walk the boundary stones and
we make sure that none of those boundary
stones had moved.
So the intuition of people from the
North Pier,
people like that is if we have a
problem,
we go to the government and we resolve
it through the government,
right in the environment of hurting,
you can come over and you can steal my
sheep and you can mix the sheep in with
your flock and I have no way to prove
which my sh which cheaper my sheep.
So we evolve things like branding,
right?
Where I have a brand,
I put it on my sheep and all that sort
of stuff.
But there's another strategy that is
used that evolved before branding.
And that earlier strategy is being a
crazy motherfucker.
You establish a reputation as the kind
of guy that you don't fuck with you.
Come on my land,
I kill you.
You touch my sheep or my women,
I fucking kill you.
And I use such an aggressive level of
violence that you know that you know,
there is no point in fucking with.
I mean,
this is not plausible because I'm saying
it,
but let's imagine it much tougher
person.
Conor Mcgregor,
for example,
is a great example.
You don't fuck with conor Mcgregor,
right?
He has a reputation as just being a bad
ass motherfucker who will fuck you up.
Right?
So that's how you keep people off your
land.
That's right.
And if you look at,
let's look at a couple of other
cultures.
So hurt cultures include the scots,
Irish,
who are the rednecks.
A herder cultures include the
Mongolians,
right?
The Mongols notoriously a very gentle
peace loving people,
right?
And they include the Bedouins and where
the Arabs,
right,
who had camels and all that sort of
stuff.
And you'll notice that there is that
same use of violence and mostly they
fight amongst themselves.
There's this inter clan warfare,
but periodically a charismatic figure
emerged is who unites the clans.
So gangas con manages to unite the
Mongols and then what are the Mongols
proceed to do?
They proceed to go use that aggressive
use of violence.
They have those horses which allow them
to move quickly,
right?
And they're really effective and they go
and they fuck everybody up,
right?
Because you know,
the gentle farmers of China aren't
prepared for that.
And the gentle farmers,
a Persian aren't prepared for that.
What happens with the Arabs,
the Arabs are mostly fighting amongst
themselves.
But then along comes this charismatic
figure with a new belief system that
unites the Muhammad and he unites them
and suddenly they fuck everybody up and
they create this great empire,
the caliphate,
right spreads all across Central Asia
and the Middle East and all across north
Africa.
Right?
And in many ways that is what Donald
Trump is.
They've been,
you know,
the rednecks been fighting amongst
themselves for a long time.
And then Donald Trump,
the gang is con of America.
The Mohamad of America has succeeded in
uniting the clans and you know,
in our time,
you don't do it by going out and like
raping and pillaging.
You go and you seize the ballot box and
you vote and you know,
you really like take back power.
And so that's what they've done.
Um,
but there are,
if you look,
there are certain problems that occur
across these herder cultures.
So if you're,
you know,
as a friend of mine.
So you're saying essentially saying that
the south,
is that the reason why Donald Trump has
been elected because of the south,
because of the herder
culture?
Well,
and it's also,
so if you've read Hillbilly Elegy,
jd Vance's book,
it's an excellent,
right?
But he's really talking about this
hillbilly culture and so it's not just
the south.
Right?
So what happened is,
is that it's Redneck,
it's rednecks,
which is a,
or you know,
whatever or hillbillies or whatever you
want to call them.
The folk.
Well,
it's not even simple folk,
it's just a particular culture and they
have certain values and I just,
it's also worth clarifying because of
the way that I sound and where I come
from and the fact that I went to
Harvard.
Yeah.
And vitamin than that.
I'm not a part of that tribe that,
you know,
Americans owe a tremendous debt to the
hillbilly culture and that tremendous
debt is that overwhelmingly they are the
people who have served in the military
and they are overwhelmingly the people
who have fought our wars and blood and
died and all that sort of stuff.
And that's stuff that,
you know,
I may sound like a liberal,
but I don't really sit in either of
those cultures.
Right.
I can critique the liberal culture and I
can critique the hillbilly culture.
Right.
And you know,
white liberals,
the whole reason why I started this
thing off is because white liberals have
their own weird things that are
dysfunctional in that aren't helping
black people and all that stuff.
If you just wore a bow tie,
people would think you were
conservative.
So you have to do well then there you
go.
Or maybe you have a bolo tie.
One hundred percent.
Actually I would like to do that.
Like I like the texting Carter rancher
rancher,
jade right there and pull that George W
Bush be from Connecticut,
but dress
like a cowboy.
He was from Maine.
Maine is,
I mean Kennebunk port.
That's where they're from.
That is the whitest of white fucking
north and people ever.
French folks.
Maine is filled with French folks.
Maniacs.
Yeah.
I'm also originally,
you know more your neck of the woods.
Yeah,
Boston.
I did a lot of gigs in Maine.
Maine's a fascinating place because it's
a entirely abandoned.
Yep.
There's a couple of cities and you have
to drive like vast distances in between
them.
When you go from Portland to Bangor,
there was just like 50 plus mile stretch
where there's nothing on the road.
It's a two lane highway and there ain't
shit on that road.
No gas,
no nothing.
If you don't have gas,
you're fucked.
Did you ever run out of gas?
Did you ever hear?
There's a friend of mine,
dad's from Maine
and he has all these great main isms and
one of them is a,
Oh,
you gotta go up past soy as band and
past Sawyer's barn is any place that is
far away.
Oh.
Which is I think fucking amazing.
Wow.
So that's sort of like the version of
uh,
the uh,
Islamic 72 virgins.
Yeah.
Right.
Like 72 virgins just means a shitload of
virgins.
Yeah.
It doesn't really mean the number seven
too.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
it's,
you're saying you have a passel of
virgin.
It's like there's a good chunk of
Right?
So we get back to this,
um,
African American culture.
So how does it,
how does it correct itself?
So what ends up happening?
Yeah,
what you have to do is,
is that you just have to have a much
larger conversation about culture and
you have to talk about how culture
works.
You have to say it's not your fault,
right?
Because the point is,
is that imitate our atmosphere.
We imitate our atmosphere.
And the reality is,
is that,
you know,
these cultures are very old,
that hurt her culture is the same one.
And that's the big ironies is that
you're not saying that it's about black
people,
it's about rednecks,
whether they're white rednecks or black
red necks.
So that hurt our culture has just
inexorably tied itself into the African
American culture without the African
Americans even knowing that it happened.
Exactly.
Which is the nature of culture.
And it's also,
it's only tied itself into this very
specific subset of Africa of black
culture,
which is why the people in the West
indies have a completely different.
Whoa.
Oh Wow.
And if you talk,
if you talk to people who are literally
Africans who immigrated to America,
like from Ethiopia or Kenya or anything
like that,
you know,
if you ever get an Ethiopian cab driver,
right?
So hard working.
Yeah.
Talk to them,
talk to them about how they feel about
that sort of ghetto black culture,
those black rednecks.
They fucking hate it.
Hey fucking hate it.
And the point is this,
because a,
it gives them a bad name,
right?
You know,
and people see a black person and
they're like,
oh,
you're like probably this,
this,
this.
Because again,
human stereotype because of the Dunbar
number,
because we can only track 150 people.
And so we have to make up stories about
them.
Yeah,
we fit into this rednecks.
That's right.
Oh you have a dukes of hazzard tee
shirt.
You are.
And we do that.
And you know,
that's the point.
The listeners are going to be sitting
here and they're going to be trying to
categorize me and all of this sort of
stuff.
And you know,
part of what you're dealing with is you
start talking about gender or anything
like that and the social justice
warriors try and put you into some
bucket and you're like,
no,
I don't belong in that bucket.
You're constantly trying to say I'm not
in that bucket.
So you could imagine if you're
Ethiopian,
right,
and you've moved here and you really
sort of believe in the American Dream
Land of opportunity and we work hard and
we all do this sort of stuff.
And You keep getting put in that bucket
with all this sort of rap culture or
anything like that,
you're going to be annoyed.
It does.
Like if you're a Sikh and people want to
beat your ass,
far as the Muslims bombed,
you know,
nine slash 11,
like it's not even near the same part of
the world.
Oh fuck heads.
Nope,
totally different headgear.
But to the person on the outside trying
to categorize.
That's right.
They're trying to make
sense of it.
But,
and that's the point is,
is that when you start to have a
conversation that is about culture,
then you start to realize that race
doesn't actually matter and what you'll
find is,
so let's take a look at,
for example,
Asians,
Asians do very well in school.
They're very productive and all that
sort of stuff except for the Hmong,
right?
So there's a group of people called the
Hmong and they're,
they're the big Asian exception.
And you know,
they do things.
I'm hunters,
big time hunters.
Um,
you know,
there's a lot of violence,
uh,
not a lot of education,
right?
They don't sort of fall into that sort
of stereotype of becoming engineers and
doctors and from what part of the world,
they're like Cambodia,
Vietnam,
like what used to be called Indochina.
They don't have their own country.
No,
no,
they're,
they're tribal grouping that sort of
exists across national boundaries
because in general,
you know,
one of the great,
uh,
destructive forces in human history is
the British map maker.
You know what I mean?
Like Europeans just love a straight
line.
They just can't get enough of the
straight line.
And so they were just like,
and you know,
like that the straight line works in
middle America because you've already
wiped out all the tribes.
Right?
Right.
But it doesn't work so well in Africa
where there are still tribes or
Southeast Asia where you suddenly start
like drawing a line,
right between two tribal groups or
across a tribal group and suddenly now
shit's all fucked up.
And they're,
what they're trying to do when they're
having all these civil wars as they're
trying to unfuck the boundaries.
A straight lines are annoying.
Yeah.
They all know it's really hilarious when
you get busted for transporting
something across state lines like my
allowed to drive around with this or not
like what?
What's the fucking law like if you have
pot in particular.
I mean you cross a state line,
you go from being someone who is
innocent 100 percent to someone who's
guilty.
One hundred percent of a felony.
Yup.
Yeah.
Well they're there.
It's so bizarre.
I mean in one one side states' rights or
a,
an amazing idea for testing ideas out.
Sure.
You know,
like testing out with like with Colorado
illegal legal marijuana again.
That's right.
Worked out,
worked out great and people wouldn't
look,
this is working.
It's profitable.
It helps everybody.
Let's go.
Yeah.
And then it's,
it's sold the idea to other pe.
That's right.
And then there's other places like open
carry and you're like a hey,
are you sure?
You sure?
Every concealed carry.
Okay.
You could just have a gun on you.
Everywhere you go,
you have the movie theater.
Okay.
But where are the places where that's
true south?
Yeah.
And that's because it's,
again,
it comes down to the what this is being
driven by.
It's being driven by old cultural
baggage.
That doesn't necessarily make sense.
So the guy who.
So there's really,
in terms of honor cultures,
there are four books,
right?
That I think that if you want to go into
this,
like don't get angry at me,
just read the four books.
Those books,
those books are a black red necks,
white liberals,
Thomas Souls Book,
a culture of honor,
which is Richard Nisbett book.
I'm jd Vance's,
hillbilly elegy.
And then a book called the short and
tragic life of Robert Peace.
Um,
and those four books essentially,
if you read those four books and you're
still saying that,
what I'm saying is unsubstantiated,
you know,
well then we should talk about it.
Or are there a lot of liberals that are
up in arms and you propose these things
start bringing up the hurt or culture?
No.
What about the Patriarchy and white
racism?
Exactly.
Know race.
You can't be racist towards white
people.
That's one of my favorite things that
people are saying today that you can't
be racist and white people.
Yeah.
There's a lot of favorite things to say.
People are saying a lot of weird and
wacky shit,
but that's one of the wackiest like of
course you can like that's racism only
works when someone has power.
Well,
when you racist to someone,
you have power over a period.
Cultural power.
Like what?
Presumed across the board by black and
white.
Like real,
real simple.
Yes or no.
Binary one or a zero.
Is that what we're doing?
Is that people?
Of course not.
No,
of course not.
Of course not.
Of course you can be racist,
you could judge someone prejudice Lee.
Well,
and in fact that is the key thing with
Richard Nisbett book,
the culture of honor.
So nesbitt was a professor in the
nineties at the height of political
correctness and he wanted to study
culture and the problem was that he's a
white man from the south and he knew
that if you studied any culture you
would have to say bad things about it.
So what does Richard Nesbitt do?
He says,
ally,
no one culture that I can say bad things
about on a college campus.
I can say bad things about southern
culture.
That's a culture I can criticize freely.
And so what he did,
and you know,
this I think gets really down to what
are the strengths of know sort of
broadly northern and southern culture.
Right?
And you know,
Kennedy,
John F Kennedy had this great line about
Washington DC.
He said that it was a city of southern
efficiency and northern charm.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
And um,
you know,
the,
the potential for America is to be a
country of southern charm and northern
efficiency,
but we're kind of got it backwards right
now,
right?
Um,
but so what,
what Nesbitt is doing is,
is that he's charming the liberals,
right?
Which is what southerners do.
He's like,
I'm going to study culture,
but I'm going to study white southern
culture and I'm going to show how bad it
is.
Right?
And so they're like,
oh,
okay.
That feels safe and comfortable.
Right.
And that's essentially how he worked his
way into the conversation.
And specifically what he knew is he knew
that southern culture had this very
particular problem and this very
particular problem was that it had
higher rates of homicide in very
specific categories.
So it had a higher rates of,
um,
you know,
uh,
basically killings around trespassing
and then killings around,
you know,
lovers,
triangles.
And so for example,
until 1970,
if you found your wife in bed with
another man in Texas,
you could shoot him.
And it was justifiable homicide until
1970 isn't really only 70.
I thought it was really recent.
Well,
I may,
I mean that was,
that's,
that's my recollection,
but
I think that might still be a law.
There's a,
isn't there like a crime of passion law
in Texas?
I feel like there is for some reason,
well they may have just moved,
moved the name or something.
I don't know,
maybe I'm wrong,
but I know that people have been
exonerated because of what,
you know,
crimes of passion because of like you're
allowed to get pissed off and shoot
people.
Here it goes.
Crime of passion,
legal definition.
There is sometimes called the law of
Texas since injuries in that state or
supposedly lenient to cuckolded lovers.
I love that expression.
Who reached their own vengeance or
rector on vengeance.
The benefit of eliminating premeditation
is to lessen the provable homicide to
manslaughter with no death penalty and
limited prison terms.
So that's crimes of passion.
So it's not legal,
but it's a much lesser crime.
Well,
I think until [inaudible] 70,
it was actually just straight up
justifiable homicide,
so it was like straight up illegal crime
of passion and now it's like a homicide
or manslaughter or go to jail for six
months.
Yeah.
But when you get out,
knows the fuck is up basically stay off
my property.
Exactly.
Goddammit.
It's that same psychology that plays
out.
Um,
and so Nesbitt and you know,
by,
by contrast in the north,
there are a lot of what are called.
There are more seven slash 11 murders,
which are basically murders or
instrumental murders,
which is where people kill people trying
to get cash,
right?
They're trying to get rich,
Um,
so there are these different.
It's,
you know,
there's homicide in both places,
but there are different types of
homicides that predominate.
And Nesbitt essentially,
you know,
the,
the big thing was to figure out why is
that true,
right?
And the answer is that it's this culture
of honor that comes out of hurting.
And so the irony is,
is that southerners who very often are
the ones who feel most strongly about
how problematic Muslims are,
have the same culture.
And honor killings,
and they do all these sorts of things,
but they don't do it to the same extent.
No,
because in general,
America is much less violent place,
right?
So much more violent than they would be
forced to adapt to the new culture.
That's right.
Which is mad max style.
And what would happen to all the
liberals and when your resources are
extremely limited,
like you live in a fucking desert,
you're forced to become even more
vicious.
That's right.
You are protecting your boundaries and
your property and your resources.
Yep.
Again,
how do we straighten out the African
American
and that's the point.
It's about profit
with crime and violence and terrible
atmosphere that they have to imitate.
Well,
that's the point is,
is that the thing that allows people to
move past their cultural baggage is
understanding their cultural baggage.
So it's that answer of why it's
storytelling.
I did this in this environment because
it made sense.
We are no longer in that environment.
Now it is problematic to me.
Therefore it screws me up.
So now I should behave in this.
And then you can start to retrain.
What your impulses are,
so somebody bumps you,
you know,
somebody comes on your land and your
first impulse is not to go grab your
shotgun and kill them.
Right?
And you don't worry so much of what it
comes down to because it's crucially
like their honor killings.
Right?
So those cultures are obsessed with
honor and purge for particular.
What you hear with African Americans is
don't dismiss,
don't disrespect me,
right?
So there's a real policing of one's
honor and really making sure that nobody
is fucking with me.
And it's the same thing with,
you know,
white rednecks,
white southerners,
right?
That's right.
Texas pride don't mess with Texas.
Um,
nobody says Delaware pride.
Well that's because if you've been to
Delaware there,
Maine,
Maine Pride,
all the dude love Maine.
Those fucking poor do trapped up there.
Frozen wasteland
with blueberries and lobster and Steven
King and Steven King.
Yeah.
God bless him.
He's up there for the summer,
summer and winters in Florida.
Snowbird.
Yeah.
Um,
it's uh,
in many ways,
bad to not talk about this.
Right?
So that is people that have the issue
with even discussing the origins of
certain types of behavior and comparing
different types of black people and
different types of African Americans
trying to figure out or African former
slaves like why did the people in the
West indies behave differently than the
people in America and you know,
it opens up this weird can of worms
where people are not willing to discuss
it openly and that's taboo
and that is why so called his book black
redneck white liberals.
Because the problem is that because
white liberals are not willing to
discuss these things,
what ends up happening is that you get
African pride,
right?
It's and you know,
as Solo points out,
right?
When was pride ever a good thing?
Right?
Pride is the feeling of that.
You know it all,
that you have nothing to learn.
Right.
It's that feeling of arrogance
or just have to be from mother fucker.
Exactly.
You wouldn't know about all that live in
your daydreams.
England when you're a little shit.
He lived here.
18 in England,
right?
Yeah.
It's a problem and it is a problem.
There's just can't be trusted.
That's a lot of culture.
They got you.
What the.
What would the.
We know the Siberian candidate.
What's Siberian tangible people are
saying,
Donald Trump is the Siberian candidate
because.
Yeah.
What do you think about this whole
situation with Russia today?
Because it seems like that poor country
doesn't know how to fucking get rid of
that one guy who's their main dude.
As much as Garry Kasparov talks about
and look at that hair.
That is wonderful.
What the hell is going on there?
Intel chiefs present trump with claims
of Russian efforts to compromise.
Yeah.
Whoa.
Around this afternoon,
like breaking news sort of thing.
I don't know how.
Breaking a Russian efforts to compromise
him while they're playing to his ego.
Oh
Wow.
Look at his eyebrows.
Did you read the thing by?
Hold on a second.
Scroll
back up to that picture.
Tell me that.
It's not a Dr Seuss character.
That's the Mayor of Louisville.
That is the fucking mayor of Louisville.
I mean,
the whole thing is just what's happening
here.
What is all that?
Wow.
So they're presenting him.
I wonder what he's going to do about all
that,
including allegations that Russian
operatives claimed to have compromising
personal and financial information about
Mr.
Trump,
multiple US officials with direct
knowledge of the briefly tell CNN hm.
The allegations were presented in a two
page synopsis that was at bended to
report on Russian intelligence,
the 2016 election.
The allegations came in part from memos
compiled by former British intelligence
operative who was past work,
US intelligence,
Fisher officials or officials consider
credible the FBI's investigating the
credibility and accuracy of these
allegations which are based primarily on
information from Russian sources but has
not confirmed.
This is a weird time and it is a very
weird time.
So fucking so crazy to think that we're
in a cold war again.
Like how did we.
We duct that forever.
Like to the whole Clinton administration
that was a nonissue through the entire
Bush administration.
Non Issue through the entire Obama
administration non fuck an issue until
2012 ish.
And then he started hearing about it
again.
Well,
a large part of what's happened is,
is that our environment has changed,
but our culture has not.
So if you look at in the 19 fifties,
right,
if you're talking about the marketplace
of ideas,
you had these guys like Ed Rowe,
Edward Armaro and Walter Cronkite,
and they had a thing called journalistic
integrity,
right?
And Brian Williams and Williams.
Yeah.
That guy,
he's,
he's just as good as any of them.
That guy can tell a good story.
Yeah,
exactly.
Um,
but journalistic integrity is now don
lemon.
Don Lemon.
Step back,
step back and respect him.
A set of check.
People.
I don't know if you know.
No
Czech people had it.
One of my favorite things.
Do you ever said on tv?
Someone was talking about something?
It was something about.
I don't remember what it was.
What was it?
When don lemon was saying he had to
check.
People had to check some people in my
life.
It was like people talk to talking
sexist or something like that.
And he was just telling people he had to
check people in his life.
Shut the fuck up.
Don Lemon.
You check checking anybody,
anybody you'd check tells you to shut
your mouth.
What's the funny part is I guess
something in this report that just came
out,
which is also going around now.
I'll let you go ahead and read this
report.
Trump allegedly hired prostitutes for a
golden shower party on Ritz Moscow bed
were Obama.
Michelle slept.
This is right out of the report.
This highlighted.
Okay.
Here's.
There were aspects of trump's engagement
with Russian authorities,
one which had borne fruit to them,
was exploited.
Trump's personal obsessions with sexual
perversion in order to obtain the
sustainable kompromat compromising
material
on him according to source diy where,
uh,
where s he had been president trump's
perverted in Britain,
brackets conduct in Moscow included
hiring the presidential suite of the
Ritz Carlton Hotel where he knew
president and Mrs Obama,
whom he hated in parenthesis,
had stayed on one of their official
trips to Russia and defiling the bed
where they had slept by employing a
number of prostitutes,
performed golden showers,
urination,
show in front of him.
Hm.
The hotel was known to be under FSB
control with microphones and concealed
cameras and all the main rooms to record
anything they wanted to.
Holy Shit.
They just go to the Ritz Carlton and
they set up microphones and cameras.
Oh yeah.
That's the Russian way.
All the Ritz Carlton.
Oh yeah.
That's crazy.
But that's the nature.
I mean,
you know,
you jerk off for the Ritz Carlton,
what do you put a blanket over?
Where do you.
A fucking camera.
You'd have to put a.
you'd have to put a blanket over
everything because there are going to be
a lot of cameras in that room.
My friend Mike,
but Mike Swick who is a former UFC
fighter,
worked in Russia with the American
secret service a long time ago and he
said that they found these listening
devices,
it hidden inside buildings that were
powered by the movement of the building
during the wind,
like what they have their own.
Their power source is literally the
building moving in.
The wind was.
He said it was so far beyond anything
that they had ever figured out that the
Americans had figured out at the time
and they were just all about
surveillance.
Well that was the things that the Soviet
Union did well.
Right.
Like they,
they.
There were a few things in the Soviet
Union really put their attention on like
space and surveillance and you know,
espionage and all of that sort of stuff
in the military and they did those very
well.
Sounds like horseshit to me.
That sounds like something somebody
would say if you're trying to emote is
from buzzfeed,
but it sounds like something someone
would say,
but the quote is not though.
Right.
Where's the quote from the quote?
The quote is from the story was from
buzzfeed from,
but that's just the actual report is
where that was from that report that
they were talking about in the previous
article we brought up.
Oh,
so it's from the,
from the Intel.
Oh,
shut the CIA.
Australia.
The thing here,
this is the report here.
It's like a,
the company intelligence report.
Yeah.
It's a long report.
Presidential.
Hold on,
sorry.
Go back up there,
certain US presidential election,
Republican Kennedy,
Donald Trump's activity in Russia,
and compromising relationship with the
Kremlin.
Wow.
A long pages and this right here.
So now,
now we have to talk about golden showers
apparent,
but here's the thing.
We know.
Yeah,
okay.
We know we've always known that
intelligence agencies will distribute
propaganda.
We know that that's 100 percent factual,
but that's the problem and that's the
problem in general is this,
that like you know that the CIA engages
that sort of behavior and of course you
know that the FSB,
the Russian security services engages in
that behavior.
Of course,
who do you trust?
Do you trust?
And that's the basic problem of 2017,
2016,
100 percent who the trust.
You got to know that if the,
if someone from any agency is telling
you something and why,
what,
what would it serve them to tell you 100
percent the truth without any
manipulation whatsoever in order to gain
favor in order to gain influence in
order to gain.
And what what,
what would the CIA have?
Any motivation to be 100 percent
accurate about it?
Why?
Well,
I mean,
you know,
I mean the CIA,
obviously Donald Trump is not clearly a
friend to the CIA.
Right.
He's already made it clear that he has
issues with the intelligence community.
So it sounds so crazy because he's not
even in there yet.
Nope.
And he hasn't been briefed by them and
he's been rejecting that and I mean
that's the point we live in.
You know,
the old Chinese curse,
we live in interesting times.
I'll tell you one thing though,
when if he,
if it comes out that there was a bunch
of girls that he hired the piss all over
the bed,
people are going to cheer him on the
streets where people will.
There's people that loved them in the
first place and that's going to be a ton
of them.
They're going to care as the guy had a
good time.
Yep.
And that's,
that's because again,
it's clan,
it's,
you know,
it is that culture of authority and
grouping around and being loyal and all
that sort of stuff.
Of course.
And those,
those are the big sort of conservative,
you know,
a hillbilly redneck intuitions,
right?
As opposed to liberals are like,
let's care for everybody.
Like that's amazing,
let's not hurt anyone's feelings and
let's have trophies for participation
and all that sort of stuff.
And so for a long time,
you know,
the liberals have had a lot of power
over the media and politics and all that
sort of stuff.
And so that's the rabbit hole that the
country went down and now you know,
the Conservatives have sort of,
you know,
gotten pissed off and you know,
have,
you know,
it's sort of like,
I mean,
in the ideal situation,
the Republicans,
the Democrats work like Mommy and Daddy,
right?
And you know,
it's not that mommy and daddy have it
all figured out,
but if mommy and daddy have a productive
working relationship than the,
than the sort of like take personal
responsibility,
you know,
man up,
like do all these sorts of things is
counteracted by a certain understanding,
compassion and all that sort of stuff.
And then the parenting that emerges is
better than what they would either of
them would do on their own or they can
both get dysfunctional as fuck and mommy
becomes an enabling,
you know,
snowflake machine,
right?
Daddy just becomes an abusive asshole
who won't pay child support and just
berates his children and is like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
Grow the fuck up on,
come on pussy.
And so that's really where America is.
His Mommy and daddy are fighting.
And fundamentally like Mommy and daddy
are having the most dysfunctional
relationship.
Possible rushes are crazy neighbor who
was like,
what a great opportunity to come in and
fuck mommy.
Right?
Wow.
Russia trying to fart mom.
I can't believe this nonsense.
But it's also,
it's good for Putin because what does
the Godfather want the godfather the.
So I think it's important to understand
like the disaster of American foreign
policy.
What is that about?
Right?
And it's because modern Americans have
grown up in,
you know,
essentially the most successful,
most productive,
most stable country in history.
Right?
Um,
and so,
you know,
if you're,
as many generations into democracy as
you are,
there's not a real understanding of how
you get to democracy,
right?
We just sort of inherited democracy and
we're like,
man,
I don't know how he make one and then
you get these ridiculous fables that
Americans have about themselves where
they think that I'm essentially,
you know,
King George,
the third was this awful vicious
dictator and then we kicked the dictator
out and then democracy.
And so that's all you have to do is you
have to go in and you have to remove
dictators.
And if we just keep removing dictators
than democracy will emerge.
Well,
what happens when you remove Saddam
Hussein vacuum?
Yeah.
Fills up with,
I said,
isn't that delicious?
Right?
Or you know,
you remove Kadafi,
right?
What happens vacuum.
Yeah.
And then what happens?
I says,
al Qaeda,
all these sorts of things.
So that,
the big question that you know,
that has always been in political
science and that Francis Fukuyama for
frames,
this is that.
It's always been what it,
why is it that the American revolution
succeeded?
And the French revolution descended into
bloody violence.
And the answer is,
is that they were actually at two
different stages of development.
Incorrect answer is America.
America and French are bunch of pussies.
Exactly.
That is correct.
That's freedom.
Fries and fries.
Kick back and relax.
Um,
yeah.
So that's actually the answer.
And I'm sorry I take back everything
that I said earlier.
It is the blaming of,
you know,
not necessarily blaming,
but understanding the root of the
behavior as being cultural and that we
have these ideologies that we become
imprisoned to patterns of behavior,
that we become prison too,
and that we're all subject to it.
Anyone with an accent understands that
this is where it comes from,
that we imitate behavior,
that it's around us.
And if we're in around an area like we
were talking about the Middle East with
poor resources and scarcity and a lot of
violence,
this is the type of behavior that we're
going to.
We're going to control our women,
dress them up,
cover them up like beekeepers.
We got to keep them,
keep them away from the other swinging
dicks that's fucking assholes that are
going to come over the hill with the
sores and the horses.
That's right.
Because that's what's been going on
forever.
Exactly.
I mean,
if you look at Iraq,
one of the craziest stories about Iraq
was a rackspace with Baghdad being
invaded by the Mongols and then killing
everybody and running the streets raw
red with blood and black with ink in the
rivers would fucking be filled with the
philosophy and all the from all these
Islamic theorists and all these
different,
um,
different scholars who were far ahead of
that aspect of the world,
the rest of the part of the world at the
time.
That's right.
I mean,
so much mathematics,
so much philosophy.
So,
so much knowledge came from that part of
the world.
It was totally lost when they were
invaded.
And so much of it is that,
you know,
the,
the old,
there's an old quote that floats around,
which is that if Nobel prizes had been
given out in the year 1000,
they all would have gone to Arabs.
Amazing it,
they were at the forefront and the point
is,
is that tells you something which is
that success is not a permanent
condition.
Bright cultures can gain it and cultures
can lose it and you better figure out
what is it that makes a culture
successful so you can preserve those
values,
fight for those values,
instilled them,
spread them,
all that sort of stuff.
And that's why poop is jockeying for
power because he believes that there's a
turnover going on right now and they
just hired a fucking reality star to run
the biggest nuclear arsenal in the world
has ever known.
Holy Shit.
This might be the time.
Yep.
And they're there.
And that the instability that has been
created is,
is that,
you know,
if you know,
you gave everyone a microphone,
that's what the Internet is,
right?
We're literally sitting here,
And you know,
you can start a show and if people
resonate with the show,
great.
And the point is,
is that there are some people like you
who can hold two contradictory ideas in
their head,
right?
And you like wrestle with that and
you're like,
man,
how do I make sense of both of these
things that,
you know,
capitalism is fundamentally generates
wealth and prosperity and all that sort
of stuff.
But corporations can do fucked up
things,
right?
How do I reconcile those two different
things?
And then there's a whole bunch of people
out there on the Internet who are
fundamentalists or who offer some sort
of very,
very simple narrative that is very easy
for people to get and people can go and
go down the rabbit hole of their
prejudices.
They can go down the rabbit hole of,
you know,
caring and compassion in the end up at
Marxism,
right?
Where people can go down the libertarian
rabbit hole of freedom.
And so they come up with this idea
called a narco capitalism and a narco.
Capitalism is the idea that we're just
going to remove all government and then
the free market will solve all problems.
So there's literally going to be minimal
or no government.
They're the most annoying people there
to me,
of the most annoying people like you.
You don't know that that's going to fall
to shit.
You don't know that people aren't going
to fix the streets.
Where's the money for education coming
from?
Who's going to hire cops?
Anybody.
No laws at all.
Shut the fuck up.
Well,
but what I love particularly and so
stupid.
Well,
I,
I got into a big fight over the
Christmas holidays with a group of a
narco capitalists and it was literally
because one of them,
there's this,
there were two things we interviewed.
There's this guy,
Peter Schiff,
and Peter Schiff is a liberal.
Yeah.
So anyway,
so I interviewed Peter Schiff and we,
you know,
part of the experience of doing this
podcast with Brian Kaylin is,
you know,
we interviewed all these academics,
right?
Two hundred and six of them.
Right?
And then at episode two,
Oh six,
there were two things that we sort of
noticed a,
there were all these amazing ideas be
you would find that any academic knew
about his amazing idea and nobody
else's.
Like we didn't know about anything else
that was going on in science or anything
like that.
Or like Meryl Streep doesn't understand
MMA exactly.
Um,
so it's the Meryl Streep Effect,
right?
That's an academics are like,
and it again,
it actually comes out of sort of what
the Western cultural biases which is
towards this thing called atomism write.
Like scientists are super focused on a
tiny,
tiny question.
They don't look for the bigger picture.
And we reached this frustration where
essentially we were like,
these ideas,
you can't,
you know,
there's an old George Bernard Shaw joke
about economists.
He said all the economists laid end to
end would never reach a conclusion.
It's the same thing with academics.
All the academics laid end to end would
never reach a conclusion.
There's all this science that piles up
all this sort of stuff.
What does it mean?
Like what should we do?
How should we live our lives?
How do we solve the problems of people
in the ghettos?
How do we solve the problems of the
people in the Middle East?
How do we solve,
make liberals have some sort of
perspective?
How do we do these things?
And that's science should turn into
practical things.
And in some areas it does,
right?
So you know,
there's a good sort of,
you know,
there's physics has this adjacent
profession engineering,
right,
and engineers go and they look at the
laws of physics and they figured out how
to engineer quantum computers and all
this other stuff,
right?
But when you talk about the human
sciences,
the adjacent profession that's supposed
to be there as storytelling.
So there's what's called the science to
narrative chain where you're supposed to
take science all of this research and
supposed to tell it,
turn it into simple stories that people
can understand and get,
and there is in fact,
just to give you a sense of this
problem,
like everybody knows that scientists
aren't the best communicators,
right?
Like the ones that are people like Neil
degrasse Tyson,
right?
You get on this show because you're
like,
man,
a fucking scientists who can communicate
like a human,
right or Carl Sagan or.
But,
you know,
these people are fucking Unicorns,
right?
They're very,
very rare in the scientific community.
So,
um,
I had,
my very specific experience was I,
I,
when I graduated from college,
I started tutoring just to pay my bills.
But I was really trying to figure out,
I had this weird experience where I
would be working with kids and I would
hear them say things like,
oh,
I didn't get the math gene.
And I was like,
what the fuck is that matching?
Because I was a biochemistry major,
so I'm like,
we met like you're 13 and failing
biology and you're telling me that you
have a math gene.
And I just majored in biochemistry and
we don't know about any math gene over
there.
So what the fuck are you talking about?
Someone's telling them that some.
Somehow they're picking that up,
getting this idea.
That's right.
Limited potential.
That's right now.
So that was a detective hunt that I went
on.
I was there is because there's a lot of
these things.
I don't have a natural ear for
languages.
Right.
That's another big one we heard and you
know,
oh I'm not a natural writer and all
these sorts of things.
And I was like,
what are all these fucking beliefs?
Right.
And I could tell that they were,
they were problematic and that they were
self defeating and specifically,
you know,
having moved between all of these
cultures,
I'd seen that different cultures have
very different ideas about intelligence.
So especially if you like my mother and
my father's side by side on the issue of
learning languages.
My Dad is Dutch.
Okay.
Now when you're Dutch,
you grew up with one great certainty in
life,
which is that no one will ever fucking
learn Dutch.
Like literally no one is ever going to
fucking learn Dutch.
So if you want to get a job and you want
to be competitive,
you better learn literally everybody
else's fucking language.
So you know,
it's routine and Holland to speak three,
four languages.
And you know,
my dad spoke 10,
right?
He studied 10 different languages his in
his life.
That's crazy.
Well,
and it's,
it's actually there anybody who comes
from a lot of these minority languages,
sort of smaller,
shittier languages,
you find they do this.
So polls routinely learn a lot of
languages.
People from Southeast Asia routinely
learn a lot of languages.
And again,
it's that environment,
like you lost the language lottery and
so you better make up for it,
like you're just going to have to do
that.
And at a certain point when you've
learned three or four languages,
it's now like,
Oh,
you've sussed this thing out.
You're like,
oh,
I get how this works.
Like this is just about work and there
are certain techniques and certain
approaches you start to get really,
really good at it.
So,
you know,
I really sort of from my dad picked up
this love of learning languages and my
dad is,
you know,
sort of,
especially into languages,
like every time they,
he didn't really like school and every
time they would tell him he had to take
another subject,
he would look up another language take.
So for example,
he ended up taking Swedish because in
the sixties and seventies,
all the pornos were made in Sweden and
he wanted to know what they were saying
between sexual thrust.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
So he learned Swedish.
He learns all these fucking weird
languages,
right?
Because they were like,
okay,
you need me to take another class.
I'm going to do something that I enjoy,
right,
like pretty normal sense.
But then on the other hand,
my mom's from Kansas and in Kansas they
don't speak foreign languages.
Like that's not the thing that's done.
And so there would be this experience of
like,
you know,
I took Japanese in high school and I
would be like,
Oh yeah,
I'm taking Japanese.
And they'd go like,
what the fuck?
Like who are you?
And you've taken Latin and ancient Greek
and they're like,
that's fucking weird.
And you know,
so you're moving between these two
different environments and you're like,
I feel like the issue here is that you
just think about languages in different
ways.
Like I don't know that it's,
that you have different potentially you
just have different attitudes to it.
Right.
So hearing all these kids say all these
bizarre things and you know,
at the time I was doing a tutoring
company with a friend of mine from
college who is from New England and you
know,
the New England is that pure and
culture,
right?
It's,
you know,
all self-denial,
no fun work hard,
all of that sort of stuff.
So she also heard all of these weird and
wacky beliefs and she was like,
you know,
reacted in the puritan way possible,
which is like,
you're just being fucking lazy.
Like fucking like do your fucking work.
No excuses,
right?
It's not Boston attitude,
so prevalent attitude.
And so,
you know,
you've got this Bostonian and then
you've got this half Dutch,
half American,
you know,
lived with the limeys,
all this sort of stuff.
Right?
And we're like,
we're the outsiders.
It's that experience that you talked
about,
uh,
foreigners who come to America or
anybody.
And we're like,
this culture of La is fucking weird.
Now,
what brought you here?
Uh,
well,
I always wanted to move to the west
coast.
So,
you know,
I watched triggered last night and I
agree with you that California is the
best place on earth,
but particularly because,
I mean,
you know,
I mean it is the what part of what I
found like a lot of what I was reacting
against,
right?
You leave places [inaudible] there's
something you don't like and then you go
to the most opposite place you can find.
And so I didn't like the culture of
England,
I didn't like aristocracy,
I didn't like that whole class system,
I fucking hated it.
And then when I went to Boston and New
York I felt like there was still a lot
of that sort of hierarchy and I think
that La is the place where it's like
nobody gives a fuck where you come from.
Like there isn't that hierarchy,
you know,
all of that sort of stuff.
Doesn't matter.
It's the wild west.
And I love that.
It definitely isn't a lot of ways.
I mean to me,
I think it's the last place that people
we know they landed on the east coast,
they made their way to the west coast.
I said,
well I don't want to live in Hawaii.
So this is what it was.
Exactly.
That's litter.
And the people that did move to Hawaii,
that's why.
I mean I fucking love Hawaii.
And one of the things I love about it is
the ex pats,
the people that go,
you know what man?
Fuck it.
I'm just out here now.
Yep.
And that's,
that's the culture that I always wanted
to be a part of was the culture that
it's like,
who the fuck cares,
like we're done with that shit,
but Hawaii is too much.
Right.
Well,
uh,
you know,
I mean I probably should have gone to
Hawaii.
It's hard.
Well it seems like now it's more viable
than ever before because the Internet,
you know,
it's just pretty much access evenly to
everything other than what's immediately
in your area.
But also engine.
I think also it's important to talk
about like how do humans actually work?
Right.
And it's often that,
you know,
I mean,
so a large part of what comes out of the
sciences that thinking and feeling are
always linked.
Right.
And so we're often driven by feelings
that we can't quite explain.
So,
you know,
the,
the why was I also motivated by La,
I think there was some attraction to the
entertainment industry,
comedy,
storytelling.
I don't really,
you know,
like if you're being really honest,
like why the fuck do you make any
decision that you make when you're 22,
23?
Right,
right.
Like you're just,
there's,
and there's some sort of cultural
baggage that's driving you there.
They watch Baywatch like.
Exactly,
but you have some sort of fantasy
version.
It is the Bible Moskovitz a shower where
you think there are no cats in Los
Angeles and the streets are paved with
cheese and then you get out here and
you're like,
they're fucking scientologists
everywhere.
Yeah.
Well Dude,
that's one of the things that I wanted
to talk to you about before we get get
to talk to you about your,
your calling Richard Dawkins,
the scientologists.
Yeah.
So the,
the larger.
So you've now gotten a taste of some of
the things that are going on across
science,
right?
There's lots of really exciting stuff
that can actually change and improve and
help people's lives.
But one of the things I think that you
pointed out that's incredibly critical
is that to or in order to be at the top
of your field,
you must be completely absorbed in that
particular subject and oftentimes a lot
like all the other systems that we find
that have limited resources and you
really don't have the time or the energy
or even the inclination to study all
these other comparable systems or
different disciplines or it's like,
I mean there's many,
many,
many examples of that,
but singular focus is,
which usually leads to greatness.
And when you're reading about some
professors,
peer reviewed work that's incredibly
groundbreaking,
oftentimes you're dealing with a form of
greatness.
And that requires massive tunnel vision.
Well,
that's the interesting thing.
So we should talk about what tunnel
vision is,
right?
So there's,
you know,
just as we have optimism and pessimism,
there are these other two mindsets,
atomism in holism,
right?
And atomism is the seeing the tree,
You like ignore the fucking forest and
you're just like,
I'm going to look at that one fucking
tree and become the world's expert in
that.
And then there's whole ism,
which is seeing the big picture,
seeing the forest,
seeing all that sort of stuff.
Now again,
everybody has these mindsets but
different cultures favor than
differently,
again,
because of the environmental pressures
of that environment.
So the Greeks massively favored atomism
and if you look at the behavior of the
Greeks,
the ancient Greeks,
they were constantly picking everything
apart,
right?
Because they were pirates pirates and
traders and fishermen.
And in that environment,
it's not about cooperation or anything
like that.
It's about everybody just trying to get
ahead for themselves and all that sort
of stuff.
Very individualistic.
All of that stuff.
And so when they would have leisure
time,
what were the things they did?
Well,
they would go and they would go into the
marketplace and they would argue with
each other and pick apart each other's
arguments and they would just pick,
pick,
pick.
And that's what logic is and rhetoric
and all that sort of stuff.
Um,
and then they would also,
you know,
when they had other leisure time,
they would go and see who could throw
shit furthest,
right?
Like who run fastest,
it's all about standing out.
It's all about trying to excel and be
the best.
And what happened is,
is that,
you know,
the is during the renaissance,
that they
say that again,
renascence and they sold in America
says,
um,
what?
So what,
what,
what is the,
what is the American way I want to fit
in genaissance renaissance renaissance
renaissance Paris,
or like the renaissance faire,
Patty Paris,
Paris,
France,
say France,
not France from France.
Well,
I just have to really channel my inner
Kansas.
Well,
whenever you want to fucking call the
rebirth,
right?
They basically were obsessed with the
Greeks and the Romans were obsessed with
the Greeks and then when the rebirth or
assaults happened,
they were obsessed with the Romans and
the Greeks.
And so they became obsessed with this
culture and that's how you start to get
this culture of individualism that
develops.
The founding fathers were obsessed with
that.
And so that becomes a lot of the spirit
of the West,
right?
Is this real atomistic culture.
Meanwhile,
over in Asia,
right?
They have different incentives,
which is rice farming.
And so what happens is,
is that rice farming is,
you know,
you have to be super cooperative because
the water runs down the mountain,
it runs through my patty field,
but then it runs through your neighbor's
patty field and all that sort of stuff.
So I have to have relations with my
neighbor and that neighbor and then I
have to think about how it affects the
next guy and the next guy and the next
guy and the next guy.
So they favor whole ism.
How does everything fit together?
And so if you look at what is Eastern
culture about,
what are those ancient Asian culture is
about,
it's all about Yin and Yang things
fitting together and complimenting it
all.
Being part of a larger system.
And Confucianism was all about the
family and relationships and everybody
has their proper role and you all sort
of have to belong and all of that sort
of stuff.
Right?
So which set of biases do you think that
science has baked into it's culture?
Adam is.
And so what,
when you get the structure of scientific
culture as it stands today,
it's super atomistic right now.
If you look at things like economics and
psychology and you know,
biology and all of these sorts of
things,
they're all studying the natural world
and in fact there's a whole bunch of
disciplines that are all studying humans
and how they behave and all that sort of
stuff and yet they're all broken up into
separate disciplines and now they're
sort of doubling down on those
intuitions and they're now breaking up
those disciplines into subdisciplines
and smaller disciplines and smaller
disciplines and left to their own
devices.
They'll just keep splitting up and
getting smaller and smaller.
And where does feminism fit in all of
this?
Well,
the but that,
that's.
I mean,
you know what,
what,
what happens is,
is that as you get smaller and smaller
and smaller disciplines,
that it doesn't necessarily make the
science better.
It can make the science worse.
And the reason why it makes a science
where it's the easiest way to understand
it is the story of the blind men and the
elephant.
Right?
So this is an old story about from India
about religion.
So a group of blind men decide come
along and they decided to figure out the
elephant.
So this what this thing is,
right?
They don't know what's an elephant.
So the first one comes up and he feels
the tail and he feels the end of it and
it feels a little hairs at the end he
says it's a rope,
right?
And the second one goes along and he
feels the trunk and it rides in his
hands and he jumps back,
startled and he's like,
it's a snake.
Right?
And the third one feels the leg,
he thinks it's a column.
The fourth one feels the side,
he thinks it's a wall,
and then the fifth one feels the ear and
decides that it's a palm leaf and then
they all proceed to beat the shit out of
other because clearly everybody else is
a fucking idiot.
And they need to die because they know
that it's a rope.
It's a snake.
It's a leg,
it's a wall,
it's a column.
Whatever it is right now,
if you look at something like feminism,
right?
Feminism is making certain claims about
biology,
right?
It's making claims about how male gender
works,
how female gender works,
you know,
they should be looking at things like
genetics and they should be looking at,
you know,
chromosomes,
and they should be looking at evolution
to see how evolution might've selected
for differences in men and women because
there are different competing pressures
for men and women.
And in fact,
if you go into,
you know,
actual science,
you'll find that there's actually lots
of science about that.
But what's happened is,
is that feminism has become its own
tribe,
right?
And as a tribe,
it rejects the findings of other tribes,
right?
So I,
if I go into the circles of feminism or
sociology or any other tribe,
and I start talking about,
you know,
the evidence of some other tribe,
they're like,
oh,
that doesn't count,
right?
It's easy to rationalize it away.
And so now we're no longer grounded in
reality.
And what we can do is we can take that
tail and we can convince ourselves that
it's a rope,
right?
Because we're not accountable to all of
these other fields that surrounding it.
Does it make sense?
Yes.
So what if you want to solve the
problem,
what you have to do is,
is that you have to make each discipline
accountable to all the other
disciplines.
You have to make people responsive to
evidence outside of their field.
So if you take someone like Richard
Dawkins,
right,
has Richard Dawkins gone down his
particular rabbit hole of figuring out,
you know,
his tiny piece of the world?
Yes,
he has done that.
And what makes you think that?
Well,
I can tell you.
So in general,
what you're going to find is that
there's a,
in a lot of different fields,
you're going to find that there are two
competing theories right now.
So for example,
if you look in economics,
there's this idea,
you know,
there's sort of what are called
classical economics,
um,
and they have this idea called rational
agent theory,
and they basically think it's a
reasonable approximation to assume that
people are rational,
right?
That they act is rational individuals
and all this sort of stuff.
And then meanwhile there's another
school called behavioral economics.
And because of Daniel Kahneman and Amos
Tversky,
who were these two Israeli psychologists
in the 19 seventies who started to study
human rationality,
and you know,
I'm sure this will come as a huge
surprise,
but what they found is that humans
aren't that rational,
right?
And so there was a group of economists
who say,
Hey,
our whole discipline is based on this
idea of rational agent theory,
but when we look at psychology,
that assumption doesn't check out and it
leads to a whole bunch of bad
conclusions.
So they formed a new school of economics
called behavioral economics,
which is based on all the findings of
psychology,
how humans actually think and all that
sort of stuff.
Now these two schools are warring right
there,
two fighting tribes.
But what ends up happening is that they
can't solve that discipline.
They can't solve that in the context of
academia,
right?
The fire papers back and forth,
lots of discussions are had and all that
sort of stuff.
But essentially you have a recurring
problem in science,
which is that scientists won't let go of
their pet theories.
They won't let their theories die.
And Max Planck,
the physicists had this famous quote
that he said,
science proceeds one funeral at a time.
Um,
and essentially what happens is it
science doesn't progress because,
uh,
you know,
people are like,
Hey,
new evidence came out.
Turns out I was wrong,
now I'm going to change my mind because
it's their theory.
And so they keep on fighting for and
defending their theory until they're
dead.
And then the discipline is like,
oh,
okay,
now that,
that guy's dead,
obviously that was dumb all along,
let's move forward.
Interesting.
So ego becomes this sort of trap.
Huge problem.
Huge problem for science in general.
And so if you look at,
for example,
that rational agent theory dispute,
uh,
there's a,
the one of the big founders of
behavioral economics,
this Guy Richard Thaler,
um,
basically,
you know,
he tells a great story and the story is
that he's at a dinner party and at this
dinner party,
there's this famous economists from the
whole rational agent theory camp.
And this,
uh,
there's also like a bunch of other
academics like a psychologist.
And so the guy who believes in rational
agent theories going on and on about how
fucking dumb people are,
right,
how irrational they are.
So he's going on about his own wife.
He says,
my wife is so irrational.
She just bought a new car but she won't
drive it and that makes no sense because
she's worried about digging it,
but she's already paid for the car.
She should use it.
God humans are so irrational.
And then he goes and my students,
my students are so fucking dumb,
right?
They can't even understand the most
basic economic concepts and all that
sort of stuff.
And so the psychologist pipes up and
says,
how come all the people in your theories
are geniuses?
But all the people you know in real life
are idiots.
And that's a problem.
That's a real problem for your theory,
right?
Because your ubs observations about
reality do not fit your theory,
but what does this guy do?
Does this guy say,
you know what?
I'm going to fall on my sword.
I'm going to throw out 30,
40 years of work on a bad idea.
No,
he's not going to say that.
Instead what he does is he does what
Richard Thaler calls the invisible hand
wave where he proceeds to wave his hand
and say,
well,
you know,
there might be some irrationality,
blah,
blah blah.
But in the end markets sort things out
and that's,
he's rationalizing scientists,
rationalized.
Humans rationalized.
They want to defend their own most
cherished ideas.
And so that's not.
This is not a problem of Richard Dawkins
is a problem of humans.
Right?
And if humans have power and
intellectual power as a form of power
and it's not checked,
they will continue to rationalize their
bad ideas.
So specifically what bad ideas is
dawkins rationalizing?
Well,
so there's the,
you know,
the,
the intellectual dispute is this.
So in the 19 sixties there was this idea
of group selection,
but it was very fuzzy and it was a
shitty version of group selection,
right?
Which is the idea that natural selection
happens not only at the level of genes
but also at the level of human groups
and the idea that selection is happening
at many,
many,
many levels.
And so Dawkins,
in 1976 writes this big important book,
the selfish gene,
and it's basically that you actually
don't need group selection to make sense
of a lot of behavior.
You can just use what's called kin
selection.
So for example,
you might do something nice for your
sister or you might potentially,
you know,
die to save your sister,
but we can make sense of that at the
level of genes because essentially,
you know,
your sister's shares many of the same
genes.
So you know,
you don't need this idea that groups
matter.
Now,
since then,
what's happened is,
is that there are,
and this is a large part of what the
problem is,
that some people read that book
including Jeff Skilling and they
concluded that what that means is that
the way to get ahead is to be selfish.
Jeff Skilling is the CEO of Enron,
right?
And you'll hear in business circles,
you'll hear this,
this idea of like,
oh,
it's all about law of the jungle killer
be killed.
That's how you get ahead,
you know,
survival of the fittest.
So it's confirmation bias.
So exactly from their ideas about guts
repeating in business.
That's right.
And know that's what scaling probably
wanted to believe.
And so he read Dawkins' book and he's
like,
ah,
now I have intellectual credibility for
what I wanted to do anyway.
And so skilling runs and ron based on
those ideas and what has this,
what he said what at Skilling.
Yes.
Yeah.
He.
So he said that he based it on Docklands
ideas.
Well,
I said that the selfish gene was his
favorite book.
Okay.
I,
you know,
to find out,
I don't know exactly everything that
skilling his son,
but he said it was his favorite book and
this is in general a big problem.
Science is the big magic of our time.
Right?
Like it's if you want to justify like
feminists when they try and justify
their.
If the sort of feminists who try and say
that gender doesn't matter and it's all
social constructs,
they try and do it all in terms of
science.
Right.
When the Nazi youth,
I mean what,
what sometimes to the point to,
well they have,
you know,
some sort of idea of culture or
whatever.
But these other,
a lot of ideas that masquerade as
science,
right?
So you know the Nazis,
the eugenics movement,
you know,
the Nazis that was,
that was based on some sort of idea that
they thought was science at the time,
you know,
the Soviets had this guy loves Sanko who
was the opposite and he believed that,
you know,
genes could be true.
Like he thought you could literally
shock and electrocute seeds to make them
do what you wanted them to do because
jeans didn't really matter and it was
all conditioning,
right?
Or you know,
behaviorism,
right?
Was bf skinner's idea,
which was the idea that it was all
stimulus response.
The human mind didn't exist.
There were no beliefs and all that
stuff.
And a lot of the way that education,
for example,
the,
a lot of the educational pace choices
that were made in the fifties were based
on skinner's ideas,
which then fucks up a whole bunch of
kids.
You know,
either what ends up happening is that
either science is applied or it's
misapplied or misinterpreted or people
you know,
read a particular scientific study and
don't have the context on it.
And so you know,
these bad ideas permeate and they're
applied and all of that sort of stuff.
Right.
And so the debate,
for example,
around rational agent theory is not some
act,
it is an academic debate,
but in addition to being an academic
debate,
economists apply those ideas and you
know,
the public needs to,
if the public wants it's experts and its
leaders to make the right decision than
it has to hold them accountable on their
ideas.
And so,
you know,
if,
if you have,
you know,
science also has to police who has their
backing,
right?
And it needs,
it has a responsibility to communicate
to the public what is the best
scientific understanding available
today.
So Skilling takes the selfish gene and
he runs with that and clearly that's
thinking that was very popular in the
seventies and eighties,
the me generation,
all that sort of stuff.
So that selfish gene sort of slots into
a culture that is already sort of
looking for that to be true.
Right?
And it lends this credibility.
Um,
and what has happened is that the
science has now moved on to,
to this idea of multilevel selection
theory and a lot of what we've been
talking about today in terms of how
groups work and how culture works is all
based on those ideas and there's a whole
group of academics and a whole bunch of
different disciplines that have these
ideas.
And you know,
there are people like John Height,
people like Joe Henrich,
people like David Sloan Wilson who's the
big multilevel selection guy and when
you put all of theirs or Daniel Conaman,
right?
Amos Tversky,
you know,
the list goes on and on and on.
But when you put all of these ideas
together,
you get a really,
really compelling narrative.
Now doc and says that his work was
misinterpreted and that I'm essentially
the,
you know,
Jeff Skilling misunderstood his work now
doc and says very clearly in the selfish
gene that our nature is selfish.
Right?
So I mean that's,
that seems pretty clear that I don't
know that Jeff Skilling entirely
misinterpreted,
but what David Sloan Wilson and the
multilevel selection people are saying
something very simple.
An eo Wilson said this as well,
which is that altruism,
selfish individuals be altruistic
individuals,
but altruistic groups beat selfish
groups.
So if you want to get ahead,
right,
you can get ahead by being a selfish
asshole and fucking everyone,
right?
But if you have a group that is based on
selfishness and you're trying to fuck
everyone,
then your group is going gonna fall
apart and it's going to lose out to an
altruistic group.
So if you compare side by side accompany
like Enron and accompany like Pixar,
which you can read about and Creativity
Inc,
you're going to find that they have two
very different environments,
right?
Pixar is fundamentally a cooperative
environment.
It's a high trust environment.
Everybody works together,
you know,
all of that sort of stuff and it's a
sustainable company that year after
year,
turns out great films and does great
work and all that sort of stuff.
And Ron is a toxic environment because
everybody is just trying to get ahead.
There is no I in team,
they're just fucking each other.
And so the thing blows up.
Now again,
science has a responsibility to
communicate clearly and what should
happen,
I think in terms of our economy,
not blowing the fuck up,
right?
In terms of corporations not engaging in
that sort of toxic behavior is,
is that,
you know,
I don't have the authority because I'm a
nobody,
right?
So I can't come out and say this is what
science is.
In fact,
there is literally no human alive today
that can come out and say what science
is because people can only come out and
speak about their tiny field.
Right?
There's no consistent message from
science especially don't understand what
Dawkins is arguing against because
didn't he also argue for cooperation in
this book?
Like wasn't one of the chapters of his
book.
Nice guys finish first.
Well,
but he refuses to acknowledge this idea
of group that group selection happens,
right?
He's refusing to acknowledge like,
what is this is actual statements.
How is he?
Well,
I mean the larger academic debate is
like,
uh,
so specifically he rejects the idea
that,
and it's important to realize that the
group selection people are not denying
construction,
so they're not denying Dawkins is work,
right?
They're building off of is work and
saying there's this extra effect.
Right?
But how do they describe that extra
effect?
They described that effect as selfish
individuals,
outcompete altruistic individuals,
altruistic groups compete selfish
groups.
Right?
But if,
if,
if you were to have Richard Dawkins in
this room today,
he would not agree with that statement,
what would he think?
He would say that selection does not
happen at the level of groups.
Hmm.
And will be the evidence pro and con.
Well,
ultimately what I would like Joe and the
reason why I called him a scientologist
is because you know,
what should happen in academic debate is
that ideas should die,
right?
The point of,
of scientific progress is that you
should live and die,
right?
It's Thunderdome to ideas.
Enter one ideas leave right now,
the point is,
is that that's not happening in science.
What's happening?
What happened to that dinner party with
Richard Thaler is two ideas entered and
two ideas left,
right,
and in general,
that's a big recurring problem in
science.
It's happening in economics and it's
also happening in evolutionary biology.
Now the point is is that I'm a single
individual.
I can't be an expert in all the nuances
and all the details of all of these
things,
but what I can do is I can show you the
general pattern that's happening and I
can show you what the consequences are
for you.
Have these beliefs not changing.
So the area in which I do know the most
right is the area of education.
And you have some daughters,
I believe.
Is that true?
Yeah.
So these beliefs that your daughters
have about their intelligence,
whatever those beliefs may be,
as of today,
will have a huge effect on the choices
they make in school.
The choice,
how they do in education,
what their experience of school is,
whether they are happy in school,
whether they're productive,
whether they're successful,
and whether they're setup for a
knowledge economy,
which was all about constantly learning.
Do they emerge from school hating school
or did they emerge from school loving
school?
Do they emerge from school with
confidence that they can learn what has
there ever is required or do they feel
like they can only be good at some
things and not good at other things?
Before we get too far off track,
I just noticed I'm still confused as to
how you feel Dawkins is ignoring the
arguments against his work.
Like what?
What?
What are his statement?
He's denied.
He's denied this idea of group
since anybody had a debate with him
about this secret and watch somewhere.
Okay.
I listen
to.
Well,
there have been debates and you know,
what has happened is,
is that you know,
they like for example,
what the debate is currently is the
debate is currently about how many
people are on each side.
So John Height,
for example,
was on Sam Harris' podcast and Sam
Harris would agree with Richard Dawkins,
right?
And John Height,
you know,
they,
John Heightened Sam Harris,
disagree on multiple things,
right?
They've had many disagreements in the
whole point of their podcast was to try
and have a civil conversation and you
know,
John Height said,
you know,
the difference between you and Sam,
you and I,
Sam,
is that I'm an intuitionist in euro
rationalist,
right?
So Sam,
John,
John Height believes,
and if you look across the science,
I think this is what supported is that a
thief thinking and feeling are always
linked.
So we're always being driven by these
intuitions even if we don't always
understand that there is,
on the other hand,
this idea of descartes' error,
which is the idea that descartes came up
with.
The reason and emotion are separate and
there are a lot of.
That's what the rational agent theories
about the idea that,
you know,
there's reason and it's,
it's separate from emotion.
Are these mutually incompatible though?
Yes.
Okay.
Then that's the point of science is that
you're supposed to kill certain ideas.
So while there's descartes' error
specifically comes from A.
There's this book by Antonio Damasio at
USC and it's based on a series of
experiments around this guy named Elliot
and people like him.
And so elliot was this banker,
financial guy,
happy family man,
all this sort of stuff,
and he had a brain tumor and so they
chopped it out.
The brain tumor was right here,
right up at the top of the base of his
nose.
And at first it seemed like chopping out
this piece of his brain had done
nothing,
right?
It hadn't effected him.
Oh,
totally.
Disposable,
bit of brain didn't really have a
function.
Look at that.
It was just an optional accessory,
like the appendix of the brain.
But then what happens is that they come
to find out that all of a sudden elliot
has all these problems,
even though his Iq is unaffected,
even though his,
a verbal intelligence is not affected,
right?
What's happening is,
is that he,
um,
he's making all these terrible
decisions.
He leaves his wife for a stripper,
he snopes.
That's actually who Elliott is.
He's the snopes guy and it's because he
had cancer.
So don't make fun of him.
Um,
yeah.
But,
um,
you know,
he,
uh,
his business,
he starts speaking,
he was business decision making falls
apart.
He falls for all these conmen,
he's making all these horrible choices
and he can't decide where to go to
lunch.
So what ends up happening is is that an
11:00
AM,
he'll try and decide where am I going to
go to lunch and then by 4:00
PM lunches past and that's because he
sat around and tried to calculate
rationally where should I go to lunch?
Right?
He thought about,
oh,
should I go like based on tables and
calories and all this sort of stuff,
and he couldn't make a decision.
And the reason why is because this bit
of the brain that was removed turns out
is what links thinking and feeling.
It's your ventral medial prefrontal
cortex and deciding where to go to lunch
is influenced constantly by our emotions
because you know,
you have,
you feel like tie or you know,
you feel like something light or you
feel like a meatball sub or whatever it
may be,
where you feel like if you go to this
restaurant,
you'll run into that really hot waitress
or whatever it may be.
So that along with the work of Daniel
Kahneman and Amos Tversky and the work
of people like John Height,
there's now an immense amount of
information that basically understands
that descartes who lived 400 years ago
was making shit up when he came up with
his theory of the brain,
right?
And his theory of the brain of this idea
of reason and emotion,
which has floated around in the West for
ages and ages and ages.
It doesn't fit the evidence.
Now,
that's the basic problem is that,
and I will tell you,
having worked with students,
your ability to improve their lives,
once you understand that thinking and
feeling are always linked,
goes massively up because now when a
student starts telling me,
Oh,
I don't have the math gene,
or I don't have a natural ear for
languages,
I don't waste my time dealing with that
rationalization.
Instead I asked the kid,
how do you feel about math?
Right?
How do you feel about your teacher?
And we start to deal with the feelings
and we start to sort through the
feelings until we get the feelings lined
up in such a way that you're making the
right choices.
And that's,
that's for me,
the heart is that there.
That's,
that's the problem that I first came to
this from was education and all this,
talking about these kids though.
Sorry to interrupt you,
but it seems almost like a.
you're talking about a user operator
error.
It's like they're just programmed
incorrectly to know how to view the
world by their culture.
Their culture is fucking them and
setting and know.
And it's.
And,
and that's what you have to understand
is,
is that,
you know,
that's human hardware doesn't.
Human hardware has not really changed in
the last hundred thousand years.
But human software,
the culture that we picked up has
evolved over time.
It's constantly changing.
And now especially because the
environment is changing so fast because
of technology and all these sorts of
things,
chat filters,
we need to change the culture fast and
we need to change the culture
intentionally and so.
But who decides how the culture gets
changed?
Is it Donald Trump or is it another
month?
And it's not either of us,
it should be the group.
Right?
And the point is to spark a conversation
so that we can have this conversation.
But the point is,
is there are certain academics who are
going to try and stand in the way of
that conversation and will use their
authority to try and shut down that
conversation because they're trying to
defend their pet theory in whatever
discipline it is.
And this is where you come back to
Dawkins,
and this is Dawkins,
but I,
the point is to recognize it's not about
Dawkins particularly.
And if you want to get into the woods
on,
like,
you know,
all of the nuances of all of this sort
of stuff.
You should get on either David Sloan
Wilson or John Heider,
Joe Henrich and they can like take you
through the whole thing.
But um,
and the basic problem is,
is that there's a lot of science that is
really,
really useful.
But you know,
one man can't figure it all out.
Impossible.
And you can't hold onto a theory.
No,
you have to expose it to the marketplace
of ideas.
It has to be tested and what I can do,
because there's a lot of this comes down
to what's permissible in the culture of
science.
So if you've got guys like,
you know,
you can go if you want to go and like
read about what David Sloan Wilson is
saying and all of these guys,
you can either go read their books which
are excellent,
but you can also go to David Sloan
Wilson because he has also seen
practically how much of these ideas can
make a difference in people's lives and
actually make people's lives better.
He's also trying to popularize the
science.
So he has a whole website,
you know,
this view of life and economics and all
this sort of stuff.
And if you want,
there's a great article by Peter Turchin
who's another guy and he'll take you
through some of the stuff around Dawkins
and all this stuff.
But what my,
my goal with all of this stuff with
Thomas Soul's work with David Sloan
Wilson,
John Height,
you know Carol dwecks work was just a
lot of this education stuff is that I
know that it's not realistic to expect
people to.
That I can't just like put a list on the
Internet,
have 50 books and be like everybody has
to read these 50 bucks.
Like people have other shit to worry
about.
Right?
Yeah.
But if you don't concern yourself with
that,
I've just suggested enough people will.
The ideas will start to permeate.
But you also what your,
what you run into.
And this is part of what I've run into
with education right,
is so,
you know,
along with Katie,
my Bostonian friend,
we took seven different fields of
neuroscience and psychology and we
condensed them all into one book that we
wrote to the teenager because we wanted
to have a message.
Problem is most of these books are
written to adults and you write the book
to the adult,
the adult reads it,
the parent reads that and they're like,
oh,
this is so great.
And then now they're in the
uncomfortable position of having to have
a conversation about school with kids
and then the ideas die.
The idea is don't move.
So we were like,
let's skip the middle man and let or
middle woman and let's write straight to
the kid.
What's the book is called the straight a
conspiracy.
And the reason why we called it the
straight a conspiracy is because we,
at the time we're working with the son
of a guy named Stan Rogo who was the
executive producer on Lizzie Mcguire.
And we'd been.
I mean,
this is the power of emotions by the
way,
like super predators.
Lizzie,
Lizzie mcguire was like that hate hilary
duff,
a kids' TV show.
Oh,
okay.
In the nineties it was like super big.
It was the miley cyrus of like or early
two thousands I think.
But anyway,
so we,
you know,
we were struggling with how do you have
a conversation about education in school
and your potential and all these sorts
of things with kids.
And you know,
our intuitions are,
we're sort of the classic teacher
intuitions,
which is like,
you can do it.
You're amazing,
like you have so much potential.
And we had sat down with Stan and Stan
said,
listen,
I've been making kids' tv for a long
time and if I've learned one thing about
teenagers,
it's this,
their lives suck.
They may not suck at any sort of
objective sense or any sort of
geographical sense or anything like
that,
but on an emotional subjective level,
they suck.
And so the only thing you could ever
tell them that they will believe is that
they've been lied to.
And so that's what we did.
And he said,
your,
the title of your book is the something
conspiracy.
I don't know what it is.
Right?
And so we went away and we did the
straight a conspiracy.
And rather than getting kids to believe
them,
believe in themselves,
we got them to doubt their doubts.
And once you got them doubting their
doubts and you know all the things that
they believed about math genes,
is that really true?
How do we know that brow like,
is that really,
you know,
all that sort of stuff.
And then you get that process where they
are now starting to question things and
you know,
we did the first chapter is all about
genius myths,
um,
which are,
you know,
essentially very clever marketing
schemes that again,
rely on that thing of all.
So if you look at someone like Steve
Jobs,
right?
Steve Jobs was very smart marketer,
And He created this image,
right?
This cult of personality around himself,
which is that,
you know,
he made himself seem like this genius
who out of nowhere came out of all these
things,
people call them the I got and the cult
of Mac and what is the effect of all the
effect of all his blind copying.
We just had to have that Mac product.
And in that he was copying the playbook
of another guy much,
much earlier,
Thomas Edison,
who in his own time created this own
cult of personality around himself.
And at the time he was known as the
wizard of Menlo Park.
But in reality,
did Edison invented the light bulb?
No,
he did not.
The light bulb was around 45 years
before he was even born,
ripped off Tesla.
You watch drunk history.
I received Duncan trussell's version of
history.
It's all on Nikola Tesla and Thomas
Edison.
Thomas Edison,
and being a con.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
And so,
um,
and that's the point is that,
you know,
these,
these people were people and you know,
the myths that you have about geniuses
are actually clever advertising schemes.
But the problem is,
is that it's an ad jingle that,
that is so good that we've essentially
had that jingle trapped in our heads for
hundreds and hundreds of years.
So there are ideas that are passed on,
like Edison had a thousand patents to
his name before he,
by the time he died,
he did.
That's because when you set up an
industrial research lab,
you make sure that your name is on all
the patents because that's the whole
point of employing a bunch of people is
that,
you know,
you want to own the Ip.
And that's true for,
you know,
Mozart was the Michael Jackson of the 17
hundreds.
Isaac Newton,
you know,
they basically knew that they couldn't
sell the ideas of gravity,
so they sold Newton is the man,
this guy who had this great vision and
Blah Blah,
blah,
and the story of the apple and all that
bullshit,
and then Einstein,
you know,
they needed to package the new physics
that was being done by lots and lots of
physicist Heisenberg and planck and all
that sort of stuff.
But there was this guy,
Arthur Eddington,
who knew he couldn't sell that,
so he sold the idea of a boy wonder with
crazy hair who had beaten Newton and was
displacing Newton.
Now the point is you go and you talk to
physicists and they'll tell you,
well,
it's not really true.
Like Einstein didn't really displace
Newton,
right?
We still use newtonian mechanics.
We only use Einsteinian mechanics when
we start to get near the speed of light,
right?
So there are all these marketing,
the marketing schemes,
right?
But in the marketplace of ideas,
part of what happens is,
is that there are these big public
intellectuals like Richard Dawkins,
right?
And they have a lot of power and it
becomes very difficult to challenge
them.
And in particular,
I don't think that anybody particularly
wants to go up against Richard Dawkins.
Right?
He's a sacred cow.
He is a sacred cow.
And if you go up against the new
atheists or you challenge anything about
the new atheists.
And I have,
I,
you know,
I like the,
the whole rationalist intuitionist thing
because I've been trying to talk about
emotions on our podcast.
And I said,
you know,
hey,
look,
you don't have to believe me,
there's this Guy John Height,
who's a big famous scientists and all
that stuff.
And then there's this guy,
Sam Harris who has a phd in
neuroscience,
but John Height is saying rationalist
versus intuitionist.
There's a difference.
Right?
And I want to talk about that and I'm
going to tell you that I think that in
light of the evidence,
Sam Harris was wrong and I got a whole
bunch of angry tweets from a guy named
at Atheist Sensei proceeded to tell me
that I was a fucking idiot,
and blah,
blah,
blah.
And what did I know and how arrogant I
was and how dare you and all this sort
of stuff.
But once you understand your argument,
he didn't really.
So what did he just jump at you because
of the fact that you're questioning his
boy.
He basically and then what?
I man his man and.
But it was,
it was,
it was productive because what he said
is he said,
what are you even talking about?
Sam Harris knows that most people are
being emotional most of the time,
but the issue isn't what Sam Harris
knows about other people.
It's what a Sam Harris believe about his
own brain.
Right?
And Sam Harris,
he's really.
And this is not sam's fault as an
individual,
just as none of the cultural stuff that
we've been talking about is his fault.
I,
when I was in college,
I also believed in this whole idea of
descartes' error,
that reason and emotion are separate.
And then I moved out to la and I was in
an acting class and I moved from an
environment that worshiped reason to an
environment that worshiped emotion,
right?
That's what actors do all day.
They fucking talk about their feelings
and so for somebody who had come from
that environment,
it was super fucking annoying.
I found actors really,
really annoying because they would not
stop talking about their feelings and it
pissed me off.
It pissed me off.
And the certain point I got so annoyed,
I was like,
you fuckers don't know what the fuck
you're talking about.
The only real authorities are
scientists.
So what did I do?
I went off and I read the scientists and
I found out that the actors were right
and it was fucking humiliating.
I don't understand where they were,
right?
How they were,
right about the importance of emotions.
Emotions are hugely important.
They drive thinking,
yeah,
but that's not what these actors are
doing.
I understand that,
you know,
they're just being emotional because
it's indulgent.
They're being indulgent and they're not
managing their emotions,
which is what you're supposed to do,
but what you find,
for example.
So here's a simple thing,
um,
you know,
there's a reason why we say that and
then you know,
that intersected with working with
students,
right?
So if you say,
for example,
students say,
I feel stupid,
turns out that stupid is a feeling
specifically,
it's the feeling of shame,
right?
And so,
and also being ineffective in your
intellectual pursuits and a sense of
helplessness and all that sort of stuff,
but feel inadequate.
That's right.
And it's specifically,
it's a feeling called learned
helplessness,
right?
In,
in academic circles where there are
terrible names for everything,
right?
So,
um,
but the,
the feeling of shame motivates a very
specific behavior which is that you
avoid the source of their shame,
your shame.
So when students get back a bad test,
what they do is they want it up and they
throw it away and they avoid math.
They avoid math.
Right?
Now,
the point is,
is that that is that behavior is
literally the worst response you can
have to failure,
right?
If you're screwing up in math or any
other subject,
what you should be doing is getting out
your mistakes,
analyzing your mistakes and using them
to get better,
and so that very simple thing is what we
did with all of our students.
We sat them down,
we made them confront their mistakes.
We made them say,
okay,
number three,
why did you get number three wrong?
And then you figure out why number three
is wrong,
and then you fix that.
Now,
how does this oppose what Sam Harris
believes?
The point is is that does Sam does.
If,
if an atheist Sensei,
and I will tell you that I think that an
atheist Sensei is pretty right in,
is a sense in his assessment of what Sam
Harris believes about.
Like most people are emotional most of
the time,
but I don't think that Sam Harris
believes that thinking and feeling are
always linked so that his brain is all
know this for a fact.
Have you discussed this with him?
Because I know I'm getting a text from
him and about fucking five minutes.
I'll tell you for example.
Okay,
so how does Sam Harris feel about God or
how does Sam Harris feel about religion?
That's a pretty open ended question.
He doesn't believe in religion and I
don't think he necessarily believes in
any form of a deity.
Well,
let's talk.
There's no evidence for that.
Let's talk about it.
I know that you have a relationship with
Sam,
but that's okay.
But forget about that.
Why those questions?
And so if you look at,
let's look at,
for example,
you know your,
your friends,
the narco capitalists,
right?
And Libertarians,
Who just want to get rid of government,
right?
And they're just trying to get rid of
all government,
right?
So what is that?
What is that?
Thinking about?
What does that psychology about or any
sort of a or Muslim fundamentalists,
they just want to get rid of these
western influences.
They basically think that a certain
thing is bad and they're constantly
trying to strip it out,
strip it out,
strip it out.
That's the nature of fundamentalism.
And Richard Dawkins and Sam Harris are
atheist fundamentalists and specifically
Richard Dawkins has talked about
militant atheism that you know,
and Richard Dawkins has said that
religion is the scourge of humanity and
that we need to get rid of religion.
Now,
in reality,
if you look at the scientific evidence,
what you're going to find out is that
religion has a very checkered past,
right?
And that it's,
you know,
that religion has a,
in terms of the history of violence,
right?
Steven pinker has this book,
the better angels of our nature and he
talks about the fact that,
you know,
the,
what the new atheists are saying about
religion is not supported by the
evidence,
right?
That in history,
religion has not been any one thing,
right?
It's,
it's had some good things,
it's had some bad things.
So that's not a scientifically
appropriate belief to go around and
saying that religion is the scourge of
all humanity or to be waging war about
over religion.
You're talking about Dawkins and Sam
Harris and all that sort of stuff.
And particularly Dawkins,
because he's the most militant them.
Right?
Right.
Separately,
you know,
why do people believe in religion?
What is religion really about?
Right.
It's because people don't understand how
to control their environment and so
their minds fill in and they're trying
to make sense of how do we get the
things that we also like all the rest of
culture,
it's passed down.
That's learned behavior and imitating
atmospheres and adopting predetermined
patterns of behavior.
Yeah.
And thinking.
Exactly.
And so if you,
if you know Dawkins and Sam Harris,
their stated objective,
right?
As they want to promote evolution right
now I taught,
I had to tutor some students who were at
a Christian school that taught
creationism and it's oaks Christian in
thousand oaks.
Right.
And I had never like honestly,
like pre doing that experience,
I had never thought much about the new
atheists,
like they just weren't a big deal.
I was like,
okay,
those guys are out doing whatever
they're doing.
Right.
And then I went into this Christian
fundamentalist school or whatever it is,
or school that teaches creationism and
all they could talk about was Richard
Dawkins and Sam Harris.
Right?
They were talking about them constantly
and in their minds,
Richard Dawkins and Sam Harris represent
science.
They are the face of science in the same
way that,
you know,
some guy in the midwest when he thinks
about when he thinks about Islam,
he's thinking about isis or al Qaeda or
all that sort of stuff.
He doesn't understand that those people
don't represent the majority of Muslims.
And in the same way in this right.
Dorkins and Harris were being used to
represent science in general and to
represent evolution in general.
Right?
So they are essentially for a lot of
people forming the stereotype of science
now,
now in opposition to them.
I mean with an opposition to Dawkins and
Harris.
And there were certain things they did
in their teaching like they would do,
um,
you know,
the,
uh,
you know,
the school,
I mean,
it was a weird experience because one
school had the very best rhetoric
department that I've ever seen of any
school because they knew that they were
going to have people attacking their
beliefs for their whole life.
And so you had to know all the logical
fallacies Straw man,
you know,
to quote quail,
that's where stuff and the worst science
department for fuck you seen in my life.
Yeah.
Wonder why?
Well exactly.
And so,
you know,
they did all sorts of things.
Like for example,
they had a whole unit on Isms,
right?
They were like Nazis and fascism,
communism and how bad isms were.
And then right after that they taught
the controversy around evolution.
So they were like,
well,
there are four different theories of the
origins of life,
right?
One is young Earth creationism,
one is intelligent design,
one is earth is metaphorical day.
And then the fourth one is a evolution
isn't right.
She's just so evolutionism,
right?
So after telling you the evils of Isms,
that's right.
So,
so you're going on a long circuitous
route here.
So because causation is about Harris so
well,
but the problem is wrong with his views
on God and what's wrong with his views
on religion.
Well,
that's the point is,
is that religion is a set of beliefs.
And actually many of these beliefs are
adapted to their environment even though
they seem cookie and they're also
ideologies that are strictly enforced
and that's one of the things he has a
big issue with.
But the point is is that is the issue if
you want to.
So this comes down to how do you change
people's minds and what does the science
say about how you change people's minds
and how do you move ideas?
Okay.
So you're saying that his mocking of
these ideas is contrary to the expanding
of knowledge.
It's a people are going to resist it and
it's,
it doesn't predict,
promote a productive exchange of ideas
between tribes.
That's isn't that debate about.
Because a lot of people in listening to
really excellent constructed arguments
against religion will change their mind
well like everything,
right?
So you know,
rule 34,
right?
Right.
So rule 34,
if you can imagine it,
there is porn of it,
right?
So in the same way,
if you can imagine it,
there is science of it,
right?
Right.
But hold on.
So there's actually science on how ideas
move.
There's a whole field of it and there's
this book called the diffusion of
innovations,
right?
And I had,
because I was working with these
students,
right?
I was trying to figure out how do we get
these ideas to move and so I was like,
oh thank God there's a book all about
how ideas move.
Right?
And what you come to find out is that
all of the research shows,
there's a whole bunch of things that
make ideas move.
One thing is they have to be compatible
with people's existing beliefs and then
also they have to be practical
so they have to confer some sort of
practical benefit.
Right?
So if in terms of moving evolution,
the first thing is to recognize that,
you know,
if we really want to like not just spend
another hundred and 50 years,
you know,
having a fight between science and
religion and all that sort of stuff.
The first thing to realize is that what
people like David Sloan Wilson are
saying is fundamentally compatible with
Christianity,
right?
Because they understand that,
you know,
that altruism matters,
right?
All this sort of stuff,
right.
The sort of doc doc type notion of it's
all about selfishness and everybody just
trying to fuck everybody and all that
sort of stuff.
Part of it is that doesn't fit well with
Christianity,
right?
It doesn't fit well with religious
notions.
Right?
Secondly,
all of this stuff that I'm talking about
with cultural evolution is deeply
practical,
right?
You can see that if we have a
conversation as humanity about culture
and how my choices are being driven and
all that sort of stuff so that I can
change my culture and all that sort of
stuff,
that we can fix a whole lot of things.
That notion of culture relies on group
selection,
right?
It relies on this multilevel selection
idea that Dawkins is not on board with
and all that sort of stuff and that Sam
Harris is not on board with.
So ultimately what I want to do is I
want to move these ideas,
but the whole point is,
Joe,
is that part of the reason why you
brought me on this podcast today is
specifically because I called out
Richard.
No,
no,
no.
I brought you on because Brian Cowen
recommends you and I listen to you on
his podcast.
He had nothing to do with that.
I just thought that'd be an interesting
topic of discussion.
Okay.
But I still don't understand.
So you're saying that essentially Sam
Harris's refused one or refuting rather
of religion and his ideas about
spreading what he believes are the
empirical truths about science are in
somehow or another causing a resistance
to these very ideas because of the way
he's presenting them because he's not
presenting them in a form that
psychologically digestible.
Is that what you're saying?
Yes,
and also fundamentally he creates the
stereotype of scientists that is being
formed around him.
And what is that well is that they're
angry,
aggressive.
They doesn't seem aggressive.
Well,
he seems aggressive.
It's not.
It's not about really.
I mean that was the point of like
spending time in at oaks Christian.
It's not really about how I was
perceiving them because I wasn't
thinking about it.
Well,
these are people that are pushing a
ridiculous ideology and the enemies of
that ridiculous ideology they attack.
They're attacking,
but the basic,
the basic problem is attacking.
Right?
But it's a very small segment of mean
schools that are doing this.
Right.
You're talking about how many people
believe Christian school,
how many people believe in evolution?
It was probably a giant number.
Well,
I mean,
you know,
you can look at different polls,
but it's like 50 slash 50.
Yeah,
I think it's like 46 percent according
to a recent Gallup poll,
but my joke was always like,
who
the fuck answer is?
Paul's mean,
is it like one out of 100 at triggered
last night?
Right?
Yeah.
The people dumb enough to answer polls
sets,
right?
One percent,
but,
but ultimately that's the,
the,
you know,
the sort of,
the larger thing that I would like to
achieve is a scientific reformation,
right?
So you know,
you the,
you know,
Martin Luther triggers this,
this reformation with the Catholic
church and all that sort of stuff.
At the cornerstone of the core of the
Catholic Church was this idea of love
they neighbor as thyself.
And basically Martin Luther said the
people in the power in this,
in the religious establishment are not
living that principle right at the core
of sciences.
This idea that we should be responsive
to evidence,
right?
Right.
And the scientific establishment is
often not living or the academic
establishment is not living that,
that,
you know,
principal.
Right.
So,
and part of the problem is,
is that left to their own devices,
they will continue to remain in their
tiny lanes and a lot of these academic
disputes can only be solved by going
outside their lanes.
So for example,
if Sam Harris was here,
right?
And I've said this on the podcast with
Brian,
the one thing that I wanted would want
to talk about,
the only thing that I would want to talk
about is this rationalist versus
intuitionist idea and try and reach some
sort of definitive conclusion on that
because if Sam Harris is thinking and
feeling are always being linked,
then he has to decide how his feelings
about religion are driving his thinking
and whether his feelings about religion
are appropriate in light of the evidence
or whether they're not appropriate.
So that makes sense.
Well,
religion as itself though,
when you talk to you about evidence,
it's extremely lacking in that.
So what he's talking about is people
that are subscribing to a very rigid
ideology that he thinks is compromising
growth in the same way that racism
justifies the behavior of social justice
warriors.
So it's not,
I'm not.
So you know,
you understand,
I understood this but,
but this religious discrimination is
based on an ideology,
of course that's written on animal skins
from thousands of years ago.
Actually my ignorance.
So there's much more to that than,
than just saying that it's,
it's similar to racism will know.
But what I'm saying is that,
you know,
in this is again,
so there's a,
there's a larger principle here,
and again,
you can find it in,
you know,
Jon Heights' book,
the happiness hypothesis,
right?
Which is,
this is something that Jesus talked
about a long time ago,
right?
Which is that it's easy to see the
splinter in my brother's eye,
but hard to see the log in my own.
So in general,
when you talk to people,
right?
Like if you look at Jordan Peterson,
Jordan Peterson criticizes people on
College Campuses,
right?
And He,
you know,
for us,
right?
He comes on my show,
he comes on your show and we all cheer
him on.
We're like,
that's so fucking great.
Right?
What is the reaction that Jordan
Peterson gets on his campus?
Mixed.
It's very mixed.
Some were saluting him,
some people were very upset at him.
That's right.
And so for example,
when I took,
when I challenged these,
you know,
the narco capitalists,
the libertarians,
all that sort of stuff,
I got some people cheering me on and
then a lot of people calling me
intellectually dishonest or whatever and
all that sort of stuff,
right?
These arguments,
nobody is saying that these arguments as
they currently stand are easy.
There's a lot of material to draw,
right?
And,
you know,
um,
my in,
in the end,
like my job is to communicate them as
clearly as possible.
What I'm saying is,
is that if you want to move science,
like science has a communication problem
right now.
If you read people in science like a
tool Guan Day,
he'll just be like,
people are fucking dumb.
Science is complicated,
right?
You,
you going,
you go on these big broad journeys for
you come back.
So,
so,
so what I'm saying is that Sam Harris
and Richard Dawkins are the kind of
friends with friends like Sam Harris and
Richard Dawkins.
Science doesn't need enemies.
They are alienating,
they are not helping us and they're
getting in the way of communicating
science.
I understand because of the very
approach that they're taking.
If science was to adopt the approach of
we are here in light of the diffusion of
innovations,
which is the book all about how you feel
the same way about Neil degrasse Tyson
and is open criticism of religion.
Well I think in general that I don't
think that the criticism of religion is
helping science.
It's a hundred and 50 year old science
has been at war with religion for a
hundred and 50 years.
So you don't think that science should
be honest or the.
I think that will.
That scientists should be honest about
their own personal.
Well,
but the point is is that I believe that
scientists should read science widely
and if you look at someone like John
Height,
part of the reason why John Height and
Sam Harris have fought is because John
doesn't have a problem with religion
because when you update your view of the
brain,
you come to realize that what's really
going on is that you blindly
internalized the beliefs of science and
your community and all that sort of
stuff and that they blindly internalized
the beliefs of their community and that
if you want to move ideas,
if you want to move scientific ideas,
what we have to do is establish trust,
but what specifically are they blindly
interpreting,
but it's this idea of that reason and
emotion are separate,
but what?
How does that apply strictly to religion
and beliefs on religion being incorrect?
Because if you look at the behavior of
fundamentalists,
right?
They get very into the,
the literal text in the wording and all
that sort of stuff.
Right?
And it's the same thing with Sam Harris
and Richard Dawkins,
right?
They're super into like breaking apart.
What does the Koran say?
What does the Bible say and all this
sort of stuff,
and what really matters is what is the
spirit in which it's being approached.
What are,
how do you feel about these things?
So if you look at something like gay
marriage,
right,
or homosexuals,
right?
What does the Bible say on
homosexuality?
Well,
it says two totally different things,
right?
There's what it says about Sodom and
Gomorrah.
And then there's what it says about,
uh,
you know,
love thy neighbor as thyself.
And if you hate gays,
you're to be like,
oh,
Sodom and Gomorrah.
That's the thing.
Right?
And if you like gay people,
you have a nice gay neighbor or
whatever.
You're like,
Oh,
love thy neighbor as thyself.
Right?
So the issue is not the text,
the issue is what does the person feel
about the thing,
right?
That's,
that's the psychology that is driving
it.
Right?
So the point is,
is that if you want to fix the problem,
right,
you don't worry about the text,
right?
You don't worry about what are the
literal.
The text is preposterous.
It should be discussed.
Well,
I mean if the taxed promotes violence
against women or against any particular
group that doesn't believe what you
believe it's discussed because it's
problematic,
right?
Different people like has the Bible
changed in the last 400 years?
No,
but different people's interpretations
of the bibles have.
Right?
Right.
And so,
so for example,
you know,
if you look at,
for example,
where are Muslims now and where are
Christians now look at Christianity and
the 1600.
Well this is an issue that Michael
Shermer wrote about recently about Islam
not experiencing the enlightenment that
other religions have gone through this.
Well,
it's specifically about Islam
experiencing a D enlightenment,
right?
Because in the year $1,000
they were.
But so the real thing that if you want
to fix Islam,
and again,
like you know,
I was born in Saudi Arabia,
my parents live in Dubai.
Like there are conversations happening
about this.
What you have to do is,
is that you have to change the
intellectual climate,
but the.
But the intellectual climate has nothing
to do with the text.
It has to do with a lot of what people
believe about learning what they believe
about themselves,
whether they find ideas threatening and
the the text that when Islam in the year
1000,
right was the most intellectually
advanced place on the planet and the
text that Islam is using now has not
changed.
So what happens is,
is that people like Sam Harris and
Richard Dawkins,
they get super caught up in the text,
but really if you want to fix these
problems,
you have to talk about,
you know,
what are your beliefs about your
intentional intelligence,
how do you feel about other cultures?
You have to talk about feelings and
that's really where the conversation
changes and the point is,
is that rationalist don't talk about
feelings.
So that's the real.
I mean that is the core of what needs to
happen and the science is there to do
that.
But the point is,
is that,
you know,
let's put these people side by side.
John Height has a following of
essentially zero,
right?
Richard Dawkins has a huge following,
Sam Harris has a big following.
Someone like Joe Henrich,
I'd probably maybe has three twitter
followers.
So the people who are representing
science,
right?
Neil degrasse Tyson,
you know,
no one's questioning like does Neil
degrasse tyson?
No way the fuck more about astrophysics
than I do 100 percent,
but I don't know that Neil degrasse
Tyson has,
for example,
read the diffusion of innovations
because I will tell you that I've had
numerous academics on the podcast.
For example,
David Sloan Wilson,
right?
I asked him,
you know,
he sent me this thing back in 2014 and
it was a 67 page paper and it said,
you know,
it was towards a science of intentional
behavior change or something like that.
And I read the 67 pages and at the end
of the 16,
17,
67 pages,
I'm like,
I feel like what you're actually talking
about is how do you move ideas and
wasn't that already solved with the
diffusion of innovations?
And he said,
Oh,
I,
you know,
I've obviously heard of the diffusion of
innovations.
Like Everett Rogers is literally famous
work,
but I've never made a close study of it.
Now the diffusion of innovations was
written in 1967.
It is an innovation that hasn't diffused
and that's specifically because even
though it's set practices,
it preaches one thing about how ideas
move.
It's written in that dry scientific
technical style.
So a guy like Neil degrasse Tyson,
you know,
or Sam Harris or Richard Dawkins or
David Sloan Wilson,
the war,
John Hyde or Joe Henrich or any of these
guys often have not heard of ideas that
are relevant to the conversations that
we're having.
Like it's not just that the ideas aren't
moving between them
sciences,
some bizarre conversation to have if you
don't know whether or not they've read
that
well,
but you can look at people's behavior
and you can see from people's behavior
whether they understand certain things
or not,
whether they agree with certain things.
I mean,
just because their behavior doesn't,
isn't compatible to that paper.
It doesn't mean that they haven't read
it and just decided that they don't
agree or they have another point of
view.
Well,
I mean the,
for a,
you know,
uh,
okay.
Uh,
if you immune,
if we're going to really get into this,
we really
camp,
we were,
we're,
we're way over,
we're like 25 minutes over.
So I was trying to figure out a way to
skirt out of here quick,
but yeah,
but I mean the,
the,
the point that I'm trying to the large,
I think the main point is this,
that,
you know,
from all of our conversations about
culture,
right,
there are ideas out there trapped in
books,
which is the whole point of what we're
doing on the brand calvin show that have
real practical value to improving
people's lives.
Those ideas are not moving and part of
it,
don't you think they're all kind of
moving?
Well right now,
everything is moving
well,
but.
Well,
so part of the diffusion of innovations,
right?
So the book opens with a story about
scurvy,
right?
So scurvy is,
you know,
this problem that killed 2 million
people,
right?
And you know,
it's all comes down to vitamin C
deficiency and it's the simplest
solution in the world.
You just suck on a line.
So between scurvy being figured out,
right in a sort of academic context and
between it being applied 150 years past
150 years.
So the point is is that ideas don't
move.
Well they didn't have the internet,
but it's not even about that.
It's good.
It isn't it.
I mean isn't that the best way to
distribute information as the internet?
The fact that it took 150 years for
scurvy to be cured,
even though the information was there,
don't you think that directly coincides
with the lack of ability to express that
information?
It has to do with.
And that's the point of the diffusion of
innovations.
It's has to do with the ideas being
packaged in a way that is culturally and
psychologically compatible with what
people already believe and it being
shown that they have practical value.
The basic barrier is this.
Why have ideas?
Have these,
you know,
the,
the science of evolution has been around
for hundred and 50 years.
That vitamin C example that you're
using,
you're talking about an extremely
limited amount of education available
when people were not expressing them.
Well,
what?
Eighteen 47 in comparison to 2016 or 17
difference.
Yeah,
but if you've got 2 million people
dying,
right?
There were 2 million people dying.
It was a huge problem.
They didn't know how to solve it and
these ideas didn't move.
Right.
But how can you compare that to today?
Well,
the,
I mean the,
the.
I mean,
you know,
I mean Joe,
we can't do the,
we can't do the experiment where,
you know,
we have one world where we don't move,
we don't do anything to package and move
the ideas and we have another world
where we do actively work to try and
package and move these ideas.
We can't do that,
but it's 160 years difference in the
world is a different world.
Well,
the technology is different,
but the human mind hasn't changed.
The human mind hasn't changed really in
10,000
years.
The human mind might not have changed
genetically,
but it's understanding of the world has
changed radically.
So it's understanding of what a vitamin
is
well,
but that's the different between you
understand well,
but that's also important is that it's
important to realize that when this
whole scurvy conversation was going on,
they didn't have the concept of a
vitamin and there are three concepts
that you don't have right now in terms
of this idea that thinking and feeling
are always linked,
right?
This idea of descartes' error,
that's not our culture doesn't talk
about emotions in a way where they
understand,
oh,
this behavior of the student where they
bought up the test and they throw it all
away.
That is being driven by an emotion.
A lot of people understand that though,
do they?
For sure.
A lot of people understand that people
get humiliated by failure and then it
makes them pull back,
okay,
so they don't grow.
And when people teach people,
there's a lot of things that people
teach about when learning new
information to make an encouraging and
to make it enjoyable and to express
boundless potential and not express,
you know,
very clear,
rigid boundaries that you're never going
to cross and that you can impart these
very limiting ideas into children's
minds or you can expand upon their
potential horizons by promoting this
idea of accessibility and have have
massive potential
of course.
But is it a standard practice in America
schools today when a student,
when a student gets a bad tests that we
all work through those mistakes and
analyze them.
I don't know what the standards.
It's not.
I mean that's just shitty teaching,
but it's not a matter of lack of
understanding amongst certain
individuals about the way people are
motivated and not motivated.
Well,
there may be a small number of
individuals,
but that doesn't mean that that is the
general consensus.
I don't even know if it's a small
number.
I think it's a fairly number.
It's just not
the consensus.
Why do you think that Asian cultures do
better in school than American culture?
Probably discipline,
well a lot of it is that faith and
intelligence,
they really believe practice makes
perfect and if you work hard at
something that you'll get better.
It's also cultural,
isn't it?
That is called talking about it for you.
Americans don't have that culture today.
They don't have that faith that if you
bust your ass and you really work hard
that you'll get better.
They did have that.
People have that idea.
Some do.
That's a giant generalization,
but look at the reserve funds don't
have,
but look at the results.
Americas are massive hotbed of
innovation and creativity and art,
which is the part which part of America
in particular as a massive hotbed of
innovation.
Which subculture?
It's silicon valley.
Silicon Valley is one.
It's an incredibly innovative.
What about the artistic community?
What about music?
There's massive amounts of comedy,
massive amounts of writing,
literature,
fiction.
A lot of it's coming from America.
All total,
all corners of the spot.
Totally.
But at the same time is the,
you know,
why aren't American students doing well
in school?
Shitty students or Shitty,
excuse me.
Shitty teachers rather.
Shitty culture and well,
yeah,
that too,
and also a lack of a lack of resources
being applied to schools.
I mean,
you find out what a teacher's salary is
and you front out how little they.
They're respected women.
It's a real issue for sure.
Yeah,
we have,
I think we absolutely agree on that and
a large part of it is that there are,
you know,
there are complicated fixes like fixing
how much we pay teachers and all that
sort of stuff and there are simple fixes
and things that we can fix pretty simply
and ideas that you can promote our,
you know,
embrace your mistakes,
analyze your mistakes,
fail forward,
and that is the I,
that is the cornerstone value of the
FAA,
which is why you're safer flying than
walking.
It's the cornerstone valley value of
Silicon Valley and I will tell you that
having worked with lots and lots of
students and traveled all across the
country,
that is not the core value of a lot of
American students.
Then we got to wrap this up.
I'm so sorry.
It's already 5:00.
I'm in trouble.
Thank you very much,
man.
Really appreciate it.
Me.
Do it again man.
It seems like you've got a lot more to
talk.
There's a lot of shock though.
Alright,
you fucks Cmr.
Bye.
You.
Sorry Dude.