Live music and then you know,
edited,
but no,
we don't even fight.
Makes it feel alive and dirty.
It is dirty dude.
It's dirty as fuck.
Bam.
Just music.
Maybe.
What is this called?
There was a slight pause.
What's the.
What's The music called?
Portal from the portal.
Soundtrack.
Still alive.
We tried to play this the other day,
but I don't think I'm high enough.
Expansion.
You know,
you want another head of this straight
homie.
Gone deeper.
How do you like that?
I'm going for,
for you.
Just keep
offering free.
Started getting into good subjects.
It's like save it,
save it,
save it.
That's the problem.
When you get cool people to come out
before the podcast,
then when you try and recycle the exact
same conversation so it doesn't have the
exact date.
Okay.
So earlier you were talking about hide
your kids.
Hide your wife.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I'm that guy.
What happened to him?
Crazy.
Ladies and gentlemen,
joining us in the podcast is the one and
only the real cliffy be Yay.
Bazinsky.
Is that?
Am I saying it right?
Fresh off the plane.
If you don't know cliff,
he be a behind us is gears of war is
playing on the big screen in Casa de
Brionne and that is one of the
masterpieces from cliff ebb and a cliff.
He is a game designer for epic games and
that's been my friend for a long time.
We'd been friends for how long now?
It's like 10 years now.
Ten years bitches.
Thanks.
Joe.
Has a habit of basically going around to
a harsh light touch it.
Is this the one you find in a beer can
that's the most used and horribly sweaty
fleshlight you've ever,
ever had.
Puddles of yourself.
This is the flashlight.
This is a sponsor of our podcast.
Before we go any further,
that's fleshlight in a camp.
If you go to.
Yeah,
and apparently this one,
that's not the most effective one.
If you're just looking for something to
have sex with,
you might as well go with the standard
version.
The can.
One is more of a novelty item.
It is a fee.
You can get it done if you need to.
Look at is dripping with water.
You're disgusting human being.
You are wretched.
Brian went through a dry spell,
he broke up his girls like,
you know,
it's got excuses.
Oh Dude,
come on man,
stop it.
You're fucking freaking me out.
If you go to Joe Rogan,
did you go to Joe Rogan Net net?
Don't blame it on me,
man.
That's not cool.
Soda.
Cool.
You wipe it on your pillow.
Your dog's going.
Oh man,
we got problems.
Anyway.
Uh,
if you go to Joe Rogan.net,
the answer in a click the link for the
flashlight.
You have 15 percent off to enter
in the code word Rogan sort him.
I asked you every week,
and I always forget.
Anyway,
that's what that out of the way.
Cliff was nce lead game designer for
gears of war and so many other fucking
cool games.
Unreal a design director.
Now design director.
Is that a different thing?
I mean it's basically like if you can
prove yourself working on multiple
projects,
then you get to try and like sprinkle a
little bit of the magic fairy dust and
all the other projects we've got coming.
I don't know if you saw that one you
have.
What is it?
Well,
it's called bullets storm now what does
that kind of like a here's you remember
a firefly and serenity.
Those TV shows just weeding did kind of
like that guy.
I sort like remember seeing the ads.
I don't think I ever like a drunk and
space pirate who winds up crash landing
on a planet.
And you wind up using like a combination
of crazy guns and your boot to kind of
fight your way off the planet.
Oh yeah.
It's actually really fucking cool.
It's coming out in February.
Wow.
That sounds pretty good to go buy a
bunch of crazy Polish guys.
And uh,
I've been working on that a bunch gotta
get gotTa we got her iphone games
robbing this Thursday.
Oh,
what is it?
It's called Infinity Blade.
It's like punch out with swords.
Wow.
Iphone.
And uh,
will you be able to play against people?
Not yet.
First release is a,
just a one player,
but I mean,
the beauty of apple right now is you
have these updates,
right?
Everyone.
The PC days,
he used to be patches and you're like,
shit,
I gotta get patched.
The substance is broken now.
It's updates and you're like,
wow,
I'm getting it updated to gift.
It's like it's thing that people don't
appreciate if you came up in the old
windows days.
It's seamless.
Always works,
man.
I started out with windows 95 and I'm
sure you probably started way before
that.
I was showing her age dude.
Yeah,
windows 95 was the first pc that I ever
had and I remember one time I somehow or
another I did something somehow or
another I installed my operating system
onto one of those big drives where those
big stupid drives remember those things?
No,
it was like,
oh,
and there's zip,
zip drive.
Slow ones was a big one.
Like it was probably like one megabyte
or something stupid,
but it wasn't that big stone tablet.
Yeah,
it was giant.
This big fucking brick shit or another.
That became my startup drive.
I installed windows and then it took
like four days for your computer to boot
up.
Wouldn't boot up.
It was just chaos and so I had to bring
it into a guy who was a pc expert who
figured out what the fuck I would
retardation.
That guy later went into the geek squad
and he's a billionaire now.
Meanwhile,
technology's built money,
right?
Like anytime you have something like six
months later there's a new version that
comes out.
You're like,
damn,
I got to upgrade this.
They say that,
but I don't see it that way.
I think it's exciting.
I don't think of like people folks
because you know,
you know,
fucking the new shoots coming out and
they build it that way.
No,
they're just trying to catch up with the
ideas.
I think technology is moving at such a
fucking insane.
I got guys at work,
they have kids right now.
My,
my buddy Lee,
he's one of our designers.
He pulled his daughter aside and he's
like,
look,
things have gotten pretty cool in my
lifetime.
You have absolutely no idea the things
you're in for like where the world is
going like the world in 10,
15 years,
it's going to be completely
unrecognizable.
I agree.
It's
like from where we were as kids,
like you can't even imagine,
right?
Like with nanotechnology and everything.
It's unbelievable.
You and I,
I'm sorry,
you and I've had this conversation a
couple of times and one of the things
that you turned me onto his fucking
three d printers.
Yeah.
The idea that you're going to be able to
have certain elements inside of a
machine and you're going to be able to
print objects we've talked about on the
podcast before,
that you're not going to have to go to
stores to buy things no more than you
have to go to stores to get a picture.
You can download a picture.
I already hate going to the store now
dude.
Like you know,
you go to big box retail,
it takes like 45 minutes to find what
you want.
Like okay,
so now I use Amazon,
but if I can actually have a fabricator
at my house,
they can print out a pen like fine,
right?
Because they have the,
you have the,
like the wooden type ones right now that
kind of printed out of kind of like a,
like shaved material.
Right?
And you can just send him a three d
studio object and then they have metal
ones were just building metal object
just layer by layer.
And then eventually it's going to be the
way to manipulate whatever atoms,
molecules to build whatever you want out
of it.
It's unbelievable.
And that's coming online man.
And smart dust we were talking about.
Right.
That was another thing that you sent me
hip to.
It was um,
the.
Well explain the whole thing for people
who don't know what smart does at a very
high level,
because again,
I'm a bit of a luddite despite what I do
for living a,
it's a,
this kind of dust that they're able to
sprinkle out in the battlefield that
each one has a little bit of a
transmitter on it and they can detect if
anybody walks on it,
like any sort of footstep patterns on it
because it essentially creates a little
network that then sends back to base.
And then what happens is it can also
kind of catching peoples' shoes and a
little bit to their clothing.
You know,
there's just like little DNA bits you
would find with pieces of hair and a
crime scene and they can track whoever
actually has that autumn right.
Combined where technology's going with
the connectivity we have in the world
and it's.
It's really scary,
right.
We talked about the end of privacy as we
know it,
right?
How big are these things now?
They're tiny.
The size of a small grain of sand Motha
fucker and I don't know how many are
actually out there yet.
Right?
Like how much sand you get in your shoes
when you go to the beach.
I got a lot to you.
Imagine.
Could you imagine if all that sand.
You probably already have this right?
By the time we know about it,
I've always said about by the time we
hear about it,
that's been in use for years when they
talk about clones in my.
By the time they tell you they've cloned
the person,
the guy telling you is probably a clone.
Yeah.
I wonder how many technology role
totally used by the government that if
your average person knew about it,
result.
It's in the body spray.
I've gotten whole body sprays only for
douchebags.
That's why they want to track douchebag
activity thing when they step outside of
chimps,
when they do like medical studies on
test out Mascara on them and shit,
and that's what the old spice guy there
in the bathroom there.
By the way,
I'm an old spice guy or whatever's
cheapest.
Yeah,
whatever gets the job done and it has to
be white.
I'm not.
I need white deodorant.
The blue kind.
It's like,
do you work?
Do you do the antiperspirant?
Yeah,
I do.
I don't think that's a good thing for
your body.
Don't worry.
I don't.
I know I stink sometimes,
but I don't mind.
You know what?
What's important to me?
It was important to me that they don't
clog my pores up when they're trying to
leak out sweat.
What is that about?
Your just gumming up your pores like
sweat doesn't come out plugging them.
You're using some sort of fucking nasty
chemical that Jack's your whole,
your whole system.
How many people get armpit cancer?
If
I got armpit cancer,
I'd be like,
thank God I had the first at something.
I'm not,
I'm not scared of my sweat doesn't
bother me.
I'm sweaty all the time.
You do,
right.
That's the problem with once you start
working at a body cam.
So Harry,
because my chest is Harry too,
so with all funks in there and it gets,
you know,
skid,
get some sort of bacterial,
had day with your shirt off.
Not that bad,
but it's a lot of times too because all
the way it starts itching and it gets
caught in Jujitsu.
People pull your chest hair so you don't
wear deodorant,
but you shave your chest.
Oh,
sexy as fuck.
You're.
You're just doing what?
I want to shave my chest,
man.
I look at myself in the mirror.
I'm like ready for the French Riviera
Joe.
I don't shave my legs though.
I have no excuse to shave my legs.
I know some dudes who do because it gets
you out of submissions.
Easier.
Jujitsu guys,
while.
Yeah.
You're still hardcore into that.
Yeah,
that's fine.
Yeah.
What do you think this was at kraft
mega?
The crap out of that is really fighting
techniques.
I think if you wanted to just learn it
for self defense,
it's a good system because what they do
is they incorporate a lot of the best
techniques and ground fighting and they
incorporate a lot of the best techniques
to stand up for someone just looking to
defend themselves.
It gives you a pretty comprehensive view
of mixed of martial arts in general.
Look it up on Youtube,
man.
It's like half the videos or like how to
get out of a gun situation and half of
them are like legit guys through real
fast.
The other half of white up dead.
Yeah,
that's true.
But you know what?
At least you have a chance.
You know?
It's like if you have an idea of what to
do and someone was trying to get get you
with a gun,
most likely they're going to fucking
shoot you.
Right.
But at least you have some sort of an
idea.
If an opportunity presents a take,
take,
take control of it or not.
Right?
I mean like that's what the whole idea
of martial arts is about.
It's not that you're going to be able to
beat people up or you're gonna be able
to fight.
It's like at least you're gonna know
what's happening.
It was like the scariest thing about any
sort of an altercation is when you don't
know how to defend yourself.
You don't know what to do.
And I've seen guys,
I saw this guy got knocked the fuck out
once and it was crazy.
You're talking about like at a bar.
It was a bar and they got into a fight
and as they got into a fight,
one guy was just that.
He just went into a full panic and was
just swinging his hands.
He wasn't even making girls.
Yes,
yes.
Full Papo swing his hands and a car got
in front of me and as the car gun free
because people were trying to get out of
this parking lot while this fight was
going on and as the car got in front of
me,
as the car passed,
he was out cold on the ground.
Yeah,
flattened out first,
but it was a look in his eyes have
complete total panic.
He had no idea what to do.
He was locked into this situation.
It was on sunset.
You understand?
I mean,
you doing what you do with mma and
everything and being involved in the,
in the scene.
Like when I went to the,
I went to my first mma fight,
we saw the one in Charlotte,
right.
Sit there and watching UFC and I'm like,
you know,
I've seen it on at bars and I'm like
okay,
this is cool.
And seeing it in person,
getting a huge amount of respect for the
fighters and how tremendous athletes
these guys are.
Right?
But whatever,
uh,
you know,
living in Raleigh and seeing bar fights
which breakout in a regular basis,
they're not as bad as Boston by the way.
We need to talk about Boston dude.
That's the land of savages.
Twelve 30 hits and it's the witching
hour is too many ugly.
Angry women do their pissed to cf
summit.
But we'll get there.
We'll get there.
But like whenever I see a fight for
life,
dude,
if it,
unless it's two guys who were scrappers
Mandy see like one guy picks a fight
with the sky,
just nobody's doing.
I think it's really ugly shit man.
When you see somebody actually
legitimately get hit and beaten up like
that before the staff and get to them,
that's pretty fucked up.
When someone knows how to fight in the
other person doesn't.
I try to make friends with the biggest
motherfuckers and tenants could hide
behind people.
Notice,
notice when the shit's about to hit the
fan and know where the door is all
important.
You can smell it,
man.
Yeah.
And they think about someone who does
train in martial arts.
Most of the time you don't want to fight
because it's not the same thing anymore.
A good bouncer.
You know how to diffuse the situation,
right?
You're not looking at cracks.
Skulls.
It's not just that.
It's like you kinda.
It's not attractive.
You know,
for some guys the idea of beating
someone's asked is like attractive.
But when you do martial arts all the
time,
it's not attractive at all.
It doesn't seem like a thing to do.
It seems like,
you know,
what you want to do is avoid all that.
This is a stupid.
This can get.
You can get hurt,
like you don't have any need to prove
yourself physically were a lot of people
do and unfortunately sometimes they just
trying to bluff,
you know,
and they get called out on it.
They don't know what to do.
They're already at step nine.
They don't know how that got there
because they're in Toronto.
Right.
And then you know,
and then they say,
well I to hear this guy and they go to
take a swing in the horror upon horrors
is when you throw a punch at a guy and
he moves,
he actually knows how to fight and he's
sober.
Then you're fucked because then you're
drunk and you did a Douche bag thing and
some guys going to let you up.
Next thing you know,
you're on the side of the street
bleeding.
They're bleeding.
Or from my experience,
I mean there's always going to be
assholes that do martial arts,
like just assholes to do everything,
but it's much,
much smaller.
Number,
so the odds of someone who wants to
fight actually being a martial artist,
most of the time they're not.
It's a big misconception like these guys
that are filing George Saint Pierre
who's like one of the nicest guy you're
ever going to meet and even Josh
Koscheck,
the guy who's fighting him this weekend,
fucking great guy.
If you're not fighting him.
I mean he likes to talk a lot of shit
and likes to like get inside guys heads,
but a lot of that's pre-fight high.
But outside of that he's a very nice.
A lot of those guys beat the shit out of
each other and then they just the end,
they're just kinda like,
what's.
Because it's a mutually kind of assumed
destruction,
right?
They're like,
okay,
I'm going into this.
That's my profession,
right?
It's that.
And some guys get real caught up in the
shit talking and some guys,
some guys,
they drop it as soon as the fight's over
and you know,
you see them,
they'll go out and have beers and shit.
It's like,
you know,
look,
there's a certain amount of stress
involved in this person's your target.
You're going to be some animosity,
you know,
but for the most part they'd like
resolve it way better than boxers do
know.
Boxers seem to be on,
I don't know what it is,
but there's like more douchebags in the
boxing community.
I'm not exactly sure what that was like
five,
eight years ago and it was considered
that nice thing and that that's always
the way with any sort of any sport,
right?
Looking snowboarding.
And that was all the skiers looked down
on,
like that's a joke.
That's never going to be big a doubt.
Snowboarding's Frickin huge.
Right?
That happens with so many different
sports.
Right.
When I was first involved in mma,
it was almost like telling people that I
was involved in porn,
like,
yeah,
because I was working on Newsradio.
Right.
And uh,
and by the way,
I'm not the only one who said this.
Dana White said the exact same thing.
He said the exact,
the exact same feeling.
You feel like you're doing something
sleazy.
I say video games,
dude.
No,
no.
Okay.
Dude.
When I was like,
okay,
this is my story.
I was on news radio and I started doing
the backstage university UFC and this
was 1997,
so this is like we were in Augusta,
Georgia and dove in Alabama and places
like that and I would tell them that I
was off to go do commentary for cage
fighter and they would look at me like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
This is terrible for your career.
You want,
you want people to know that you're,
you're commentating on cage fighting.
You know?
It's like,
it was almost like I was doing girls
gone wild or something.
The video game analogy though,
I mean it's not a one to one,
but at the same time it was one of the
situations like,
you know,
10,
15 years ago was like,
you want to do that?
And it's like,
oh,
that's cute.
You know,
my,
my little son plays that in the
basement.
Right?
And now it's one of those things.
You look at everything from the three 60
that we to Natal and Oh,
I see what you're saying,
but it doesn't have a negative
connotation.
Does it not ever used to.
Now it's the coolest fucking drop and it
was,
it used to,
it was more of a frivolous connotation,
not a negative,
it wasn't negative,
it was more of a pat submissive.
Okay.
You run along little billy with your
little video games thing because he used
to play pong.
Right?
Right.
But now there's games like call of duty
that make more money,
way more than Avatar and that like,
that needs to sink into people's.
Had they go to the difference of $6 day
one versus,
you know,
10 bucks,
right.
Immediately takes,
you know,
not as many people to do it.
Right.
I mean they are getting so good at
building up the hype for these midnight
launches for all of this.
Right?
Like,
I mean,
the biggest issue right now is how much
of that money you think the actual
developers are saying?
I don't know necessarily a lot.
There's a lot of controversy about call
of duty.
I don't know if you heard the whole
thing,
please tell him is.
So basically the call of duty guys
originally were uh,
these guys,
uh,
from infinity ward and Jason and fence.
Real good guys.
And they,
uh,
had originally built this brand after
working on metal of honor because they
built up metal of honor and then that
didn't work out for a number of reasons.
You can look all this up.
They built the call of duty brand up and
then basically a modern warfare hit,
made a ton of money.
They basically didn't see much of it and
then they were like,
screw you,
we're going to go do our own thing.
It's a very controversial thing with a
lot of lawsuits and everything like
that.
Um,
I just,
I stayed on the site generally that the
developers,
because I believe in developers,
riots,
I believe paying people what they're
worth.
And when you create a multimillion
dollar to potentially billion dollar
brand,
you deserve to be paid for it.
Right?
So the issue is that the people that
finance it or getting the majority of
about the large studio,
uh,
activision basically,
from what I can tell again,
this is secondhand knowledge.
You know,
the guys basically did not feel that
they were paid what we're worth for
because when they have contracts,
once your studio is purchased and you're
part of a larger conglomerate,
your game can make a billion dollars and
they could just give your studio,
have half a million,
it'd be like,
fine,
we own you,
like whatever,
like,
yeah,
and I don't know what the numbers are,
but you're increasingly seeing in the
video game industry,
people getting a lot of representation,
people getting a agents,
they're people you know,
getting a proper accountants and lawyers
and they're actually negotiating this
sort of thing.
So,
you know,
people like Warren Spector,
her created Datastax,
people like Ken Levine who created
bioshock.
They've got deals now.
They're making amazing games and they're
going to make sure that they and their
staff are taking good care of.
Right.
I remember back in the day when,
uh,
John Ramirez,
it was broke off from id software and
that was like the first drama in the
game community that this Guy John
Romero,
who's the game designer splits from this
Guy John Carmack,
who's this fucking super from another
planet
wizard guy.
Yeah.
He's the one of very few dudes.
When I'm around them,
I get intimidated.
Yeah.
Like when I'm talking to John Carmack,
I'm like,
why am I even talking about talking to
this guy?
Did you ever fucking alien?
Yeah.
Same sort of thing.
This whole lake one in a billion type of
personality genius alien do right.
Like it's amazing.
I thought another level than all of us
and carmax would sit in front of the
computer for people who don't know who
he is,
16 hours a day code and then he would go
make rocket scientist in his spare time.
Right.
It was involved with the x prize and I
was like trying to win the x prize.
That's his hobby.
And when he wasn't doing that,
he was turbo charging Ferrari's,
building turbo charges for Ferrari.
It's a big no,
no,
by the way,
right there,
like if it's like,
it's like buying a Mona Lisa and just
painting over it,
right?
Yes.
But he just doesn't have no reverence
for any objects.
He's like,
fuck you.
But it has an alien with the rumor was
that like after he started doing that,
that Ferrari kind of was like,
dude,
what are you?
Come on,
like we're undermining all of our
engineers here.
You,
our,
he still fucking with that shit.
He was making like these 12,000
horsepower Ferrari's fucking nuclear
energy die.
Oh,
for sure.
Well he apparently was really nutty
thrill seeker.
He used to really like to go really
fast,
which is.
Yeah.
What happened was we cannot expect he
left id software.
The guys that do do this.
John Romero guy to get back to this
story.
This guy was like the playboy character.
It was like rock docstar and you know,
and then they left.
And what was that crazy game that they
came out with afterwards when they did
an acronym and diatonic diatonic that
was the one.
So they.
So he leaves and you know,
it was like sort of a cult of
personality thing.
Oh yeah.
There was.
The big debate was who was the most
important,
is that the game designers have a guy
with the vision or is it the coder and
how easy it is to actually design the
games.
The game designers often the chaos and
the programmer or producers usually the
order,
right.
It's a combination of those two persons
saying what's the best part of the band?
Is it the singers and the drummers get.
If you get the singer who could be on
stage and be charismatic,
you know,
you get David Lee Roth but you don't
have Eddie van Halen backing them up.
Right.
You don't have the magic.
And the example,
he wasn't in Van Halen on his own,
on his own.
It was just David Lee Roth.
He's gone,
he's doing some cool stuff now.
Man.
He's great.
He's a great guy.
I've met him.
I met him at the comedy store,
was one of the fucking coolest celebrity
meetings I've ever had ever.
But my point was that,
you know,
as a group,
those guys created some pretty fucking
dope games,
doom,
they created as a group.
And the idea was that it was all this
guys.
So this guy leaves and he gets this
giant fucking deal.
Is John Romero,
did you visit the Dallas Office?
No,
but I heard it was insane.
It was like the top floor with a
unbelievable views.
Just stupid,
crazy overhead.
Right?
This is legendary gaming history you're
talking about.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well this is how much of a Dork I am
about this shit.
And um,
he uh,
he gets crazy,
crazy money and then to just lazy as
fuck and they just barely working,
man.
This game like takes forever to come
out.
It comes out all wonky and shit.
And you walk through walls.
That's an abbreviated version man.
But I mean,
the thing is,
is he,
he assembled a team so fucking fast and
try to be so ambitious so quick.
And that was with [inaudible] money.
This is basically the Lara Croft tomb
raider paying for this.
Right?
And so once you build a team that
quickly,
like you can't just overnight assemble a
bunch of people,
I can Hollywood and have magic,
right?
And so half,
not half,
but a good percentage of the guys I work
with,
my fucking art director,
who's this amazingly talented,
awesome guy,
bled out of the eyeballs to ship.
I katata he went to work for mirror
because he thought Ramiro was a cool
guy,
but he still tells me stories about
having panic attacks in Dallas and how
he almost killed himself to Christ.
And so like I always look at that and
realize how much you guys work dude.
It's like if you look around the room,
right?
Every little bit,
somebody has to work and build every
last little bit of it.
When we visited you and you were talking
about when crunch time comes into,
it's like right at the end and
everybody's like basically sleeping at
the office.
That's all you do is you work with all
dense.
Gotten better than that with like we've,
we figured out how to make games better
now.
Like you get a producer who knows his
shit and it's kind of like,
okay,
we're not just gonna all work really
hard to hope it turns out great.
We're going to actually have a plan.
Right?
So if you say when it's done,
that doesn't mean you really know what
game you're building.
At the same time,
you need to have a little bit of wiggle
room because it's not.
It's not a like a a definable process.
You're,
you're,
you're panning for gold,
you're trying.
It's comedy.
I like comedy.
You iterate,
right?
It's so comprehensive though.
I mean people don't understand what goes
into making a game that just the amount
of effort.
I remember we were exhausted leaving
thinking about the hours that you guys
work,
but remember we were talking about it,
but dude,
you can't burn through people that much.
Right?
You could maybe get away with a few
crunches like that.
So we're the point where it will do
maybe 10 hours a day,
12 tops,
five days a week tops,
and then we,
we,
we call it.
We're like,
dude,
if we just say it's not worth it,
be smart.
You know,
because we're over 40 dude.
Yeah.
They just got fried,
right?
Yeah.
That's interesting.
I'll tell you about that dike atonic
thing though,
even though it was like a long time.
It was a fun game to play.
Man.
Deathmatch deathmatch was fun on it.
They had some cool to cool rocket,
crazy weird rocket launcher.
They haven't had a shotgun that had like
18 barrels or something like that.
It was.
They had some cool shit.
You know,
Romero was like supposedly like he was
into first person shooters and death.
Magical.
It was him.
It was him in Carmel and that whole crew
that just birthed the genre.
It's one of the lessons I tell the guys,
if you have a new camera angle,
you can create a whole new genre.
The first quake was a fucking
masterpiece for like death match.
Brian says you're still hung up on it.
Oh,
well I'm still hung up on all games,
but not really quick to quick to never
really got me.
But quake one dude.
The only thing that got me about quick
too,
as the rail gun,
that was very key because when.
That's when accuracy,
it became very.
You know what your problem,
the fact that with quake two to actually
balanced the weapons.
No,
no,
I just didn't like the way it felt.
It just didn't feel as good.
It wasn't as fast paced.
It was a little slower.
Whereas quake one,
you can move much quicker.
It was much more like chaotic place.
The numbers,
it has to be point seven seconds or
less.
What it is is that I just really love
death match.
That's what I really love.
That's all I played in college.
A team death match.
Like anytime it comes up with any sort
of domination and CTF,
might I just want to shoot people.
How do you feel about those things that
hook up to a console and give you a
mouse and a keyboard of those good.
I mean they're,
they're cool and all.
But do you.
I mean the thing about halo is
they built the game of halo for that
dual stick controller and if you're a pc
guy is used to that level of accuracy.
It feels like you're like drunkenly
using like a rubber hose to a your car.
But if you build a game for it,
it can work.
And that's what halo did.
Golden,
I did it before that.
But you look at Halo,
they basically introduced a genre that
was new to a whole generation of kids.
I have this whole 10 year rule where
like the kids who played halo,
most of them,
many of them didn't play a lot of quake
because they're like,
wait,
what does this new xbox thing?
I'm gonna play this.
And then they become hooked.
It's like the.
We talked about vampires on the way
over.
It's like,
okay,
well all these kids who love twilight
don't know what buffy the vampire slayer
is.
So,
but if you wait 10 years,
right?
Your kid who liked buffy the vampire
slayer or you're a person who likes a
twilight.
They were what like,
you know,
six when buffy came out and now they're
16.
And so they,
they didn't know about that.
So you can basically wait every 10 years
and find something that was old and make
it new.
And then if you can introduce it with
new technology,
you might be good to go.
Yeah.
Um,
for people who don't know what we're
talking about,
those a hand controllers,
the consoles,
when you have a console,
you have xbox or playstation,
what they are,
that's most people are listening on
Itunes,
the same help,
but he's holding one up but they have a
bunch of buttons on it.
And with,
with pcs,
when you play with a computer,
when you play online,
especially your,
what you're using is a keyboard and the
mouse and what it is is for whatever
reason,
the keyboard and the mouse,
you can just control it better.
You're far more accurate,
you're accurate with the keyboard as far
as your movement,
having four very specific buttons,
right where your fingers are and you're
much more accurate with your hand as far
as like aiming.
And that's where it came into play with
games like quake is like aim,
especially when the rail gun came about
and became very,
very important.
So how do they optimize these games for
these controls?
Do they have auto aim or something?
You get close,
you're in the neighborhood of it and
it'll.
There was one of the things that halo
did was they kind of introduced this
idea of friction and adhesions,
so what you do is if you,
when you move your,
your console kind of stick over the
enemy.
The game actually slows down a little
bit.
Like it's like,
oh,
you want to hit them,
don't you?
And then it provides a little bit of
that kind of assistance.
Right.
That would drive me crazy.
Whole generation loves it right now.
Those fucks,
those lazy constant march what it is,
they don't even want to aim these
fucking kids that a self righteous and
titled Children Back when we were
acquired,
we aim.
It was a pixel.
That dude,
that's what it was,
right?
Your crosshair was this one pixel and
you had to shoot.
That guy's edbd had across the map,
except for in quake one where you had to
just hit them with a rocket launcher.
The had radius of half a mile.
That was the cool thing about quick too
is a lot of people would put their own
crosshairs in.
They would build their own cross hairs,
but quick three that came out of the
box,
like a bunch of cool ones,
you know,
like figure out what was the best for
you.
Like I would have different ones for the
rail gun,
different ones for the rocket launcher.
It's all.
It's all customization,
but it's insanity is what it is.
I can't.
It's a constant subject on this fucking
side.
Do you trust the pots or whatever it is?
Millions and millions of kids that are
perfectly fine with the two sticks and
they're going to grow up pussies.
We are.
We're entering what I like to say,
we're entering into the feedback list
generation,
right?
Those kids growing up
with those consoles,
this is the last,
the fall of Rome.
This was when they were getting drunk
and throwing up and trying to get more
food in that sort of is gluttony.
He touched him.
Joe,
look at touch screens.
Look at,
look at connect.
We're getting to a point where people
don't need buttons right now,
which you,
right?
Is that what's going to happen?
Is it going to be like gaming with your
fingers and.
Shit like pointing where you want to do
the Microsoft thing is Ryan,
isn't it?
That's.
Yeah,
that's what is that called?
Connect men connect.
Yeah.
You don't need a controller and you.
You stand in front of it and move
around.
I guess you haven't.
Have you heard much about this?
This is not that much.
I know this is going to trip you out,
so it's a camera that can track your
body movements without anything on you.
You've seen the motion capture systems,
right?
You know the type that would set up with
whereas a spandex and all that.
This is a very light version of that
where you just stand in front of the TV
and it can procedurally form your
skeleton and then track that.
So there's a dance game.
Dance Central,
which is a ton of fun.
Just playing with my niece over the
holidays.
You literally just dance right in front
of it attracts your movement.
It can judge your score.
Here's where it gets weird.
There is a video,
like a microphone on it so it can do
voice recognition and it's got facial
recognition on it.
So once you do the facial recognition
thing,
which makes you stay out of the room to
kind of build an aggregate of your face,
it,
you then can just walk in the room.
It goes,
why hello cliff,
look,
oh Jesus fucking Christ.
I smoke too much weed for that dude.
I don't want my computer talking to me.
You know what I want to see.
I want to see imax movies like screens
like where you walk in and you're all
sitting there in the video game.
So there's like 500 people all joining
in plain.
This huge video game
in front of you,
like I told you about from doing
standup.
He said,
my friend John [inaudible] has been
doing these conference stand up.
Things were there in front of it,
some new technology where they get them
in a room and he's got all these screens
in front of them and they see him and he
sees them live and he does standup.
Really?
He's like,
he's doing a desk in front of like all
these monitors.
So he gets to see the reaction like yes,
two way video.
So he's watching the reaction.
They're watching him live,
it's like he's performing on stage,
but he's nowhere near that.
We're talking the shit.
I would love that if I could do shows
from my house and not have to travel all
the time.
That was good.
You Judge People's reactions,
right?
I mean that's what we're talking about
iteration,
right,
and how much we panned for gold and we
try and find fun and we fail a bunch
before we figured out what it is.
I mean,
talk about Jerry Seinfeld's comedian,
how much comedy they.
They go to the little dive bars and they
do a surprise appearance and they just
bomb and then they figure out,
okay,
this joke work.
That one didn't work,
this one did.
Right?
It's,
we find it's the same thing with game
development.
I know people in the restaurant business
that try new menus,
they figure out what works and does it.
It's all iteration.
Nobody.
Very few people ever actually nail it
right the first time.
Right.
We'll fail early and fail often,
which I found is the key to so many
instances of success in life.
Right?
Well,
you fail and then you find out what you
don't like about what failed.
Yep.
No,
and that's how you learn.
Absolutely.
You have to learn what you do and don't
like and when you're doing something
complicated,
there's a lot of failure involved.
For sure.
Keyboard man.
It's a,
it's still relevant but you know,
it's the market split between fall
between des,
between like I see no controller is very
important.
I think like making it so it could be,
you could do just sit there and do that.
What I don't like though is when a lot
of times I just want to sit back and
play a video game in bed or I'm just
trying to run through the forest.
I don't,
you don't want to sweat,
you don't,
you just want to,
you want to lay back and just sit there
with the controller display,
right?
You don't have to jump around like an
idiot.
Right.
I sit here and go like this though,
like tron style and just move my hands
like Doo Doo.
I'm going through.
When they're working on type stuff like
minority report,
where are you gonna?
Be able to just keep it like that so you
don't have to like mark.
There's a certain percentage of person,
a lot of them out there,
especially girls.
If you handled the current console
controller,
they act like you handed them a flaming
bag of dog shit.
Right?
Like really?
I'm supposed to use this for what?
Like I don't want to play this and
granted there are some exceptions,
but most people,
parents like you're met with cliff.
He being.
That's a year old girl voice.
That was a nine.
That's your becky voice.
Oh my God.
Yeah,
exactly.
And it's such an asshole.
He is play a game.
The.
We have this whole theory that there's a
certain type of girl that somehow gets
that voice preloaded into her with that
bubbled writing.
I think they just imitate everybody
else.
It's like,
why?
Why would anybody have that fucking
horrible Boston accent?
Why?
Because a bunch of other people have and
they just imitate it still.
I still miss it though,
Dude.
Do you really?
How dare you,
dude.
I agree.
I had a great time growing up.
I miss it with as far as dudes.
You know,
you don't like the girls know Jesus
Christ.
Some of the most horrendous experiences
in my life came out of a female Boston
accent.
Yeah,
get some.
Just gets too cold.
Yeah.
We had this experience where a buddy of
a buddy of ours was in Boston.
He hooked up with some chicken while
they're fooling around.
She goes,
he tell you friends,
wait a monster sound.
It was just hideous and he just fucking
swinging it.
And I got a buddy of mine.
He dated a girl from Long Island and
they woke up the next morning and he
asked her what she wanted for breakfast
and see what count.
Chocula dude.
So I took Lauren back to see my
hometown.
Right.
Like I had to blackboard.
What town did you grow up with that over
north andover?
Yeah.
I mean it's totally like Nice suburbs,
right?
Like really?
Like we went up in the fall,
false.
All the foliage,
like the local farm standard.
Rob is a kid is like this now,
like national.
What month was this?
Was October.
Late October is good.
Was right before it gets horrible,
horrible,
horrible.
And I'm sitting there and there's
something about certain sections of the
northeast that just kind of take
something out of you.
I don't know if it's the Diet or the
weather,
but there's a certain tiredness that
kind of creeps in.
Man.
I don't know what it is.
Lack of vitamin D to lack of vitamin D.
But there's something about the weather.
You know,
Italian food cold.
Yeah.
It's not supposed to be that cold for
that long.
We're just sucks.
Well,
you just assume that every year for four
months it's going to suck to be outside.
But I grew up.
You grew up with it,
right?
Like I grew up and I had to get my.
I do a paper route as a kid.
Right.
Me Too.
And they deliver it and they deliver it
in like a.
They deliver the papers.
In November,
the snow would hit and I'd get up at
10:00
AM to do my paper and the,
the it all be plowed over it.
And I have.
My papers aren't there.
I'm like,
I guess they didn't deliver my calling
for a refill sometime around late March,
early April.
That would thaw out and I would find the
papers for March,
like a time capsule and I'm sitting here
going,
is this how it is?
Because my dad loved him dearly but he
was super cheap about the heat and he'd
like it 90 turn off and like in the
Monday morning getting up and going to
school.
Oh,
it's the worst.
Like getting into that shower man.
Oh,
we used to have to use a hairdryer to
unf on clog the pipes.
The pipes would freeze.
Yep.
So my dad had like this opening
underneath the floor in the basement and
he would have to lift up this opening
and it'd be sitting there with a fucking
hairdryer before anybody could take a
shower.
But we retaliate who's retarded?
We grew up,
my dad decided one year he was going to
buy a coal stove that was going to like
take care of all this.
Right.
So he gets it installed and literally
like a one folly as two tons of coal
put,
like put it in the basement.
Right.
And we literally have to go down there
with a hopper and like bring it up
there.
And you have to hold your breath,
otherwise you get black lung basically.
And we come up and like this thing he
did like two square feet of the whole
house.
So if you want it to stay warm,
you stayed in the living room and just
hovered right in front of that thing.
Oh yeah.
We had four.
I got four of the brothers,
man,
I've grown up with that in one house and
it was a decent size house.
But one of the.
What's that?
I'm sorry.
I had central air.
You're spoiled.
How old are you?
What do you like?
Fuck is wrong with you.
Shit.
Huh?
One of the houses I looked at in
Colorado had one of those wood heating
stove in the middle of the living room
and they were talking about how
economical it is to use this wood
heating stove to keep the house warm.
I'm like,
what are you fucking talking about?
Hooker?
I got kids and you've got a giant red
hot ball of metal and the center of the
living room,
but they're just supposed to avoid.
Dude.
I used to say I was a kid.
I used to take prongs with the hot coals
and take them out aside from the living
room,
like through the hallway and go into the
snow,
like write my name with a blazing hot
cold.
Like how did that not like drop this on
my foot and burn myself.
Right.
I don't know.
But in 2010 they should eliminate that
stupid shit and get a God damn heater
when you've got a fucking giant cast
iron fucking in the middle of the rope.
That was not common at all.
Well you guys are talking about like,
I didn't know anybody that had columbus
gets pretty cold though.
Man didn't have central heat or air.
They're like,
dude,
what is this lake?
The technology I guess can old heating
and cooling in Ohio was better than.
Well No,
Columbus doesn't get death cold though.
Right?
What is,
what is winter?
What is it like a terrible January got
negative 10.
That's the real shit.
That's cool.
So yeah,
I grew up with who are brothers,
right?
And we had to share a lot of shit.
And so like we have to share towels in
the bathroom.
We only had a certain amount,
we all took the golden lion and take
showers.
Right,
and I'm sitting there one day and I get
out of the shower after my older brother
and I take the towel and I'm kind of
wipe my face and it's a light color
towel and I realized the towels smells
like ass.
Oh Jesus Christ.
I pull away and I'm telling this story
to his daughter recently.
She's like a little eight year old kid
and her dad and I looked at the towel
and I realized there's Brown streaks in
the towel.
Oh my God.
This explaining to his daughter that
this is a double fail because not only
did
not remember to wash his ass,
like he forgot to like wipe right and
asked my niece.
I'm like,
what's the,
what's the lesson out of the story?
And she says by dark towels,
I'm like,
no,
you're doing eight.
That's brilliant.
You're doing it wrong.
No,
that kid keep an ironer.
She's Brown and red towels.
Ideal match for me.
That's.
I would never thought of that in a
million years.
Have you seen that?
That's a great line.
You understands the genes and true story
dude.
Great Line,
right?
They have to tell.
He can buy online.
It's like one half is brown.
One half is a white and says face and
ass.
It's like a split title.
I it in my bathroom was good reminder.
I would want a brown towel that looked
like,
like a dexter splatter of blood on it
and that was the design of the towel bar
that you can actually bite dexter is a
shirt.
The kill a thermally.
Where's?
Yeah.
Do you.
Did you do?
Did you give up on Dexter Joe?
Mrs Rogan's really intuit though,
so I'm going to have to try again dude.
Even though John Lithgow that quit
because of John Lithgow,
shitty rear naked choke,
John Lithgow get some woman getting her,
gave her the fucking weakest bitch as
rear naked choke I've ever seen in my
life.
I'm like,
no,
that's not going to kill anybody.
That's me stopping watching a TV show
because they're holding the controller
wrong.
When you try to kill people,
man,
they fight.
They fight back.
The cloche you,
they kicked,
they try hard.
They don't just lay in the tub and go
while you're choking them.
Your little fucking old man arms didn't
even put any pressure on that thing.
Amazing that season,
dude.
And you know welders on the season.
Have you seen him lately?
He looks like the most.
I didn't even read that again.
Who's a cop?
Robocop first.
Rub it and you're just like,
oh my God,
dude.
I don't know.
He looks like the sleazy,
amazing.
Like Miami pd guy.
He looks great.
It's still a good show in spite of the
bad choke holds.
Okay,
well I'll give it a second chance.
Watch walking dead.
No,
but I've heard.
That's pretty awesome.
It's the end was a little bit,
but say that.
Then I got nothing to look forward to.
Frank Darabont fire the entire writing
staff.
Whoa.
Yeah.
He's a guy.
He did shawshank redemption.
Green Mile.
Right.
Wow.
Fired the whole staff.
It's hard to find fucking good writers.
That one right.
Your Shit.
Yeah.
No good writers want to write their own
shit.
Yeah.
Well let's just say.
Well,
I've had people approach me and they're
like,
hey,
we were doing this a dual ip and we want
epic to make the game.
I'm like,
dude,
we do our own stuff,
man.
Like we can either create our own thing
like years or we could do like the star
trek movie video game.
What's going to happen?
Right,
right.
We're not going to run inspiring.
Nobody gives a fuck about those stupid
movie video.
There's the occasional exception.
That's a good one,
you know,
but it's hard to make like a superman
for the Nintendo 64 game.
Every etf for Atari to have my feet,
you know,
that's very desert,
right?
They actually,
oh yeah,
that's one of the craziest stories and
urban legend story.
It was the,
the video game,
right?
And the Atari Twenty 600 and they
basically assumed it would sell millions
of copies and it sold like five.
Oh my goodness.
Decided to like bury out in the New
Mexico desert and they actually is still
out there.
They buried it,
buried it.
Why
did it?
Because I don't know.
I guess they didn't confront somebody
better and whatever disposal economics,
huge landfill filled with that game and
in fact many of them I don't actually
know that you can look it up and we'd
meet.
What's the urban legend though?
Well,
people think it's an urban legend,
but it's actually true,
but what is the number in the urban
legend?
It's millions,
millions,
millions because they hired some
programmer.
It had to make the game over the course
of a month.
That's the license we can print.
It will make money,
right?
Like no,
you actually have to make a good game.
Like the new call of duty was done by
the second team,
which previously had made a very solid
one a couple of years ago and it had
made a one a few years ago that wasn't
as good,
but they have really stepped it up.
This new one.
It like,
I didn't even play the campaign,
man.
You did.
You play it much?
No,
I've never played it.
It's true.
You should give it a government.
I know you have dual analog fear.
Can't do it.
You have to try.
You have to at least give him some time.
What's going to happen with all the
shooters are like emotional funnels.
I guess I'll play pool.
You gotta.
Imagine going like this and playing
pool.
You don't even need a pool table.
No,
no,
no.
You need a pool table,
bro.
That's the whole game.
The whole game was.
Did any of them feel the ball contact
the queue?
It's either feel the ball and how much,
how much effort you put into your
stroke,
how relaxed your grip is.
Keep your shit together.
It's kind of stroke that ball son.
You'll change the mind trying some
different things.
All right.
How do you do different things?
Uh,
I don't know.
It's Disney.
So it cost them 100.
And did,
did you move to 150 million?
Do you know the guy who directed it is
the guy who did the first gears
commercial?
The mad world one where really?
Yeah,
that was a joke.
Fucking commercial was awesome.
It was.
I remember when that commercial was
coming out before gears came out,
I saw it on tv and I went,
whoa.
Like they just nailed it.
It's a song as a perfect song to that
song was actually one of my favorite
songs,
but I was going through all that up on
youtube,
right parental pull it up.
That was one of my,
like I was going through really tough
time at that point.
They actually didn't even know about
that,
so why don't you just call me.
I would've snapped you out of it.
That's ridiculous.
Don't listen to that kind of music when
you that kind of mood.
I was that movie.
That's a good song for
good mood to go.
Wow.
That's kind of a cool song.
The last thing you want is when
depressing ass fucking song when you're
in a shit mood.
You remember it was a remake of the
tears for fears song,
right?
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
It was a remake of softball and it
caught a faulty off auto Kaunas side and
then they just did.
Gary joules redid it.
It was like number one in the UK over
the course of the holidays when it came
out and then it had another like rebump
like that.
Put that commercial,
put that song back the top of itunes for
like a month.
What's that game was the last game that
I played with on a console.
It's the last day you didn't like your
student?
No,
I played gears one.
I fucking loved the way it looked.
I loved everything about it,
but that fucking thing was driving me
crazy.
Trying to move around and look what this
stupid controller and I'm like,
why is this have a mouse and keyboard?
It will be so much easier.
Like if I had a mouse keyboard,
shit touching some fucking ass up in
this bitch where it's just.
It's,
Oh,
is gay already?
Get this away from me.
This away from me.
You can't even.
Don't
be a gaming dinosaur.
I am dude.
Also,
the second one they did was called the
last day.
That was for curious to who?
I like those features that was
aching.
He Zoom in,
right.
Left trigger.
Right.
Trigger is so slow.
Can you adjust the sensitivity in the
mouse?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well it looks fucking spectacular.
You're missing out.
I'm missing out on a lot of things,
man.
I'm not skydiving.
I'm not climbing rocks.
That was all I needed to do.
Brian's got a great story about his dad.
We tandem set up a couple of times,
but it's an interesting story.
I'll tell it because he's told it twice.
His father,
um,
had a person at work that was always
saying used to go skydiving with me.
I go skydiving.
I love it.
She used to go all the time.
Well,
she fucking died.
Really?
She fell out of a plane and her shit
didn't work and their second shit caught
up in her first shit that didn't work.
Clatsop fucking went screaming to the
ground from 10,000
feet in the air and slammed into the
earth.
Ending her time here.
Fuck that noise about it.
That afraid of death.
I'm afraid of the screaming before
knowing the sense of we're not even four
minutes.
How much time does it take?
Terminal Velocity?
Ten thousand feet.
I'm sure you could just figure it out.
Three hundred 80 miles an hour.
Three minutes,
three minutes of terror.
It look up a gears of war.
Mad World Zero.
That's what it was.
Nobody.
It seems like a lot of to have it on
youtube so you can just assume that if
something's out there,
it's on youtube now.
If you ever actually want to find,
try and find somebody official music
video.
Good fucking luck.
Because what they'll do is they upload a
video where it's like,
hey,
here's what I think of Nicki Minaj,
this new song,
and it's like Nicki Minaj official
video.
You Click on it,
they use the thumbnail to make it look
like it's the video.
And then some guy showing,
talking about.
You're like,
can I actually find this frigging thing?
Like usually the one that's actually has
millions of hits is like the last one to
actually appear.
What's up dog?
This is it right here.
This is the ad.
Damn.
I want to watch it man.
Tell these fuckers that.
Go on Youtube.
It really changed the game for a lot of
video game advertising.
Fuck Yeah Dude.
Dude.
A lot.
Also,
you guys raised the bar so high as far
as the graphic appearance of game when
we were in your uh,
we came into your office.
It was,
I guess it was like two years before
this came out and you guys were deep
deep in development.
You had all these crazy models and all
these,
you know,
it was mostly just demonstrations of the
technology,
but you know,
I remember asking you like,
what are you guys up to?
Like,
what's going on?
And you're like,
we're about to take a big fat shit on
dual Dr Berman tonight.
And then uh,
then I went,
oh wow.
And I watched it and like the,
especially the light,
like a lot of the shit you had was like,
demonstrations.
How the flash hiders go is that was
awhile.
It says 40.
Think about where technology is going to
be in a few years,
man.
It's going to be insane.
Like if,
if,
if Sonia Microsoft getting around
actually making next generation
consoles,
like imagine what that's going to be
like,
what is the bottleneck?
I want it personally.
I want,
I want some avatar quality stuff,
real time like that.
Imax,
imax theaters.
Imagine that concert where you're all
together in a
world of warcraft everyday.
Everyone would just plug into their
computer and be some sort of an Elf.
We'd just wandering through the forest
and we'd all turn into the apartment on
South Park with a whale episode.
What's that fucking dangerous thing
we're doing here?
Because if we make games more exciting
and way fucking cooler than real life,
it gets weird.
It's like it's a brain that's getting
hooked up,
right?
Well,
the scary thing is what happens when we
can download consciousness into a
computer singularity.
She is too.
I want to live in fucking Avatar,
man.
You know?
Well,
you do about the whole thing about the
singularity where I sure Ray Kurzweil
and all that,
right?
Like it's,
it's,
I,
I have a feeling that's within our
lifetime.
For those of you that don't know,
Brian's little butter dog is attacking
me right now with sweat.
You know what a butter dog is?
No serious slugs.
I bet that Joe.
No.
What's a buddy of mine?
He came in,
he's a photographer from New York.
One time we were doing a photo shoot for
magazine and he's telling me how much he
hated dating in New York City.
I'm like,
well,
why?
He's like,
well,
there's a certain type of girl in the
city who's given up on the dating scene
and she has what's called a butter dog,
and I'm like,
what?
Like she's a good girl,
but her dogs annoying.
No.
It turns out that this type of girl,
and this might be an urban legend,
he might've been fucking with me,
but it sounded the way nut butter.
Their boyfriend is their little dog with
a little tongue,
a little peanut butter and then that's
their boyfriend for an hour now.
So anybody who's from New York and
confirm or deny this,
if it's an urban legend,
I would love to know.
It's just a regional thing in Manhattan.
It's your message boards that we can
meet and greet other peers of enjoy
everything,
but yeah,
I'm sure there's a message board out
there for girls like to give their pussy
licked my dogs.
Have you guys seen this shit?
That pirate base doing like attacking
visa and mastercard because of this Wiki
leaks thing?
Yeah,
they are.
They are not hosting it and I did all
the mastercard.
You can make a donation and Wiki leaks
right now.
They're all attacking them and don't.
This wiki leaks thing is fucking
fascinating for people who don't know.
And I just found this out today,
already brought it up yesterday or day
before when we had the podcast and then
uh,
was it yesterday?
Yesterday,
yesterday.
I already brought it up yesterday at the
podcast and then today I went online and
started looking it up.
The guy was arrested for surprise sex.
Alright buddy.
The guy was arrested because his condom
broke and he didn't tell her that's the
crime and apparently it's only a crime
in Sweden,
like this is nuts like that,
an Interpol look to try to get this guy
and bring them in for questioning.
But this is the charge girls to try to
get married that way,
to put this woman that he did it with.
The woman who he had sex with.
This chick has published websites like
with a detailed list of how to get
revenge on men.
It's this craziness.
I mean the idea that this is enough to
bring this guy into justice.
The Internet is going to stop that man.
There's some,
some shit is going to go down from this
and say I'm going to be this easy.
It's really
hard for any organized system to fight
because somebody somewhere is going to
be willing to host something and how
many places you're going to break down.
Shut it down.
It's one head of like,
wow,
this is fascinating.
There's information I shouldn't be
seeing that,
you know,
maybe some of it needs to be exposed and
on the other hand I'm like,
this is national security man.
Like we're talking about serious stuff
that could really put people's lives at
risk.
So I,
I'm on the fence with it,
both sides of it.
I can see both sides of it too,
but I can't see defending against it.
You know,
I,
I don't think it's right or don't think
it's wrong,
but I can't see stopping it from
happening.
When you fuck with people that are that
powerful,
they find some sort of way to get to
you.
I know,
but that's what's fascinating about this
is how transparent it is.
It's incredibly transparent that all of
a sudden this woman,
who by the way has CIA ties follow my
twitter,
just go to Joe Rogan.
There's a bunch of things that are
tweeted today when I started researching
about it and I'm not talking about.
I'm talking about like CNN talking about
legit news sources and they're showing
all this,
you know,
how the connections are,
what this guy is actually being arrested
for.
It's a fascinating thing,
man.
I'm Sarah resting him for having sex
with no condom.
This is consensual sex is not like any
main.
It's not rape,
it's not assault.
It's craziness and this is something
that's like Interpol warning for him and
go searching for him all over the place
for having sex or you got extra day.
That's insane.
Did he get extracted from London to
Sweden?
Yeah,
it's craziness.
It's really good.
Really
transparent.
Transparently.
Those things didn't happen sooner.
I remember sitting there and uh,
I had a friend right about the time we
were working on real one.
This is about 97 and I went over to his
house and he was downloading like full
high quality,
like Hollywood movies off of a website
and this was [inaudible] 97.
Wow.
I'm sitting here going and now it's like
bit torrent is everywhere,
right?
Like,
it's.
And you have a generation that doesn't
want to pay for shit.
Right?
Right.
Like the Scott pilgrim movies.
You see that Brian?
Yes.
One of my favorite movies out of
nowhere.
I can't believe they pulled it off.
I thought it was a meet Edgar Wright who
did Shaun of the dead,
right?
It was just a great movie.
And what happened was a bond at the box
office,
but at the same time it was like a
perfect movie for the Gamer.
Neurogeneration write a hipster
generation even.
Right.
And uh,
I saw somebody tweet about it.
They're like,
Scott Pilgrim is the movie this
generation.
The problem is this generation doesn't
pay for shit.
Right.
I had a friend of mine one time,
she posts on her facebook.
She's like,
oh,
I saw the lovely bones.
It was amazing.
And it was two weeks before the film
came out and like,
you're posting this on your facebook,
did you get like a screener from
somebody in la or something?
She's like,
no,
I tore into that shit.
Yeah.
People just admit it.
Just talk about it openly on people's
doors.
Like the music industry,
right?
Nobody wants to be the fucking music
industry right now.
Mark my words,
we have to get rid of currency and make
it likes because all those people would
have liked it.
And so then you just want to collect
likes,
like they're not even money that's going
to be the currency in the like sixth
grade.
Do you like,
like me,
like me?
Yeah.
But it's kind of point.
I mean,
you know what I mean?
Because that's all you're going towards.
And that's like the new currency would
be a good idea.
It's actually some sort of a revamped
idea.
Have you ever actually tried to,
unlike anything on facebook,
it's a nightmare.
Yeah.
But that's how it should be.
It's like,
it's easy to get calmed down.
Drama Queen.
Just to think about this for the crazy
bitches.
You're really disliked cupcakes and
really you know,
you like what's with the thumbs down?
Why is the 32 thumbs down and 1 million
thumbs up?
Who you 32 people I want to know who
pays for those things like gifts is that
they're calling.
You're paying like $3 for a balloon to
put on somebody's facebook and that was
a part of facebook or are you talking
about like the lytic?
You've got a button or something.
Buttons.
That's what it was.
Virtual goods.
Huge.
Yeah.
I'm not into it.
The whole rage right now in the industry
is they called freemium.
Really?
It's like the game is free,
which is a brilliant idea in a bad
economy and so you start playing it,
but hey,
you see that guy who is the fancy cowboy
hat?
You could have that dollar
me ask you.
What do you think about this?
What do you think about games where it's
like like everquest and shit where they
sell the character that like build up
some crazy super human character and
then they go sell it to digital farming.
Yeah.
That's great.
There's
places where they just.
They busted for world of warcraft where
they'll sit there and they'll just farm.
Yeah,
I watched that on TV,
man.
There was this couple.
There was all about addiction of gaming.
I don't know what the show was,
but it was a sad,
sad couple men because they weren't
paying attention to their kid.
Their poor kid was like,
Mommy,
Daddy.
No,
no.
It was a real TV show.
It was at and the one of the things that
they had is a.
all these people that were in,
I think it was like Russia or somewhere
like that,
that were playing games for a Americans.
They build up their account.
They play all day,
and then they sell it.
This is the fundamental tradeoff that
you have right now is you get to the
certain point,
we realized there's people often talk in
the industry about kids versus adults.
Kids have no money and all the time
adults have very little time and half
the money,
and so which audience are you?
Right?
If you can have a person who's can get
paid,
you know the equivalent to five cents an
hour and every hour you can earn a
dollar's worth of gold.
That's a business model for somebody,
right?
I don't think blizzard is a fan of that.
Right?
But once you have eyes,
like I laugh often talk about the seven
deadly sins is game design,
right?
Like I walk into this world and I see
you with your fancy,
you know,
two girls went up,
shirt on and I'm like,
Ooh,
I want one of those.
How do I get that?
And then I envy you.
Right?
And then I wind up getting greed so I
can collect money and then I want to get
in too many into wind up with gluttony
and then it's just all these start
factor into each other.
And once you have eyes,
it's the way the world works.
You see the guy with the nice car.
It's like,
oh,
I envy him.
I want that nice car.
You can apply that to the virtual world.
Exactly as you can apply it to the real
world.
You don't blizzard and world of
warcraft,
I don't know the exact numbers,
but they had released a pet whereas it
was like 25 actual dollars or something
like that and their servers wound up
getting crashed.
People lining up to buy it just for like
one little pet.
That's the power of what they've figured
out how to do is make it so that the
more you play the game,
the better you get.
The better your life is.
The more successful you are,
the more powerful you are,
the better the experience is,
the more you have control of the people
in the game.
And that's like the really trippy thing.
It's like it's a time thing they like
locked you in like it's,
it's a,
it's a show that you're totally hooked
on and it never ends and it keeps
getting crazier.
New
People and they,
any,
any blizzard,
mark my words has created this mold that
so many other people in the position
going to follow.
We get this,
uh,
this thing in the new gears and we have
a calendar.
It's like you play gears and it's like,
Oh hey,
you know,
don't trade in your game because in two
weeks there's like ticker Tuesday or
triple sp Thursdays.
Right.
And then your friends are playing on
that same day and you want to keep
going.
Right.
And maybe there's like a psychologist
trick.
There were like,
you know,
you don't sell the game because you're
thinking there might be something coming
up.
Right?
We're dungeon masters and we're always
like manipulating experience online to
have
new shit happen.
Yeah.
It's kind of crazy that it just keeps
going though.
But I mean your average person have over
their life.
Right?
So in a world where you start gaining
that control as like the biggest problem
is like when you're young is figuring
out what you want to do when you grow
up.
Right.
Like that.
Thankfully I was lucky and I saw games.
I was like boom.
That I've talked to kids are like,
I'm going to school and I don't know
what I want to do.
It's like,
dude,
pick something and be surgical about it
and decide that you're gonna be the best
at that.
But the problem is finding something for
a lot of kids,
the real issue is finding something.
Then you got lucky.
I got lucky a lot of people did,
but it's like it's very difficult to
find the thing that you're into know you
don't want to like say,
oh,
it's going to be this,
and then you're doing it and then
halfway into you're like this fucking
belonging.
So it's difficult to find what that
thing is.
It's like asking,
asking it a young,
especially at a young age when you don't
know,
you hardly know a lot about what's going
on in the world around you.
But at the same time,
that opportunity now with the internet
is greater than ever.
Right?
Like you could shoot a viral video,
you could start a podcast,
you can do anything.
And if you start getting better and
better at it,
you can build community,
right?
If that's what you want to do.
But what if you want to be a carpenter
or what if you want to be a painter?
You know,
there's so many.
For kids,
the hardest thing is finding the thing,
finding whatever the fuck it is like you
know,
most kids don't get enough exposure to
interesting ideas between the
schoolwork.
When you,
when you go to school,
when you think about what you gotta do,
you gotta get up at fucking 7:00
in the morning.
You've got to leave,
catch a bus with a bunch of other Douche
bags,
do a bunch of shit that sucks all day.
Listen to a bunch of people tell you
never going to make anything out of your
life unless you pay attention to them
and they're like,
listen bitch,
you're teaching school.
I know you don't make any money.
Shut the fuck up.
Don't you love how life is so great when
you're a kid like no the other moments,
but it sucked.
So to find something that you truly love
in the midst of all this,
like programming is what school is no
more than programming.
It is education.
There is information that you're going
to download,
you're going to remember it,
but the reality of what it is is getting
you program to get used to doing things
you don't want to do.
Listening to people that you don't want
to hear,
you're around people.
You don't want to be around.
There's a Buzzer,
but wide.
Why does there have to be a buzzer?
Stupid?
What is it so important that we fucking
leave at a certain time and get there at
a certain time?
You're turning me into a robot.
You know you're turning me into some
worker asshole that just goes and does
the same goddamn thing everyday.
Providing order for a certain mind that
might otherwise to just the devolvement.
Again,
there's ways to educate people.
A little teasers.
My favorite hobby is if I'm out with
friends and I was out in San Francisco
with a buddy and he had a date.
Who is this?
A public school teacher at any time I
find one of my polaroid,
I'm like,
America,
me buy your drink and it will just sit
there and pick their brain for like an
hour about.
My uncles were public school teachers.
They have horror stories.
Oh of course.
Teaches in New Jersey.
Yeah.
Like so you know the classes that are
huge,
like kids who are young,
like super young hooking up and
bathrooms.
They have to call child protective
services.
It's a horror story of well you know,
they're all doing crazy shit now too
because of the Internet.
You know,
you hear like 13 year olds are talking
about,
you know,
making out with other girls.
There was no girls making out with girls
when I was 13.
That shit never took place.
They're all doing it,
you know,
13 year old girls.
Yeah.
That was the,
I knew a lot of 13
year olds,
dude.
None of them were making out with each
other and everybody would say they were
going to do something and you never knew
quite what it was.
Right.
And there was this kind of like adult
conspiracy to keep like pornography or
away from you and things like that.
You had to go to the woods and find
porn.
We've talked about this 100 times on the
poc finding,
finding the woods.
So funny.
Everyone's got the same story.
Everybody dirty stuff.
We didn't bring this up to you and
everyone has the same goddamn story in
the magazine.
You shouldn't make an adult bookstore in
the woods.
It'd probably be the most successful.
I just don't even have any signs.
Here's like a Johnny Porto Ct.
It looks like ron jeremy and going
through with a giant sack of porn and
it's like,
yeah,
cherry a playboy.
It's the dirtiest shit you could find.
It was the bad stuff we grew up with.
oh,
your dog.
There we go.
It was always penthouse with a lot of
water damage.
It was always the girls.
I like that.
The sarlacc pit down there.
It was horrible,
right?
Getting your young impressionable mind
is like,
oh my god,
I was supposed to think this is hot.
What is going on heRe?
And it was terrifying.
When you click of a button,
you can see two girls.
One cup.
Yeah,
we,
we've talked about this before about how
crazy it is,
how close all this stuff is.
Like someone can send you a twitter link
and you click on it and Just give me the
most horrible
mark my words if I ever have children
and they were not going to get a
cellphone until they're maybe 13.
Yeah.
But you know what the worst thing you
want to have is an uninformed kid.
True.
when all the other kids talk to them and
just let them be in the same flow as
everybody else,
just to let them know what the fuck is
going on while,
as long as that basis there.
Right?
Yeah.
It's the old expression,
the kids are going to be all right.
You know,
and there they are.
They're going to be all right.
They're going to be fine.
She's like,
we're fine.
We're worried about them,
you know,
and I have little daughters and
logically,
you know,
I can say this and of course,
you know paternally,
I just want to protect them in the
fucking world.
and all that,
but I understand where that's coming
from.
These kids are going to be fine.
They're growing up with other humans
to some extent.
You want them to make their own
mistakes.
Right?
I've known parents,
yes,
pad the house of too much and it's like
let them
fall over once in a while.
Let them learn how to balance,
right?
Like,
well,
yeah,
but you know,
you gotta be Careful.
You don't want them to be kids die,
you know,
they don't have a stove in the middle of
the living room right now.
But I mean if you have hard floors,
you know,
like I have marble floors.
It's kinda tricky.
You know,
you gotta you gotta watch them.
But,
but that's not the point.
The point is,
you know,
what these,
they're growing up with other people and
I think things always get better and
even though it seems like shit's worse,
even though it seems like shit's worse
as far as like the economy and all this
craziness as far as invasion of privacy
and you know,
and uh,
the,
the access to information that we have
and they're getting inundated with
images and videos and all this shit that
we didn't see it until we were well
mature.
They're goIng to be fine.
They're just,
this is how they're grown up now.
This is just how it is.
And we're just the old people that are
just like our parents,
like,
oh,
kids these days don't get on.
Okay.
Same video games.
It's just weird.
Like we're like kids these days with her
fucking ass to mouth porn.
you know,
they've got asked her mouth porn on
their fucking iphone.
Well,
just what it is.
It's just
this is the new world and the world
constantly keeps getting more and more
complex world of estimates.
It's,
the world is always getting more and
more fucked up.
It's always getting more complicated,
more so bizarre.
Is it going to the zombie apocalypse is
the look.
I think as long as there's freedom of
information,
the way we were expressing each other
right now and communicating with each
other,
people are gonna be able to figure out
things quicker,
you know,
and I think kids are going to be able to
figure out this multifaceted,
fucked up chaotic world far quicker than
some fucking doofus from 1963 now he
takes some kid from 1963.
You can talk them into anything they
didn't know shit.
Now today kids are going to be more
savvy,
more aware and more innovation to ask
anybody anything anymore who will fuck
it up?
You can find it.
Right?
It was.
Wasn't was complaining about this
actually he was a.
There was steve wasniak when the
creatOrs of apple's doing an interview
where he's saying back in my day,
you know,
you had a.
If you had a question,
you had to find a smart person and ask
them,
well that's dumb.
Why would I?
Why are you complaining about that?
There's not that many fucking smart
people,
but I've got to seek out one dude that's
retarded.
I have To go and talk to the professor.
That's why they're so god damn arrogant
about their estimation thing about the
mayans.
RIght.
If they used to control them by the,
you know,
all the quote priests,
figured out science and figure it out,
you know,
how the,
uh,
you know,
the lunar cycles and how everything
would turn out.
and then like,
everyone's like,
wow,
how did they know this?
It must be magic.
Or like we're controlling this through
knowledge,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
there's now before the library of
alexandria burned down,
they had.
I mean,
that was the idea as well.
They,
they kept all the knowledge.
they had all this information about all
sorts of different things that the lay
person was unaware of.
So everybody can get it.
Google bitch.
Damn you.
We used to have to seek out a tim
sweeney,
eric john carmack and hang onto the and
right up to the top.
That's true.
Now there's just fucking computer
connection to the internet and all your
questions answered,
but it's not always true to not.
Oh,
that's the thing is,
but it's getting there.
It really is getting closer and closer.
It's getting to the point.
There's a lot of misinformation,
but there's also a lot of information.
There's a lot of good information and I
think that's good because I think it
developed just like we need to be able
to discern between bullshit and reality
and the real world need to be able to
discern between bullshit and reality
online and people will sort it all out
and figure it out.
You know,
if you know,
there's a lot of people that have it.
There's a lot of urban myths about all
sorts of different things.
You know,
if you drink a coke and take the,
you know,
fucking this with it,
you'll die.
You know?
I mean,
how many different stories,
if we ever heard when they just go pop
rocks growing up.
Yes,
that's right.
That's what it was.
It was mikey from the life cereal
commercial died.
His stomach explodes right when there
was the urban legend about the girl that
stuck the hotdog in her pussy and then
had to go to the hospital.
You never heard that one?
Didn't hear that one.
That was the other one there.
All the maggots were starting coming out
of her ass.
And then there's the one about the
lobster that right.
You heard that one rIght?
What was that one?
That girl apparently took less than one
lobster.
Put it in here.
Then like lit a match to it to make its
tail flip around and turns out the
lobster head,
like planted a bunch of eggs in her and
then three weeks later she died the tub.
IT's like,
yeah,
I can certainly See thAt some disgusting
giRL wAs shit breath telling me that
story.
It really seems like life is going
towards like the having a matrix where
you live a bubble and your whole life is
like you're in suCh a harsh.
She took this lab staff.
She's stalking and helpless here.
Right?
Right.
And it was fuCking lobster traps all his
eggs in a snatch.
It was a lobster fest until fucking labs
is a crime and I have a pussy.
What a whore.
Think that's the case that that life is
going towards where we're going to be in
a bubble in our whole life is going to
be some kind of like matrix style cocoon
where we're all working for the people
who actually have people skills will
suddenly,
everybody's to know how to be connected
and how to get all this data.
RIght.
But those,
you actually can interact in real life
will actually do pretty well if you've
got a combination of that.
It's interesting to try to speculate as
to what exactly was going to happen,
but we all know that something's
happening and that's the most
interesting thing about this
conversation is that we all are just
admitting like everyone's saying is no
one saying,
well,
this is going to stop and everything
will level off and then we'll just,
you know,
go fishing,
go faster than ever though
exponentially.
Right?
Yeah.
It's moving in a weird direction when
you were talking about that smart dust,
you know,
and uh,
the ability to track you and little
particles that can hang on to you and
three d computers and this whole wiki
leaks thing.
I mean,
what would the transparency of the whole
process now seeing this guy get arrested
for not wearing a condom and there's
tracking him down like he's a killer and
that is the main thing.
He's done wrong.
He didn't wear a condom.
Nobody knows.
Nobody knows anybody else involved that
though,
right?
He's the one who's like willinG to stand
up there and take it on the chin as the
face of this whole operation.
I don't understand the whole story.
I need to look into it more and I
hesitate to say anytime anything
involves anything political,
I always just,
you know what it's like watching a tv
show that's fucked me over.
you know,
this show sucks.
You're not getting me again.
I'm not going to watch your stupid show.
And that's how I feel about politics.
So I wouldn't anything like this is in
the news.
I'm like,
fuck you.
My time is valuable.
You guys are all crazy.
You're all full of shit.
Kiss my ass.
I'm not paying attention,
but as this is getting further and
further along,
I'm getting sucked in because it's so
surreal.
Yeah.
It's so strange.
You don't really.
Only a certain percentage of the cables
were actually released.
It was something like $20,000
out of like three or 300,000
or something.
Fucking panicking,
man.
These politicians are panicking.
They're going to know all these other
nations are going to know what kind of
shit we talked about them.
You have a hard time containing data
though.
Even in my business,
it's just like,
oh,
suddenly something just appears as a
rumor on a website.
It's like,
how the fuck it is amazing.
It's interesting.
It's somebody's profitinG by this
because I know in the gaming industry,
If you're going to leak something too,
like you know a video game website,
you're not going to make money and hope
somebody wouldn't have two beers at a
pub and tell him something like that.
It's people run with it.
Right?
That's one of the most fascinating
things about bit torrents and all this
stuff.
It's almost like people feel compelled
to contribute.
It's like there's a,
there's a like a human urge to put
information and stuff available online.
Like before people were getting chased
down.
People love the idea that you could go
to their site and get a bunch of shit.
Yeah.
You can get a bunch of shit from them
and they,
they,
they love to be.
Yeah.
They love to be distributors of it,
you knoW,
it was so common.
There were so many
different sites that had illegal shit
and there's got to be like a human
nature thing where you just want to like
share and host and have community and
remember where's,
where's sites?
YeAh.
I mean that's different than bit torn p,
don't people don't know that there was
these weird fucking hidden sites.
We can go and download yours with z.
Yeah.
W a r you go and Mexico suarez and they
got all shut down.
They've and figured out how to stop
them,
but then this whole peer to peer thing
came up and the peer to peer thing is
too confusing for people don't know.
It's like when you were downloading,
so if you're getting a movie,
you're not getting it from one person.
You're getting it from like 100 people
or more even.
You're getting all these files and
somehoW or another they're compiling
your computer.
Yeah,
but it's craziness because you're taking
all these ones and zeros from like 30
different places and then the final
product is illegal.
Yeah.
Like,
whoa,
what are you saying that.
How do you,
how do you track?
Right.
Where did it come from?
Somebody had it.
If the one person that had it,
there's one illegal copy,
right?
And then they're all illegal.
but what if there's one legal?
So here's the key is to provide a
service that people are willing to pay
for.
Why do you think hollywood's betting on
three d so much right now?
Right?
It's like,
okay,
what are we going?
What are you gonna actually do think
that's adding a third dimension and the
key to that as nfl,
I don't think it's porn and I fell.
It would be dope too.
There were filming all ufc isn't
thredup,
ufc in three d that that'd be genius.
Right.
Then it's an event,
right?
like filmed a bunch of them already.
I want,
I want my three d to be an event.
I want to go see avatar,
toronto and three d.
I dOn't want to go see like meet the
foCkers six and three d.
I don't really care.
Right?
Yeah.
In my house,
like you know,
I don't really need to see like,
you know,
your average rental in three d,
but when there's an event,
there's a fight,
there's a superbowl.
I will,
I'll put mY glasses on to watch that
movie.
Something fucking super like the more I
watched you.
I'm sorry.
The more watch tv in three d though.
It's not really about that.
I think why they're trying to make all
the movies,
three ds and all the games.
Three d is to make it to the point that
what we're going towards is like walls
of tvs or like I was saying,
the imax movie theater where it's going
to be the bubble,
aren't you?
Well,
the three 60,
like I think they're really trying to
push that,
that not the three d part,
just the depth part of it.
So that's what it's going towards.
A bigger screen.
Do you think that they can do that?
Eventually there'll be able to create an
image that looks three dimensional
without actually having to have glasses
and you see the nintendo three ds?
Yeah.
They already have it already have it.
but does it look like
you remember when we went to that?
Um,
I don't remember where,
where the place was we went to and we
saw some,
some sort of a big screen was in an
austin.
They had a big screen that was,
um,
it was a three d thing.
They have super dope.
It was in best buy somewhere in.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It was.
Remember they had,
it was incredible.
We were watching that monsters.
Monsters versus aliens.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It was insane.
The depth was so fucking gripping.
I was like,
this is like given me like a mental
boanerges to watches like thrilling.
So now it's like it's so alive with like
visuals,
you know?
Your story doesn't always have to be the
most original thing,
but if you can provide something silver
somebody never seen before,
that's why we play games.
That's why we go to the movies,
just to get away from the shitty day to
day,
monday life.
That's why there are people who love
avatar so much that are when they leave
it right,
because they created this whole virtual
world.
They just wanted to do exist as me.
Man.
I wanted to go there.
I wanted to lead.
When I read about that movie,
I'm like,
it is like the.
So it's blue people means for golly,
and I'm watching.
I'm like,
oh this is cool.
That was a perfect example of depth
though.
When you saw avatar for the first time,
how like that one scene where they're
going down,
they're pulling out something like a
dead body or something like that.
Long hallway,
you know?
That's what it seems like.
Everything that I've been watching
regular tv in bed for like a couple
months now and even like regular tv
shows that,
that they have like a reaction that
makes the tv try to make it in three d,
that reenactment recreation of trying to
make it three and even shows like that.
You're just watching tv and you're like,
wow,
this background is really far back.
You know,
so it seems like everything is going for
depth nowadays that the technology is
going to be like us in a pod and we're
just going to sit there and get
communicated back.
Exactly.
That's what it seems like we used to the
what?
That they can't go back.
So it is with hd are familiar right now.
Right.
But never underestimate how many people
don't have the money or the upgraded
conversation I ever said.
Sorry.
We don't like we,
we,
we can track how many people have hd
versus standard definition,
televisions and games.
Right?
Based on their settings.
And it's actually not as many people as
you think have hdtv still to this day,
they still have a great percentage of
rural America that's still doesn't have
broadband.
Right?
There's so many people that lag behind
it because it's just not a priority for
them.
Right.
You'll always get your early adopters.
You guys like you who have 3d.
There's still tons of people out there.
Like I stream all my stuff on my xbox,
like when I saw the red box,
you go to the supermarket,
we're out where I live,
and like a friday night or the college,
there's a line out the door at the for
the red box.
And I'm like,
what is this?
Right?
It's just,
it's,
it's blockbuster condensed into one box
that you just read.
Right.
And it's huge.
Not everybody has the broadband and has
an xbox set up.
They can easily stream everything from
the comfort of their living room.
Right?
But not everybody had electricity 200
years ago.
Yeah.
I mean it's like it's all,
oh,
we got to keep pushing forward.
Right?
So going to eventually going in the same
direction.
It doesn't matter how many of these
hillbilly fucks don't catch up with no
broadband in 2010.
I got no fucking time for you,
but you need to move stupid.
You know you need to fucking get your
family out of the woods soon.
Come on buddy.
It's like there's not going to be
carpenters anymore though.
It seems like you were saying like if
you want to be a carpenter,
like how is this person going to find
like a his job and stuff?
That's what's going to happen.
There's not going to be houses anymore.
We're going to live in pods.
Where will we have gigantic three d
computers or three d printers that we
set up that build a house?
Is that what it will be?
There'll be something.
It'd be like a cocoon of a third
dimension wall that wraps around your
body.
You don't want to live like that.
You're not going to be able to live a
bomber style,
but what if you're young and you grew up
with that?
You don't need that much space and you
prefer the virtual world over the real
world.
Right,
and you're.
You're perfectly comfortable running
around a virtual field for a real one
and wouldn't be going to be inevitable.
Maybe it will be.
Get so dope that why would you want to
live in the real world?
Stupid.
Maybe the the,
the fake world will be so talked about.
What if you could just go and you
remember when
her virtual reality was all the rage in
the noodles with a giant dick and and
eyes that can see through walls and
there's no racists and racism and
perhaps some money that has ever been
printed.
It's all yours.
No penis.
We all have faulty penises and you can
just go to other world.
You can travel to other worlds.
You can do anything.
It's not real.
We can make it their own world,
right?
That's the million dollar per billion to
a trillion dollar prize.
Everybody wants to go for,
for games to give you that your dream
that you can ultimately control.
Well,
let's think about this man.
I mean,
what is imagination?
Imagination is some sort of energy that
allows you to think up something that
isn't there and create it and now it
becomes real.
It manifests itself in the real three
dimensional world and you can beat on it
with a hammer.
It all comes from imagination.
So imagination is like some real
creating force were,
but nobody really ever knows where that
comes from.
is it coming to your environment is
coming from like what you're exposed to,
like what is it?
Well,
they also the concept of the muse that
the urine antenna and that you're tuning
into all the energy that's out there and
I'll just,
you know,
you just sort of some sort of another
process.
it just like,
you know,
like a satellite dish pulls it out of
the sky and makes these numbers ones and
zeros and do this.
But it's true.
I mean when you,
when you Look at what imagination is,
I mean it really is some sort of an
energy,
something that exists in the mind and
that it's ether role and then it becomes
a solid thing.
It becomes a miller lite,
you know,
becomes a computer,
it becomes a microphone,
you know,
and this,
all this is eventually got to move
further.
Right?
So if,
if the imagination of all these thoughts
can become a real thing by someone
getting out and and sawing some wood and
nailing some things together,
eventually it's going to become
something through code where you can
alter things not with a hammer and
nails,
but you can use your mind to create a
real world that could be 100 percent
real with your imagination applied
operating system that tunes into neural
interface and becomes a part of you and
you and this operating system connect to
some sort of a computer or whatever the
fuck it is,
whether it's wireless or whatever,
and then all of a sudden you enter into
a tangible third dimensional three
dimensional world that you control.
Then you upload it into it.
What the fuck man?
And we leave meetspace right?
Space,
but think about what happens when the
meat dies and he's just rot and then
someone has to come along and clean you.
They have to recognize as a whole in the
matrix and see you fight it weird.
That is 2010 and we still bury people in
the ground scam.
We should address those people up and
fucking dancing around like we need to
burn them when you're talking about
stupid.
I think that'd be a play.
They should be the respect for the guy
and it's like six months long.
So crazy.
You got to burn them.
It's so dominant.
The cost.
So much money to bury people.
Man.
I was at the duncan show,
the,
uh,
at the cemetery.
Yeah.
What's it called?
Uh,
the hollywood cemetery.
It's got some weird show he does at the
hollywood sign.
I had the gears launch party.
Yeah.
That's where the gears are that sign,
this form.
They do movies and shit there.
Yeah,
it's awesome.
It's like a hip,
really weird cemetery.
But they comedy,
they do a comedy show there and we were
there.
And so it was the first time I'd ever
been around,
um,
uh,
gravestones in a long time and they'll
like,
they'll all high tech now.
They'll have like laser etched people's
faces and shit into the gravestones.
Did they have like video screens and
stuff like the sopranos and stuff like
that on the laws and like Harry Potter
inside the.
Inside the what I'm talking about where
the dead people are.
Yeah.
Where the dead people are.
The,
the headstones there,
there,
there were like high tech now.
Yeah.
Like the whole place is like,
just like a trendy place like that.
So even there's like neon lights around
like some of the graves and there's
these digital candles that flick.
It's like this,
like a hip,
you know,
you do is ridiculous.
What you do is if you die,
you have a live streaming thing that as
a twitter hashtag with your names to
shout outs.
Yeah,
totally.
I wouldn't give a shout out the
gravestone number.
Forty two.
Everybody who died,
he still has a facebook.
Oh his wife updates is facebook all the
time.
You and shit like that.
I've known people in.
It's weird.
They,
they almost hot you on facebook.
They keep popping up and like and stuff
that aren't tagged like tagged me and
it's just a.
You'll be in the middle of the day just
eating your lunch and it just pops up.
You're like,
oh man.
Like it's a weird,
sobering reminder in.
You're not going to delete it.
It's this weird kind of ghostly memorial
to that person.
Right.
And the trivial way.
what happens when that person starts
responding though,
and it's not like there's a twilight
zone,
right?
It starts with the poke right button and
you're like,
I think the assence kicking in,
there's this article in fast company
talkIng about how twitter is kind of
taken over in certain ways and how
basically during the maze this year they
had like twitter projections on the wall
of like the number of hits like each
artist got and there had life youth,
what people are saying about each artist
and so we're.
We have a generation right now that
wants to interact 24 slash seven.
it started with the remote control and
now like it's not enough.
I know friends who've been sitting there
texting other people and I'll say
something like,
hey,
do you wanna go to the you wanna go to
the store and they'll be like,
did you actually hear what I what I just
said?
And they'll be like,
yeah,
you said you wanna go to the store while
they're in the middle of typing an
email.
the human mind is adapting to this kind
of multitask ability.
It's not just enough to sit down and
watch something you need to.
You need to a her feet,
you know,
we're playing an online game and in
between rounds were tweeting at the same
time.
Right.
You have to keep doing something and
doing multiple things.
Otherwise the brain is bored.
You know what?
I don't think it affects traffic as much
either because I think the majority of
people that have like the,
the,
the google maps,
live traffic view sorts that out from
people that are just sitting there,
twittering our mom and driving slower.
Like it cancels each other out because
now we have better technology so we know
where to drive better and where the
traffic is.
So that equals out the other retards,
they just sitting there twittering and
slowing down traffic at different way.
So what do you think about that?
Your steering wheel with a shit about
your phone to the center of your
steering wheel.
Now I did.
I just did this side straddle thing.
I looked down at the map.
I'm like,
okay,
gotta turn right up.
You're at the point where like you're,
you could feel the tug of your phone in
your pocket sometimes.
Oh yeah.
We're just like,
oh,
I just want to look,
you know,
having a twitter fan base and just
seeing you,
you,
you post something before you leave the
office or whatever and you're driving on
the road,
you just learn to know what they're
going to say.
Right,
right.
I just want to respond to that in itself
is having a communitY,
right?
That's incredibly addictive.
So if you have an instant response from
thousands,
if not hundreds of thousands of people,
right?
Like how could you not want to know if
they're gonna say and half the time it's
the same thing and half the time it's
something new.
Right?
Totally.
Yeah.
It's very addictive,
very addictive,
just wanting to know what's going on
Because every now and then I'll check
twitter and someone will turn me onto
something really amazing.
Right.
You know some incredible fucking video
or something.
A little weirded out by the links
though.
Like you just worry about clicking on
it.
Like,
hey,
check out this video.
This cat who farts while he burps and
you're like,
Macedonia.
Do you have,
don't you use a mac?
No.
Oh my,
my,
the big,
the big apple cherry popper from you was
the ipad man.
Oh yeah,
totally.
I love it.
Yeah.
You got to get mammograms.
The not clicking on links nowadays.
Who cares?
Right.
You don't worry about viruses.
Don't worry about anything.
I'm still a pc guy.
That's what we develop on at work.
Right.
That's all nice.
But it's nonsense.
Yeah.
You got to have dessert.
Like being a person who's allergic to
peanuts and you're eating everything
blind,
hoping you don't run into a peanut.
Yeah.
fair enough.
No,
it's silly,
right?
Is this ustream.tv
or [inaudible] dot net.tv.
Fuck.
What's the difference?
The wrong link on my twitter page.
You put it up for you.
I'll put up the wrong length.
These people can't take the piss anytime
you want to get up here.
Just business wise for cables.
He's been here before,
man.
Trust me,
if you want to pee on my dog,
she's out back.
She likes iT.
Dogs love p man.
You know what's crazy about video games
nowadays is that angry birds game.
There's a bird,
a game.
I don't knoW if you heard that.
ninety nine cents right now.
I think it is,
but that game is sold so many fucking
ninety nine cent apps that.
What does it look like?
Spielberg is going to be making a movie
with brad pitt any day now as an angry
bird or something.
That's how crazy you know what you're
talking about.
This is a game on a that you can get on
your iphone.
You could also get it on the droid and
stuff like that.
it's called angry birds.
Uh,
it's so has sold like shitloads of
digital copies to the point where that
game,
it's like making millions for a ninety
nine cent video game.
It's gotten so big that now they're
making it for ipads.
They're making it first console's,
but now it's like there's even a movie
maybe in the works that's coming out.
So what does with the numbers,
like how many millions?
Millions.
Lost millions.
Yeah.
What would you say?
Three point $7 million today.
just taking ralphie may.
that's what we're going to call them
now.
It's a.
Ralphie may make up a number.
I'm going to ralph number.
Remember that?
And then we looked up to thousands of
people started as black as coal people
died.
Gang ralph.
He's a great guy and he's very funny but
still fucks with numbers.
You know,
he's not where he doesn't suck it
numbers.
His popularity of that episode is one of
the fastest,
most popular episodes.
Popular man.
we had so many people love crazy mad
fans.
Ralphy ralphie
and this was ralph.
He was the one who was the best at
capitalizing on that last comic standing
show.
He did it better than anybody.
He just ran with that shit.
like I said this on the podcast,
he watched them destroy rooms,
like just howling,
like a show on the show and that's what
made me got into thinking like,
wow,
he is,
he is a real comic,
or here's an animal dude.
that dude,
I mean he might be 500 fucking pounds or
whatever it is,
but he's working.
he's out there constantly huffing it.
I heard he did like three hours shows
too.
Sometimes.
It's just as ridiculous shows.
I'm,
I want to know is like stealing a lot of
comedy,
man.
He's doing a constantly his feet,
so his feet must hurt that they must
have.
They must just fucking anybody sits down
after awhile.
Maybe it lays down and it maybe what he
does this,
the audience is,
it's like one of those amusement park
rides.
They all strap in and they're raised
them up over him so they're hanging from
the ceiling and he's lying on his back
and that's what he does is common.
And what if he had a waterbed onstage
and just laid back in a wider bed and
there was this candles all around them.
And then that's how,
that's how I did his whole show.
Cool fucking idea.
How about just being in the tub?
Just in the tub with candles comedy.
Oh totally.
That's actually not a bad idea.
You had your opener in there with you
and they're just hanging out laying
there girls though.
You only had one person who's funny.
One person who lives you in that camp
that thinks girls aren't funny.
Most giRls are not fun comedy thing,
right?
Like there's a bunch mean sarah
silvermans reallY funny.
And so I shouldn't say most girls,
just.
Most comics are funny either.
There's less girls doing comedy.
So there's that funny
comedians that are women.
I mean there's no asterisks.
FunnY little esther.
She's very funny.
She's a good comic.
There's a bunch that are really good
comics.
I'm gonna have a bunch of friends that
are comics that are female.
It's a joke.
But uh,
there's a lot of women that are
terrible.
It's a different to have different
restrictions.
They can't talk about as many things
that can't leave.
Sarah silverman does,
but she's such a rarity,
you know,
most.
But that's kind of what it takes,
right?
Like he looked at richard pryor sort of
class to be you.
It has to be you.
And so very few women actually are that.
I mean,
sarah silverman,
the reason,
one of the reasons why she's so funny
and so brash and dirty,
it's like that's what's funny to her,
that's who she really is.
And it has to really be you.
And there's,
you know,
for doing an act.
Yeah,
for a lot of men that's always meant
men.
Ninety percent of all men talk about,
you know,
a lot of the same situations and you
know that you can relate to anyone even
if they're on stage,
unless they're like as extreme as like
say joey diaz and until he deals,
we'll take it into the average man
really has no.
But for most women,
you know,
like conversations like men don't want
to hear you talk about politics.
Men don't want to hear your opinions.
Men don't want to hear you talking about
you getting laid and then don't want to
hear you talking about like,
what the fuck is this bitch so limited.
They're limited.
And they can't be the alpha,
they can't be the one who has this idea
that maybe everybody should listen to
because it makes sense.
You can't be that person.
The last thing any fucking asshole man
wants to do as being the audience with
some woman's smarter than him.
That's making a lot of sense.
it's saying some shit that he should
have thought up on his own because look,
controlling that.
Good luck that.
Yeah.
And good luck with politics.
Know.
And then I'll always oppose women on
political issues.
I know a lot of men who,
when women think one way,
they'll think the other way,
just because a woman thinks that way.
It's just like,
you know,
it's just natural.
It's ingrained.
It's ingrained to not want a woman to
control you.
So.
So many comedians just rely upon the
whole lake.
Marriage sucks,
like unhappy american male type thing.
Then it's just,
it's sad.
Well,
You know what it is.
It's like,
first of all,
that is a lot of what they are.
I mean,
a lot of people,
especially if you're shitty at
relationships,
you don't know what I mean.
You're most.
We know a lot of people that are fucking
terrible relationships.
yeah.
It is what it is.
And it's also,
it's,
you know,
they,
they get programmed into thinking that
that's what's funny.
You know,
That this is,
this is the angle was what everybody.
The whole like,
oh my life sucks like that.
So that's the way it is.
And I,
I feel sympathy for you.
Yeah.
But some people will come out with it
and you know,
you know,
it's real,
it's like two people can talk about the
same subjects and why it works and the
other one that doesn't.
And the one that works,
it works because the shit is coming from
a real place.
That's like the most important thing.
I think any kind of art,
it's got to come from a real place to
order to really resonate with people.
This has to actually be what you want to
do.
You and I started watching,
uh,
for about five seconds on cable.
The other night was pauly shore is dead.
Did you enjoy it now?
I wonder why.
That's where anything was growing up as
a teenager.
We would watch that shit like we would
watch movies.
Yeah.
Well pauly shore of Then is not the
polisher of.
No,
no.
Fair enough.
Life moves on and he's still a go.
Do you go while you worked at the comedy
store still or no?
Never.
No,
no,
no.
That's the main reason why that whole,
uh,
carlsbad ca thing.
That was the end of it for me.
Yeah.
I don't want to bring up a little.
It was just gross.
I mostly do the improv now and other
clubs,
but
you're all right buddy.
What is brian's moving around?
Down the butter dog was fucking dog.
Wait,
what?
I miss walking around with his dog.
We get a suitcase for it.
We're in the middle of a podcaSt.
he's dazzled perth and just walk around.
You get a dog now?
Yeah,
I've got a couple dogs.
Well,
you know my story about when I was
living in Colorado,
my dog had eaten by mountain lion,
but he told me that.
Yeah.
So I have two left.
I got a master's when I have a bulldog.
Your master,
a buck 40.
Jesus.
I'm buck 50.
He's big,
he's super friendly though.
Just dog.
The bigger the dog,
the nicer they are.
The media there.
Are there more little shits?
Well,
there's some big dogs that are scary
though,
like pressing scenarios,
you know,
there's,
there's some,
there's some giant dogs that are fucking
dangerous that usually the masters and
the danes are cool,
right?
Yeah.
Great.
Danes are also really confident.
They're really friendly,
but mastiffs like this dog is the best.
He's just got the perfect personality.
So she's so sweet to everybody.
It's just a nice.
I can't do the little dog thing man and
know how you do it.
Well,
the little dogs,
the one that got eaten and I had a cool
little dog man.
He was a pomeranian and american
eskimos.
Fluffy dog,
but he got jacked by mountain lion.
Did he just vanish one day or do you
come crawling halfway?
Like this story that we've told many
times
I,
I saw the mountain lion was having,
you know,
having little dogs lIke that.
It's like,
you know,
they really can't protect themselves
from anything.
Foxes can jack.
Um,
we,
you know,
I saw a fox with the little baby deer.
I didn't know,
like everybody was talking about how fox
is or like sweet.
Oh they're so cool.
Look at the fantasy five too.
Then I saw a fox dragging a font and I
was like,
oh,
this is real shit.
You ever actually get to be around into
the big katzman?
Well I saw this one mountain lion that
was in my yard and it was about 60
pounds,
70 pounds.
It was like a dog,
like a german shepherd size wasn't big.
Like,
like,
holy shit,
this is going to eat me.
It was big,
like,
whoa,
that's a mountain lion.
It was like,
it was almost kinda like more shocking
that it was smaller because then I knew
it was real.
you know what I'm saying?
Like I expected if you're going to see a
mountain lion,
I must,
he a full grown mountain lion walking
through the woods and something about
the small one.
And I was like,
whoa.
Like there's small ones too.
Like how many of them are out there?
I started thinking like,
how many of these fucking creatures will
live in the woods and just kill it.
I had a cat killed by a economy.
I think it was a coyote,
one of my mom's place and tIme.
And you hear them at night,
right?
You just hear all the howling start
kicking in,
right?
Yeah.
Yard sometimes or they used to be.
I had a fixed my yard so they couldn't
get in,
but they would,
uh,
they would get in and they would ship
all over the place.
They would shit over by my pool.
And it was creepy man,
because I stay up late dude.
Yeah.
I'm up til like 4:00
in the morning.
so while I'm writing,
you know,
these fucking monsters are wandering
around my yard.
Look over shift.
Yeah.
But if you're out there,
they probably the you there and they do
avoid it.
Right.
You know?
Yeah.
But,
you know,
don't,
don't fucking take a chance with a small
person if there's no one around.
Dude,
I chance people before I,
uh,
I had a chance to take my brother and my
little,
a seven year old niece at the san diego
zoo or the wild animal park and kind of
go behind the scenes to check out the
whole sheet set up there and uh,
there's one sheet of there that was hand
raised,
my brother and I got a and like pet the
fucking thing.
Right.
And just hearing that it sounds like it,
like a harley davidson right in person
and you see this the first actually
really course and they have a certain
presence about them just like I don't
fuck with me.
Right.
And I'm at that point I'm like,
okay,
I'll go and I'll get my photo op and I'm
gonna get the hell out because I don't
want to have my face eat and like that
bad in that lady a while ago.
right.
And then there was another one that's
just pacing the cage,
the cage.
And when she saw my little niece,
she stopped immediately made eye contact
and my niece could sense that this
creature like looked at her and want her
to eat her and just like completely
brand behind my brother's legs.
Right.
Because the cheated just saw her as
food.
Right.
It's just that primal instinct just
kicked in.
Yeah.
They can't help it.
Cheetahs can be domesticated.
They're one of the few animals that,
that you can successfully domestIcate
them or they're actually in the low end
of the cat food chain in africa too,
right?
Is that what it is?
They're actually somewhat majored.
Yeah.
And people have actually kept them as
pets and trained them and shit.
I guess they don't kill you dude.
I mean a few animals.
I'm still not going to trust it.
Right.
Yeah.
I was a smart move,
especially with your nice man.
So she wasn't allowed in with them.
Of course.
Right.
I mean even,
you know,
having it aware that that's food,
if you know it overseas or again,
it was funny to realize is it right?
And they didn't realize it was.
It was a magic moments are like,
all right,
this is something that.
Right.
That's
some scary shit dude.
Big cats of the scariest.
They say that the reason why we have
scared where people afraid of monsters
like every kid is.
So I'll just leftover dna from monkeys
getting jacked yet.
But cats back when we were,
you know,
subhuman,
hominoid parental instinct to avoid
scary stuff,
man.
Right.
And like if there's an old Stephen King
thing line,
I can't remember what it was from where
he was saying,
you know,
the lightening crashes and the door
opens and you see a 40 foot bug,
they are part of you is happy because
you're expecting 60 foot bug.
Right?
Like thAt's why alien worked,
right?
Because you don't see the full alien
right at the beginning you see the
little bit of the leg,
a little bit of the tail and you're
imagining like what could this thing
possibly look like?
And yeah,
it was the most screwed up.
Awesome hr giger design like ever.
but at the same tIme in your head,
it was still out there.
We already watched aliens recently is
good.
But the problem with aliens is that they
established an alien that this thing is
super fucking intelligent,
really fast,
gigantic,
super resourceful,
very crafty and sneaky.
But then the second one,
they're just shooting them left and
right.
And they're dying.
They needed one.
You know,
it was one daily versus the truckers to.
They went too quick.
They should have had less aliens.
Let's look who the fuck of mine.
Movie designer telling them one of the
greatest science fiction movies of all
time.
IT's still an amazing movie.
But to me I was like,
wait a minute.
You can just kill them that easy.
everyone's just running around shotgun.
I knew better than one.
One is an exercise in action.
One is an exercise in suspense,
right?
One is the tease of the leg.
The other ones the full on blown out
porno,
right?
Yeah.
And if you ever watched a rewatch the
things to shoot scenes in the second
one,
like when she was battling it with the
exoskeleton on,
I was like,
why isn't it just stabbing you in the
heart?
It's got this giant fucking monster
tale.
Why isn't it just scooping you out of
your camera and sat down and he's like,
I want to see a fucking mac versus an
alien.
there's a certain point in creativity,
man,
where you have to be like,
you know what?
A gun with a chainsaw.
It makes absolutely no sense on it.
Like even look at the design.
If you went to grab the gun,
you saw your finger off.
RighT?
But it's cool.
Yeah,
but what I'm talking about is cut the
shit moments.
I'm the suspension of disbelief where
you make me go in a place where I think
you got lazy or you did.
So why are you making me go here?
Why?
Why is this your conclusion?
What?
How?
How's this bitch fight in the city?
All they had to do is build a certain
amount of,
but they had make it believable.
You gotta you gotta,
you gotta.
I can't like have to go.
Oh well I guess it's just really bad
with its tail today.
That's the same argument that says the
lord of the rings.
why didn't they just grabbed those birds
at the end of it and have them fly over
and drop the ring into the volcano?
Right.
Like there's always.
It's always possible to find words.
Don't listen to you fucking ryan.
The birds at the end of the movie,
man,
carrier pigeon trust birds,
birds,
birds are all former dinosaurs.
That became something new.
That's evil bird ever is the african
grey,
the most evil bird you ever see a shoe
bill.
Now there's a Congo documentary from the
bbc that freaked me out once because he
was five foot tall,
prehistoric fucking bird with his giant
bill.
That jacks these fish.
It's fascinating,
man.
The thing that fascinates me most about
birds,
because they really are dinosaurs,
they really are.
You know,
they,
they think that a lot of.
There's a lot of theories that a lot of
dinosaurs had feathers that,
you know,
they just wrote it off and then we don't
see
the fossils of feathers.
Yeah.
The fossils were just placed there to
test our faith.
Dude.
Dude,
that I argue with on twitter all day.
I don't argue with them all day,
but I read his shit all day.
What is your threshold for blocking
people?
Oh,
I just there if they're annoying.
I just.
I don't.
I just go on instinct.
If you're annoying me,
I just blocked it.
I love it when their dicks.
Yeah.
It's just so easy.
It's a little bit.
I read a thing for you.
Do you get a block block?
I always quote that old comedy,
but you did about the disproportionate
amount of racial interracial porn being
sold in the south.
Right?
It's like,
dude,
like if you hate me that obviously
there's something that I fucked up with
my team and the game that we did
something wrong.
Like how can I flip this to turn you
into somebody who likes what we do?
It's just one switch away.
Maybe it's a,
it's a reply saying,
hey man,
sorry.
The matchmaking sucked in gears too.
We've been working on fixing it like
something like that to win you over and
if you do then you could wind up with a
fan for life.
Right?
You would have to go back and
time and stop that bus driver from
fucking them in the ass and and roofie
in them and given them moonshine.
You'd have to do that and maybe why
they're angry,
whether mom didn't love them or maybe
it's just.
Yeah,
it was it.
The 36 inch lcd testicles that the
internet provides people,
right?
Once you have an amenity,
suddenly they get giant ball,
right?
There's that,
but why are they angry at something?
You know?
Don't take a healthy,
happy,
super cool person who watches a game.
it doesn't really like it.
It goes into tax you on a personal
basis.
There's,
they're coming from a deep anger of
depression,
peps.
It's,
it's a lot of different things,
man.
It's your life not being what you wanted
it to be.
Unfilled expectations were all around
you.
There's people like paris,
hilton and kim kardashians that are
multimillionaires driving around a
bentleys and they do nothing,
and your dry going crazy and so you
attack and so you lose your game is for
faggots.
You Read shit.
I hope you die in a fire.
You know,
like,
whoa,
we're in the era of the art of the bed
celebrity man.
You don't have to be famous for
anything.
You could just be famous for being
famous.
You know what it isn't.
So it wasn't angelina,
the blonde.
He always used to have billboards.
Yeah,
I'm going to pee,
but go into.
It's the continuation of that,
right?
I mean,
it's just like,
oh,
you know,
you just want to be famous.
So you are right.
It amazes me right now.
How many celebrities can bounce back
from like doing anything right now
because America just loves a comeback
story,
right?
You look at like charlie sheen,
remember everyone forgets.
Kim kardashians had a hardcore sex tape
out there.
You're like,
dude,
really?
Like in their little girls out there
that are looking up to her right now.
I had a buddy of mine recently who,
uh,
actually finally,
I'm sure this happens in la all the
time,
but he found it ex-girlfriend actually
in a random porn video online.
No way.
It's got to be.
I want it to happen one day.
I want to be able to just go sell my
feelings.
Right.
And it's,
it's one of those things like if you sit
there,
like I say,
like porn is like on the internet,
it's like a,
a mandelbrot fractal.
he just keeps going and going and you
could just keep the.
And it's never ending.
Like when we were growing up it was like
asia carrera and like a ginger lynn and
then like jamison and then janet and I
was like the same 15 actors just
repeated with different spoofs of
movies.
Right now it's like you can just go on
there and it's like an amount of girls
and you're like,
at what point are you like,
all right,
so this is a thousand dollars.
I don't think anybody's ever going to
see this.
And his reaction,
man,
it felt so bad for him.
And of course I teased them like
nobody's business,
but I was like,
dude,
you're getting your,
like you're chasing amy type of a,
a girl next door type moment.
Right?
Like if he was just kind of crestfallen
about it,
they didn't even go out that long.
right.
But the fact that,
you know,
at some point he found this girl cool
thing hung out and then he finds a video
over on some random internet site doing
some bad cheerleader porn and it was
just like,
just coming back,
who is this?
You're talking to a buddy of mine in
town.
You see peopLe in a,
in la,
I'm sure it's a common thing to like,
you know,
data girl,
then find out later she's a porn girl
where she's done stuff like that,
but you don't see it that often.
And,
and,
and outside of that.
And I had a friend of mine recently
happened to and imagining the mix of
feelings.
He came like,
like of comedy of crestfallen.
I'm like,
I'm,
dude,
did you,
did you rub one out to it?
And he wouldn't,
he wouldn't admit to it,
but the feeling he would have of the
lottery just saying to brian about the
chasing amy slash girl next door type
vibe.
Right?
Or just like,
oh man,
it's kinda funny.
I blame joe frances.
Hey,
what's going on with the gears of war
movie?
They're stiLl making that you guys still
make for the sirens.
Goodbye.
I'm optimist.
Still working on it.
I learned a lot about how a filmmaking
and how hollywood never end the business
works,
right?
I mean,
you really realized that it is very much
business.
It's annoying as fuck,
right?
There's so many people with so many
different opinions and you gotta listen
to all of them.
Well,
and it's,
it's,
there are people who just don't mind,
don't even have an opinion,
but in order to stay relevant they throw
their near here.
I'm only hearing that on one side,
one side to see test,
test.
Oh,
you know what?
I think it reconnected.
I think it's just the base.
Sorry.
So,
um,
what happens is it's a business like any
other business,
right?
And people want to make money and often
the people who make the decisions are
often very rear with looking like,
well,
I'm looking at the last two years and
according to this,
movies with monkeys and them do well.
So you need a monkey.
And I'm not saying that's my personal
experience.
Exactly what it is.
Yeah.
I'm not sure this project,
but what happened was they had a.
They were like,
okay,
why don't do this big,
you know,
he got,
len wiseman attached.
He great guy,
amazing director.
Okay,
well great.
Well you know,
we have a really good script.
You know,
we think we can knock this out.
They looked at the budget like okay,
so this is $120,000,000
estimated and there's no real love story
in here.
It's got it.
It's got to be rated r because the,
you know,
if I show up at comicon and we have a
clip that doesn't have people getting
cut in half and blood flying everywhere,
they're going to tear us limb from limb
and then there is no little kid jayden
smith type story and they're like,
this just doesn't add up like the
assistant head.
All the demographics.
And I remember reading a storY about
these guys who kind of created a
computer formula for it where you can
literally plug in the genre.
You could plug in the actors.
You flipped the time of year it,
russell,
release the various themes that are in
it and they could,
you know,
vegas type betting odds,
you could bet on whether or not their
production would actually make money and
they,
they make money doing this.
Right.
And you're at the point where I'm
sleeping,
right?
Yeah.
And it's,
it's.
And they're saying,
well we won't get the matrix that we
will get the 300 out of it,
but we'll get some sort of will ferrell
comedy that where he's got to where
you're doing a wacky sport,
right?
And you get to the point where
creativity,
it goes to die in that environment
and for,
you know,
now everybody wants to make a district
nine,
right?
Than like how can we make something that
only costs 60,
$60,000,000
and then blows it out because
everybody's conscious about how much
money they spend.
Basic economics,
right?
So,
I mean,
we're kinda redoubling of doing
something that's a little bit smaller,
you know,
recycling the script projects.
Not dead man,
but uh,
you know,
doing it with live people a tbd bad.
I mean,
a lot of it depends on who gets attached
as a director,
things like that.
I mean,
I personally would like to see live
action as little cg as possible.
I would like cgi people.
Man.
You know why your people don't look
real.
These motherfuckers,
they're giant heads.
What are going to get brock lesnar to
play every role?
dude and dudes look like fake dude.
There's not a lot.
Not a lot of thick neck guys like that
that have that level of charisma to hold
up on over there.
A two going to work.
You gotta go cgi son that he gets some
little voices.
Yeah,
geek dudes who are crazy like they're
getting closer with that,
but duty they carried.
The guys don't have to be that jack dude
like,
but your guys are so jacked and gears of
war.
Everyone's jack.
That's part of the cool thing aBout
dIesel to your average person in pitch
black looks jacked and he's five foot
two and was maybe what like five to.
He's a lot bigger than that.
When I've seen him,
he was short maybe.
I think he's six feet tall.
He's friends with rigo rodriguez who
used to be ufc heavyweight champion.
I met a metal maybe in a bad angle,
way bigger than seems short.
When I saw a man,
well,
I'm short,
but he's bigger than me,
but the bottom line is,
dude,
it's more about charisma then is about
muscles.
You get sliced charismatic.
Look at the hawk that you can't have a
lou ferrigno doing the hulk in 2010.
We want that big fucking crazy cgi.
Crazy hog that fucking smashes down.
There's a huge.
There's a huge delta between markets.
Phoenix at the hulk.
His fists are his biggest pickup.
How head is this big compared to his
body?
Marcus phoenix is jack,
but he's not like insanely jack.
He's not even as jackson guy.
The cubs were muscle and fitness
magazine.
Yeah,
he is.
He's just as jacked and his head's extra
super wide because he's a double alpha.
The armors part part of it,
dude,
but it's fucking head is giant.
These perfect dude.
I fuck around man.
Listen,
dude,
get some super duper fucking cgi peps on
this shit.
Why?
You can do anything man.
Monsters and everything.
It all exists.
You can save a world.
That's insane.
Do that for 60 million,
but was it too expensive,
dude?
Do you know much avatar cost?
I mean it was insane how much they cost
200 million plus trod cost.
One hundred 50 million.
Here's a better idea that you're in game
footage.
Movies like in,
in your video game are so good.
You should have like sItcoms with those
guys going home after work,
like having a,
having a relationship with the fucking
king and queens,
queens.
We're just get some dads home.
It takes 20 minutes,
take off his armor of god,
do it in game footage and stuff.
I've got like a sitcom with all your
characters in it and they're all like
family guy style.
They're all friends and they hang out
and get drunk.
It was a terrible movie,
but it was a game,
right?
It's a terrible movie.
But it was an interesting concept.
There was a Bruce Willis movie.
Uh,
we're uh,
I think it was called surrogate
surrogate's.
Yeah.
It was really recent.
Where everybody wide uptake.
They,
they,
they stayed at home and then they had
the younger version of that all exist in
the
world.
The younger perfect version,
you have this full head of hair and
perfect skin.
It was like kind of weird.
I don't know.
Cgi had him somehow,
but uh,
you're getting at the point where they
can Kind of track your body and then
kind of cgi over in such an amazing way.
Right.
And I mean,
you look at what they're there for tron
that are recreated.
Kind of like jeff was saYing,
it looks a little bit more like gary
oldman.
Then Jeff Bridges.
Yeah.
There's look at all the posters for
that.
I'm dying to see the film and I think
Jeff Bridges to me,
I thought it was pretty cool.
Jeff bridges gets cooler looking the
older he gets.
Have you seen the trailer for trigger
it?
Seen him naked.
It looks awesome.
Talking about his face that he looks so
just drizzled,
right?
He just loses it.
Doesn't know where the fuck.
Think sagging and it was just bleed.
It's got skin tags breaking left and
right and he's got,
you see the trailer for true grit
though.
Yes.
I crazy heart too.
That was good.
yeah.
That was an interesting movie man.
It was kind of cool.
I like sad.
Right.
But dude was sad but it was good.
I mean it was The life lesson of being
on the road that much.
Right.
In the loneliness.
It's also the party in men,
you know,
I've,
I've met a million people that have
problems with partying,
with alcohol especially,
but with coke and with a bunch of
different things,
they just,
people that are performers are
performing all the time and they need to
get up to perform and that's the respect
I have.
Like I've,
I've,
I've done like the european press tour
for the games where it's five european
cities in five days and that just wrecks
me.
Right.
I cannot imagine doing like 30 cities in
40 days.
Right.
Like what it takes to actually pull that
off and to sit there and to show up
every night and to command a stadium.
Like what does that,
what does that do to you?
Right?
Like how can you actually show up like
that?
Right.
And then at the end of every night
there's an infinite amount of partying
or just the girls lined up to just do
whatever.
Right?
Like at different city and new people
experience,
you all think you're gone.
You really have to get Back to your
hotel because you got to get up in the
morning and five hours ago to your
flight.
That's,
those are the ones who are responsible,
right?
Yeah.
Well it's all the.
The reality is those,
uh,
those tour,
like I only did one tour like that most
of the time what I do with comedy as I
go out on the weekends and then I come
home,
I go out and go out for a couple of
days,
then I come home.
But a lot of guys will go out and
they'll do like,
you know,
like I know why mazda brawny we're
talking about and he goes out and he
goes out for like a couple of weeks,
three,
four weeks.
But one time we did this maximum tour
and we were gone for like a month.
Yeah,
like a whole month of just constantly
doing gigs and it's a fucking weird
thing,
man.
It's not how many cities?
I think we did 22 to 22 and three days.
Do you have like a comedy bus or both?
We took a bus some places.
Most of the time we flew,
but it was a.
It was a brutal man.
Weird.
Everyday.
What'd you.
All you're doing is Traveling and then
trying to get as much rest as possible
and getting onstage and then trying to
get as much rest as possible.
And traveling.
You never get a full night's sleep.
You're always flying.
You're always eating terrible food.
It's interesting.
Even though it was fun.
Your comedy gets tight.
She loved awake.
Did she left the waking up and going?
Where the fuck am I?
All the time.
Yeah.
I still did that.
I do that so often because I travel so
much.
Like,
oh,
get up to pee and I'll go,
okay,
where's this bathroom?
Where do you know my trick?
Leave the bathroom light on,
close the door.
Oh,
that's a good.
Because when you don't know where the
hell you are and your,
your,
your hey,
you got to go like you.
That thing will be like this.
God you motherfucker,
you.
But I've had that happen and there's a
worse feeling in the world.
you want to.
Weird thing,
man.
It's a hotel room.
You just pee on the floor.
And joe had like a scare at a hotel
where we both thought we were going to
die and we've talked about it before,
but that really changed the whole thing
for hotels.
For me,
I actually fear hotel to hotel rooms.
We'll check.
I'll always look out the like somebody
knocks at the door,
always look out the little law.
The people and fire.
Yeah,
wasn't it?
You know what the problem was?
It was in an old hotel.
It wouldn't have been nearly as much of
a problem,
but there was a single file staircase
and we were on the fifth.
I was on the 15th.
What floor were you on?
I was on the 14th I think.
And um,
you know,
and you could only get one person on the
staircase at the time and people were
slow as fuck.
You feel that you have,
you probably felt that like people are
about to trample each other like at that
threshold,
right?
Where there's just that instinct kicks
in.
I was like,
that kiddIng.
I'm the head of the pack.
I was the one who will be running on
people's heads.
I was seconds away from sprinting
through these fucking people with
slippers on,
man.
All ambient.
You can tell they were fucked up from
sleeping pills and shit.
And they were moving slow as shit.
And the problem is the announcement like
the lady on the things like please
evacuate a building.
The building of fire has been detected.
Please evacuate the building
immediately.
And what time did that happen?
Like three in the morning,
4:30,
4:30.
and especially not knowing where the
hell you are.
You know,
it's like a robot voice that woke us up
at dan chen.
But it wasn't,
it was a woman.
There was a woman talking because while
she was talking she was doing it.
so robotic,
we were trying to,
it was,
first of all,
we're so foggy and we're trying to
figure out why,
why,
you know,
if this is really happening,
it doesn't seem like how you would tell
me that the fucking buildings on fire.
Exactly.
So this,
this,
uh,
fire has been detected in the building.
Please evacuate immediately and I'm not
sure if this portal,
I don't know if it's a robot or if it's
a real perSon at the building until I
hear in the background,
we got to get these people outta here.
Shut them.
There was a guy in the back behind her
that must,
must've been like,
you know,
behind the counter with her.
It's like we gotta get these people out
of here and then it was just a false
alarm and he's just decided to fuck with
everybody.
Like,
no,
it's on the twelfth floor now we need to
get him out.
I remember thinking that I was the same
exact thing as joke because we had
talked about it afterwards and I was
thinking the same thing.
Like I am going to have to start
throwing people out of my way.
And then I looked at the windows like in
the stairways that was like off the,
it just,
it's just amazing how slow people can
actually physically move.
Like,
like that plane that landed on the
hudson a couple of years ago.
Like I would've just crapped my pants.
I'm like,
get me off of thiS.
Right?
So how many people do,
are barely taking care of their body?
Barely.
Barely,
barely.
Next to that guy on the plane.
It gives you the extra elbow rest.
Yeah.
When it's leaking over under your seat.
And we were thinking about that when we
were,
we had ralphie on the podcast.
He means brian and he barely sat in an
account together.
Mean what happens if you're on southwest
and you got to sit next to him to say
it.
It's all about the lap band now.
Yeah.
What the fuck is this dude?
It's everywhere.
It's on every billboard there.
so gluttonous that,
you know,
there was a picture from a long time
ago,
the beginning of the,
uh,
the 18th century or the 19th century,
there was like a carnival and they had
the fat man in the carnival sideshow
free spirited woman,
the fat man and the fat man wasn't
nearly as big as ralphie may.
This guy was a freak back then we'll do
what because people had a fucking work
and move around that it's moving.
But it's also the average american diet,
the average american diet like three
flavors,
fat,
sugar and salt that everywhere you're
trained,
we have an entire generation of kids
that will not eat food without ketchup
on it.
Like they just won't.
They just have to catch up and catch up.
Chicken fingers and it's like,
do,
heaven forbid you take them out and I'll
give him some fish or try curry or
something.
Like just,
oh no,
it's just.
And then you don't think about
mcdonald's.
Get them young.
Right?
Yeah.
Well the thing is about like this lap
band thing is what's really creepy about
is all you're doing is making the
stomach smaller.
So that you get full quicker,
so all you have to do is just stop
eating so much.
But it's not,
it's that simple.
It's,
it's hitting your dopamine receptors and
you've been trained for that and that's
the only thing,
you know,
we,
we talk about,
you know,
can you just try and get half portion
please?
Like it's huge now.
Right?
Right.
But when you're filling up and you have
this lap band thing,
so you have this tiny baby fake stomach
now and that little fake stomach filling
up.
Do you,
does your doberman receptors go off?
Do you get the chemicals that sale it?
Dude,
it's on every billboard and apparently
the surgery is not invasive enough that
it's the point it's going to be like
you've watched people get the lap band
installed in the mall,
like laser eye surgery.
Right?
Like I do that dental.
Why'd they get your lap band while
you're at it?
Right.
You know,
it.
Isn't it like a shitty fix to a problem.
That's obviously a lifestyle and diet
problems.
Somebody saw profit.
Right?
And yeah,
I mean that's true.
I mean obviously like the shake weight.
Yeah.
Well,
what's so weird though is like when you
talk to somebody that's like insanely
obese,
I know he's drunk,
she's drunk,
sled,
don't do that.
I'm drinking a bottle.
She licks,
he's used to list looking cylindrical
things in your home,
but it's like you talked to these people
and they're always like,
I don't even know what the problem is.
It's fibroids.
This is that.
I'm on a diet.
But then you hear the other stories were
like,
no dude,
he went to jack in the box and pretty
much ordered like 13.
I honestly think it's the same thing as
the guy who just works out to the point
where it looks like he's just comedic.
I think it's,
it's an addiction.
I honestly think it is.
Yeah,
I guess so.
But that's a little more.
That's a different kind of totally
different kinds of craziness.
The crazy,
the fat craziness is just like they're
just trying to die or something.
You know,
like I have a friend who I know has like
a massive food addiction and just
anytime he's around fast food,
he just,
he can't drive by a jacket.
Oh yes.
He's going to go in and you're trained
at a young age to enjoy those flavors.
also mad and it's,
it's a stealth calorie thing also.
I mean,
he knows he's fat.
He's on talks about it.
He's trying to do things and never has
done anything and you know,
if you know in your head that you should
stop doing this and you have a problem,
it's very strange that you can't rewire
your brain to recognize that like,
oh,
this is something I'm aware of now.
Now I just need to stop.
It's a.
Once people get set on a certain path,
then at a certain point they just go,
right,
right.
Breaking that cycle is the hardest
thing.
Right?
But why does that exist?
The big question is why is that in our
system?
Why is it,
is it the same thing that allows us to
get obsessed with things and get really
good at things?
Is it like a bastardization?
How do we all know what borders are now?
My grandpa was a hoarder when she died.
My,
uh,
my uncle wound up having to clean out
her place.
I remember as a kid going to visit her
and she would have stacks of national
geographic five feet high with her goat
paths.
We'd have to navigate.
You go to the bathroom to pee in her
bathtub.
Was used to have bags of clothes in it.
She'd never really.
We always wondering why grandma smelled
sweaty and you know,
she wouldn't.
Didn't wear deodorant,
joe,
but my grandmother was the same way.
Your,
your grandmother didn't wear deodorant
up?
Clearly?
Not.
Why not?
Maybe she just didn't think it was okay
to plug up her armpits with stuff.
I'm interested to wear deodorant.
I just don't wear antiperspirant.
One thing is just smell.
Just giving shit,
man.
Stopping the.
My grandmother was completely crazy.
My grandmother when she died was exactly
the same thing.
They had a.
They had a clean out her.
My uncle.
I think it's a control thing when you
give her much borders.
Yes.
Usually the husband obsession husbands,
some train wreck and the.
Something's gone south,
so it's this one thing that they can.
They can control and in their life,
right.
It may be,
but she was insane about a bunch of
different things,
but the whole house was just stacks of
boxes and no one knew anything and it's
never anything valuable.
It's usually just little.
She had a lot of money that she didn't
even probably know she had like $30,000
was stored in the house,
some some ridiculous number and they
were broke and it was really because she
had grown up in the recession and when
you grew up in the recession,
you're like constantly worried you're
going to run out of money,
can stash our parents,
and our grandparents were always like,
no,
you're going to finish that.
You're going to take that home.
And now this current generation is like,
eh,
screw it.
I don't need it.
Right.
She had an aneurysm and she forgot where
everything was.
So she had all these fucking cans around
the house and nobody found until she
died.
So it was like 12 years.
She.
Yeah.
They gave her 72 hours to live.
She had a massive aneurysm and nobody
found it for a long time.
I came outside and she was just jacked
and so,
uh,
they uh,
they brought her into the hospital and
then they're like,
you know,
maybe she's got 72 hours.
Maybe she lived 12 years.
Wow.
12 sicilian peasant genes,
bro.
Diehard right.
Karen rocks up hills for generation
after generation.
Josh ortega,
he wrote a gears to had one point where
he was an apartment manager department
and he got a phone call that this person
had the strange fluid like that.
They assumed it was a sewer leak above
the rest.
Something like the dead person.
Yeah.
He called it.
He called him like it was a cop or some
sort of cleaner guy.
Touch it,
smell.
It was like you got death above you.
The guy got had died and bloated and
actually soaked through.
Oh boy.
And he,
once they took the body out,
josh actually had to clean all that out.
You can't clean the ceiling.
You have to cut it out,
suck through.
The smell does not go away.
Or the wallboard leaking through the
wall board.
You've got a body and your ceiling.
Would you live somewhere like a place
that somebody had been
murdered at?
No.
You wouldn't?
No,
I don't think I would.
And you know,
one of the reasons why I don't think I
would is I really honestly believed that
there's something to the.
I think it was rupert sheldrake,
who's a evolutionary biologist,
had this idea that everything has some
sort of a memory.
I believe it was his idea that memory
doesn't just exist in the human mind,
but that objects and things have memory
and the world around you.
that's one reason why you can come into
certain buildings and creepy shit has
happened there and you know,
people are fucking flakes,
man.
People tell you they can read their
paul,
your palm or I sent you a good person.
There's a lot of weirdos that talk crazy
spiritual talk,
but there's California,
there's for sure,
right.
Everybody out here wants to be special
without working for it,
but for sure there's something about
feelings.
You know,
there's some,
some,
there's some fields that you get for
some places and so many people have had
like gone into a house where someone's
been murdered and no one even has to
tell them and they feel terrible about
the house and the house has a nice
house.
There's been so many stories about
something like that.
The wallpaper is murder somebody in
there.
Dude,
you know what?
I think ghosts aren't just.
There aren't just potentially these
things that exist around here.
I think it's like a memory,
right?
As far as uh,
there's this awesome game system shock
two.
Do you ever play it?
Yeah.
And they used to,
they basically had these implants that
allowed you to see the memories that
people right before they died and he
come up with,
come up with.
IT was a great storytelling thing
because a ghost,
he couldn't interfere with the cuts.
He couldn't shoot the guy before he did
the thing.
You just saw the last like eight seconds
of his life play out and he came up the
elevator shaft and this guy in front of
you who's standing there with a shotgun,
he was like,
I'm sorry,
you know this,
the space station has gone to hell.
I can't deal with this.
You know,
lee and the kids forgive me and he,
you see him put the gun in his mouth and
it phases out.
Well,
they use that throughout.
Right as an amazing storytelling
technique.
Right.
It's classic stuff,
man.
Right.
He brought it back to gaming right
there.
Did you see the mario kart started that
with the.
Goes around the track that.
Yeah,
exactly.
That was you compete against yourself,
right?
Yeah,
exactly,
dude.
And now we're all figuring out how to
basically have different types of events
happen online.
You know,
like angry birds.
You were saying now they're doing like
the holiday edition.
Right.
But they're handling it right to man.
Those,
those people didn't charge anything for
that game and then they've been updating
it and you know,
patching it.
I wouldn't be if I finished angry birds
and then there was a screen to come up.
It came up and said,
hey,
you could have 30 more levels for 30
bucks.
That would have been like,
yes,
and my first born please.
They're treating it right though and I
mean they make money,
they get it,
they sold the game.
They're giving a lot away for free right
now,
but they weren't you just saying that
they have some like ninety nine cent
like eagle that'll take out the whole
level for you that they've been.
They've been planning what they have
that and they also had like the
halloween pack and then they also have
the whole new christmas pack.
No,
you can't just play all the levels.
it's an advent calendar sooner.
You can only play one level on each day
so you can't just burn through them all
in one night,
but it's such a well designed game that
you're just going to keep coming back.
Right?
Totally.
So simple.
Perfect kind of ios game,
just doo doo doo doo doot.
Definitely tablets,
swipe baby.
that's the way to go.
Everything's turning into applications.
To have you notice,
notice that nowadays you're not paying
money for like a magazines,
you're not paying money for,
for this and that you're now having
applications and apps.
Apps are just fancy programs,
right?
That are just smaller,
well maintained.
The personal.
You're taking these apps with you on the
road.
A loT of people are concerned with on
the internet right now that like,
it's no longer as a series of linked
websites.
It's huge.
It's facebook,
it's various kind of silos of
information where it's all self
contained within that.
Right.
The thing that,
you know,
again,
I like facebook,
I think it's cool.
You know,
I like stalking people.
I went to high school with.
It's cool at the same time,
like the fact that every website I go to
now has like a facebook integrated now,
right?
We're like,
I don't necessarily want somebody
knowing I go to one website and
accidentally click like broadcast
because,
uh,
you know,
any comments,
you can make comments on these a lot.
Oh,
absolutely.
And you do it through your facebook log
into your facebook.
I'm like,
wait a minute,
where's my password going?
How do you know what's going on?
I'll never forget you connecting.
I'm allowing you to connect through my
facebook.
So here's a question for you.
If you.
If you could have perfect memory,
like day to day,
you will remember everything when you
were 10 years old every single day,
but it had advertising in it.
Let you do it know it already did.
Dude,
that's fascinating.
That's a very good question.
So like I want to go from August 4th,
19,
74,
3:00
PM.
They're like,
okay,
this is sponsored by gecko who go to
[inaudible] dot com and you're like,
fine,
whatever.
Then you're like,
bam.
Now you have that day in front of you on
video of course,
because we're all living in their
memories.
Right?
Or that thought.
At least you would definitely.
But then you would say,
well,
where's the store?
Does this nonlocal?
No,
no,
no.
It's like divek circuit city.
Yeah,
that's the thing.
There's a story on.
I'll pull up this shit on my own.
They were able to surgically kind of
removes certain memories for mice.
They've started to come through.
Some of that is technology like eternal
sunshine of the spotless mind,
so if you're a ptsd sufferer and you
have traumatic events that Afghanistan,
they can surgically remove the stuff
that happened to you so that you can
move on.
Since there's some dude that you fucking
hate in Afghanistan all sudden you're in
New York and he sees you like,
yo,
fuck,
and you're like,
I don't even know this dude.
That's not cool.
Yeah,
this guy would hate you and he'd be
following you around.
You're like,
what is this dude's deal?
Or you get out,
get out of a bad relationship and you're
killed.
Everyone he knows when and he made me
make the iron man outfit,
right?
Yeah.
You get out of bad relationship and
meanwhile she still remembers you and
she's fucking sharp in an upward
daggers.
She was like traveling over the trailer
behind the condom can break to get you
arrested for.
She's got all sorts of outfits.
She's like blade and shit.
She's got a trench coat filled with
weapons looking to take you out.
Blissfully unaware of the fact that
they're starting to make these
breakthroughs.
Right?
There's a breakthrough in nanotechnology
that happened,
I think it was about a year ago where
they were able to figure out how to
actually have a cells that were bonded
in an injection that would actually then
melts a,
a,
a tumor that was a tumorous growth like
without any sort of radiation treatment
or anything like that.
Right.
It's just,
it's right in the fridge right now,
right.
Like hAve so many diseases and
everything like that,
like it might actually happen within our
lifetimes and forget about your kids.
It's not just
happening in,
in technology,
it's happening in space.
Like all the shit that they're finding
out about space as well.
Are you following any of the astronauts
on the international space station on
twitter?
Know there's that guy dig up.
His name is,
uh,
he's been just tweeting photos of like
amazing,
like,
like sun sunsets from,
from space,
from the space station.
like somehow they hooked up,
you know,
he's an internet connection up there and
he has like $300.
twitter.
He's like,
hey,
look at this,
this his name's,
um,
I guess that you sound not gucci.
It's a astro underscore,
soi.
Chi has got 300,000
followers and he's like,
hey look,
we're taking off and to go to the space
station and he's just got this following
and like these making space travel.
Cool again.
Right.
Whereas you know,
you joke about kids who want to be mma
fighters,
video game designers.
Now this guy's doing that for the job.
Right.
Which I think is really cool when he.
Yeah,
I actually do follow that guy.
I have seen some of his cool stuff.
I forgot.
I think also many people are forgot.
They compile it on the huffington post
once in a while you just look at it just
to go through just like,
this is amazing.
There's so many things that are just so
crazy that are unmissed not even
understood about this world.
The whole lake arsenic based life form
stuff they came up with.
I know what they found out that that was
bad science.
Really?
Yeah.
That was very poorly written and that
nasa nasa rushed to try to get this
press conference or this press release
out there before it got reviewed by all
the right people and there's a ton of
criticism all over the internet that
what they did was they drew some really
unscientific conclusions and and kind of
a.
It's not,
it's not.
It's not disproven completely,
but it's not proven either.
It's a,
it's not ready yet and it's kind of like
contact where they're not really sure if
jodie foster really went to the other
world,
some nutty shit going on.
Man.
Have you heard about this new object
that they found outside of pluto?
That's jupiter sized really just out of
nowhere way the fuck out there,
like probably as far or more from
jupiter as we are from jupiter or excuse
me,
from pluto rather as we are from pluto
and it's outside of pluto and it's
gigantic.
They don't know what it is.
They have no idea where it is exactly,
but they know there's something out
there.
They're pretty sure.
I knOw you've probably talked about this
in the area because you're big on aliens
to.
The whole idea with Stephen hawking was
saying like,
no,
if aliens actually find us first,
then it's going to be a situation where
were the native americans and then it's
everybody else coming over from europe.
It didn't turn out very well.
or were monkeys were not even native
americans.
Man,
native americans released human,
you know?
I mean if something is a million years
more advanced than us,
it's going to be like us collecting
bugs.
LIke again,
like I said,
your kids are probably going to live to
be 150 plus to see this.
If not,
if not you.
Who knows?
Man,
who knows what the fuck is going on,
the breakthroughs that they're coming in
to live to 1:50
working in video games.
Would you stress?
Yeah.
Maybe we'll just kick back and go jay z
style.
Once you compile all your money,
dude,
because the developers,
the people who have the money or the
people that put up the money and those
are the people that make all the money's
at what's going on and that it's much
harder for the developers to go jz
style.
It is.
Yeah.
You get.
WeLl,
you get to the point where it's.
It's so hard for one person to really
break out and do his own thing,
especially in the triple a space because
you're seeing where it used games and
rentals are eating up so much of the
market that for somebody to spend,
you know,
millions millions of dollars to make a
game and that to actually launch it with
all the marketing is a huge risk.
And then so a lot of people are turning
to mobile that running to all these
different kinds of places.
Right?
But I would think that at a certain
level,
like your level,
when you have a certain reputation
behind you,
that it might be easier for a bunch of
people to come to you and say,
listen man,
you're a proven commodity.
Why don't you get your team and you
know,
we'll give you guys a cut of the
publishing hypothetical.
I knew what he did an early age that by
doing the pr and being able to have a
little bit of a theater background and
go on stage and this stuff would get me
a certain amount of leverage and then by
working with talented people,
making great games,
I have built a brand for myself.
So hypothetically I could probably go
knock on a lot of publishers toward to
mom and be like,
just give me a bunch of money.
Let me build a team,
do whatever I want.
The problem is epic takes good care of
me and I worked with everybody and I get
to do the shit I want and I know I've
got a great setup,
so why fuck with it for something that
may or may not work out.
Right.
That explosion was brian fucking around
in the background.
What do you think that the world's
coming to an end.
What do you think the current,
a lifespan of the consoles are?
Leg until the new year?
We have for the first time ever in video
games,
we've just gotten past the five year
lifecycle.
Yeah.
It seems reason yet is I think for a lot
of people graphics or quote good enough.
Yeah.
Right,
and like what if,
if you were to put something new on tv,
that's what is the current state of the
art versus the latest playstation.
Xbox game would've passed the mom test,
which your mom look at that and go,
that looks amazing.
Compare to that.
Maybe.
Maybe not give it a couple of years.
Yes.
Right.
So right now maybe it's good enough.
You know,
you have all the emotion controls and
everything like that.
They can kind of keep everybody
occupied.
What do you think the next thing is?
What do you think is just going to be
faster and bigger?
Or do you think there's going to be the
personally.
Yeah,
my personal opinion,
personal opinion,
fastest hell,
avatar style graphics,
avatar level of graphics,
something that is always connected to
the internet.
Is it ever going to come to a time where
that's easier to do than it is now?
What?
In regards to building the log,
building it,
creating it,
I mean there's things like that will,
there's ways that you can procedurally
create content,
right?
Like we'll write it spore where like a
lot of the textures were automatically
created so we figured out what like a,
an algorithm would be for grass and wood
and things like that and there's a huge,
not huge,
but there's a subset of people that are
working that technology like,
okay,
just hit a button and just generate 50
types of wood for me so we don't
actually have to build it.
Right.
Then you get to the point where there's
a certain library of do I really need to
remodel the couch for the 8000000000th
time?
Like work smarter,
not harder,
right?
Figure out ways to use more modular
architecture.
Do you really need 50 columns of
different types of.
You can just spit them all out,
right?
The key is going to be figuring out,
you know,
like how to craft that within a certain
financial model.
That's the billion dollar question.
How do you put that aaa content.
That makes sense,
right?
Like hoW do you remain profitable?
Will there eventually you think will be
software that makes it easy?
Like the average person can create
games.
That's what we do.
That's half of our business.
You could go to utk.com
and download the same exact stuff we
used to build our games for free so
anybody can for free,
go and take your technology and make
their own game.
They can.
The problem is of course if you start
making money with it,
then you have to talk to us about
officially licensing it.
Oh,
that's pretty funny actually,
but the reason why,
the reason why the smart is because you
have so many college campuses out there
that want to find a solution.
How do we train college kids to learn
how to use this technology that goes to
it?
Is it how hard your builder to builder
or killed for these tools?
When I was 13?
Yes.
Now they're not making games hard.
Right?
Like you still have to know what to do,
but if I was myself,
17,
I would've been able to do such crazy
shit.
Like I had to learn visual basic and get
a programmer.
You're the programmer.
I did jazz jack rabbit with back in the
day is the guy who works in kill zone
now.
It's just one of those weird like,
you know,
professor x mag needle type situations.
Right?
But he's cool guy,
great dutch dude.
Um,
but yeah,
like you can just go download it out and
start building games.
So I get these kids a tweet all the
time.
How do we get the business?
I'm like,
go to utk,
download it and start building
something,
figure out what you're good at and work
your ass off and be better than
everybody else.
I've been playing that hard shaft.
I mean
mineshaft game that's on the slip there.
Brian king called big black dog,
king kong and it was great.
It's minecraft,
right?
Uh,
so have you been playing that at all?
I heard they think it's the first pc
game I paid money for and years.
Really?
All right.
So we got through this whole episode
without anybody talking about big bucks.
That was a horrible slip.
It was like one of those big black dicks
though.
It's almost like it's impossible.
It's like it's embedded into our system.
We track dick talk,
we've through the black car and so mine
shaft,
how do I.
Okay,
I'm going to go from people at cox to
minecraft,
minecraft game.
joe,
this kid,
this kid decided to make this game out
of it,
out of
his garage.
And he's making god I hipaa,
I don't even know the numbers.
He's making money hand over fist,
right?
And it's basically a world where you
can,
you,
you initially start off and you can
build cubes at different,
uh,
materials in front of you and then build
anything you want basically.
So imagine building three d pixels and
there's people who have built like the
earth in this game,
right?
Right.
And then there's this mode where the
nighttime comes and you have to
eventually figure out how to survive
your first night and start building like
a workbench and built all these
different things.
And it starts getting deeper and deeper.
I haven't gotten too deep into it,
but it's become this kind of phenomenon.
He's talking to valve about doing
something with it and what you see right
now is these kind of little micro
developers who are having success.
Right.
The guy who did brave jonathan blow,
you have the team who made portal was
like a handful of kids who made an
independent game that then they started
working with valve.
Right.
The guy who did the limbo,
the team into the limbo.
They were at the independent games
festival.
We saw that and were like,
this game is great,
and then every time I'd love supporting
these indie kids because you never know
like what's going to come out of them
because they can often take risks that
we can't because you know,
in their garage and they're,
you know,
bill,
would it be for someone to make a movie
with your game engine?
Pretty easy.
Real,
yeah.
Wow.
Yeah.
They call it machinima.
Oh yeah.
Mastermind.
I'm going to the award ceremony where
they call it spelled.
I always call it
[inaudible],
but I don't know the art of,
of readmission.
Machinima.
It's the art of a virtual camera,
right?
That's a c,
h I,
m a s,
s,
l I t dot.
I've seen some old ones done with old
game engines that looked really hokey.
That was good,
but the game engines of today,
they're so sophisticated.
That was what red vs blue was,
right?
That was that whole web series that
became huge.
These guys,
little characters and they just made
them target these incredibly funny
situations.
You need to have a sitcom of your
character's having wives and stuff in
that forum.
We will absolutely do that in our spare
time.
No,
no.
He just hired two speed iphone efforts
and high school kids to do it.
Yeah,
but the marine guys pulling their
assholes apart and the goats,
he posed no beauty of so many of those
internet memes.
Just I could sit there eating a giant
bowl of cereal,
just watch it and not even care because
it's been sent to you so many times.
Right.
That's true,
and that's the other thing.
You know,
we were talking about kids getting
freaked out by all the input that they
have today.
They're just going to get desensitized a
little quicker than us.
If you can handle it,
the kids can handle it.
Just gonna be trickier,
trickier in the beginning.
But I will tell you bringing it full
circle,
like every time I see real life,
like,
you know,
violence in front of you see somebody
get hit at a bar.
It makes me nauseous.
My problem is I'm so used to it.
I see people get beat up and it's so
normal.
My wife cut her head and she opened up
the back of her car,
you know,
the hood and banged her head on it.
She accidentally the skull but bled.
No,
it wasn't that bad,
but it started bleeding because I talked
about this already.
No,
it started bleeding and um,
I just looked at a cut for her.
I was like this traumatic thing and I'm
like,
they're not even gonna stop this fight.
This is nothing to tap on this.
This is ridiculous.
This is barely cut.
Like there's only one inpatient wounds
bleed a lot and I'm like thinking shit,
I might have to take her to the hospital
for this little baby cut.
And she's gonna freak out if she gonna
let me stick like crazy glue in there
and glue it together because that's what
I would do.
Those my head.
I'd be like,
just drop some crazy shit,
man.
Crying you.
Pansy cuts when you get cut,
they put crazy glue on it and push it
together with the little one gets put
some vinegar on.
My point is I'm so used to trauma,
I'm so used to like dudes getting
punched in the face and you have that
kind of fighting,
bringing constantly do.
And again it comes back to boston once
there's that,
but there's also working for the ufc for
over a thousand fights being three feet
away from these murderers,
these fucking trained killers punting
each other in their head.
You know what I mean?
I've seen so many dudes just get fucking
flatlined.
What's,
what's.
What's the lifespan of a fighter with
the amount of head damage?
Everything,
right?
It's a good question.
I don't think we know.
I'm not saying lifespan.
I'm saying as far as like how long can
you actually fight before it starts to
come in?
Have you seen,
have you seen that it becomes like a
visible issue,
like you start to see things get a
little off?
I have seen guys go from being
absolutely normal to absolutely not
normal,
absolutely normal to frightening.
I've seen that.
I've seen the full spectrum.
That's very shocking and I've seen also
also guys like randy coture who get out
of it with not a,
not a single problem,
you know,
and randy is so super lucid,
you talked to
him,
he's very intelligent,
very aware and you know,
and he's been,
he's been knocked out a couple of times.
He's recognized how to build the brand
though,
right?
Well it's also,
he's a smart guy.
He doesn't take unnecessary punishment.
Some guys,
they try to be more exciting so they'll
take unnecessary punishment.
They'll,
they'll,
they won't fight strategically.
They'll fight like in an aggressive
style and an attempt to overwhelm this
person with their physicality.
And when you do that,
you know,
it makes for an exciting fight for the
fans,
but it's very dangerous for you.
It's very danger for your long term
mental health.
That's a management issue.
You'd assume that demIng fighters have
their managers who kind of advise them
on these impossible.
You can't tell a guy what to do.
There's no way he's going to not going
to listen to you.
If he's.
The guy wears his underwear when he gets
in that fucking cage and they shut that
door.
He's not gonna.
Listen,
yeah.
Fighters will take.
They'll take direction as far as
coaching.
technique.
They'll take direction as far as,
you know,
they have a guy that they really trust
and he raises them correctly and trains
have to be a good fighter.
They'll go out there with a healthy
respect for the art form and they'll go
out there and do it right.
But if you get a guy and he just.
That's how he developed.
He developed like this is a style,
and then he tried to coach him.
It's like,
you know,
good luck.
The new tricks that will you mean.
So to see some fighters and all they
want to do is brawl and they brought
every fight and then you see other
fighters were.
They skillfully avoid strikes.
Take the guy down,
strangle them.
You never see.
Very rarely I should say.
I wouldn't say never.
He never.
He very rarely see someone go from being
the meathead brawler to being the super
intelligent,
ultra skilled technician to get through
a fight and takes no damn.
Imagine you want to be surgical about
it,
right?
You should.
Yeah.
Well you should treat it like what it
is.
It's a martial art and it's a game and
the game is due punishment without
getting punishment done to you.
Be superIor in every single aspect of
the game.
Be able to force your will on that
person.
Yeah.
That's the intelligent part about it.
But you know,
you know,
it's also when you get fight of the
night bonuses and you know,
you want to make the crowd cheer and you
know and get that adrenaline.
Yeah.
And a lot of guys,
you know,
they love to say they finished fights,
they go out there and they put it on the
line and it does make for more exciting
fight.
That's,
that's absolutely true.
But I had this exact conversation with a
guy named john donner,
who's is a pretty infamous jujitsu
instructor,
really super,
super smart guy,
and he and I both agreed that the most
important thing is,
even though it's good to be exciting as
a fighter,
it's good to,
you know,
it's good to please the crowd and it
makes the sport more popular and
everything.
I absolutely agree with that too,
but the most important thing is to be
very skilled and to be the most skilled
and do the exact right thing that you're
supposed to be doing in order to apply
damage,
but take little return.
And when you take unnecessary risks and
you do something in an unsmart manner,
you're degrading your art.
You're,
you're,
you're watering down your purpose.
You're,
you're,
you're doing something that's not the
optimal way to do it.
It's not the artistic way to do it.
You're not,
you're not fighting it correctly.
You know,
it's like riding a wave,
you know,
when you get off that way,
what do you want to do?
You want to face plant into the rocks.
Of course not.
No,
you want to,
you want to ride that bitch and be
perfect.
That's the way that I can't.
I can't speak on them.
And it's just,
it's a world that said so
alien.
Yeah.
I would say it's alien to me and I've
done martial arts my whole life,
but I've never fought in the ufc,
you know,
and being around over at least a
thousand fights,
you know?
Yeah.
But we were talking about like guys like
being used to trauma.
I'm way too used to trauma.
So normal for me.
I've been at bars with dudes are beating
the fuck out of each other.
I'm like,
yeah,
these guys hit each other.
Keep your hands up,
dude.
A fucking pussy.
That's the irony,
right?
Is like,
you know,
when we do these games these days for
your pet as guys and they just need a
terrine arms off beat people to death of
it and like you see anything in real
life and it's just like,
jesus,
I get seven getting sick.
Right.
Well that's a good question man.
So like,
what do you think about this whole
debate that,
you know,
this,
I think it's pretty silly and kind of
like not,
not well thought out,
this idea that violent games make people
violent.
I don't think that's true.
I think whatever happened to crazy first
and foremost,
right?
It's a chris rock's kind of think about
it.
I honestly think it's a situation that
they,
they relieve more stress than they
cause.
LIke it's a cathartic thing.
Like if there's a certain type of mind
that's drawn to a certain type of
entertainment that was just predisposed
to that,
right?
Yeah.
And that person's sick period.
So you're not going to get violent
games.
Was hitler playing?
Right,
that kind of thing.
Right.
And it's just like,
dude,
I mean,
right.
We cannot create a society based upon
the lowest common denominator of
entertainment.
Thank you.
Write like a or anything or anything.
There's,
there's entertainment for kids,
it's entertainment for adults and that's
the way the world works.
I mean it should be that way with
everything.
Access to information,
you know,
propaganda you can't,
you can't like program society for the
lowest common denominator.
What you're doing,
if you're,
if you're not allowing intelligent
people,
we're not going to be effective if
you're trying to restrict their access
to things like video games and I
personally think the market will bear
what the market will bear,
right?
Like you look at what we do with a
styliZed violence of these big giant
guys and space armor.
Ripping the arms of lizard men.
If there's a game about a guy on
flatbush avenue with the yankees hat
pulling off the arm of somebody else
with the red sox hat and it was depicted
real lake,
it be kind of like,
eh,
but then the violence in grand theft
auto on the other hand plays very well
because it's done within the context of
the story or it's done comedically where
you're running over a hooker or
something like that.
Right?
It's all people.
If people are willing to say that,
okay,
but,
but what if the government steps in?
I mean,
there's been many times where there's
been talk about legislating what the
content of video games and making sure
that there's rules what you can and
can't do.
They're already rose though.
That's the thIng.
that's what people forget is the fact
that this rating,
so if there's a rating system,
there's a parental restrictions on the
consoles which are very easy to set and
there's also the fact that the games
costs a certain amount of money in order
to get access to.
There's multiple gateways there that are
in place and on top of all of that there
is of course the parenting issue,
but is there the situation like there is
with movies where they tell you,
hey,
you can't release this unless you cut
out a bunch of shit or it's going to be
like x ray.
It is reviewed,
right?
It is viewed videos nc 17 or something
that you can get an adults only rating,
but it's the.
It's a kiss of death
much like the nc 17.
Whereas you know you're not going to be
in walmart.
You're going to.
You're not going to be in mass effect.
Isn't that at walmart mass effect or
whatever?
The one with the prostitution,
the add and that was massive effect.
Did have some sex type question it,
but there was,
I don't know about.
I don't think it was prostitution in any
mention of amazing that you can have
chain saws and the end of your gun where
you can cut people in half,
but you can't fuck.
Well,
that's America.
that's amazing.
okay.
Okay.
I think or something like that.
Alright.
Alright,
we're back.
Anyway,
it's rough being this cat.
we're going to have to split this up.
This audio is split up.
I'll put it together at the end to ask
her.
you know what the fuck you're doing.
This is the end.
Dum,
dum,
my only friend.
Cliffy be twitter.
Thank you very much man.
It was a lot of fun.
Like I was saying before we cut off,
uh,
we covered everything,
man.
We covered the universe.
We covered video game development.
We covered greedy concert,
black cocks,
brian's whore,
dog.
Anything else?
I'm sorry about my dog.
What else?
Angry birds.
The universe.
The galaxy fighting.
Bleeding technology with glue and dude
come to town once more than once every
five years.
It's tough to get to raleigh and
charlotte.
Even charlotte.
Yeah.
Well maybe I'll do charlie goodnight's
again.
I haven't done that time.
It wasn't.
Yeah,
but you know what?
The problem is too many.
God damn hecklers.
That's why I stopped going there.
There's too many really.
You can always tell him.
Dude.
It was brutal.
The last time was there.
It was just people talking shows.
I'm not.
I mean this is a fun club though.
Great owners too.
Anyway,
ladies and gentlemen,
that's it.
Thank you very much.
Cliff.
He beach like.
Yes,
thank you.
Thank you to the fleshlight for
sponsoring the show.
You can go to [inaudible] dot com and if
you go to joe rogan.net,
there's a link that takes it a
fleshlight.com
and you type in the keyword rogan the
promo code and you get 15 percent off
and then you'd get beat off like a
fucking savage,
like a man alone in the ocean trying to
figure out how to get by on cans and
dried fish and some rainwater that
you've collected.
Fleshlight get enough spit and you're
hallucinating because your fucking skin
is getting cooked off by the son.
You ain't got no sunscreen stupid.
Your dog is just walking all over the
minimum.
So rude.
That's the end of the show.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you very much.
Next week.
Um,
it looks like we're probably going to be
greg fitzsimmons.
He wants to go on.
Cool.
Um,
and uh,
who knows what,
you still got to get brian post and I
still got to call Bobby Lee.
We got a lot of shit happened in people.
Thank you very much for tuning in and we
appreciate all the positive energy and
all the support and all the um,
I appreciate all the people appreciating
the podcast.
It's awesome.
And all the people on twitter and
facebook and all you people out there
sucking cock in the streets.
Good for you.
Wiki leaks,
baby.
Interesting.