Just talk.
We're good.
All right.
We're live sort of sorta.
We're,
we're rolling.
We're rolling.
Dog.
So,
uh,
so we were talking about the game we
stopped because we figured it's probably
be good for the podcast.
So Ari finally paid off the bat.
I paid it off in a big way,
man,
in a big way.
Um,
so if you remember when we were doing
the weight loss challenge,
it was like whoever wins decides the
sporting event,
we're all sports fans basically,
you know,
and,
and I said at the time I was like,
let's go see Barcelona.
I think I wanted to say Barcelona,
play Paris in the,
you know,
some tournament cups,
some channel,
a tournament that they were playing in.
And I was like,
you know,
two of the premier teams and it'd be fun
to go to Europe and make already pay for
it,
you know,
so.
So I told him that and he was like,
I'm going to like fucking Malaysia.
And he just left.
So I never heard from him again.
Then four months later,
you know how it all,
it all played out.
So when he got back,
he was getting fucking slammed by people
because he was supposed to pay up this
bet,
you know,
and people were destroying him,
that I mean,
online,
they were just like,
well true,
you're a piece of shit.
Probably worse than that.
But,
um,
anyways,
once we got,
we got to like hanging out.
Once we did the sober October thing,
um,
he was just like,
right before that actually,
I think he was like,
well,
go.
Which means like,
what do you want to do?
Right?
And I go,
well,
how about I go,
uh,
he was like,
you know,
you pick the event.
I go,
I'm a big college football fan.
Let's go to the national championship
game.
I remember,
uh,
in 20,
at the end of 2013 season 2014 Fsu and
Auburn played in the rosebowl out here
and Burton Fsu alum.
I'm a big FSU fan.
I was like,
let's go to the game.
And I remember that we met,
uh,
it was like we kind of somebody who had
student because they both always win the
national championship.
They allow students to go to the game
for pretty expensive,
much less than the general public can go
for.
In other words,
because you want students have the
ability to go to see their school play.
So we got like student tickets for,
I think they were three slash 50 each
and that's pretty expensive especially
for a student.
But I remember burt treated me.
He,
he bought the ticket for me and we went
to that,
to that game and he left that fucking
halftime of the national championship
game.
Why'd he leave?
He was,
I'm tired.
I got to see the kids had been drinking.
He left.
There was one of the best players left
you there yet?
We were sitting in separate sections,
but I was like,
are you fucking.
I was like texting him.
He was like,
so you were by yourself and he was by
himself?
Yeah,
yeah.
When he knew more people at the game
because a lot of his friends that he
went to school with were at the game
too,
but I'm like,
you're gone.
Did you see the kickoff return that just
the lead just like swung.
He was like,
I'm at home.
I was like,
alright,
so alright psycho.
So weird.
I,
I gave him shit for it.
I still give them shit for it,
but it ended up being just this amazing
finish.
So anyways,
when I tell red I want to go to this,
I'm kinda thinking that's the ballpark.
Like because that's the only experience
I have.
So the games in Atlanta,
he buys tickets and I'm like,
I go,
you're not flying me coach,
you know that.
He's like,
no,
you go first bird rookies,
coach,
you don't work as coach.
And I'll give them a seat bill
extension.
Oh cool.
But burden ended up going from somewhere
else.
So anyways,
he bought the ticket,
he got an Airbnb,
a really nice house,
you know,
for a few days in Atlanta.
And then it's a,
you know,
the big thing is game day.
I'm thinking like,
oh that's cool that you got these
tickets and you got,
you know,
but I think it's reasonable.
And then we get to the stadium.
It was a total fucking disaster to get
in because trump went to the game.
So it was raining.
It was wet secret service everywhere to
our lines to get into the venue and I
paid a guy,
a security guy 100 bucks to walk us
through the line,
which is,
which was almost impossible because it
was so packed,
but I dunno,
he just started walking us through the
line,
like in front of people.
People were yelling at the security guy,
which was like so uncomfortable.
He's like a young black kid and like old
white people,
where the fuck are you doing?
He's like,
I'm security,
and they're like,
you're not security you piece of shit
like right to is right in front of us.
And I was like,
God damn,
like,
I just have never seen someone flip out
like that.
What we were doing was highly unethical.
We shouldn't have done it,
but like we just weren't going to wait
in that line.
And then burt,
of course,
bird in a crowd like that,
he's like,
it's okay.
I'm famous.
Were famous guys like yelling that to
people,
which is like,
no,
you didn't.
Oh absolutely.
He's like,
he's like,
we're everywhere we went.
If we went to a restaurant,
they would come up and be like,
Hey,
can I get you guys something to drink?
And he'd be like,
do you recognize this?
We were like,
they were like,
what was he serious?
I think it's part of his like,
you know,
whatever style.
And then.
And they were like,
I'm sorry,
so part of a joke or part of kind of a
joy.
He's joking but I'm not.
He's like halfway in the middle because
one time,
one time he was like,
we were famous comedians and the lady
was like,
Oh,
I know who you are.
And he was like,
isn't it ultimately the famous guys shut
up and he was serious.
I mean he's like half serious.
He's like,
but it's like you see him in his
element.
It's like him in with crowds is really
like,
you realize that he really enjoys it.
Like he really enjoys the large groups.
He enjoys being recognized.
He fucking like sometimes we were
walking and people were like,
Hey,
you're the guy,
I've seen you on facebook.
He's like,
you want a picture?
And they're like,
okay.
Yeah,
he loves it.
He loves it and then we were talking
about how like people would say,
like,
Tom and I were like,
yeah,
and they're like,
hey,
and then they would walk away,
they wouldn't come over to me.
They were like hi.
And then they'd walk in another way.
But with birth they're like,
hug you to take their shirt off.
They love,
they love it and he's like in his glory
with it is perfect.
So anyways,
we get through this horrific line into
this unbelievable.
One point $6,000,000,000 stadium that
they built in Atlanta.
I mean,
it looks fucking amazing.
It's such a beautiful.
Just standalone stadium,
you know,
is so state of the art.
It's incredible.
We get in there are,
he got us 50 yard line,
so right in the middle,
like 20 rows back and I'm like,
these are fucking amazing.
Like you couldn't ask for better seats.
It has like some club access for like
free booze,
free food,
catered food,
prime rib.
I'm like,
Jesus.
how much did you pay for these tickets?
And he's like,
Oh yeah,
I want to know $3,500 each.
Whoa.
I was like,
are you fucking shit?
And he was like,
Oh,
do it,
do it.
But he spent over 10 grand on tickets
for us.
Wow.
Yeah.
Unreal,
man.
That's amazing.
I mean those are,
those are great seats to like,
those are absolutely amazing seats.
You know,
when the Mcgregor Mayweather fight was
going on.
Yeah,
I was hearing that people were buying
tickets for a quarter million dollars.
That's fucking retarded.
That's so dumb to pay that much money.
But you're balling pretty hard right
now.
I mean,
back in the day he thought about some of
the shit that you're.
Oh,
you can do now.
Yeah,
that's true.
I would be like,
that's impossible.
So we were talking about Jeff Bezos
before the show,
who's now the richest man in human
history.
It's like,
it's inconceivable amount of money.
He's worth $105,000,000,000.
Right?
Which is just like,
what the fuck?
He's like the eighth biggest landowner
in the United States.
Do you know that?
He just buys.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
And I'm not certain though.
No,
of course not.
She goes 300,000 acres of Texas.
Whoa.
That's a lot.
Yeah.
That's a big slab.
I'm pretty sure it's just balling out of
control.
I'm pretty sure his DC home was either
a.
I feel he was either a museum or a hotel
before.
He was like,
make that shit my house now.
It was a museum there,
like it's your house.
I wonder what he's like to hang out with
because there's a photo of him.
See if he could find this.
Photo of Jamie is a photo of Jeff Bezos
from 1993 and he's got like a vinyl
banner above his desk that says
Amazon.com and it's just him and this
Janky little fucking Ikea desk,
like bad kind of Chubby typing away and
she got some muscle and he's jacked and
Tan and probably got a supermodel for
girlfriend.
Does he know he's got a wife for
curricular?
Yeah.
Normal.
Really?
She's an author.
How long?
I know I'll have.
He doesn't schedule morning meetings so
you can hang out with the kids.
Really?
Yeah.
Wow.
I read all this stuff.
I wonder why he's going so hard.
Hm.
You know,
when you hit 105 boop,
boop,
boop billion.
Yeah.
You would think you'd go,
Eh,
we're good.
I now I think you just start really
collecting because you're like.
Because you know,
when he bought the Washington Post,
you know,
it's not like he's like,
I love journalism.
He be cool to own a newspaper.
You know what I mean?
Like what do you at that level,
you're just like,
I like waterfalls.
Are there any for sale or something?
You know,
he's got Washington Post is one of the
weird ones where you get a link some,
they'll send you a link and you click on
it and it's a Washington Post article
and it says,
you obviously love great journalists.
Right?
Sign up like fuck off.
They don't even give you the free reads.
I feel that New York Times will give you
10 free.
I signed up after I,
you know,
I kept clicking those.
I was like,
I didn't sign up Washington Post.
I feel like click number one.
They're like,
do you want to read this?
You have to pay or not?
Yeah,
I'm not,
I'm not paying.
Yeah,
I mean I,
I,
I support paying for journalism,
but I feel like I should give us a
taste.
You know,
we could get a little taste.
It's tough to trust journalism these
days.
It's tough to trust like how fucking
weird or your article's going to be.
That's true.
It's true.
Journalism was tough.
Watching news has become,
man.
I remember when it started to skew to
personality and taste.
Now it's like off the rails.
It is off the rails.
That's where the money is.
I know,
but it's like you were totally just
going with who?
Like you're going to watch,
you can select what do I feel like
leaning towards.
Then you watch that.
Tucker Carlson.
Yeah.
Or you know.
Rachel maddow theory is.
That's that picture.
Oh my God.
Isn't that crazy?
Yes.
He looks nothing like that.
Now it's what 105 billion will do.
He's just sitting there with that
Amazon.com banner.
I hope that's still hanging somewhere in
his house.
Yeah,
he probably shoots loads on that.
What do you.
Oh my God.
Yeah,
crazy that he started out.
I remember Amazon being a book thing.
Yeah.
I remember being a place to buy books
and I remember thinking how weird like
an online bookstore,
why wouldn't you just go to the
bookstore store where you could see the
book,
right?
Like,
and all those bookstores shut.
She like,
they closed.
So there's only a few left.
Well,
I know a guy who got a deal with
Amazon.com to publish a book,
like when Amazon started publishing
books and they blackballed him because
of this,
because he had had a traditional outlet
deals before and you know,
his books would be front and center in
Barnes,
noble and all those other different
places.
He's a pretty popular author,
but as soon as you went to Amazon.com,
they're like fuck you.
And they just shut them out.
They shut him out of all those stores.
Yeah.
And I was like,
whoa.
Like there's like a weird book war going
on that I didn't know about.
They're both probably try mean
those book.
People were trying to keep their
business model going and thriving,
you know?
And he wasn't doing it by threats is
never the way to go.
Probably not.
No.
I mean the best way to go is when Amazon
publishes a book that people actually
want to buy in your store.
You dumb fuck shirt and your store.
You know what I hate about these?
A super rich guys.
They'll never,
they never in their interviews have like
the only one who will talk like what
it's like to ball at that level and make
it sound fun.
And like the things you want to ask is
Mark Cuban.
I've seen him in interviews be like,
I got last shit and like knows that.
Like that's a genuine curiosity for
people.
Like how fun is that?
You have to 7:47.
He's like,
yeah man,
that's pretty cool.
Right?
And he talks about it,
but I saw this interview with gates and
this guy was asking all those questions.
He was like,
you have to worry about like when
somebody asks you to,
like,
when you ask for something that
someone's gonna try to ask for more
because of your known wealth.
He's like,
you know,
my charity really is like,
just like dodging all those questions of
like the fun ship that everyone wants.
He just kept going back to his charity
and we're like,
we know you're a fucking charitable guy.
Tell us what it's like to own six
planes,
bro.
Like what kind of Shit do you have?
Like Zana do house.
It's like 70,000 square feet or
something.
Well,
he's got a house.
I think it's on puget sound.
Um,
it's somewhere in the Seattle area.
Medina,
Medina or Medina says that what it is,
I think is what it's called.
It's so freaky.
Look at that.
Looks like using an ad blocker.
What'd he pulled up?
Which pull up 19 crazy facts about his
house.
Oh,
okay.
One hundred $23,000,000.
Disable your ad blocker so we can read
it.
So we,
um,
we were in Seattle and there's this
thing that's near a bridge,
um,
where you,
you go under this bridge and they have
this,
uh,
these clear walls where you can see the
salmon swimming up the salmon ladders,
like they have everything set up with
these clear like glass walls.
So you can watch it.
It's really pretty bad ass.
But the guy who was there who was the,
uh,
you know,
the guide of this thing,
who's explaining us how this works in
which kind of salmon you're looking at,
the whole deal.
He was like,
you know,
my uncle worked on the bill.
Gurtz almost starts talking about Bill
Gates' house where Bill Gates House and
where he lives.
And I remember thinking like,
how weird must've be if you're so rich
that all everybody wants to do is talk
about like,
Hey,
my friend worked on your who's Huh?
And I was like,
well,
what's it like?
And he just starts describing skill as
well.
He has some sort of a submarine access
and Casey's getting kidnapped.
Like someone's trying to jack them.
They can get in a submarine shoot out
into the river and I'm like,
what?
Yeah,
I don't know how much of that is even
true because this guy seemed like he was
missing a little piece of his brain
start really adding stuff to it.
I was like,
how much of this is urban myth?
I know that they were reporting even
like,
I don't know when that house was built
10,
15 or whatever years ago
that even back then there was shit in
his house because it was super high tech
of like if you walk in a room,
music would play as you left the room.
Music would die down and pick up in the
next room so that you know,
it had,
which I think you could probably regular
person could probably do something like
that now,
but that was unheard of.
I think you wore a pin him pin on and
that pen as you walked into different
rooms,
recognize that you were the person so
you had specific colors that you liked,
so they'd be like backlighting.
That was his kids.
He's big on.
He's the one that started that giving
pledge.
Which is for billionaires to give the
overwhelming majority of their wealth to
charity so that you don't pass on
billions to your children.
Right.
You like,
so his thing is like,
I'm going to leave my kids money but not
like crazy that money.
Which you're like,
yeah,
that's,
you know,
I totally get the idea behind that.
But also like if you grew up with his,
you know,
you're his kid and you're like,
oh there's,
we got lions this year.
And then you're like,
you know,
you grow up and you're like,
I'm a photographer now.
Uh,
my dad left me $5,000,000 but like
$5,000,000 is great.
It's great.
But my thing is like,
it's such a step down from what they're
used to.
I feel even remotely bad for some
fucking kid who gets $5,
million dollars from ms dot don't feel
bad.
What I'm saying is that that adjustment
has to kick you in the balls.
I mean,
the exposure that they've had,
the lifestyle is like,
it's not,
it's unfathomable to us.
Like we can't even,
it's beyond.
They're just like a.
it's like being the prince,
you know,
it's like your dad's assaulting a Brunei
and then he's like,
well go fuck him.
I mean,
they're probably,
well just that.
I don't know why I assumed that,
but I think that like,
uh,
he and his wife seem like such
reasonable people that I bet they've
prepared them for,
for,
for what's coming while they've got to
figure out a way to make it on their own
and how do you get a kid to do that?
That's tough,
right?
You know,
how do you get a kid to do that?
Who's,
who's grown up like that?
Yeah.
I don't think about that with your kid.
Like as you're starting to ball out of
control.
Yeah,
I think about it for sure.
Like,
um,
how do you,
and then like had to not,
you know,
you want to prepare your kid for that
and then how does,
how will a boy,
I don't know,
maybe especially a boy's aligned with
their dads usually in a certain way,
you know,
like kid compares himself to you and
your success,
but you don't want them to feel like,
uh,
you know,
he's less than in your shadow.
Sure.
Especially like,
what if he goes into comedy.
Oh my God.
Have you thought about if your daughters
were to go with my seven year old's
hilarious.
She's really funny.
Does she ever like,
uh,
I'm sure she like,
does she know what the fuck comedy is?
No,
she just knows how to be silly and she's
seen me on TV doing it.
Not
really,
no.
She flipped through Netflix and makes
fun of me.
Really?
She's,
yeah.
Yeah.
Nice jeans.
Dad starts mocking me.
Really?
Yeah.
She's just ruthlessly funny.
She goes after a seven year old.
Is the younger.
Yeah,
she goes after it all the time,
going after jokes.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
She's just,
she's really funny.
But I see her becoming like a youtube
character or something.
Well,
how do you,
what do you think about as far as like
them not feeling,
you know,
overwhelmed by your success or status?
Do you ever think about that?
I think it's less likely because they're
girls,
you know,
but um,
I was actually having a conversation
with Neil Brennan about this last night.
We were talking about another famous
guy,
I don't know him that well,
so I won't use his name,
but he has a Tucson's and uh,
at least one daughter.
The daughter is highly motivated.
He's not worried about it at all.
She kicks ass in school.
She's awesome.
The sons are fucking insanely lazy and
they just sit around and they know that
when they turn 26,
they get a giant check and they're 25
now and boy they don't do shit.
And he's civil super worried about it.
I wouldn't be able to do,
you know,
that's a,
that's like a nightmare man.
Well,
it's like,
it's so hard to actually do something if
you don't have to.
It's so hard to,
to make something happen in your life,
right?
To start a business,
to enter into a career and become
successful at it,
to really focus and try to get good to
the point where you're successful at
something.
You have to have a fire inside of you.
You have to have a need to achieve.
And if you already have a Ferrari and
you're already living in a mansion,
you already have $10,000,000 in the
bank.
You already have all your bills paid.
You don't have to get up in the morning
if you don't want to get the idea of
just becoming this discipline machine
out there to try to kick ass in this
life and be self actualized.
So hard,
so hard to pull off.
You got to like dial back to on the
spoiling.
I think I went to high school with a
grand son of a billionaire and they were
very present in the area,
you know,
and uh,
they drove,
used cars,
the grandkids I'm saying and had
obviously they could have gotten way
more,
but it was like instilling this.
You're not just going to coast through
everything and they got jobs and uh,
as far as I know about now,
what he's doing now is like,
he's working,
he's really working,
even though he's gonna inherit like just
crazy amounts of money,
you know,
but I mean,
part of it too is just the nature of
that person.
I think you can try to not go crazy with
um,
you know,
taking care of them gifts and all that
stuff.
But some of that drive has to come from
within no matter what your socioeconomic
level is.
Yeah,
I would imagine some of it.
I think there's people that are grow up
rich that it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
They're just,
they're going to succeed.
They love it.
They like succeeding.
They like working hard.
They like getting things done within.
There's like what causes a kid to be a
lazy fuck,
you know,
like you come home,
the kids on the couch just with their
feet up and they don't do what I asked
you to do.
I was gonna yeah.
But something happened.
Mike called and fucking.
I know people like cars and gas and I
think there's something wrong with just,
I mean,
I know people like that who you want to
shake the fuck is wrong with you,
but they,
I think a lot of times they just,
it's almost like they fear doing the
thing.
They're scared,
they're scared.
What if I do something and I suck at it,
you know,
that kind of thing.
There's definitely that.
There's,
will you see that in a lot of,
um,
like
amateur comics that are sort of starting
to make it into comedy?
Yeah.
You see like a lot of like sabotage.
Do you know that stress of you're just
doing open mic nights and then all of a
sudden you starting to get paid and then
some people start moving forward and
other people get left behind.
I remember,
remember those days,
of course I remember thinking like,
man,
boy,
there's a lot of people here that are
sabotaging themselves.
Oh yeah.
See the stress of [inaudible] stand up
in particular,
so open ended like you could make of it
what you want.
You put in as much as you want.
You either can be successful or not
depending upon how much you focus on it,
how much talent you have,
how much drive and discipline you have
in a couple of breaks,
a couple breaks.
There's a bunch,
bunch of factors and sometimes those
factors are just too overwhelming to
some people and see them just start
tanking it.
They're drinking at the store every
night.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Because it's scary.
The truth is that it's scary.
Yeah.
I remember when people handle it
different ways.
Like I remember the people who'd be
like,
they would just say like,
this is a,
you know,
this isn't going to work out.
Like I don't know why we're doing this.
Oh yeah.
Those people.
And I always was always like,
dude,
don't talk to me anymore.
You don't want to hear.
Yeah,
you're fucking so negative.
But they do in that just to sort of
eliminate that pain of failing.
Yeah.
You know,
just trying to like,
just address it now.
Eh,
come on,
we're just normal guys.
Never going to happen.
Never going to.
And I will just get a fucking regular
job,
will be working for Amazon or something.
And you're like,
what are you talking about,
man?
Yeah.
There's people who are like,
yeah,
this doesn't know he can't make any
money doing this.
I remember that a lot too.
It's like you can't make any money doing
this.
I was like,
Whoa,
you can't make any money right now.
It doesn't mean you're not going to make
money later.
And they're like,
how are you going to get to later?
Because there's no money now.
I'm like,
you know,
it's almost this weird.
Do you remember the development deal
years?
Were you around during the development
deal in detail?
And I was at the where they were like,
they were like,
ah,
two years ago you would make $600,000
for that same Jesus Christ.
I was there for the development deal
years,
but I kind of was working during.
Most of it was during most of it.
I was doing news radio when it got
really hot,
I was doing news news radio and I
remember that there were comics that
would go to Montreal.
They would do the comedy festival,
they would have these sets and they
would come back and they had half a
million dollar deals and they were,
there was sitcoms and they were
convinced that it was all fucking
happening for them and I remember I had
quite more than one conversation with
one of these people that we're trying to
put me on their show comics that have
never worked since,
like do not hear from them bro.
My shows guaranteed is what's going to
happen.
It's guaranteed go to air.
It doesn't go there.
There's a million dollar backup deal.
Like they had all this stuff that they
were telling you about,
like they went the opposite way instead
of like being like terrified of the
future to the point where they were just
letting themselves off the hook.
They were super confident in this weird
delusional.
It's definitely happened for me thing.
Odd Man.
Yeah.
It's odd to subscribe.
I see.
That would always scare me because I'm
more.
My,
my just more life perspective is like
you don't,
you don't react until the check clears.
Yeah.
Right.
And every.
Yeah.
I don't go like that's definitely
happening.
No,
it's always like wait and see.
Well those people that.
It was interesting because they.
None of them made it.
Yeah.
None of them and they were all
convinced,
but it was a weird convinced.
It was like if you what?
You're not even that good.
That's what I wanted to tell him.
Like you got lucky man.
You had a pretty.
You're Kinda cute.
He had a pretty decent set in front of
a,
a very willing crowd and someone took a
chance on you because people are.
There was a nutty time.
I guess we should describe it to people.
There was a nutty time where they were
just chucking around development deals
like a regular person who probably had
no business being on stage.
You get $100,000 development deal.
Yeah,
we,
I literally just missed that.
I think they said that the last big one
that they talked about was like,
oh five.
They're like,
that was one of the last big six figure
development deals,
which is basically you go to Montreal,
which is the just for laughs.
Big Festival.
All the executives go,
they all basically party for a week.
Yeah.
It was like an excuse to do work and
then,
you know,
they were signing people up with those
checks and we literally,
I went in the o seven new faces class
and they're like,
uh,
two years ago someone got,
I got $850,000 for his 15 minutes at
850.
One of the big last big ones that
failed.
They had a record.
There was like a tallying of like this
person,
this person,
this person all got them and nothing
came of it.
And then went all in and Oh,
five on a couple of other people and
then that didn't pan out some.
So they're like,
fuck these development deals man.
Now it's done.
No,
never.
It never happens.
Now you know,
you never hear about them.
No.
I got one in 93.
I got a development deal.
Ninety three.
Wow.
Yeah.
One of the first ones are just just for
the festival.
Wow.
Yeah.
I went to the festival with a deal.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I had a deal with Disney.
Now they,
that shit never happens.
It was the weirdest thing in the world
because it was,
I went from being fucking broke,
like,
oh,
I'm making $300 this weekend if I go to
this place and do a set on Friday night.
Yeah.
And then,
uh,
you know,
you got six figures.
Yeah.
Did you think,
were you like,
this is crazy right now?
I got 100 the first time and then there
was a second part of it where I got 50.
It was just like,
what?
I was eating lobster every night.
Then you say that your accountant
manager,
he thought I had a gambling problem.
So funny.
It's like,
nope,
just kidding.
Yeah.
And he was like,
what?
How are you spending so much money?
I was like,
I'm just spending money.
Like,
this is how I'm going to live from now
on.
Yeah.
He's like,
that is the stupidest fucking thing I've
ever heard in my life.
Why I was right.
Yeah,
because I was right.
you're right.
It just took a chance.
Yeah.
That's so cool.
It could have turned out terribly wrong,
but the,
the thing that was weird about it,
that was the most incredible thing was
that once I started working and wants
the money,
the check came in and um,
I didn't have to think about my bills
anymore.
There was a physical feeling of relief,
like a physical feeling of relief.
Yeah.
To go from being broke and have no idea
how you're going to pay your bills and
just trying to hustle up $100 sad or a
$75 set somewhere to go from that to
just not having to worry about money.
Yeah.
Instantaneously instantaneously,
you know,
after taxes,
having x amount of dollars in the bank
and just go on and what that's in the
bank.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
I know.
But then the feeling like a lightness of
being like,
like I felt physically lighter,
like it's so much of your life,
it consumes you for so much of your life
is like.
And there's this bill and then there's
that bill.
It's like it's on your mind all the
time.
Yeah.
You know,
like shit.
And I got no,
I got these weeks of work lined up,
but then that other thing is going to
come up so I better not,
I need to call it because it's all you
think about,
but I think it goes the other way too.
I think that when you get to like this
Jeff Bezos level,
I think then all of a sudden it's a
burden because I feel like there isn't
the lightness.
The lightness is like Brian Cowen had a
saying once and I've repeated it a bunch
of time because I think he nailed it.
He said you want to get rich enough so
that you don't have to worry about your
bills and you don't have to worry about
how much things cost when you go to eat
at a restaurant.
Yeah,
that's great.
It was everything else after that is
bullshit.
That's true.
Yeah.
All that other stuff like acquiring
stuff and jewelry and shit like that,
like dealing with all that.
No,
you're right.
And it's like,
um,
there's that thing too when like when
you have enough money to go to
restaurants and sometimes you'll go to a
and they'll like and the
special is a this cut of meat and
there's a lobster on the side and it's
69,
95 and you're like,
not a problem.
I always feel like it's weird when I
tell you the price,
I know you're like,
what the fuck is going to embarrass me
here at the table?
I'm good.
But instead it's an odd thing.
Like sometimes they tell you the price
and sometimes they don't.
Sometimes they just tell you the special
we have a rack of lamb.
That sounds good.
Nice restaurants.
A lot of times there's multiple items.
It just says market price.
Yeah,
that's a weird one.
And you can just be like,
I want that.
And they're like,
you said.
So they just bring it to you.
Like that's $400.
Like what?
Yeah,
what kind of market is this?
This is crazy,
but don't you think that if you get to
the point where you're worth $105,
billion dollars just to focus on you
alone,
it's a lot.
Yeah.
It must be overwhelming.
And also to the Bill Gates thing is
like,
it is the thing that everybody probably
wants to ask you talk about.
Oh yeah.
It's like everyone knows you have a 15
inch Dick and then let me see,
just let me see it.
Can I touch it tastes like a regular
Dick.
Like his limp and shifting and just.
It's crazy.
It's like knowing that about someone.
It's all everyone.
So yeah,
I think that energy,
you feel that everyone's like you're
super rich because we're all fascinated,
especially in this country with,
you know,
accumulating wealth.
It's like,
I feel like it's.
I feel like it's heightened here.
Yeah,
for sure.
Well,
I mean think about how much of the
culture is about balling.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
It's all about young entertainment.
Culture is all about diamonds and
stepping out of role.
I saw this dude,
I don't know his name.
They showed him getting a jewelry that
he bought and you saw that and it has an
emblem with the 69 and it spins and he's
got like diamond teeth and then he had
like,
he had like 200 grand in his waistband.
He just took it out and was like,
ah,
stacking the money.
It's just like,
it's a fascination with like,
look how much shit I have,
all this shit I can buy.
Like that's part of the culture now and
going on for a long time.
It has been coming up from poverty.
That's what it is.
It's the,
the idea is that these guys were all
like super poor and then they made it in
here.
This is what happens when you make it.
It's kind of,
you know what it's kind of also,
uh,
we see that in like hip hop a lot here,
but it's also what you saw with a major
drug traffickers.
They all come from extreme poverty.
All of them.
Uh,
El Chapo,
Pablo Escobar,
super,
super poor.
And they accumulate in crazy amounts of
wealth.
And then they're like,
look at all my shit.
You know,
it's like you see this,
like the parallel.
It's the same thing.
Yeah.
Like when Pablo Escobar,
oh my God,
when he had the hippos and shit.
Fucking zoo.
Yeah,
he had when he built his prison time,
but I'm building it and there was soccer
fields and then he would fly in national
players like play soccer with me today.
And they're like,
okay.
And even after all that,
he was like,
Nah,
I don't want to speak anymore.
I'm going to get out of here.
And we'll even.
Yeah,
somebody else built his own prison.
Columbia,
they had parties.
Joey Diaz got me on this show because I
watched narcos,
which is a great netflix series.
And then there's another series called
surviving Escobar.
And it's,
it,
it follows a escobar had a right hand
man,
uh,
his right hand.
Hitman killed like 300 people for him
named John Heidel of Alaska is baskets.
And if follows him from like the day
they got Escobar and this guy turned
himself in and it shows him in prison
and how he just ended up starting
another cartel from basic,
from within prison.
And it's a fascinating series.
Yeah,
that's it.
And this is a new netflix pressure.
I think what happened was that I feel
like it was a.
seems like it was a Colombian series
that they acquired,
is what it seems like.
I'm not sure,
but it's really good.
I mean,
it's,
it's all in Spanish,
uh,
with subtitles.
But it's,
that's the real guy on,
in that picture right there.
Is that guy still alive?
Yeah.
His nickname is popeye.
And uh,
he,
yeah,
he fucking murdered so many people and
they had such a dedication to their
bosses.
That's one of the things they followed
them,
like religious leaders,
you know,
like if he's in an interview Popeye,
this guy saying,
if Pablo Escobar had told me to kill my
dad,
I would have done it.
What?
Like I wouldn't have hesitated either
that they have such devotion to the boss
really was a dick.
Maybe it was like,
yeah,
my dad was a big asphalt.
So yeah,
of course I killed.
There's that movie that's coming out now
about,
um,
the,
the uh,
the lady from cocaine cowboys.
The fuckers are now resell to Blanca
cell.
Done.
Yeah.
We have Jennifer Lopez.
No,
it's Catherine Zeta Jones.
Oh,
that's right.
And she actually made her like,
not as hot.
Really?
Yeah.
I mean she,
she's like 80 now.
That's just 150 years old.
She weighs 6:50.
Like Bert.
Yeah,
we took pictures a picture before we
went to the game together.
[inaudible] posed together.
Right.
I have a tee shirt on.
Bert has like a Hoodie like this with
pockets and then a jersey over it.
So it just looks so much everybody.
Everybody was like,
Jesus Christ Bergs you put on 400 that
picture because he,
he has like six layers on photo.
It was all.
They were all pretty slim there though.
Are we got fat for awhile?
He.
Yeah.
I already got into a serious.
A candy.
A addiction.
Oh quite a bit.
Uhm,
which is fucking terrible for you.
That sugar fat.
Just getting fat from nothing but sugar.
But he just decided to cut it out as the
weight.
Yeah.
I look good.
We look.
That was a long time ago though,
but the way he did it was pretty
interesting.
Just said,
ah,
I don't want to be fat anymore.
That's a good way to do it.
Didn't join weight watchers,
didn't do anything.
Here's a body that responds to that
pretty well too though.
You know,
like I feel like there's different.
There's definitely different body types
and he's the kind that could probably
make a slight adjustment and see things
sway.
Well,
I guarantee with burdens,
booze,
if burt just cut off the booze,
I mean he would lose a massive amount of
weight.
He goes so hard.
It's,
it's bizarre.
Yeah.
Now he goes hard,
man.
To the point where I was really stunned
that he made it through sober October.
I was stunned.
I think he really responds to challenges
he likes.
He likes,
he likes to challenge because he,
you know,
he,
we always joke how he speaks in
hyperbole and he's always just like,
yeah,
like if you go like I bet you can do
like definitely could to do that.
It's always immediate.
Yes.
Without consideration of it.
He's like,
I can definitely do that.
Yeah.
Now already said when we were hanging
this weekend because I was like,
I'm definitely doing definitely doing
the La Marathon and I think it's in
April and he's like,
if you do that I will show up in roller
skates.
I will fucking kill you.
And like there's no way.
There's just no way.
And we were like,
what are you talking about?
Like you can casually rollerskate a five
minute mile casually.
Not even close.
No sweating.
No.
And he's like after,
after when your feet hurt.
So it just push through it.
Like why,
why do you think you can push through
something and somebody else can't.
We'll just fucking push through.
It will beat you.
I was like,
I'll go take a nap and get back and then
still be cute.
Was like,
no,
definitely definitely be used.
Well he ran a half marathon.
He did and he did surprisingly well.
I didn't think he would do that.
How long did it take them to run a half
marathon?
One to say it was like the 2:40,
something like that.
Right?
Something like that.
Maybe to 35 to 45,
something that.
Is that a clean split like can you say,
oh,
that means that you would do a five hour
marathon?
I don't necessarily lower.
You'd be slower.
You get tired.
Yeah.
That second half and everyone that I've
talked to said especially that last
stretch,
like the last five miles are supposed to
be the most taxing,
you know?
Yeah.
I mean,
mom,
my friend campaigns is running a
marathon.
It's really,
really crazy.
Really crazy psychopath.
I know.
And you watch him,
you know,
I pull up his instagram and I'm like,
just fucking positive man.
Just do it.
He's getting up every morning before
work has a regular job.
Is running fucking miles and miles at
six in the morning.
And I heard her say the only thing that
made him seem human was him talking
about there was a time when he said it
was hard to run a mile or something.
He was like,
yeah,
I remember when it was hard to run a
mile.
I'm like,
seriously?
You had trouble running a mile?
Yeah.
When he first started running like
everybody else,
running is a weird thing,
man.
They been doing it a lot more.
Yeah,
but when I do it now too,
it's a.
I'm kind of amazed.
I think back at like where it used to be
difficult
and it's not difficult there anymore.
I'm like,
well,
how come it's not?
It's almost like your brain's like,
well what happened?
Like,
what changed?
How come I can just run up this section
now and hustled through here and push
through around this corner and get up to
that Ridge and go over the top and then
to the top and that's where I stopped
now.
Why did I get so much further?
Yeah,
you brought your.
Your body does.
It's almost like your brain doesn't want
to believe that your body can get in
better shape.
Like you know,
you can,
you know,
like when I work out and have worked out
for a long time and I'm fit and I'll do
like rounds in the bag or something like
that.
I'll know I'm not getting as tired as
they used to be,
but I don't want to believe it.
That is weird why your body is your
brain is.
It's like trying to keep you from
progressing in a way.
I don't know.
It's like your brain has memories of the
Times where you were getting tired doing
stuff that you're not getting tired
anymore.
Confused.
Like what's happening here?
I've been doing,
I hired a trainer and a part of our
workouts has been bike sprints,
like stationary bike sprints.
Fuck men.
Do you get an airdyne sprint or do you
do just like a regular bike sprint?
Um,
I mean it's a stationary bike,
right?
So I don't know what type of bike it is,
but it's like,
it'll be like a max out 32nd sprint and
recovery.
I've never felt as close to dying
really.
How it's like,
I mean,
especially on like the third sprint,
it's like,
you know,
lungs,
heart,
quads are just like,
I,
I have a whole new respect just for
cyclists,
just doing those fucking stupid sprints.
I do.
It's just,
it's so taxing.
You know,
it just.
Where'd you get this guy?
I found him just searching and I met him
and then uh,
started doing where he's just been given
me like a one on one and I've been doing
is just mixing it up so like we'll have
like strength phase where it's like
power days,
you know,
like higher weight,
lower reps and then he'll throw in core
stuff and then we'll do high rep days.
I like the mixing it up.
I guess I get bored,
you know,
and of course it's been fun to like work
out with somebody who mean he knows his
shit and has been like super
challenging.
What's his name?
You want to know his name?
Just give me his first name.
Uh,
there's two dudes.
Two different guys do different guys.
You go to two different guys.
You have two trainers.
I got three extra.
Hashtag Paulin.
I guess what I'm talking about again,
how your kids can relate to you.
Man.
The Guy had three trainers,
dad's on tinkers.
Daddy's got a six pack.
I got,
I got a trainer,
I got Micah,
Shawn and Kelly.
So how do you mix it up?
Why do you go to three different people?
Um,
as you can?
Yeah.
Just to make it challenging.
Different.
Yeah.
Just to do different shit.
Really.
This the truth.
Real.
Yeah.
Just to do different shit because I know
that I'm going to get something
different out of them on different days.
And how many times a week you work it
out.
Now if you've got three different
trainers,
you must be hitting them at least once a
week.
Each guy I'm doing like three or four
days a week.
Yeah.
Tommy bonds can shape [inaudible] I'm
super strong,
man.
Yeah.
I don't know why,
but it just happened because your
family's.
Yeah.
Recognize me.
Here's one picture.
He was a real pleasure to her shirts on.
Girl Goes,
oh my friend that works here at this bar
is a big fan of yours to burt.
We used sign the back of this to her.
He was like,
how about a video?
And,
and then she goes,
okay,
take shirt off in a black cigar bar in
Atlanta.
Okay.
And like everybody.
Yes.
And then he takes the camera and he goes
like up his stomach.
Fuck.
But of course she was like,
that's fucking awesome.
Of course she lost her mother.
Of course him and I saw this,
like,
what happened here?
Dude?
He just,
he's a.
we're buying booze and nobody was
dancing.
Oh yeah.
Just him.
He got the vibe going,
man,
I'm telling you,
this is natural element.
He's also about 19 drinks in 19 boy.
He looks hammered.
I mean that whole,
that whole store was dancing with him.
People walked in and knew him or he's
drunk to look at art dancing.
He dances like the widest phish fan
ever.
That's so true.
It's like jumping up and down with his
legs together.
These guys knew him.
Yeah,
it was.
He was in.
He was in heaven,
man.
Boy.
What a.
What a weird life that Bert Kreischer
lives.
So he's really as the party guy.
Oh yeah.
Just the machine.
I think for awhile I was like,
that's your act like I'm your friend,
but that's your act.
And then I hung up hanging out.
You're like,
that's really who you are,
man.
You really the party guy.
He enjoys it.
Yeah.
But it's so rough on your body.
I don't know,
he pushes through man.
It's amazing.
He gets up the next day and was like,
he'll be like,
I'm really feeling it.
But you're like,
you don't notice,
you know,
you know what I did when we went out to
breakfast on,
um,
what was it Monday?
I think it was Monday.
Yeah,
we went to breakfast the day of the game
and uh,
my friend Justin lives in Atlanta,
it comes over,
picks us up and he's like,
oh,
first feeling more than we sit down at
this breakfast place,
coffees,
and we ordered breakfast and he orders
eggs and toast and bacon or something.
And then he's like,
all right.
And then as the waitress walks go,
oh,
could you send them a waffle also?
Um,
like in front of him,
you know,
and he's like,
what?
And I go,
you like waffles?
And he's like,
yeah,
that's true.
So she's like this massive,
awful.
He was like,
this was a really good decision.
It's totally tearing it up.
Scarfing.
Yeah.
I know he wants to do another challenge.
He was talking about doing something.
He keeps bringing things up and makes
these videos already threw one at us.
Yeah,
yeah.
Which I think actually would probably,
again,
it's something that would benefit him
the most,
but other people will get benefits from
it too.
Was the go phone free social media free
for a month?
Oh,
that's Ari.
Ari does that all the time.
All the time.
That's like me asking you guys to do
Jujitsu.
Yeah.
No,
but I think like I,
I respected the challenge in terms of
like,
yeah,
I do look at that shit too much.
I do it,
you know,
it takes,
it takes too much of your focus away,
which like already talked about.
And then of course where it was like
easy,
like it's not easy for you.
You're on it.
He brings his charger with him when we
go.
When we went out I was like,
why?
He's like curious.
My battery runs out like you have 70
percent,
how are we going to run out?
And you've used it a lot.
He's always on it.
So I was like,
that's actually a good challenge for you
because you are consumed with it.
But he was like,
I don't know,
he was pretty hesitant to accept that.
The problem with that is it's a,
it's a tool for work.
That's the point.
But his thing was like,
well,
you can have your assistant,
the guy that helps produce your podcast.
You could send him things and be like,
Hey,
you got to post these things.
You could post these promotions for my
shows and Blah,
blah blah.
But you can't be on.
They're consumed by likes and consumed
by comments and and that whole thing.
I Dunno,
it was just,
it was just definitely an idea.
It's not a bad idea.
It's not a bad challenge.
Good luck with it.
I'm out.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean,
I think the physical stuff is really,
really interesting and fun.
The physical stuff,
the most interesting.
Even like even for me,
a guy who does yoga on a regular basis,
doing 15 of them in a month,
it was like,
wow,
I've got a lot to make up.
What would it be?
Another good one.
I don't know.
But let me tell you something,
that the last nine days I did nine days
straight,
you know,
of Yoga and it wasn't the last nine
days.
I had plenty of time to go,
but I just decided to burn it all out in
one shot.
I was like,
I'm learning a lot about myself.
Like I've never done anything that's
that hard.
Ninety minute hot yoga classes,
nine days in a row with no days off.
I was like,
if you just don't give yourself a day
off,
your body starts to adapt to not having
a day off.
You can accomplish way more than you
think you can.
That's what that shit taught me.
You ever had like those.
I remember being on the road once and
having a deadline for a writing packet.
It was some type of submission or they
were like,
I was getting paid like,
well you got to send it in by this by
like tomorrow.
Yeah.
And I was doing so much writing in the
hotel room and that when I submitted it
and everything was fine,
I was like,
man,
I could get a lot of work that in these
hotel rooms.
Good.
But I needed that experience to tell me
that.
Yeah.
Because all the time I'm like just
sitting around and he's fucking hotel,
right.
You just watching TV,
flipping through the channels and not
doing shit.
Watching those fucking pawn shop shows
and they're like,
I just wrote fucking 20 pages.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
If you just make yourself do it or you
have.
Like for me I have to have have two,
but one thing does help is when I have a
schedule of shit that I wrote down.
Like I have to work on my act for an
hour a day for five days.
Put that in there.
Yeah.
Like that's.
I give my,
I,
I think that's really reasonable.
I'll give myself five hours of writing a
week.
That's totally to light.
It's light work.
I've been working on it more expensive.
I know my special special comes out
tomorrow.
Oh Shit.
Tommy Netflix,
special number three in the pipe.
Bitch.
I'm exciting.
Fresh coming out to Ivan.
I'm excited for it.
But I also have that,
that uh,
10 special anxiety corner where you're
like,
oh,
it's back to square one.
But that's where the material comes
from.
Right?
Totally.
Yeah,
of course.
And I'm actually,
I personally,
I don't know if everyone works this way.
I definitely work better when it's a,
when it's 100 percent out,
in other words,
not like the month to like,
you know,
it's coming out in two months when it's
actually out.
I feel the fear and the drive more,
I create more when I,
when I know it's all,
it's gone now I,
it really fuels me.
Me Too.
Same thing.
But it's the scariest fucking thing in
the world.
Herald not scariest thing in the world,
but it's,
it's scary because you're,
you're so terrified of being up on stage
with what I call without weapons.
Nothing.
Yeah.
So you have to like really focus on
getting that shit done.
Yeah.
And then I find myself going to the
store with notebooks.
I'm going over the shit before age just
really tightened in.
Yeah.
I'm doing a couple of spots tonight.
Like,
yeah,
I have like all new shit.
You have one hour you have.
I mean you literally have like one day.
Yeah.
And then in one day.
Better have all new shit tonight.
You can go up and just whip out some
polished,
smooth fucking sharpened weapons.
I actually thought about it and it's
like,
you know,
I've been,
I have been for the last especially
month or so really focused on the new
stuff and I go,
so tonight's the last night.
Do I feel like doing like will I do,
I want to say that thing one last time.
And I was looking over like the bits and
I was like,
not really.
I think I'm done,
you know?
Yeah.
So I'm trying to focus on just all new
now we're being forced into this
position.
Yeah,
for a good thing because you have fans
because the fans want to hear new stuff
and it just makes me think about that.
I always used to pity those old guys
back in Boston that never wrote that
they had that same hour that they would
do for a decade.
That's so nuts to me.
It's crazy to think about now because
back then there was no social media and
none of these guys got on television,
so if you didn't go to see them alive,
you did not know their material.
Yeah.
That's really wild.
It's crazy to think that that was the
norm and that guys would polish an act
together and put it together and then
they would just work and they would
never write and I fucking
never.
Right.
I feel like the norm now without
question,
I feel like it was kind of debated for a
little bit is definitely want a special
comes out.
Like that shit is gone.
Yeah.
I feel like that's accepted now that
you're done with that.
Totally.
Well,
I had a conversation with someone at the
store a year ago because she did a
special and then after the special she
was still doing the same material.
I go,
what are you doing?
she goes,
well,
I don't think most of the people seeing
that.
I go,
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
I go,
I guarantee you,
if they're coming to see you,
they're paying to see you.
They've seen your work.
Yeah.
Like she's like,
well,
I'm in new material.
Whoa,
why the fuck are you touring?
Yeah,
like you can be touring with the same
exact act.
It was on comedy central just six months
ago.
You can't.
No,
no.
Specially people paying,
you know,
they,
it,
it is weird and that you will,
I ran into it a bunch of times,
but it's definitely the minority,
which is the person who's like,
why didn't you do that one bit?
And you're like,
because you know it.
Go Watch that on Netflix.
Yeah,
I think I told you,
but I did one,
people were asking me to do some bits.
Uh,
when I was touring,
I think it was not 20,
17,
2016.
They were like,
do,
are you going to do this bit and that
bit.
So I just do one show at a club.
I was like,
I'm gonna,
try this,
this thing out.
This encore thing,
so I did my,
I did my new show and then I said,
uh,
so people ask me to do some bits that,
you know,
or whatever.
I forgot how I got into it,
so,
and that got this huge round of applause
and then I would be,
I would start it and there'd be like a
big,
big applause.
I would go through the bit to complete
silence,
like they would just watch me do the bit
they know and then when I would end it,
another round of applause.
I was like,
that's horrible.
That was the worst feeling ever.
And the reason,
because there was no lab because there
was no surprise.
Like they're like,
yeah,
of course they knew the whole thing.
I did like the next bit and I was like,
you might,
you know,
whatever.
No,
this one as the same thing.
They're like,
oh yeah,
we do know this one,
and then I go through it and they were
like,
yeah,
no,
that was horrible.
It was my one attempt at doing,
you know?
Yeah.
I don't even know how to do them.
Yeah,
no,
it was an.
And then people were like,
I was like,
I forgot the next line.
They were like,
it's this,
like people knew he knew the bit better
than I did.
Yeah.
Somebody asked me something about the,
um,
the bit about people breaking into the
White House about a woman who was
guarding the front door,
the White House by yourself.
That's on your last one.
And I had to go back and watch it again.
I was like,
ah,
I forgot all this.
I literally forgot how it worked.
I forgot all the different beats
and it's not in like in a day is not
going to come together.
Well,
no,
a terrible.
I did a private event in Vegas for these
rich guys and I was like,
just,
I flew in and I was talking to them like
five hours before the show and I was
like,
just so you know,
I mean
like I'm,
I'm doing my current show.
And they're like,
oh,
we were hoping you would do this,
this,
this and this though.
And I was like,
all right.
So I went up to my hotel room,
pulled up Netflix,
started watching and making notes.
And then I downloaded the album so I
could listen to it and I would walk
around and I was like,
no,
like forgetting the thing that you think
is a throwaway is actually like a
connector.
The thing you're like fuck.
And I was doing like halfassed versions
of it at the show.
Wow.
And they were still like on board with
it,
but I was like that's not how that goes.
I knew I was fucking it up.
How many specialists do you have out
now?
You have thrilled,
which was a CDC,
the white girls,
white girls cd seeding and then complete
hours.
They're completely normal.
Completely normal.
She's a special,
mostly stories especial and disgraceful
comes out to five hours of recorded
shit.
Like stop and imagine that if you had to
like do your whole catalog,
like a bruce springsteen concert.
Yeah.
You know,
I mean the thing about like a bruce
springsteen or any of those guys,
is that on any given night you could
bring back that one and really get it
sharp again for like five nights and
then kind of drop it and then do you
know what I mean?
We go like,
that's old,
I don't do that.
Yeah,
and it just,
it just goes further and further away
from your mind,
but they have to like,
if you go to see Bruce springsteen and
he doesn't play born to run.
Yeah.
You know,
like what the fuck kind of piece of shit
show is this.
I wonder.
I wonder because I feel like the.
But then again though he's famous for
doing like for our shows,
so maybe he never does skip it because I
have so much energy and I know me.
He's on those trump diet pills.
He's got to be.
He definitely looks tired and every
photo of course married.
He's married,
he's doing.
He's always like,
just doesn't know.
Like,
should I just bail on all this?
God,
incredible.
This is the,
the,
the inside story.
But a bruce springsteen and his concerts
has always been that people get bummed
out when his wife was there.
Feel like they like Bruce without his
wife.
They're better than they like bruce with
his wife.
They're like a friend of mine.
Her friends.
Energy changing.
Yeah.
Her friend is a crazy bruce springsteen
fan.
She goes to like tons and tons of
concerts,
sees him every year,
all like multiple times a year,
all over the country.
Crazy.
And the people that are like super
hardcore.
See there's a different energy that he
has called the wife sick.
The wife sick and she's sick.
She's not here.
Yes.
I'm fucking pumped.
When the wife's not there,
it's hilarious things with his wife.
His wife's a part of the band,
right?
She was with the tambourine or
something.
That's important.
None of this shit works without that
tambourine,
that tambourine fucking shows bunk.
I don't know man.
I never could have imagined touring and
working with your wife all the time.
My wife and I,
we always talk about how like it's
really unique.
We can do our podcast together and we
have fun doing it.
Yeah.
But like when anyone.
But she leads.
This is not like a guy thing.
When someone will be like,
Hey,
do you guys ever tour together?
And she's like,
that's gay as fuck.
No,
we're,
we're two different people.
We do our own show.
Like,
no,
it's not to.
You guys are in a rare situation to
where are both really good.
It's usually one of you is really good
and the other one is like bad.
She's definitely not too bad.
She does and she's a now shit.
I can't wait man.
She's selling tickets and shows and was
bawling.
Gave me that money.
Give me money.
You give me fucking shit.
Yeah.
No,
I'm excited for her.
I think she's one of the best comics in
the country and she's awesome and she
knows.
Yeah.
Christina don't sleep on her.
No,
I mean I remember saying that to her one
night,
like four or five years ago at the
store.
She'd fucking crushed in the or and uh,
I came up to upstairs go,
no bullshit.
You're one of the best comics alive.
That set that you just did right now
that's one of the,
like,
it's not just funny but it's insightful.
She's smart.
She points out shit that other people
aren't pointing out.
Real writer to writer writes a lot.
How does she bright?
Does she sit in front of the computer
and paper and then a computer and then a
pen and paper.
But yeah,
a lot of notes to writing a lot of
actual,
like you're talking about spending that
time working on it.
A lot of time you gotta do you know
that's the difference between someone
who produces a lot of material and
someone who doesn't like I've had these
conversations with people before.
It was like,
oh,
I only write onstage.
I was like,
all right.
Yeah.
Why is that?
Because it's the only way it works.
Or is it because you're lazy and this is
how you justify it?
It's probably more of that,
more of that.
Yeah,
for sure.
Now that I write on stage stuff,
it's like,
well I do too.
Yeah,
I write onstage stuff but don't like to
give it out as.
The thing that drives me crazy is I see
them giving it out as advice to other
young guns.
Like don't write on paper dude.
Just say,
Hey,
I write on stage man.
That's why I do like,
okay.
Right,
but is that the only way and is it the
best way and isn't,
isn't it possible that you're missing?
I say what happened was two was like
when Louie got like really,
really popular and he was just like,
I never write anything down that became
like folklore and attend like attractive
to see comics.
I feel like,
oh,
I gotta do that.
So he said he never writes anything.
It doesn't,
right?
Doesn't even write down bullet points
really just all in his head.
So then people are like,
oh,
you know,
I think,
I think I heard,
I started to hear that more when his
fame really exploded and that was a big
thing,
you know,
I was like,
not,
you don't even write shit down.
They're like,
no.
Okay.
Well I guess if you're doing stand up
every night,
three or four nights a week or three or
four times a night,
like you're doing those New York sets
and you're constantly working
constantly in your head,
you can get away with that.
I would,
I guess you could,
but like I would,
I always liked having at least a bullet
point list.
Like even when I wasn't writing anything
long form down,
I still like to have that.
Oh,
what can I just to see it all,
like how the,
you know,
how the,
how the movie plays out and they'd be
like,
oh,
I should move this over here and this
should be right here.
I couldn't imagine not having any of
that written down,
but I just think that the more time you
spend focusing on it,
whether it's the more time you spend
just writing stuff down or looking at
bullet points or the just the more
intention you put on things.
More attention.
The more focused.
Definitely.
It's gonna you're gonna have it's gonna
be better.
You're going to know it better.
It's like getting good at anything.
Yeah,
no.
You put a lot of time into it.
It happened for you.
Yeah.
Comedy,
writing those.
One of the weirdest ones because
everybody does it a different way.
Yeah.
You know,
everybody's got their own weird sort of
style and no one can tell you exactly
how to do.
Like you could never tell Theo Vaughn
how to write a joke,
right?
No.
Initially him,
his ax.
So odd.
You know,
and know.
Then you're like mispronounce things,
but like that's like.
But it's like a disguised so well,
you know,
it's like,
it's shit like that where you just like,
how'd you come up with that?
You know,
was it an accident the first time like
that,
you know?
And then like I remember a Carlin,
he would write on a note cards,
note cards and clubs and then kind of
shuffle through them and be like,
that's shit and throw it on the ground.
And then,
uh,
I saw him,
one of his last tours,
that universal amphitheater and he for
his last,
because he called them like individual
pieces,
like his bits where it was really
heavily about the writing,
like the specific word play the flow,
you know,
rhythm patterns.
Like his comedy was very melodic like
that.
And when it got,
like,
when it was like one of his closing
pieces,
it was like five pages and he brought
out the pages and he's like,
I'm going to read this because that's
how I memorize it,
memorize it by doing these shows and
reading this.
So just so you know,
for this thing I'm going to look at it
like he told the 6,000 people that wow.
And then he would know it and then flip
the page and he's like,
how was it?
It was funny,
man.
It was great.
It was what it was like the second to
last special and I remember the uh,
like it was a,
it was a really well constructed piece
of writing is a little throw,
threw you off a little bit to have him
be reading it,
you know.
But he,
I would say when he,
when I saw the show,
that piece was probably at least half
committed to memory and he was still
trying to like,
you know,
repeat,
repeat to so that it would be in his
memory.
It was still really funny.
Well he was also.
How many,
how
old was he?
Sixty nine.
70.
I think he died at 70.
So yeah,
he looked.
He looked older because of,
you know,
he,
he went hard in the paint too.
Drug use.
Yeah.
But he was upset when he apparently had
a pain pill.
Problem for awhile because I remember
there was a time when he committed
himself to Rehab and uh,
I think it was wine and pills.
He was taking pain pills plus kind of.
Damn opiates,
man.
People they do get you get,
you know,
but you got to think that your memory
must eventually at some point in time
start to give out when you're doing
these long monologues.
Oh my God.
Do you do long,
long monologues?
Yeah.
Then he would write out his whole act,
like the whole hour and then just start
doing it.
[inaudible] is a new one every year,
like reading like a book almost.
I think you said 16 months was the
turnaround
that was.
Yeah.
[inaudible] every year he ended up doing
14 think specialist.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
What are you up to now?
You have quite a few.
Um,
like if you combine albums and specials.
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven.
I'm on my eighth.
There's a lot.
That's a lot.
You're going to catch him.
Number eight is coming up.
Do you know what you're shooting it yet?
Boston.
Are you doing in Boston?
Yeah,
I just changed my mind.
Oh,
oh,
sorry.
Boston.
Would it be at the Wilbert?
Yeah.
If,
um,
if I,
I have one other idea in mind that I'm
still bouncing around in my head at my
house.
I'm thinking about that.
Really?
Yeah,
that'd be great.
And you kids are in while he's sleeping.
That's awesome man.
That'd be a hit for four d,
what did you think of Chappelle's?
Two specials.
I thought it was really interesting to
see him do this big Polish special and a
big place and then do the little special
in the belly room.
I was like,
well,
this is this.
The room felt weird,
man.
Well,
I mean I personally,
my take on it is like the second one,
the belly ruin w we're and we're in the
practice of calling that a special,
but it's really not a special,
in my opinion,
what you're seeing is what here,
at least in definitely in Los Angeles.
And if you live in San Francisco,
Denver,
New York places he likes to frequent a
weight is what you see Dave chappelle
known for in these cities,
which is,
he would drop into clubs and like spill
out everything that's on his mind.
So I mean,
I don't know if it's more like
semantics,
but it's like,
it's not a special to me,
it's like you're seeing one of the best
guys ever do a workout set,
like a,
a loose riff.
It's only been six slash seven weeks
since the special was shot that that
plays before it broke,
when which he toured for like a year
with that you can see how like polished
and,
you know what I mean?
So I think it's really cool if you're a
big standup nerd to see the other one,
like that's what happens a lot in those
cities that he,
he'll just fly into and be like here's
shit that's on my mind.
Right.
And,
and that.
So you're seeing like,
it's,
it's masterful.
But I think it's like,
I don't call,
I,
I think of it as separate then a
special,
you know,
like a [inaudible],
a special to me is like,
you tour,
you prepare and then like you present
it.
Right?
I mean,
I know,
I understand that you'd be like,
well yeah,
it's a separate thing as a special.
But I'm saying that within that there's
something really specific going on which
is like,
this is like in the moment,
uh,
almost all topical commentary and that's
how that dude works.
He,
he just,
he will walk into a club and be like,
I want to get on stage and like just
talk about it.
He said he also,
he loves topical stuff so it fits
perfectly.
But it was,
it's very different.
It's,
I mean,
you can see the total differ,
that contrast,
especially if you watch one after the
other,
you know,
you're watching toward proven like
worked out stuff and like here's some
shit I thought of basically in the last
week.
Right,
right,
right.
But a whole hour of it,
which is really crazy.
Yeah.
So prolific.
And um,
the,
the fact,
the way it worked was doing the two of
them together that way you got to see
the big Polish special when you get to
see the fuck around workouts set.
So it's like if you watched the big
Polish specialty,
like I need more.
Yeah.
It's really interesting to see,
uh,
I think just to hear people go back and
forth on which they liked more.
I thought that was really interesting.
I've seen a bunch of people,
at least online.
I'll say they liked the belly room,
you know?
Well the belly room was so intimate to
be in that room.
I was there for one of those shows.
It's so interesting to be there when
you're watching someone film in front of
70 people.
It's so tight and small,
you know,
you're kind of naked a little bit,
and the people in the audience where
they were fucking on the show.
I mean,
the people that got those front row
seats,
they were,
they were featured prominently in that
Netflix.
Yeah.
Kind of makes you entertain the idea of
like a really small,
special what that would be like.
Yeah.
There's,
there's different kinds of comedy,
right?
This is like the comedy that you do for
70 people.
It's just not exactly the same as the
comedy that has done it for $700 or
$7,000 and the way you present it.
I mean he was,
he basically sat for most of that.
Yeah.
So that's,
that's different.
You know what I mean?
Usually if you were in a big 2,500
seater,
you're not gonna like chill,
sit on a bench.
Mark Marin,
mark parents cosby,
oldschool cosby.
Yeah.
He was always sitting even as you got
old.
Yeah.
Cosby did it.
Not just old school cosby,
but old,
old,
old cost.
But you're right.
Do you think Qosmio tour again?
No.
No,
I think that's done.
It's over.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I think so.
Well,
I remember when he was touring promoters
obligations,
but not.
I would think it's not worth the trouble
really.
I think so,
yeah.
I think Louisville to Oregon.
You think so?
Yeah,
I think so too.
Yeah.
I think he'll take a year off.
And then he'll do some shows and people
get mad
and then it'd be a.
and then like if,
you know,
the real thing is like the corporate
side of it,
like in other words,
a channel or network that would went to,
let's say host show the special,
but he has such a dedicated.
No one's website following is like what
he ended up developing and he's sold
shows and made millions,
you know,
when people were doing the like download
my special thing.
I think he could book a venue,
shoot something and go back to his $5
model and do really well.
No,
I'm sure he could and people would be
really interested to see it.
Of course netflix would have them on.
They still have his old stuff.
Old stuff.
Yeah.
I mean I,
yeah,
I was on a flight after,
right after all of it went down.
I watched his,
uh,
the special from DC,
which I thought was really interesting
to watch it knowing the DC one was,
is that the latest lotus one,
2017.
But just to know that it was like right
around the corner that he was going to
get busted.
Yeah.
Beating off in front of people.
It's a weird thing to get caught,
dylan,
to get to all the things that people
have done that they got caught doing all
the rape accusations and all the
horrible shit.
Like his is the most pathetic and also
kind of the most innocuous.
Yeah,
just humiliating.
Just petering off in front of people.
I know.
It's like his kink,
it's what he likes,
but it could be way worse,
you know,
like what,
what he actually did not saying it's a
good thing to do to people now it's hey,
watch me beat off.
I know a bunch of people.
He did it to apparently laughed.
Yeah.
Quite a few comics that I've talked to
that know people that
he did it too.
Yeah,
I knew somebody.
They did.
Yeah.
And which she think not happy.
Um,
but like,
you know,
I don't know,
man.
It was like weird.
I knew it for a long time.
That story.
Yeah.
And I,
I mean I said it before.
I was like,
I mean,
I knew it and then like every other
person I talked to in comedy to it and
we were all like,
that's fucked up,
but also,
I mean this doesn't excuse it at all
either,
but there is something about something
at least that as you know,
that something somebody did a while ago.
So it's like,
what am I supposed to bring this shit up
to them?
Right.
You know,
like how do you know?
But,
but the other thing is how do you even
know that they did it because one of the
things that happened during the whole,
like,
did he do it or do not do it thing
before it came out was uh,
someone had told me that it was bullshit
and that what he had done is take some
pictures of female comedians with his
dick out just being silly and stupid and
like,
and then tell him,
please delete those pictures were just
having fun,
you know,
how do I get in trouble?
I mean,
the story I heard was very specific.
Yeah.
And like,
you know,
is basically one of the stories reported
in the times and I was like,
I remember hearing that story and the
person was not,
you know,
was pretty upset about it.
And then a lot of people heard the
story.
Yeah.
And then I dunno,
you know,
another year would go by and two years
and three years and you're like,
okay,
I mean that's bad.
But like as far as my role in it,
you know,
as somebody who knows the story now,
it was just one of those things where
you'd be like,
yeah,
that's fucked up story.
I mean it's not someone that like,
Hey,
you know,
that guy he fucking punched someone 15
years ago was a real asshole.
And you're like,
that sucks,
you know.
But 15 years ago is a long time.
Right.
I mean,
kind of it's like is there,
is there,
it's not to like minimize the
wrongdoing,
but like I sit there some part of the
conversation about how people mature and
become different people as they get
older.
And I'm sure a lot of people that are in
their fifties and sixties,
you go like,
you know,
who are not celebrities.
You'd be like,
do you know that when this guy was 26 he
did this fucking horrible stupid thing
or something like Jesus.
But you're like,
well,
you know,
there's long time ago now.
I mean that was kind of,
at least that part of the conversation
exists in this.
Right?
It's like it's,
it,
it's something really bad and he's being
punished.
So that's,
we're not saying that it's,
it's definitely,
it has not been excused because he's
being punished.
But it's also old behavior.
Yeah.
Like that's the Dustin Hoffman thing,
you know,
Dustin Hoffman,
this is where it gets really strange.
A lot of his stuff was 30 years ago,
1985 and shit.
It's like,
I think part of the difference too
between the Hoffman stuff and Louis and
maybe everybody else is louise
admission.
Right?
That's very different because even the
stuff I heard with Hoffman,
he is like,
he's definitely trying to justify a
versions and the behavior and that's
what people did you know,
is that what he said?
Oh yeah.
He's like,
you know,
on the set like you try to like get,
you have to break the tension or
there's,
there's a monotony to it.
And so people would have these
conversations and say,
so it's like he's trying to appears that
he's trying to be less accountable for
what he said.
Yeah.
Whereas Louis was like,
these stories are true,
so it's,
I think all those things end up
affecting how your redemption goes
because they're like somebody like,
I did this shit.
I was wrong.
Right.
And I think in this country people love
punishment.
Like are you punished for the thing you
did?
We hate like somebody getting away with
something.
So part of him I think coming back will
also be the people realize that he paid
a price.
I mean he lost deals.
He lost shows.
Last money.
Definitely lost a lot of fucking touring
money.
Yeah.
It's that day is probably at least a $50
million a day for him,
you know,
with everything together.
So crazy.
Yeah.
I mean,
what a weird kink jerk off in front of
people.
Yeah.
I wonder how you develop it.
I mean,
I guess I can imagine how you develop
it.
Do you think that you could even do
that?
Like I was trying to think,
could I even ask them,
Hey,
do you mind if I jerk off in front of
you and then just get hard and actually
like,
well that's the thing.
I imagine he had to be leaking ripe like
before that,
like to come that fast.
It had to be something he's thinking
about all day and like hanging out and
then like,
Hey,
do you want to hang out?
Like do you want to come back?
Or whatever might come up.
And so as he's getting closer to doing
it,
I'm sure it's,
it's,
it's the only fuel that's on his mind,
you know?
So it's like to just ask me that,
I'd be like,
well that's not my kink.
So you're like,
hey,
could you go from fully flacid to come
out of these people?
Like,
I don't think so man.
I don't think I could do that.
No.
Kinks are fucking weird.
Kinks are weird.
You know,
like I had a friend and him and his
girlfriend and used to tie each other
up.
They tie each other both up.
Ball gags.
Yeah.
The whole deal.
And He loved it.
He would talk about it with great glee.
Yeah.
I'd be like,
why?
Why do you like tiny each other up?
Like,
what are you doing?
Yeah.
Hi.
It's fucking great.
It's just something about like trusting
that person to put that rope in their
mouth and like I wonder how much,
how many of those kinks develop later?
Like you realize it later as opposed to
like the more common theory that
everything's tied to childhood.
So that must have been,
you must have been tied up or something
as a kid once and then you somehow
relate that to sex.
But I wonder if the,
if you can be 28 and be like man,
it's tying thing is fucking awesome.
I guarantee you can just date one crazy
person,
like if you have one girl who's just a
wild animal in the sack and she just
wants to tie you up and you're like,
all right,
let's do it.
Yeah,
she doesn't your love it.
And it's amazing.
And as we need to answer.
Where's Jim Norton when you need it?
Oh yeah.
He would go deep with this.
He gets all sweaty and shit and it's
bugging out.
I blinking.
Yeah.
Nobody embraces their kinks more than
him though.
Yeah,
I fucking admire that.
So yeah,
everything,
whether it's trannies or any,
anything that he's experienced friends,
that's it.
He says it.
He says,
oh he does.
Yeah.
And he's definitely supports the
industry.
So the industry is that.
It's weird that you can't say tranny.
Tranny is somehow or another negative.
Yeah.
Look,
these are noises that we make by now.
Chappelle was like the,
that was the thing,
you know,
he brought,
he got a lot of shit on the old one or
the one from a year ago and so he,
he brought up the topic again,
but he's said Trans people.
Yeah.
It was real specific on that part.
I guess the last one he was like fucking
Chinese man.
Well there's certainly a lot of thought
policing going on
and there's language policing.
We have to wonder,
like how much of that affects the way
people actually feel and how much and
how much of it is just people trying to
control the way people communicate and,
and dictating the languages because like
when you go to the far end of the
spectrum,
there's these new,
uh,
gender pronouns that there's,
there's literally ems or 78 of them,
which I think are utterly preposterous,
absurd,
absurd.
You're make believing you have,
you've make-believe language,
you're inventing all these new words and
it's not like there's some universal
agreement going on and everybody.
It's not like remember when ms dot was
the thing.
Yeah,
there was mrs and Mr. but then there was
miss [inaudible] and Mr was married or
Mr [inaudible] was not married and women
were like,
well,
what the fuck?
How come we don't have one of those?
Yeah.
So they came up with ms.ms dot,
but it never really stuck.
No,
like nobody uses Ms.
it has to be like a real formal,
you know,
Raven.
Would you say ms dot,
I guess they would ever in writing,
they might,
you know,
might write ms if it was like,
I don't know,
a piece of journalism or something to
add to indicate the person that's single
status.
Never hear that.
Yeah.
But you don't hear it spoken a lot.
No,
no,
but they were trying to push for it for
awhile.
Yeah.
And that was something that was like on
the borderline of being accepted by the
Common Vanessa.
Killer shit is xer.
I also wonder like how many people are
just professionally upset at shit that's
said wrong.
You know,
like they,
they're just,
their reaction to everything is like,
it's like their job is to police and
react in a fucking.
No,
no,
no.
That's not.
Okay.
What about,
it's like almost how academia exist
today.
You see like the way that people are on
campuses,
it's like fucking.
That is not a reflection of the real
world.
No.
To consider everyone's feelings at all
times.
Why?
That's not how shit works.
No,
no.
People get upset and get offended at
things.
That's fine,
but like that,
everyone should like dial back
everything they say to make sure
everyone feels protected.
That's not how it should.
What's been really interesting in the
last five days,
there's been a battle going on in my
twitter mentions that I haven't dived
into at all really.
But yeah,
but lesbians had been going at it with
transgender people in my twitter
mentions,
and this is like long ongoing
conversation with going back
and forth and remarkably civil.
But what's interesting is all these
lesbians,
one of the things they've been saying
it's been,
I dive in every now and then I read some
of it and going,
what the fuck?
This is crazy.
I gotta get Outta here.
But that lesbians,
um,
we're trying to say that a lot of the
violence that happens in supposedly
lesbian relationships is actually
transgender men to women where they
switched over and then they're beating
up their girlfriends and they're
bringing their masculine toxic violence
into the world of lesbianism.
And they're not willing to be honest
about it.
And there was all this crazy debate
going on back and forth.
This lady was citing statistics of how
many.
I'm wondering how accurate that is.
I don't know how many women in which she
was a lesbian and she was pretty,
uh,
pretty.
Not that you're a fucking expert,
100 percent on facts if you're a
lesbian,
but she was pretty adamant she was a
lesbian who was like,
well,
the other thing she was saying,
lesbians like women and that she doesn't
know any lesbians that want to date a
transgender woman like that.
Used to have someone who used to be a
man and is now a woman.
She was like,
that's not what we're attracted to it.
And actually women wouldn't.
That kind of negate the argument because
they're like,
she's,
if,
if formerly male transgender women are
beating up their lesbian girlfriends,
then there are lesbians out there.
There are some that are dating and
attracted to these transgender women.
Yeah.
It does get it muddy there,
right?
Yeah.
So she's saying like,
we're not into that.
It's like,
well,
your stats then don't back up your
argument because that's clearly what
you're indicating.
You're saying that these transgender
women that were formerly men are dating
women and beating him up.
I think she was saying,
and people she knows her friends.
So like Elizabeth and Sarah aren't into
it,
so that's supposed to.
It's like,
how else could,
you know?
I mean,
you'd have to have like a pole you gals
out there and eating pussy,
like eating fake pussy.
Yeah.
That's a wild stat to consider.
I'd never thought of that.
Yeah.
And there was this going back and forth
with lesbians versus a transgender women
and then they started getting.
Some people started getting hostile,
like let's just cut the shit.
You have a y chromosome,
you're a fucking man.
And then it was like,
whoa.
There was a lot of that going on.
There was a lot of you want us to assume
and not just assume we want.
You want us to just go along with the
idea that you absolutely are the wrong
gender and there's no way that you could
just be crazy.
There's no way you could actually have
gender dysphoria.
There's no way you could actually have a
mental illness.
It's impossible and that's.
That's one of the weird things about any
group,
right?
You're going to have a certain amount of
people that are mentally insane.
They're mentally there.
They're gonna.
Oh yeah.
Group.
Any group,
any group or there's a certain.
If you have a thousand people,
there's a certain percentage of those
people that are just going to be insane.
Yeah,
but when it comes to gender,
we're supposed to ignore that were never
supposed to think like out of your mind.
Yeah.
No,
you're out of your mind.
You're.
Yeah.
You know,
you're definitely a woman born in a
man's body and did I tell you,
I support all the trans rights and
everyone doing all this stuff.
The only thing that I ever go like that
doesn't seem right is with athletics.
Oh yeah.
That's the only thing where I feel like
it's not that I don't feel like someone
should be able to play any sport
compete,
but like when a dude,
it transitions to becoming a woman and
was like,
I play basketball now.
It's like,
come on man.
Yeah.
Like I get it.
You're,
you,
you have the right to live your life and
play,
but like you have all those skills that
you developed as a man and now you're
playing against frailer,
smaller,
you know,
like that.
To say that like you can't bring that
up,
that that's offensive is ridiculous to
me.
Well,
especially when it comes to fighting.
Fuck yeah man.
That was the big one and that was where
I really understood like how bizarre and
defensive for that.
Yeah.
How cult like this,
this ideology is that like to see you
transition to a woman and fight women.
It'd be fun to have what,
12 murder charges.
That would be the fun part.
It doesn't make any sense.
No,
of course not.
The bone structure is so different and
people that deny that are fucking crazy.
I know.
That's that.
That is silly,
man.
What if I like transition,
whatever anyone man and does a power
lifting well,
people have done that and they're
winning and breaking all these records
they are,
and why are we like,
why are we not stopping being like that,
doesn't know.
That doesn't want to save people's
feeling.
Exactly and silly.
What's really fascinating is in the
process of being super progressive,
you,
you go towards the most maligned,
a part section of society which is like
transgender people and so everybody else
who also has been marginalized by
society like women,
women get put on there.
They get put in a less protected
category.
Transgender women,
so a man becomes a more protected class
of woman.
Then a natural born woman herself.
That's very interesting.
That's crazy.
It is.
It's very true.
Also.
Yeah.
It's crazy because all these women that
got beaten up by that man who became a
woman,
started fighting in mma,
fought to women before ever disclosing
the fact that she used to be a man
because she said it was a medical issue
that had nothing to do with them,
which is just shows you how completely
insane the logic behind all this.
She's still fight this.
She hasn't been awhile,
but uh,
now
everybody knows she lost to a woman who
did.
Yeah.
Was an actual one who wound up.
Uh,
yeah.
I said actual fuck off.
Yeah.
People are like,
whoa.
Wait,
what did you say?
That's wild,
right?
That a woman beat good.
No,
she's not good.
She's not going to fight her.
No.
She's just strong.
Like there's nothing.
You don't look at her and think like,
oh,
she fights like Chris Cyborg or she
boxes like Claressa shields.
No,
she's not that unbelievably talented.
She is physically way different.
Yeah.
She's a fucking man.
Some man for 30 years had children.
This was when I knew it was crazy.
I got into conversation with someone and
online with this woman was like,
she's always been a man.
I go,
even when she got another woman pregnant
and had children with her and she goes,
yes.
Even then she was a woman.
She was a woman.
She was a woman that fucked another
woman who got her pregnant.
Okay.
What?
Just hang up.
What are we doing?
I know like this is so crazy.
You got to tap out of those kinds of
things.
Even Bruce Jenner,
when he transitioned to Caitlyn Jenner
and then eventually got his.
His surgery,
right.
Got Her surgery become.
She said even before the surgery though,
it didn't change anything.
I was always 100 percent a woman.
Okay.
Then why get surgery?
Well,
because you're thinking that gender is
just with Genitalia.
Liam mistake you personally.
What is it?
It's genders,
not just genitals.
It's in your mind.
Right.
So,
so it's also a facial reconstruction.
Just said something fucking stupid and I
just let you know how dumb that was.
So what is the difference?
Someone said that there's gender and
then there's there's biological sex and
gender is the operating system,
and biological sex is the hardware.
I hundred percent agree.
It makes sense.
Outrage over transgender female weight
lifter who destroy her rivals by
hoisting.
Nineteen kilograms more than the runner
up.
Now she's a contender for the
Commonwealth Games.
That's A.
Yeah.
Guess what?
Oh my God.
Look at the size of her.
Fuck laurels it God damn gorilla.
So maynard country national
weightlifting debut in Melbourne's about
pounds more than the second place.
Yeah.
What in the fucking Holy Hell.
Oh my God.
And look at the size of her.
Fuck.
Can you imagine if you're a biological
woman who has been training and working
hard all her life?
Yeah.
And then all of a sudden you have to
compete with this and you're like,
I'm first place like and she's giant.
Like look at the size of her head or
formerly male head.
Yeah.
That's a giant woman.
That's just the way to get metals.
Sandbagging.
Yeah.
That's what a lot of it is.
That's fucked up man.
That is,
that's what it is.
What a lot of it is,
people don't want to admit that.
Yeah,
sandbagging,
if you don't know what it means is like
you would get that in martial arts
tournaments,
like say you would have a tournament and
the tournament would be um,
like for blue belts on lane,
which was like one rank above white belt
and then guys would be like a black belt
in judo and they would enter into the
blue belt division and dump everybody
and he's like a belt in that,
but he's sandbagging and like,
you know what they're doing and
everybody knows what they're doing.
You see that shit and you,
you see there's,
there's a lot of that where people just
want to win.
And the way they can win is by competing
against people that are not on their
same level.
Sure.
If you don't think that people do that
when they switch over from being a man
for 30 years and then competing as a
woman and not tell them and just start
smashing these women.
So there's something in that that you
don't understand.
Athletics,
you don't understand competition.
You don't understand sandbaggers and you
don't understand the kind of people that
wouldn't tell people about that in the
first place.
Sure,
yeah,
but they don't want to look at it that
way.
They want to.
Everything has to go through the filter
of being progressive,
so you have to err on the side of being
the most open minded,
the most liberal in the most
progressive,
which I'm 100 percent for.
If women want to fight a transgender
woman,
if a woman wants to,
I think you should be able to ride
bulls.
I think you should be able to sky dive.
I think you should be able to do a
fucking bungee jumping.
I think you should do a lot.
You should be able to do a lot of
ridiculous,
crazy dangerous shit.
You should be able to do flips with BMX
bikes.
Why shouldn't you be able to fight a
man?
Yeah.
Why shouldn't you be able to fight a
transgender woman?
A woman that used to be a man.
You shouldn't be able to.
If you're a man,
you're up for it.
Yeah.
If you're a woman rather than your 130
pounds,
you want to fight 130 pounds,
100 percent,
man.
No,
no transgender,
no nothing.
If you want to do that,
you should be out to.
You should be allowed to.
I don't advise it.
I think it's a terrible idea for you.
Yeah,
you're going to get pummeled.
Well if it's a good fight or there's
just.
What is this?
What's going on here?
Bodybuilder.
We just show me.
The article says,
this person can't decide to compete as a
man or a woman and this is what they
look like.
They can't decide whether to compete as
a man or a woman.
That's what he used to look like on the
left.
Fucking a man and then,
oh my God,
he was super jacked and now he is on the
right,
an easy trip,
but he looks like he's still.
A man says he hasn't a Trans Trans
transition yet still lives his life as
both he lives his life as both seeing.
This is where you're seeing that there's
some of these fucking people have mental
illness,
but there was an episode of radio lab
where this one guy who's also a girl,
um,
switches back and forth and under
pressure.
He changes like he's Paul or ascending
and this is what on what radio lab so
and,
but radio lab is so fucking left wing
and I love them.
They're amazing,
but they're so left wing and so
progressive that they are unwilling to
note and,
and,
and even even address that pro postural
nature of this fucking person who's
like,
I just switched now.
I'm cindy right now.
Now I'm back to Paul.
Went back to Paul in the conversation in
the conversation like I just turned over
like,
Oh,
you did?
you're this special creature that can
just go back and forth and switch
genders or are you fucking crazy?
Paul Slash Cindy.
We would never have violated pages
wishes in the story.
It's an unfortunate understanding what,
what he did.
He pulled up
when they had to change the whole story,
remember they had to go back because
they got mad that they as gendered them
in their original.
How did they miss gender?
If she goes back and forth,
they have to keep up at the moment.
So they mis-gendered.
How were they called her?
A him or him or her?
Which ones?
The mis-gendering
miscommunication was between the
reporter and the actual person they're
talking to.
Yeah,
the person's fucking crazy.
You can't just go back and forth and
back and forth like cut the shit.
You know this.
This whole thing is just preposterous.
Coming will remove references to the
name.
She no longer recognizes.
Does that mean that afterwards,
afterwards she decided to go full
female.
That's what happened when you saw me
Craig,
for a man.
So at one point in time during the show,
she's.
She switches like,
come on man.
Paul.
Now Paul.
Now,
now back to Cindy.
Cindy.
Cindy's light.
You can cindy's loose psychiatric help
at this point.
At one point in time we see.
Here's the thing,
you're not allowed to say that when it
comes to gender,
when it comes to anything else,
if you like,
oh,
I recognize it as a wood Elf.
I'm a Wood Elf,
you know?
That's how I,
that's how I identify a sprite should be
in the forest,
flying around with the butterflies.
Like people go,
Oh,
you probably has a housing issue because
schizophrenia.
Yeah.
But if it's a guy who's built like brock
Lesnar who's like,
you know,
I've always identified as Amanda,
small thin woman and people are like,
yeah,
who dance?
Yeah,
you should respect that.
we should respect that.
When it comes to gender.
Gender is true.
Weird thing that we allow all sorts of
very illogical behavior.
Well,
yeah,
like these 78 plus gender step by the
way.
They're adding more.
There's more like,
there weren't enough.
There's more gender pronouns now than
ever before.
Like if it's a guy at a bus stop,
he was like,
I am the president.
You don't go like,
oh,
we should respect the fuck out of that
right now.
Right.
You're just like,
oh man,
identifies as the leader of the free
world.
You should address that.
No,
you're supposed to be like,
hey,
stand over here.
Yeah.
When it comes to gender,
we're supposed to.
We give like a lot of leeway.
A let a lot of things slide.
Get us through.
Yeah,
and I think it's for good reason.
I think the good part of it is that we
recognize that there are people that
really wish that they were a woman would
like you to call them a woman and why
not let let the guy become a Gao and
maybe there'll be happy that way and it
shows,
I guess shows acceptance and kindness on
our part to just allow that to happen.
True.
But the problem with that is that
goddamn slippery slope and a lot of this
weirdness that's going on is people
trying to control other people's
behavior and one of the ways they try to
do that is try to get you to use words
that they've made up.
Yeah.
This is where you're seeing how
preposterous it is.
The level,
the number of pronouns is also 78.
I mean until recently and somebody
saying like,
I don't identify,
like I understand that concept,
it's not too hard to understand,
but where it's like I also have free
reign on 100 words that you should
possibly know to address me by.
It's like,
what do you fucking.
Why are you bothering everybody?
Know what it is that when you get off
on,
would you become special that way?
Of course you get special rights,
special privileges,
special attention you get.
It's just special consideration.
I'm trying to remember if my,
uh,
yeah,
on my.
Yeah.
I've,
I've had on my profile on twitter for a
long time.
Like if you read my first bio says I'm a
comedian Comedians,
that's my pronouns.
But nobody respects it.
Well,
I didn't even know.
Zim.
Zim is a big one.
It's been,
I know zero Z,
h e r or z e R.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Those are these motherfuckers.
There's just so many.
What does it say?
We were really feeling dog cons.
What does it say there?
What does it say?
There were really feeling dog,
constant want to thank the people of
Australia for bringing it to our
attention that we saw this clip or this
guy,
if you hit view there.
He was like doing this video and we just
heard them say,
I've never heard somebody say that.
He,
he.
Can you play it or no?
I don't know.
He,
um,
dog.
I like dogs.
I've never heard.
I've never heard that before.
It's been really good.
He drinks a beer.
He's like dog and Australian guy were
like,
fucking a.
and then all these Australian people
were like,
that's right.
That's one of the things we hear.
Like what does it mean that I actually
got really great explanations of it,
uh,
about how,
how common it is their only see this guy
wrote a,
well,
first of the guy goes,
no,
no problem.
That's how we talk here.
A dog and Australia is like a dirty rat
or an ugly person or a dishonest person.
We use it to put people down.
So it's like,
you know,
if somebody,
you say dog a dog,
like as like a shitty person.
Oh,
okay.
So,
um,
so there's a lot of Shit cunts here too.
I like Shit cunt.
He said it's to insults because dog is a
common insult.
So don't.
And this guy is a total.
This guy's a total bogan,
which is a like a white trash redneck.
I'm now.
The Guy said if you say you fucking dog,
come to the wrong type of Ozzy,
you might get stabbed with a sharpened
toothbrush multiple times and instead
it's a snitch in Bogan slang.
So a dog can,
such as a snitch.
A dog con is a snitch.
So Matt Kahn is a good bloke.
Sick cunt is a,
like a professional bmx rider of Fatca
is burt.
I'm a dog kinds of shitty person.
Oh,
if you see your mate,
he ditches you for a girl on a night out
and he's a fucking dog cut.
Uh,
yeah.
If you see your mate,
your buddy pitches you for a gal to
fucking dog.
God,
what's he supposed to do?
Like what if he can get laid?
Supposed to hang out with you,
man.
You guys had plans certain point in
time.
Like what if she's really hot like that?
Changes everything.
If she's super,
she wants to get hot banging out right
now.
And your friends being a dog for getting
upset at you.
I think.
Hm.
Interesting.
Okay,
interesting.
You know what's in.
I don't know where I came up with her.
I'm having a hard time pulling hot
chicks names for references on the fly.
The other day I said Jennifer beal from
flash dance.
It's like where?
What payment in this special place in
your mind.
That's I guess.
Yeah,
I think we all go to like an era.
I wouldn't do that to be that fucking
Kathy Ireland smoke show.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
She's like 80 now.
Yeah,
but that's because there was a time when
I was really stroking to her.
Were you proud?
Yeah,
I mean I'm sure when that sports
illustrated was coming out I was
probably like 13 or something,
so yeah,
that would have been prime time for all
that era.
It's was like when you discover what a
hot woman is,
when did you discover what a woman is?
She's like someone's mom now.
No,
definitely Pearson.
That's what she used to look like.
Yeah.
So that right there,
it's got to be so hard for those women
to let that go.
Yeah.
And to be that hot.
Celebrated for it.
And now to be just like a regular old
Nice lady with price.
Nice Gal.
Someone's mom.
Yeah.
I think the thing about the ski stuff
with the sports,
with when the swimsuit issue would come
out is that they were kind of household
names and kind of not.
So you felt like you knew something by
learning their name.
Do you know what I mean?
Like because it wasn't a movie star,
a swimsuit model was like learning that
name.
I'm talking about like as a teenager in
a bizarre way you thought like he knew
them better because you knew their name,
you know,
so like I would be like Oh Kathy
Ireland,
Elle Macpherson,
and then people would catch on.
But you'd learn their names and feel
like you knew something.
I don't know.
It's really weird.
Really?
Yeah,
I think so.
Like you were better than people that
didn't know their names.
I think at 12 and 13 definitely.
Was it like a sports thing?
It's like knowing stats like six,
nine,
2:45,
you can really fucking movement.
You feel like you know more.
Yeah.
That was always a thing.
Right when you were young to be able to
pull out sports stats and players' names
to know the entire lineup.
It's really crazy.
I know I saw this thing a already lange.
Do you know that he can name for like 40
years who played in world series and
like like the two teams that played,
but I'm talking about you can be like
1958 and he's like,
that was cardinals versus mets game for
this happy.
Like he knows he knows like a span of 40
or 50 years by memory.
Wow.
That's some,
that's some really,
really ridiculous stats to know what.
He's a fucking banana baseball fan.
Yeah.
But this level of it is really.
I've never seen anything like that
before.
Why doesn't he do like sports radio
then?
He did for awhile,
didn't he?
He did.
He did with Nick Depaulo.
Wasn't that like a sports radio show?
I'm not sure.
I know.
What is he doing now?
He,
he checked himself into Rehab,
right?
Um,
I think so because he was doing that
show with Anthony and then I think he
checked himself into Rehab.
I think so,
yeah.
Which is good.
Yeah.
He just did it.
He did that last,
uh,
or the new season of crashing the HBO
show.
Pete Holmes show.
He's one of the guests or one of the
stars.
He's one of.
He's a cast member I think.
I think so because he was on it the
first season and yeah,
he returned for guy.
He loves the drugs.
Yeah.
And the hard ones.
He's a true addict.
Yeah.
Like you gotta wonder.
He's so funny though.
It's hilarious.
And that's a,
like I said,
that that sports analogy has,
is fucking crazy.
Do you have sports knowledge?
You have a lot of sports knowledge now
that I know some,
some random things,
you know,
I know some things like,
I mean I basically,
like I said,
I like college football and so like I
can,
I can hold a conversation with different
levels of college football fans.
Like I could,
I could talk to a super fan and hang
with them in that conversation,
but I'm not like I can tell you every
championship game for the last 20.
No,
no.
I remember people team's winning and
stuff for sure.
But I don't,
I don't have a level that you'd be like,
what type of autism do you have?
Like that is like,
so like savant level shit where it's
like you're such an expert in one field.
You know,
like all these weird stats you retain.
Well not like that.
Yeah.
Just you ever see a Al Franken draw the
United States like that?
No.
He's got this weird ability to draw
every state that he went all 50 states.
He draws the shape of them,
puts it together in the,
in the.
He draws the United States by freehand.
Really?
Yeah.
That's his ability to do that.
Like,
like this.
Look at this.
This is before everybody knew he grabbed
butts.
That's already impressive.
Just that.
Yeah.
I know he does the entire country
completely freehand and it's an accurate
map of the country.
How is this possible?
Well,
because he's a real patriot.
This is one of the things that's kind of
disturbing and sad about the whole Al
Franken thing.
The worst they got out of him was that
he may or may not have grabbed
someone's,
but when he took pictures with him,
I don't know if he did or he didn't,
but this is basically it.
Incredible.
And he's resigning.
He's not going to be a senator.
I know he's done and.
But they didn't get them on anything
like completely horrible.
I was just like,
he may or may not have squirrels in
someone's butt.
A few people's butts.
How many fives?
A few butts.
A few buts.
Few bought like five or six.
That's really impressive actually.
Yeah.
It was very impressive and that means.
Yeah,
I mean,
does California the whole deal look,
come on others,
even as Alaska and Hawaii,
they do the state tomorrow.
Two thousand.
Yeah.
Well he was all high on his performance.
He just was feeling,
I'm the fucking King of the world.
I can see how it could happen.
I had my butt grabbed the bunch.
We're taking pictures of the women for
sure.
After shows.
Yeah,
I never got.
I'm like,
Nah,
that's just not.
I don't do it,
but I could see how people's butts
woodcut grabbed bill byrd was talking
about on this podcast.
I was like,
this is a particular type of woman in
her forties,
drunk,
a little loud,
getting kind of crazy and there's the
ones going to grab your eye,
grab your ass.
They'll say like a can.
I mentioned nipple or.
And they'll say something and then
before you could even say no,
they're going for it.
Go for it.
And they're always boozed up.
They're never like,
yeah,
that's always alcohol.
Yeah.
Alcohol is the catalyst for all shitty
behavior and decision making.
By the way,
did you see that born strong doc?
You see that born strong?
Is this documentary about the world's
strongest man competition?
No.
It's really fucking interesting.
Men and these guys are such fucking like
not normal species of human.
You know?
I was like the Iceland guys.
They're doing those power lifting
competition and they do it like that.
It goes to the arnold classic every
year,
and these guys,
these guys are such fucking beast,
man.
I mean it is like it.
It's not.
I mean this doesn't.
1,100 pound deadlift watts.
Yeah.
Eddie,
six foot to 400 pounds.
Yeah.
These so unhealthy for you to be that.
But that guy is interesting.
He was a national champion swimmer.
Wow.
Yeah.
As a kid,
like a thin guy.
Yes.
Lean and thin and he,
he's competing against guys.
Most of the guys he competes against are
like a that guys,
the next smallest.
Basically everyone,
all the other guys were like six,
eight,
six,
nine,
four,
10,
24:30.
And the,
the,
the swimmer guy has to eat like all day
and they explained the physiology.
Look at that size of that guy.
Six,
eight,
four,
27.
I mean they're just Jesus Christ.
So they're so crazy.
But this level of competition is.
This is the guy from game of thrones
right here.
He's a competitor too,
but it's like the physiology of I'm
eating that much to sustain the muscle.
Eventually you have to put on the weight
like the you need the fat and they
explained how,
you know,
this is like his physique is like that.
He's just kind of put together that way,
but most of the guys have these big
barrel bellies and a doctor explains how
at a certain level of consumption the
these guys all basically get Belize,
you know,
like because people are like why do they
have to get fat?
And just as you think that they start
explaining it so when you're that big
and you lifting that much weight,
you have to be fast.
Yes.
That's basically what the guy says.
But the game of thrones guys,
not really that far,
but I think it's for,
but he's one of the unique cases where
he is actually built to be a fucking
viking.
In other words,
the other guys are eating so much to
sustain themselves,
be able to pick up and recover from all
this crazy weight lifting.
He's a guy who is essentially born
walking around six,
eight,
three 95 or whatever the like.
He's a unique freak,
huh?
The other guys have to eat crazy amounts
of food.
I mean,
they show what one of these guys.
It would blow your mind.
He forced feeds himself like nine times
a day and he has to.
He said he has to.
Yeah.
And has he ever tried to not do it and
see if he's less strong?
I think so.
Yeah.
After the force feeding yourself,
make yourself stronger.
Yeah.
It really is interesting.
I mean like why?
Why do you get stronger if you're fatter
or do you need that much food to keep
the muscles up and if you just eat that
much food to keep the muscles up,
there's going to be a certain amount of
fat that's kind of.
Yeah,
I think that's more of the,
the way it goes.
They talk about steroids.
Um,
no,
not really.
No bullshit documentary then.
I don't feel like they did fucking guys.
No one,
no one.
No one wants to admit it.
That's a weird thing about that world.
That's this swimmer guy.
Look at him.
Wow.
He was all lean and yeah.
Gay Porno with.
Yeah.
Not that he was,
I'm just saying if you were going to,
there was a film about a guy working out
in the backyard and a bunch of guys
showed up to suck his dick.
That'd be the guy didn't even believe it
was real life.
The fact that one of those guys could
just become a woman and just enter into
women's weightlifting competitions,
so it would be respectful,
don't.
Yeah,
the path.
She's a woman.
She's always been a woman.
God,
she beat the competition by an
astounding 600 pounds.
Really crazy.
Yeah.
Beat the second runner up by 40 pounds.
No big deal.
It's normal.
Super Normal.
That happens.
Yeah.
No everybody does it.
No,
no.
We're going to look back on these days
and it's gonna.
It's gonna.
Be An astounding sort of observation on
mass mass thinking like group.
Think like what happens when people are
scared of expressing themselves honestly
and in expressing controversial points
of view because of the time and the
culture,
like what it.
You know what,
what ramifications it has.
By the way,
here's.
Here's what's weird.
I'm an.
I don't know if it's good or bad.
It's not a judgment call,
but I am.
I know so many people whose children are
now transgender a lot.
Yeah,
like five or six where I didn't know any
before,
like when I was growing up.
All in California.
Yeah.
Well one of them in Canada,
but yeah,
really important.
What's this Toronto theories?
Jessica plot is A.
CW has first openly transgender player
now.
She used to be a woman and now as a man
used to be a man now as a woman and
she's playing women's hockey.
Okay.
Fuck that.
That's crazy.
You know,
five people.
Yeah.
Talky get's.
It was an all star this year.
Jessica.
Yeah.
Take.
Take that fucking mountain from the game
of thrones.
Put them in a skirt.
Only people he plows over like God damn
human bowling ball.
Oh my God.
That's so funny.
It's just if you're going to play
sports,
there should be.
Look,
there are physical freaks that are
women.
There's no doubt about that.
There's some women that are just
physical freaks and there's some women
that also take steroids.
That's,
that's another very controversial issue
because you have women that are
ingesting large amounts of male hormones
and changing their physiology and then
they also compete against women,
but then there's women or just women.
Yeah.
What about them?
How about looking out for them?
How about not letting them get their
head smashed in fairview and this comes
down to.
It's not fair,
but it's also,
it's just.
It just shows you how silly people have
gotten and about how weird we are about
looking at things and that everyone is
so and it because they don't have.
They don't really have a personal stake
in the game.
Everyone is so concerned about being
viewed as being incredibly progressive
and open minded.
Yeah.
That they don't want to criticize.
It's really interesting point because if
you really put yourself in a competition
you care about say like,
it's important to you to imagine
yourself competing in something where
it's important to you to when they go,
but they we're going to have this person
in and those are the circumstances you
would.
You'd be the first one.
It'd be like,
fuck that.
Yeah,
that is not fair,
and those women get called bigots.
Yeah,
it gets.
It's really strange.
Yeah,
that is very straight.
Those women get attacked online like a
bunch of women that didn't want to fight
that transgender man who became a woman
in mma and they got called bigots and
transphobia and that and the transgender
people.
That community is like super aggressive
about defending that intellectual turf,
defending that idea.
See,
that's an interesting place is work
where you go because you have to have
empathy for let's say this transgender
person who's like,
I want to compete,
and you're like,
yeah,
you should be able to compete,
but how is.
How is this circumstance fair to both
sides?
You know,
to those women that that are really
wanting attention.
Part of part of the wanting to compete
is also wanting attention and wanting
everyone to know that you're a man or
transition to a woman and that there's,
look,
there's a lot of energy in that.
There's a lot of people that are paying
attention to that and and anybody who
says no,
that's preposterous.
People,
they want their privacy when it comes to
these matters and they they're not.
They don't want to be open to the
ridicule bullshit bullshit.
They,
they're,
they want attention 100 percent.
That's why they're competing with what
they're doing.
It's why they're letting everybody know
that the first openly transgender woman.
It's a lot of this is about.
I mean some of it is about transgender
rights.
It's about transparency and showing
people how many of those folks are out
there.
I'm sure a lot of it's about horseshit.
Yeah,
there's a lot of attention.
A lot of it.
I mean for you to sign up for that
competition when you know what's what
wildly attention getting,
especially things like power lifting and
mma,
like to deny that there's some sort of a
difference in the male frame.
There's also a lot of horseshit when it
comes to like what actually happens to
the body during transition and how much
strength you lose and how much bone mass
you lose and there's a woman named Dr
Ramona crushed sick.
I think that's her name and they
interviewed her and she's one of the
very few people that's been interviewed
about this as an actual endocrinologist
that's not a gender transition doctor
does.
That's what a lot of them are.
A lot of the people that talk about
these things and have these,
these discussions about these things
that are hashtag experts,
they're actually transitioned doctors so
they have a vested interest in sort of
expressing the ideology that there's no
physical advantage and that these women,
you know,
they once they have been under these
hormonal treatments for x amount of
years,
they become physiologically a woman and
there's no distinction between them and
a biological woman.
But this one woman doctor Ramona
critique,
she wrote an article for,
I want to say it was.
It was either SB nation or bloody elbow.
I forget what it was,
but they interviewed her and she was
saying,
not only do you not lose bone density,
but you maintain it because you're
taking estrogen.
And she's like,
well,
the the is that a man has more bone
density.
They're thicker,
they're built different,
and that you would lose a lot of that in
your transition to being a woman,
but you don't lose the bone density
because estrogen is actually what causes
people to maintain their bone density
when they're older,
when they're women,
like that's one of the things that
happens to women when they get older to
get osteoporosis.
What part of the problem is that your
body doesn't produce as much estrogen as
it used to and so you have a lack of
bone density.
One way to heighten that it's to
supplement with estrogen interested
actually maintains bone density.
So it's a good argument,
but they're not the same as men because
they don't have testosterone anymore.
And if they're not taking exogenous
testosterone,
they're definitely a have a disadvantage
against men,
but they still would have an advantage
against men about,
against women rather than mechanical
advantage,
of course.
But that's also a mental advantage.
There's a reaction advantage.
The reaction time is quicker with,
uh,
with men than with women.
Like there's a bunch of weird three d
space recognition advantages that men
have.
And then there's the thing that people
want to pretend that there's no
difference between men and women.
There's that group,
that group.
No,
but that seems like so stupid to even
entertain the idea.
No,
that's.
This is a common thing among the most
ridiculous of the progressives is that
there's no biological difference in the
sexes.
What?
Wha,
how could anything dumb,
but it is dumb,
but it shows you how insane a lot of
this thinking is,
is that this group think this mass
progressive thought process that they
just accept things that they're totally
irrational and then repeat them as ad
nauseum.
Like we played this one clip where
there's,
it seems like as a transgender man to a
woman to man who's saying she was
talking was Jordan Peterson debate and
she was saying there's no biological
difference between the Saxon.
I'd be happy to unpack that for you.
Oh really?
Oh,
you'd be happy to unpack biology.
Sure.
And just no difference at all in our
biology is now it's not real.
Okay.
There's no biological basis and sex in
general.
What did I say?
This is an expert.
Dig It.
Yes.
I'm sorry,
he transphobic.
Are you a bigot?
Is this an this is an expert?
No,
but she's teaching at a college.
Oh,
that's.
Yeah,
that would follow,
but that's what a lot of good lots going
on.
There's a lot of that going on in
colleges where people are teaching.
Unbelievably ridiculous shit.
I got to go right buddy.
Go for it.
Oh my God,
Dah,
Dah.
Tommy buns.
As done the three hour podcasts and
while it doesn't have the kind of
bladder for it too,
by the way,
we can go live with that.
Just go,
oh well it's too late.
We'll go live with tyron.
When he comes in earlier later,
people were parking in front of our
garage again.
Fuck heads.
So young.
Jamie.
This game that Tommy Buns and Ari
Shaffir and Bert Kreischer went to.
This was the game that you were
interested in as well.
I was watching it.
It was actually a really,
really good game.
They were.
They took the side of Georgia who turned
out to not be the victors,
but the final five minutes of the game
was insane and you as non football fan
could probably watch it and enjoy it
too.
Really?
Yeah.
Now let me ask you this because this is
what I was going to ask.
Is there any other sport like football
that has the kind of attention on the
college level because it.
Does basketball have that kind of
attention to people care as much about a
championship game in March,
in March,
March madness.
Oh,
that's what my marketed thing,
but not baseball.
Baseball.
No,
no.
They do have a college world series,
but nobody gives a fuck about that
summer when no one's paying attention.
Hmm.
But that's it.
As far as in terms of other sports,
right?
I mean there's no other ones.
Yeah.
I was just trying to think.
Wrestling as well,
got a little attention,
but it's very small,
but in their world they sell out arenas
and whatnot.
It's just not televised.
Right.
But in wrestling it's really only other.
I mean,
it's like wrestling fans that are into
it and you're not a national thing
given that knife.
I'm pretty sure not every college has a
wrestling team,
just like they almost all have a
football team.
Almost all have a basketball team.
They don't all have wrestling team.
Yeah.
You know,
one of the things that we're
highlighting,
I was reading this article about,
um,
the coaches and about how the coaches
were getting these large bonuses for
victory.
And uh,
they were,
it was,
they were saying how crazy it is that
the kids that are playing aren't getting
any money,
but that these fucking coaches are
making shit tons of money and that the
university prophets massively from these
successful football programs and yet
these athletes who are damaging their
brain,
damaging their body and then a large
percentage of them are never even going
to go onto a career in professional
sports.
So I'm pulling this up,
this now here's another pop up.
But,
um,
this summer,
I think it was right before the
basketball season started this a
scandal.
It had hit the world.
Rick Pitino is,
I think he might've been running the
athletic program in some capacity,
I don't know if he was the age,
but he was definitely.
That is one of the top basketball
coaches in the country and he was
getting 98 percent of the cash of this
deal they had with Adidas.
And what
did she know about this deal?
That's.
That's so he raked in 98 percent of the
cash from the University of Louisville.
Is Current Adidas deal?
How is that possible?
It's a.
it's a.
it's hard to explain how it can even
happen.
If you watch the movie blue chips from
the nineties,
they sort of almost tap into it,
but this was 15 years even before this
has happening,
so there's a whole extra world going on.
Right.
He said,
this is what's funny.
The reporter asked him of some of the
proceeds will be shared with the
university.
He says in quotes,
it's for the athletic department,
junk reply.
How do you say his name?
Derek Jurich replied.
It's for these student athletes.
It's been earmarked for them high.
In fact,
under the current deal with Adidas,
which explained,
which expires July first 98 percent of
the cash provided by adidas goes to one
person,
Rick Pitino the now suspended head
coach.
That's fucking crazy.
Look at the next sentence.
Oh God.
Two Thousand Fifteen,
2016.
For example,
one point $5 million went to Pitino
under his personal services agreement
with the Apparel Company is $25,000.
Went to the program according to the
contract obtained by the courier journal
under the State's public records act
the year before the department got 10
grand and we got one point 5 million.
That's incredible.
Why would they pay him so much?
Because he didn't work.
He can recruit a,
it's so he can recruit the kids to this
school because he's got the name and
whether or not he's got some sort of
ability to sell them also,
you know,
I don't know that,
but he can bring them in because he's
got a,
uh,
almost a franchise of national
championships or at least the ability to
be on national TV.
And then that level of Spanish
tournament I'm telling you about.
Like he'll get your eyes on there,
which gets you with the NBA contract,
which is the old old dream.
While you can sell that,
they can sell that dream to them.
Those NBA deals are the best fucking
deals in the world.
The guaranteed contracts to play and the
shoe deals.
Those shoe deals are big.
Do the shoe deals for those guys.
The NBA guys for the top tier guys,
which is of course a very select few,
but it's nine figures before they ever
played ball like they're.
They're signing like hundred million
dollar deals.
Jesus for they play professional
basketball.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
There's fucking amazing and outrageous
amounts of money.
We were talking about under armour,
about how one,
what was the player that said nobody
wants to play in under armour's having
there and said that he needs sank the
stock.
By saying that because universities have
deals with sneaker competence and that
no one wanted to play for Maryland
because they didn't want to play with
under armour.
I didn't want to wear under armor and
everything just went and they had been
struggling ever since.
Really?
Yes.
It's amazing to me the way under armour
has been able to compete,
period,
like that is so outrageous that that's a
former university of Maryland student
athlete.
I think he was a student athlete and
that he was able to start an apparel
company,
Athletic Company,
and really actually compete with Adidas
and Nike.
I mean that is so nuts.
It would be like you starting a fucking
car tomorrow and then you're like,
yeah,
it's you Porsche,
bmw or a joke or what do you like?
Like it's fucking,
it's.
That's how nuts that is to break into
that field.
Really?
Yeah.
Fuck.
Yet his men that they have that shit so
locked down.
They have such deep pockets.
They're the,
the levels of endorsements and like what
he started doing,
the under armour guy wouldn't even pay.
Like now they have paid endorsed
athletes,
but at first people were just liking the
gear.
He was like one of the first ones to
develop that,
you know that like tight fit,
breathe.
Right.
I'm like compression gear and like he
developed some of it and we'd give it to
a former p,
like people he knew at University of
Maryland,
we're now like in the,
they're like,
I like to shit and so does my boy,
you know,
throw us some more of that.
And it was like that.
It was like,
you know,
just kind of a very organic way of
developing,
of like somebody would be like,
if you bake something and you're like,
oh,
that tastes good,
like you make me another one from me and
my friends.
It was that I was reading something
really interesting where they were
saying that they,
they're fucking up the brand because
they've put them into discount stores,
that they're trying to raise the sails
and by raising the sales they put them
in a discount stores and by putting them
in the discount stores,
they're going to change the way people
look at the brand.
It's not going to be worth as much.
That's probably a very realistic man.
That's very interesting.
Weird people think so weird and no.
If you saw a pair of Nike's at a
discount store,
would you like go for north?
That what?
That means?
Zero to me.
Yeah.
No,
and they hadn't been in Nike has a
outlet stores,
which is like discount now.
Yes.
You know,
so that's,
that's Kinda weird.
But it is true about how.
I mean the other one is like that big
baller brand there basically attempting
to compete in the apparel world.
Lavar Ball,
right?
Yeah.
President guy that got in that crazy
thing because his son was arrested in
China for shoplifting.
Yes.
The China.
He was in China.
Yeah.
He was shoplifting and then trump says
he got him out and the dad says he
didn't get them out.
Yeah,
it's that.
That's him.
Then.
And then the dad is trump's calling the
data fool.
What happened that trump's.
I mean,
well that guy is very brash of our ball.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
But I think you know,
that guy knows what he's doing,
man.
As far as,
as far as pr,
definitely.
He knows he's going to say some wild
shit and he knows people are going to be
like,
oh my God,
what did he say?
And then he knows that that gets him
more press and like it,
it kind of just feeds itself and people
act like he believed the fucking crazy
shit that asshole just said.
And he was like,
yeah,
that's what I do and that's why you keep
putting me on the show.
But he's like trump,
when he was running for prep 100
percent,
it's the same school of thought and now
though that guy.
So he has a son in Lonzo plays for the
Lakers,
who's a fourth round,
first round draft pick,
like a top tier player from Ucla.
Then his other son was two more sons.
One of them was on Ucla team this year,
got arrested for shoplifting in China.
If he hadn't been released,
if it wasn't high,
blissfully highly publicized thing,
he definitely could have gone to jail
for a while in China.
They don't fuck around,
you know.
Right.
So,
but anyways,
when he got out and came back,
Lavar pulled him from like from school,
from Ucla and also pulled his 16 year
old son at a highschool and flew them to
Lithuania where they're now playing.
Both of them were playing professional
basketball in Lithuania and professional
professional quotes.
Jamie did the air quotes.
It's got to be in big air quotes.
Yeah,
for sure.
Well,
I mean there's definitely some,
some good players that come out of
there,
but it's like,
I mean it is a circus over there if you
see like how it was when they arrived.
It was like some crazy.
The reception,
you know.
So what is he trying to do now is trying
to start some new league.
He's trying to do a couple things.
He started a brand big baller brand and
they know that's like their ball and
they came out with these shoes.
They're basically $500 retail sneakers
and if you're like,
that's expensive because you're not a
big baller bitch.
That's why,
you know,
it's like what are they like made by a
real organization?
Didas no,
no,
no.
They're not made by definitely not any,
and by the way,
the sun that's in the NBA turned down
real money,
like real fucking money because he was
the father demanded that you basically
pay to develop this brand from the big
uh,
apparel and the guy's like,
give us like a billion dollar contract
and like develop this brand.
What?
And they were like,
no,
we're not doing that.
And he's like,
well then we're not even going to talk
to you about endorsing my science.
Seriously.
One hundred percent.
Yes.
Then now he's had like,
there's so much a conversation about the
brand that he's definitely elevated the
awareness of it.
What we don't know,
what nobody knows is like,
to what level are they actually selling
this apparel,
you know,
like are they.
Because they have everything.
They have shirts and shoes.
They just got it rated an f by the
better business bureau because their
shoes are not the ones they sold.
They sold a bunch of shoes and they're
the ones that people are getting are not
what they bought.
So people are pissed.
There's no way to return refund.
Yeah.
Great Fund or exchange them.
Yeah,
and they're just telling people they're
literally.
I think I read that the customer service
people told you,
oh,
you must be a brook baller then if
you're not satisfied.
Yeah.
That's literally what my God.
But he's also.
I mean he's.
So anyways,
he's,
he's the,
he took these kids to Lithuania.
They're going to play basketball.
He's like,
he basically says they're going to be on
the Lakers when my three sons are going
to be Lakers.
So.
And we have no idea really realistically
whether the two younger sons even have,
we don't know to be fair whether they're
going to be mba quality players yet,
you know,
like the clearly one is the one is on
the Lakers,
but so we don't know if that's going to
pan out in any way,
shape or form.
He also talked about developing a league
for like kids that are coming out of
high school that don't want to go to
college and play in a league where they
get paid like a salary,
you know,
a reasonable salary,
which is an idea that a lot of people
think is fascinating.
I don't know logistically whether he
could pull that off,
you know,
that's kind of a know for sure.
Right.
I mean,
but.
But the idea is one that people have
talked about for years because college
athletes generate a lot of revenue
getting fucked.
Yeah.
Pay Athletes Getting pimped out.
One hundred percent.
Especially in football and basketball.
But will.
You were telling me what I was talking
to Jamie when you went to Pete about
the,
how big the game was that you went to
fucking God.
And I was saying is what about baseball?
Baseball like down,
like,
no,
nobody gives a fuck about college
baseball.
Basketball is a little bit,
you said March madness.
Definitely those are the big college
football.
Get that big time.
That's the end.
It's worth billions of dollars.
Many billions.
Yeah.
Which is crazy.
Those kids aren't getting paid.
That doesn't make any fucking sense.
Well,
we've got a free scholarship,
Joe.
He could go to school for free and oh
great.
Get $25,000 a years.
Where the free education.
Fuck you.
I,
I tend to agree.
I'd say there's a couple of kids,
a interesting story that came out
earlier this year.
He's on one of the teams that did really
good UFC or ucf,
I'm sorry.
GCFS kicker was a youtuber right as the
season started and he got in trouble
because he was making profit off of his
likeness on Youtube.
So they took away his ability to do
that.
Oh,
he got kicked off the team and I think
he left the team.
Oh my God.
You fucking monsters.
Like,
I know what,
you don't own people that.
That's what drives me crazy.
It's like you don't own people.
They're providing a service that makes
you an extraordinary amount of money and
yet you are keeping all of it like depth
pitino thing.
One point 5 million to give him 10
grand,
10 grand out of the money.
Oh,
that's the argument.
I know.
I think that the thing about assholes to
people who,
um,
who really argue the free education
thing and like how that should be of
value is because they ain't worth a
shit.
Like that's why they think that's
awesome.
Yeah.
Like your skill level is not impressive
and you don't generate millions and
billions of dollars,
so you go fucking $100,000 worth of free
education there.
It's like,
yeah,
but like I'm bringing in 10 million to
the table,
bro.
That's the thing.
And here's the big thing.
How much damage are they getting in that
four years?
How much damage they're doing to their
body and football in high level,
division one fbs football.
Lot of those dudes are playing and
they're playing basically with,
you know,
the,
the next NFL players.
So they're,
yeah,
they're fucking each other up.
They're fucking each other up.
And the odds of their body getting
damaged to the point where they can
never compete professionally are very
hot.
Oh definitely.
Yeah.
So if you think of like there was a
statistic about nba or excuse me,
nfl players,
like how many of them make it into the
fourth year and it's very low for long
league.
Very call it.
Yeah.
This is what they call,
that's the nickname for the NFL.
Not for long.
Yeah.
The average NFL career is three point
some seasons,
so yeah.
Yeah.
So think of that you're,
you're basically trying to do to outrun
that through college and then make it
into the pros.
Yeah.
That's why you really,
from a business perspective,
you really have to support guys coming
out of college early to the NFL.
Oh,
100 percent.
I mean there's people who are like,
some people I've get the fuck outta
here.
I'll read a book.
Yeah,
I'm balling.
I'll go back,
go back with my free time,
then go back.
You're still only going to be 25 years
old when your career's over.
That's fucking nuts.
This millions on the table.
Millions.
Twenty two.
Come on.
Hello?
You ever think about how poorly you
would handle that?
I think about it now a lot.
If I had been 22 and so it's almost like
here's $10,000,000.
I'd be like,
wow,
I would definitely not have been like,
yeah dude.
Able to handle that.
Well,
yeah,
I think about that hardcore.
I think about like what if I won the
lottery when I was 20?
Like what?
Go nuts.
You go nuts.
Yeah.
I got diamonds in my jacket,
man.
Check it out.
Diamonds on my teeth versus from my
buttons are all diamonds on my Dick
Hole.
Definitely.
Yeah.
I think um,
we talked,
we were talking about earlier about a
guy being rich and having enriched
children struggles.
Fucking very important for you.
Yeah.
It's very good for you.
It's very important for you.
It builds character.
It builds,
resolve,
respect now.
Yeah.
Respect money.
That like how many professional athletes
who wink millions of dollars work out as
hard as my friend Cameron Hanes,
right?
Think of that fucking guy has a regular
job.
Dude works with department of Water and
power and Oregon.
Does he really?
Yep.
Nine to five.
Regular job during his lunch hour.
He doesn't work.
Nine to five.
He works like seven to four and one of
the reasons why he's got an extra hour
in there is because he runs during his
lunch break,
so he takes like two hour lunches and
runs for two fucking hours,
runs the hills and then comes back and
finishes out the rest of the eight hours
of the day.
What that did,
it feels good all day though to savage.
Yeah.
It doesn't feel good.
He doesn't want to feel good just one
more time,
but he's happy.
He's happy and pain gets not grimacing
in pain.
He's like,
this shit hurts.
There's like it.
There's a mindset of those people though
that can do those ultra marathons.
That's a different world inside your
dome and you're some darkness in there.
You're trying to.
What was that woman that smashed all of
the important until Walter?
Yeah,
she passed.
Did you listen to the podcast?
She's not.
She's amazing.
She's Nachos and drinks.
Beer eats candy.
She's eating candy when she was hanging
out with what's going on in her brain,
man,
that's what I want to see.
I want to see a ct scan.
She's a straight up savage.
I'll tell you what she does.
She telling us about how she had some
sort of Retina Adima
where she was almost blind because,
uh,
her contacts fucked up or something like
that.
And her,
her,
her eyeballs were bleeding and she
couldn't see and she fell,
cracked her head open like,
like blood pouring down her head still.
One couldn't see,
couldn't see where her feet were while
she was running.
Her brain.
Can Not be the same.
She's just tough.
There's,
there's mental toughness that some
people have that is almost an
explainable like you don't like.
What makes them that tough?
I don't understand it.
The ability to block out all the
negative voices.
The stock.
I mean,
well,
think about personalities,
right?
Like a personality like burt.
It can be the life of the party.
That's not me.
I'm not that guy.
Never been that guy.
I mean I can.
I can.
If we're all hanging around together,
we're all drinking.
I can make everybody laugh and be silly
and we could all have a good time
together,
but I don't gravitate towards that
thinking,
that kind of behavior.
Whereas burt can walk into a liquor
store and having everybody sing along to
I would die for you.
He's got his phone out and people are
dancing and yeah,
it's genuine personality type too.
He is.
That's his personality type.
Some people have that personality type
where they'll get up at 4:30 in the
morning and you know it's dark outside
and they relish the fact that they don't
want to put the running shoes on and
they don't want to hit that mountain and
run.
They relish the fact that there there's
going to struggle.
They like it.
They like the pain,
they liked the stinging of the.
The lungs is there.
Your lungs struggle to fill with air
would like it.
Yeah.
True.
They like also the fact that other
people can't do what they can do.
That like the fact that there's people
that are in bed that are comfortably
asleep while they're out there doing it
and it gives them an edge.
Sure.
Yeah.
Well,
what,
what makes a person's personality to be
this outgoing extrovert like Bert
Kreischer?
What makes that stoic individual that
can sit and go over,
you know,
like an accountant who can just sit and
go over things for hours and hours.
A coder,
somebody could sit in front of a
computer and go over a 10,
12 hours a day is worth a certain
mindset.
It's a different kind of human,
right?
Yeah.
Because both of those personalities,
I could never entertain just so far from
what I am.
I'm fascinated by personalities.
Yeah.
I just find it.
There's so many variables like,
as to what makes a person who they are
and,
and how it changes over time and who,
who you are.
The more you consider yourself.
Like I did a podcast yesterday,
uh,
about meditation.
It was all about meditation with Dan
Harris from Good Morning America who's a
big proponent of meditation and um,
This Guy,
Jeff Warren who wrote this book,
a head trip,
very,
very interesting guy who was his
meditation teacher.
We're just talking about thought
processes and the mind and managing on
and managing the way you do things.
Don't do things and how much of these
little weird kinks and pitfalls can just
trip you up and fuck you up in your
life.
Like imagine Louis ck without this
desire to beat off in front of women.
Like let's say he did that 10 times in
his whole life.
Imagine if you could get to them before
those 10 times and go,
hey man,
look,
you're a real nice guy.
You've always been friendly to people.
You give good advice as a comedian.
Just can't beat off in front of people
because it's going to cost you like
$50,000,000 one day what you think so
yeah.
Yeah.
One day is going to cost you
$50,000,000.
We just beat off in front of people.
No one's going to work with you,
so just don't do that.
Don't do that.
Or here's what you could do.
Pay a hooker and say,
I want to beat off in front of you.
And she'll go,
okay,
and then you give her a thousand bucks
or whatever it costs and you beat off in
front of her.
If you could do that.
And he'd be like,
hmm.
That's not to say,
but like what would make a person what
makes a person tick?
Really?
Yeah.
What,
what?
What is it inside your head?
Like it's all your experiences really
that become your personality.
I think it that there's your
experiences,
there's managing your particular
biology,
you know,
there's so many,
so many different things.
Yeah.
Because like you,
you're at the age now to where you can
see like with your children.
Do you ever see how they're a certain
age now,
but you go like,
I saw that trait in you when you were
one.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You see like the stuff that's natural in
someone there,
the natural personality trait and then
you sprinkle life on top of that starts
to develop who the person becomes.
Well your son son's probably just now
starting to talk you.
You will start to have a little
conversation with them and then you'll
start to see you in them and that's
where it gets really weird.
You know?
You've inherited all my craziness.
You see that in your nine year old in
particular.
Really.
She's got a lot of my crazy enter.
Yeah.
You,
you,
you totally see yourself.
She gets obsessed with things.
I got assessed where she just,
she'll just do them like all day long,
like we went on a vacation and we were
walking back from the resort.
She did cartwheels all the way back from
the resort to the room.
It was a half mile to find cartwheels
over and over and over again.
She just gets nuts about stuff.
Is it the kind of thing we were like,
hey,
we should probably stop doing that,
or no,
let her do it.
I don't.
I think as long as your kids aren't
hurting themselves and hurting other
people,
the more you say,
Hey,
don't do that,
the more they're going to want to do
that.
It's just natural.
What I try to do is encourage healthy
things.
That's it.
I try to like when it comes to like
candy and sugar and stuff like that,
I try to tell them,
taste great,
taste amazing,
but you're really only supposed to have
a little bit of it for your.
Just it's bad for your body,
you know?
I don't,
I
don't just give them the,
hey,
you can eat candy.
Hey,
you can't do that.
I'm like,
little bit's good.
It's a little bit.
It's fine.
Let's have a little bit.
Let's enjoy it,
but let's understand what it is like,
let's be aware of what it is,
but don't be afraid of it.
Don't run from it.
Don't you know?
Yeah.
Nobody died because they had an ice
cream once a week.
Sure.
You know,
it's not going to hurt.
You just don't have it every fucking
night.
Yeah.
I just don't get crazy.
Don't let it become a part of everything
who you are.
And one of the things that I do the most
though is encouraged them.
Like what are they,
what do they enjoy doing?
Like what do you enjoy doing?
You know,
like my youngest one loves art.
He loves to draw,
loves it because it's constantly drawing
this awesome.
Like let's draw,
let's see,
let's look,
let's do smart.
It's fun.
It's like there's something like find
out whatever it is where you can find
this avenue for expression and,
and I want to encourage that as much as
I can because I feel like if there's
anything in this life that'll guarantee
you some satisfaction or some feeling of
accomplishment or some,
some,
uh,
some way to fuel your passions,
it's find something that really hits
your switches.
Find that thing.
Like you found it,
right.
You found it,
but stand up.
Yeah,
totally.
I mean,
but you imagine doing something else
other than stand up?
No,
of course not.
I mean,
at this point,
I don't know.
I tell people that all the time
actually.
It's like that's the thing you become
aware of.
I think when you get older you're like,
I'm so lucky that I do the thing I
really liked doing the most.
That's really the thing.
And then you meet people like at the
time,
but like I talked to people who,
you know,
I'm just happy with what they're just
like,
I'm not happy with my life and this and
that.
I'm like,
what is it you really want to do?
And they got,
I don't know,
like real question,
real question.
If somebody wanted a trade lives,
Jeff Bezos wanted to trade lives,
you get to be Jeff Bezos,
you get 100,
$5,000,000,000,
but you can't do standup anymore.
No,
because I love it.
I love it.
Yeah.
That's so hard for people to imagine.
Well no,
because like I mean that,
that I know that sounds like a comical
amount of money and that like who the
fuck would turn that down?
But it's like I don't really feel like
I'm turning something down because I
have,
I get so much pleasure and joy out of
doing what I do.
So he made that deal and you came back
to the comedy store and you're watching
somebody just kill and you'd be like,
fuck,
I want to go up.
And they're like,
Nah,
man,
you got to take your spaceship home now.
And you're sitting around writing things
down when you think they're funny and
you never just getting it to people.
You take a see if you can make it work.
Do you remember Tom Agnina [inaudible]?
He's a really funny comedian.
And uh,
apparently he lives in Thailand now and
just fucking retired on is a writer's
guild money really?
And uh,
his mortgage is like 500 bucks a month
and a,
Neil Brennan went to see him last week
in Thailand.
Really?
Yeah.
And he was a comic?
Yup.
He's a funny comic.
I knew him from Boston.
Really good guy.
There's Tom,
magna.
Really good guy.
He's retired.
He lives in Thailand.
Good for him.
Just on the beach,
just kicking back.
And apparently he writes still.
He'll still like write,
write stuff for people but doesn't give
a fuck anymore.
Good for him in.
Yeah,
I mean I hear about things like that and
I go,
wow.
He did it.
He figured out a way to do it.
You figured out a way to get off the
bus?
Yeah,
I don't think I'm getting off.
I feel like I'm going to George Carlin,
this motherfucker keep driving it.
Yeah.
I feel like one day I'm gonna die in a
hotel room somewhere.
Eighty years old.
I don't know.
I mean sometimes I think about like how
like God damn I'm going to.
How much longer am I going to do this
for is it feels like there's too much
time still ahead of me.
You know what I mean though,
but I mean like I go like,
wait,
I'm gonna do this for 25 more years or
something.
That's fucking nuts.
The only thing that excites me as much
as outdoor stuff.
So you really love that shit.
Kinda jealous of all your hobbies,
but not,
not.
I mean,
just that you.
I'm jealous of the fact that you're
passionate about like hunting,
shooting pool,
Jujitsu,
you know,
archery.
I'm like,
God damn,
I wish I had that much passion for at
least one other thing.
You know?
I just think I'm crazy.
I think I find these things and then I
get obsessed with them.
Yeah.
You know,
I'm lucky that there's like I have to
manage those things.
Like got to be careful.
Like I'm,
I'm lucky I don't know how to fix cars
if I knew how to fix Kadlec I ha.
I entertain this idea for awhile of
building a car from scratch,
really of getting a frame and then
starting to put suspension on it.
And I said,
no,
you've got to stop.
Like you can't do this,
this will take too much time.
You can't do this.
I can't.
And I would like it.
I would like it.
I'd start wiring things.
Surprise you.
Don't move or at least get a place in
the woods.
I think that's something.
We're got to get to that too.
Yeah,
I'm scared of that too.
I,
you know,
when we lived in boulder,
I liked it a lot.
I went to that house.
Yeah,
it's beautiful.
Yeah.
So peaceful up there,
right?
Amazing.
Just woods and mountain lions eat and
your dog and shit.
I guess it's weird,
but I don't know man.
I just have to for,
for me,
it's always like make sure,
like there's almost like there's two
me's,
there's the manager me,
it's like,
hey,
hold on.
Before we,
before we embark on this journey,
let's take a look at where this could go
wrong.
Let's take a look at where this can go
before I release the hounds.
And then there's the other part that's
like,
just wants to just go,
go for it.
Go do things.
You know.
I want a hobby though,
Dude.
You what kind?
I don't know.
When I go hunting with me.
Um.
Oh,
hunting.
I would go to a range first to see how
much I dig.
I haven't shot.
I've shot an arrow bow and arrow,
but it's been like 25 years.
I've got a range here.
Or You have a range here?
Yeah,
that's an indoor archery range in this
place.
Okay.
I'll.
This weekend I'm getting to a thing
called a techno hunt installed.
Techno hunt
is a.
have you ever seen that video game where
you hit a golf ball in the virtual golf
ball screen?
Yeah,
they make that with archery.
You're doing that with bow hunting here?
Yep.
So there's the animals walk across the
screen and you shoot it,
the animals with a regular compound bow.
And instead of having sharp pointed
tips,
this is,
this is the game right here.
You have a tip that has a flat head,
like the head of a nail.
And so these animals walk across the
screen and you literally shoot at the
target and like,
watch it'll show you like it's going to
be like,
yeah,
I have what's coming this weekend,
Bro.
See,
watch it.
It hits where shoots it,
where you would want to get right there,
right behind the arm.
Bam.
Perfect shot.
So that's going to be like kill.
So it shows where the,
the,
the thing hit and it shows your score
and your vitals,
stuff like that.
Very cool.
You're going to be really into this.
It's crazy.
There are a burt and I went to top golf.
You know what that is?
Oh,
that's in Vegas,
right on top of that.
Exactly.
They have one in Vegas and they have
like,
I dunno,
like 25 locations.
Oh,
they're all over the place.
We stayed.
We stayed there for like hours hours.
Like we thought we were going to play
around but it just became addictive and
fun.
We just kept kept doing it.
It's not just driving.
Do you have like a bay?
Right.
And then like your own the tea and,
and um,
you know,
the three of you put your names in the
system and you get a real golf ball and
they,
uh,
track the balls.
So like when you hit it,
there's targets that you can go for
points.
Oh you hit that flat nose like already
hit the flag and it like,
so you get like eight points and then it
will be like your next balls were double
and if he hit the blue flag it's going
to be like 16 points.
So like,
and then there's different games within
the system.
You can go just for like chip shots.
You can go for distance anyways,
we just,
man,
I thought we were,
we thought we were going to play like an
hour.
I think we say four hours.
That's crazy.
And,
and we were all like,
we got to find another top golf.
Like we were really,
really into it.
Man.
You guys don't even play golf now.
I mean I know those two used to play,
like already said he played regularly a
long time ago.
Same with Bert.
They both had much better shots than me,
but I was equally obsessed with it,
like I didn't care that I was even
shitting the bed.
I was having so much fun doing it.
So many different things you could do.
That's why when people tell me that
they're bored,
I mean,
unless you're broke and there's nothing
you can do,
but even then there's so many physical
activities that you do that are free.
No.
Yeah,
I understand.
I'm not bored.
I didn't mean to.
I just like um,
you know,
throwing myself into an activity like
that.
So you need a hobby?
I think so why don't you get into
Jujitsu?
Nah,
no,
I don't like that guy.
I just need a gun.
I never liked.
I never liked wrestling.
I wrestled,
I hated it.
I just don't like having like guys on
top of you.
Yeah.
And I don't like,
you know,
my neck being jacked or any of that
shit.
Like I didn't,
I never liked,
you know,
how about more time.
I liked throwing punches.
That's cool.
I like that.
Yeah.
Just taking them more Thai class,
learning how to kick the bag or and how
to hit the pads.
Maybe learning how to use your defense
move.
Push away.
I like that.
Maybe photography.
I'm like old ladies tries to pinch her
ass after show you sweep the leg,
sweep the leg,
knock her out.
Take her down.
Arash.
Get some good press next day.
Q magic.
Did you see that thing with uh,
Josh Homme from the Queens of the Stone
Age kitten?
Some photographer?
Yes.
The fuck was going on?
Yeah.
Apparently the later stories like with
her flash was really fucking bothering
everybody.
Oh,
it wasn't like she wasn't supposed to
have a flash going,
but that was not okay.
The way that shit went down,
man.
Yeah.
You're supposed to go,
hey,
lady turned the fucking off.
And he wasn't part of his thing.
Like I was trying to kick the camera
where be like,
kicked her in the head or cities kicking
equipment around and he accidentally
kicked.
He made a bunch of bullshit for
delivery.
You can super.
Yeah.
He kicked her in the face like the
cameras like right here.
And he hits her in the Mug.
Yeah.
No,
he fucked her as well.
In his defense though,
he might've been like super frustrated
if that was the case.
Someone was like flashing and his face
by the way over.
And I can totally see a,
you know,
losing your shit on stage.
I think it's happened to everybody to
see it,
but it's not okay.
Kick it.
So no,
no,
no.
Something I've wanted to kick someone
have you for sure.
I mean over the course of a whole
career.
Yeah.
I've wanted to kick someone.
You know,
it's interesting.
I watched a,
I did long beach.
I did that.
Um,
was it the terrace theater?
Forget what theater is in Long Beach.
Big Ass theatre in Long Beach.
Great Theater.
Really weird because there's no,
you could never have this theater today.
It will be completely illegal because
there's the way to get out like the
rose,
the rose or like 70 seats long.
And there's no aisle in the middles.
There's eye on the left side.
I on the right side.
But the whole span in front of you is
just seats.
It's amazing to perform there.
It's still there.
Yeah,
that's the place.
Yeah.
God,
yeah,
look at that.
Oh yeah.
Crazy man.
You got to get up,
take a picture.
You got to Piss in your,
in the middle.
You're fucked.
You 40 people,
especially if you're overweight,
if you're a big fella and you trying to
get through all that.
Um,
but anyway,
when I went there,
uh,
they,
they informed me that that was where
Richard Pryor did his live in concert
from 79.
That's rerecorded.
And I went back and watched it after I
got home and I was like,
holy shit,
this is crazy.
He pulled up to the same doc where I
pulled up.
He walks in with his wife,
goes to the same back area that I went
to.
Then I watch it and in the beginning of
it there's a fucking guy in the front of
the stage who's getting
like Richard Pryor is on stage and he's
standing there taking pictures of
Richard Pryor while he's filling
especial and Richard Richard's going sit
down,
motherfucker.
Stop taking my picture.
Like he's saying,
even in [inaudible] 79,
it was an issue.
I'll take a picture and it's just a guy
in the audience.
It's not a professional photographer.
What do you think that phone thing are
you going to do that?
Yes,
I'm doing that.
You are that,
that is.
Oh,
okay.
I should probably tell people,
um,
for my shows upcoming in Austin,
Houston and Durham,
North Carolina.
There's a company called Yonder.
Yeah.
They take your phone,
they put it into a bag and you keep
your.
Keep your phone,
but they have to open your bag when you
leave.
So you're not making any phone calls.
You're not doing any tax.
You're not filming,
you're not doing anything.
I watched Chappelle special when
Chappelle did that and I was like,
this is it.
Yeah.
And it was fucking amazing how much more
tuned in people are like when they don't
have their phone.
Yeah.
Especially it just checking your texts
and every time you're on stage.
I mean,
how many times are people just standing
there filming things?
So I just did a show where it was like
fourth row dark house and you just see,
see the light fucking beacon of light
and I was like doing,
I'm doing,
I'm talking,
I'm talking and then just like trying to
finish a bit and then I did it.
I'm like,
hey man,
what are you doing?
What,
what are you,
what are you doing?
He's not even listening.
When I asked him what he's doing and
then his friends were like,
Hey,
he looks up,
I go,
what are you doing for work?
you bought these tickets to do work?
And he was like,
I just,
I got to do it.
I go,
no,
you had lighting up the whole room,
like always believed.
Don't realize that.
Go.
There's like 15 minutes left.
And he's like,
alright.
And he flipped it over,
put the phone down,
not not two minutes later he's back on
his phone,
back on it back doing things that I was
like and I actually knew to not say
anything at the second time because I
didn't want to.
I didn't want the show to be about that
because I was like,
this is going to be negative.
Right.
But thankfully the staff noticed and
they went over there and,
and I don't know,
Tom,
I'm doing this from now on.
I think this phone thing,
some people don't like it.
That's okay,
but it's gonna make a better show.
Here's the thing so that people know
because I know a little bit about the
honor thing too,
is like if you're like,
well,
what if I need to.
You can actually.
You can leave the showroom.
Yeah.
And they'll unlock it for you.
You can make your call.
Yeah.
In the lobby,
but it's just keeping people tuned in
and not distracting people.
I went to see a love the Beatles show at
the Mirage.
Fucking amazing.
The cirque Du Soleil show is incredible.
Incredible.
This guy in front of me has this
brightness Jack to the fucking roof and
he's texting people like,
so while I'm trying to watch the show,
this guy has this bright phone and he's
just sitting there texting.
Yeah.
All over and over and over again.
Completely disrespecting all the people
around him.
Everybody's just got to go like this
because the place is pitch black,
so a lot of this stuff is going on
because there's like there's stuff comes
down from the ceiling and people are
descending and they're doing this
acrobatics and this Dick had is just
constantly on his fucking phone.
Yeah.
It's like just do you want to fucking
experience things for a minute?
You know what I mean?
Like you go to Cirque du Soleil or you
go to Joe Rogan's show,
it's like you fucking.
When you decided to go to the thing like
don't you want to experience the show?
Yeah,
just watched the show for a minute.
You got to force people because there's
a certain amount of people that are just
not going to.
You're getting a deal.
It's not cheap.
It costs money.
Yeah.
But I feel like it's gonna be worth it.
I think so too,
and I'm definitely going to do it for my
special.
Oh yeah,
I'm good.
I understand it from now on because my
last two specials I dealt with people
sitting in the front row and second road
is standing there holding that phone up
in front of you,
holding it right at you.
Like you don't think that's distracting.
You don't think that's weird.
Live your life I think is especially
good thing to do in a big,
big venue.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So that's it folks.
So if you come into a Austin,
Houston,
and Durham for taking your phone and put
it in a bag,
phone up.
Keep that phone up.
Give me that.
You did.
You're special in Denver,
right?
At the paramount.
Yeah.
It's fucking great place.
It's great.
I love that shit.
It's still.
It's still my favorite man.
It's my favorite city.
I think if I moved anywhere it'll either
be there or maybe seattle.
Those are my spots.
I would love to live.
I love actually downtown Denver.
I would also think it'd be amazing to
live like 20 minutes outside of Denver.
Yeah,
go to golden.
Live in the woods.
Be Amazing.
I really think.
I think it's in my future.
Do I?
Do?
You're going to bail out in California.
I don't think I'm gonna do it in like
the next couple of years,
but I think in my life I will move to
Colorado at some point.
Um,
yeah,
I really love it.
I love to all aspects of it.
Like I like the culture.
I like,
I like the outdoors.
I liked the people that I meet.
They're always had great people there.
Yeah.
They have all the infrastructure you
want from a big city.
You have access to everything.
Oh yeah.
Great restaurants you have great.
Uh,
you know,
the big sports,
they have entertainment.
They have,
they have everything you want.
The people are cool as fuck too.
They really are.
It's just,
they're not pretentious.
Like a lot of people that live in la or
San Francisco or New York,
they're very laid back,
but you know,
they're surrounded by also.
I think there's something about being
surrounded by the rocky mountains.
I think it's good.
Start taking yourself seriously.
You just look out and go,
Oh yeah,
fucking the vastness of all this.
It's incredible.
There's a great nightmare.
I had such a fucking lucky night.
It was an awesome night to do the
special.
I'm trying to do red rocks,
but every time I look for a date I got
to look to three years in advance.
It's like Tuesday and Wednesday nights.
I heard about that.
I was talking to them about red rocks
and they're like,
people will take a date they don't even
want because it's years in advance.
Yeah,
well that's what they offered me.
They offered me a bunch of Tuesdays and
Wednesdays and they're not in the in
like in 20,
20 or something.
Twenty 19.
There's like Tuesdays and Wednesdays and
29.
That's all that's available.
Yeah.
Wow.
I was like,
I can't get a Friday.
Yeah,
but the Belko the place that I do
normally.
Yeah,
I liked that too,
but that's like 5,000 something.
Whereas red rock is like 9,000.
It's a lot.
But.
But you were doing to bell to Bell Co's?
Yeah.
That's $10,000.
No,
it's not.
I can do enough people,
but it's just.
I like people want to go out on Saturday
night.
Yeah.
They want to go out and Friday night
they don't want to go on fucking
Wednesday.
Yeah,
hi to them.
Some weird.
Have you been out to red rocks
amphitheatre?
No.
Yeah.
We need those to be the shit that.
Yeah,
I heard.
It's incredible.
Brian Regan was in and he was telling me
how he performed there.
There's video of it.
He made like a whole film but really
loved it.
So it was amazing.
Not a lot of comedians perform there
though.
It's pretty.
It's pretty special.
Yeah.
What's it got to be?
You got to do it.
Yeah.
All right.
Well let's wrap this bitch up everybody
tomorrow.
Meaning tonight,
midnight tonight.
The great and powerful Tommy Buttons
special comes out on Netflix.
Don't sleep.
This is what you do.
You get up early and you watched the
last one first.
Yeah.
Mostly stories get jacked up.
That'll be a warmup.
And then describe why disgraceful.
It's how my mother described my standup.
One time she came and saw me on this
tour and she saw,
you know,
like when your parents come and you're
like,
ah man,
you know,
and uh,
it was a good one,
like she came to a good show,
right?
And they came backstage and it was like
my dad was,
a lot of people are buddy kind of money.
You get something like this total dad
question.
And my mom was,
I was having,
we think mom and she was like,
amazing battle your language.
It's like if these bullets,
no,
if,
if you said these case was like thinking
of titles.
And I was like,
oh,
I love upsetting.
So I called it disgraceful.
Various.
Your mother has a strong Spanish accent,
right?
Very strong.
That's funny.
Yeah.
When you speak Spanish in front of you.
I've talked to people about it before,
but it's funny when you speak Spanish in
front to people that didn't expect it.
Yeah.
I talk about it in the special.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I have a bit of bad.
Yeah,
because it throws them off guard.
They're like,
how do you do that?
He looks so white.
I know,
I know.
And then my sisters are darker,
like they have a darker complexion than
me.
Oh,
do they?
Yeah.
Especially if we go,
like if we go into the sun for a few,
they turn in the fucking incas and just
burned.
So yeah,
it's very just you could tell it's just
genetics.
I got like my dad's skin and they got
hers.
Alright Ladies and gentlemen,
that's it tonight.
Midnight.
Tommy bonds on Netflix.
Don't sleep.
Definitely watch it.
Anything else?
Thanks brother.
I love you.
Thank you.
I love you too,
man.
Thank you very much.
Anytime by everybody.
I will be back in a little bit with UFC
welterweight champion,
tyron woodley.
See Ya.
Tyron here today.