Hello everybody.
What's happening?
This episode of the podcast is
brought to you by legal zoom.
Legal Zoom is a website that allows you
to do a lot of things that you would
normally have to go to a law office to do.
You could do online the comfort
of your home. And this month,
legal zoom celebrates innovation
by helping you launch your dream.
You're gonna apply for a patent,
cure your invention,
register your trademark to protect
your products and services.
Incorporate or form an LLC
to start your business.
All the things you would normally
have to do at a law office,
you'd have to make an appointment.
You have to spend a shitload of
money enough to go somewhere,
do it all from the comfort of
your home quickly and easily.
And if you get into a situation where
you're not sure if you're doing everything
right and you're kind of panicking,
legal zoom can help you by hooking
you up with a third party independent
attorney.
They are not a law firm,
but they can provide you with self help
services and again connect you to a
third party attorney. If you're a
scared little bitch and you thank you,
done fucked up. They can set up
a lot of things at legal zoom.
Like you could form an
LLC, you can, um, you can,
uh, incorporate, you
can set a living, will,
you can even get divorced. Believe it
or not, you can get divorced online.
Um, I think you'd have to get, like,
it would have to be really amicable.
So you know,
couldn't be like arguing custody and shit,
but you get a divorce or 299 bucks.
If you and the missus were so inclined,
you know, like, look enough,
I got 300 bucks, let's fucking
do this. You can do it.
And you going to do it all again
from the comfort of your own home.
These are strange times.
We live in ladies and gentlemen,
Legal Zoom also has an a plus from
the better business bureau and a plus,
which is pretty fantastic.
I'll let you know what a an
awesome service they provide.
They don't just hand out a pluses.
They have for 14 years. Um,
they've been in business and they've
helped over a million businesses get
started. Uh, that's
pretty impressive stuff.
Celebrate innovation with legal zoom
through the end of June and get a special
price on a trademark copyright
or provisional patent by
using the referral code.
Rogan at checkout legal zoom provides
legal help through independent attorneys
and self harm and self help
but they are not a law firm.
Legal zoom.com use the code
word Rogan at checkout.
We were also brought to you by
on.com that's o. N. N. I. T.
We are a human optimization website.
We sell you the very best and
strength and conditioning equipment,
the very best in nutritional supplements
for cognitive function for your immune
system, for health, for mood,
for endurance, shroom Tech Sport,
which I took today before I worked
out with Duke motherfucking Rufus.
I take it one hour before every workout.
Shroom tech sport is one of my all time
favorite supplements and if if we didn't
sell it at on it, I would push a
justice hard. It is fantastic stuff.
If you're into anything
that's very difficult to do.
If you're into like some sort of crossfit
star working out or if you wrestle or
do martial arts or anything that's very,
very strenuous.
Shroom tech sport is one of the most
amazing supplements that I have ever used
as far as giving you a little bit of extra
push and it's based on the courthouse
steps mushroom,
it's all the stuff that we salad on it.
This is one important feature.
If you go to the website and look
at all the different supplements,
there's an overview. There's a bunch
of different tabs you can click on,
but one of the most important
ones is the research thing.
All these supplements that are like,
whether it's an endurance supplement or
supplements that are designed to raise
your testosterone or supplements are
designed to enhance cognitive function.
All that stuff can be very controversial.
So we try to show as much research as
possible and provide you with as much
information and data as possible
about what has been shown by um,
different double blind placebo studies
like the ones that we perform and the
ones that other people are performed. We
performed our own on um, on Alpha brain.
The results are all available online.
We're actually in the middle
of a second test right now.
Very happy with the results and very
happy with the results from other tests
that we can show you.
A quarter seps increases oxygen
utilization utilization by 50%.
Pretty fascinating stuff.
Double Blind study published
in the medicine and science
and sports meant sports
and exercise. Researchers gave 30 male
athletes either cordyceps or a placebo.
The athletes did not change their exercise
routine during the study and after
six weeks as cordyceps group,
their oxygen intake was almost double the
placebo groups. All interesting stuff.
All with sources. It shows if
you go to the research, um,
click on the tab on
any of the supplements,
it'll give you all the information
that's currently available.
All the current science on all of the
ingredients of any of the supplements that
we carry.
We also have a 100% money back guarantee
on any of the supplements that we carry.
A 30 day or 30 pill rather,
90 day,
100% money back guarantee where you
do not have to return the product.
He just say, I want my money back. This
shit didn't make me work out harder.
But if you use it,
I guarantee you you're not going to want
that because you're going to want to be
able to buy more of it because it is
fantastic. Um, go to [inaudible] dot com.
Use the Codeword Rogan.
Save 10% off any and all supplements.
That's O. N N I t. Use
the codeword Rogan hang.
Get your freak on. Ladies and gentlemen,
Duke. Motherfucking Rufus is here.
Why play games? Jamie? Cue The
music. Let's get this shit started.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Try it by day.
Joe Rogan podcast all day,
my friend.
Well, martial artists,
former kickboxing champion,
commentator for glory,
more accolades on and on.
And I'm trainer of some of the greatest
mixed martial arts artists on the planet
earth. Two goofus ladies and gentlemen.
Thanks Joe. It's been a pleasure.
We had a great workout today. We are
changing, exchanging some thoughts.
Retro Rogan, man. That's, that's our new
term. Retro Rogan. Well, those tickets,
what we're talking about is a martial
arts techniques that were a part of what
you would consider a traditional
martial arts like taekwondo or karate,
that a lot of these techniques are
starting to find their way into MMA.
And so the arcs and kicked
and kicked by Raymond Daniels,
knock out of the century.
A Ed Cory 16. Yeah,
he threw this Raymond Daniels who was a,
a guy who had a background and karate.
Is that as it is? He took karate
or taekwondo. Kempo. Kempo similar.
Not unlike a MMA open martial
arts tournaments. Even
though you have one style,
everyone's got to learn how to do it so
everyone knows how to spin kick and so
forth. Um, that was an
incredible kick. Yeah,
he threw like a sidekick with his right
leg and then in the middle of the air
spun and hit the guy with a spinning side
kick in the face with his left leg was
just beautiful to watch. Go look it
up on Youtube. It's incredible. Yeah,
we'll pull it up.
Raymond Daniel.
We might've played it on the
podcast because it was so awesome,
like after it had happened
to Raymond Daniels, uh, k Oh,
it's just wild, wild kick. And
it was a crazy fight before that,
that he was in this wild exchange,
caught the guy with a punch, heard him,
dropped him, and then finished him off
of this wild kid it and style. Actually,
I mean, you look at some of the,
we were talking MMA kicks. Yeah,
I'll test.
So now even some cool stuff.
Some of my favorite spin kicks in
kickboxing. We're Stefan Leco verse,
uh, Badr Hari one in Amsterdam. He,
he knocked Badr Hari out with a back kick.
Then that was June of oh five.
Then November, November,
December of [inaudible] Five,
her Hari came back and knocked him
out with a wheel kick. And then, uh,
I think a year later,
uh,
Peter Graham knocked out Badr her
with a rolling thunder kick. I mean,
people don't think of that, those types
of moves and kickboxing, but yeah,
people are using them. High
level guys, if you could do,
we were just one of the things
we were talking about today.
If you can do the traditional techniques,
like in mode,
in kickboxing, leg kicks,
knees, all those things.
If you're good at all those things,
then you can add those things to your,
to your repertoire. The rolling
thunder kicks that wheel kicks.
So we're starting to see that a
little bit more and kickboxing,
but a lot more in MMA and MMA
it's become a big weapon. Yeah.
I think an MMA is just so wide open
because of there's so many weapons on the
battlefield.
I think it's easier to catch people
with them because you don't know it's a
takedown. Four ounce gloves changes
everything the size of the cage,
they move around a little
more. It makes it, I, I,
it's a controlled chaos
in there and I enjoy that.
I can kind of get crazy with striking.
Well,
do you think is that you're in a really
interesting too because you're, you're,
I mean,
people think of the UFC
as being established sport
and it most certainly is,
it's on Fox. It's on paper
view. You know, you say UFC,
everybody knows what you're talking
about. Pretty much mainstream. However,
it's still in this growth stage as
far as the techniques themselves.
No one has,
like if you're playing football,
there's pretty much everybody plays
football. Like a football player.
You don't see people
doing anything you'd like,
where the fuck did that come from?
But in MMA on any given night,
you'll see some crazy submission
that no one's ever done before.
You'll see someone do some crazy flying
kick that no one's ever attempted before.
You, you see things that you'll
see them for the first time ever,
like in a match and you go, that's the
first time. Like perfect example, um,
Mitch Clark pulled off a,
a a Darce choke from the
bottom against a ally Quinta.
And no one had never done that before.
No history of the UFC.
Nobody had ever pulled off
a Darce like a guard pass.
Doris like Jeff Glover hits that,
that move all the time.
Guard pass Doris in an MMA fight.
No one's ever done it from the bottom.
That's what I enjoy about
MMA. Like I said, the chaos,
something new is happening.
I mean,
I remember when Alan Belcher and on
the Tanwin says Nanako would call them,
but my man Alan Belcher hit that Superman
Punch at the UFC 100 and that was kind
of the beginning of even our
little evolution of, of doing it.
And then Anthony did it
against bark, Pella Chesky he
did a superman punch in WC.
And then of course is showtime
kick against role where
you actually use the cage
to sweep rower. I mean you were at
our old Jimmy saw small. It was,
and that's where a lot of
our like, uh, you know,
birth of those techniques.
And I told you how it started.
It's a blend of wound Bach and the
movie, the Lords of Dogtown, uh, the,
the documentary on it, like how they
change skating and I just, I dunno,
I got an a cloudy little phase where I,
I just wound Barack ran off the cage
then all these other techniques and,
and here we are.
I actually,
I mean I'm not bs and when I say to
Anthony as like another 10 moves he can do
off the cage, it's awesome.
Oh, I believe it was it,
that was the thing about the showtime kick
was that it was pretty clear after he,
after he threw the kick and
then after he talked about it,
this is not a technique they
just came up with on the fly.
This is something that they had
drilled. Oh yeah. It was so funny.
September before that fight,
um, he did a shoot with, uh,
the UFC magazine and he was doing the
kick off the wall on the pads and then
they're all like, stop. I'm
like, what did we do wrong?
We want to get our iPhones out the film,
this,
they're loving all the cool things here.
He's doing. And then the, in that camp,
he was doing it a lot off the wall with
his training partners. I mean, uh, I,
I love Anthony's, my really good
friend. We're close. He's a,
he's a god rather than my little
daughter and he's so open minded.
I'll show him something and people
look at him like, yeah, right.
I remember my really good friend
a Giuseppe. I was up at his place.
I was shown the showtime kick
at a seminar, the seminar
before. Everyone's like,
there's no way. And I got so many texts
after the vite. Yeah, you were right.
You know, I love that. I mean,
um, you know, it's again,
like you're talking about who,
who would've thought Alan Belcher
did what he did against Paul Harris.
He put them in the twist or almost
finished him with the twister and then not
again, we've seen, uh, the
Korean Zombie catch up.
Leonard Garcia with the twist or, I mean,
these are all moves would be obvious.
Doesn't work. I think anything works if
you train it enough. Yeah. And we'll,
the Paul Harris fight was really
interesting with Alan Belcher because Paul
Harris is known for being this
terrifying leg lock master.
Nobody wants to go to the ground with
them cause you go to the ground with him.
He just ripped guys and legs apart.
I mean you saw it in his world
series of fighting premiere. Oh yeah.
Fought for 30 seconds.
Got Ahold of the guy's lag,
rips his ligaments apart, its death.
I call him the Mike Tyson a of of,
of grappling like people fear,
grappling him.
There's not a lot of guys
that people were like, I fear,
but he has that Mike Tyson esque approach.
Aw Man,
my legs going to be toast. You know, I
remember in the fight, no Alan. Oh wait,
keep doing that. You're doing great. Yeah.
When he went to the ground with them
and it was engaging them with leg locks,
I was like, this is crazy. Like
he's going to get submitted here.
He's going to get his leg ripped apart.
But Alan had perfect defense.
It was one step ahead the entire way.
You could really see that he had studied
Paul Harris his game and just knew how
to defend it and it just was with him
every step of the way and then beat him
down. Oh No. That was fun. Again,
I love having people do things that
people can't or don't think they can do.
I did an interview with Ron
Kirk and inside MMA, um,
rate the week of Anthony's fight with
Henderson. They said, so how's the Viking?
I go down and he's going
to beat him with striking.
I said he's gonna beat him anyway once
they're like, yeah, right. I'm, I'm,
I'm telling you,
he can submit Ben Henderson,
who was the closest ever to submitting
Ben Henderson before he did Anthony.
Exactly. Almost caught him with a good
team right back. Yep. So the guillotine,
any Ed, uh, the rear
naked choke. So, you know,
I love instilling that.
Never put limits on yourself.
You know what I mean?
You talk about it in your broadcast
and if you're world class at one thing,
you can decide to be world
class in another thing.
You take that drive you had that got you
to be a worldclass martial artists in
this discipline. Go put
it. And the other one,
well I think people forget too with
Anthony Pettis who's the current UFC
lightweight champion.
People forget how good his ground game
his cause he's so scary standing up.
They think of him as the guy who knocked
out Joe Lozan with a head kick knocked
out,
Donald's Serone with a liver kick.
They think of him as this devastating
kicker, which you most certainly is,
but they forget about his
triangle of Shane Roller.
They forget about his wicked ground game
that he showed in the first Henderson
fight where he took his back. He had his
back for a full round. I believe him.
I'm going to look them up quick.
He might have more wins by submission.
The knockout actually that's crazy.
People forget for whatever
reason they don't think of his ground
game as like the same level as they think
of his striking game.
And it's just,
it's because it's striking game is so
scary because everybody's afraid of
getting knocked out. And his, uh,
his striking game is very
unique in its effectiveness.
Well,
what I love about a lot of the guys that
trained mostly all the guys and Gals,
they're trained, they're very open minded.
They want to get better all the time.
Anthony's had a little downtime,
he couldn't kick.
So he's becoming a master boxes.
Sit Up there. 15 submissions,
65% by submission. Yup. There you go.
That's crazy. Yeah. Uh, you know, it's,
it's, uh, I, I love the
change. You know, again,
everyone's worried about the knock off.
He wants to go to the Mat, you know?
Yeah. He can do it. All.
A kid can do it all.
It's gotta be nice for you to like train
having trained that guy like from the
jump and to see him like flourish and
become the Wec champion and then the UFC
champion in such a spectacular way.
That's got to be beautiful.
Yeah. I mean, I,
I started crying slightly in Milwaukee
in the octagon tears of joy. I mean,
if anyone deserved it. He did. He's
got a great attitude. He's a cool kid.
I always say it's the coolest famous
guy. No, I mean, wherever else we go. He,
everyone knows him as the guy who
jumped off the cage, he showtime.
But to me it's just a Anthony, this really
cool kid when he's at our academies,
just mellow when he's in his element.
He's a very humble guy,
but that's what makes them
great. You know, he's, he,
we might go to Thailand and do some
cross training with saint shy. Um,
I want to talk to Nick Holt can from
Gloria and, and having like Anthony,
he's hungry to train with everyone.
One of his best friends from
Milwaukee's on the money team.
One of the top boxers sees eight
and old for Floyd Mayweather.
So while he's in Vegas,
during the ultimate fighter is going
to be training with the money team too.
I mean, this is the type of guy he's a,
wants to be a master martial artists.
So he's trying to train with the best
core. Are you guys best Muay Thai boxers,
wrestling, Jujitsu, you
name it. He'll do it. Yeah,
and that's what we were talking
about before. This sport is
really evolving and growing
and developing and you know,
in a lot of ways he
represents a new element.
He represents like the taekwondo stylist
who got really good at everything else
and now has that weapon
above everybody else.
Everybody can Moitai everybody can
do Jujitsu, everybody can wrestle,
but not everybody can throw kicks
like him on top of all those things.
And he's one of the few guys is known
like, like very cro cop, like in a way,
you know, no one for just
devastating kicks. That's a,
that's a big weapon to have.
What I love, what I love about kicks,
they're very unpredictable strikes.
And when they hit you and they
didn't land, they still hurt.
You hit your arm and you're like, what
was that? You know, I love that look.
I'm fighters face when he kicks him
and it's like the look in their face.
Like what? Wait a minute. I'm
not supposed to feel like that
dude. You were demonstrating
shit on me today. Just lightly me
demonstrating shit. There's the
kicks to my forearm. Just just,
just popping the Shin into
my farm. It's like, ah,
your arms starts going numb and you're
barely hitting me. Barely hitting my leg.
Just, just thumping it. Just a little
bit of that. And it's like, man,
you can't even for the average person,
they really have no idea what it would
feel like if a guy like pedis or garlic,
you leg kicked him. They have no fucking
idea how hard that would be. Well,
even let's think about Anderson
shattering his leg and Tyrone Spong. Yeah.
Like when I was at the glory fight, we're
Tyrone Spong. Uh, I knew right away,
I'm like,
the fights over.
You can hear it was like being at a
baseball game and you hear the crack of a
bat, you know? That's all you heard
that Oh yeah, I heard it right away.
It was a very ugly sound.
And you know that that's
a one dip. Like, oh,
explain combat sports. Like I always
get people, one's better than the other.
They're all freaking crazy.
I think it's crazy to have to do eight
Jujitsu mantras in a data when the world,
some Jujitsu.
I think it's crazy to have to do 10
minute rounds and Abu Dhabi's and how many
studs? I mean, it's crazy
to win an NCAA championship.
How many matches over how many days?
It's crazy to box 12 rounds and get
punched in the Dome for 12 rounds.
It's crazy to get elbowed and clinched.
And Thailand,
it's crazy to to win a glory tournament.
It's crazy to MMA.
They're all tough in their own right.
I've, well I respect each one of them.
But when it comes to striking,
I think the most brutal thing you'll
ever do striking wise as an eight man
tournament,
which happened in glory this weekend,
cause you gotta beat three dudes in one
night. So you got to like, imagine you,
you kicked me really hard.
My arms jacked. Well I won,
but my right arm doesn't work. Wait
a minute, you kicked my left leg.
My hand's broken.
I mean,
I've never been able to win
a beat three guys in a night.
I've tried and it's tough.
I'm better at single fights,
but these guys who go out there and can
beat three guys in one night and find
that the nuts to do it,
I don't know how they do it still.
I only fought kickboxing three
times and it was all in one night.
I fought in a tournament like that.
Oh Wow. I won the first fight,
won the second fight and I
lost in the finals. And you,
you're so beat up by the time it gets
to the files, your body, it's just done.
It's like you're, you're, it's like
fighting with the flu. It's like fighting.
You just,
there's nothing left you,
you're a shadow of yourself and
plus you have time to cool off.
That's getting that adrenaline kicked
in again. It's like, I remember, um,
2001 I fought in Vegas.
I knocked out two mosque.
Who's for Shooski right away I felt
great. Like, whoop, celebrate. Oh Shit.
Hey asshole, you got to fight
again. Sorry, I got to go get up.
But Mike McDonald and your
body cools down. You know,
you've got to be able to control,
you know,
I mean I love and then knock
the guy out so you get so high,
there's no better feeling than finishing
someone in a fight. So you're like,
oh wait, tone down dude, you got
two more fights to win. You know,
and it's a special thing.
I think that is the wildest feet.
Another crazy sport to
me is Kyle Keshon karate.
I was at an all Japan karate championship
and I've never seen those guys are the
most insane people. They just sit
there and you kicked me, I kick you,
you punched me with bare knuckle and to
one of us falls down and we'll fight 16
guys in it. It's a really inefficient way
to fight though. I don't understand it.
Well, I punching to the face
and punching to the body.
They're standing right in front of each
other. I just think, not all of them,
you know, there's the great
ones like Andy hugged, right?
Michael Thompson who you know,
were more effective. You know,
they move around and you know,
that's actually GSPS core discipline.
Um, you know, there, there
are guys who really get into
the Butoh. I'm not into it.
I think it's more dangerous. And
Moy, Tai, you know, it's uh, me,
the style I love might die,
but the style I've always related to is
the evasive fighters who hit and don't
get hit. I mean, that's my rule. I'd like
to hit you a lot and please never hit me.
Well, I think we're seeing that more
reinforced in appreciated more in MMA.
There was a period of time
that was disturbing to me.
We're guys were just banging,
you know,
I remember I read some guy's Twitter
account who was a really nice guy and I
read something. He wrote something
about like, fuck, technical striking.
You know, I think what you do is
you get out to you, if you're a man,
you stand in the center
of the cage and you bang,
you meet each other side of
the cage and bang and let the,
let the chips fall where they may. And
I'm like, that is the craziest debts.
So I can't even tell you how dumb that is.
That's like saying fuck steering.
When you're on a race car,
fuck steering,
you just fucking hit that gas and
whoever gets to the finish line,
that gets to the finish line. That's so
ridiculous. Like you have to be technical,
otherwise you're not.
You're not, you're, you're,
you're not doing it your best.
What you're doing is you're handicapping
yourself for machismo for bravado.
Like what? Why would you stand in front
of a guy and trade blows with them?
There's a, there is a chronic
problem. I'd say right now an MMA,
there's a lot of fighters who have
had some cerebral issues and you know,
I think Martin Kampmann
it's taking some time off.
I know I can't say a few other fighters
I know of that I've heard and I'm not
sure if it's public,
they've taken time off from,
from taking too many blows and
l your thing, that should be,
I thought martial arts
is about self defense.
If we really get to the
root of martial arts, it's,
we're not to get your ass kicked.
And I think the defense is everything.
The greatest fighters in every
discipline of all at defense. You know,
and I think whether it's
grappling, weather, great
wrestlers don't get taken down.
Great Jujitsu guys don't get submitted.
Great.
Kickboxers don't get knocked out may
whether it doesn't get hit. Um, you know,
like you're saying,
it's easy to get,
I went through a stage in
my career where yeah man,
I'm going to go out there and
put on a show and you know,
I'm just going to bleed for the crowd.
Well you know what,
when you're done bleeding, you put the
show on, uh, it doesn't help your career.
I'm not saying fight boring,
but um,
like just purposely going out
there and making it exciting.
Yeah, making it over exciting. Umaine
you can be exciting and not get hit.
I mean that's what I try and teach my
guys. You know, if you're getting hit,
you're losing. Well it is an art form
and it sounds crazy to call Marshall.
I mean the,
the term martial arts,
it seems to a lot of people
to be an inaccurate term
or a term that doesn't seem
to make sense cause it's fighting.
But the artistic aspect
of it is the performance.
Like if you see a guy like Anderson
Silva fight only flood Stephan Bonner,
that was a beautiful artistic performance.
It was art because he's creating on
the spot he's created, he's putting,
he's got this series of moves
that his body knows how to do.
He is techniques he knows how to utilize,
but it's all about putting them together
against an unwilling opponent in the
middle of a competition in the middle
of a cage where you're on broadcasting
front of fucking millions of people
worldwide and to pull it all off in this
incredibly perfect way. It's a work
of art like definitely it's beautiful.
You go and watch it over and over again.
You could see it on TV,
you'll see the highlights and it's just
like watching a dance or not even a
dance. I don't dance is not that
impressive. No film, music, comedy. It's,
it is art because it's an expression
of your soul. You know? It's usually,
I do really stress the art part.
I want my athletes to express
who they are, you know?
I mean that that's what they're doing.
That's the canvas of the octagon
or the ring is that they're,
they're little canvas too.
I mean you get a chance to put to film
in front of the world what you are,
who you are, you know, cause the way you
fight represents your personality. Yeah.
And if you see those moments where a guy's
hitting someone and can't be hit back
like the famous video of Anderson Fighting
Forrest Griffin where he's bobbing
and weaving in front of him,
forest has hitting an air and
then Anderson cracks some like,
like they're both fighting
at two different speeds,
two different frequencies. Anderson's
just in this complete different level.
That's art. It's beautiful
to watch. That's reminiscent,
I watch a lot of old boxing.
I Love Sugar Ray Robinson films and
obviously reminiscent of the great Allie.
I mean he, he could do things
that other people can do.
That's why that's what makes
fighters special. You know,
any fighter can sit there and get beat up.
But I think that's why we talk
about people like Silva Ali,
you know, and now like I said, there's
guys coming up in glory that are special.
I mean even, you know, my favorite
fighter, some of you guys might not know,
uh, look up a guy named
[inaudible] rune. Um,
he's from sit your dog camp.
He's one of my Moitai idols,
but he's a WBC boxing champion.
He dodged 13 punches and um,
he,
uh,
w knocked a guy out with one
punch. It's s a m, a r t
and look up 13 punches.
I trained in timeline. It was why
rob calm and was friends with them.
But if we bring this video up, it is bad
ass boxing. It used to be Moitai champ.
He's probably one of the best ever and
Moitai why he didn't get hit. But again,
that style is able to dodge, move,
evade, hit people, not get hit.
And that's what makes striking fun.
Yeah. Here he is right here. Yeah.
Watch this gang. Look at this. This is my
idol. If anyone wants to know who I love,
I went to train in Thailand
at his gym because of him.
There's an that's amazing.
That is beautiful.
Bang and the fights over. Yeah, that's,
that's incredible. That's actually
want to Anthony's idols to,
and our couple of more guys really,
uh, I have a vault. Are you, I mean,
back in the day I didn't have TV.
I didn't have an antenna,
so all I did was watch VHS tapes.
I've lived at my gym,
so I watched fight Thai
fights, Dutch fights, Japanese,
like, uh, you know,
how a good musician or any other
artists' lives with their craft.
That's how I mastered my craft.
I watched fight after fight
after fight after fight.
That fight is a perfect
example. That was art. Yeah.
I mean I can find so many different
fights like that. That's what I do.
I send a lot of videos to all my
guys. I send, I exposed them to. Um,
one of my favorite compliments is
when Alan Belcher fought, uh, uh,
Patrick Otay, everyone goes, yeah. Mainly
it looks like Yo turn Clyde fairtex hose.
And matter of fact,
he studied Yo 10 Clyde to a t to I'll
take a fighter and have my athletes study
that for that particular game plan.
And I'll see you're going to do this.
Use this technique, you know, uh,
a technique that Anthony and Serge have
been doing is the hands thing kick a
Sanchez or king star from Thailand.
They're trying to land that. They're both,
they're having a race. Who the hands?
Yeah, we're the cartwheel the hands. Yeah.
It's a cool move from [inaudible]
the old school. But Sam Chai, s a.
E. N. C. H. A. I um, he,
he's a bad ass. He's from,
from the Jackie. Jim. Hey,
here's a good question. If
you're doing a cartwheel kick,
like say if you're standing,
if you got one hand down,
if our t and you're throwing a kick,
are you down?
Is that a downed opponent? They get
let you get away with it and boy tie.
But I believe technically it is.
So you're not supposed to be able to kick
the guy in the face when you're a down.
No, you're right. Ah, here we go,
Bob. Yeah, look familiar guys. Yeah.
But what I'm saying is like,
say if he's thrown that kick,
the guy who he's kicking can't kick him
in the face when his hand is touching
the ground. Yeah. Right. Uh,
technically I believe so,
but that's what you would want to do.
You'd want to step in and kick him in
the face and his hand soccer kick round.
Anybody's on one limb. I
think there, if you do that,
that I don't, I hate an MMA when guys
play the game, you know, touched I'm down.
I'm not done. I'm done. I'm gonna explain
that for focusing on, no, you're not
allowed to need it down to opponent.
Like what a down deponent means is you
can need a guy in the face when he's
standing up, but once the guys on the
ground, if he has a knee on the ground,
uh, and one hand, as long as it's,
as long as it's anything other
than your feet on the ground,
you can have one knee on the
ground and you're okay. Right?
You could need a guy in the face
with one knee on the ground,
but as soon as his hand touches
three points, right? Yes. What it is.
So what you'll see guys standing up and
they'll reach down and just touch the
ground just to keep from getting kneed
in the face where you can, you can,
you need a guy in the face when it, if
he's got one knee and one leg. No, no.
The knee has to be up.
The fee.
They have to be up because you
have to be honest feet only.
Like if you get down to
one knee, no, no hands,
but one day you can't be a guy
in the face. All right. Yeah.
There's some weird rules, man. Well the,
the, the 12 to six elbow, like you said,
Thomas, stupid cause we could
see some killer techniques.
That's where we'd see even more Moitai
elbows because then I would have my guys
climb the old school Moitai
and dropped the double elbows.
I'm the the cage. Oh yeah. Oh
yeah, definitely. Yeah, for sure.
I mean I'm all about it. I love those
techniques. Well, that technique is,
that is really one of the most ridiculous
rules ever. And the reason why it's in,
for folks who don't know,
the 12 to six meaning an elbow that comes
from like the 12 o'clock down to six
o'clock.
The reason why it's outlawed is because
when they tried to get mixed martial
arts past, they brought it to the
athletic commissions and they said,
well you can't have that one
technique Coz I saw it on ESPN.
There was a guy breaking bricks with it.
No way you can allow people to do
that because they could kill somebody.
And so they went all right as if this
has anything more powerful than this,
which is probably more Po. No, I
think when you're on the ground,
the downward album was the most
vicious drag. Do you get a fault?
I think that like getting it,
that's why another thing when Alan bead,
Paula,
Horace and the fight before that
he beat Mcdonald on the Mat.
We really been working on our
ground and pound on our team. Um,
cause it's another place to beat
someone up. It's also so ridiculous.
You're not allowed to do with like
a 12 six elbow to the thigh. Yeah.
That's so crazy.
Like if a guy's in your God you
can't do a 12 six elbow to his thigh.
It's just, it makes, if, if it were
me, I'd love to have soccer kicks.
Well do you think that soccer
kicks though? They had him
in pride and I liked it.
I liked it.
But what I don't think,
I think in pride you were in a ring and
you get your head could slip under the
ropes. You can get away from stuff and
the in the UFC that cage would like,
you'd be mashed up if someone's
soccer kicked your head. You're right,
you're right. I forgot about that. Yeah.
The problem is you can't move. It
was an open space. Say if you fought,
like say if every fight took place
in like a basketball sized arena,
like a basketball court was plenty of
room to move around, but there's no cage.
That would be really interesting. You
know, it'd be really interesting if they,
if they, if people fought
like that because then take
downs would be completely
different.
Getting back up would be much harder
cause getting back up against the cage now
has gotten to a real art form.
Guys figured out how to press their back
up against the cage and use it to stand
back up and postop and get,
once they get that under hook and they
get one hand down there popping up like
crazy.
No I, it's crazy. They're it guys
are getting way better at wrestling.
Way better at Jujitsu faster.
Again, I think it's technology.
There's so much knowledge out there.
There's so much.
I mean when I was trying to learn
Moitai besides going to Thailand,
watching videos,
who was such a slow process,
I remember my friends when they first
like it was a big deal to have a blue belt
around and Jujitsu and now it,
you know,
there's black belts everywhere and
the knowledge is everywhere guys.
So get a bravo.
He has a site where he sent it out info
and you can check out techniques and
there's so much going on with that
and just youtube and everything else.
It's on TV too.
You know how the kids learn how to play
basketball in America on the playground.
How do they learn how to play on the
playground? They watch TV. You know,
people are doing this stuff everywhere,
whether they're in an organized school or
just friends and their garage training,
it's happening.
Well there's so much information now.
Whereas when I was a kid,
you would buy a book on a martial
art or you know, you'd never,
it was very rare that you would get a
really good like VHS tape martial arts
back then because when I was a kid I was
training in the 80s I don't think there
were any instructional martial
arts tapes that I wasn't aware of.
You had to go to a school,
you had to go to a school and learn
from somebody and then occasionally you
would get fight videos and
then you would watch, you know,
try to emulate like Benny the jet,
you know,
like try to be like Benny the jet or
Kitezh or you know, one of those guys.
It was fighting back then. That
was like really, really good.
My first, uh, instructional
tapes I had, cause I,
I still watch everything. I'm,
I'm a student of the game was uh,
a guy by the name of put bad noise.
You mean his name's the golden leg.
Five time Roger Down during
champion and lived in France.
That was my first Moy Tai Instructional.
And I luckily got a chance to go
train it as GM and in Paris. And then,
uh,
the other one was,
I don't know if you remember the Chocker
Riki [inaudible] Tom [inaudible] and
you know,
young Peter Arts is in there,
Bronco sick it tick and Gilbert Valentini.
So those are like my first
kind of core hell cause I,
20 years ago this year, I went to
Thailand. You want to hear irony though?
A friend of mine, his name is
Rambo, he fights MMA. He's, uh,
one of the top one 15 ers in the world,
but he's tie look up Rambo on r a m B,
a Rambo Moitai.
He's the crazy dancer.
The first fight I ever went to. When I
got the timeline, I took my bags rate to,
to um, the hotel and I walked into
[inaudible]. I walk in and he's
one of the main fights that night. Irony
is, he fights them. I may now, it's just,
I don't know.
It's one of those weird destinies.
The first fight card I see in Thailand
is Rambod and now he's fighting and MMA.
Yeah. Yeah. And I mean there's,
you're finding for out of
it, he lives in Japan. He,
he, I think he fought you least
Gomez at tachy. Yeah. Yeah.
He fought. Uh, sorry. I was going
to call them as a Eugene name.
All my useless. What's up
underground? I'm on there.
I'm on there. Yeah, I know. I know. I
see you on there. Yeah, it's a event.
I know it's been a little shady on there
lately. We're a lot of Douche bags.
We got it.
So it's not turning into that other thing.
Well, you know what it
is, man. You can't, if,
if it's on the Internet
and anybody could sign up,
anybody can sign up and
if anybody gets signed up,
you're just going to get a lot of
shitheads. If people are anonymous,
it's almost impossible to keep any forum
completely clear of shitheads unless
you just start banning people and then
you worry about censorship and why are
people banning?
Yeah,
I'm lucky. Everyone's really nice
to me. Um, you know, it's cool. Uh,
it's been a good time. We want bring up
that video. There's a couple of them,
maybe a highlight of them.
It's Rambo highlight cause dude,
he has his own little crazy style.
He does the worm,
he does the running man after his fights.
He's really fun,
entertaining Guy Ran Bob.
His name literally means are crazy dancer.
Now what do you think about
there's a, there's a thing
going on right now where, uh,
people are talking about this is him,
what people are talking about this uh,
past UFC, which I thought was great.
I loved the mighty mouse fight.
I love watching that guy perform,
but that a lot of folks don't care to
watch 125 pound fighters and they're
saying, um, you know, there's a
rumor on the underground, again,
who knows if it's substantiated,
but that the papers you buys were wanting
some of the lowest ever for the UFC,
um, that it was, uh, somewhere around
a hundred thousand pay per view buys,
which is really, really
low for the UFC. Um,
do you think that that's what it is?
It Americans just do not want
to see these little tiny guys?
I just think the timing was bad this time
around. It was a few weeks coming off.
Another big, uh, you
know, fight. I think they,
they should just drop a
couple of the paper views per
year. I mean, I'm no expert,
but I like it when there's kind
of a buildup for the paper,
make the paper view the big bomber. And
then we got all of our good free fights.
You know,
it's kind of like back in the day,
remember Tuesday night fights on the USA.
You've got some Friday night fights.
He got some HBO and now we're going to
have a big pay per view fight, you know,
build it up. Just don't have pay for
view fights. Just that paper view finder.
Yeah, it's definitely seems like there's
a lot of fights going on. And you know,
one hand it's great as a fight fan. Like
on the 28th we were talking about this,
there's two fight cards playing
at the same time or the same day.
One from New Zealand and then hours later,
one from Texas,
Jeremy Stephens is going to fight cub
Swanson, great fight, fight, fight.
Ooh, what a crazy fight that is. Stevens
is so fucking creative. You don't talking
about a creative guy in there. Oh yeah.
I'm a big fan of called, I really like
what he's doing with his striking.
Not only is he doing base kickbox and
he's got some spins and he's honing his
boxing as well.
He's really,
and I think that's like a big thing
that a lot of people don't do because I
think it's one of the hardest things
to do. Um, I was talking to Rico,
Verhoeven is fighting. Saturday he went
and trained with uh, this guy, Tyson fury.
And he said the first
couple of times he went,
I mean he just got lit up like a
Christmas tree by cause that boxers,
that's all they do. And that's like, um,
if you go watch someone roll with
Marcello Garcia and you're an MMA fighter,
you're going to get crushed. You
know, cause that's all Marcello does.
But I think it,
that's always a cool thing.
I love watching people humble
themselves to get better.
And that's how you get better.
And cubs working with a worldclass
champion level boxer and it's showing,
well that's a real problem with a lot
of fighters that especially if they come
from a kickboxing background,
they don't want to get tapped.
So they don't want to do, they don't want
to do Jujitsu. And they never learned.
There's certain guys that
never got good on the ground.
They'd been doing MMA for 10, 15 years
and there's still a God damn blue belt.
I mean, they just doesn't
ever got good on the ground.
He never became lethal on the ground.
And conversely,
there's certain guys who are
grapplers that just suck at standup.
They always suck at stand up.
They just,
their whole game is predicated on
getting a hold of you and turning into a
grappling match. But if it stuck
standing up there helpless. Yeah,
I've always looked at any fighting.
Even if your kickboxing,
you gotta know how to do every skill.
I know some guys who don't want to train
clinch at all. Well I don't clench.
Well learn it so you don't get beat by
it. I know a lot of guys who, you know,
knees are stupid. I don't.
Well, you got to learn.
What are you going to do when someone
else says knees are stupid that no come or
anybody sees Niesr stupid needs to
watch Travis Browne vs Alistair Overeem.
I know Travis Browne survived that,
but Jesus fucking Christ and Alice to
take it to him when he to the body. Oh,
a Bogan stoic. If you want
to watch them, cool knees.
He's fighting Saturday and
the glory tournament he's got,
he did this knee where
he flew out of the ring.
There's a highlight if you
bring up bog down bog, d a, n,
a, s, t. O. I. C. I C I believe.
Um, but he's, he's sick dude. He
comes out with flying out of the Ray,
went over the corner posts.
He missed the knee and he got back up
and whoop the guy's ass. Wow. Yeah,
but he's going to be fun.
He's fighting Wayne Baird who kinda
has a wild ass wild. Yeah. Main Guy.
I think the, yeah. Here it is. Check this.
Look at this nice knee. We'll get that.
He, he's fighting Saturday. Um, you know,
just look at this pile that,
that's the new age of what's
going on with glory. Um, you know,
a little bit different. Here we
go. Wow. That's so crazy. Yeah.
The dude went completely over the
top madness. Oh, I know. I know.
He was just laughing about it today
when I was hanging out with him. Yeah,
he's okay. He could have broke a leg
there. There's a wild fight in Thailand.
Will bring you up in a second
there and knocked him out. Look up.
M D e n space.
Monks are in m u a n G. S. U. R,
I. N. Verse Rainbow. Boy.
These ties have some crazy
ass fucking oh yeah, yeah. Um,
you're in the golden era.
Moitai you spill it,
grab the leg and run them across the ring.
You can't do it anymore because
too many injuries happen.
And I'll show you the fight, why
they can't, the cooling and the cage.
You can still do it. But if this
clip comes up that one more time.
Den d e n Space Mung.
Seron.
M U. A. N. G. S. U. R I.
N Verse Rainbow Though the Word Rainbow.
Wow. And you could run across
the ring. It was called the plow.
Now you can only take a
step into half this fight.
You'll see why the guy actually
broke his back. Oh No. Yeah.
This is insane. Yeah. Here we go.
So a den is in the Blue Rainbow,
some pump the lake.
Do you know Greg Nelson, who from
the Minnesota martial arts? Every,
he actually used to train with, uh,
some, some Pontalis camp. So yeah.
Greg's a old friend of mine. Really
good martial artist. So yeah,
he trained with a [inaudible], uh, den
monks ran, actually scrapped with Danny,
Danny, Bill and, and uh, Ramon
decker back in the day. So he,
he's a class too. Wow.
Watching high level ties. Yeah.
This is a class that's an Olympic neath.
I miss the old stadium.
I was there in the 90s. Man. Somebody
good fights. I got to see. I'm blessed.
But uh, how long did you
go to Thailand for? Um,
I've been there like I'd
go three months at a time.
The best thing I ever did honestly is,
um,
I was able to bring some of the
top guys to come live with me.
I used to have four guys from
timeline living with me. And uh, it,
it was awesome because I was able to
plug in and extract all that information.
You know, it was fun. Um, might have
to fast forward a little till the,
you see the end. These guys are gone off
though. This is beautiful to watch. Yeah,
it really good technique.
Actually.
Den also did some boxing for the Thai
amateur team to Eh, you know, just uh,
actually the logo you see on the right
is Song Chai. If you're on Youtube,
go to song tries channel.
It's a killer.
That was the biggest promoter in Thailand.
He used to promote boxing Muay Thai.
He's the one who promoted decker. Rob,
our friend rob common. Just uh, yeah,
here we go. Here. Watch this doc bow,
but check it out in Thailand. The bet.
So much den monks in celebrating, he won.
He won because he fell out
of the ring. See, look at
that. They're jumping for joy.
They won the bet.
So that's when they switched the
rules a little bit in Thailand.
Guy got fucked up. He broke
his back. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Check this out here. See I picked
picks it up. Plow, jump, boom.
We've got fucked up though.
Yeah.
The guy who's doing the
plow got fucked up. Crazy.
I know that it became illegal because the
guy who we plowed didn't even get her.
There was a few other incidents
where they hit the ropes and bolts.
Would flip and yeah, that's the thing.
Timeline. Do you know I miss those days,
those rules because of
actually like the fights from,
they call the golden era before 99,
2000,
there was a better style of fighting.
Something may happen. The bedding change.
Too many stadiums.
Like everyone got into doing
premiere league betting on that.
Instead of going to the stadium, you
know, it's premiere league soccer.
They liked soccer more.
It really hurt the economy or more time
the economy went down and they can pay
the athletes as much as well.
Well now we'll knock.
I Kim fell out of the ring like that.
What happened?
He shattered his back when he came
back to fighting though. Really? Yeah.
He healed up and he returned.
He just broke a bone. Broken
bone. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Probably a back rib
backbone. Yeah. Crazy. Right.
But it's crazy that that is the one that
made it illegal because the guy who is
executing that technique is the one that
got hurt. Yeah. It's old school mean. Um,
but no nice thing.
And UFC,
we get to see that you gauge the cage is
much better because it stops guys from
going out. That was an issue in pride as
well that would fall through the ropes.
Guys would get caught up in
the ropes and techniques.
They couldn't defend themselves, you
know, problematic. No, it's show.
I used to like there was a ring,
I think it was um,
storm San Mariah I think are
theory fighting from Brazil.
The att or a Btt verse and the verse,
the shoe box guys, is that when they
had the net at the bottom right? Yeah.
That was actually going out. Yeah. Those
were insane. Like if you're just in the,
you, you want some blood clause
and a soccer kicks and stomps.
Did you ever see Chuck Liddell
versus Palae? Yeah. Yeah.
That was back before
chuck fought in the UFC,
fought palae and in the real valley
Tudo days where there was no rules,
no gloves, no rules, no, no nothing.
They're beaten the fucking shit
out of each other and Paly,
it was trapped in the net.
Like he was underneath the bottom rope,
like stuck in the net. Chuck's
beaten on them. Madness.
The speaking to old school.
I was in Cincinnati at the UFC.
I made a Sean Shelby and
Joe Shit civil laugh.
Why lead Ishmael walked by
and I seriously had to go,
you know what guys like I scares me.
Luckily I know him because our team's
part of the Carlson Gracie team. He's,
he's nice to me,
but he's,
that's one of the most ferocious like
dudes have ever seen choked hoists.
Gracie unconscious on the beach in
Rio. They were telling me a story, uh,
some of the Carlson Gracie guys, how
down he has for Carlson Gracie, the team.
He was at a tournament in Brazil.
He won,
he got his elbow popped and um,
some,
uh, the, the loop delever guys
storm the tournament and like,
they're all challenged him
and while he jumped up,
he of course he's going to
lead the charge while he goes,
I'll take on every one of you efforts.
But he couldn't straighten his arm.
So it's fingers pointing that way.
It's like armors is dangling
there and he's still ready to go.
What a tough sob. His, you
know, he was tough as shit.
You remember those recordings of him
when he was mad at high and just telling
the story about high end Gracie, somebody
had a great video that they had online.
It was on the underground of him
explaining like the thing, you know,
he had the thing he's called Gauher Geez
chicken and he's doing with his accent
describing high end. It's
a character now. Now.
I mean luckily we both got
the know Carlson senior.
I was there at the end with Stephan.
You trained with them. I mean it's that,
that branch or the Gracie
family man. Real deal. I mean,
not that anyone else isn't.
I'm just saying what they
did to MMA. Yeah. Incredible.
I mean, Vito Belfort, Mario Sperry,
Marillo Bustamante the Noguera's thinking
about all the different people that
came out of that crossbar. Andre
Punt and Eris Bonner, Stephan Bonner,
Miguel Pinero she went out to be
novel and Yao and level and yeah,
it was the biggest for all the lightweight
guys in Brazil. That's the biggest,
toughest team. And as well, our
friend Fabio Prado, who's with a, um,
a Alpha male and our coach gain of
underway to who lived with Carlson in
Chicago. So like even it's part of the
roof of sport team. It's just school.
Actually Carlson junior has been coming
up and helping out. It's fun to see him.
He is a great guy and he's, he's, it's
cool man. He's a real MMA pioneer too.
If you go back and watch his
fights fighting. Oh yeah.
Yeah, me the organization.
It's been fun to, you know, again,
I really like making all these
new friends and everything I do,
whether it's Jiu Jitsu,
kickboxing,
now I've got a lot of fun wrestling
friends even, you know, I've, I mean,
being exposed to the asking bro,
aspirin brothers even.
I have a friend Eric Jergens who's a
really good Iowa wrestler that I met
through Pat Miletich and, and um, that's
the neat thing about combative sports.
They're the, the, the camaraderie.
It's, there's a special,
a fraternity that I want to
exchange for anything. Well,
I think it's also these folks,
first of all, they need each other.
Like you can't get good at MMA without
people to teach you and you need people
to train with and they appreciate that.
And they also appreciate that there's
very few people that understand them,
like other martial artists do or
other other fighters, you know,
when they're training the lifestyle, the,
the amount of effort that you to put in.
Very few people understand or appreciate
the dedication and commitment that's
required to be a professional
level MMA fighter. I mean,
you can't have, you can't,
there's no going out at night. There's
no life. You don't have any lie.
You might have a girlfriend and what do
you do? You, you might watch a movie,
get a little sex, and then pass out
before your training. And that's it, man.
You're not doing shit. You might get
to go on a vacation after your fight,
but guess what?
Your,
your amount of time you're
actually relaxing is so
small because if you did well
in that fight, they're already
talking about your next opponent.
So you start thinking
about the next fight.
And so you're on the beach somewhere and
all you thinking about his fucking head
kicks and tackles. And to me,
finding reminds me of apocalypse now.
We are in the bush. You think about being
an rnr, but when you're out in the rnr,
you just,
you want to get back in the Bush because
you don't want to get soft because
Charlie's gonna come get you. You
know what I mean? That's how I,
that's how I would be like, fuck,
I'm having a great time. Fuck off.
Fuck does not now another dude,
that's how it was for
Anthony won the world title.
It's like he was right back from the gym.
Cause he knows some dude wants that strap.
Like he wants to take what's his and,
and yeah, it's, it's a really unique
lifestyle. You know, it's very unique.
I mean,
it's not unlike any other movie musician,
comedian. You're only as good
as your last show. Honestly.
You're only as good as your last
performance when w the spotlights I knew.
But you got to love that.
You know the special people like Anthony,
Ben Askern, you know Alan
Belcher, they're the type of dude,
if it were the the final for the Ncaa
Championship or give me the ball.
I want to shoot it. Take to be a
great fighter. You got to be that guy.
You're the quarterback is like, I'm going
to call the play coach. I got it right.
It takes that special person to be one
of the best and I love being around those
people because a,
it's empowering to watch them be
that person. You know I I've love,
it was actually funny in Anthony's,
I'm fight with Serone,
I want them to stay righty and he
kind of stayed left. He kind of,
I was like the catcher and he was
a pitcher waved me off like no.
And I liked that though. I want my
guys to quarterback their own fights.
I don't want,
if they have to count on everything,
I say they're not ready to be champion.
This whole Ben Astrin things are very
interesting subject because Ben asked her
and was a,
who was a great wrestler,
like elite amateur wrestler,
got into MMA and shows dominance in the
grappling that we have rarely ever seen
before.
And for whatever reason he gets labeled
as being boring because of that.
But you see what he's been able to do
to guys like Lima, like these killers,
you know, he takes these guys
that normally, you know, they're,
they're in the involve these crazy wild
fights with people and he manhandled him.
He gets a hold of these motherfuckers
and he dragged him to the ground.
He beats the shit out of
him and for whatever reason,
because he's not finishing guys or
he's not finishing as many guys,
and it's just a constant
state of frustration for one guy to be
on the bottom and the other guy just
getting ragdoll by asking over and over
again, people label them in a bad way.
Bella Tor didn't even negotiate
two to reinstate his contract.
He was there fucking champion.
Now I had a real hard time with that.
I didn't understand the logic behind that.
Even slightly.
They let him go as their champion.
I thought that was completely
stupid and crazy too.
And then the UFC didn't even fucking
pick them up because there was some weird
shit there with them not wanting
to pick up Bella tours guy and
well we did it with Hector
Lombard. It's frustrating. Um,
you know, it's really hard. I'm
really good friends with Ben.
He's doing great at one FC. They're
taking care of him. You know, it's just,
I want Ben to have a chance
to put his legacy out there.
I want to see him fight the best guys.
His fucking grappling is ridiculous.
He's more, he's moves are
very unique. It is. I mean,
I've seen him give high level black belts,
fits it.
Definitely mean he's, he's
good and he just, you know,
submitted his last opponent mean
Ben is so good on the ground.
He makes it look easy that people
think he's not, you know, working hard.
But I think he has a new focus is who's
finished his last three opponents and
this law. He likes getting out of
there early now it's like, oh, okay,
don't get paid for overtime.
Yo.
A lot of people won't realize he's
third all time in the NCA at in pins.
Wow.
And he's one of two two
time hodge trophy winners.
The Heisman trophy or wrestling. So I
think him and it was a Cael Sanderson.
I'm very,
very impressed with that guys wrestling.
And I was very upset that it didn't go
down, that he didn't fight in the UFC.
I was,
when they were saying they were releasing
him from Beltre and he was talking to
people in the UFC. I was very excited.
And there's a lot of people like, oh,
he's boring. He's boy, I think.
I think Jane has said Ben Aspirin is
what ambien takes when it wants to go to
sleep or I don't, I don't
find them boring. I don't,
I mean it,
look,
is it as exciting as watching Anderson
Silva knockout Stephan Bonner with that
knee to the body? No, no. It's not as
exciting, but is a huge element of MMA.
It's one of the biggest
elements of MMA is grappling.
Was Damien Maia versus Anderson Silva
tiding? No, no. Exactly. Not at all.
No.
What I watched boxing matches were two
guys are supposed to beat each other up
and it's a defensive stalemate and
that's just sports sometimes, you know,
sometimes. Um, and this is going to be
the greatest super bowl and it's boring.
The last May where the fight was one of
the most exciting fights he's ever had
versus my Donna is because it came,
became a brawl that's not an Mayweather
fight. Mayweather fights are fights,
three boxes,
guys faces off and then it goes away.
Like the Canelo Alvarez fight
wasn't particularly exciting.
No means you just sort of boxed him
outboxed him, moved around them.
Definitely. I mean, I, I,
I hope then in the next
year or so gets a chance
to show him he and I, I think the, the
welterweight division is kind of wild.
Placers. I mean, yeah, we got Johnny
Hendricks is a champ, but I mean,
Robbie Lawler lost a close fight
to him. Eh, there, there it's,
it's scary how close it is right now.
Yeah.
And Robbie Lawler just looked sensational,
knocking out Jake Ellenberger him.
He looked like a fucking murderer.
Then Rory Macdonald just looked
outstanding and it's tiring.
You got Hector Lumbar, who's
fucking ridiculous. I mean,
who is faster or more athletic than Hector
lumbar and he hits those fucking judo
throws on high level guys to see Jake
shields go flying through the air on a hip
toss like that. It's like Jesus Christ. I,
I just know who I'm the happiest for.
Robbie.
I've known Robbie for a long time
through Pat Miletich and man,
that guys work so hard to
evolve, adapt, change and grow.
I don't care what people say.
You can teach an old dog new tricks.
It's all comes down to
attitude. I think, uh,
one of my favorite quotes by Zig Ziglar,
it's not your aptitude that
determines your altitude.
It's your attitude. And he has the right
attitude. He made the changes. I mean,
he got way better at grappling. He's,
and he's so disciplined. I mean,
what a comeback story. The other comeback
story at one 72. How about Matt Brown?
Uncredible. Yeah. I mean, when people say
they can't get better, won't, don't want,
or sometimes when my guys get upset,
if they lose a fight,
then Matt Brown yourself,
you know,
pull yourself out of the be the
Phoenix that came out of the fire.
Just work hard and at the right attitude.
Matt Brown was submitted by Seth
Bazinsky just two years ago. You know,
people don't forget,
they forget about some of the fights
that he's had where he lost the look.
If you are,
if you can still move correctly,
if you don't have a debilitating injury,
if you don't have cognitive problems,
you have been hitting the head too
many times. You can still learn.
You could still grow.
But some guys,
they do not do that because they're very
stubborn in their ways or they're stuck
on there.
They're on a path there.
They're stuck on that path and they
never develop. And it's unfortunate.
It really is unfortunate because the
beautiful thing about MMA is the fact that
there's so many options.
And when you see a guy get to a high,
like a mighty mouse,
like a Demetrius Johnson who gets this
incredibly high level of aptitude and all
these different areas, it's a
beautiful thing to watch, man.
So I'd love to his fight,
honestly,
I thought he did a great job of using
his Moy Thai style clinch to negate
wrestling used knees. Well, I mean it was,
he reminded me of a mini Anderson
Silva and that aspect using the clinch.
I enjoy that type of fighting.
Uh,
I think Matt Hume is an incredible
coach, one of the best. Yeah,
I mean a great guy. And, and I, I
really enjoyed his performance. I mean,
um, you know, sometimes people are
just into the heavyweights. I mean,
I like watching smaller fighters fight
personally myself because there's much
more going on. Not saying I don't like
heavy weights, but I mean, you know,
it just in general, you know,
it's small than that. Good.
Well then what are you guys going to
think of 115 pound chicks white and, yeah,
I mean, well that's coming and we
were just talking about that. Oh yeah,
division is going to be the next
division in the UFC. Excuse me,
the Straw Weight Division for
women for one 15. It's exciting.
I'm going to be, uh, assisting Anthony
Pettis on the ultimate fighter.
I'm only going 10 days and then
I come back a little later. Um,
I want to Anthony to shine as a coach.
People don't realize he's a really
good teacher coach and these really
competitive,
he'd knocked his baby daughter off the
chair to win if it were musical chairs.
I mean he, he is the type of
guy he likes to, you know,
a couple of our, last summer we had
a pickup basketball game. Oh my God.
It just turned into something
we'll funding thing on.
He looked like Jordan going for the third
ring. It was just like every rebound,
every, this kid wouldn't stop it. We
had so much fun. I mean, but you know,
when you do things like
that, casual games, you,
you find out what certain guys are made
of, you find out how crazy they really,
oh yeah. We, there was two, there was,
there was 10 alphas playing basketball.
Not a smart move, but that should
probably be banned from the, the,
the fight contracts. No basketball.
Yeah. Right. What is banned?
Can they ride motorcycles?
They're allowed to ride motorcycles
and things in our band. Right.
I believe they can. I'm not sure. I don't
handle the management side of our stuff.
I know that, uh, Anthony has a proud
owner of his Milwaukee Harley Davidson.
He won for his title. Does he ride a
little bit? Not Too much. So, yeah.
I mean that's why I don't drive sports
cars or motorcycles cause I'm that idiot
who wants to see how fast they can go
there. That's why, that's why I fight.
You know,
that's where I get my adrenaline out.
I would worry more about the other
drivers. Yeah. With a motorcycle.
My Dad's youngest brother,
my uncle actually got
hit by a glass truck,
um,
motorcycle and he fell and didn't have
a helmet on cause and he's had many
issues because of it.
But yeah.
And I mean unfortunately every year
or two I lose her friend in Wisconsin.
It's just such a culture there. Live
to ride, ride to live, you know.
But we have such potholes.
And the other thing I've done I never
understood is jump on your bike and go to
a bar and start drinking. Yeah.
You know, that's uh, you know,
people bar hop. What's crazy? The
bars of parking lots. Yeah. Yeah.
Not a lot of drink and drive,
but it's a bunch of people drinking
and there's a bunch of cars. Hey, wait,
there's less people in the bar then there,
where's the designated,
wait a minute is not enough. Deadheaded
drivers. It's not possible. Now it's uh,
you know, it's gold. Uh,
I, I, I can't handle the,
the motorcycle culture. I love it, but
I'm the guy who will test my limits. Well,
I'd started trying to get
my motorcycle license.
Me and a few friends that
were working on fear factor.
Lot of the guys in production.
We all signed up for motorcycle safety
classes. We started learning how to ride.
We did all the thing.
I got a helmet.
And then during the time where I was
learning three different people I knew,
well one person saw,
she saw a guy get hit by a motorcycle
and two friends got fucked up.
Frank Mir got his leg, he got t boned
by a car. A guy ran a red light,
slammed into him, broke his leg, sent
him flying like 60 feet through the air.
And if it wasn't for the fact
that he's this giant heavyweight,
he probably would have been
paralyzed for life mean to it.
Amazing that he came back to fight
and, and, and become good again.
Actually approved. Yeah. And then another
friend of mine, uh, Edson fell down.
It tore his shoulder apart.
He was going around a turn and to pikes,
slipped out from under him at boom,
hit his shoulder on the ground,
mangled his shoulder.
Dude,
crazy for my friend cognitive path who
used to live with me. I'm from Thailand.
Deets down here in the states. Really
killer dude. And he was for time,
Roger Number and she stadium champ.
He went back home to Roy yet
northeast Thailand and his motorcycle.
He had all souped up.
He got in a motorcycle accident,
his ankle got bent back the other way.
And the accident,
that was after his first title.
He went on to win three more championships
and go outside Thailand and fight
with that ankle.
He'd be like rib randomly holding pads
at the gym and you just fall down like
Kong. What's the problem? Oh, jet mark.
My ankle like hurts bad. I'm like,
it would just give out on him. Yeah,
man. I'm like, how the thought? Yeah.
That's incredible. I know. I mean, it's
uh, you know, motorcycles or, you know,
if you've ever been to timeline, you've
probably seen a family of five on one.
It's crazy. It's like they can fit a
family of five on a little one 25. Well,
if everybody was riding motorcycles
like in Thailand back in with less cars,
probably safer.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, the traffic's so
bad. So they go in between and uh,
you know, taglines crazy though.
It's a, it's a fun place,
but a crazy place.
Yeah.
Yeah. How did Thailand get so many
ladyboys? What happened there?
I don't understand,
but it's the Thai culture is so,
um,
tower.
Yeah, like the Buddhist
religion. It's um, my pen lie,
which means don't worry, it doesn't
matter culture. But yeah, I don't,
it scares me because I used to train it
a state you're talking when I first went
and you know, I'd go to the beach on the
weekend and you know, all these chicks,
weird looking chicks, hey, 60
men, I'm like to my friend, man,
these chicks really dig us man. Hey
Yo, text week this guy in a walker,
hey 60 man. I'm like, wait a minute.
I think their whole Cursio but
point being then that you can spot
them a mile away. Your Adam's apple. When
you said that the big Adam's apple boy,
they spite them to Mike cause some of
them you can't spot a mile away. So very,
very, very feminine. Yes and no.
I mean they look like the other
Thai women.
I mean,
ah, I see. Say you can tell.
Oh at least, yeah, yeah,
yeah. I mean, but it's
fascinating that this one culture,
it's just known for ladyboys. Yeah.
And that it's a normal part of, like,
I had a buddy who went over there
and was drinking Brody Stevens.
Brody Stevens told a great story about
it and we determined that he was 84% gay
sex. He started off at that
he was 10% gay and a we,
by the end of the conversation
we've worked at that.
He was somewhere over 50
definitely over 50% gay,
but he told the story about a
meeting ladyboys there and you know,
just having a good time and enjoying it.
It didn't feel,
didn't feel abnormal because he was
there in a culture where it's normal and
it's accepted. There was all
these other people that, you know,
even guys that were like,
you know,
straight guys were hanging out with these
ladyboys because it was just how they
did it over there.
Not me, not me. I just
know what, I never really partied much in
Thailand because I was always training.
One trip I've had little fun,
but I mean like it's just weird.
The one night my wife went to Thailand
with me once we were on a took,
took late night in Bangkok crews and back
to our hotel after some fights. And uh,
we were right up to the dude and we
totally see this guy mash and kissing with
total. This, the Adam's apple.
Both my wife and I were like, oh,
oh if the crying game going on, oh
maybe that's what he likes. Yeah.
But hey whatever, whatever floats your
boat, man. Whatever floats your boat.
Thailand's a a wild place and all
sorts of other ways too, right?
I mean it's like prostitution is rampant.
There's Moy Thai fights in bars.
It's just, it's a wild, wild place.
Why this thing I saw in Thailand was
I'm going to the temple fights or like
church festivals on the weekend and they
line up all the kids and they put them
in a line and there's no scale.
They just used to you too. You too.
And then their families like all cause
some go to camps and someone just trained
with their families and then they
all bet on their kids, man. Wow.
And you see like kids
getting elbowed and lily
and then own the music
speeds up in the little kid.
He kicked the shorts are way too
big yanking him up. You know,
it's just like, I consider myself
kind of a tough dude, but I,
I don't like watching the little kids
scrap down with elbows and I'm like, Hey,
you know, I have a daughter and
everyone's like, cause she gonna fight.
And I'm like, maybe, I don't know. I
mean like fighting isn't for everybody.
You know what I mean? No one time
at one of the other camps I was at,
this kid had just come from
way northeast Thailand and um,
he just wasn't sleeping well at night.
He was used to eating different
and one of the trainers, you know,
sometimes the trainers drank a lot cause
they get the shit kicked him up out of
pads. They're all former fighters, you
know, like live at the gym with you.
And so they just,
they're little well
being beat up and when they crack the
shit out of the kid to shut up, you know,
like they just, you know, just basically
a little toughen up session at midnight.
You know, it's just little things you
see you don't like. I love Thailand,
but I don't think it's healthy to send
a kid away at nine years old to become a
boxer. No. You know what I mean?
Like some of the guys I
brought over from timeline,
I had to teach them things about life
that they didn't learn when they lived at
the Moitai camp. You know, it's
not normal to go live in a,
basically what a white
I camp is a modern day.
Lewdness it's a gladiator school.
You know what I mean?
I love more eye to eye in a lot of it not,
and please don't make it seem like
I'm trying to put it down. It's just,
you have to understand what it is.
It's a third world country.
It's not martial arts,
it's a boxing gym. It's,
it's professional horse racing.
They're there to make money for the camp.
50% of their earnings go to the camp and
then the rest of their money they try
and send back home to their family.
Something that folks don't realize too.
When you hear like bullet crop, a
little book I'll pour promote. Yeah,
that's his name is one thing.
The Gym name is the name that he takes on.
That's not even his real name at all.
It is is he has a boxing name.
Wachau boycott means uh,
cows white and boy is lotus.
So it's the White Lotus. And
then poor promote is, uh,
he's a student or promote,
promote is the boss of the camp.
So he has a real name and then
that's essentially his nickname.
I forgot his last name starts with a B,
but it's real name is somebody
that's his passport name. Yeah.
All the boxers get a different name.
You know the of your boxing name and,
yeah. So it's the White Lotus. Yeah,
that's what his name means. Cool.
His nickname actually is dom, which
means black cause he's so dark. Oh No,
it's messed up in Thailand, dude.
Like I think they got good skin tone.
We're trying to get tanned going,
running with them all.
You can tell all the boxers running.
They got hats on.
They got long sleeve tee shirts and long
shorts on because they don't want to
get tan cause it's frowned upon to be dark
skinned in Thailand. Really? Yeah. Yeah.
It's like if you're dark skinned, you're,
you, you, you're from the country.
You work in the fields, you know, that's
what's going on with the Philippines.
Yeah.
That sucks man.
They're using glutathione and
glutathione somehow or another. Uh,
it's an antioxidant, but
somehow or another, I think
they inject it or something.
I don't know what they're doing,
but they're doing it to, uh, to,
to lighten their skin color
and it's become a very common
treatment and hear you.
And I want to be tamed. I liked being,
I want my vitamin D. I want, you know,
it's messed up, man. It's not
only that Steve Maxwell who, uh,
has been on the podcast several times
told me that vitamin D levels actually
when you have vitamin D from Sun,
that it actually has an anabolic effect
on the body. It helps your body recover.
It helps develop and build muscle.
Like there's a lot of positive
aspects to having vitamin D.
I've, I mean, the hardest thing about
where I live is a tough winters, you know,
from being from the Boston area and the
last couple weeks I've had some pep in
my step, man, I, you know, the
sun's out. I'm feeling better,
I'm working out better. You know,
it's, I believe you. I mean,
a trick that I do because I struggle
a little bit with seasonal depression,
our whole Gmu been, there's painted
super yellow, it's in a basement.
I do it the trick myself
psychologically and my students.
So you can't tell how
dreary it is outside.
And then another trick they say to
do in the winter is don't wear your
sunglasses out.
The best vitamin D comes to your pupil.
So right away while you're outside
in the winter and it's sunny out,
what that vitamin D come
through your pupil. It's this,
that's the only way because it's not
strong enough to touch your skin in the
winter when you live in winter areas.
But yeah,
I'm a firm believer in vitamin D Sun.
Um, I'm really into the elements of life.
Water is so important.
Sun, the wind, you know,
in the stars. So like it's very
revitalizing all those things.
That's one of the stars.
Like a good starry night dude gives you
like a feeling like your body. Like wow.
That's why I love my wife is from central
Wisconsin and I love going out into
the woods and just chill in and
he would go out and there's lakes.
It's just so beautiful. That's, you know,
looking up the stars, fresh air. I mean,
it's uh, it's so important to
connect with nature actually.
Like in Vegas, every sex,
how are you going to a party?
Go crazy. I'm like, no man,
we're going to go hiking.
My wife and I are going to go
hiking every morning at 6:00 AM,
we're gonna stand Milwaukee
time, you know? Well that's our,
I like going out into the mountains, red
rock, go up the Charleston, you know,
do that. I mean, you know how it is older,
you get a been there done that bought
the tee shirt, you know, it's pretty old.
Well, a lot of fighters have
a real problem with without,
when they live in Vegas too.
And the ones who tend to do best are the
ones who avoid this trip and do things
like a little like me, maybe do a
little jet ski, maybe go hiking,
maybe go fishing, do something where
you're getting out of the Vegas,
Vegas and getting into the
Nevada. Yeah, for sure.
State I've been going to Vegas
and so I was 18 for fights.
So am I.
The first fight I went to was at the,
at the sands. That's how old
I am. And, and I just, I'm,
and even, it's weird. I, I
uh, when I trained in Vegas,
I used to train that master toddies and
he had all these really killer trainers
from Thailand and they would all laugh at
me. They're like, Duke, you're not like,
I, I be home on the weekend.
They're like, you're not going out.
I'm like, no, I want to win. I
go run on Sunday. They're like,
you're not going out. Like, I dunno,
I has everyone else who's come here
before done that. They're like, yeah.
So that's why they gave
me so much attention.
I was so disciplined that like for me,
I know I'm not the most
gifted and talented guy,
so I'm the person now I'm having the
time of my life. I, I have a ball.
You know what? I try and tell all my
fighters, all you fighters, man, dude,
like Joe and I were, we're in our forties
and we're having the time of our life.
It don't like it. It's a number.
Doesn't change how you live. You know?
I keep going after competition.
Yeah.
I mean I have more fun now
doing everything than I
did when I was a fighter.
I was pretty boring when I was a fighter,
you know? Like I said, I just hang out.
I became a movie buff comedy
buff because I watched that.
That was my hobby, you know? But
Dude, you can't, you can always party.
You can always chase girls. You can always
eat bad food. You can always do drugs.
Whatever you want to do. After
fighting, you can do that,
but you only have so many years.
You know what I mean? You have a,
you have a lifespan to be great and
that's, that's what I preach to my guys.
Cement your legacy and then have some
fun and it's also important to take it
into perspective.
Like there's guys that are super talented,
they're supernaturally talented and it
doesn't take much and they can, you know,
there's guys who were champions are
notorious for not working out very hard,
but you know what comes along like say
like guys who don't train in between
fights, they just sorta hang out
somewhere. You know what comes along?
Somebody who's exactly like
you but disciplined. Yeah,
exactly.
And those guys are out.
Those perfect storm athletes are out
there that are really physically talented,
really mentally talented,
very strong,
very creative and super disciplined
and hungrier. Man, you know,
that's, to me the person who wants
it is who wins the fight. The one,
the person who wants it,
it just doesn't start on fight night.
It starts all year rum.
The guy who trains all year round
wants it more than the guy who doesn't.
Yeah. Yeah. You know,
and there's so many examples now
that you could look to as far as,
one of the most important things about
martial artists is learning from past
martial artists, learning from
their techniques, emulating
techniques as you were,
you were talking about before with Belcher
and a lot of different fighters and
this is like the greatest time
ever to have that opportunity.
Like do you know what sugar ray
Robinson would have given to have,
be able to see a sugar ray Robinson on
video before him to be able to study
films? There's no, what did you see? He
saw some grainy Jack Johnson footage.
Exactly know. That's Kinda like,
I would say that's the, you know,
like in basketball, you know,
people who change the game.
I would say it was first it was Bob Cousy,
then pistol Pete,
doctor j Jordan and then maybe Lebron now.
But like those game changing the athletes
and boxing, who would it have to be?
Jack Johnson, first athletic
moving guy, sugar ray Robinson,
who I still watch and study. That is the
blueprint of the greatest of all time.
Muhammad Ali,
of course it's a ram dog man.
Duran Duran is like one of my favorites
because the youtube cause like my
family, I remember we read that paper
view fights. My Dad has five brothers.
I got five brothers who'd be crazy.
Like everyone would be on one side of the,
you know, Duran over
here, Leonard, you know,
I got to meet Ray Leonard to my brother
and know him. He's a great guy. But I,
I didn't like Leonard.
I W I was a blue collar type guy.
I was a Hagler and Duran guy
cause I was a hard worker.
So I related to,
you know,
Duran and Leonard wasn't a hard worker,
but everybody had this opinion of him
as they'll be this glamorous. Sure.
Ready boy, you know,
showing up with, you know,
like a beautiful girl and mink coat.
That's the,
the idea that you thought of
when you thought of it. Leonard,
the golden boy from the
Olympics. Meanwhile, pretty
fucking hard work. Oh No,
it ray ray was,
man,
I got to hang out with ray a couple
times and he's cool. Rarely cool.
And He loves martial arts. You know, he,
you know who his idol is. Uh, Bruce Lee,
he came out, um, when I think the,
it was either when he fought Donnie
little blond or when he fought Hearns the
second time it was cold fight and
Caesar's, he came out in the Kung Fu suit,
not the yellow and black, but
the traditional black, you
know, style. Oh yeah, dude.
He used to train a little bit June Rhee to
really, yeah. Interesting. Yeah. I mean,
uh, knows it. Speaking of, um,
you've got Bruce man, you know,
it's, people just don't
realize how awesome he was.
Yeah. Just like member was the first
armored a movie. It was enter the Dragon.
Right. And then that, then you have, um,
a Kareem Abdul Jabbar and the head
arm triangle and game of death too.
I think he did. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, just, you know,
it just crazy. Just,
I'm huge, like kind of,
I love the guys who kind of shake it up
because actually even one of my mentors
in Thailand,
crew get tongue.
He had a different style of Moitai that
wasn't necessarily the same or the other
gym. I liked a lot jockey Jim, they're,
they're not the norm. And, and I,
I like finding the innovators,
you know what I mean?
It's fun cause th that's the,
you know,
it's like what would we do without
Steve Jobs, you know? I mean what he,
I want my goal,
like with what I'm trying to do.
I want to be an apple type product that
changes people's lives with martial
arts, you know? And uh, I just,
every day I try and think of like,
we were trained around,
kicked today.
My probably show you something
a little different every time.
I'm trying to like innovate.
Yeah. Even the simplest move,
you know what I mean? Cause that's
time is what makes techniques happen.
The faster you can splice the time that,
that,
that technique locks on or Wayans is
how you win a fight. We're also the,
the various aspects of the techniques
that allow you to avoid counters,
sales to doing it one way. You
don't avoid the counter, you know,
those all those little subtle aspects
of striking that are lost on some folks.
Yeah. I think that's why
it's good. The watch like um,
those, uh, the UFC shows on Fox where they
break down the fights after the fight.
Dominic Cruz is really good at that.
Really good at breaking down.
We're fighters made mistakes.
Like a good example is the Conley Rich
Franklin fight when you're only knock
Franklin out with a co with a punch.
We caught Franklin straight
up coming straight out.
I'm not moving the head
off the center line.
How many fighters do you see that
are really talented? Great fighters,
but they don't get with a good camp.
They don't leave their comfort zone,
their surroundings. They might start out
with some gym that has limited trainers,
but they're talented themselves.
They get to a certain level,
but then they can sort of
stagnate and they fucking,
they get fucked because of it.
Really?
Yeah. I mean, it's like
any other sport, you know,
you got to go to the right
college and basketball,
baseball to get selected to go to
the NBA, NFL major leagues. You know,
it's unfortunate. I know everyone has
their Cinderella story. I mean, I,
one of my students is fighting
Saturday, he's from Marshalltown, Iowa.
He moved to Milwaukee and his careers
blossom because of he's fighting for the
world series of fighting title. Uh, the
featherweight Rick the gladiator, Glenn,
great kid, man. Atlanta,
incredible winning streak and his
game has gone up x exponentially.
There's a nice fight to his
on an MMA junkie today. Um,
he knocked the guy out in the world.
Great Kid. And that's, it's hard.
You've got to leave home. Something's
got to be on TV. Yes. I believe NBC.
And who is he finding?
Um, oh, Alexi, the hoods,
the good Russian kid. I forgot how to
say his last night. I got damn good.
Rough number. Risky is there.
They know how to fight, man.
They are not regular
white people. No, no, no.
Off. How many knees did he take from
mighty mouse? Oh, like a hundred,
a hundred knees in the face now.
Crazy. That guy just ate him.
He ate all those knees.
Speaking of Russians, I like,
we were talking about him earlier. Um, so
stoked. Um, about this tournament are 10,
11. Oh yeah, yeah. He's got
a, a cool style fighting.
I'm not picking his style over anyone.
What I like about him,
he's a [inaudible] stylist, but he's
also good at boxing and, but no,
it's funny you're going to
love her because you're a
social media guru is during
his fights.
He's tweeting during the fight.
He's got someone a and is his
Twitter feed. It's awesome.
But the, there's a, he's
awesome though. He's a cool,
he's going up against that Pereira
from Brazil who like this guy,
he trains in the mountains that I
think there's a cool video on youtube,
maybe a Alex Perrera.
He's a native Indian from Brazil and
he channels all I spell Perrera for g.
E. R. R. I. E. R. A, I believe. Um,
maybe had glory into that too.
But yeah,
there's a cool video of him
training up in the mountains,
but he's a former boxer
and he did take Wando.
She's got a sweet turning
sidekick. Uh, yeah, he, he,
he was not the fan favor are the favorite
fighter to win the middleweight Turner.
But this dude's tough. He beat a lot
of good. But um, I like loving a lot,
eh? Eh. Here, check it out. This is him.
He's getting ready for the eight
man tournament this weekend.
Okay.
Look at this.
He's really in tune. He fight. Who was
he fought so far in glory? A fight.
Tyron spa. No, he's awake.
Class lighter. But uh,
he beat a really good guy from
Mike's gym in the final, uh,
oh. I know who he fought. He
fought no, in his last fight,
he knocked somebody out with a left
hook. Oh, I'm Jacoby. Yes. Yeah,
yeah. He, yeah, he brings it, man.
That was a nasty left talk to and
Jacoby's toughest shit, man. Yeah.
And how about Melvin Manhoef is
going to be in this tournament today.
That's another guy that scares
me. I'm like, Hey, Mike passenger,
can you put his collar? I'm
pleased there's a dark color.
The ring. Excuse me, Mike,
can you take them back to the gym? You
know, he's walking around. I'm like,
I think my goal over here,
that is one of the wildest guys
that has ever fought in anything.
Melvin Manhoef is a wild motherfucker.
Oh yeah. I mean, there's just,
I've trained in,
in Amsterdam and there's
just a unique crate.
Yeah. There's just a unique
craziness. His walkout out,
you got to get this real Couto his
walkout where Mike is this firing them up.
They know what Mike says to God.
God Damn for him at work. Oh yeah.
Him and bought her Howery to
animals and uh, they got Saki too.
Yeah, it's crazy. I'm having a
lot of fun with the glory Gig.
Um,
I'm real thankful to have the opportunity
to kind of expose people to just stand
up. It's fun. I mean, you know,
coke ups finding this weekend,
he's on the, he's on the prelims. We
also got a really good kid from Thailand.
He's only 19 years old with
106 fights. Watts. Yeah.
19 with 106 fights I was hanging
out with is just gentle as a lamb.
Nice little kid. I mean, he's just that
little baby face killer. Jesus Christ.
And when you say cro, cop's in the
prelims is the aired prelims. Yeah. Yeah.
It's on Spike TV free. So yeah,
that's our warm up to the paper view.
Now, hey, I got to tell you,
normally these guys are kind
of reserved, but a Rico,
very human and Daniel Guid or
going at each other on Twitter. Um,
they've been good.
I think Geeta has been calling a Rico.
They call him the prince a
kickbox and he's the princess.
He's going to steal his
Tiara. And then, you know, uh,
[inaudible] has been going off about, he
says he's the number one of, you know,
in the rankings. He's like, well, you
know, you're the number one shit talker.
And I mean, they, the bolt of them today.
I've never seen European
guys this animated. I mean,
they're there. They fought.
Yes. And very controversial
fight, right? The first one,
Rico won the tournament.
There's that kind of controversial
knockdown with a Saki,
which he pushed the RAF and he didn't
get cut from a glory for that Saki pushed
the raft down. Right. Yeah. We'll,
we'll talk about that subject later.
But now that,
then he beat a keyed in a close decision.
Geeta thinks he won. Geat has come back
and knocked out two big wins off. Yeah,
he looked really good and now,
you know, very moving bead arts.
He just had his first pro boxing
fight though. Very haven. Teddy Riley.
He's been training with Tyson
fury and really working on it.
He fought boxing really recently.
It has seven weeks ago.
I was a lot of guys and Gloria
are moonlighting. Nikki,
uh,
Holtz can,
he's been pro boxing marked
a bone to funding a bazooka.
Joe Van Hel to Leni Veltin Leni is
fun to watch and fun to watch. Yeah.
Raymond Daniels was a awesome, yeah,
fine. I, I'm big fan of Raymond,
but he did exactly what
you're supposed to do to do.
Can we get that fight up there? Raymond
Daniels and Bazooka Joe and debunk.
Is that for the title? Yeah,
it's for the title. Yeah,
the bone just beat a carpet care
patching in Denver. Yeah, very technical.
I mean, uh, carpets are
really super smart fighter.
Both technical and Karpov was really
coming on those last rounds too,
which is interesting. Um, no, like
the bone, he throws some jump kicks.
He does the jump, scissor kick. A
lot of cool moves, jump fly knee.
But you know, Bazooka Joe,
he reminded me if I did do,
just describe who Bazooka Joe is.
He's the arterial Gaudy of a
kickbox Canadian Italian scrapper.
But here you can see it stayed
on the legs. Nicely dissected.
But when after the high kick, that's
all she wrote. Mama Mia, you know,
it was beautiful. Yeah.
That was beautiful.
He's only got 11 pro fights and he
went toe to toe with Nikki Holt's can,
you know? Yeah. And was hanging in there
until the end. Yeah. And the final round.
But that was also a fight where he
fought that fight before. Exactly.
I mean I think,
I think Bazooka Joe was going to be
tough to beat in the single fight format.
I got to tell you,
I don't particularly like the,
the tournament format because I think
it's unfair if a guy has one fight early
and he knocks the guy out in the first
round where's his opponent might have to
go a fourth round because the
three rounds of gone to a draw.
I think that's crazy to have
those two guys fight afterwards.
I know it's kind of exciting, but I don't
think it's fair to the athletes. I, I,
I've loved that Gloria has done
our five round title fights.
It's just been magnificent because we
see the art of fighting. We really do.
Um,
the tournaments are,
are there a cool spectacle for the fans
who want to see the blood and Gore,
but the technique and the art of strategy,
I think we see that in a title
fight. Yeah, no doubt. No doubt.
There's been some gray great
fights too in the last, uh,
the lightweight division fight
that last fight with um, uh, the,
the uh, Kachin. Oh yeah, yeah man.
Cause Rusty was coming off those two
big wins over Giorgio Oprah Petrosyan,
which is a huge upset. Oh yeah. Petrosian
who is like one of the greatest ever.
Yeah, definitely. He was up to that point,
considered the Mayweather of our
sport and uh, you know the glory.
That's the crazy thing.
The parity. That's what,
what I love about the kickboxing.
The fights are so evenly matched and
this is Rusty's first fight back. Yes.
Glory card this weekend he's fighting
in the tournament, right? Yeah,
he's actually fighting Chi Hollenbeck.
Um, the spike TV broadcast too.
So that's another tasty fight for fans.
Not a tournament fight. Not to fight on,
on Spike TV.
There's going to be a four man,
a featherweight tournament and that,
that's going to be a really good,
you've got a Yo yo come
poon sit chai from Thailand,
the 19 year old with 106
fights. Uh, Gabriel Varga,
who's a really lifelong martial artists.
I like this kid style a lot.
He's good at kickboxing, incorporate
spin kicks, he can punch.
He has a fun style. He's
a lot of fun to watch. Uh,
and you got Marcus vis a
vi Venetia's excuse me,
from Brazil as well.
So it's going to be a tasty tournament.
So that's the tournament.
And then receives fighting
Hollenback a single fight.
And then cro cop is
fighting Terrelle Miller.
She has a win over Pat Barry in the
world combat league and he fought
cro cop, I believe in the k one last
year. The that whatever's left the K one.
Um, but everyone thought
GRL one, so I didn't,
I watched the fight. I, I could have
saw it that way too. It was in Croatia.
So I was going to cro cop's making
this resurgence as a kickboxer. Yeah,
it was pretty cool atmosphere in
Zagreb when he fought. I mean,
I thought he'd beat Remi.
I did too. Yeah. Rentable.
And Jessica was another great fighter
who's been around the block a long time.
He's been actually, uh, no, it's really
cool. Is on the broadcast isn't, yeah,
they're bringing in Stephen
Quatros a microscope vow and remi,
we're going to have some
extra kind of like you,
you're talking about the UFC is doing the
extra analyst and breaking things down.
So we're going to have a fun and it
will be run crock and I in the booth,
Luke Thomas, we're going to have a
lot of fun with this broadcast. Uh,
I'm having a ball doing this cause I,
what I like doing,
like what you do at the UFC is let
people behind the curtain, you know,
it's different.
People kind of understand punching boxing.
That's a jab across a hook.
It's martial arts.
There's a little bit more detailed to it,
not taken away from boxing.
And we need to have that time and room
to explain everything because there's a
little bit more going on with the kicks,
the knees and some of the sweeps trips
and obviously in Jujitsu and wrestling,
a lot of minute details that
make a big difference. Yeah.
And there's also people can relate to what
it feels like to get punched. I don't,
there's like we're saying about leg
kicks things people don't understand.
They just don't, they people who judge
fights unfortunately don't understand.
We have a real problem with
Matt. I remember the first,
uh, I was at that fight.
UFC One oh four.
A shogun versa.
Machida owed him a shitty yeah.
And he kicked the shit out of his legs
and he didn't win the fight. And someone,
one of the judges actually said leg kicks,
don't finish fights like the
fuck are you talking about?
Are you just ignorant to history?
Because I'm both times I broke into guys
likes with leg kicks size on the femur.
I, I fought Mitchell Holla
in 1996 and Australia,
I think it was kicking heart.
He broke his, the Tibia,
he stopped on the stool because it
was blocked wrong. So broke that.
And then Pat Smith,
I kicked him on the back leg and I
cracked the bone right above raped by the
knee joint there. So
yeah, it's uh, I like,
I liked the like kick a little bit.
Leggings are awesome. I'm sorry. I mean,
it's a great feeling to know that you can
do that to someone. There's something,
I don't know. I, I, I've always told
my guys a, this isn't a some mad,
but as I've gotten older,
I've probably changed my opinion on it.
I used to have a quote,
uh,
knocking someone out with a head kick
is better than sex. You know, I love,
there's nothing better.
It's my favorite thing to do.
That's my favorite coup to
ground, to finish a fight
and striking as a head. Yeah.
The head kick. That's why I really push
it with all my guys. It's weird too,
when you connect to someone's had a
lot of times you don't even feel it.
It feels that it goes right through them.
Yeah. Especially the neck kick. I mean,
that to me is my,
my favorite technique.
Air Coke's gotten a bonus with it and WC,
Anthony's got a bonus WC knockout and
UFC and when got it against a Jorge
Santiago, um, yeah, it's, it's,
you see Sir Little Sergio's hunting
fork constantly. We like to kick that.
It's this cool man.
It's,
it's yielding a special power that most
people don't have. Dude. Like, Whoa,
he's trending. Knock me out with
a head kick. I love it. You know,
it's an intimidation factor. It's
like Peter Arts, he's same age as me.
That's one bad motor scooter and he's
still winging head kicks in his fights,
man. Yeah, he's still at it,
man. Hundred percent. Yeah.
Peter is something else to me in his last
fight. No, he said he was retiring. Yeah,
he just fought in Dubai, so he said he
was retiring and he just fought again.
Anyway, man, that's just never
going to retire. I love Peter.
He sees a man like he, he, uh,
he just exemplifies what's
special about our sport. I mean,
got like Rico Verhoeven grew up in
wanting to be him and now here he is.
And I mean, Peter's
just, he's funny, joking,
laughing and his,
he been stopped something like
14 or 15 times. Yeah, I think so.
I mean he's, how's that possible? But
he's got over a hundred. Some fights. Is,
is it possible
that you can kick code 14
times and you're still right?
You're still out there and I hope
he is. I don't know if he is. Yeah,
he talked to him a little
bit. What's it like? Oh,
he's got a thick Dutch accent these days,
so it's hard to tell if he slurring
his words. That's a weird moment,
isn't it?
When you're talking to a fighter and you
know for sure somethings going on that
didn't used to be going on.
You know,
I've met a few kickboxers that or we'll
punch drunk and I know boxers from back
home. I mean one of my training
partners, years ago, Chiro,
Mcclellan almost died in a boxing match.
That was one of your training partners.
He's a mark. Yeah. Yeah. That
was scary, man. That's scary.
That scared a lot of good
differences or phones.
Sometimes boxing
commentators and you guys,
I feel we're empathetic.
You're empathetic to people's problems.
I remember like doctor [inaudible]
Pacheco was calling the fight. Like,
I can't believe this guy is quitting.
You could see like he was blinking.
There's something seriously wrong. I, I,
I'd never call fight again if I call the
guy quitter and he slumped over in the
corner and Freddie Pachecos yeah,
he was old school.
You know,
a lot of those old school guys,
they had that sort of an attitude
about about, okay, yeah, go, go,
go get punched yourself. You
know what I mean? You've,
you've gone in there getting punched.
You gotten so made it wrestled.
You'd know what it feels
like. You know me too. And uh,
now there's nothing worse than
the guy who's never done it.
Who's judging the guy who does it?
I mean it is horrible and
it's very unfortunate.
It's unfortunate that a lot of those
guys get into that position whether the
reporters or what have you.
And they start talking shit about
fighters after their performance,
questioning their heart
and courage and like, look,
you can say that a guy didn't
have a good performance.
You can give an assessment
of their performance.
When you start making
character assessments and
character judgments, that site,
you're stepping way out of line. Do
you ever have bad days at work, Jamie?
Sometimes you have bad day or off.
Well guess what? Fighters fight two,
three times of the year.
Unfortunately their chance to have in
bad days are higher than a guy who works,
you know, many days a week. You know
what I mean? It sucks. I mean, you just,
I am not making excuses,
but the Anthony Pettis that fought Guido
was like the worst. Anthony Pettis,
every was flat in the locker and he just
wasn't feeling good and know what it
was. The best thing for him
losing is the best medicine.
If you use it as a medicine to make you
better, but people have bad days, man.
It's just, it's life. I mean,
it sucks when you have a big moment in
your life and you just can't show up.
But what Anthony has a piece of crap,
a pussy, you know, look, you know,
I mean I overrated. Yeah.
You know that Duran,
he's a wimp. No mohs. You know, like
that fucked him up for a long time.
Know that fucked up
public perception of them.
That fucked him up personally
for a long time. Why
is it, it's okay. In
our sport, we can tap,
which is humane and smart and MMA.
But if you know you're hurt like my
flour but not in the Roberto Duran round.
That was pretty shameful. Yeah. But the
no mas fight me. He's like, that's it.
I'm done. I'm done. He was
fine and he wasn't even trying
to fight. Yeah. It just,
I mean he knew it was getting smashed
though, but he wasn't getting smashed.
Getting out box. My friend Nathan
Corbett, it's great duties here at La.
A training that black house that was he
real, hey, so you're a busy man. So, um,
I think he's going to start helping,
uh, teach striking here in la. Dude.
So if you're in the La area, look up
my man Nathan corporate, Gray, Gray.
But did you see him when he got smashed?
He knew his ear was done.
I mean he didn't want to, you know,
he took by tyrants bong and spawn,
hit him with this left hook
and or go Comstock. Yeah,
hit him with this left Hook and blood
started pouring out of it and he was just
like touching his ears. Like this
is over. I mean that's the thing.
Do want guys to go out on their shield
or they didn't want to be intelligent.
I mean, um, that was
intelligent. It's also a guy,
Nathan Corbett has fought so many
fucking times and you saw the replay when
[inaudible] hit him. It was just a
perfect left hook. His ear was fucked up,
rattled. It starts pouring out
of it when your ear jumps popped.
But the fight is basically, that
means you could do it, you know,
all these guys I respect win,
lose or draw.
I mean that's the hardest thing about
going to the UFC or I have personal
relationships. A lot of guys, there's
not a lot of people, I mean in,
in professional martial arts that
are bad guys are just not like,
I got like a high, you lost,
you know, I just don't, you
meet every guy and you see,
you know,
like that ABC wild world of sports,
the thrill of victory and the
agony of defeat. It's just
so you see that. It just,
it's so hard to see the nicest guys get
there. That's the weak side of what I do.
You see? You know, cause that's what
this is, you're fighting me to the crush,
my dream to build yours.
It's so like it's old school coliseum,
you know.
I mean,
you know some crazy yeah.
For guys to transition out of that to
go to the next phase of their life. Man,
I get fight offers all the
time I missed. Oh yeah, I love,
I mean it was the last time you fight.
What year was it?
A 2007 I think. 2008 it
says, what would you,
where'd you fight in 2008? Uh,
Canada. Yeah, I I love, uh,
I love it.
But you know,
you gotta you gotta do the math is the
fighting part of my past or my future.
So no, what I do, I go
a couple of weeks ago,
anything was boxing in the gym I saw
on Saturday. I'm like, oh screw it,
I'll just spar three rounds with him.
So that's,
that's my thrill now I go on spar. We had
a pretty good heated session, you know,
it was fun. Not like we go hard cause
I'm way bigger than him. But we work,
we have a good time. He had
fun. I had fun. But you know,
it's a quick reminder like that, man.
That's one little bad mother fucker.
I don't think I want to him or her again.
And that was fun,
but that was practice not, I'm going
to go back to doing what I was doing.
Actually. I do some Jujitsu tournaments
when I can, you know, I want to,
I won the Arnold and I won a,
the grapplers quest.
That was when I was a white belt.
You got my blue belt.
Now I'm just looking for a pocket of time.
I can get serious. Cause I, you know,
our Jujitsu team's grown tremendously
under my friend and brother Dan have
underway.
Like we,
we had two weeks ago we had 14
fights at Rufus Sport and MMA.
13 one nine of them were on the mat. Like
that's not a Rufus sports dance. Right.
I've been really pushing all my
guys to be dangerous everywhere. We,
a lot of my guys are going to
Ibj JF tournaments, you know,
big Nagios grapplers quest winning.
Like I'm really,
if you choose to be an MMA fighter
than really be an MMA fighter.
Let me ask you this. So if you're training
the Anthony Pettis world champion,
say if you're training him for his title
defense, uh, against Gilbert Melendez,
which is going to be a great fight.
I can't wait for that fight too.
Amazing fighters.
When you train him,
would you schedule his entire training
routine? Do you, do you set a schedule?
Like in the morning,
you're going to do this in the afternoon,
you're going to do that.
I want you to do five rounds on Tuesday
and then another three rounds on
Wednesdays. I'll give
you his schedule. Um,
we have a really good strength and
conditioning team. The guy who the,
who trains Jj watt from that.
Can we bring that up? Jj Watt?
Uh, do a box jump. Um,
there's either box jump.
He's one of the best athletes
in and it fell and it's not,
he's from the Milwaukee or
it's not by chance though.
He's been at our strength and conditioning
center, annex level, Brad Arnett,
who used to be the head
strength and conditioning coach
at Arizona and Minnesota.
Incredible. A lot of NFL or NBA guys
watch this, does it do to our 90 pounds?
59 and a half inches. Yup. That is insane.
That's who trains our
boys at that facility.
That guy does not know Jesus in
the NFL as an insane vertical jump.
Yup. And he, he's a big fan of the
guys that he's out there all the time.
He tripped plays for a who was at the
Texas Titans. Um, but needless to say,
what is the Texas tightens? The Texans
are Texans six. And is that NFL? Houston?
It's an NFL team. Yeah. But
the soul out of the loop. Yeah.
I'm not a big team sport guy,
so please excuse me. Um, yeah,
the only so many guys
in MMA at the same way,
like once you get used to fighting
everything else is like, yeah, I, Nah,
it's not even that I don't have the time.
I'm so busy watching
my craft and then like,
you know,
like I dunno about you on Sunday.
I don't want to watch a bunch of
sweaty dudes who don't care about me.
I'd rather hang out with a hot chick,
which before we were married,
it was my w you know,
I'd just, I'd rather, uh,
get a little r and r if you
know what I'm saying. But what,
get back to this Anthony Pettis.
So also the schedule,
the strength and conditioning is the
big ruler of what we do. It's through,
it's the recovery,
the active warmup act of recovery.
But every Monday,
Wednesday,
Friday he goes there on Mondays at one 30,
we have practice every day at one 30,
he works a striking based MMA practice
and then we have MMA sparring.
Our hardest sparring is on a Monday.
I believe we do that
because it's their freshest.
So the injuries aren't going to happen.
I don't like to do smart.
And at the end of the week, they're
mentally, emotionally, physically drained.
That's when injuries are going to happen.
Does he do the sparring before,
after the strength and
conditioning program?
After the strength and conditioning
to that'd be counter intuitive.
You'll probably be better off doing after.
It's just the guys like doing
it first thing in the morning.
They get it out of the way. And, and the,
the other thing I'll say about our smart,
we've really backed off on the intensity.
We have a lot of good technical guys were,
I mean any,
right now we're doing about three rounds,
a little bit harder a week. That's it.
I'm really in everyone's wearing helmet,
everyone's wearing high and gear,
so no one's getting hurt because
it's those wild scrambles in MMA.
Were you getting weird positions,
the wrestling and awkward positions
where you getting hurt or collision? So,
and then,
um,
after that practice he'll rest up and
he'll come back and do a one on one pad
sessions with me, uh, work
in drilling and uh, you know,
fight specific game plan. So he'll
do on Monday, three times Tuesday,
a little rest. He has the Tuesday,
he rolls real hard on those days.
It's Jujitsu practice.
And then again at night
he'll come back pad work,
drilling a Wednesday is
wrestling day with Max or Ben,
ask him with the team and strength and
conditioning in the morning at night
again, pads, technique and you
set the schedule for him? Um,
somewhat with the whole team
of everyone, you know, uh, our,
our primary is in the evenings we do are
are white work technique and a lot of
drilling.
And so when he does his strength and
conditioning program is it based on five
round fights is based on,
and the timing of the training we all
meet as coaches and we put together what
the intensity each week opt down if
we're backing off tapering or if it's
intense part of the camp.
Oh, fascinating. Yeah,
we really worked together like Anthony's
taking all the coaches that he works
with from our teams.
So it's going to be great synergy
for the girls who are on his team.
And that's the part where it's really
touchy to try to figure out how to peak
and athlete. Correct. Yeah.
I mean for folks who are not
familiar with that kind of training,
you really can't keep it up for very long.
No,
you do what you're doing during
a six week camp. You can't,
you could never do all year round.
Yeah, we've really cut back.
We see my guys train all year round so
they don't need to do 10 12 week campaign.
10 12 Lee camps are for slackers
because they're trying to get in shape.
And Anthony took the Henderson
fight on a month's notice he had,
he was at a going away party for
Danny boy downs in my backyard.
He had a Negro Modelo in one hand and
a plate full of us take our chat on
another hand and I said, Hey, um,
Dana wants you to fight here in Milwaukee
versus Henderson might want to put the
beer down. He did. He was, he ran to his
father's grave. He went for a crazy run.
Boom. Started running. And you know,
the point being, they're human beings,
but if you're training all the time,
it's a lot easier to take fights on short
notice. Like a guy like Donald Cerrone,
all the respect in the world.
He likes his Budweiser. What?
But he's training constantly, you know
what I mean? He's in, he's ready to fight.
He just mentioned he wants
to fight at one 70 of,
if no one wants to buy them at 55 I love,
I love his attitude.
I didn't like him when he fight Anthony.
But no, I re I, I liked Donald that,
you know, you're my enemy when you're
fighting us. But I, I liked Donald.
He, I love what he is, what he
represents. Like wow man, I love him.
And he's a savage. When you
say fighters, it's Serone. I,
you know what I love about him too? When
he's in his off time, he does crazy shit.
He's fucking jumping with jet skis
through there and done snowmobile jumps.
You see that snowmobile shit.
This dude was training for his last fight.
Like what are you doing man?
It's on your Sunday.
You have fight training
in the morning and you've,
you've taken snowmobiles
over the top of this hill.
No, I mean, I think you
know some of the best,
what makes these fighters specialists
are great risk takers. You know,
you gotta be,
there's gotta be something special in
you that doesn't tick like other people
that makes you want to get into a ring
and fight for amusement for people.
I mean you for a bunch of people that
are going to go online and call you a
loser. Yeah. But you know people,
what I miss the most about the fights,
it's not the Paparazzi.
I love that moment.
Especially if you're the main event,
you go back to the locker room,
there's no one freaking there.
Like people thought like when all
the people back to and walk in,
they're so supportive and we have this
big circle of people help out sex.
It wasn't when they Anthony one,
well we had a press conference.
Everyone's long gone after
the press conference.
So did the ring girls hang out with,
you know,
what's their champagne in the
locker room? No, it was me, Anthony,
and I forgot who else walked out of there
with our crap in the arena was close
enough.
We could walk to the hotel.
It was pretty lonely but not
lonely in a bad way. You know,
it's our own little La Cosa Nostra
this thing of ours. I like it.
It being in a small circle and we what?
We share the people who
know what I'm talking about.
It's like that's what I miss that moment
yourself when you've accomplished it,
not the after five
party. Not everyone. That's
cool. I appreciate that support.
But I like the quiet moment after
like all that work, hard work,
dedication, the blood, sweat
and tears and you soak it in.
Um,
that's what I miss more than anything.
I am no one know what I miss.
I miss the most is I love it.
That feeling when you get hands taped,
it's like in gladiator when he grabs the
sand. Dude, you're getting a hand safe.
There's no turning back. You're,
you're fighting. You know, it's like,
it's the best feeling in the
world, man. I'm a gold this though.
It seems to me like you want
to fight again. Always ready.
It's a drug man. How old are you now?
I'm 44 do you stop and think like, look,
if I really want to fight again,
I kind of do it now.
But you see guy like Bernard Hopkins give
you a little hope, always 49 years old.
All the light heavyweight timing.
To me it's like,
it's all comes down to time and schedule.
But that being said,
I love my students so much of my fighters,
no one happened.
I'd start training and I'd stopped
cause I don't want to jeopardize their
success. You know, I miss it, you know?
But you know, it's like, uh,
you know, a cocaine addict, man,
I'm missing, I'm going to say shit. You
know? But you're still getting some,
a big amount of satisfaction
from training. Oh, you know,
there's nothing better than helping other
people fulfill their goals. Not even,
I'm not even just talking the fights,
but I come to the gym,
I spar with all my students.
We have a ball. I mean,
I'm seeing people change their lives
through martial arts. So that's what I,
that's what I gotta do to keep my
drug in check. I got to spar a lot,
train a lot, just to have fun.
When I get hurt and can't train,
that's when I like,
or I just,
or if it gets too, I'm too busy and I
can't be on the mat actually doing it.
That's when I get crazy thoughts.
Like who I might need something to
motivate myself like a fight, you know,
I try to justify these stupid stories
too in my brain. Why should do it?
Do you ever justify like maybe
I should fight MMA? It'll help.
My MMA coach was supposed
to fight in 2007, um,
for the CFC FFC the,
it was me.
I was going to fight this dude
Derek pains I kickboxer and then uh,
Kimbo slice was fighting tank and
then the winter is our two fights.
We're going to fight each other.
So yeah,
I was training them and
I was into it and yeah,
I was digging it out and the thing fell
apart like 10 days before, you know,
Kimbo slice is apparently going to fight
for Bellatore. Yeah, I heard that. Yeah.
That leg kick him now.
He's cool dude.
I met him when he fired Michio and I
mean when I trained Matt Mitrione, uh,
for the five days good.
I mean,
but no one, there are guys like
him who can come into our industry.
They fight and they,
they,
they have fans and I mean look good
Brock Lesnar did for our industry,
but well bitch, Yo man, that
was a great performance by hand.
That was like one of his
best performances. Yeah.
I mean I just think stylistically, I
mean Matt, Matt told me this thing,
he played in the NFL. He goes, I just
wasn't athletic enough to make in the NFL.
I'm like, Jesus h Christ.
Then what are those guys?
Cause this dude is our freak
man. He's strong, fast,
tenacious.
I mean all the attributes that you
want and a heavyweight ease is a big,
strong dude. Yeah. What do you
think is going on with him and MMA?
Like what do you think about
his, uh, his MMA future?
I mean he's training down at black
ceilings. I think it's a good fit for him.
Doesn't he have a fight coming up?
I think I forgot.
It's just so hard to keep up
with everyone. But he is, I
think that's a good camp.
They got the right size guys.
Cause I mean I can't help man.
I don't have any big guys. I
was like, man, he's cool. He's,
and some people they saw the show,
they don't understand that guy's awesome.
And at head games credible, he knows how
to get in people's with people. Yeah.
I mean I think that that uh,
that verbal a Jiu Jitsu judo and
Jedi mind tricks, it's so important.
Yeah.
It is right that that is an extra added
element to psychological warfare and
fuck with a guy and get inside his
head before a fight. Right. Well, um,
I'm the youngest of,
for the longest time I was being youngest
brother and my family before I had my
younger brothers.
My Dad has five brothers.
His two youngest brothers are almost
the same age as my two older brothers.
So basically I got tormented growing up.
So the only way I could mess with people
for a while was verbally and I had to
learn how to mass with them fall
break. You know, just, just, uh,
you know, and then I started, I
didn't do it at first and fighting.
That's how I got a little
older then. I, you know,
started using little Jedi mind tricks.
It's amazing how many good fighters come
from a background where their brothers
picked him up and made, it. Makes
you kind of look at John Jones,
two big giant super athlete brothers.
Here's, here's, here's our cool story.
My really good friend from Greek community
in Milwaukee played for the eagles
for many years. He started, he opened
up the strength and conditioning place.
My boys train it. He, he's the agent
for Jon Jones brothers and the NFL.
Wow. Huge, huge MMA fan too. He was the,
he played for the eagles for many years
and Rosebowl cabin in Wisconsin. Yeah.
Those guys are huge. They make John
Look like he's like just a little wimp.
John is a freak.
Oh No.
It really isn't the nicest compliment
I've gotten from someone at UFC 100 towns
that he learned how to strike from my
DVDs from the old school. I like Johnny,
you know, uh, we have a great
relationship. He's a cool dude.
He really is a freak man.
I mean,
you want to talk about a
guy that's learned quickly
and has his own way of doing
things and the best at utilizing reach.
Not a second guy
I've ever seen fight that knows how to
keep a guy in his range better than John.
I liked DC a lot. I think DC could give
him some troubles, but the thing is,
John still is so good at what he does
and that reach plays such a factor.
Huge factor. Yeah. I mean John's going to
get better too. Yeah. That's the thing.
He's going to,
if you fight him six months from now,
he's going to be a better fighter.
You fight him a year from now,
he's going to be even better and DC
is going to go to surgery in July.
He's getting his knee redone,
his ACL is fucked and apparently it's
got some other damage going on in there,
so he's going to get crazy.
These wrestlers,
how they can continue to train what
their knee like. Knock on wood,
I've never had any knee injuries. I
don't know what it's all about. Like,
well Chris Weidman,
before he got his knees fixed,
he got meniscus scoped on both of
his knees. He had terrible knees.
They said that he couldn't even get
as heel to touch his ass. Just crazy.
He's fighting for the world title and he,
you know,
he doesn't have full use of his legs,
but he's still,
he has enough that he can force himself
into positions where it doesn't matter.
It's just incredible. All right,
let's talk striking who, let's,
I want to pick your brain.
Who's the greatest kick boxer
of all time in your opinion?
Ramon Decker deck or a rob came in.
Those are,
those are the two guys that I look
up to other than the ties. This,
there's some great ties.
Yeah. I mean, there's so many
great tie fighters. For me,
I love decker style, but
for me, rob, I mean rob,
rob is a big influence in
everything I did. I, I went,
the reason why I went to my first
gym in Thailand. So you're talking,
cause rob went there like I saw rob,
there's a great fight.
He beats her Nesto who's, Oh yeah,
with low kicks and a Hook Kale.
But I mean Ernesto,
super athletic,
but rob systematically
broke them down and I,
and I really enjoy fighters who know how
to systematically break someone down.
Um, greatest boxer of all
time. I would say, you know,
classically people say
Sugar Ray Robinson and a,
I think sugar ray Robinson
is probably one of the all,
I look at it as terms of errors. Okay.
Cause I don't think anybody ever,
if you look at their entire career,
yeah. You know, you could say,
well this guy was better that
guy, but what ad is best? Julio,
Cesar Chavez was one of the
most impressive of all time.
He had this unrelenting
marauding style where he,
he never threw everything in
every punch like Mike Tyson style,
but he just wore you away.
He would just come at you.
And Andy was in a strong era of
fighters. Yeah, very strong. I'm like,
look at his fight against Meldrick Taylor
systematically broke his body down,
broke his and change Meldrick.
Meldrick was never the same. You know,
that fight broke him. If you've seen
the legendary nights about that on HBO,
it's very sad.
I think Roy Jones Jr and its prime
was one of the greatest of all time.
There was a window where Roy
Jones Jr was untouchable.
The only fighter ever to have gone a
single round without a single punch scored
on him. The Vinny Pazienza fight, it's
only fighting copy box history. They go,
one guy landed, you know, x amount of
punches and the other guy landed zero.
That's madness in a professional boxing
match. Roy Jones, when he was at his best,
was a fucking freaked, wasn't
technically sound, you know,
relied on his reflexes but knew
his body and knew his skills,
you could say wasn't technically sound,
but nobody was hitting him and
told Tarver knocked him out.
No one was hitting him.
He was fun to watch.
You know the Rooster Punch you through.
You know where I think he fucked up.
Where I think he fucked up is,
I think when he went up to heavyweight,
he went all the way up to heavyweight.
He got real big and then he went
back down to light heavyweight.
It messed his body up. You can fuck to
his body up. He looked like shit when he,
his body physically looked like shit.
And I think also hormonally he looked
like shit because let's be honest about
how he got up to heavyweight.
He didn't get up to heavyweight taking
fucking friends stone's chewables. Right.
He had some help. And when you're in
your thirties especially, you know,
your body doesn't bounce back
very quick from steroids.
You see someone pulled on over
20 pounds of muscle quickly.
It's just can't be done
unfortunately. Yeah. Pull up. Um,
Roy Jones Jr versus John Ruiz.
You could see how good he was that he
was a fucking former form middleweight in
the Olympics. Fought one the
super middleweight championship,
won the light heavyweight championship,
went up to fucking heavyweight outbox
they shit out of John Ruiz who was a
former heavyweight champion,
you know from your area, right?
Is he quiet man from Boston? Who
is he? Is he with Petronellis or,
I don't think he was. John Ruiz was with
somebody else. Right. But look at this.
This is Roy.
I mean he was thick as shit.
That's way thicker than you ever
saw him at a light heavyweight.
But he was only about 200
pounds. You know, even even then,
like even as a heavyweight,
it was all about speed and movement,
but he was so good and so hard to hit,
you know,
Jones Jr when he was at his prime man,
it was a big over achiever and I use this
style to teach people well as a Oscar
de la Hoya, before he switched with
Floyd senior, his nineties fights.
He was an incredible over achiever,
a big fucking Roy Jones is in this fight
that he had never been that muscular
before.
And then he went from that to the Tarver
fight and he just looked terrible and
car Tarver knocked him out. And then
after that, Glenn Johnson knocked him out.
And that was even scarier
because he went out from a punch.
It didn't even look like
that big of a punch,
but was out completely out cold like
next if to hang out with Roy last year at
been aspirins, last bellatore
fight. He was there. And,
uh, Albuquerque, cool dude,
great guy. Great Guy. I got a chance
to meet him in Vegas recently.
It's a picture with him.
I was so excited that I was with Evander
Holyfield and uh, if there's, uh,
Croatia, he's school. I mean, uh,
my brother used to box at crunk and
I got to meet Tommy Hearns. Nice.
I, you know, I've, I've, uh, met a lot
of cool old school box and guys, that's,
I mean there's this something we grew up
on that sport.
You can't,
you don't discard it and you
don't think about Roy Jones.
Man is that he never had his Joe Frazier,
he never had his Tommy Hearns.
He never had like Tommy Hearns had
Leonard Leonard. Do you know, they,
they had each other, they
had that rivalry. Roy Jones
was just so above everybody.
He had nothing until Tarver knocked him
out. There was really no rivalry. Yeah,
you're right about that. Hey, here's
a, you just made me think of something.
You know Tommy Hearns verse Leonard the
first fight, if that's in the modern era.
Oh yeah. Hurting this one. Cause
it was a 15 rounder. That's right.
If it would have been a 12 rounder, he
would have won that fight. That's right.
You know the 15 rounders stopped after
boom, boom. Manzini knocked out duck.
Who Cam right is. That's
when they stopped. I think
they'll, yeah. Duck cook him.
Dot 15 rounds. It's insane.
Long fucking 12 rounds.
We used to do kickboxing rules,
12 times two stupidest thing ever.
Getting off the stool 11 times. No,
let's do one round. I don't want to,
I don't want to sit down now.
Modern kickboxing.
The the championship fights are only
three rounds or five rounds. Five rounds.
Yeah. Yeah. I'd like to
see boxing. Shrink it down.
What'd you really enforce?
The action.
I think that's why MMA
and kickboxing or growing.
What would you think boxing should be?
Eight eight rounds. Really? Yeah. I mean,
think about our culture.
You want to know what Joe Rogan is doing?
You can click on Twitter,
Facebook,
everything you want to order some cool
stuff from Joe Rogan's shopping cart.
You can click now. You want to go onto
the Duke group, his striking university.
You can click now, get whatever you want.
But that's our culture. We're fast food.
You know, sometimes a boxing
fight, it's like jazz.
You got to wait for the jam to pick
up. We're so fast food, everything.
That's what, why I love MMA and
kickboxing. The actions like now and then,
oh that fights over and knock out.
Cool. Let's bring another fight.
Like a fight like the my Donna
Mayweather fight where my Donna,
that comes on strong in the beginning,
but Floyd levels amount and starts to
pick up the pace and the fifth and six
rounds and starts to
write down the stretch.
For the guys who are making a lot
of money, the 12 renders her great.
The guys who find on ESPN Friday night
fights for 10 and 12 they're making 10
grand, right? And then
they're so busted up,
they can't fight as much as
kickboxers and MMA fighters.
How did it make a living?
How do they survive?
I mean that's the tough thing about boxing
those long. I'd like to see, you know,
and I've never understood why they go
even rounds because you got a better
chance for a drug that is true,
right? Yeah. Go nine rounds. Yeah.
We'd have a better chance for
a victory. Yeah. I mean, or
11 rounds. Yeah. Something.
I mean, you know, it's uh, just
one of those things. I mean, I,
I do like the title fights, but I just
think for the guys brains, everything.
Like how about two 10 minute rounds.
Oh Wow. That would be interesting.
Could you do that with boxing?
I would think that with boxing you'd
actually be easier to fight a 10 minute
around that it would to be to MMA.
Like those pride guys fought those
10 minute rounds. I had ends in any
way here last week. Oh yeah.
Fucking awesome. So cool.
Talking to him. But you know,
that 10 round Mr younger more.
Yeah.
That first 10 minute round man was brutal.
You'd get into a crazy exchange
gassed out. You look up at the clock,
eight minutes to go, what, eight
minutes to go. Yeah. I mean,
and they were real made into standups too.
They're just really like yellow card
if you're a passive. But I, yeah,
I fell in love with him and
May 1st with pride. So I, I
love pride. I use, you know,
I was the one guy,
all the pride factor is
going to come over the wall.
They were, I thought pride was fun to
watch, but from a tactical standpoint,
I would watch the way they would fight.
I would say,
well some guys are going to give people
some problems like Ninja and Shogun and
all these guys were going to
give people some problems.
But I would look at the like elite
of the elite guys and it's like, hmm,
I wasn't like George Saint Pierre
or someone like that. You know,
someone in the higher weight divisions.
Well, I mean we saw it. Forrest Griffin.
Yeah, whipped show Shogun shogun
had some serious injuries.
Man Shogun for a while had some serious
knee problems, couldn't train hard.
And that's been the knock on Shogun
is the, that he doesn't really enjoy,
like completely dedicated himself
to training and being, you know,
an animal in the gym constantly.
And if you're not that guy,
you're never going to be able to
compete with those world class fighters.
You're not going to beat John Jones
if you don't like training. You know,
it's crazy. Nikki holds
can, can take this fight.
But if you follow his Twitter feed
and everything, like this dude is,
he hadn't gotten a car accident when uh,
rape before the last Denver.
That's why I didn't fight for the title.
They are broadening car patching,
but like,
but he's been training but he's still
didn't think he was ready for this fight.
Like he's uh, the kid trains
all year round. I mean,
and that's the different like Mayweather,
the reason why Mayweather,
who is who he is. I mean he
likes to train, you know, and
guys, if you don't like your
craft then don't do it. Yeah.
There's a lot of people that just do
not like it anymore. I mean, you know,
I talked to Mike Dolce who,
you know,
he was working with rampage for one
time and it would just say the guy just,
he didn't want to train.
It would find candy wrappers like
tucked underneath his mattress.
He had hide candy in his bed and he just
didn't want to train and it's like so
hard when you've got a
guy who's so talented,
so good but just didn't want to do it
so hard to dry and then you've got other
guys who,
you know they're supposed to be there
at five 50 they're there at five 30
they're stretching out there,
they're skipping rope before the gym
opens and Pedis is La is the Lowe's on
fight and the Serone fight was back in
the gym Monday training Sergio Monday
cause they know what they get so inspired.
Amen. Then polling checks for mind.
That's what I love about the
UFC man. It's like, oh okay.
I mean I was just counting up
bonus checks from some of the guys.
I think Alan Belcher's dump
300,000 just in bonuses
from the UFC.
I mean I love that.
I I I'd like to see glory maybe do that.
I think that would make the fights even
crazier like knockout of the night,
move in the night and fight of the night.
Now, what is it like being on spike? Oh,
enjoying that. Yeah. Yeah. I
mean it's great. I mean, uh,
the art productions pretty
cool. It's fun. I mean,
I definitely had to get better when I
was the third guy at k one it was so
different. I actually went to broadcast
school with Bruce back in New York,
the original UFC.
Yeah.
He really gave me some good pointers
when I worked with him. He's awesome.
He helped me so much. Um, it's all about
your notes and preparing and you know,
because I'm not a class, you know, so much
easier for you. You're, you're an actor.
You're a comedian. I, I can talk
right here. I'm getting a booth.
But those live opens, those
are tough. And you know those,
that's the toughest part for me. The
live opens, but we're getting better.
That's the easiest part for me
is the live that too, man. That,
that is the easiest part of my day. You
know, we don't even rehearse it. Yeah.
Goldie doesn't even, they don't even
tell me what they're going to ask me.
I think you guys have a really tight
production and we're getting there. Um,
you know, we're going to get some
more shows under about yeah, it's,
that's what it is. Shows under your
belt. I'm having fun though. It actually,
the other thing that's really helping
me is my, my online striking university.
I teach so much on there and I'm filming
and I'm getting a camera since back
cause a that, that's really helped
me. I'm having a lot of fun with that.
I'm reaching people all over the world.
Kind of like what Eddie Bravo was doing.
I got this a technique technique,
a training site.
Now we have a affiliation too. So if you
want to affiliate with roof for sport,
kickboxing and a lot of cool benefits,
people can come train with me as much as
they want and it's having fun. You know,
it's a check me out@dukeroufus.com it's,
I'm having so much fun doing
it because I have, uh, I,
I even respond in my forum Q and a put up
cool videos. I, I'm a teacher at heart,
so I love interacting. I have a
student now who's in from Ireland.
I've just had some coming from tech.
Like you were saying something
really cool about your university,
your online university debt.
When you sign up for it,
you get a free week at your gym. So I
decide to travel down to Mecca. Yeah.
Wait a Milwaukee they could
train with you for oh yeah.
I mean I love it cause I mean
you never know who is training.
There's different guys visiting me and
you just don't get my kickbox and you get,
I like it, dude. It's a buffet. You
want to train wrestling with aspirin,
you want to train Jujitsu
and your boundary. You want
to train with the MMA team.
Um, you know, hey, there's Anthony Pettis.
He uses playing around boxing
with a few guys have visited.
Like they taped it and everything and
that was cool. I mean, like I said,
I always say I have a great group
of guys at, at, at, at our team.
I actually designed roof sport
to be like a camp in Thailand.
When I went to the timeline, all the
kids were so cool. The Thai kids,
they all help me. Especially if I
worked hard and had a good attitude.
They all took me under their wing and,
and that's
what I try and teach my guys. You
know, they're just very welcoming.
It's really good for my,
my,
my students because they get new looks
and new people to train with and it's
just a fun time.
That's awesome man.
And your university is a great resource
for someone who maybe doesn't have a
Duke Roufus in their city cause it's
hard to find a really good high level
kickboxing camp. It's really
hard. You know, if you, you,
if you're stuck in a town that doesn't
have a good martial arts school,
you can learn like really
high level instruction online.
Apply those techniques, videotape
yourself, analyze it, compare yourself,
helps a lot.
Yeah, I mean I, to me,
I'm still a video junkie.
I mean Joe, Joe actually gave me some
pointers today, some new techniques.
We, we, we, we, we got into, we got
into the think tank today and you know,
and that I'm always looking for,
it's a game of just
milliseconds in milliliters, eh,
or millimeters. It's that little thing
that will make the biggest thing happened.
People don't realize that, you know,
it's Anthony Pettis, a showtime kick. No,
it was four and a half
rounds of a great game plan.
He did executed doing great basics that
led to a special moment in his life.
If he can do foot work, do the
proper punching, kicking, defend,
take downs, defense submissions
we would ever got there. Yes.
People look at the outcome. They don't
look at the journey. You know what I mean?
You've got a w w we were joking,
Joe was doing a bad ass kick,
his favorite and he has a good
quick side kick. And I said, Joe,
you'd got the 10,000 rule down.
They'd take see you 10,000 hours
to be an expert at something.
And people don't realize that they want
it. You know, we have this culture. Yeah,
I do teach a lot of wild techniques, but
they work for the people who, you know,
it's like I want to do a flying arm bar
in Jujitsu. Well, you can't do an arm bar.
You can't move your hips, you can't
shrimp, you have no idea of position.
So why are you gonna do a flying arm
bar? You know, you to build up. Yeah,
definitely. And just like everyone
asked Ben when Ben asked her,
I want to do the flying Granby roll. No,
let's work on this boot verse. You know,
it's, I culturally, we live in
a ESPN sports center culture.
You know what I mean? We don't see
the whole game. We saw the dunk,
we saw the home run,
we saw the cool soccer shot.
We didn't see the whole game of,
you know what I mean?
Yeah. Well it's also what you were talking
about earlier about shrinking a boxing
match down to eight rounds or you know,
be the fact that you could download
anything you want or order something on
amazon.com with one click
this, this, want it.
Now thing that doesn't apply to MMA.
MMA is a mountain that you have to
build one grain of dirt at a time and it
takes a long fucking time to
become a martial arts master.
To be able to kick like Anthony Pettis
to be able to wrestle like bend askern,
it takes thousands upon
thousands of hours.
And that's one of the things that we
were showing today that we were working
with like that.
The reason why people don't know how
to do it correctly is cause you don't,
you don't see anybody doing it like that.
So you see one person do it like
that and you go, oh, that's possible.
And that's all it takes.
You see one person that can bang,
that throws that thing like a fucking
lightning bolt and you go, oh, okay,
everybody else is doing it different.
But what you said about Anderson Silva,
he kicks one dude in the face. There's
fun kicks every fight. Yeah, it's crazy.
What's, well Edson Barboza with
that we'll kick of Terry. Adam.
All of a sudden everyone wants
to throw wheel kicks, you know,
and then you see v toward do it to Luke
Rockhold and a junior dos Santos do it
to Mark Hunt to me.
You start to see that everybody knows
is this technique is really viable.
And they start seeing it
over and over and over again.
It's a copycat sport and a lot of ways,
I mean we all have healthy egos.
We all want to outdo one another.
We're all Alpha males there, you know,
so the athletes themselves especially,
they want to one up each other. I mean,
Jujitsu question,
who can deal with Ron does armbar
that's a very good question.
We don't know because you know,
you're seeing girls who have been able
to defend it a couple of times like Misha
Tate and the last fight
defended it a couple times.
I mean she did a really good job defending
it until she finally got caught. Um,
bill look at a mean.
There's,
I think Liz Carmouche show that there's
some holes and Ron as game with that
take down that she likes to do,
cause she likes to grab the headlock
and throw girls down to the ground and
essentially giving up our bag. She gave
up the hooks and then she got, you know,
look with, she got away with
it with Liz Carmouche who,
I don't know what belt she is, but
she can't close, does fucked her job.
And Rhonda had to uh, actually like rely
on her neck to try to release the hook.
She had to let go and just to not defend
for a second and then got out of it.
Luckily. But she was tweaked. I
mean she couldn't chew food right.
For like a week after that.
If that happened.
And let's say it's some real high level
world champion, Brazilian Jujitsu,
black belt, what would happen then? I mean
that's going to be really interesting.
But then again,
the Ronda Rousey,
the fought Liz Carmouche and Ronda
Rousey that you're going to get today.
You getting a way better, Rhonda,
you're getting, uh, Rhonda.
That's way better in the
clinch at delivering shots.
Like Sara McMahon knocked her
out with that fucking liver body.
Then the new deliver, she's just
getting better. She's not stopping.
She's going to continue and
she's getting more comfortable.
She's getting more relaxed with fighting.
She's getting more relaxed.
The fact that she's the UFC champion,
so it's going to be really hard for
someone to deal with that. Yeah, it works.
Davis has got a tough task, but she's
tough. She's very tough. But I mean,
uh, that's that one
signature move. It's crazy.
It's only been a few guys that
have like a one signature move.
They continued to pull off over and
over again. Paul Sas comes to mind.
Submitted more guys by triangle than
anybody I could think of. He's a,
he's got a lot of wins by triangle.
His triangle is fucking wicked.
If you get on the, he just it down.
It's just going it down. Alright.
Greatest Jujitsu fighter. Just
Jujitsu. Not MMA greatest.
The most impressive I've ever seen is
Marcella Garcia. Yeah, most impressive.
I got to see him alive in 2003 in Sao
Paulo when he emerged onto the scene when
he fought Shaolin. Yeah. Yeah.
And he hit Shaolin with an arm drag and
he took his back and Shaolin rolled and
he kept rolling with them. They roll.
Roll, roll roll until the time is done.
Rolling. Charlene was asleep.
Wow. I mean it was just wicked,
wicked speed. And his squeeze
and his technique, he was,
he's the most impressive
I've ever seen in real life.
But I've seen him lose in real life to
shock array. Tapped him. I saw shocker.
Right? Shocker. Ray was very clever. He
pulled guard and and got them into Kamora.
Just fucking snapped his arm back
and it Komora like on right away.
All high level dudes. Yes. MMA grappling.
Well, grappling. Grappling. Okay. This
grappling and then there's submissions.
Okay. Submissions. I've seen some pretty
impressive MMA submission performances.
Damien Maia, when he submitted Rick story,
I mean that is pretty God damn wicked.
My is one of the best.
But like wrestling or a jock or
raise a beast for sure. You know,
he's one of the best,
but fucking Ben [inaudible] of the best
grapplers as far as a guy who could take
a guy that's a really tough,
like really dangerous,
big lightweight,
really strong or welterweight rather big
strong guy and just toss them around.
Ragdoll I'm taking them down at
will guy can't defend against it.
Aspirin is impressive as fucking
shit when it comes to that man.
Really impressive.
One of the reasons why me as a fan
of just the martial arts period,
I'm a fan of, I want, I think that one of
the things that martial arts represents,
what mixed martial arts represents
is potential scenarios and how do you
overcome potential scenarios
if everybody agreed, okay,
let's no more take downs from now on.
No more take downs though.
An MMA would just become kickboxing
and there's fights where that happens.
There are fights where that happens,
but they're true.
Stick of standing Wang is,
as Bj would say,
Wayne take 'em down.
Like I can't stand watching guys. Not
that they suck. Good striking like, dude,
you're really good at wrestling. Like a
bunch of it must that suck for Andy Wang.
Wang Bro.
Cause it's about based on his high level
presented Jujitsu black belt decided to
stand with people. But he's like,
what the fuck is he doing? Well,
here's a fact back then.
I tell people constantly and I,
I um,
I don't think I'm going to get good
enough to submit guys like you,
Mark Jujitsu borough, Daniel
Voll underway. I'm Anita,
a cannon to take Minastrin down.
Fact,
fact is you can knock me out, Ben, conduct
me out and Daniel could knock me out.
Striking mathematically is a
much more chaotic sport right?
By Zig
when I should is ag. I get
knocked out. There's no hate.
Duke luckily tapped me with no,
there's no walking, Jujitsu,
maybe an MMA. If I hit you
enough and you fall into leap,
you can stay and get caught in an arm bar.
But you know,
it's not as easy as there
was no walkie punches.
But if I zig when I could have
you go to sleep easy and striking.
So if you're not,
that's why I teach all my guys to
make sure they get good at wrestling.
Make sure they get good at Jujitsu
because if you're struggling,
say you break your hand. Wait a minute, I
hurt my foot. Let's take this to the mat.
Like an MMA striking.
If it doesn't work can be your downfall
really bad. And especially with hands.
Hands are so easy to break. You hit
someone on the forehead, your mind,
and it's just so jacked from years and
that's what just normal gloves, man.
My hand, it's just maimed. Yeah.
You have like one shorter knuckle.
It's smashed out of there. Whoa,
that's crazy. Yeah, it's missing.
That one's really overdeveloped.
Am I? My hands are bad.
It's been broken back there. There's
a metatarsal there. Pop. Oh yeah.
You get it fixed or to just, um, I've
gotten a cast but it just, you know,
the years of doing it, it just, does it
hurt when you punch with it now? No. What?
You catch somebody with that funky
knuckle? This one or that one? This one.
The first one. This. Yeah. But I have to,
I have to put a bumper in there if I,
if I'm going to fight again how bumper.
Yeah. But a nice little gauze pad
in there to make it even so, yeah,
thanks to my main stitch, he showed
me how to fix that. Well, you know,
vittores broken his hand.
Something ridiculous like eight times.
He said seven operations on his
hands. Yeah. It's just the MMA gloves.
You got to learn how to punch accordingly
with an MMA glove. You can't swing.
Remember when your, your AIA
through down with, um, like Brown,
both paws were smashed. Broke
both his hands. Yeah. I mean,
dude, early in the fight.
Yeah. Man. Uriah, he's a really
good friend of mine, man.
That guy has an incredible heart. There's
no quit in favor. Mental tough. Yeah.
Like dude, I remember when he got carried
out of the cage by Master Tong and,
and uh, Fabio Prado after his leg
with, although he lost the fight,
but there was no way
that guy was quitting.
And that's why I respect a lot
about your idea, you know? I mean,
he's one of those great fighters who
I not get the UFC title, but man,
he's got heart and that, that just,
he can't put a price on that. Crazy.
Would it be if Tj Dillashaw beats Borow
again to rematch and then we see Uriah
versus Tj. Wow. That's possible. Yeah.
I mean that's the hard thing when you
have a lot of fighters in the same weight
and your gym. I mean everyone's the
same squirrel going after the same nut,
the ball and Kira Petchem we're sparring
the week that he got the call for the
fight, then they had to go fight each
other. It was like that movie, uh,
with um, with a woody
Harrelson. And who's the spin?
Antonio Banderas remember the
boxing movie? They had the drive
to the fight together heavy. Are they both
trained in Holland? What'd we say? Hey,
you're on the same flight as me.
That's happened to me where I've been
on the same flight as a guy. Well,
you know that you see with MMA guys being
real friendly with each other before
they fight in a way that you
never really see with boxing.
My why is that you think?
You know,
I think I noticed wrestlers
will wrestle each other. Train,
wrestle each other.
Train. Same with Jujitsu.
We're like in Thailand,
everyone's respectful,
but no one trains with each other in
the hall when they're good sportsman,
but no one trains with each
other. Like, I don't know. I mean,
but then again in like
collegiate mean wrestling,
like Minnesota and Iowa are bitter rivals.
They never,
you know, I would just, I
was their own little world.
They don't do anything with anyone.
They're just like feral cats.
They don't mess with anything.
Also in another place,
like we were talking about Boston,
about Boston,
the women aren't the best look and
it's cold as shit. Everybody's anger.
Nobody wants a fight. That's nothing
compared to Iowa. You know, people would,
I would, would vacation in Boston and
change and go, this place is amazing.
Everyone's hot. Look at all
the teeth payback. It hit
you. I hope you're listening.
Just the fact,
I'm sorry,
but the plus side is I would create
some of the toughest motherfuckers ever.
I mean, not just a military camp and
one of the legendary camps of MMA,
but I mean, how many top end they grow.
Giant fucking deer down there. Holy Shit.
Some of the biggest deer you ever seen
your life. I got to give a quick thinks.
Um, Pat Miletich, she's been a
big part of my development in MMA.
He really took me under
his wing are come down.
We used to bring a lot of our
guys to cross train together. Um,
Pat's a dear friend of mine and I love
the way he calls fights. Yes, I do too.
He's like you and I,
he,
he's telling all those little extra
details that people want. It's a punch.
A kick. No, the what? The, when the where,
the why, the how and no nonsense too.
I liked his no nonsense
approach to commentary.
He'll tell you when a guy's in trouble.
Like he's in trouble.
He's losing this guy. This guy's got to
get busy. He's got to go do something.
He doesn't take a safe
path. He doesn't, you know,
he doesn't sit on the sidelines
and just sort of call the action.
He'll tell you what a guy has to
do with this. Guys got to get busy.
He's got to do this. If he doesn't do
this, you're gonna lose this fight.
Now pad actually was one of
the first innovators of true
MMA, mixed martial arts.
Wrestling, striking. It's good at
grappling was a bad mother fucker.
Dude was a bad motherfucker,
dude. I took no, no.
What I did when I wanted to find
out what Anthony Pettis was made of,
I took Cayman Sergio down to probably
circa oh seven are probably oh seven oh
eight oh seven.
So I took him down there
and pat random through the,
he sparked with both surgeon and
you know, Oh yeah, no, you know,
you know, it was cool. Is
I, that was before I built my camp. That
was the testing ground. You got to go, uh,
that practice room. Oh my
God. But the practice room,
the way they did it back then as
opposed to weigh and intelligent camp,
they didn't know any better. They
were, they were. Yeah, they were.
And they were the innovators of the
MMA camp. They were the original,
you know what they call
themselves? The Black Legion. Yeah.
It was based on the Croatian
Black Legion. Nah, man. I mean,
I've seen guys get knocked out.
They drag him off the man. Hey Pat,
what's going on today? Has a lot of guys
are going, I've got to thin the herd.
Duke. Yeah. Okay. You,
I mean it's a, but I
mean, I was there with,
you know, there's Tim Silvia
Rothwell says Malevich Rory, mark,
um, uh, Jens, the dentist,
Josh Neer,
um,
McGiver in just the list goes on of
all the different killers on the mat.
And it was just fun. I mean, you know,
they had this crazy dude,
Ackerman,
he was a former wrestler with his legs
cut off and he had the craziest strength.
I grappled them.
He could do the weirdest submissions.
He had like the shoulder of awkward stick
is halfway egg into my hip and lock my
shoulder. And it was like the most
painful submission I've ever been in.
Nicest guy. But he was, he, if his legs
were not cut off, he'd be super tall.
One of the best rappers
I saw him actually,
he did a submission
tournament with red Shafer.
He was getting put in a north south and
he did it back to him from the bottom
and choke them unconscious. He
countered. Yeah. Whoa. Yeah.
It was a really cool counter. How
did he do it? Like I want way, uh,
I'd have to pull the video up somewhere,
but this guy just had crazy strength.
So the guy had north, south
on them are nowhere. Yeah.
And he had a counter to it is,
it is crazy.
I forgot what he caught
him with, but he just, he,
because of his unique strength and we'd
be warming up and he'd run on is for cut
off legs. Yeah. But just a great
guy. Great incredible grap word.
And he was a great wrestler too.
And because his legs are cut off,
he could fight it. A lighter weight
class. Oh my God. So he had the army?
Yeah. Wow. Yeah. Cool Times. And just, um,
some of the old school guys that
fought way back from the day,
I forgot the guy's name,
but he looked like Mr. Freeze.
I've never been grabbed harder by
one man. Just grins. Jeffrey's uh,
what was his name? Uh, the
guy from, I forgot one of the,
he fought in the old school,
UFC. He's a cop and, and uh,
I'm having a brain fart to look
like a white bald guy. Pretty big.
Not Monson. No, no, no. He
only fought once or twice,
but definitely, I mean, padded the
history there. It was so cool. I mean,
and then he'd have Brazilians
visiting guys from all over the world,
kind of what I'm doing now of it,
you know,
he had guys in what happened in military,
says gym just doesn't exist anymore.
It's there. I just think Pat's doing
a lot of military teaching and uh,
as well, he is doing his
color commentary and access.
He's really into his family, to his
girls. He growing up, I mean, uh,
and so he doesn't train fighters
and he helps out a little bit. Yeah.
I don't think it's something he wants
to do full time. It's not for everybody.
You know what I mean? You gotta
be, I mean, sometimes, you know,
he got her a bit of a ride, that emotional
wave, you know, I've had some times,
you know,
that negative influences and uh,
your Jim and team where I'm almost ready
to give it up. Negative influences.
You mean like people in attitudes,
but I gotta tell you I'm,
I'm the happiest I've ever been coaching
and teaching right now my whole life.
Like there's gotta be some indication
now you've got a world champion,
not just a world champion.
He hadn't belt or with aspirin,
but now you've got the big, you know,
the big one. I think that's cool,
but I'm going to tell you, Joe, Nora,
it's all about the people. You do it with,
the peep the faces you're there
with every day. You know? I mean,
that's what it's all about for me.
I would be doing this if I didn't have
champions and didn't have famous UFC and
guys on the high level. But
it's the feeling you, you know,
the feeling you have when you
walk into that place every day.
The people that look back
at you and that to me, I,
I can only do things that make me happy.
I unfortunately,
I'm not the guy who shuts up and we'll
do it just to do it right. Paycheck.
It's not me. And so that's
when I'm happiest. So that's
why you're so good at it.
Oh thank you.
You're so good at it because you have
so much passion for it because you throw
yourself into it cause you commit
to it 100% and because you're,
you're so deeply engrossed in the world
of MMA and kickboxing and you're just,
you're so mean. You're, you're
living in it all the time.
If you didn't work for glory,
you and I can have the same conversation.
Definitely. For sure. I mean I
can watch fights, talk fights,
like people come into the gym visit
and that like, holy crap. It's like,
what time I could keep
going and going. And God, I,
this is again, getting back to
the team. I love the people.
My guys are, they're not saints.
Well trickles down. Yeah.
I just saw today are you set a great
example in that champion that train
training your gym before and it's a very,
very friendly environment.
It's really cool. Hard worker. Thank you.
Everybody's there to, to do their job.
Everybody's here to work hard,
but it's a very friendly,
like very family environment. Cool.
We tried to set up like the new place,
especially at like a clubhouse. So if
you're not training, you're hanging out.
We got the flat screens. I mean, um, you
know, everyone's going to watch the, uh,
free fights it and the world series
of fighting at the gym Saturday.
Like I wanted to create
a community like a real,
again, that's kind of how Tang on was all
the guys lived at the gym and you know,
fights around guys would watch one of the
guys fight on TV. It's just in general.
I mean,
I think that's what martial arts is.
The dojo is a extension of the
community center. You know,
for me, I really like reaching out
because I have a lot of guys besides like,
you know, the pedis. His Dad was
shot or stabbed and killed. My,
my Guy Mike Biggie Rhodes, who fights
in UFC is fighting the New Zealand.
Great Kid, moved from Iowa, actually
his cousins, Mike Van Arsdale. And uh,
he, uh, you know, he has
a tough story growing up.
His parents abandoned his grandmother,
you know, raised him. He went,
earned his degree in college
once he graduated from college,
moved up to Milwaukee when the RFA
title and then he's now in the UFC.
Live in the dream.
But what I love about him
is he's so positive about
the shit life he comes from.
He doesn't complain.
He's about the same with Anthony.
He don't cry about what it was.
It's,
he's focused on what he wants to become
and what he has because he's happy now
because he's overcome. Yeah.
And just, I mean, even my guy,
Rick Glenn,
his sisters dying of cancer and he had
to cancel out of the fight earlier this
year and he's struggling.
He's going to win that belt Saturday
and he's going to dedicate it to sister
who's, you know, been in
hospice struggling. And I, I,
I love the character and the strength of
the people I'm around. It's inspiring.
It makes me want to do more.
So when I say I want a
flight that's selfish,
those guys make me not want to fight
and focus on them. Yeah. Cause man,
they're just,
I love people who dedicate to themselves.
There's nothing worse than
watching people waste their money.
Pancho. It's cause the spike
game so hard, man. It's such a,
it's such a grind. Everything in
life. Yeah, you're right. You know,
even you probably know Comedians,
actors who just are self destruct.
I medians especially. Yeah,
it's the roller coaster, man.
It's so hard to watch
guys who have everything,
but they just won't talk
to be dedicated hard.
That's why a gym like yours is so
important to be around a bunch of other
dedicated people.
You inspire each other.
I have a bunch of dedicated comedian
friends and I call upon them all the time
for inspiration.
We inspire each other and being around
guys that are constantly writing and
pushing and going for it,
it makes you want to do the same.
The same thing with training when you're
around guys that are training twice a
day and training hard and they're
really enthusiastic about it and pushing
everybody and going for it. It brings that
up in you. You want to do it yourself.
Yeah, I love it. Like I don't have
to raise my voice too much anymore.
I love that because they know I won't.
I won't.
I don't want to be a dick in the
practice room. I want to be cool.
I want to laugh if we're working hard,
you know, my pound sign is having fun,
getting it done. If we're doing work
hard but have fun, you know, it's cool.
I mean I got my other
guy Dustin or t's fight,
tough fight and Scoggin so some of the,
you gave me some tips for the
fight that thanks. You know,
some techniques with science has a very
interesting side to side stance and he's
very good wrestler too, which is a
real con weird combination with that.
That karate background. Big Fan of that
kid. No, no, I mean f flyweight division.
I don't care what you fans
are talking about. That is
a sick stack division. Wild,
wild, wild division.
You know, how will you,
I'm enjoying transitioning
into commentary. Do,
you're doing commentary now for glory,
you know,
and it's very nice to see high level
kickboxing on spike and I commend them for
putting it on.
I was so happy when Gloria got onto,
I was one of the first people tweeting
about it. I've watched every event.
I fucking love it. I'm a huge, huge
fan. What does it like doing the,
the commentary you enjoying that I'm,
I'm the biggest fan myself.
You know what I mean? I really am. That's
what come, it comes across. I think.
I love it.
I mean even before,
like I surprised myself that I became
a world champion and kickboxing. Like,
I just wanted to fight to
validate my coaching and I
just kept on winning fights.
I'm like, Oh, I guess I'm all right
at this. But at the end of the day,
I'm still the biggest fan. Like, I,
you're going to have to kick me out
of here today. I could just keep,
you want to look at more fights.
Like I can watch it until the cows come
on with you, man. It's, it's, that's,
you know,
that's why I don't watch
other sports because I think
we're in the coolest sport.
There's, you know what, the two oldest
sports on the planet are wrestling,
no fighting and runners. Oh, either run,
not the beef food or
running to get your food.
Either fight not to be food or fight it.
They're the two most primal things you
can do. Especially fighting, I mean,
that's what this, uh, kind of kind of a,
it's a Cicero quote or my arm. The best
protector of the sheep is the wolf.
I believe that some people
in there, wolves and some
people are sheep. You know,
people love fighting there. The wolves,
they're the protector. So, you know,
and it's kind of like training days to it,
talking about it takes
a wolf to catch a wolf.
But like fighting is dude,
it's the most primal thing.
I'm, I still miss that.
That dude wants to kick my ass.
I got to kick his ass.
It's the most nerve wracking.
It's like, uh, all right.
So I was a little experimental when I
was a child and teenager after I lost my
sister, I saw about 25 or
26 grateful dead concerts.
And I, I'll use this
analogy, I'd say that I'm
fighting your first fight if you'd never
done it before. It's like taking acid.
Either find yourself or lose yourself.
I've seen people are the baddest
ass person on the planet.
They're the best fighter in the gym.
And they go to the fight and they just
melt like butter. They're just can't,
you know, it's like
they trip out, you know?
And that's what I love about fighting.
You got to take who you are and that and
the the gym and you're a god in front
of people.
And I'll do it in front of
20,000 people or in a local show,
do it in front of 2100 people.
It's still, I love that vortex,
that rush of proving grounds.
Yeah. Real, true. Proving ground.
An exposure of truth like nothing
else because that's what I think.
It's like I've seen so many people
lose themselves. Dude. All right.
Bring up being dwarfed by the mall.
Bring up this clip.
This is when I knew Anthony
Pettis was special. Um,
Anthony, all right, I'll
give you the fight. He,
he gets his shoulder popped out and he
gets up and knock the dude out with a
head kick. Like, check this out.
And this is when I knew like,
and I have a lot of kids like
this who just have that thing. Um,
Anthony Pettis verse.
Yeah.
Dead Air. Mike Lamb, brick, l a m B, r, e,
c, h. T and this you'll see raw.
But you want to talk about how you find
yourself and lose yourself in life.
This is one of those moments like,
and uh,
you know that, that's why I love that.
You know, whether it's, you go do it.
I do Jujitsu tournament wrestling match,
whatever man.
Like getting in a Mano a Mano situation
is until you've done one on one sports,
you just don't know what I'm
talking about. Here it is.
So how did he get his shoulder? Fuck.
They'll see it here in a second.
He's teeing off on it. Yeah. That's
old Anthony. That's that, that,
that's hood red ant just come out the
bell rings and that don't look like new
Anthony, right? Yeah. He's
throwing a wild share right there.
All came down. Yeah. Fuck
the shoulder up. Yeah.
So now how bad was the shoulder?
Fucked up. Wait till he stands up.
You're going to see something
just crazy. And uh, you know,
just what I do is I always
judge people on their potential,
not a each performance.
And like when I saw this,
I knew that this kid had super
potential like hearing hip escape.
Yup.
Marking fines away.
See it dangling. Oh yeah.
It's fucked up. So watch this.
This is why this kid special.
All right moves.
Wow.
Oh,
switch off the front leg too, right? Yep.
So that's why when you find
yourself with a fucked up shoulder,
yeah. Didn't have out, didn't think about
quitting and show that again. Jamie,
Jesus Christ. You know what I mean? Wow.
Everyone thinks he's just this flashy
kid and deep shin. That's, yeah,
that's perfect. It's, that's
beautiful. Then you're going to be,
you can't celebrate his shoulders so bad.
Now what happened to his shoulder?
What did he want him doing?
It popped
it out. That's why I hesitated.
He never gets injured in training.
It's in fights, man. Wow. You know,
and that shoulder was hurting him for
awhile and he had to go through it and he
got it fixed and here he is,
you know? Wow. Yeah, just crazy.
I mean like you just got that,
that thing that,
that's what competing in the
ring, the octagon like, you know,
it's just, I love that. That's
what I missed. That we got to,
you know your mind.
Like when I'm in the locker room,
I don't care how bad ass your,
your mind's fucking with you.
It's like you're on a trip. You don't feel
so good today. You don't want to fight.
They got to be like, fuck
you, he, come on, let's go.
You know, like everyone has doubts
in your mind. That's the key.
You got to keep all those voices
out of your head. Like Ah, you know,
it looks kind of Arosha is,
you know, seriously man,
you're tripping out back there and
then you know, it's like you find it,
you get your hands taped and
you figure it out. But you know,
it's such a head trip. There's a
Mike Tyson used to talk about that.
There's a cool speech he has where he's
like, if I met before in the locker room,
I'm getting my gloved up, I'm pounding
the leather and, and I'm scared.
He's been training for me and I go up
there. But then I walked to the ring,
I feel like a God.
And then when I walked to the ring,
I look at them and I don't take an, I
look for a Ci, a chink in his armor.
You know, it's just, I love
that intense moment. I know
when you see it anymore.
That's one of the reasons why fines are
so intense when you're watching them.
On television.
When you see Chris Weidman stepping there
against Anderson Silva and two weeks,
or excuse me,
against Leo Machida in two weeks and you
see those guys opposite each other on
the other side of the octagon.
You know those are the two best 185
pounders in the world and they're about to
go and the referee, whoever it
is, looks at him. Are you ready?
And it looks at the other one. Are you
ready? Like, Holy Shit. Here we go.
Well, I'll give you my perspective. Like
I just get these dudes who are like,
I could be the best fighter.
I'm great at street fighting.
So you're good at going, hey,
I'm going to hit you by surprise.
You want to know what takes to be
a real gangster? I don't like you.
I got to fight you. I'm fighting
for the world title. Guess what?
We got to go on press tours. So every
time I see you, my adrenaline spikes,
man. I hate fucking jober. What do I
got to be here with them? All right,
we've got another press conference.
Oh Shit.
We're in the same hotel room all week.
I keep running into this asshole.
So every time it's like, I got to think
about this guy more than anything. Oh,
we're at the way in the back and
I get to stand next to him. Oh No,
now we got to walk out. Now we've got
to stare each other down. Oh Shit.
And this is all you think about. Then
you walk out, you walk out first.
Now you got to hear his song you're in,
you're in the ring waiting for him,
and then you know how many times I'm the
high level you confront with each other
as I love about little shows.
You see the dude at the Wayne and
then you show up and kick his ass.
There's nothing but on the big man.
Then
you're constantly forced
to be with that dude.
And that's something that folks don't
take into account when they think about a
fight,
a championship fight,
the amount of press these guys do and
the amount of interviews they have to do
the same question that you have to
answer over and over and over again.
Morning radio shows, interviews with the
reporters. Had enough. Enough, enough,
enough. It's an added element.
Oh, stressful element. People
who can handle the, the,
the big, big light media. I
mean that, that, that's, you
know, that's a tough thing.
Gory. I mean, here you're the
fuck fucker Milkman, right?
You know, but the restaurants
small, the way we're, we're at,
there's not a lot of stuff
around there, so it's like, man,
I used to hate it in k one we take the
same bus to the fights. Wow. It, my,
my first time I fought in Japan,
they didn't have separate bathrooms.
My opponent was on the table next to me.
That's how it is in Thailand
at Lindt Bunny Stadium. Like,
then you got to sit like in
a chair waiting to go right
next to the dude you're
going to scrap with. It's
just like the coliseum. Wow.
Walk out with your opponent.
It's a trip.
You know what I mean?
Like people don't understand the
head trip about fighting again.
That's why I say it's like taking
some Hallucis, the gins, it's,
he can trip out a little there.
You know, it's very distorted.
Very reality distorting.
Yeah man.
I've seen people crumble under those
situations. Like I've seen the toughest,
most athletic people who can handle
the psychological side of it.
And when a fighter loses
that's when things get cause
then you start to question
everything. Your camp, you start
questioning your conditioning program,
you start questioning how you're set up
and how you're setting your training up
as far as how much emphasis is
on this and how much is on that.
And maybe I need to do Jiu Jitsu coach
or maybe my striking coach doesn't
understand striking for MMA.
Maybe I need to move to Albuquerque.
Maybe I should live in Seattle
with Matt Hume or go to Montreal.
It for us a hobby. Yeah. I mean do you
mind starts fucking with you? Yeah,
I mean especially people if they've been
an Alpha male successful their whole
life.
My biggest advantage,
I've been an underdog my whole life so
I'm really good at like I'm like Henry
Hill,
I know that once like he
said and everyone's got to
take a beat and once in a
while. So I'm, I'm mentally
strong. Cause I know like meetings.
You know what it's like. Yeah. Whether
it's verbal, abusive, you know, physical,
the like people who've
never had the struggle.
Those are the people
that drop off the worst.
That's one of the reasons why those
guys who have brothers are so fucking
dangerous. You who's
had brothers? Jon Jones,
because Chris Weidman was beat up by
his brother his whole life and widens
brother, put him in the hospital, dropped
a metal plate on his head. Wow. Yeah.
I mean there's a lot of shit
with those guys. Matt Hughes,
he had a fucking Twitter, just as bad
ass as him. Another gorilla growing up,
beating the fuck out of it.
She decided not to fight so his brother
could be championed. It's that crazy.
I know. Or think about what his
brother could have been. Yeah,
it would probably cause his brother
was good at it. Very, very successful.
We fought once and he didn't eat.
Yeah.
I mean you fought another organizations
too. I believe. I believe so.
But other Marilla
huge. I mean, so again, that
mental side of this sport that's,
I know what I like to
do. My new, I run my, um,
my older fighters are kind of like navy
seals and the base navy seals don't have
to wear the uniforms.
They don't have as much protocol.
But my newer fighters I put in
through my spartan training,
I try and see what you're made
of early on in your career.
If you have any aspirations, if you
can't get through the spartan stage,
you're never going to get to the
top level. You know what I mean?
It's kind of what, what
difference. I'm just,
we're a little harder on them. And then
my pro guys, the pro guys are made guys,
man, they've been doing it, you know,
that's the difference the way you talk
to a high school football player as
opposed to a NFL work. You
know what I mean? And I'm
not, I don't do it to be mean.
I want to see what you're made of man.
Right.
If you break down cause the coach gotten
your ass or kind of a pussy, aren't you?
You know? Sorry, I wanted to make you
great. Yeah. Sorry. I want you to win,
so I don't want you to get
your face three arranged. Yeah.
Dealing with adversity
and have an all forms,
verbal adversity and if
you can calm yourself down
during those horrible moments
of Duke Roufus screaming at you. Yeah.
I mean that's not always, but I mean,
I just know my brothers
did. My, my brother Noah,
I'll describe my, my sister died when
I was 15 and I, I found her dead.
She died of sids.
It was pretty tough.
It's probably why I didn't have
a kid for a long time, honestly.
That's told my wife and I,
you know,
later in life and it's is
pretty traumatic for me.
He used to say it's not
feel sorry for Duke,
it's just what I figured out
and I feel better now about it,
but I was 16 that I decided, hey, I've
been doing martial arts my whole life,
but I said, I want to be a fighter.
My brother was older than me.
He's 20 he's already world champ. And Rick
was a killer. The scene at a godfather.
I remember when Michael Goes,
you know,
I want to be in the family business
and my brother's like Sania hothead,
like the same. The same for
you kid. Remember he goes,
you're used to shooting them from
far away. We kill him up close.
And my brother was kind of like scoffed
at me. Like, you want to be a fighter?
So I had to go through the Rick roof,
this indoctrination.
My brother man, he used to lay Beaton's
hounding me like you wouldn't believe.
Yeah, hit me with spin back wheel
kicks back then. I mean, that kid was,
you know, dude, my brother is amazing,
especially in his game,
PK style kickboxing.
But I was like a rocky movie. I just
kinda kept coming back every day. I just,
I was so messed up, but I
just wanted it so bad. But
I'm not saying that bad.
I'm glad my brother did that
to me. He made me so hard.
He made me Bain, man. You know,
I was molded in the darkness as he said.
You know,
Remember Bane and the Batman movie, you,
you guys nearly choose the darkness. No,
I was
molded in and I had,
I had to go to hell every day.
I used to box in the inner
city in Milwaukee, in the
Martin Luther King Center.
It was like they had seen at our member a
true romance. Is it whiteboard date? No,
I don't think so. You know,
my nickname was snowflake.
You know the only white guy
in the room, you know, is,
it's like years of oppression.
Just, you know, but it's cool.
I got my ghetto pass now I'm all like
everyone knows back home that I can throw,
you know. But that's
what made me, you know,
a lot of guys don't
want to go through that.
I'm so happy I had to do
it that way because it made
me so mentally tough that I
have gotten my ass kicked and had the,
that's a hardest thing in the world.
Get the crap kicked out of you and
then you have to go beat someone else.
You know it's dude. What's the worst
humiliating thing you can do in life?
Get your ass kicked in for our, gotten
everybody, God and everybody. Yeah.
Some guys, they have one loss, one big
loss and they just never recovered.
They never the same again. Toughest
thing I had to do in my whole career.
I fought 2001 they needed
a quick replacement for um,
k one at the Blasio.
I took the flight like on three weeks
notice I had another fight plan.
I was just starting my major strength
and conditioning for a flight.
Seven weeks later, no, or
like 45 days after that one.
So the decent amount. So I've
just, but hey man, it's k one if I,
when I'm back in the super 16 to
go to Tokyo. So I come out there,
I threw down with Stefan, let
go. Um, it was a great fight.
I think it's on youtube actually. We're,
we're, we're going in. I felt so great.
First round. I sit down on that
stool, boom in a wall and then man,
we're going at it.
We're going to eight drops him once in
the segment and then the second round I
go to opera cut and I
just reached too far.
I see that fricking opera
got common. It's like, it's,
that's a worst thing that can happen
in your life. See a counter. Oh fuck,
I get it with it. Next thing you
know, I'm looking up at the lights,
but the thing is,
I was suspended 45 days.
I think it was fight in 46 days later.
So I had to go fight.
That one's on youtube to me,
verse Pedro Fernandez.
He lost by stoppage and then 46
days later he fought again. Yeah.
It's against the guy who only his only,
um,
losses were to my brother and Marie
Smith coming into that fight. Wow.
So when you do that, I, that was the
toughest challenge in my career. Wow.
How much time do you wait
until you spar again? Uh,
I waited a good amount.
I really didn't spar it all a
shadowbox pads, everything. Wow. Yeah.
Just to give your brain a arrest.
Yeah. That's so important. Yeah.
There's so many guys get knocked down and
training and then they go to the fight
and then they can clip by one shot and
there, but I know a couple of guys,
I won't,
I won't rat them out to the UFC that
have gotten knocked out and training and
still fight. And they told him, I'm like,
man, you can't do that. So yeah, I mean,
yeah, it was, that was the
toughest of my career. It was
because not only that,
but man,
I just got knocked out f out
like that takes a PCU away.
Like you think you're some
bad mofo, you know, like, Eh,
I home rink, I had gotten
stopped by someone since, uh,
Mike Bernardo and 96,
so I hadn't been stopped rock put on
my ass by anyone since like that point.
You know what I mean? So it's
years, you know, it, you know,
when you get dropped on your
ass and it takes the, you know,
it's like maverick and a in top
gun. Can you get a bag? You know?
But that was for me, the toughest
fight of my career. I ended up winning.
I stopped a guy in three rounds.
But you know,
that's the thing people don't realize.
And Golf and tennis, Yay. Loss Bro.
You know. Yeah. You lost
a basketball game. When we
lose, it's, it's catastrophic
guy loses in an MMA fight or a
kickboxing fight or even a wrestling.
It's like someone just stole who you are.
Yeah, definitely part of your essence
triangles. You and you're
like, he just owned you,
Ben Henderson.
You could see like not robbing it into
Ben Cause I like Ben respect them a lot,
you know. Um, he the great
performance, by the way, Ben Curry,
I told him personally at the time,
fight fight was fantastic. That's
so good enough. Yeah. No Dude,
he has the pedes factor. Anthony
creates his own little Frankenstein.
He's making this dude get better man. He
was like, he's coming back, got damaged,
stay down. Don't come back. I can't
wait to see that rematch shut up.
I know cause it's hard to
be the guy three times.
I always say that it was always hard to
beat someone, you know, sooner or later.
Like how mark has caught up to back.
Yo,
you know it,
you could see Ben just crushed.
Yeah.
That's the artist thing.
I respect them.
And that's the hardest thing about the
sport. You see your opponent. I'm glad.
Yeah. It drives me nuts when guys don't
tap in to get their arms snaps and then,
you know,
they're fucked.
Well Jon Jones lost his title or could
have lost his title to Vito Belfort,
but he decided not to tab.
Yeah.
And when Vito was cranking on that
arm and it was hyper extended,
John made a decision, a decision, I'm
going to let this song and get fucked up.
And his arm was fucked up for a long time.
That's why he coached on the ultimate
fighter with jail because he really
couldn't train her fight. So
He's like, just coach. You
know, what's the worst time,
worst lock break you've seen? Is it
Maghera or Tim Silvia? Yeah. That'll know.
Gary is just as bad, if not worse. Maybe
no. Garris worse. Cause it was no, Gary,
I remember my boy Danny downs.
I can't believe member when the Kimora he
got put in. Yeah. That kid is so tough.
Yeah. Amazing. Yeah. He's
actually coaching in San
Diego at a victory and remain,
he writes for the UFC. Oh,
beautiful. Yeah, he's got some
funny stuff, man. He's cool.
But that's one tough
Irish kid. I just, yeah,
I couldn't believe like
he just, you know, again,
sometimes guys don't do as well
as they'd like to do in the UFC,
but I'll tell you one thing
about that kid heart courage.
He went out on a shield.
You know,
sometimes as an athlete
you're the hammer or the nail.
Your job is to entertain the fans.
And the kid came out to fight every time.
He was very fun to watch, very fun
to watch as all your guys are you,
you produce really exciting
fighters or tried to, I mean, uh,
something I learned years ago from
growing up, my dad was a promoter.
You know, you want to be a
promoter's delight. You know,
you want to be the guy that, hey, we got
to get these guys on there. You know,
it's fun. You know what I
mean? To Sergio's credit,
he tried to finish a fight.
He was winning against Bruce Lee
Roy and he dropped first submission,
made a tactical area wanting to finish
with a heel hook personally where I got
them. You know, I'm a big fan of Bruce
Lee. Right? I think he's underrated.
I think he's a very, versus Uriah.
Interesting. I mean it's just,
you know, he's tough fight. Yeah. Tough
fight. I mean your eye is a veteran.
I mean if he does what
he did to Mcdonald's,
just runs out and makes the street fight,
throws him on the ground vintage.
That's what I like seeing Uriah do.
I W I think derives doing good striking,
but I think when he comes out,
you're right cave man. Yeah.
Alan just chokes people out is that he's
kind of a a blueprint for what I want
to see a lot of my wrestlers do. Go
Punch him, take him down, throw him down,
choke him out and let's go home.
Fight was probably his finest performance
in the icon. That was spectacular.
I think older fighters, like he kind of
reminds me a little of Oscar de la Hoya,
like Oscar switched training with,
with Mayweather's dad.
And you get bored with
certain styles or like you,
you put weapons in your arsenal,
but sometimes learning new weapons
actually hurts you more than helps you.
You know what I mean? Cause it
gets you confused. Cause yeah,
he led are almost too much. I used
to do that. I, I, I'd be like, man,
I'm really into this technique but it's
not helping me. It's actually hurting me.
We're running out of time. We've just
about hit the three hour mark. Oh, sorry.
Yeah. How do people get Ahold
of Duke? Roufus University. Ah,
how do they get their two
groups.com [inaudible] dot com
for a dollar rate now you can join,
check it out.
Mannerful and Duke Roufus on Twitter,
Instagram, Facebook, all that.
This Saturday night glory is going to
be live on spike the prelims and then
paper view for the main tournament. Yeah.
Yeah. Joe is going to be in the house.
If you're in the La area,
come on out meat.
There's going to be a lot
of fun people and the forum,
right? Yeah, yeah, of course.
Joey karate, he's making a comeback.
Joey Diaz is coming down to and,
and uh, that guy had no issue
that Brazilian guys, my buddy.
Yeah. Master orange. He'll be there.
We're going to get him. Hi. Oh yeah.
Should be a good time. All right. Thank
you brother. Oh, no man. My pleasure day.
All you guys keep listening to Joe Rogan
podcast. It'll change your life. Oh,
I don't know about
that, but we'll give it a shot.
Yeah. Uh, thanks to legal zoom.
Go to legalzoom.com. Use the
referral code, Rogan at checkout,
and save yourself some money. Thanks
also to [inaudible] dot com go to o,
n n I t used the Codeword Rogan and
save 10% off any and all supplements.
All Right, ladies and gentlemen,
many, many, many podcast to com.
Lots of good guests next week. Much
love to everybody. Enjoy your weekend.
Talk to you soon.
Big Kiss.