Hello Freak bitches.
You know,
my brother,
uh,
he was,
he passed away.
My brother was a,
uh,
I kind of say a hundred,
but he was actually a poacher.
My brother,
when he passed away,
uh,
people said,
hey,
can,
um,
can I have your dope permit?
And I was like,
what?
He's like,
my brother had been getting a dope
permit in my name for like 20 years.
Oh,
really?
Yeah.
He had all these forge dope.
It's,
he shot animals all year long.
He didn't read the game.
Warden would bust into his home with a
bolt lock cutters and crack open his
freezer and there'd be all this game out
of season.
Oh Man.
He,
uh,
yeah,
but you know,
he ate it.
Right.
But he,
uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
He didn't abide by the rules.
Well,
no,
it did not abide by anyone's rules is
his funeral was,
uh,
it was awesome and Eclectic,
but there's two things.
Someone should've given me a heads up.
Well,
first of all,
a couple of the pallbearers were in
Cammo.
Really?
Yeah.
Had a serious hunter.
Oh,
hunter biker.
Where do you live?
Uh,
central New York and Syracuse and then
Rome and around.
But you know,
I love my brother,
but he was wild.
And,
and then the other thing,
they probably should have given me a
heads up that it's friend a little.
Ricky was one of the pallbearers.
Yeah,
he was,
uh,
I just like,
um,
I don't want to use the word,
I was going to say,
he's like a Munchkin.
Good,
safe.
I didn't want to use the other word.
I mean,
he wasn't a tiny person.
It's a little person.
He wasn't a dwarf,
but because he was regular size almost,
I don't know.
He was tiny,
but he didn't look,
you know,
I mean I get it,
but nobody said ricky was going to be a
pallbearer or give me a heads up.
So I looked down the end of the church.
He's in the middle on one side of the
casket and then middle.
Yeah.
And I said to my daughter,
go,
looks like Ricky's riding a subway.
My Dad,
he's like,
I think he just got air.
And so the brace is going on about how
my brother Tommy loved the outdoors.
And He loved animals.
And then I went on after the breeze,
I go,
father,
I don't want to be impolite,
but my,
my brother was like to kill animals.
There's a lot of deer right now in the
woods going,
whoo,
whoo.
Upstate New York.
So very dear rich place.
People don't have a lot of tolerance,
those animals,
a lot of car accidents.
Well,
there's a lot.
And there was more now than when I was a
kid.
But when,
uh,
you know,
Tony Vee,
Boston,
Tony,
I went up to visit my brother.
I had given him some money to buy some
windows for his house.
It's a long story,
but he lived,
this is what he's really in the woods.
And,
uh,
we pull up to his yard and there's just,
um,
there's just corn growing.
Like there's no rows.
It's his whole front and backyard of
corn.
Like there's like psycho coin.
There's no rows or anything.
Right.
And uh,
and Tony didn't know my brother and he
comes out and he goes,
hey,
what's,
what's up with the court?
And he's like,
oh,
it's for the dear bobby.
You know,
he's like a,
and Tony's like,
oh,
you help them through the winter.
He's like,
no,
I'm blast.
Him and my brother actually made he just
house.
Yeah.
Oh that's so fucked up.
And I go,
I'm in the bathroom in the new window is
cracked.
Did I go tell me what happened to this
new windows you have bob,
you had a little problem with recoil.
So my brother would sit on the toilet
and shoot deer.
Swear to God,
swear to God.
I'm sure he's probably burned in one,
two taking a shit.
You want to go hunt and you know,
meet me in the kitchen,
you know?
And then then one time,
him and his friends really high and
they,
they just turn this a station wagon and
doing convertible.
Would the heel yard torches and then
they would use that.
That was their hunting moby?
Yeah.
That was their term car.
They're driving and shoot out of it.
Oh my God.
Yeah,
yeah.
Oh,
so I brought this part of the story,
so,
so Tony Visconti,
you'd brothers certified,
but like you said,
been around my brother.
So he goes to Tony.
Tony and I get back Gar and we're
heading to her.
The car in the,
Tony sees this woodchuck across the
street until he goes,
what is that chucky would chuck and
then,
um,
and then we're not even down the end of
the driveway.
Tony's going,
I just figured that would shut yo man,
that would just dead.
You dropped it.
The home on net.
We'll check you fingered that would
check that his family is going to go
papa papa coming to the door.
Yeah,
my brother,
God rest his soul.
He was a wild man.
Wild for living.
He was a sheet metal worker and uh,
you know,
he rode bikes for a long time.
He was always a,
you know,
there was always our home when I was a
kid was like,
you know,
the movie mask,
it was just always bikes and motor clubs
will come over to the house and keg
parties and stuff like that.
Whoa.
Yeah,
yeah.
It helped me to go to the bigfoot
conference.
No,
hell yeah.
So that's what I grew up with.
You know,
guys name like low life and all these
guys.
And My mother was great because they
would come in,
you know,
uh,
my mother was sweet because she would
know,
only know their,
you know,
their bike or names.
Yeah.
And so he's,
you know,
hello shithead.
Yeah,
exactly.
It would be like,
you're like a low life.
Showed up with a shirt that said
Harley's the vast fuck the rest.
And he's like low life,
not in my house.
So it was a g and they had turned the
sure not.
Yeah.
So I grew up with bikers and it wasn't
until later on I realized,
Oh,
you know,
some bikers aren't Rad.
You know what I mean?
Like,
you know,
oh,
I see.
I mean,
look at my him.
I will,
hey,
how are you?
Like,
you're a nice guy,
so you associate me.
They're always nice.
It'd been like cool fun.
Yes.
And my brother had a lot of clout in
that world,
so yes,
everyone was cool.
But,
and then later on I was like,
oh,
some of these guys aren't so awesome.
But so basically bikers are like bears
at the dump.
Like they look cool,
but stay in the,
okay.