I was out there,
have the answer,
a real solid answer for the tail summons
for.
Isn't that weird that Bj would,
would not have a guard like that,
that he wouldn't have this Ninja
assassin guard?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Like you know why?
Because he didn't.
I and I,
and I would say this,
I mean I've told this to Bj,
tell him like,
you know what,
if you stay at 55,
there's really no reason to master any
kind of guard.
Just get back up.
You're fucking ever be better than
everybody standing up.
Nobody at 55 can take you down.
Even big wrestlers can't take you down.
I even thought he doesn't need a.
He doesn't really need to focus on his
car.
I thought he didn't need to develop an.
I really didn't even know it was
interested in the rubber guard and he
fucks with it a little bit,
you know what I mean?
But he,
I'm sure he felt like no one's going to
put me on my fucking back,
but maybe now,
now that he knows like shit,
these fighters are getting so much
better and there's so many wrestlers out
there,
you really have to have the answer for
Chael Sonnen and for like Frankie Edgar
and framing.
Yeah,
for these elite wrestling.
What he did to Florian,
he took him down and got on top.
When they talk about your garden,
the only answer for,
for the elite wrestler,
and they're all,
they're all over the top 10 of every UFC
weight division.
The only aunts or one of the only.
There's only a couple of answers and one
of them is having a.
When they talk about your guard,
they don't say that.
It's just a man.
He's got an okay guard at a decent
guard.
They have to say,
your guard is a fucking amazing,
like don't go in his garden.
Your Garden has to be like Ryan Hall.
Your guard has to be Shinier Yolk.
You don't want to fucking be in your
flag raid like Anthony Pettis and Shane
Roller.
When Anthony Pettis slapped on that
trial,
exactly.
You have to have a super dangerous car.
If they are not.
If people don't talk about your guard
like it's amazing and it's fucking crazy
wicked,
and they.
It's one of the best guards in your
division,
then you're not good enough.
You don't have the answer for the elite
wrestler most of the time.
Sometimes you throw up a,
a,
you know a pop triangle and it lands
like Anderson Silva made it work in the
fifth round.
I'm Chris Leben made that pop triangle
work and you know the Nogueira style of
triangle at work that works.
It does work,
but not at the highest rate.
You know there's,
there's a lot of the things that you
could do as well to add to that already
game,
you know,
to those Nogueira triangles,
you could mix it all up.
There's a lot of things you can do.
Just look at what Shinya Aoki has done.
Look at what Dustin Hayzlett has done.
Look at what Matt Horwitz has done.
Just pay attention.
It's out there.
You can watch it on youtube.
You can do it too.
You need to have the answer for the
elite wrestler and man,
having a crazy wicked guard can be the
answer.
What is the image name?
Tony and I ran into James.
Tony,
it's amazing that you lived in.
You know,
I was pulling for him at first.
Well,
I thought that box.
I thought that these MMA guys really
didn't know these.
When you're a boxer in you're that high
rate of a boxer,
you know,
you really don't know.
These guys get hit and their hands and
that the timing of this shit.
But when I watched the countdown was
when I was like,
he didn't work.
He didn't work.
He got a great opportunity to represent
boxing,
but he didn't work.
You don't think you've worked out.
I lost a lot of weight.
He lost 15 pounds a month.
Okay.
If you're rolling,
Eddie,
student law 60 in a couple months.
If you're really fucking roll.
Let's say you take this guy on,
you got four months,
the first month or you're doing with
them.
You're not working his hands.
They're already there.
So you're basically working and getting
up and just rolling little things.
Just surviving on my back right there.
All those things are bad.
You know what?
I used to go to judo when I was a kid.
I was skinny as shit because the hardest
thing about judo is flipping.
It's every time you get up and down,
you get up and down.
50 Times a day that you get skinny.
This guy didn't do that.
He got some guy from the FBI to come in
and train them.
You know what the fuck?
They go,
Oh,
you know I'm in.
I'm in.
I'm in Hollywood with Ladell.
I'm rolling.
I'm rolling with Einstein.
I'm learning the basics.
How to Bro?
What?
How much can I learn?
And four months to get me out of a mess.
That's what I'm learning.
He didn't know any better.
You didn't know.
He didn't know where.
He got a guy from the FBI that God knows
that they fucking paid up.
One was the guy who trained him to Kenpo
videos of him online,
like Campo with guys that come behind
him and cut his legs and stuff and the
guy was trained,
James Tony that's on the underground.
I say James.
Tony actually doing it.
Well,
I mean he,
you know,
he looked the guy set up a program for
him,
but what does the guy know for real?
You know,
what he really needed to do is go to
Colorado Springs and train at the
Olympic training center.
He needed to get a guy who's a fucking
Jujitsu master to come with them.
Okay,
these guys are going to take you down.
He going to do your best to stop,
to take down.
Then once they get you taken down,
then you're going to work at guard.
That's what you need to get down and try
to submit those bureau a motherfucking
daily basis.
When I watch the countdown show,
what was very clear to me is that the
guys who was working out with,
we're letting him do things for the
camera and that it was.
They weren't elite grapplers.
They were letting him do things like,
I was like,
ah.
It was a demonstration,
like anytime you change roles all over,
like,
ah,
I can't believe he's doing this.
It's like they were like letting him do
it.
They're putting on a show and letting
james throw them around.
I was like,
this is silly.
I'm like,
he might not know anything about
grappling.
There was this dude that found Hobby
Vasquez back at my first king of the
cage show in 2000.
He comes out in claims,
he's a Brazilian jujitsu black belt.
He's this French karate guy,
and he thought back then he just started
like,
you could just say shit like that.
And so he said,
I'll take the.
He said he's been training Jujitsu 12
years and he's a black belt under hoists
gracie.
That's what he was telling Carrie
trouble cock.
And Terry's got,
I think we've got a live one here.
He calls the police Gracie Academy.
They never heard of the guy.
The guy's bullshitting.
He's trying to scare harvey into going
to the ground with them.
And Hobby was a purple belt.
But uh,
did Matt destroyer on the local southern
California scene,
he would've gone to Santa Santa Cruz as
well and smash.
He was the fucking destroyer of the
purple belts division and there wasn't
very many browns and blacks at that
point and he was going to go against
this guy who claimed to be a black belt
dude habit.
Took them down and like the guy had no
training dude,
zero has used,
just laid flat on his back and he tap
really crooked hobby powder in them a
couple of times.
He just kept and it was over.
It's like,
what the fuck was that?
That's an interesting story,
but a much more interesting story is the
other guy that we know that claim to be
a Brazilian jujitsu black belt that
really didn't know anything that turned
out to be a murderer.
Yes.
Yeah.
There was a dude we knew his,
his fake name was Raphael Tory.
But his real name,
what was his real name?
Damn,
I don't remember.
But he told people he,
uh,
he taught karate karate his whole life
and he taught karate and he told people
he was a black belt in Brazilian
Jujitsu,
but this Guy Eddie was hanging around
with this guy.
He was doing Brazilian.
He said it was a website,
right?
He was.
No,
he was a writer.
He was probably one of the most popular
journalists back down on the
underground.
I mean Ralph El Toro was all over the
It was 2000.
It was still in the dark ages,
so it wasn't easy for a guy to bust up
and he was on speed all the time.
I didn't know this until years later.
So he would work hard.
She would always have shit and pride
loved them.
He always had reports.
He always had interviews.
He was always,
oh dude,
he was probably one of the top three
riders in Alabama.
And I remember he was very productive
and he would do.
He was doing his version of Gonzo
journalism for MMA,
like asking MMA fighters if they like
anal sex.
I just like being real crazy.
That was my shift.
So it turned out that this dude wasn't
really a black belt at all and um,
we,
you know,
it wasn't half Brazilian.
Yeah.
It was like,
it was all crazy.
We were driving and Eddie had this
confrontation with them on the phone.
To make a long story short,
homeboy winds up killing some dudes
strangling him to death.
The husband of this chick that he's
banging and he winds up going to jail
for it.
When he was,
he was a murderer.
He,
he,
he got this guy insurance.
Medicaid.
Yeah.
The,
uh,
the wife of this guy that he strangled,
you know,
so they,
they decided to set this up and he
choked the guy to death until the guy
with a real naked choice.
How ironic is it?
That is black belt wasn't legit,
but he killed someone with a rear naked
choke.
A Guy,
poor guy killed in a trained at all and
probably didn't even see it coming.
I just jumped up and choke the shit out
of him.
Can You Imagine Matt Madman,
your fucking wife as banging some other
dude?
That dude comes to your house and kills
you.
It didn't go to his house,
he's lured him into Jim and I testified
on that trial.
Did you really had to go to court and
just finger,
um,
and they called me.
They called me.
The cops called me because I called
Gerald wants and when I was talking to
Gerald on the phone,
the phone was being tapped and Gerald
and I are talking about,
you know,
his,
uh,
possibility to him fight in the UFC who
is,
you want to fight this Napa and Rafael
Torres name comes up and I'm like,
what's going on with that dude?
And so Jerald was being tapped and he
was talking all these different people
about it.
And then,
you know,
the,
everybody that he talked to on the
phone,
they had to talk to the cops.
But I didn't really know anything.
I didn't know the guy.
I just knew the guys ready.
Fortunately I want to fucking go to
court about that.
Yeah.
So what'd you have to say?
Yeah,
that guy's a fake.
He's a liar.
Basically.
I forget the questions they made me ask,
but I hung out with that.
Like he was always brought in on
whatever show I was commentating,
whether it was king of the cage or pride
or even a too hot to handle.
He was always the reporter who's going
to blow up the handle was in Holland,
right?
Boss Man,
boss Dude.
And he was,
he was so busy.
He was so amped up on speed.
He always had articles and to blow up
shows you bring Rafael Torah and they'll
blow it all up.
All over the Internet.
Right?
Always on speed.
Huh?
How'd you find out?
He was always on speed.
It came out later on the trial.
Do you know I'm already took a uh,
what is it called?
Adderall.
Took an adderall.
Says is the fucking greatest thing ever
for getting things done.
He said it just cleaned out.
The speed did.
Yeah.
But what is it?
Why is it speed can help you get
organized?
How does that work?
How does it give you fucking energy?
What the fuck?
You feel like you could do anything?
You just want to paint the fucking
house.
You want to go to college?
It's to fucking Louisiana.
You know what I mean?
Is it bad for you?
Come on.
It's gotta be it's gotTa be right.
What comes up must come down.
Right?
Anything that speeds you out.
It's got to be bad.
That's like super,
but it's not just super speeds you out.
It makes me like really organized.
Robert told me once,
he took one accidentally and he said he
just started organizing all of his
notes.
Just that's what happens when you add
speed to think that you could use that
though as a tool if you could really
make sure you didn't do too much of it
and didn't fuck up your whole system and
short circuit everything like every now
and then when you knew that the problem
as you come down so hard that you want
more to come down from adderall.
I don't know about adderall but anything
speeding usually goes up.
Comes down hard on it every day.
Are you,
what does he say?
Buddies.
He said he loves it and it helps them
organize.
Helps them work and he's pretty fucking
ambitious.
He's,
he's a hard worker,
but he said he was just really listless
and couldn't get anything going on and
you know,
and they got them on the adderall and
then pam just couldn't focus and
concentrate on things.
He just had a hard time committing to
things and concentrating.
Maybe it works different than speed
because speed somehow I don't know how
it works really well by Athena speed and
that's the fuel of the capitalist
society and I mean look,
we're the,
we're the people who drink coffee
everyday.
We have a,
in every union contract they have to
negotiate a time where you could take a
drug.
There's a fucking coffee break,
you know,
and union contracts have coffee break
time.
What does the coffee break cover?
Break was your work.
It's fucking 11:00
AM.
It's not quite launched yet.
Coffee truck pulls up and you get a
chance to take fucking five slash 10
minutes off and fuel up on some,
some stimulants.
It's good for the company.
You come back,
I'll jazz and charged and you feel
better.
You work harder,
you feel better,
and you feel like you got another little
break.
You know,
that's,
that's union things is one thing they
figured out that was smart.
You know,
look,
everybody doesn't have to be a slave.
Like people will like go against unions.
The unions fuck up business and they
don't work hard and they make too much
money and blah blah blah.
They make work easier and that's good.
All right.
It's not good to have people work like
fucking slaves.
You know?
Wouldn't it be better if they got a
little bit less done?
But everybody was more happy when that'd
be better.
They get a nice coffee break and get to
relax for an hour for lunch where they
don't feel like they're getting tortured
all day.
You know?
Maybe if they got some shit to do during
lunch,
they can go somewhere and fucking pay a
bill or you know,
pick up the fucking thing that they were
supposed to buy fast.
Do those hours go by God damn that our
break our breaking shit.
Talking about coffee break is a smoke
break.
Get outta here.
Josie.
Twenty $100.
It is and it's fucking joe job does
podcast two to 4:20.
That's the moon going there.
We got to respect this fourth one that I
got shit to do with people who see.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm doing this next one.
No one.
I didn't even fucking thank the pot.
The fleshlight for sponsoring this.
So we're doing this next Wednesday,
next Wednesday.
Doing this as,
as often as we can.
And uh,
as this fucking.
This camera sucks man.
I got a camera that it autofocuses and
so are,
you know,
you gotta move before it goes into focus
again.
All right.
We'd like to take the flesh the
flashlight.
Fuck your hand.
No more.
Fuck the fleshlight why fuck your hands
that worn out after 18 years.
Give them a fucking break.
Work your muffler with that.
You could fuck the flashlight.
Straight up.
It comes in colors.
What's the website?
Joe Rogan.
Fleshlight.com.
And listen,
Joey's not even speaking to the voice of
experience.
I personally had fucked.
Well,
I've never fucked the flashlight.
Fleshlight fleshlight.
Eddie Bravo is fucked one.
Yeah,
I've had one.
What?
I've had like a fake flashlights.
I've had this thought.
I'm tele.
When you do it like this,
then you roll it like this.
It's kind of like a fucking flashlight.
So 71 cock suck and I use it on camera.
People on twitter,
please stop sending me the video of the
chimp.
Fucking the monkey.
Like it's a flush or the monkey.
A fucking.
The restaurant is probably better than a
front.
Yeah.
Do we need to get those chimps frogs to
where the frog feels awesome.
What did you do it?
No,
no,
no.
I don't want to.
I don't want to fuck a frog and it
didn't kill them.
Maybe a deep throats it.
Have you seen the size of their fucking
throats?
Have you ever seen that?
There's a girl I deep throat.com.
I think her name is heather.
She's like famous online for her ability
to swallow cock.
It's always her husband's cock.
Like it's always like he films her
sucking his dick all over the world,
right in bathrooms everywhere and she
just goes straight down to the boss and
you guys got a big deck.
She goes straight down the balls and
just look at his balls while his dick
just disappears in her mouth.
But the problem is you see a girl like
that in video.
Totally sets up your expectations way
too high.
How?
How many chicks can do that?
And she sponsored by fleshlight.
No,
that's the bits that should be now.
Why did it?
She's.
She's a human flashlight.
You don't.
You can't get to anybody until she gets
to your town.
Use the flashlight.
That's right.
What love you?
Cock size anyway.
You're not going to.
If you go to a fleshlight.com,
there's a link.
If you go to Joe Rogan Dutton,
that supposedly if you go off that link,
you get 15 percent off and it really is
better than beating off.
That's my point.
You know you beat off.
I do too.
You know,
you know we all do.
Just stop being shy.
Get one of those was excellent.
$60.
Well invested.
You'll enjoy your,
your nuts sessions to the creators.
A flashlight.
You guys need to think of a thing that
where you can just.
You can close it up and then throw it
into like your washer and it washes
through on its own.
Taking notes.
Cleanup.
That sucks.
Yeah.
It's a little annoying dishwasher.
You know what I mean?
You can't be lazy,
Bro.
You can't have a self cleaning
fleshlight.
The last thing I want to do afterwards
from a,
from a jerk off session is clean some
shit up.
My Samara Dvds.
We didn't give him a music video this
week either.
We'll give you one more Sashi I love
your cock sucker.
[inaudible] Musashi.
A film by Hiroshi in a a 10th planet.
Kush 19 is up right now.
Just went up today.
10 planet watching on Youtube.
Thank you.
Everybody came to Boston this week.
We had a great fucking time at the
Wilbur theater.
That was awesome.
Thank you everybody that tunes into the
podcast.
Hi.
Love you bitches.
And we will continue to provide free
entertainment to you.
As long as it's fun and it's fun as
fuck.
So we're going to keep doing it.
Thank you very much.
Everybody loves you.