The Joe Rogan experience podcast.
Full charges here.
Can you type in and not look at the
screen?
Yeah.
I took a typing class in high school.
Had no idea I was going to pay off.
So huge.
I can barely do it.
I kind of do it.
My mom was a receptionist.
I can type it runs in the bloodline.
Crazy,
bro.
You got skills to pay the bills.
Even if this comedy thing doesn't work
out,
I can still type like a Kelly girl.
Fuck.
That's amazing.
I wish that was still a thing.
So full motherfucking child.
It's good to be here on a special day.
Good to.
Good to be here with your brother.
Um,
comedy store tonight.
Oh yeah.
My first set of the comedy store in
seven years.
I went there the other night.
It was just too much fun.
It's great.
I got to go back.
It's not the same sadness that it turned
into when you left.
No,
it's way more upbeat.
It's crazy.
The management's great.
Everybody's like all professional and
everything.
Like a in that show they do that roast
battle show.
Holy Shit.
Is that,
that might be one of the best shows like
for an audience member to attend in La.
It's fun.
It's so fun.
It's so well done.
All those dudes that are in the.
Well this week there were terrorism guys
and some weeks there are black guys.
What do they call the Negro Wave League?
What do they call it?
Oh my gosh.
Watkins who's also the host of the desk
bod pod podcast.
Thunderpussy is a hilarious comic on,
you know,
in his own right,
but he's a part of this little group
that during the roast battle when our
joke does really well,
they run on stage and do these crazy
antics and the terrorist guys joke
murdered.
It just murdered and they ran on stage
and they water boarded to dude.
They threw a towel over his mouth.
Poured water in his mouth.
I mean cause like,
you know what it's like when when
someone kills with a bit shit.
And this is a small room where we saw
this is in the belly room.
The comments to which might hold 100
people if you stuffed to the gills.
That might've been 100 people in there
that night.
Hanging out the window is everything.
I mean,
people would just see just crammed into
this fucking spot.
And uh,
we had a great fucking time.
We really had a good time.
I saw Joe joke over so well one time and
the Negro wave league,
there was one white guy and they threw
all this paper on the ground at first,
just kind of for the sketch started and
they start picking it up and his cotton
face because it's white guy starts
whipping them all.
Oh my God,
they got a whites only section that says
racist shit.
Totally Racist Shit.
And is a sign on their table that says
whites only really good and you know,
it's just fucking good.
And Brian Moses who hosts it,
he's fucking funny,
man.
Funny.
And he's great at that Gig.
It's reminiscent of eight mile and the
whole the MC battles and he's very MCI
for whatever that guy's name.
You know what I like to that he says,
Hey,
at the end of it all,
we hug it out.
Yeah.
You know,
I liked them.
Not like it comes,
the whole thing comes off like what it
is.
It's a joke writing contest.
Did you know that if two white guys go
head to head that they're allowed to say
the n word once each?
I didn't know that.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They allowed to allow me to put their
phones in a basket when they go into
that because someday someone's going to
be on stage and the people that are like
on fucking whatever,
you know,
super progressive blog that gets US
radio.
I'm sure Brian said something about it
the other night.
He goes,
listen,
if you get easily offended,
get the fuck outta here.
What happened on a blog?
Somebody wrote about like,
you know the n the n word is thrown
around a lot in that room from the
whites only from the black guys,
from the judges,
from the all Negro wave crew.
They say it a lot and who is the was
somebody went home and blogged about it.
Really?
Yeah.
As that's how it goes down now.
Los Angeles,
the comedy store giving white comics as
you're saying,
it's gotten more professional at the
comedy store,
but that's so far old school that way.
It's so funny that someone,
first of all,
it's someone just doesn't get what
they're doing at a place like the comedy
store in a show like the roast battle,
like the whole point of the thing is
pushing it over the top way over the top
in the most ridiculous unrealistic.
No one's actually saying that it's
almost the white section is almost
progress.
The whole thing is pretty much progress
in a lot of ways,
which is one of the reasons why
Hinchcliffe fucking loves it.
It's fucking great.
Love it.
Great God damn show.
So I went there for that and then I went
there for red taping of his show and it
was just too fun.
I was like,
I got to come back.
It just doesn't seem like what I was
running from the old school vibe is
there again,
like just,
I don't know,
it's just really cool.
It's like Swanky,
classy and,
but kinda dirty and down and out at the
same time.
There's just no place like that and I
felt it when I was there.
I was like,
this place,
there's something,
you know,
it used to be Ciro's nightclub in the 19
whatevers,
the early,
the Bugsy Siegel owned it and the story
that we always heard from everybody
there was at taunted and that a bunch of
people had been killed there and they
say there's a sniper point in the green
room looking down on them and well there
is not a sniper point,
but there's a small window.
But apparently it was like with Jerry
Lewis wanted,
like Jerry Lewis wanted to watch the
opening act so you could,
I guess know where they're at so he
could get nervous,
you know,
she can get a view,
see how everything's going right now.
Like in case they didn't have cell
phones,
it couldn't tech somebody,
uh,
you know,
it's,
this fucking crowd sucks at Dick.
He couldn't just,
no way to let each other know.
You couldn't call.
Hey,
just to let you know,
there's a guy,
a drunk guy in the front row.
And so I guess he just would watch the
opening or maybe he's,
you know,
he's insecure you opening.
Yeah,
exactly.
There's kinds of tell you to take it
down a notch.
I've got guys on the road like a work
with guys and the guys tell him,
dude,
you're going a little too hard down.
Yeah,
I've,
I've had people tell me not to do
certain jokes really,
that,
that really didn't kill their jokes.
You know what I mean?
Well,
well,
well did they tell you not to do it?
Like I was just starting out and I had
this closer and it was very hip hop
oriented and this guy and he's awesome
comic.
I won't even say who it is because I
think he's awesome.
But he was like,
Hey,
I got one hip hop joke so you can't
throw it.
And it really hurt me at the time
because it's all I really had,
you know.
But that's life.
That doesn't,
that doesn't seem too bad.
Oh,
that's a tricky one man.
You know,
I've worked with guys before and they
were opening for me and they touch on
the same subject that I'm going to touch
on later and so unless you already been
doing a bit and then the dude does it
and he's opening for you and then it's
Kinda like you're paying someone to trip
you up,
you know,
you can.
That can,
that can be argued,
I guess.
Yeah,
we maybe it was,
it didn't harm is bit.
You said,
no way.
This guy is way too funny to have
anything I say harm them,
but there's just like a maybe a paranoia
or something there,
you know,
maybe.
I don't know.
I was telling Brian earlier,
it's like all the road trick is just to
go,
hey,
Brian was talking about this earlier and
then you do your fucking thing.
That is,
that's all you have to do.
Real.
Yeah.
That's the road trick.
And that's a great way to segue into it.
We don't pretend that it wasn't already
discussed exactly 40 minutes ago where
the subject wasn't.
Yeah.
The,
you know,
Brian Cowen had a,
an interaction with a guy on the road
once and it was,
it was real weird because I was on
Brian's side because Brian's a great
friend,
but I was also not on the side,
you know,
it's hard.
He worked with some guy and the guy
opened for him and the guy apparently in
the course of like his bombing,
like he wasn't doing so well,
he started talking to the crowd and like
telling the crowd just some shit that
whatever,
just something about like the way they
were reacting or the way the show is
going to be for the rest of it.
It was some non funny thing.
We were just talking to them and Brian
Goes,
what are you doing?
Like why,
why are you just talking to them?
And he goes,
hey man,
that's my time on stage.
He's like,
no,
you're opening up for me and you weird.
And the whole crowd out.
He just like started bombing.
Then he started talking about comedy or
talking about why they're not laughing
at you or whatever the fuck it was.
I don't remember specifically,
but I remember thinking like,
man,
I kind of see both sides part like the
guy sucked,
right?
It wasn't doing well,
but we all sucked at one point in time.
Like how do you not suck?
And that's also how you get past sucking
is to go.
All right,
jokes are off the table.
I'm just going to talk like a regular
human being now.
Sort of maybe your jokes are not funny
about.
I mean there's a bunch of things that
you do,
but you know,
it's weird when a guy tells you not to
do something,
it is in you.
Just like,
oh,
I don't know,
like the only thing that I could see.
It's like what I said earlier,
I'd say if you have your bit about uh,
the Dolphin bit,
like if you had a guy who went on before
you who also did like a super similar
bit about having sex with something like
really similar,
you know,
like a monkey or something like that.
Something smart,
you know,
you can be like super trippy.
Like it would trip you up.
Meaning,
you know,
like if you went up and did your bid,
the whole premise has been kind of
beaten down even if it's a different.
Yeah.
And that's my dolphin bed actually
started as a sex type joke about having
sex with a dolphin and then now it's
nine
has nothing to do with sex,
with adults.
Isn't that interesting how that happens?
It's like when you come up with a bit
like it starts off as like a seed and
then from there it goes off and
sometimes like just a tag line becomes a
totally different branch that becomes a
totally different tree and,
and a lot of the lines come from our
eating didn't get a laugh at first and
then you're trying to save it and then
you're on a totally different page in.
There's just some weirdness in the room.
You went left when you should've went
right and a new line just pops into your
head.
Absolutely.
Whatever weird reason.
That's why I like the act of comedy,
like creating comedy is so it's so
complicated.
There's no,
no one exactly knows where all that
shit's coming from.
It seems like the only consistent thing
that seems to work for me,
because you just got to do a ton of
sets.
Yeah,
it's about.
It's about doing it because like you can
sit there and memorize your bit and
you're like,
it's got to go exactly like this.
You do it exactly like that.
It doesn't go over that well.
Then you start talking,
you start riffing and all of a sudden
all this stuff you just made up on the
spot is way funnier,
way funnier.
Sometimes you need the audience there.
Dick Sandwich sign.
Sometimes it's Dick and poop on bread.
Yeah.
And you just gotta eat it.
You got to eat it like you like it.
So it's kind of get that.
Brian was saying,
Hey,
this guy's bombing out the crowd before
my,
my set.
But then I kinda get that this guy is,
you know,
he's just doing a shit.
That's why I take guys I know with me on
the road.
Absolutely way I know.
I know what already does.
Doesn't know what Brian does.
I know what you know.
We know what everybody does and it's
funny.
So you get to enjoy it,
like I like enjoying the worst is when
you don't like your guy and you're
working with them and then they laugh at
him and you're like,
what happened to this guy?
Or it's like,
yeah,
it's like if they liked this shit,
are they going to like la?
But even if they do,
you're like,
I don't even like you guys saw what you
liked the like awfulness.
One thing that we ran into I last week
in Toronto is all there.
People were really funny but like
getting people that you don't know
thrown up in front of you,
you know,
because it could go really bad and it
could go really good,
you know?
Luckily there was a lot of funny people
in Toronto,
but you know,
we did this one show and this one guy
who opened it up did 10 minutes opening.
He was only supposed to do five and it
was some of the worst comedy you ever.
It's one of those words that guy's
screaming at the eye,
right?
Right.
Guys.
Like,
like trying to make them say yes,
you're right.
All right,
that's fun.
You know,
homeboys in a panic.
Was it angry?
It was just loud,
loud in just inexperienced and just like
the audience just sat there and watched
him,
but he was like trying to get them like,
no,
you have to respond,
respond,
you know,
it was bullying,
bullying,
bullying.
Well you know what it is,
man.
It's just misguided energy.
He's just trying to get a result and
it's just not happening.
So he thinks that he's just really big.
Like people will like watch some standup
and they go,
oh,
I know how to make it.
I know how to do it.
Sure.
I'm going to do with Kevin Hart's House.
I'm just going to do that kind of thing
and we'll just literally try to emulate.
But Kevin Hart's funny is his funny.
He knows how to do that.
Funny.
Like if you try to do that funny it
could fuck you up.
And definitely it'll definitely like
sort of hide what ever real funny is
inside of you.
You'll be trying to be Dane Cook.
You'll be trying to be Steve Byrne,
you know,
whoever it is that you think is funny.
And when you do that,
man,
it can really fuck with your head.
Absolutely.
It takes so many years.
It takes longer and comedy than anything
else.
Right.
Neurosurgery is probably weird.
Comedy,
I think.
I think a bunch of things you do quicker
than or they would take a way longer
time than being able to get a laugh
consistently.
You're right about that,
but doesn't it take most guys like three
years to even be somewhat funny?
Sometimes.
Some didn't really funny out of the
gate,
like with her a couple of years.
Like it depends on how much alcoholics
anonymous they've had up in front of
those people and talk.
How about substitute teaching?
They've done,
do we have guy back in Boston?
A rest his soul.
He's passed since.
But his name is Dave Fitzgerald.
And it was a funny guy,
man.
And he fucking.
He learned how to do stand up completely
from a do an alcoholics anonymous
speeches.
He was a guy who like was longstanding
drunk,
you know,
and then got his shit together.
Started doing stand up at these
meetings.
Started telling us stories and the
stories were fucking hilarious.
His stories of excess and just had a
great delivery and timing.
Yeah.
That fucking guy was a solid
professional like inside of a year.
Nice.
He just,
for whatever reason,
like we were all like marveling at him.
Like the guy used to be a drunk,
but look at how organized he is,
you know,
he's constantly performing and
networking and he got sick.
I don't know whatever happened to the
guy but something,
some cancer or something.
He died.
A couple of guys from Boston were really
funny.
Died of cancer,
but this guy,
my point being that he did something
else,
like if you do something else,
like some guys like uh,
like your buddy was in bands.
I'm Dean Delray,
Dean del.
Right,
right.
And like being on stage all the time and
being in bands.
He had a point about that.
It's like kind of understand what it's
like to be on stage so that,
that part of it is not as difficult.
Right.
Yeah.
I mean he jumped into it pretty quick,
you know what I mean?
He started,
I don't know,
like five,
six years ago,
but he had been in a band for 25 years
and he toured with some of some major
acts.
Yeah.
Uh,
so yeah,
he,
I mean I used to do open mic him at the
beginning
and he jumped right into it.
Well,
they've got to get him on.
He's got some funny stories.
I saw him on his podcast.
It was really funny because he's toured
with bands for what,
like decades,
right?
He's got a story.
We'll go to the Dama rare one.
He's got a student,
don't go to it now,
but I mean if people listening to this
go to the dom irrera podcasts and he's
got the story about,
I think it's Joe Walsh shitting his
pants on stage.
They put waiters on because they were
gonna fire him.
Like he really did have diarrhea,
but he was such a mess.
He was constantly missing shows and
Shit.
So they were like,
dude,
if you do this,
they're going to fucking sue you like
you,
you got to perform.
So he put fishing waders on it.
Just shit his pants while he was onstage
and it's,
it's dean.
Dean does a great job telling the story.
It's really,
really fucking funny and it's a good
podcast.
So Dom irrera has a live from the laugh
factory with dom irrera and can't say
enough things about dom.
Check it out.
Shit.
I love that guy.
He's just so classic.
He's the man.
He's so classic.
He was always funny and in,
you know,
when he's at his best in situations like
Thunderpussy,
you know,
like when he was judging Thunderpussy Oh
my God,
he's a murderer.
He killed Tony.
Tony.
Oh,
United States on diversity yet you don't
judge thunderpussy killed Tony,
you know the,
the one with the cliffs obviously.
But he's so fucking funny on it.
The one he and I did,
it was just so good.
He's such a cool,
like I love a classic standup comic book
that with the attitude and the authority
and just the jokes and the whole deal,
the whole deal,
the whole deal just loved that car.
So,
uh,
you know,
I saw him the other day to joey was
there the other day at the comedy store
too.
It just felt great.
It felt great to just be there.
It's weird.
I was watching the uh,
I was watching the youtubes last night
with you fight and hosting the show
tonight.
That would be hilarious.
I almost asked you should ask.
I think if that would've been,
it would've been the funny shit of all
time and say yet I was actually on that
show that night.
I opened up the show that you really
have 2007.
It was a 2007,
I believe it was February or something.
Yeah.
I still have the seven page letter that
crazy sent me from the comedy store.
So did you get in trouble with the
comedy store after that?
A little bit or something like that.
What exactly did they say?
It's a long story.
A guy behind it is gone.
Gotcha.
It's all,
it's different there.
I went there the other night too,
man.
And when he was filming a special,
I plopped myself down next to polly and
I almost shit myself because people were
like,
dude,
go look inside this room right now.
And I look over and I'm like,
what?
Joe?
And polly's sitting there talking,
well I looked at him like,
I don't have a problem with this dude.
Go be friendly with this dude.
I just sat down next time I shook his
hand and we had a nice little
conversation.
We have a nice little conversation about
how happy he was that he was doing the
special in the original room.
Really cool.
And I was like,
yeah,
I mean it's a classic room and you know.
And Paula was like,
yeah.
And he's so comfortable here.
Like he was a nice little conversation
we had.
So it was good.
Yeah,
he's very.
A poly is very matured now.
It seems like the more I lately
I think it's totally unfair to judge,
judge,
judge anybody based on who they were.
And then you kind of know who they are.
But to say that that's who you are that
defines you right now in this current
moment.
It's pretty unfair,
so I,
I try not to do it as much as possible,
but there's,
you know,
there's obviously exceptions like Ted
Bundy was out.
I'd probably have to kill.
I'm sure.
You know what I'm saying?
Like the certain dudes like you can't
get away with what you can't cut women's
pussies out and put them on your head
and some things you can't shake on
photos and then you get out of jail.
And then I'm gonna yeah,
you did that in the past.
We're going to judge you on that.
We're going to hold you to that which is
going to end it for you.
But,
but you know,
there's,
there's people that you become enemies
with that.
It's almost like getting a pattern of
remaining their enemy.
So it's like,
and that was never enemies with poly
entries had been been CEO.
Never really enemies with poly.
But you get into this sort of a thing
where it's,
this is just what we do.
You know,
we can't just let it go.
Like I fucking hate that fucking guy.
What he tried to do to me and fucking
this and that.
And then he turned around when the shit
goes on for like years and years where
you think the echoes of one conversation
or the echoes of one interaction can
remain with you for your whole life just
because you choose it,
that person remains your enemy.
You put so much vested interest in
energy into it's a complete waste.
And if you can just,
whenever you have like these little
conflicts with people just as many times
as possible,
resolve them.
Absolutely.
You'd be amazed at the psychic weight
that's lifted off your soul when you do
that.
I think you're in a really negative
space every time you think about that.
Totally.
Yeah,
totally.
Yeah.
People that you have,
like there's.
There's some conflict in life that it's
unnecessarily necessary.
You know,
it's necessary,
but it's unnecessary in the sense that
if we were all living in Utopia,
if we all had our shit together,
if everybody was cool and balanced,
it wouldn't be taking place.
But the vast majority of conflict
wouldn't be taken place.
Because if you really think about how
many people there are on earth and think
about how little actual conflict or is
everybody was always wants to dwell on
the horrible aspects of our current
existence.
They won't get Iraq and Afghanistan and
murder and crime and a woman walked down
New York City Street for 10 hours and
all she got was met at wanted to fuck
her.
You know,
I understand that.
That's an issue.
I do understand.
Look,
I have daughters.
I have a mom.
I don't want anybody feeling harassed by
a bunch of apes shares because some
dudes like,
Yo,
I got some.
I got a picture on my wall.
I think I've told,
talked about it before,
but it's for like 1951.
It's an American woman in uh,
in Italy and she's walking down the
street.
Have you ever seen it?
It's a classic image of it's huge
picture and it's these guys from like
1940 or whatever the fuck it is.
And they're holding a dick.
Say,
hey,
with this fucking broad,
oh,
I ripped us congee,
Lo va with a fucking piece of this.
And this is like,
I used to think that people were like
fucking father knows best back then.
Well,
you know,
I,
I heard that.
I mean obviously those guys actually
acted like that.
But I read that that photo was somewhat
staged in that they did a couple takes
of it.
No.
And they knew they were going to get the
picture.
They knew they were going to get it.
Dude,
that's reality TV.
And in 1951 or whatever it was,
what year is it,
Brian?
Does it say I'd love that picture.
She knew the photographers and they set
that up kind of.
I mean,
even though they're actually really a
boss yelling at her,
those are really,
that's real.
That's my people.
That's my ancestors.
Savaging monkey folk.
They're savage monkey folk.
I'm allowed to say that because I'm
Italian.
I'm glad that I'm Italian because I
could shit on an Italian behavior.
Some Italian behavior.
Nineteen 51 and 51 and their animals
look at them.
But Tony Hinchcliffe,
you know the woman walking down the
streets in New York,
some of it they should've just not left
in the video because it really fuck with
their point because some of it was like,
God bless you.
Beautiful Day.
You look beautiful.
Some of them,
I mean,
come on,
people meet each other.
What they,
what,
what bothered me a lot,
which is one guy who stood next to her
and kept walking with.
That guy was a creep.
Yeah,
because a piece of shit.
There was a couple of guys that were
real legit piece of shit and that I
think should have been highlighted in
that video that these guys are out there
and that a girl could get,
you know,
your wife,
your girl,
your mom stuck next to some asshole
who's creeping on her.
That was real.
But you know,
hey,
beautiful.
Bless you.
I got a lot of shit because I said I
just tweeted that video when it came out
and I said,
God,
this has to be annoying.
Because I was thinking if it was me just
trying to walk down the street for me,
that would drive me crazy.
Just be able to high five the dues and
keep walking,
stick their penis inside you and
ejaculate.
I don't want any interaction with people
that I don't know.
How great would it be?
What are you doing?
Why are you doing shows and why you're
doing a podcast show because these
people know me more than anyone telling
me no.
In real life.
You wouldn't like to walk down the
street and have girls try to fuck you
all day long.
No.
Hold up.
These people know you more than anybody
in real life.
You mean people listen to the podcast.
People that listen to the podcast know
me more than like my friends back home
in Ohio.
Well,
they listen to the podcast or my sister
because these people know hours and
hours and years and years of almost a
biography of all this is the last place
you want people to judge you on.
This podcast is literally
last place on earth,
right?
You should have like,
this is basically me,
like someone like a smash house made a
compilation of you,
like if you're confused as to who Brian
is,
watch this.
Those
guys are walking down the street that
has to be running at you.
Asking questions.
Hey,
do you believe in evolution wire black
Dick.
So much more delicious.
Brian didn't take it.
Take it.
This is how I am.
If I were to imagine my sister walking
down the street and this happened to my
sister nonstop,
I would be pissed off if all these guys
are pretty much just like,
you know like hawks in a wounded animal,
you know?
Well some of them,
but some of them were like,
Hey,
beautiful.
I like she would walk by,
Hey,
beautiful.
Right?
And here's something that someone told
me online them I read this.
Someone was saying that they have a
friend who's a girl who's from South
America and in South America.
Women like it.
Yeah,
we will be upset if they made cat calls
the illegal what?
Girls like it when they walk down the
street and guys talk,
Hey baby,
what's up baby?
Because their butts or swallow,
they're wanting to make it
in estrus.
I'm not.
I don't think that's the issue.
I think the issue is that they,
it's a different culture and that our
culture is becoming hypersensitive,
acutely aware of sexual assault and rape
and they,
they connect every single act of.
I won't even say aggression,
but like enthusiastic courting,
like on the street,
like even an unrealistic like Yo baby
won't come park that shit on my face.
Is that ever worked ever backed up and
just planted her ass on dude's face when
he said that?
Probably.
Yeah.
No it works though.
Probably as your horn honk every.
That's how my parents met.
You could honk your horn,
you could yell out the window.
All that stuff is valid.
Do you remember checks out?
Do you remember?
Like a year ago I told you that I was
trying an experiment where I would add
lights out,
like honk the horn and be like hey,
what's up?
What's up kitty?
And like talk to people and cars and it
was really uncomfortable to do what
would happen and it really was girl just
sitting there like,
don't look,
don't look over.
And that's what I feel like that,
you know,
like even if you say,
Hey,
beautiful,
hey,
beautiful girls are like,
come on man.
Like,
like,
leave me alone.
I'm just trying to walk for the most
part.
I,
most girls,
the reality of being a woman,
but don't women,
uh,
accept or love aggressiveness on some
level.
Maybe like a subtle aggressive because
they don't like to do that.
That's not guys they liked though women,
I
can appreciate a certain amount of
aggression from a person that they like
and trust,
but a certain amount of aggression like
that kind of an aggression.
Sure.
The average person,
obviously there's going to be with women
and no one likes to say this.
There's going to be women that have rape
fantasies.
There's men who have rape fantasies.
Men who have rape fantasies of them
being raped.
There's everybody,
there's.
Everybody has their own kink share now.
So there are some people that have like,
maybe they have fantasies,
like have you ever see that?
Louis ck jokes got a great joke about
that,
about how we made out with this girl
and tried to push it and she said no.
And so he stopped and then the next day
she's like,
what happened last night?
And he said what?
And she goes,
I thought you were just going to go for
it.
And he's like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
She was like,
I was hoping you were just going to go
for it.
He goes,
what do you think I'm going to take a
chance on the off chance that you're
into it.
I'd be really into rape.
It's a really funny bit,
but it's like there are.
Those people do exist.
Absolutely.
But that said,
the majority of women don't want to be
cat called when they walked on the
street.
But this.
There's a difference between like some
of what we saw on that video and some of
what you're just going to get when you
pass by a group of men.
Right.
You know there's going to be a group of
men that go,
God damn,
even if they don't look at you,
if you're hot and you walked by men,
they'll go cheat us is what is that?
Is that.
Is that cat calling?
Is that bad?
I don't know.
But if you're wearing a fucking tiny
miniskirt that's just clinging to your
ass and you have high heels on and you
smelled like the nectar of the Gods and
you're walking past a group of men and
there's more than two guys.
Yeah,
we're going to curse.
One guy is probably gonna.
Keep talking about shut.
Yeah.
There's something that happens when we
get in packs of apes where it's almost
like if you get over it exponentially
gets more likely that someone's going to
say something or three almost.
And a lot of it is men trying to make
each other laugh.
You know?
A lot of it is not even like trying to
pick up the girl.
It's certainly not being considered the
girl's feelings,
but a lot of is like,
Jesus,
what I would do to that,
you know,
and people fall down laughing or we make
each other laugh,
but there's a victim in that column.
We're to feel like shit.
I just curse quietly to myself.
I can't help.
I'm just gonna come kind of like that.
That's quieter.
Yeah.
You know,
just go Jesus Christ,
but it's in A.
I know it's positive,
but I keep it to myself because I don't
like to make people feel uncomfortable.
Yeah.
Problem is,
isn't like there's five or six guys
around.
That's when it gets uncomfortable and
that's what you saw.
Like even like two or three when you
saw,
when you saw like a lot of what she's
getting catcalled it was dudes like
almost making each other laugh as they
were doing it as like passing the comedy
store on sunset.
If you're,
you know,
all the comics are sitting there on the
patio.
Anytime a girl walks by like a mini
dress.
It's just kind of what did you just do?
You're going to do social justice
warriors going to be out on sunset,
going to strap a camera to the most
attractive woman.
They could find the best.
The best looking one is passed back and
forth.
Nothing.
That's a game show or that show right
there.
Just go back and forth at the comedy.
We should make a show called I'm
offended and just get offended at
virtually everything.
You see the fucking latest thing.
I tweeted this today,
and this is.
This is not bullshit.
This is actually real.
There is a Portland,
Oregon teacher that is against peanut
butter and jelly sandwiches because she
says they're inherently racist.
That's peanut butter and jelly getting
along post.
Okay.
Peanut butter and Jelly Racist
Portland school principal tie sandwich
to white privilege.
This is where we are,
ladies and gentlemen in 2000 and fucking
14.
They're saying black people can't afford
it.
Oh Man,
I don't even.
I mean,
I don't know why my trash isn't it?
Peanut butter and Jelly.
Okay.
Super White.
What about Somali or Hispanic students
who might not eat sandwiches?
You?
Tara says according to the Tribune.
Another way would be to say Americans
eat peanut butter and jelly.
Do you have anything like that?
Let me tell you.
Maybe they eat torta or Peta.
Ugh,
what the fuck is going on?
What the fuck is going on in this
country?
For Real?
It's just a god peanut butter and Jelly
Sandwich.
There's not even any meat in it.
You can't even get Vegan pissed.
I really think that what's.
I mean,
this is going to sound completely crazy,
but I really think that what's going on
when we're becoming more and more
hypersensitive and more and more aware
of like these little things that don't
mean a goddamn thing and focusing on
them and spending all this energy while
you have this finite amount of time in
life.
I think people,
especially as we get older,
our fucking terrified of death were
terrified of death,
of death,
of the planet,
of our children,
death of our friend's death,
of our loved ones,
and as it,
as things move on,
we concentrate more and more a
nonsensical minutia more and more on
Pulse Shit,
more stupidity and it just,
it gets more and more ridiculous and
even intelligent people if that's the
creepiest thing about these social
justice warrior folks that are just.
Some of them are just completely out to
lunch on some shit,
but one of the things about them is
they're almost all well read,
almost all articulate,
almost all intelligent be at the
beginning completely roped up and this
nonsense like wha,
what do they call outs and the doxing
and they're just spending all their time
online going after perceived slights and
some of it is legit.
Like this bill cosby Shit,
right?
That's legit,
but some of it is like peanut butter and
Jelly.
Fucking sandwiches are racist.
Like,
Oh,
what?
What are you doing?
You're an adult.
Couldn't be any less important.
You're not even an issue.
You're making up an issue now.
I think you're right.
You're,
you're definitely avoiding your more
complicated thoughts when you start
bringing trivia into your fucking brain.
Complete total trivia and I also think
that.
I think it's just super bad for your
brain.
It's super bad for your brain to
concentrate too much on.
Well,
especially if especially if it's making
you angry because then you're just
sitting in a chair anger,
angry,
and it's like you need to use that
energy in other ways.
You know?
I mean,
it's just that basic primal like ready
to fight feeling,
but you're just sitting in a chair.
You don't put that energy anywhere,
so it's bad for your body to.
I've been paying attention to a lot of
people's twitters lately,
like watching people that get into
consistent twitter,
twitter wars,
and you just look at them.
You're like this person sleeping four
hours a night madness.
It's the whole lifestyle.
They're fighting with strangers too.
There's a lot of people that are like
living in front of the computer saying
shit,
waiting for someone to respond and then
saying something back.
Like sometimes it's a tweet,
something mean to me,
I'll just go to their site and see what
they do and it's like all mean tweets to
to other people,
to everybody responds and they always
have about 13 followers and you just
gotTa let it go.
Even if you have a good comeback,
you got to let it go.
Otherwise you're in a twitter fight in
public.
I don't care if they have hundreds of
thousands of followers.
It's still the same thing.
What do you.
What are you doing?
You know,
like it's,
it's one thing if there's something
legitimate,
if there's something legitimate,
vast majority of these discussions.
Have you paid any attention to Gamer
Gate?
You know what Gamergate is?
What's said about fucking completely
baffled.
Yeah.
I backed out like I did when those
things were.
I walked in and he's like,
yeah,
well I definitely care,
but I think it's,
it's so confusing.
There's so many sides to it for this is
the idea behind it.
The idea is ethics in journalism on one
side,
that's what they're saying.
Ethics in game journalism and the other
side is saying it's really about
harassing women and that this,
this woman who they initially went
after,
like,
uh,
you know,
who gives a shit and what's the big deal
and she's just a game designer.
Apparently she slept with some guy's.
I'm butchering this story.
I've heard a little bit about this,
the worst part of it,
the absolute worst part,
but was all the death threats and all
the negative people speak.
This is feminist chick and Anna,
I think analysts are keys.
Anything thunder foot as a bunch of
hilarious videos on her,
but whatever's her,
her idea is that she's trying to promote
gender,
not just um,
I wouldn't say like equality and gains,
but she just wants to discourage
stereotypes and she wants cheese showing
that there's some aspects of video games
that show women as objects like,
you know,
like the fucking what is the vice grand
theft auto,
grand theft auto game.
There's a lot of bad shit.
Well,
I don't think she's necessarily saying
censor it.
I think she wants people to be aware of
it.
You know,
and again,
I'm trying to be super open minded on
all this stuff,
but the worst aspects of it for sure,
or the death threats,
sure,
but this is where it gets really crazy.
Some people believe this is the
conspiracy theory.
Of course,
some people believe that some of these
in fact death threats or some of these
threats aren't real.
That what they're doing is trying to
discredit the gamergate movement by
making it out.
That there are all these massages and
creeps,
so then these other people that are
involved in Gamergate started this thing
calling not your Hashtag,
not your shield and it's all people of
color or women.
All these people who support ethics in
game journalism who think this whole
issue is getting sort of misconstrued
and distorted and twisted,
but it's so.
It's so convoluted and multi-sided.
I think both sides have some sort of a
point for sure,
but I don't want an involved like deeply
in video games,
but I think what they're trying to do is
they're trying to discourage this
extreme left from taking over from
controlling the narrative from like
saying that all video gamers are
misogynists.
All video gamers are assholes and I
think for a lot of these guys,
they're super socially awkward.
Yeah.
A lot of video gamers,
they,
you know,
they're,
they're online all the time,
like it's a big percentage of their
social life.
I know this because I used to be in a
fucking quake clan and I used to hang
out with these dudes,
like we used to get together and have
land parties.
I had dudes come over my house man when
I was on TV.
Yeah,
I met dudes online.
Yeah.
They all came over to my house and we
had a fucking land party,
you know,
I was a super dork.
I used to make my own computers.
I would go down to fry's electronics and
buy a motherboard and a case.
Fuck yeah.
Put the ad.
The hard drives,
the whole deal.
My friend Andrew would talk me through
it when shit would go bad,
but for the most part I kind of figured
it out.
Andrew,
who developed my website?
Yeah,
menthol.
Yeah.
Fucking jumpers.
Jumpers,
like one little jumper could make the
whole computer work or not work.
It's like a Christmas light.
And this was guys that were like,
there were like overclocking.
They went over clock.
They would get these,
these,
uh,
these cpas that weren't as strong like
the seller.
Ron's memory,
those celeron processors.
You can get a 300 Celeron and you could
jack that sucker up to like four,
25 and guys would put like extra fans
and shit and he'd blow cold air on it.
Yeah.
They were just trying to like.
And so I was involved in this culture.
Like this is not,
I'm not talking out of my ass when I
talk about these guys.
And for a lot of these guys,
they're,
they're very,
they're very sexually inexperienced.
Some of them,
you know,
some of them are there shut-ins a lot of
ways.
They don't go out and they don't,
they don't meet a lot in.
So like this idea that they're,
you know,
objectifying women in these,
in these video games,
I see your point,
but if you look at the people that are
watching these things and playing these
games,
if you really want to think,
I don't,
I don't think you can make a real
argument that it's affecting their
behavior and making them go out and
assault and rape and others.
They're very shy.
People that aren't aggressive in the
least.
I don't mean that's a huge.
I mean that's a huge generalization.
Obviously I've made a generalization,
but I think that it becomes an issue of
you can be a really good person who
doesn't have any malice towards any sex,
any gender,
any orientation.
A huge could be just non-racist,
normal,
cool person and enjoy playing some
fucking crazy game.
We will,
you a,
you can smack a girl.
You know,
there's a game when you're in a fight
and you're shooting guns at people and
you know,
every now and then a girl comes out,
you screaming at a time the pimp slap
swatter,
right?
And then you get a 10,
like 10 shows up,
like you can really catch her perfect
with the pimp.
Slap this.
Not a real person.
I know.
It's no,
it'd be terrible to actually slap a
woman in the face.
It would be terrible.
One of the worst things you could do,
but I really think that you can do that
game where you can slap a cartoon,
women in the face and you're not a bad
person.
I mean,
could it.
Because it's fantasy.
It's just like when you watch a movie,
like think of any number of movies that
have,
have horrible scenes where women get
beat up.
Or how about that fucking.
I'm the Quentin Tarantino movie.
True Romance.
Perfect example.
That was um,
James James Gandolfini and applegate,
our cat,
our cat.
Patricia Arquette,
right?
Yeah.
Fuck too.
It's tough to watch.
Oh my God.
He beats the shit out of her and she
eventually kills them.
Yeah,
but I mean he's beating the shit out of
it and you're watching it,
man.
You're watching this fucking movie.
Are you controlling it?
No,
but you're watching a movie that's
depicting a horrific scene that could
possibly happen now.
I guess you could say that it's
different if you're playing a game
because then you're an objector.
You have an objective,
you know you're.
You're accomplishing something,
and if this is a part of your objective
is that you get to slap girls.
I could see how that could be kind of
fucked up,
but all of it is fantasy.
I know.
And if you're a good person,
I think the real issue is how much to
games or any media for that matter,
how much they actually affect the way we
behave and how much of it is how our
parents raised us and the environment
that we lived in.
The actual real human friendships that
we had.
How much of is that?
All I know is I've smacked the girl in
the video game but never in real life
and I and I don't intend to,
and that real life,
unless it girl smacked you really
fucking hard and really got your Irish
up.
My Irish ego driven this flash.
Hm.
Um,
yeah.
Look,
that was the argument when that dude
knocked the girl out in the elevator.
What was his name?
The football player,
Shawn Ray Rice Ray Rice,
who uh,
his girlfriend cracked him or his
fiance,
whatever she is.
And then he left,
hooked her and knocked her unconscious.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's fucked up.
But is he right handed?
It doesn't matter because it was a short
left hook because very good punch punch.
But the point being like,
yeah,
absolutely.
It's way fucked up to knock someone out.
That's your wife or you know,
anybody like that.
Especially a woman.
Like you couldn't control her in some
other way.
However,
she shouldn't have had him either.
Right?
She shouldn't have hit him and no one's
saying she shouldn't have hit him
saying,
hey,
you crazy bitch.
Why'd you hit ray rice?
It's almost like because of what he did
to her in response to what she did,
she doesn't get blamed for what she did.
Right.
So if there was a video where she just
punched him in the face in an elevator
and then they left,
do you think there would be this giant
outrage where everybody was like ray
rice got assaulted by his wife?
That woman is a terrible person.
She needs to be in jail with.
Is it based?
Is it the action I've seen this is the
action or is it based on how much damage
you actually do with what you've,
what your action is?
You know what I'm saying?
Like if this woman is hitting this guy
and then he smacks her in the face.
This is,
take this off.
I don't want to watch a shit.
Um,
what,
but,
but look,
both people did the same thing.
It's just one person was better at it
and one person actually started,
right?
I mean,
yeah,
it's more fucked up because he's a
powerful man.
He's a professional athlete.
He obviously knocked completely
unconscious.
It,
a whole lot of brain trauma there.
She could have died all the about me.
She fucking clanged her head off.
That bar handlebars was playing.
I mean,
she was out.
Do was one of the worst knockouts.
I've seen it.
I've seen a lot of people get knocked
out.
That was a bad doc out,
but no one is saying she's a bad person
for hitting him.
Yeah.
I haven't heard it once,
but yeah,
but it's not cool.
No,
that's what.
No one's supposed to hit anybody.
Yeah.
Right.
And you definitely shouldn't hit a
fucking super athlete and a small space.
I wouldn't do that.
I mean,
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
It's not good that he hit her for sure.
But you're also dealing with dudes.
You know,
I talked to Michael Irvin about this
once and Michael Irvin works with a lot
of young kids that are coming up that
um,
you know,
have been in impoverished situations
growing up and they've had a lot of
violence in the family and he was saying
that your body just gets when you're
young,
especially when you're going through the
womb,
when your mother is going through a
tremendous amount of stress,
your body gets almost designed to react
instantaneously and make poor choices
like your body almost as response just
so shellshocked that your body's
designed to like it's set up to deal
with the trauma of a bad neighborhood
really.
And it's based on when you're still in
the womb.
So based on the stress that your mother
experienced as well,
she's got you in her womb,
Jesus Christ,
crazy shit.
And so you make worse decisions based on
that.
You,
you follow your instincts,
follow your instincts.
You become more aggressive and violent
and more aggressive and violent.
A lot of times leads to poor thinking,
poor,
poor planning.
And you know,
he was saying that this is what a lot of
these guys are dealing with a lot of
these nfl players,
but a lot of young athletes,
it's like they were literally program
different than people that grew up in a
nice house with a nice family,
nice environment.
Like they're literally hardwired in a
different way because your brain thinks,
okay,
well this is the game we're playing.
We're not playing pokemon.
We're going to go ahead and we're going
to play fucking aliens vs Predator and
I'm low on armor and it's best to act
quick before you're in trouble.
Yeah.
So when you see a guy like ray rice
clock,
a chick like that,
literally that guy might not even be
able to control that kind of a thing.
Right?
I'm not giving him a free pass at all.
What he did was totally fucked up.
I would've never done it.
But when you're dealing with head
trauma,
major head trauma,
that guy has been hit who knows how many
times throughout high school,
College.
And in the pros,
I mean he has collided with some giant
men.
Yeah,
there is a hundred percent likelihood of
head trauma going on there.
One hundred percent percent.
Then you punch him,
you know,
and who knows
how much control he has over that
switch.
You would like to say,
well me Matt,
the full charge,
I have full control of my situation,
but I don't claim to know what it's like
to operate his body and mind.
I definitely don't.
Or hers.
Why did she punch him?
I wouldn't have praised them.
Bitch woman.
Crazy.
I don't know.
I mean who knows?
Maybe he did something but we didn't see
before that,
but it's just craziness and should be
avoided at all costs and definitely
don't get married to somebody that that
happened with the to the fence or unless
you really both don't ever do it again.
I mean,
is that possible?
Again?
Can people grow and learn and so this,
this is beyond say sister is the head.
This was no,
so it doesn't really different story.
You son of a bitch,
you're racist.
He's a totally different groups of black
people.
Say sister started hitting Jay Z.
Okay.
Yeah,
that's what I thought.
Who knows what?
Yeah,
I get it.
Mixed.
Jay Z just dealt with it like a year.
He threw money at it.
It should have not a fifth should
fucking thrown diamonds on the ground.
So she slipped.
Isn't it funny what pitches we are.
We get a fascinating.
What do you think he said?
She said to him exactly what you're
talking about.
So worried,
worried about death and obscurity.
Worried about space.
Worried about the fact that we're
floating around.
They landed A.
Oh,
here's a great story.
They landed a fucking comment.
They landed on a comet and uh,
the guy who landed on the comet was
wearing a shirt that had all these
photos,
are these drawings of women on it and
land on a comment.
They landed a drone on a comment.
It says,
I don't care if you landed on
spacecraft,
landed a spacecraft.
I'll say it again.
I don't care if you land a space craft
on a comet,
your shirt is sexist and ostracizing.
I'm not kidding.
This is where our world is today.
Pull this up,
Brian.
Pull,
pull it up,
pull it up.
Um,
it's on my twitter feed.
I retweeted it,
but here's the title is I don't care if
you landed on ace 11,
landed a spacecraft on a comment.
Your shirt is sexist and ostracizing.
It's just God damn a beautiful
representation by the way,
the shirt is designed by a woman.
And who said that?
Who said that to him?
That's an article.
There was an article.
Yeah.
I mean it's just a social justice
warrior status.
That is funny about the Internet is that
everyone has.
Everyone has a voice,
but the bad thing is everyone has a
voice.
Yeah.
Look at this carefully and is fucking
beautiful.
That's beautiful.
And it's just women in scantily clad
outfits.
Now,
here's my question.
This is,
we're willing to get real with this.
When you see,
um,
maybe there's a better picture of it,
but we can get a close up look at his
face,
look at his,
find his name and find a shirt.
I'm sure there's some closeup photos of
it because there's a big event that they
had and this guy chose to wear this
shirt and everybody's freaking out that
he chose to wear the shirt.
Um,
and you know,
people are saying,
yeah,
they wonder why women aren't accepted in
science and I don't even know that
that's true.
How much or how hard it is for women to
get into science or how easy it is.
I really don't know.
So I'm not going to be talking out of my
ass,
but look it.
There it is.
You can see the picture and it's just
women in lingerie and fetish outfits.
Comic Book.
It looks like wonder woman in.
Well,
no,
I wouldn't say that.
I mean that chick has like a skin tight
leather core set and I can just now make
it out though.
You know,
it's not like,
it seems like kind of cosmic too,
right?
What is that a son behind that one
chick?
Yeah.
It looks like Superhero.
Other planets involved in there.
I don't know what it is.
You should be able to wear a shirt.
One of those of like someone's killing
children are those online and I'll wear
it for the next podcast.
You can order a bunch of them,
find it,
find out who makes it online,
what's where I'm willing to make the
guests.
Were it for a week at your hazing?
Well,
you know,
I don't know if a woman makes it,
how it could be sexist.
Well,
I guess it could be if you were.
It was sexist intentions,
but for some women it's not sexist at
all.
For some women it's just sexy women in
seductive poses.
Like would you think that it would be
sexist if a woman had like Chippendale's
dudes all over her shirt?
I wouldn't get upset about it and I
don't think it's either.
Maybe I wouldn't even necessarily think
she was a horny chick.
Well,
if the dicks route that's a different
story had their dicks out and they were
holding onto him like,
like shotguns,
you can't ignore dicks that events.
That wouldn't.
I wouldn't be mad.
I wouldn't say that shirt,
sexist.
I wouldn't be upset at all.
So is the object objectification of men?
Is that acceptable?
But the objective,
it is acceptable.
Everyone's fine with that.
Do you see what's going on?
Man?
You're going crazy,
the world's going to go a little crazy,
but there there is a double standard
with the sexes and I think it has a lot
to do with that.
Like you know when men are the
aggressors,
of course.
And that's the difference.
Yeah,
and when we,
when we get raped,
nobody cares.
No one cares that it's a joke photo.
It's a big joke,
you know,
that I put up the other day of this dude
who was blacked out in these three girls
with bikinis or climbing all over him
and the caption was captured,
was poorly spelled,
but it was something like a,
you know,
how different would it be if the sexes
were reversed?
Yeah.
In this particular photo blacked out.
You almost go to jail just for that
photo.
You know,
even if it was an overweight woman that
was blacked out and a bunch of guys that
were like studly,
every woman wants to fuck guys still.
It still be a creepy photo.
Go down as harassment and borderline sex
crime.
Why are they giving this guy a hard time
for his fucking shirt?
They sit,
let them.
God Damn bought on a comment.
Let them have.
Can you land a robot on the comment I
didn't even know was possible.
I wish a hundred miles an hour.
I wish his reaction though when she said
that to him,
I wish he would just be like,
shut the fuck up and locked away.
But hold on a second.
I don't think someone said anything to
him.
Oh No.
This isn't someone who interviewed him.
This is a review of him doing it.
Yeah.
The girl with the mic doesn't care at
all.
Right.
In the eyes.
I thought this was him going like her
freaking out.
No,
no,
and by the way,
it's by a dude,
the articles written by two and he's
ultimately just trying to get laid to.
That's the funny part.
He is doing what he thinks is right.
Yeah.
You know,
he's,
he's pointing it out.
He thinks it's right.
I mean we could disagree with them all
day.
I don't know.
I don't think it's a big deal,
but I also think people are so fucking
hung up on bodies,
man.
People are really hung up on the use of
people's bodies and imagery and you
know,
comic book depictions of bodies and it's
primarily a female issue,
primarily of objectification of female
issue.
Like if a guy showed up at work and he
had a bunch of male bodies,
just like really yolked superhero male
bodies all over his shirt,
it would just be hilarious.
It will be fine.
It would be,
it would be funny.
But if he shows up with these,
these looking at these women in these
photos are these,
uh,
these images on a shirt,
they're just all like perfect specimen.
Like,
yeah,
cartoonish looking characters.
I just sent you a link to buy the shirt.
I don't want to say it out loud so they
won't sell out.
Don't sell out there.
Fifty $9.
I'll take it.
Go Up to seven xl.
That's actually cut to layer it with a
fat shaming version.
That's what it is.
You know,
it's just,
uh,
a bunch of people that think those
images look good.
Is it sexist?
What,
what is that?
Because of sexless Matt.
Uh,
what is sexy exactly is sexist is when
you,
I think discriminator treat people
differently based on their sex or the
way they look.
All right,
so is having a shirt with a bunch of
pretty women on it like that.
Is that objectifying women?
Kind of,
right?
Um,
to some degree.
But if you're asking me,
I don't find it offensive ones.
One bit assurance.
God Damn Glorious.
I can't wait for it to arrive.
We can make our own shirts and Brian
Cowen,
that's me in the lower right hand
corner.
When you're 21,
you're right.
It is funny.
When there's naked guys.
Foley,
if you went to the gym in the middle,
man literally is kind of funny.
If you had that uninsured,
I don't,
it wouldn't really bug me.
No,
there'll be no blogs about it.
Oh see that's type t t e a.
Why is this a tea?
Is that a t shirt?
This is a fabric.
So we can make our own clothes.
We should make our,
all of our clothes bedsheets out of
that.
I should hire like a real shower.
Expensive.
Tailored to make me an awesome suit of
the jacket and the pants with a vest,
a tie.
The whole thing will be on the inside of
the vast,
like the ones the UFC made me.
They have like little skull and
crossbones and the sat and we could have
all little dicks.
Yeah.
Little Dicks.
And we're talking about this last night.
Like I want to um,
have a house and have the people trim
their bushes.
Yeah.
I want to cut my bushes in the shape of
a cock and balls.
Yeah.
Just have it all through the,
you know,
the front of the yard.
Just all cock and balls shaped right.
Bushes.
Do you think that would get you in
trouble with the Neighborhood
Association?
Would,
would not like that one.
They know exactly what it is.
It's a Bush.
They,
they would still get pissed window
fucked up and talked about it.
That's what.
Yeah.
Once you're in a neighborhood,
like I'm assuming like if you have
people cutting your bushes that it's a
nice neighborhood.
If they can see that shit,
they feel like they can say shit about
that.
I assume.
What could,
what does that,
Brian,
just this,
this fabric,
a fabric.com
has all these sexual.
That's fantastic.
That's fabric that is sexist,
Brian,
and that's male.
Patriarchy and I'm all bad things.
Wow.
I'm going to write a blog about how
great that is.
How much of it.
I mean,
how much of it is.
Is there a line that ever has to be
drawn?
I mean,
what if you had like tits?
What if,
what if these girls on this shirt,
we're completely naked instead of these.
I mean,
these outfits are tiny.
They're wearing these little corsets and
thongs.
They're acids are hanging out.
If you ask me totally naked,
if you ask me,
it's fine.
I mean it's just,
it's just the body.
But if you're a woman,
okay.
And you're working with a guy and he's
kind of creepy anyway.
Yeah.
But he's got a shirt with naked chicks
all over.
It probably wouldn't like it if I was a
walking hate it.
So that is kind of sexual harassment,
right?
Right.
So if that sexual harassment and you
take it just one step before that,
which is their scantily clad,
it's pretty God damn close to them being
naked step before it.
Got to see how if you were a chick and
you around a guy wearing that,
that would be on the creep tip because
although we would like to compare it to
men,
the problem is like a woman with a,
a bunch of men on her shirt is probably
not going to rape you.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
And it's not even the worst thing in the
world.
If a woman ramps you,
not that most men wearing this shirt
would rape you because most wouldn't.
Right.
But there's a few guys who would rape
you and it only takes one.
Let's face it before just,
you know,
it's a huge inconvenience or they
probably would wear like some Mr Rogers
shit so that you would never see it
coming.
Yeah.
You got to watch out with those guys for
that with the sweater vest sweater.
That's a dead giveaway.
I don't know man.
I just to make a good point,
I would hate to be a chick working in an
office with a dude who was creeping on
me.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Have you ever worked in an office where
chick was creeping on you?
Um,
I can't.
I can't remember a chick creeping on me.
Yeah,
that was definitely flirting and
actually,
yeah.
Now that you mentioned I did hook up
with this,
that I worked at it,
but that seems fun.
That's like voluntary.
It's fun and say Hook Up.
But you hear about the one dude that was
like jizzing in this chick's coffee for
like a year.
Yeah.
That's awful.
And then they caught him.
He admitted he'd been in her coffee for
a year.
That's so great.
How long did it take from an admitted,
whereas he just like bad.
Did it?
Let's find out.
How long was he?
He was just in her coffee for a long
time.
Right.
You would never drink liquids again.
You would never let anyone hands you a
cup of anything ever again.
Fifty percent of women love the taste of
come.
I saw 35 percent.
Actually,
I saw one recently where a guy was
caught on a hidden camera pissing in the
coffee pot.
He was using pis to make coffee.
Yeah.
And uh,
he was,
he was making these guys that he worked
with drinking and everybody was like,
there's something going on here,
man.
This coffee smells weird.
As they install the hidden camera and
you see this guy looking around and
pulling his cock out and pissing in the
fucking coffee client like you to think
of how much of that guy's pissed.
Those dudes drank his coffee.
He's given me a weird buzz man.
I hate to hear shit.
Like that's what happens when you have
to work in an office for 1130,
literally insane.
Thirty four year old Blaine,
Minnesota man is accused of ejaculating
on his coworker's desk and inner office.
You faces two counts of criminal sexual
conduct for that.
Allegedly happened since late February.
There's been checking off on her fucking
death for like six months.
Creep arrested for ejaculate.
Coffee Creek.
That's so non objective journalism.
That's the difference between like the
fucking Internet,
like what you're doing a blog and like
New York Times.
That's why the Internet rules,
because the New York Times could never
have creep ejaculates in women's class.
It would be man.
Yeah,
but the Internet is more accurate.
Man.
Arrested for or allegedly.
Yeah.
This is like how many girls I like
fingering themselves.
Then stirring your iced tea.
Very few.
Like,
I don't know.
Very 70 percent.
Very few.
Yeah.
No,
that never happens.
It probably wouldn't.
It's Kinda happened somewhere.
Someone has done it.
Is that the guy started off guy.
Okay,
now think about that poor bastard life.
Yeah.
How about we show a little empathy
towards him.
If you really get to the moment in your
life where you're jerking off and your
coworkers Coffee Cup dudes are women
that were drinking the juice makes a
lot.
It means a lot.
He has one chicken particular and Jackie
elated coworkers.
Coffee is that.
Oh my God,
she's so prone to jerk off in her
coffin.
You GotTa do what?
You got to get a little on her lip and
she doesn't know his licks it off.
Oh my God.
This is hilarious.
She didn't.
She didn't taste that for a year.
Huh?
She didn't listen to this.
According to the criminal complaint
employee
at,
we don't need to say the names.
Place hardware store called police.
On August 26th saying she thought Lynn,
her coworker was leaving bodily fluids
on her desk.
She told officers that she found Lynn
that afternoon standing in front of her
desk,
back turned to her and his hands near
his crotch.
The worker wasn't sure what Lynn was
doing,
but she told police that he had a deer
in the headlights expression on his face
when he noticed her behind him,
quickly left the room and slammed the
door behind him.
The worker said seconds later,
Lynn came back and told the worker that
he had a question for her,
but for.
Got It.
He then left the area.
The worker told police.
She inspected her desk and found fluid
on the surface dripping onto the floor.
A lot of it had been absorbed into her
hair scrunchy,
which she put into a plastic bag when at
the scene officers collected the coffee
Mug,
coffee and scrunchy the worst told
police that she had been.
She had problems with Lynn for months.
He had allegedly leave his zipper down.
Often it happens so much that the worker
said she threatened to,
uh,
portland if it happened again.
She threatened to report.
And why don't you report them know.
Wow,
this is what happens when you make
people work eight hours a day.
He admitted to ejaculating on his
coworker's desk and coffee on August
26th,
which was his birthday.
Well,
come on.
Give him a pass or leave that the story
flows.
Fucking mean.
Officers.
They arrested that guy on his birthday.
Oh my God.
He said he ejaculated and the coffee
twice in the last six months and a on
her desk four times wiping up the mess
with the scrunchie.
Hmm.
He told police he was attracted to his
coworker and did this to get her to
notice.
And her desk.
Oh,
you also said that he knew it was gross
and wrong.
The complaint states this is,
the world has become a fucking parody.
Do Piano and Jelly sandwiches for racist
dudes jerking off and people's coffee.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
I think it all comes back to what you
said.
Like everyone's just trying to distract
themselves.
Yeah.
You know what?
We're trying to just get over that.
I think living life,
knowing that you're just a part of a
giant mystery,
we don't know how it's going to end.
You know,
how works,
what's going to happen for me to do the
next.
Right.
It's just too much for most people.
You also,
a lot of people are doing things with
their lives that they're not even into
like you got.
Get that guy's not into his job.
Oh yeah,
no doubt.
No doubt.
That's why he's jerking off on desks and
shit.
Exactly.
And so,
you know,
you got to do something for a living and
most people don't get to do what they
want for a living.
Poor bastard,
but,
but way more poor her than poor m.
Oh poor that dudes come twice.
Who would you ever trust again?
Not,
not dudes with their pants down.
Tell you that the fact that she didn't
the first time like report,
it means that she doesn't really care
that she's been drinking.
Come.
No Man,
she still be embarrassing for her,
but if you got caught drinking come,
you'd be like police,
like your boss.
You'd go right to be like,
I don't want to drink.
I think I might be a little embarrassed
to admit that I drank com.
If you found a.
do you know what I mean?
What would you rather do?
Have you found a dude he knew that he
came and your Coffee Cup.
Would you be?
Would you be like,
look man,
you can't do that anymore.
It was at work.
If it was like at a job.
Can we talk about this?
I mean,
would you be like,
Hey,
don't do this anymore.
Would you hit them?
Would you just go immediately to the
authorities?
Like how would you handle it?
I've kissed him on the cheek and go,
you fucked up buddy.
I have no idea.
I think I will report it within the
company and let them take it to the
cops.
Don't you think that a dude coming into
your coffee cup is so extreme that you'd
be real cautious about how you
interacted with them?
I don't think you'd beat his ass.
I'll tell you that.
This is why if a guy came in your crop
and you drank it,
you'd be like,
whoa.
Like what are you doing?
Like,
who?
Who are you man?
I'm like,
are you a fucking serial killer?
Or something like what kind of a person
can jerk off in your coffee and then sit
back and watch as you drink it.
That's like a mentally ill person.
Absolutely.
So you didn't have to think like how you
handled that situation whether or not
you beat their ass.
No violent.
What'd you go?
Then I would take the Coffee Cup and
smashed it over his head.
And then to that man,
if you hit someone with a Coffee Cup,
that's like a fucking deadly weapon.
Yeah.
But if he had to come in my fucking
coffee.
Okay.
But if he had saliva and your coffee,
would you stab them with a broken clock?
Spit.
I would scream at him.
They'd go to the bus.
But comes completely different.
What if your hot cocoa is different?
But if you have to be pretty close Cox
not regular snack,
I would.
It would get violent probably if I.
If it.
What?
Would you rather drink guys?
Louis or a load?
Probably a load because I'm sure it
tastes better.
It tastes better smoke because there's
not one girl that goes.
He's a mediator.
He opens your mouth and spit it.
That should be a fucking new game show.
I should be a new game.
Show me smokers.
Spit in your mouth and see how many
times you can take without swallowing.
Throwing up a smoker,
hooking longyis and spitting in your
mouth and the every.
For every lucky that goes in there,
you get 10 grand.
Yeah,
that'd be fun to train for.
I know that much.
You know why?
Because there's some people with some
serious fucking student loans.
You know like I know a friend who has
$300,000
in student loans.
I bet you could hook loogies in his
mouth for a couple of days.
I would be very tempted this month to do
that,
to play that game.
I hate to tell you,
I don't know if I do it,
but I think about it,
if you could start to think about it.
I'm going to start a business.
I look into some Novacane from my
tongue.
Why?
No Dude,
who,
uh,
he needed money to start a business.
So he went to fucking Iraq,
whereas a mercenary.
Really?
Yeah.
He was in the military and went back and
worked as a contractor a couple of
times.
Did it twice.
He did it just because he needed money.
Does he work for when he does not have
those fucking unmentionable names?
Gotcha.
Crossed.
But uh,
people do anything if they need money.
I know people,
people get to that situation where they
have a serious debt and no way out of
it.
Yeah.
You can split their mouth.
Absolutely.
There's no doubt about it.
Spitting out cum in your mouth.
That's a different game show.
And that's higher stakes.
Well,
that's what God fear factor cancel.
Really?
Yeah.
They had a drink.
Come.
There's a video of it online.
Have you noticed by the way that the
facebook for fear factor just started
posting videos again,
out of nowhere,
they're making all these new clips,
these new fear factor clips with UNM and
it's probably because it was on like a
bunch of those channels like chiller and
all those different things.
It's been on them a few times out of
nowhere.
I'm just getting all these like,
hey,
fear factor page released a new video
that was a ridiculous show.
It's hard to believe that the show was
even real and I was,
I was the host of it.
It was real.
And so did you didn't really audition.
They came to you with that idea up and
running,
right?
Well,
no,
the idea already existed in another
country.
It was called now or never land in the
Netherlands.
In Holland.
And what was your reaction to this show?
I was like,
this is ridiculous.
I really did that,
that it was going to be cancelled
immediately.
I got a whole joke about it.
Yeah.
You know,
used to do on stage.
But um,
I did have to audition for it though.
They had to see how I would interact
with people.
So um,
I went down Hollywood boulevard with a
camera crew and just stuck cameras in
people's faces and start asking them
questions like,
can I ask you a question man?
And they,
you know,
they come over and then I started asking
them like,
what kind of food and just be silly with
them.
So they wanted that baby.
Look at me.
Gorgeous fire dude.
Damn that fear factor on twitter's now a
posting again too weird.
Don't try to get me to do that show
again.
Brian.
Joe,
come on.
You're getting too busy already,
man.
I'll do be doing less of this and I'm
better at this.
What if somebody like live leak bought
the name fear factor in like,
Joe,
we want you to do fear of not doing
anything different.
No.
The only way I would ever do that again
is if they broke the bank.
I mean they'd have to.
I'd have to literally do some shit that
would bankrupt a small foreign country.
Drown you in cash.
I'd have to literally make so much
money,
I would think about like giant hunting
preserves that I could buy,
you know,
like in Colorado by a thousand acres and
set up a fucking solar log cabin and
vibe Brian over for dinner and then hunt
him.
No ever have things like Brian.
Brian's like,
he's like the puppy.
You keep her on the house barks when
Shit's going down.
You don't want to chase him.
So rude.
I had a friend that went to one of
those,
uh,
they have these hunting ranches.
It's really kind of fucked up where they
will let an animal out there,
like which animal do you want to hunt
and what not,
like have a menu and you go and you
point it.
And like this is
one deer that has awesome antlers.
So.
Okay,
let out number a.
So the open the cage and this fucking
thing goes wandering out.
It goes right to the feeder because
there's like a feeder that the deer's
eat from every day and you just sit and
wait in front of the feet or for him to
show up and then you blast them.
Oof,
wow.
I mean look,
I guess that's better than farming.
I guess that's better than just,
you know,
raise their cow houses I guess,
but it's kind of,
I mean the only thing,
I mean it's not a big area either,
so like a couple hundred acres.
It's a pretty small.
I mean it's big for a yard,
but it's not big for where a deer can
get away from you.
Sure.
No,
they just let us fuck her out and you go
looking for them,
but they keep pens.
I was like,
that is one of the craziest things I've
ever heard of in my life and it's
totally legal.
Yeah,
I'm sure it is.
Yeah.
I don't know about all that.
That seems.
It seems like a good way to get antlers.
You know,
if you want to make sure you shoot a
deer with a big giant fucking head of
antlers.
But I mean,
I guess it's what the supermarket,
if somebody wanted to kill you just for
like your teeth,
just to know that you're so crazy.
It's worse than your teeth because you
lose your antlers every year and then
the that baby teeth,
I'll give them to you.
There's a whole thing about collecting
sheds.
Yeah,
like people collect these deer sheds and
one of the things that does is it lets
them know what kind of deer on their
land.
So if you go collect the sheds and you
find these big antlers,
like,
Whoa,
there's a big deer on this land I don't
even know about because a lot of them
they'll,
there'll be like nocturnal,
like especially when there's like
hunting pressure or they think that
there's too many people around.
They bed down during the day and they
only come out and eat at night.
So you don't,
you don't even see them there until you
find these antlers like running around.
So it's worse than that.
Someone would want to kill you for some
shit that you throw away every year.
But then there's the meat,
the meat's delicious.
So sweet potato and garlic,
little semen and coffee to full charge.
You need to wear that fucking shirt with
all the guys on it and go sit in the
corner.
Fuckin terrible,
terrible person shirt.
No.
This shirt with all with all the tax on
it.
Yeah.
We need a name for that shirt.
We should do that.
Like one day where the shirt will get
them tailored.
Would you wear them?
If I got stuff tailored,
I'll wear a cream pie.
Okay.
Try to find the gayest material that you
could find online and we'll bring it to
a tailor and we'll have some suits made
up.
Have you seen David shows?
Butthole hat?
He has a butthole.
Just a butthole.
Aso's Butthole.
Am I speeding?
So there's no cheeks or anything.
It's just the whole.
The butthole.
It's so great.
It's the best part.
That's uncomfortable.
David chose.
Fuck crazy man.
He's fucking crazy.
That's exactly what happens.
Like David chose exactly what happens
when you say,
what would you do if you had all the
fucking money you could ever want?
That's what you would do.
You do exactly what he's doing and on
top of that,
he can still sell those paintings.
He makes for an godly sums of money when
he makes.
It's not like he's not making money.
He,
he sells his paintings were like insane
amounts of money,
but then on top of that,
he's got hundreds of millions of dollars
that came from him painting facebook.
Right.
So,
right.
The whole thing,
he just doesn't give a fuck.
Yeah.
He literally doesn't give a fuck.
He's so crazy.
His shit that he's doing like on his
instagram is so hilarious.
Have you watched any of them?
No,
I gotta I gotTa look into dude,
it's so funny.
It's him and Bobby Lee and they have
this thing called,
one of them is called Han Dynasty and
the other one is,
uh,
what is the other one?
The other one is something about space.
Let me pull it up because it's so
ridiculous.
But he's constantly doing shit
constantly thing.
This is the guy that took stock and
facebook.
This guy.
Yeah.
He's hilarious dude.
And he's awesome as a podcast guest to
you.
Let me find out what the fuck is.
His videos are called,
but they put them up all the time and
they're really ridiculous.
That looks great guys.
A genius.
It's made out of pizza.
The pizza crust.
This is a.
He just recently did this mural that he
posted on his instagram.
Check this out.
How awesome.
That is.
Awesome.
He's a bad motherfucker,
dude.
He's such a good guy too,
man.
He's just like such a sweetheart.
And he's,
he,
he enjoys being shocking and he was a
victim of a lot of people freaking out
about one of his podcasts because he had
said something crazy about how uh,
he got a massage and forced them to suck
his dick forced.
But people got mad at him because he
raped somebody who kind of,
you know,
he exaggerates shit.
It's a girl he actually is dating or has
sex with on a regular basis.
Like his version of the story is not
completely accurate.
Like he,
he leaves out stuff and add stuff to
make it more fucked up because he's,
he's,
he's fucking with you.
Yeah.
You go down until you find this one that
looked good.
Okay.
He's got underwear on his face and him
and Bobby Lee and it's just,
it's so ridiculous.
They're doing all these crazy videos.
Hong Galaxies,
the other one.
There's Hong Dynasty and Hong Galaxy and
he's just having fun.
That's what he's doing.
He's just having fun.
He was on vice for awhile,
but when he did that thing where they're
doing the wrestling girls,
but when he did that thing where he,
uh,
told that story about getting the
massage lady to blow them.
Yeah.
They kicked them off.
Vice.
Really?
Yeah.
He got kicked off the show.
I know a girl that used to write for
advice and she got kicked off for
writing something racist like two years
ago on twitter.
They went through a whole twitter feed.
I should rephrase.
He didn't get kicked off,
but they gave him an option.
The option was get rid of your
instagram.
Get rid of your twitter.
No more social media stuff.
Get rid of your podcasts.
And he was like,
what?
That's what I did my thing.
He spelled it w t two.
It was a fuck outta here.
He pulled out his bank card.
I just want to show you how many Zeros.
There's a lot of Zeros.
Those don't give a fuck points.
This is fuck you money.
So fuck you.
I mean,
I see it.
Nobody's point,
man.
I really do.
That's the real problem with twitter and
blogs is you get one point and even
twitter it's one point and then one
point and then one point.
Then when you know one person back and
you're playing tennis back and forth
with the idea,
it's just an ineffective way to
communicate and resolve things.
Communicating live in person is the only
way.
Yeah.
Everything else is.
It only works if everybody agrees to a
certain series rules and like you
establish that you're going to
communicate with someone the way you
would expect to be communicated with by
then like best case scenario.
I saw you on twitter sticking up for
somebody that was just getting hammered.
Oh,
that was a person who wrote something
bad about me too.
But you were like,
hey look,
we can all have our opinions.
It's all good.
Yeah.
I mean I never said anything shitty to
her.
Yeah,
no,
we,
um,
when we went back and forth on twitter
we were,
we were talking about the actual issue
at hand.
She said a few ad homonym things about
me,
but they weren't anything really bad,
you know,
it was like something about um,
uh,
like what qualifies you to that opinion?
Is it making people eat bugs on fear
factor things along those lines was
like,
okay,
you know,
even if you say something mean to me it
just means I'm going to stop
communicating with you because I know
I'm getting better at this.
Right.
And um,
I know when to engage people when not
to,
but I also know like what I get out of
it,
you know,
what do I get out of it?
I get it,
something out of it.
If we can get a little long and get
through something civilly,
I get something out of it.
I feel good.
Sure.
When I have an interaction with somebody
online and if there's some sort of a
minor disagreement we could end with.
It's all good.
That's cool.
Well thank you very much.
Alright,
cool man.
Nice.
I liked that.
So I go towards that as much as I can in
this life and I've made mistakes.
I think we all have,
but when I go to someone's twitter page
and it's just a constant series of these
fucking bitter back and forth feuds,
I'm like,
you're doing it wrong,
right?
You're doing it wrong.
We're all,
you know,
we're all learning this as we go along.
I think.
How'd you feel after the men see a
fight?
I hate to keep bringing it up,
but I just watched it last night.
Again,
Brian and I have talked about this a
million times.
Brian's favorite piece of,
or my favorite piece of Brian's work.
It was this cool to get all these
pieces,
it easy songs.
Um,
but uh,
there was a lot of negativity attached
to it,
a lot,
a lot of negative fucking comments and
tweets and messages I guess was like my
space back then.
But it was,
there was a lot of email.
A lot of people got my email and sent me
a lot of,
like really nasty shit,
but it was so poorly spelled,
like the majority of it to save.
Think he's still
got a folder on my fucking email called,
it's just called fans because it was so
bad.
It was so ridiculous.
It was like,
come on.
Is this real?
This is real.
People like it didn't even like the big
one.
One of the big ones was them saying,
you know,
he did it better.
Yeah,
I heard that cause he did it better just
because he did it better.
Okay.
You're like fucking all jealous over
there because he did it better.
But even that died off.
Man Stopped.
It was a moment in comedy history.
Yeah.
But a lot of negativity,
man,
lot of negativity attached to it.
But sometimes you gotta get your hands
dirty.
Well you stuck up for a lot of people.
That's the thing.
And I remember you used to write about
it.
I think I used to see it on my space or
whatever.
I mean you stick up for a lot of little
guys when you did that,
you know.
Well that's where it all came from.
It came from guys like Johnny Sanchez
getting fucked over and are we getting
fucked over?
And countless numbers of dues.
It's,
it makes for a hostile environment when
you have to hit that flashing light at
the store because you know he's in the
back of the room.
If everyone comics,
I'll have that little little signal
thing.
They would go over and flick the light a
couple of times because he was in the
back of the room.
Right.
That's just dark dude.
Yeah,
but we're learning,
you know,
and we're learning.
Now.
Look,
if he had to start his career over
again,
dudes,
good performer,
man.
If he could start his career over again
and just do it the right way,
you know,
he,
he would have been a different person if
he started out today as opposed to back
then,
yeah,
probably be a different person,
but if you get off on the wrong foot and
you stay on that wrong foot and then you
justify your actions all along the way,
you get to a point where you're two
decades into a career that's bullshit
and you don't know how to write.
Yeah.
You don't know how to write it all.
That's a super common thing.
You see that with biters,
you see that with guys going back and
trying to create new stuff and it's
like,
oh my God,
you're lost at sea.
Like you,
you literally don't know how to do it.
Like the,
you would see the contrast between the
stuff that they obviously stole and then
the stuff they obviously wrote.
Right?
And it's like,
oh good Lord,
like this is like you're speaking two
different languages.
It's like one of these things is made
out of vegetables and one of these
things made out of shit.
It's so obvious to anybody who's paying
attention,
but I don't know,
man.
It's um,
sometimes it's important to do negative
things.
Yeah.
It's just,
it depends on what's happening.
But it also exposed a lot about the
businessman that people didn't want to
believe.
Yeah.
Because nobody wanted to believe that if
you like,
had a beef with some famous person who
had it out for you,
that they could ruin your career.
Right.
But he tried to do that to me.
Yeah.
And he said he didn't have the power to
do it.
It did it work so far as the comedy
store,
was that where you work that weekend?
I mean,
he got me banned from that weekend.
Right.
But he made a deal with the guy that's
not there anymore.
Oh really?
I don't know the exact details of it,
but it was the only time ever where his
name was on the marquee.
He never let them put his name on the
marquee names on the marquee and he was
headlining the whole weekend.
Yeah.
So it was like this big thing that I was
gone and he was headlining,
put his name on the Marquee and um,
I forgot my point.
It doesn't matter.
It's a pointless beaten into the ground
story.
But the bottom line was after all the
dust settled,
everybody sort of eventually got a sense
of what it really was all about.
It's really all about is all these
people.
Some have a similar story and we're all
dealing with something that is just
undeniable.
Is that door open back there?
Jamie?
See if that fucking doors up because
that shit is super loud.
It's not.
We need to figure out a way to like
soundproof the ceiling because when they
those guys are banging shit over there
banging shit.
Not like that kind of bang.
I was at a hotel and I heard someone
fucker did happen in a long time.
I was in a hotel.
I was 18.
I was in a hotel room with my parents
and the people next door were fucking.
We beat each other.
No,
not at all.
In the same room with your parents was
in the same room with my parents and
those people.
Fucking next door's.
Did your parents do Dave?
Everyone.
We wanted the elephant in the other
room,
like good white people.
Oh my God.
This lady was going like.
Yeah.
It was like a shaky thing.
She's been rattled.
Right?
Who's weird?
One of the Caesar Girls.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I wasn't loud enough for me to record.
I was trying to get my.
I phoned up to the door.
He hotel.
We were in Washington dc at this old
hotel.
By the way,
those old hotels,
they can all suck it.
Those old hotels.
They try to pretend that it's cool to
stay in this creaky ass fucking hotel
where when someone flushes their toilet
three floors above you,
it's like a roaring train is running
through your room.
Every time someone walked above me or
hurt,
I was like,
this is stupid.
Yeah.
It's a boutique hotel and they're using
more expensive than like some of the
newer hotels.
Yes,
it was.
It was expensive as fuck.
It was stupid dumb ass hotel,
but people be fucking couldn't figure
out where they were fucking there above
me or to the side of me.
You ever hear that?
It'll stand bit where he's like,
not only can you hear them fucking,
you can smell it.
That's how bad the hotels where there
was this place in Arizona,
we stayed at that.
The bottom of the door had like a good,
like three inches underneath it,
so you would just be in bed and you
would see people walking down the
hallway.
It's like,
that's ridiculous.
Yeah,
but that's part of the fun of the road.
Especially,
you know when you're with friends.
The early days especially,
I stayed once.
I did a Gig on this fucking island,
block island,
an island outside of Rhode Island.
I think that's a black guy on a blog,
but it's,
uh,
it's the people that lived there were
the drunkest troglodytes I've ever
performed in front of ever.
I mean,
this guy,
Scott Scott was the guy who booked it
and he was the opening act and he went
up and just ate a plate of shit.
It was just no one was getting anything
out of this crowd.
We both sucked at the time,
but I mean it was,
the Gig was impossible because no one
was getting through this alive.
It was,
there was maybe 30 people in the room.
It was like they had a bar and then they
just announced the show was going to
happen.
It was the first one ever first and only
one it was me and him.
So we did the Gig gigs,
death,
just hot death.
They didn't want to pay us because it
was awful.
They said,
we've salted the people that were,
that came there.
There wasn't a yelling shit the moment
ago.
It was just monsters.
There were,
there were pirates and then we had to
stay in a supply room.
We had cots that they had set up in a
room with stacks of like canned tomatoes
and fucking,
you know,
Syrup for soda machines and Shit and
containers of nitrous oxide,
that kind of shit.
It was like a storage room and they put
two cots there with no bathroom and
that's where we slept.
Shakey's they said they had a room for
us.
Where's the room?
Well,
we take it back here and they brought us
to this room and it was a storage room.
They put a cotton you could sleep here.
Fairy comes at six in the morning.
So we had to sleep there and then we had
to leave on the ferry at 6:00
in the morning,
whatever.
Time was fucked.
Oh,
it was gross.
And the dude I was with was partying.
So he was a disaster.
It was just,
you know,
if you wanted to get drunk and do coke,
it was there.
Right.
It was just everybody was just like,
there's no cops here.
The cops are coming this fucking crazy
island.
There's only 100 people.
Everyone is like one drink away from
death,
just barely hanging on.
You might as well stay up until six.
You could hear their liver like pop
rocks going off under their skin.
So they're shouting so much liver.
It's just fucking struggling to stay
together.
Like the Millennium Falcon when it was
shaking,
trying to achieve the warp speed,
the liver.
I'll just never forget.
There was this table of like three or
four people together talk and and Scott
starts to show when he starts to show
that I got,
they just turn to them and like yelling,
fuck it.
That's bobby missing teeth.
And their faces are all pruned up from
the fucking cold wind and the sea water.
It's death.
It was one of those places you could not
live if you lived.
Everybody would just slowly start
disappearing and horrible accidents.
Sure.
Like if they made you live on that
island,
you'll go,
you know,
and you had that guys your navy.
But alright today I'm taking him fishing
and I ain't taking them back.
There's mother fuckers gonna fall in the
water.
Yeah.
Where do you live?
Fucking super important part of your
life.
You live in a shitty spot.
It's really hard to have fun and now
that means shitty spotlight.
You're way better off with like really
good friends were the weather sucks
Dick.
Sure.
Well yeah,
whether cannot destroy you that much,
but if you're in a bad neighborhood,
that's why.
Yeah.
Like anybody thinks kids should pull
themselves up by their bootstraps.
It's tough.
Imagine being born and fucking watts
living in the worst sections of
Inglewood or or you know,
being a Gypsy Caravan family and fucking
England.
You might not even know someone that
could teach you how to do it.
And there's a lot about examples all
over the place of what to do and like we
were talking about with Michael Irvin,
like kids,
everyone's programmed differently so it
becomes like this repeating cycle.
Unless you get out,
unless you are a performer or athlete or
someone who figures out a way to start a
business and get out of the get out of
the neighborhood and sort of reset
yourself and figure out what the foot.
What kind of fucking trial was I on?
What kind of path was I riding on?
It must be weird to mix with the rich
after that.
Well,
you know what's the weirdest shit?
You could just drive to Beverley hills.
Yeah,
it's right there.
It doesn't take long to get there.
So you could live in the worst
neighborhood in La and just close your
door.
Start Your car,
start driving in 15 minutes later you're
standing in front of a house that's
worth $50 million.
That's,
that's weird.
It is weird.
I mean that we are.
And then how about this?
The person who lives in Compton or
whatever,
shit neighborhood they could get in
their car and drive to Tijuana and go,
oh,
I thought I had it.
Let's get back to compton.
I'm worried.
Get away from this cardboard house with
no windows.
You know,
are we allowed to make fun of Gypsies?
Like is there any kind of.
Except for gypsy.
That's not true.
There's some feedback.
There's some blow back in England.
Really Gypsy's yeah.
If you start shitting on Gypsies in
other countries,
they get very upset.
Can we still call them Gypsies?
Rogatory yet?
I don't think so.
I don't think it's derogatory.
Hmm.
Let's look it up.
Someone is offended.
A lot of Gypsies in Burbank and they,
they,
they're always hanging out in my
dumpster there.
American Gypsy hanging out in your
dumpster.
They pull up in these weird vans that
have beads all over on me just like all
come out of this van and they all just
start going through all the trash and
there's a lot of bands in my
neighborhood recently,
like people just live on my street now
in advance.
Here we go.
Ready?
Yo,
that's racist.
A racial slur.
This was a surprise.
The end where it wasn't in the retort
article on Gawker about a child that was
taken away from a couple because she
didn't look like them and it says police
rescue,
mystery,
blonde child from Gypsy couple,
and then this article goes on to
describe that it says the term Gypsies
and non preferred and often derogatory
term for Roma people.
For those of you who aren't aware of the
Anti Roma Bigotry,
the Roma are an indigenous people of
Europe who continued to be pushed from
nation to nation and mistreated.
Okay?
That's one take on it by a friend who
lived outside of London who had these
Gypsies move into the lot near their
friend's house and absolutely destroy
it,
destroy the neighborhood,
leave their trash everywhere.
Rob,
all the houses in the neighborhood like
there are also notorious criminals,
notorious,
right?
I mean there's no.
They're not all criminals,
but there's a lot of them.
They live a crazy lifestyle.
They're always bare knuckle fighting.
They have these videos,
they challenge each other online.
It's awesome.
Various beautiful slice of our human
culture in 2012,
but to this portrayal of it is so
ridiculously one side of him,
right?
They are pushed from nation to nation
and mistreated.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
We don't want you leaving your garbage
everywhere and fighting in the streets
and stabbing my friends.
No,
please don't do that anymore.
Or whatever you been doing.
Say stabbing.
I don't know if they're involved in
stabbing,
but that's part of the game is we got a
row of town to town and we got to hustle
money.
They're wild people,
man.
I mean,
it's fascinating.
The movie snatch was awesome.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
We're actually moving on it.
Fucking awesome with the way Brad Pitt,
that whole dialect,
so fucking awesome.
The article goes on.
They are frequently denied legal status
and therefore social services.
There are many stereotypes about the
Roma,
but the most predominant is that they're
all sociopathic.
Drifters who steal children and anything
else that isn't tied down well.
It's been my experience that very few
people who do nothing wrong or labeled
as sociopathic thieves who steal
children.
Very few people.
One of the things that they don't say
about those Tibetan Buddhist monks is
that there's sociopathic thieves who
steal children.
Yeah.
They said that about a mother theresa a
lot to.
Right,
and all the stationary I think feeds who
steal children.
Yeah.
I don't know man ejaculates in people's
coffee.
It's not healthy to paint things in a
completely unrealistic biased way like
this guy is doing just to prove that
you're not racist.
Right?
That shit's not healthy.
Now.
I know you should talk about the reality
of their life.
Like it doesn't help anybody if you
bullshit people on what these folks do.
Right in,
and again,
it's not all of them,
but the fact that you're saying that
Gypsy's haven't been involved in
conflicts or the Roma people,
whatever the fuck you want to call them,
you'd be lying.
Right?
Right.
When we could all come up with different
reasons for why cultural biological,
you know,
there's all sorts of variables that are
entering into this equation,
but to portray it like this,
like these,
these beautiful people that are just
roaming from town to town and everyone's
just pushing them away because of the
patriarchy because white,
white people privileged.
Right.
I check my privilege online.
Did you do that?
Yeah,
I saw that.
Yeah.
My Shit.
Lord.
What?
What website is your shit?
Fucking asshole.
You're a part of the problem.
What,
what,
where can you get your privilege?
Check your privilege.com.
Okay,
cool.
Yeah,
I'm just about what should be an app and
it already was.
And then someone sent me a link.
It's an actual website.
So I went through the website,
check my privilege and so you don't have
a lot of privilege.
Your Shit.
Too much privileged.
So I'm,
that's what it is.
Everyone who's.
I think if you're white and you don't
have aids,
you're shit Lord.
Okay.
I think that's pretty much how it goes.
What's going on in this world?
There's something strange going on in
this world,
man.
Just something strange,
this,
this article is proof of it.
People are going way out of their way to
show that they're sensitive and open
minded to the point where they're not
really open minded.
You're denying reality.
Yeah.
It's like it doesn't help anybody.
It doesn't help anybody to only only
side with the maligned and mistreated in
the misrepresented to always side with
them.
Yes.
That's not,
that's not healthy.
Like marginalized people.
There's marginalized groups for sure and
it's good to recognize when they're
being mistreated,
but the reality of their behavior can't
be ignored.
Like you can't do that.
Right?
It muddies up the whole thing.
Yeah.
You can still sign with them,
but you have to admit the facts and you
have to admit that they survive ways
that can hurt other civilians.
Other people.
Yeah.
And you know what man,
hey,
that's the reality of the world they're
thrust into.
Yeah.
If you were there,
like,
you know,
I watched this video on poachers in
Africa and all these people that like,
they,
uh,
they illegally capture these animals and
sometimes it's the only food that these
people can get,
like,
like they're in terrible situations.
They have these ridiculous guns.
They construct,
they,
they make their own charges and light.
They're gone sometimes with a lighter
and then shoot it at these animals.
I mean they pack these things like
muskets.
I think a rifle and a packet,
like a musket and then like,
like,
like a fuse,
like it's a bomb.
I mean,
it's ridiculous how poor and rudimentary
some of this shit is.
These guys are doing.
You gotta wonder like,
what are this?
What are these guys?
Options man,
right?
I mean,
you're getting mad at this guy for
poaching animal's needs.
Yeah.
It's terrible to shoot someone else's
property.
You know?
Even if you are starving to death,
it seems,
it seems wrong,
but moved to America and work on Wall
Street.
Why does he do that?
He knows it's this should.
Why doesn't he get an education?
Why hasn't he wash his feet?
He's got old plastic water bottles that
he's turned into flip flops.
What's this Guy Thinking?
Why isn't he smarter?
Yeah,
you can't.
You can't judge people like that.
The way you would judge a person from a
normal neighborhood with a normal
background.
I mean normal bilich healthy.
No,
no,
no.
Serious trauma.
There's a reason he's in that situation.
You're not in that situation.
You don't seek that situation.
No.
What the fuck,
man,
that's,
that's the real problem with the world.
The real problem in the world is like
the one percent that everybody wants to
think about that if you make more than
$34,000
a year,
you're in the top one percent of all
people on the planet.
Really?
I did not know that.
Yeah.
Kevin Smith and I talked about it the
other day and I've talked about it on
this podcast before too.
That's a real number.
That's so when you talking about
poachers,
are you talking about impoverished
people?
The level of poverty that the people who
work at Foxconn have.
When you say,
man,
those people live there.
There's nets around the building to keep
them jumping off the roof,
like we can't even imagine what that
life is like.
And those are people just like,
you just like me,
just like you,
just,
just people just,
if we were born in China,
we'd be like,
fuck dude,
we got to go to the Foxconn.
We can't go.
We can't have the option to go to the
store tonight.
You know what's called perform at the
comedy store?
No,
we can't.
We have to make cell phones for a nickel
an hour.
I got a suicide at noon.
Um,
how,
how does that work?
They don't like apply for those jobs.
Do they just kind of.
If they can,
I don't even know if there's enough jobs
to supply all the people that are poor
and looking for jobs there.
There's a billion people in China.
It's crazy.
A billion and they just hacked our
weather system.
Did you see that?
We're talking about the US said today
that China has hacked our radar and
satellite are or whether or like one of
our things that we use for our news
every day and they packed it or
satellite and that's why I pull up an
article on it so we can get a more
definitive description of what's going
on.
That's why I feel like the whole month
of October,
I think there was very limited radar in
the news and the consumer from China
hacked our radar dishes,
governments,
but that's hilarious.
China,
so the Chinese government hacked our
radar system or whether system,
whether it radar,
what are they doing with it?
They stealing the data.
Why do they care what the temperature is
over here?
US weather's so much while I'm at 75
degrees in Los Angeles,
by the way,
terrible accidents.
Both of us,
both of us.
I didn't know which way to go to go.
Super Chinese are just weird.
Weird.
If you don't know what you're doing.
Chinese reportedly hack us weather
systems.
What Chinese hackers allegedly broke
into the US weather systems in September
and caused federal cyber security forces
to block sensitive data needed for
crucial uses,
including disaster planning and
aviation.
So they,
they,
they fucked with like a lot more than
just like the weather radar.
Wow.
But uh,
who knows who's doing that though?
You know,
we say China,
like who just is a billion people.
Could be one asshole would call it
China.
Yeah.
It's only like one to 10 assholes.
Who were they saying,
you know what I mean,
to be food in China.
Did this.
And we're blaming China.
Right.
Let's go to war.
I mean,
is this.
Yeah.
Is this an official government a thing
that did this or looking by the way
while we're looking.
Did you try to sit in that chair?
You prefer better?
This is way better for my posture.
Right?
Better for my back.
But I knew I was going to need to lounge
a little bit while I was here.
I don't know.
That's your thing.
So this is a clearly better chair,
but this me more relaxed.
I'll give up relaxation for posture.
Yeah.
Alright.
I'm still with the Ergonomic chairs,
the best ergonomic chair I've ever had
earlier this week.
The posts also reported that Chinese
government hackers were suspected of
breaking into the US Postal Service
computer networks and stealing the
personal data belonging to hundreds and
thousands of employees.
Retires and customers or employees of
the post office.
Yeah.
The Chinese government's supposedly
awesome broken to our usbs or us,
but their.
Their government hackers.
Yeah.
They're government hackers,
meaning that they know my po box.
That's terrifying.
They're getting all those things that
try to get you to join scientology.
They're getting all those first.
Getting all those postcards to again,
take a personality test before I can
fuck.
I've been scientists.
Who knows what that means though.
Chinese government hackers who does.
What does that mean?
You know,
I'm not sure.
That's such a broad statement for what
department?
Under whose jurisdiction?
Like with what objective,
who are the humans that are doing it?
You know,
you say Chinese government hackers like.
Yeah.
Okay.
It could be anybody.
It could be someone blaming the Chinese
because they are doing it.
Know who the fuck knows.
They don't really break that down.
Huh?
Fucking Gypsies.
So.
So Gypsy Bro.
Well,
Romas at black chips.
So that's kind of like a loophole.
No,
you better not transgender Gypsies to
stop right there.
Don't say God damn.
Trend to Gypsies.
Trans Gypsies got our podcast canceled.
You did this shit Lord.
Tractor hit the roof.
Kind of look into that loophole.
You're not supposed to say bitch
anymore,
which is a new one to try and take away.
Bitch sucks.
It's such a nice heart out on a sentence
like fuck you bitch.
You know,
listen to you and works comedically.
Some girl at the comedy store the other
day,
one of the waitresses said,
get the fuck Outta here.
Bitch said it to this dude.
And I gave her knuckles.
I go,
that was a strong bitch.
Yeah.
It's like she goes,
it was right.
Yeah.
The way it came out just said,
yeah,
I would hate to live in a world where
someone couldn't say something like
that.
Like the Joe when Joey d is correct.
You like,
please bitch,
get the fuck Outta here bitch.
The best way to condescend and just and
humiliate someone and onstage.
It's one of my favorite words.
I will not stop using it if you got.
If you got a sentence,
it's not.
Or a punchline is not really working.
You can throw one bitch a set in there
and that'll save that punchline
sometimes.
Yeah.
Maybe you just need to get back to the
drawing board with that fucking bitch on
it and call it a day.
Silly Bitch.
I'll never give up.
Say No matter what Allie bitches.
So unthreatening yeah.
That it just should be let slide in it.
Which makes sense.
You know what I'm saying?
It's like you can't say you silly kike
no.
Hey,
that's on you a,
it's not even cute.
Rude,
silly gypsy.
That middle ground.
Yeah.
You know,
I wonder if you could still say homo.
No,
I haven't heard anybody trying to ban
it.
You'll be okay.
But it's not.
It's frowned upon.
I think it's not supposed to say
something's gay.
Sure.
Can't say,
Oh my God,
this movie's Gay.
That's uh,
that's not good.
You obviously can't say the F bomb.
Yeah.
He can't say fag.
She easily not even with the hail,
usually you can say faggotry because it
has not been defined.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah.
But,
um,
Homo.
I haven't heard a peep nobody's band at
yet.
Maybe I should shut the fuck up homo
campaign.
It's like the seven words you can't say
on TV became the seven words you can't
say on TV in a way.
Well,
like,
fag isn't Mafac is short for Faggot.
So it's not like a part of a word that's
a legitimate world like Homosapian,
Homosapian,
homosexual homeostasis,
you know,
there's like a lot.
I know there's a lot of trap doors in
that.
There's a lot of ways out of that.
I meant homosapien.
Yeah,
yeah.
No Homo sapiens.
Gypsy,
you know,
you can't say that.
That's,
that's.
Yeah,
that's kind of gypsy though.
They don't procreate.
They do.
Their magic balls had to ruin.
It isn't like the ones with the magic
balls and the cards and like the.
Yeah,
they are,
they have the crystal balls,
crystal balls and the uh,
reading your fortune.
I mean,
there've been hustlers from the
beginning,
but again,
it's fucking born into.
You're born into that shit.
What would you do?
You're telling me that you would figure
out,
oh,
my culture is insufficient in so many
areas.
I need to get out and explore the subtle
nuances of life and education and change
my verbiage and my vernacular and moved
to Cambridge and come on.
Yeah.
Maybe by the time you're 15,
if you're lucky to have that kind of
individual thought,
but otherwise you just don't fucking
cards out three card Monte fucking
hustling.
Motherfuckers drugging babies.
Oh,
that's what I heard about the Gypsies
drug and babies stay drugged to babysit.
I don't cry.
There was a story of a lady drug to baby
on an airplane.
She got arrested.
She was a stewardess and she gave a baby
benadryl because the baby was screaming
and crying.
Yeah.
We get warm Jack.
Two babies in Ohio.
Put a little in there.
No,
it turned out cooked your brain and shit
ain't good.
You think it's okay to say Homo Gypsy?
Yes.
These are all terrible things.
When Israel terrible would have done
your lump better.
Yeah.
Good night's sleep at some orange juice.
Get your fucking electrolytes in order,
son.
It's bugging me,
man,
that like this already laying thing that
we were talking about yesterday and we,
we played his,
um,
we read rather his tweet the other day
during the Dahmer podcast and we were
shocked at what everybody was upset
about.
Now did he said this on the podcast,
is that what happened with twitter?
Twitter,
he tweeted it as a fucking comedian
known for being
dirty and because he said something
about an African American woman,
but her whipping him and him coming all
over himself,
like a fat father.
It was just,
it was about her disrespecting the
plantation.
I mean,
his tweets were hilarious,
but people were so offended that he was
kicked off of that midnight show.
He couldn't do the midnight show.
And then on top of that he,
um,
he got banned from Espn.
He can't go on espn to care of ESPN.
Last night he torched espn for ripping
him off.
He got up,
he got it,
like a phrase or a bit stolen yet.
And so he just,
he redid a whole sketch,
ripping them.
Tasha has this thing called Web
redemption,
right?
Right.
Where he's,
you know,
he watches like famous,
like,
like videos and just,
you know,
look,
let's get redemption for this lien.
And so he meets the people there in the
veil.
They pretty much exactly did the same
thing.
And so she's been on there since like
six years or something.
So they're doing the same thing.
They're just calling it a different
name.
Don't play it,
don't play it.
It'll get us kicked off of youtube every
time,
every fucking time.
Even though I've got a comedy central
special coming out next week,
they would still kick us off.
You can even play your clip for your
comments,
especially my clip.
They'd pull me off youtube.
Not Kidding.
Welcome to the world.
We live in full charge.
I know you signed the paperwork.
I don't know what you signed,
but I signed some shit that ain't mine
no more.
There's a lot of motherfuckers out there
that want to own everything.
God,
that's the beauty of the podcast.
Full charge.
I know.
We do whatever we want.
You've got a full charge podcast to full
charge power.
Our very funny.
Everybody check it out on you.
Sure.
It's very funny,
very,
very funny.
Very funny.
Nobody believer sees what's the matter.
Oh,
nothing.
Well we not recording.
Ah,
fuck.
I can't hear anything right now.
Yeah.
The microphone is just not working right
now.
Oh,
but it's recording.
Yeah.
His is recording.
So what happens when you park yourself
there?
Jamie is here.
Everything was nice and smoothly.
Now.
SD cards in the middle of fucking show.
I just want to remind people that all
the equipment works on the full charge
power hour.
It's very high.
People don't edit it.
Actually.
Are we fall?
Is that what it is?
Why don't you guys fucking plan this
shit in advance.
There's not a lot of things that you
guys have to do.
This only gets full like once a year.
You should just check it.
It's not a lot of shit to check here.
Just fucking Christ.
Yeah.
One SD card.
So what is this show being recorded?
Yeah.
This is just backup all the time.
You spent going to massage parlors,
son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch.
Full charge man.
Have a tour coming out or something.
Yes I do.
It's,
um,
it's a little west coast tour,
San Francisco Doc Ricketts,
November 29th,
Woodstock,
crickets.
Doc records used to be the purple onion
in north beach and it's a new club now
and November 29th.
So that's like a really small,
intimate room.
Didn't get special.
Yeah.
So it's pretty cool.
I'd never been there,
but uh,
I can't wait to play it.
And I'm going to be at the analog cafe
on December fifth.
That's in Portland,
Oregon.
Beautiful.
And I'm going to be at highline in
Seattle,
Washington on December six and I would
love for people to come out and see me.
Good Lord.
Full charge.
How do you do it all?
I just,
I get to writing.
I memorized the jokes,
do some stage time company,
then I've,
then I go to the city.
This is.
Yeah.
Do you bring people on the road with you
and you're working with Logan?
Actually my co host from the full charge
power hour,
Craig Coleman is going to come open from
a code soured alone.
Everybody's got a podcast now.
It's great.
It's gonna come a time when no one wants
a television show,
you know,
like,
wow,
I kind of like podcasts or in the time
for this,
too many cooks tomb and what is too many
cooks.
You guys keep saying this too many
This amazing video that these two guys
that work at adult swim has had been
making on their own for the last year.
I think they're like pas or something.
Like I said,
they'd been taken like a little bit of
money and making this little stealing,
stealing project on the site and so
they,
they got the a 4:00
like info commercial spot on adult swim
and it's kind of like a video that's
making fun of eighties sitcoms openings
by on mushrooms and at first year it's
just like this annoying song that starts
getting into your head and it's over and
over.
And then a lot of people just turn it
off after like four or five minutes
because they are like,
I can't take anymore of this.
But if you get over the lump of like the
four minute mark,
it becomes one of the most fucked up,
demented.
Beautiful videos I've seen on a long
weird.
It's really weird.
Yeah,
but there's a lot of that.
Tim and Eric Style comedy these days.
They just keep going.
Yeah,
there's a lot of cool stuff out there
now I know and especially when you could
just make a clip and just throw it up on
youtube or throw it up on the Internet
and there's so many people that could
just do things now.
Yeah,
it's really cool that they did.
They took a chance and overnight it got
like 3 million hits in less than 24
hours.
That's awesome.
That's beautiful man.
We live in a great time.
So fucking best time ever.
It really is.
It is.
And it really wasn't and it's just so
new.
All these opportunities is so new,
you know?
Yeah.
Trials and tribulations aside,
all this shit about like peanut butter
and jelly sandwiches being racist and
all this stupidity still awesome.
I know the most awesome time.
It's just,
there's too many people talking.
That's all it is.
It's weird that people use so much.
They use the uh,
technology just like complain and stuff.
There's creators and there's destroyers,
there's whiners,
and there's just people that like
fucking contribute.
There's a lot of distributors out there,
but you know what I mean,
man.
A lot of it is just misplaced energy.
I've talked to destroyers.
Former destroys her now.
Creators.
Yeah.
Apologize to me.
Like for like some shit.
They wrote like,
I'm sorry,
tweeted that out.
You are sorry.
I said that.
I was just blah blah blah.
And they want to.
They want to be creators,
but they don't have the balls or they
don't have the experience and then they
see you doing it and they get.
They put that energy towards you.
Yeah.
Well there's.
There's also
some people look at other people's
success as their failure somehow,
like you're detracting from them.
Like every time a full charge goes on
tour,
people back home and go,
fucking full charge out there in
Portland.
Fuck.
Now they're pissed.
Fuck this man.
You know I,
I started out that dude.
Fuck man.
I can't even get booked.
Who booked you there,
man?
He should just call me.
That's another beautiful thing about
this.
I just fucking.
I booked the venues myself.
Segura said that to me.
He's like,
this is the thing that people do.
That's like the grossest thing guide.
How'd you get that?
Yeah,
I've heard that expression since I
started.
How'd you get that?
What's the formula?
What's the math equation?
So I can do it?
Yeah.
Fucking Ian Edwards just talking about
that too.
He's like,
that's weird shit that people say to
you.
How'd you get that?
Get that.
I just called this guy jeff did a lap
bro.
Super easy.
You're writing a fast start talking.
It was a million different things
combined individual to me and that's how
it happened.
Million different things.
You freak pitches.
Yeah.
So,
um,
when you put together these tours are,
you're doing this shit with an agent,
you're doing it all by yourself.
I just do it by myself.
That's cool.
Yeah.
That's a,
that's another thing that you can do
today that you could never do before.
The middle men across the board are
getting cut out,
which is beautiful.
Yeah.
And they don't have to be middlemen.
It's not like there's not a whole lot of
opportunities for other shit to be done.
Right.
It's just great because of email and
twitter.
You can have these people that are
following me on twitter.
I'm like,
Oh shit,
there's this club that's following the
in September and in Portland it's
falling out.
Just tweet them and see what's up.
Exactly.
Did you see the video of the,
uh,
the elephant fighting off?
14 lines on my twitter.
Follow it.
It's,
it's pretty awesome because the elephant
winds,
elephants just seemed,
spoiler.
Elephants just seemed so fucking cool.
Like it's really kind of hard to believe
that people shot them just for their
ivory.
They just,
I mean,
I know that they killed people sometimes
and storm into villages and stomp
everything down,
but look,
don't hate the player.
What game wasn't it?
This podcast you guys were talking about
how they used to.
They electrocuted an elephant as an
experiment.
Yeah.
I'm with Thomas Edison.
Did to show the power.
No one blogged about it.
You can just,
you can cook an elephant and Times
Square and nobody gives a shit.
Back then it was for a,
so that video is the advancement that
video gets pulled,
but if we do like a screenshot,
it really goes both ways.
Yeah,
I'm sure it will.
Right?
Here's a bunch of fighting over it and
then we'll just skip ahead with second.
Well,
here's what happens.
The lions jump on these things back and
they try to drag it down and just google
it.
It's worth watching because it feels
good.
A young elephant fights 14 lines and
wins,
but you know what,
man,
if you shot one of those lines,
everybody was super mad at you.
If he was sitting there watching,
like,
imagine this is what happens.
You're sitting there watching this
elephant getting fucked up by these
lines,
so you just fucking pull out of your
four by four,
climb up on the roof,
line this motherfucker up and you see
this lion's body.
You'd be.
People would be really pissed at you,
dear Internet.
I can't believe they shot that line,
but if you,
you know,
if you'll just sit back and let the
lions killed the elephant to do you pick
a side.
Do you pick a side when you see 14 lines
trying to kill an elephant?
Elephant.
You've picked us out to the alpha.
I think so too,
because elephants are herbivores.
They're not predators.
Right?
But isn't that just how it works,
man?
If the lions can bring down the elephant
to eat it,
that's how it works.
That's the game plan is not the game.
We're all playing.
That is the game.
They're all planning.
Like if,
if it's a person like some chick on
facebook posing with a deadline,
she's the cont.
Right?
Right.
But if the lions take this elephant out
there,
like the lion had to do it,
the chick took a flight over here.
She's an asshole.
She's just doing this for fun,
just like a homo gypsy.
But if the chick was there and she was
doing it for fun and she saw this and
she said,
you know what?
Fuck these lines.
I'm gonna.
Kill one of those lines.
Would people be angry at her?
I think they probably.
Would.
People pick teams?
Yeah.
Even when it comes to animals.
[inaudible].
That's a little weird.
I love lions,
but I just know elephants are way
fucking smarter than A.
Yeah.
They can paint.
They can paint their face.
You know what I'm saying?
No,
no,
no.
That'll get us pulled too.
But there's a video.
If you go and Google it,
there's a video of an elephant painting
his own portrait or her own portrait.
So there's a,
there's only the males have the horns.
Is that what it is?
The tusks?
Don't know about that.
Would they use only.
I'm the only antlered animal that's a
female.
Um,
as far as like,
like deer and elk and Caribou.
Female Caribou.
Have Antlers coming out of the fight off
wolves and shit to female elephants.
What about female rams?
Female Rams.
GotTa have horns,
right?
Otherwise you're not around right now.
It's a sheep.
Females,
sheep rams just swayed on fuck ramps
growing up.
Both male and female.
African elephants have tusks unlocked or
Asian relatives.
Um.
Oh No.
I'm not like their ancient relatives.
African elephants are not easily
domesticated in incorrect sentence.
I only had to click on it here.
So yeah,
they both have tusks.
You guys hear about these cat dicks.
They have little knives in them.
They all have good nights.
Yeah.
They stick in like a bb fishing the
fishing for pussy.
Get cat calls.
You ever heard cat cat screaming every
night?
Yeah.
It sounds like they're fighting.
You hear it night.
I have a lot of feral cat in my
neighborhood.
Did Gypsies brought on.
That's what happens man.
When you live in a neighborhood where
people just let their cats out and then
they.
They like people like let their cats
free.
Especially male cats.
Most people don't want to get their
mail.
Cats fixed.
It's paying the asset of the money and
so just let the little cute ball you
want to look at.
It's weird because you could tell that
there was a couple of the cats that are
just like they don't have homes,
but then there's cats because I live in
a nicer neighborhood that are mixed with
like Persian cats that have callers and
you're like,
it's a gangs of cats though and at night
they just fucking hanging out on your
car where you rarely see a cat with his
balls and really see a male cat with
balls.
If you go over people's houses,
their cats,
their male cats are always neutered
because if you're your male cat is
annuity pisses everywhere.
Right?
Back up and Piss on your wall.
This is mine and you can't stop them
there.
You're going to do it.
I had a cat do it.
I had my feral cat.
I don't know if you ever met him.
Do you ever meet Jack Dempsey?
Was the all black cat?
I don't think they'll kill them.
Yes.
Yes,
I did.
Frank Sinatra.
The pit bull told them was awful.
He just got cocky one too many times
with the dog.
He's a.
It was a fierce little cat,
but he.
I had him neutered,
but um,
it's very rare that you find one that's
not neutered,
you know,
that my cat was feral,
like I got him.
He was a couple months old and my friend
Lanie had rescued him and it was a total
disaster.
It was,
I should never done it.
But when I brought him home,
he's pissing everywhere.
Man.
He's picking his ass up and trying to
piss on the walls.
When I had to bring him to the vet to
get them,
uh,
get them neutered,
I literally had a throw a bathrobe over
them and tackle them in the bathroom.
I trapped them in the bathroom and he
was like,
hissing at me,
climbing up the drapes.
I'm like,
listen motherfucker,
I'm not going to kill you.
I love you.
Just here to take you to the vet.
If I picked him up once I picked them up
and start preparing like instantly,
like he would know that I was okay once
I picked them up,
but on the way to pick them up and,
but fucking scramble up the walls and
it's run from me.
It was the funniest shit ever.
And then I would,
when I first adopted him,
I slept with him in a room for like
several days,
just me and him in the room.
I pushed a bed into this room.
I had a spare bedroom.
Uh,
I pushed a push some books in there and
like how to keep shutting the door real
quick so he couldn't run out.
I put them in there,
put a litter box in there and put some
food in there and just hung out with him
just so he totally got used to me.
And when I come near them,
even like after he,
I picked him up a bunch of times.
I come here,
I'm going to run across the walls.
He was a little tiny thing man.
But when I finally would get them
right,
but as long as I kept a hold of him,
he was cool.
But as soon as I put them down,
fucking started hitting,
running away.
Wrong
cat noises,
man.
You got that down man.
That guy was nuts,
man.
I had all black cat when I was a kid.
What do you think my mother named this
cat face?
Sam.
Sambo.
Sambo,
nice parents you got there,
don't react to people fucking and named
the cat racist,
but those are too fucked up things.
That's very fucked up.
Why Sambo?
What does sambo?
Sambo is reference to a chain
of restaurants.
I guess 100 years ago,
it's very.
That aunt Jemima minstrel show.
Cartoonish.
A minstrel.
Not Menstrual,
right?
I don't know what I'm saying.
The racist thing.
Um,
but it's very like black face.
And there was a chain of restaurants
called Sam Bose.
Um,
my mom said there was like a black guy
in the Bible named sambo,
but I don't think that's true.
I don't think that's true.
Will Your Parents Bible thumpers?
No.
No,
no.
They like,
they're like Catholic,
so they're not really into it.
They're just guilted into going every
week.
Yeah.
Catholic is a different kind of
relationship.
Yeah.
That's why you'd never see Catholic
suicide bomber had this whole bit about
it because no Catholics believe in it
that much.
Exactly.
They just know they have to go there,
guilted into it.
The whole deal.
Did you hear about the fucking tiger
that's loosened France?
Yeah.
There's a real tiger loose in France,
like someone thought it was a links or
something like that and they got a photo
of it and then they realize like,
oh shit,
this is a tiger.
There's a young male tiger wandering
around Paris.
Jesus Christ.
That's romantic.
That's fucking terrifying.
Isn't it?
Full American Werewolf in London.
No,
American tiger.
There's no this.
There's more tigers in Texas than there
are in the wild.
Didn't know that.
You know what I say?
Good.
I like Texas and tigers can go fuck
themselves.
That's what I say.
I think we got a win win situation here.
I like it.
Are there any tigers in Mexico?
Like is it just Texas?
No.
Mexico has Jaguars.
Gotcha.
Tiger on the loose in Paris,
suburbs.
People told stay inside.
You think fucking look at that guy.
He's dead.
They're going to grab the back of his
head and Disneyland.
Paris,
strong cat noises.
Fucking horrible.
Horrible feeling.
It must be to just feel that thing
biting down on the back of your head and
know you'd be so great at reading books
to kids like,
like,
like a classroom of kids,
like a book about animals.
You would blow that shit out of the
park.
I do.
Um,
I did read one book on tape once you
remember the book.
Was there any animal story?
No,
no.
It's just,
you know,
I just had to be dramatic.
It was a little kids book because a book
for little kids.
I love reading to my kids though.
I get really.
We read the Gruffalo yeah.
Or Cat in the hat.
I'm a bad motherfucker.
I do the different voices and shit.
Yeah.
They love it to make me read the same
books over and over and over again.
Kids are weird,
man.
They want to watch the same shows.
My daughter has watched frozen no less
than 100 times.
Like my four year old can sing the
words.
Yeah,
I,
they,
they just want to see the same shit over
and over and over again.
The like Jamie with interstellar want to
see the same shit over and over is a
little weird that like books are still
interesting to kids too.
I mean imagination.
Yeah,
it's.
You
know what?
These guys are called.
No.
Bernstein bears.
Berenstein bears.
Whereas my mom used to call them the
sambo bears.
That's a.
here's a weird thing.
These aren't.
These are not called the Berenstein
bears.
What are they called?
The berenstain bears.
S t a I n,
but for some reason everybody thinks
that's Bernstein,
including myself,
but yeah,
growing up,
we used to always call him the
berenstain bears,
but look at the name.
It's so weird.
Weird fucking bear family will eat your
asshole
monsters,
but everybody wants to think are cute.
There's a bear thing is so strange,
man.
That's the weirdest thing that people
have an attachment to because bears are
fucking.
They don't give a shit about you.
Kill you as soon as they made 100
percent.
The only reason why they're not like
when people run into bears and they're
not killing them,
it's because they have other food it
just ate or something that they have on.
They have some.
They a bunch of salmon.
They have some berries that they ate.
They don't need to eat you.
What about panda bears?
Vicious rapist.
Horrible racists.
Pandas are the worst.
Koala bears.
Very lot of sexually transmitted
disease.
Chlamydia,
like for real.
They call bears transmitted sexually
transmitted disease to each other or
they die.
People,
I think.
Where'd you get the clap?
I never cheat on you with people.
It was so cute and then you just start
fucking man.
Yeah,
it's weird.
Koala bears.
Yeah,
it's that.
It's killing them though.
Like as a.
It really is threatening the funny to
take them out.
Lydia,
the std threatening and Australian icon.
Let's take them down to planned
parenthood.
That gets of.
Here's the thing,
man.
We're so funny.
What we want to keep them around.
You know,
we have this idea that we are in charge
somehow or another.
Make sure that animals don't go extinct
and the like a Koala bear needs to stay
around.
Like does it really?
I mean I don't think we should go kill
them all.
Okay.
I don't think that,
but if they all died because of fucking
herpes.
Yeah.
I think maybe we should concentrate on
poor people before we concentrate on
herpes.
Written Koala bears.
Dude,
you're writing crazy sensible when it
comes to that shit.
You can accidentally get an std from.
That's what you should have.
You should have called bears in your
house that way.
You always have a built in.
You should.
You should get a fucking Koala.
It's not what you think.
Connie baby.
Look,
I'm going to show you the article on
Google pdf.
File your house in Edu address.
Your House has just tanning beds and
just so you have an out of shit that can
give you stds.
Has anybody ever really gotten to a
tanning bed?
Venereal disease?
I have no idea.
I didn't.
I know this is
first I'm hearing of this.
Yeah,
you can get.
Supposedly you can get herpes from a
tanning bed.
Get herpes from a toilet seat,
you know you can use.
My sister used to.
Oh,
I got it from my sister.
Used to own a tanning bed in Boston
in a business that she started crying
and she said the problem was girls would
masturbate inside of them and they had
to clean it.
She does.
Sometimes she could smell it.
She would go in there.
You could smell it.
These chicks just been fingering
themselves,
whether in their tanning.
Keep it in your coffee,
girl you been off in the tangent because
especially since the beats off
everywhere else that worked there,
they're all pretty high and Tan and
they're all girls that worked there.
So you,
you come in,
you're just like,
you know,
she's just right on the other side of
this little like little cheap door.
So you're just like naked or going,
why not?
I'm just going to beat it up and it's
always those hollow shitty doors shut
them.
Clung,
Echo.
It's like this barely anybody could just
punch their hand through that door.
The shade design,
you know like the shades,
like the window shade design where you
can actually see through it.
So if you walk past one you can see like
a second,
you could see a woman like laying there.
So yeah,
that's Kinda crazy.
Like you're naked and you're compressed
in this thing that puts a light on you
that comes from metal,
glass tubes.
Like how weird are people man lying
there and you got little goggles on and
shit.
But you're buttholes this but hold the
glass and you get that Weird Tan spot
where you get a little white spot in
between your ass cheeks because your
cheeks compressed when you lie there.
So like I would try to spread my ass
cheeks while we're in there to make sure
that I got some tanning on that one area
at tech.
My Dick though in between.
So I don't want my Dick Tam for some
reason.
It never needs a 10 but it could make it
look bigger.
Sure.
I don't know if it does.
It doesn't.
I don't think it was bigger than their
white.
Isn't that why overweight people like to
wear black?
Black is slimming.
That's why black dicks are so impressive
and seem like Jesus Christ.
Imagine if it was white.
Imagine if you had a white Dick was all
white and it was giant.
A big fucking albino.
Brock lesnar styled Dick.
Do you think that would be fantastic?
I don't think it has little anything.
Who giant shits please.
The giant human.
What's going to have this little?
His little pinky shack has a small Dick.
I don't buy that for a second.
I lack shack has probably got an
enormous Dick.
He's just so big that it probably looks
normal sized on him.
He's seven foot tall.
It's huge.
That guy.
So big man.
I,
I've stood next to him on a bunch of
occasions,
shook his hand.
Shit.
He always comes by and says hi.
He's a big UFC fan and when you put your
hand in his to do that,
that bro handshake and you know this,
this one who do like that on my hand
just disappears.
Like I'm shutting my hand on a like a
refrigerator.
It's a giant hand.
He's an enormous man.
Sticks probably probably fucking huge.
Probably exactly what it is.
It's probably so big that it just
probably just looks normal compared to
him.
I mean,
look at that.
Let's get the fuck Outta here.
You're telling me that guy's got a
little dick.
I think he's walking next to his dick.
Just stick.
Please stop it.
How is it possible that God has a little
Dick?
God,
can you
imagine him?
Even though it was small for his size,
it's 10 inches.
Can I imagine him?
Fuck that.
Brian,
you just crossed the line?
No,
I mean like the size difference.
It's just ridiculous.
Just murder her baby.
Take it.
Some girls just so he ain't working out
no more.
Huh?
Is that what that picture is all about?
Is that looks checkup that.
Well,
big dudes like that.
That is a reality of life.
I don't live that long.
They all.
We're saying,
okay,
so tall guys want to.
Someone were saying that backwards and
that still makes me freak out.
Imagine if a girl had a guy like that.
You would imagine the girls just
stuffing that guy in her pussy.
Just making them Peter out from the g
spot,
just a shack she like only goes out with
guys who can hold their breath.
How long can you hold your breath?
Could hold my breath for like three
minutes.
Show me okay on Ge.
The inside of my pussy for three minutes
each.
The g spot?
Well there's certain animals that have
absorbed the mail after they breed a
black widow.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of a bunch of bugs that
kill the male after.
After they breed.
I think females do too.
I think praying mantis do,
don't they?
Yeah.
I think there's a bunch of.
A bunch of bugs that do that.
Black widows do the.
There's quite a few.
There's one aunt where they take the
mail and they bite all of his fucking
limbs off.
Like the male is like bigger and they
take them and they bite all of his legs
and wings off and then they bring them
to the hive and then they make them
breed.
That's weird that there's this society
where like that's all the males are good
for.
I don't think it's the society.
Well,
you know what I mean,
it's crazy little and it's a group
that's the real danger about spaceman is
that like a starship trooper style.
You could land somewhere and there's
giant bugs like that.
That's,
that's the reality.
Like we're lucky to have plugs are
fucking little man.
No kidding.
They live with us.
I mean they are in our world.
I,
I found a praying mantis the other day
and I got a video of this.
My daughter found it and I put it on her
hand and then she was holding it and
they try to get you and stuff,
but they can't get you there,
you know,
they can get like a bug or a hummingbird
or something like that,
but they really can't get a person and
we put it on this,
this branch and just right where we put
it just by total luck.
It was a bunch of ants crawling on the
branch and just starts eating the ants.
Wow.
Just picking him up and eating them
while sitting there and they were going,
oh my God,
he's eating.
The aunts were like,
Whoa,
this is so cool.
And I tried to video it,
but it's just hard to like get that in,
you know,
but uh,
that's going on right now.
You know what I'm saying?
Like that is a reality of life.
Now,
if that thing was as big as a giraffe
and the answer to the size of pigs and
you open your window,
you looked out there and you see this
fucking eating paste the pigs can and
try to get away.
We would live in a horrific environment.
That's like starship troopers.
Like the only difference between that
and you know,
and,
and our reality is that these bugs are
small,
right?
But there bugs,
man bugs.
They have a Dev,
no motions yet.
As far as we know,
they,
they lived this very alien,
almost mechanical life there.
They're like similar to like robots.
They're like a little weird robotic
alien creature that lives side by side
with us.
It's just so small we don't think about.
It isn't a word.
The,
Oh,
like the see all their friends getting
eaten and they don't react to it,
but they just walk right into the walk
right into it because they're
programmed.
They're not
like,
I almost think like in the future way,
thousands of years we're going to find
out the bugs and stuff are actually
completely way more advanced than us and
that,
you know,
like,
look at hummingbirds that doesn't look
like nature,
that it looks like a fucking jet
fighter.
It's,
that does not seem like the same thing
as a snail.
Well,
can you imagine if someone could figure
out a way to make a military aircraft
that can maneuver like a hummingbird,
like a large military occur,
ethical,
like what they can do is incredible.
The ways that we can move back and forth
and all around,
Hey,
have a hummingbird feeder outside my
house and had tons of hummingbirds and
if you have the new iphone,
it has that slow motion video thing.
It's really good.
Cool.
That's dope.
Yeah,
they're beautiful,
man.
That's funny.
That's one thing I noticed about,
again,
I watched the CEO video again last night
and just how bad camera phones were for,
uh,
for motion picture.
Oh yeah.
Like at the end of the video it's like
really,
you know,
that's an e eight,
15.
That's A.
Yeah.
Lg or Motorola made have been right
before the razor,
I think it was,
but it was that one that you flip open
and it was like the first camera phone
that did video and it was the ones that
you flipped open and it was side.
Oh no,
it wasn't.
It wasn't the envy.
It was way before the envy.
This was the first video phone which was
on verizon and my battery died when I
did them and see if there's [inaudible]
there's like an extra two hours that
they've never been seen.
But then my,
my,
it died and so then I was like,
fuck,
what do I do?
Oh my camera phone.
So the last part where Steve is easy and
all that.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Wow.
That's crazy that,
that was just a short amount of time
ago.
But if we ever landed on another planet
and found bugs,
like big giant bugs like that,
you know,
what a mind fuck that would be.
Have you landed on some planet?
And it was enormous.
Dinosaur size praying mantises running
around.
They attack the drone.
Like we landed drone somewhere and it
fucking picks up the drone and crushes
it,
starts sucking the batteries out of it,
or if it had all the same animals and
people and stuff,
but mixed together weird like humans
were like in love with ostriches or
something like that.
This,
what about a species specific meeting
wasn't necessarily that everything
fucked everything.
Hybrids.
Everywhere you looked like dog hybrids.
You can fucking.
You can fucking anything you wanted and
every.
Whenever you fuck something,
it would make a combination like
everybody get everybody pregnant,
including animals.
Get people pregnant.
That'd be so much fun.
So cool.
We'd be in the old comedy.
That little bear you get herpes out of
it,
but it'd be worth it.
It would be figuring out a way to make a
weapon to protect your butthole
everywhere you.
Every time you left the house,
something will be trying to fuck you and
get you pregnant and then you try to
tell people about this planet and all
they care about is your fucking tee
shirt.
Imagine how much.
Imagine how much more sensitive we would
all be to each other if we could.
All get pregnant if it was universal,
if everybody got pregnant,
I wouldn't trust anybody.
Like if there was no disparity.
Sleep.
Think about how much disparity there is
and like physical strength and ability.
Like we were looking at Shaquille o'neal
and his wife.
Obviously he's just so much bigger and
stronger than her.
Right,
but what if everybody was the exact same
size,
like all people are the exact same size
and everybody could get everybody.
Now you're talking.
What?
What would the reality of this world
bait?
Would there be more people or less
people will depend on our urges,
right?
We have the same urges.
It's probably the same amount of people.
We just figured out a way to deal with
the fact that we're just going to fuck
each other.
Yeah.
I think it would be relatively the same
amount of people because most.
I'd say most children come from a a
mutual relationship.
We'll just think about how many people
back in the Roman days,
how many men went gay because they were
just off on campaign together in there,
but fucking fees,
Musky unshaven shit.
Smeared assholes have soared murderer.
No babies should be born that way.
I mean this is not a love child.
The reason why they went case because
back then they didn't have anything to
clean their pussies and then he just
smelled really,
really bad like pussy smell and dude's
ass hole unless you're shooting out of
your pussy because you can wipe the
outside of your butthole out.
But like there's just like shit dying in
those pussies some.
I think some of it probably smelled
great.
I bet people you know,
like people are not supposed to be like
washing with soap,
you know,
they said that they say that like when
you wash with like one of the things a
big mistake people make when they do
Jujitsu,
don't take a shower right before you go
to class.
Right.
You actually shouldn't.
You should like limit your showering to
about two hours before class because
when you shower it takes about a half an
hour.
Supposedly from the stuff I've read,
obviously I'm no expert for your body's
natural flora to start to replenish
itself.
So if you go get scratched or you do
something where you're going to be in
physical contact with someone,
uh,
then you take a shower first,
you have a higher likelihood of you not
having the skin flora to fight off any
potential.
Weird Shit.
That's interesting because I always
shave after I shower.
We can do that.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
I mean it's different.
We're talking about Jujitsu.
No,
that's not the same as shaving.
It's almost like an injury.
What are you doing when you're shaving?
I always cut myself.
I'm sorry.
I guess I missed,
you know,
Jujitsu.
You get staph infections and funk.
Gotcha to ground.
So I think the point being that a
woman's natural flora,
like the natural bacteria in her body,
that's why one of the reasons why women
supposedly are more susceptible to yeast
infections when they take antibiotics
because antibiotics kills all the
bacteria.
The good stuff too.
And so they can get the poster form and
there's a smell.
And this is not any woman's fault.
Okay.
This is just unfortunate,
but there's a smell that is capable of
coming out of a vagina that until you
smell it,
you can't believe it,
and when you do smell it and you go,
how is this possible?
How is it possible that the human body,
what is,
what is the human body?
St will warn you.
He's trying to say this is good,
right?
Don't go down there.
How come?
If that's the case,
why doesn't hurt me smell?
I don't know.
It should.
How come?
Yeast infection smell,
but why doesn't venereal disease isn't a
person smell again.
And how can dog sometimes smell cancer?
That's what they train them to smell
cancer.
Did you hear about this guy that
recently lost his hearing and he can now
only here like Wifi signals wherever he
goes,
he's almost deaf,
but it's driving him crazy because he
can only hear Wifi signals.
Whoa.
That sounds like hell on her.
Well,
you know,
they say that bees can hear cell phone
signal's really.
Is that where they're dying off?
There's that.
And there's also pesticides,
like,
um,
they have a bunch of bs,
died off really recently,
like millions of bees and it coincided
with the production of some genetically
modified crop that resist pesticides was
real recent story.
I'll pull it up.
That's why these a big gossipy lately.
And bees bees going extinct as a way
bigger problem than say Koala bears go
extinct.
Right?
Yeah,
man.
Yeah.
These are really,
really a big issue.
When,
when bees die,
it's not good at all.
Trying to find the most recent shit.
It's,
it's a very recent story you've ever met
a guy that collected butterflies?
No,
the pins in the box.
I was just seeing that like in movies
and shit,
but I've never seen anyone actually do
it.
A man who can hear Wifi wherever you
will.
There's insecticides that they're
blaming on killing off bs.
I think apparently the Wifi signals and
the,
um,
any like radio signals and cell phone
signals,
they all have the potential to disrupt
the natural communication methods that a
lot of insects use and beads especially
are sort of susceptible to a cell phone
signals the flux with them.
Yeah,
millions of bees.
Did I to find this be used to because
they were trying to figure out what it
was.
Why did $37 million bees fall out of the
air?
Thirty 7 million.
Man,
that's pretty crazy.
And they're,
they're trying to put it together.
But some people of course are connecting
it with genetically modified corn.
So as the shock incident came just weeks
after genetically modified corn was
planted in Ontario,
according to the local honey gatherers
beekeeper,
Dave Schultz lost about $37 million
bees,
which is around 600 hives.
Whoa.
Urban homestead,
honey.com
is where he,
uh,
he did this interview.
He said once the corn started to get
planted,
our bees died by the millions that
collapsed in the local honeybee
population is called why caused
widespread concern with many pointing to
pesticides as the cause in the decline
of colonies.
Yet supposedly they were making a
comeback though.
Some recent reports like this one says,
after decline,
honey bears are appear to making honey
bees.
Honey bees.
Bigger bus kids need.
Um,
yeah man,
I don't know.
You know,
it's like when people fuck with nature
like that and you start messing around
adding pesticides and pesticide
resistant plants and you start fucking
with what that plan is and then these be
started dying.
You know,
I'm,
I mean I'm all for.
I'm all for people trying to improve
things,
but the,
this,
this seems like a complete disaster if
that's what it actually turns out to be
doing it.
That's scary shit too man.
That someone could just invent something
like that.
Thirty 7 million bees can die.
Like instantly.
Yeah.
That we're capable of doing that.
It was just total unintended consequence
of creating this pesticide resistant
plant.
You plant it and then just everything
dies dear start fucking stiff leg and in
the middle of the street and you don't
even fall from the sky.
You don't really know how it happened.
Yeah,
because birds eat the insects and
insects eat the pesticides and all the
shit just comes together and then you
get cancer from eating the birds and
you're promoting pseudoscience.
Man.
Why don't you just stand those
anti-vaccine man?
You're anti science.
I think it's actually,
there's science in $37 million bees
dying right after genetically modified
corn is being planted.
I think there's probably like science to
be had there.
I think so.
I feel like if you studied it and you
analyze the data,
just the idea of being a b is pretty
fucking trippy.
Living with a bunch of other assholes.
Yeah.
Making this weird fucking geometric
pattern with little cubicles and
everybody lives in these cubicles and
they all know how to do it.
They all know no bees come along with.
They forget the old ways and I had to
make hives every year.
They figured out how to make homes and
then that queen can't.
She goes around stabbing all the female
babies.
The Queen Bee is the only one that
doesn't have a retractable removable
her.
Her little pincher,
her little,
her little pussy nail that she has down
there.
Her Stinger doesn't go out.
She can stinky all day.
Right.
And the reason why so that she can
murder female babies.
So she goes near the hive,
sniffs out when she smells a female one
in the actual steps.
That shit out of it.
She's stabbing babies so she doesn't get
it.
It can be born so she doesn't get
overthrown by a female.
Exactly.
Because there can be only one.
It's like highlander which goes around
with their sword pussy and just starts
stabbing little little baby females in
their box before they even get hatched
and they spend their whole lives just
making honey.
Huh?
And they could be the size of horses.
It's more humane way.
Imagine.
Oh fuck that match.
If they were like elephants,
big conti flying elephants.
That stang babies would be.
Would we still be so kind?
If they gave us honey now.
Fuck honey.
At that point in fighter jets after
those bitches,
you hae a batch.
Would have been due to a fighter jet
though.
Probably just grab it and rip it apart
for b.
was the size of an elephant.
It probably just throw jets out of the
sky.
Just grab bitch.
Stick a Stinger right through it.
Take you to a volcano.
We see fucking live video.
The pilot screaming is the bees flew him
over the volcano and drop them in.
I hope we never get to this point.
I really do.
What do you think we would do if if
insects started getting bigger?
They just kept getting bigger and you
know how like every year it gets a
little warmer as well.
First I'd panic and not know what the
fuck did though.
How long would it take before we would
act if bees started getting like that
big of bees started getting that big and
if kids kids,
what I'm holding up is a coffee stirrer
that's probably about.
Was at about four inches.
Five inches.
Yeah.
Four or five inches.
Imagine the.
Okay,
let's go.
Six managers.
Six inch bees.
Would we still tolerate that?
No.
No,
no fucking way.
I would find a way to cook them.
They'll be like little lobsters.
Vicious,
but they're great.
What if they look soft?
Shell crabs.
Then I'm eating them.
Problem solve.
Well,
they're edible.
I know that puts some old bay on that
shit.
I'm pretty sure we made me bleed bees.
I know we did actually.
Yeah,
that will.
That's A.
I'm Asian Hornet.
That's a hornet.
They kill bees.
We've actually showed that video before
and it also got us pulled from youtube.
When did you start getting pulled from
youtube?
Like crazy man.
People have copyrights on all these
videos,
especially nature videos,
which we being the retards that we are
watching and whether they have those and
they put those on youtube,
they own the video.
So if you play it in,
even if it's fair use you play and do
commentary on it and even tell people to
go to see it on youtube.
Big still have a copyright call on you
and they pull your video down,
but it's not.
It's not like you're doing anything
illegal.
It is actually fair use.
Look at the image of that thing.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
That's probably like three inches long,
right?
That's a God damn bug to three at about
three inches long.
Half that guy's hand,
right?
About three inches too.
So I know what size my Dick is guys.
Guys,
Hey,
now that's about three inches.
That's a fucked up bug.
But if they were like a foot long,
we'd have to start taking them out.
We wouldn't tolerate it if they were
killing babies and shit.
If they were bird size,
pigeon size,
it'd be war against the bees.
Fuck honey.
Fuck.
Any repercussions of those fucks.
Oh,
we're already there.
One of those things.
What are they called?
Uh Oh.
We're looking at bees that are like cell
phones.
Those are like cell phone size piece
already.
That's a STARTAC.
Motorola STARTAC.
A
Asian giant Hornet Asian giant Hornet.
Fuck that.
No wonder the jumping off buildings in
Asia.
That's bullshit.
Jesus Christ,
his horn.
Hornet will be the last day before he
died.
Oh my God.
And that easily could,
you know,
staying the shit out of you and ruin
your week.
Yeah.
Sting.
You're writing your dick hole climbs on
your and you were inside your whole.
You wake up screaming in the.
You can't get the Stinger out because as
the Hornet dies,
it pulls out and you'll see the Stinger.
It's in there with the tweezers are too
big and you can't get it,
but you still take a picture of it
because your Dick is swollen because it
makes it look better.
It makes it look bigger tech by giant
Hornets,
the eight holes through his arm.
What?
I'm never going outside.
But is that from the venom?
From being stung?
Yeah,
but go to the actual page itself and see
if that's like if the venom erodes your
skin tissue or something like bullet
holes.
Nature.
Scariest.
Fuck Dude.
When I was up in Canada this week,
is that what it is in the stink and
dissolve human tissue,
so not cool.
The more we learn,
the more scared I am.
Dude,
go to the outside world,
go to my instagram and check out the
picture of the cow,
the calf rather the moose calf that got
torn apart by wolves that we found when
we were in British Columbia.
We're up in British Columbia and there's
a lot of wolves up there a lot.
Look at this.
Holy Shit.
We came upon that.
It was only like a day or so old because
there was still meat on the bones and
they're still like,
like the tissue,
like the meat tissue around the legs.
That was still there,
like wasn't rotten at all.
So it was a pretty,
pretty recent kill and there was hair,
all that white stuff that you see on the
ground,
that's all hair.
Geez.
All that stuff that you see,
it looks like feathers.
That's all moose hair.
And they uh,
the wolves had drawn a calf and calves
are huge.
A wall,
like I'm a moose calf is like the size
of a big deer,
like they're really big and just tore
this thing apart and we came upon it
whatever a day,
two days after they did it and we came
upon it because the Guy Mike,
that was the guy that we were with,
he saw crows flying overhead.
So it's like,
let's go find out what these guys are
eating right.
And we could smell it as we got closer,
but it's just so eerie to be right there
where you know,
that some wolves were like howling and
ripping apart this thing and he was
still alive.
The.
Oh yeah.
Well the horror of all that shit.
This guy who was there said that this
Guy Mike said that his friend had found
a moose that had lived for three days,
why wolves were eating it's ass and
somehow stayed alive and in shock,
and when they came upon the happened,
it took three days and they were there
when it first started and they didn't
step in.
They didn't intervene and the wolves I
can and they came back two and a half
days later.
That's fucking Moose was still alive.
Then shock while the wolves were like
eating its legs and its asset end
because if they eat it slowly,
like it just goes into shock and it
didn't die like he has no idea how it
stayed alive,
but it was alive for three fucking days
before they finally killed it.
So they were just feeding off of it
while it was still alive.
And oftentimes they eat it from the ass
first.
For whatever reason,
they have a natural instinct to take out
the back legs because the hamstring you,
when they take out the back legs,
you can't run away and then just start
eating you.
And so there's this,
there's this crazy video of these two
deer that had gotten into a fight.
They were like clashing antlers
together.
And when they clashed antlers together,
they got stuck.
Sometimes this happens,
deer get stuck and they can't.
They can't get away and they're like,
they're moving around,
their antlers are so interlocked,
they literally pulling apart and they
can't.
So the coyotes ate one of them while the
other one was still alive.
And so there's this video of these two
deer stuck together and one of the deer
is dead and these hunters had found it
and it had asshole first.
So these,
this pack of coyotes got ahold of the
one deer was eating it asshole first,
while the other deer was like,
move in and flip and attached to the
rest of the carcass is this deer.
So they finally went over and they
separated the two of them.
And then the one deer,
they let them go and then they took
photos and videos,
the deer that it was all fucked up,
but it had literally eating it.
Asshole first.
Jesus Christ.
Man.
I can't imagine.
I mean the other deer is alive.
Yeah.
Well this is happening.
Fuck man.
Nature is a scary.
So there's a bunch of coyotes in
Griffith Park.
Fuck yeah,
there are.
I see them running around all the time.
Be like they go into the neighborhoods
and stuff.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
As long as they have food,
you're okay.
Right.
But as soon as they run out of rabbits
and squirrels and shoot to kill and cats
and dogs and they start going into the
suburbs,
they start looking around for other shit
he buries too.
Sometimes he'll come across like coyote
shit that's filled with berries,
which I was.
I thought it was weird.
I didn't know that coyotes weren't
totally carnivores and I'd never heard
that.
So just now.
Do you think you could eat a coyote if
you had to stay alive?
If I had to.
It sounds like a lot of work though and
I don't know if I really know how to do
it.
Do I have a knife?
How to kill it?
You mean I have a knife and do I have
fire one thing?
Yeah,
you have fire and yes.
You have a knife because you have to gut
it.
Okay.
Then.
Yeah,
I could do it.
You don't want to cook it with the guts
in tact.
Hmm.
Right.
Yeah.
No,
I mean you got to take,
you got gut.
You got to skin it,
you got to cook it.
That's the world of nature,
man.
And you've got to eat it and then
you're,
you know.
Then you got to do it again tomorrow.
The full charge.
Have you ever thought about going
hunting?
Um,
I went hunting one time.
I shot a bird.
What kind of,
I don't know.
Did you eat it?
No,
it was terrible.
It was a terrible thing to do and I felt
horrible and I moved on with my life.
It was a shotgun.
The bird had no chance whatsoever.
That's a weird thing.
People say,
why don't you make it fair?
You can't.
We can't make it fair.
Dude.
A beaver will kill you if you try to
make it fair.
Right?
Beaver will fuck you up.
Like you can't use your hands and you
have to like get on the ground trying to
bite it.
I think that the beaver will,
when they eat trees with their face,
how are you going to kick a beaver's
asked now you got to use a weapon.
Yeah.
You're not going to win.
There's no fair.
Nothing's fair.
We should have fucking shotguns for this
shit.
People want to like that.
This one thing that people want to say
like,
why don't you make it fair?
To make it fair,
we would have to be like a 50 slash 50
proposition that you would die and that
the animal would kill you.
Yeah.
Fifty slash 50.
The animal will die.
50 slash 50.
You would die.
It's not going to happen.
Why would an animal is going to win?
Why would you do that?
That seems so stupid.
It seems like such.
That's distorting what's going on
because we ultimate fighting with
animals.
Are we eating them?
Like what's going on?
We're eating though.
I mean do we have animal weight classes?
Like you know,
like we have to find out like what was
our will fuck up a 20 pound house cat?
If I get ahold of it,
it'll probably scratch me up.
But the bottom line is if I can get
ahold of it and get its back legs just
bashed his head on the ground,
I'm going to kill that cat most likely
with my hands.
But a 30 pound cat,
he might fuck me up a 40 pound cat.
I'm going to be really scared of 50
pound cat will probably kill me.
Yeah.
Fifty pound cat will most likely kill
me.
So you'd have to like for,
for fairness sake,
you'd have to have like a 35 pound cat
fight.
Right?
Or normal person do trust me.
But I tell you that I was scared of this
kitten that I had.
Feral kitten.
I'm telling you man,
when when the shit goes down and cats
are fighting for their lives,
a 30 pound,
35 pound cat will give you a beating.
We'll look at that report or that video.
The reporter then they kept going up the
record,
his leg and two,
they'll fuck you up man.
They live in a totally different world
of movement.
They live in a world of superhuman
athleticism.
Yeah.
You know,
a 35 pound cat as a formidable foe.
30 five pound pit bull is a dangerous
little dog.
You versus a kangaroo fighting.
Trying to kick my ass.
Kangaroo would kick my ass.
The only way I'd be able to beat a
kangaroo is if it didn't understand not
to give up.
It's back.
I mean if there's somehow or another
that I could scramble with the kangaroo,
like you would try to kick me and I
would know it's going to try to kick me
so I get out of the way an arm drag it.
I'd have to arm drag it and have to take
it's back.
Okay.
No Jujitsu.
Only a kickboxing I would lose.
Most likely.
Didn't Woody Allen box a kangaroo?
No.
Tiny man.
He did.
And digital's children?
No,
he blocks the kangaroo in like the
sixties on the tonight show or
something.
Come on.
I'm serious.
Brian,
can I get some help?
I'll look it up real quick.
Um,
you remember the old looney tune
kangaroo?
It was always a boxer.
The boxing gloves.
Well they definitely have kangaroo
boxing.
Yeah.
I mean I've seen that.
I've seen videos of that.
Oh,
what are y'all in boxing a kangaroo.
God,
how do you not get hurt but you don't
play.
This is going to get us pulled.
I don't know.
Can you think?
60 six.
Let's find out
tonight on hippodrome.
You're gonna.
Watch me fight the Australian light.
Heavyweight champion.
Boxed warning.
Oh my God.
It really is a cane.
This is so funny.
If you tried to do this today,
if you tried to do this today,
people would say that.
This is like animal cruelty.
I'm going to blog about this right now.
Look at him moving around.
Wow.
I can't believe this is real.
That that fucking kangaroos going to
Jack Him.
He actually moves pretty God damn good.
Yeah,
he does that.
And Woody Allen box before they say it
was a good athlete.
I'm telling you,
man,
he's moving pretty good.
That's not a guy kicked him.
Wow.
The guys pushing them into it.
That's just fucking fucked up.
This is good writing,
right?
Punch that guy behind him here.
That kangaroos dead.
Because if he does that shit to me,
I'm taking this back.
I guarantee you that kangaroo has zero
choke defense.
You need to update this bit,
Joe.
Dude,
he's moving well.
Yeah.
Just to kick it,
you're not allowed to kick and box a
kangaroo because that made me start
kicking.
I don't want to take them.
You don't want to take them.
See that?
That's what I'm saying.
He can hurt you,
man.
They hurt you.
Oh God,
baby.
Jesus,
believe that they grab you and kick you
spit on the ground.
Whoa.
Keep it going man.
I want to say fuck that kangaroo up
right there.
That's good.
Dead Kangaroo right there.
If I get that position,
I'm throwing the hooks in.
I'm riding his back.
He's not going to know what's up.
I'll choke the shit out of a kangaroo.
Yeah,
I changed the position.
If I was that guy in the suit,
I'm killing that kangaroo with my hands.
That's just how it's gone down.
What can you do?
I would never be in that position.
I would never fucking buck.
I think it's cool as shit,
man.
Isn't that funny?
He such like known as such an
intellectual comedian that woody.
Yeah.
And then he just,
and then he just fights a kangaroo is a
bit.
It's not his idea.
Obviously.
It might've been.
He was young.
I seems fake.
Piss and vinegar.
It seems like fun.
Dude.
Seems terrifying.
You Woody Allen moves pretty good.
I'm pretty impressed.
I bet he boxed.
I really do.
I,
he's definitely into something.
The way he moved.
He's always talking about fights and
going to fights.
He didn't move like a,
uh,
like there's some guys that go to
boxercise,
like Bryan county goes to this place box
and burn going.
You get a lot of these executives that
have never barks a day in their life and
they're in there at like drawing these
ridiculously uncoordinated punches and
it's comical to watch.
But that,
that was not that.
Like the way he was moving.
Yeah.
He looked like he knew what he was
doing.
Would you fight Woody Allen today?
A Yes for a lot of money or whatever.
How much?
How much publicity stunt to fight woody
Allen.
But if you fucked him up,
I,
I'd back off.
There'd be a ref you back off if you had
them.
Right.
If I were talking about like a boxing
match,
right,
whatever you want to do,
how do you want to do it?
You could do it.
Tom.
Post little funny looking glass and
rope.
Claude van Damme.
I wouldn't want referees.
I wanted to be like a civil fight.
I wouldn't wanna I wouldn't wanna beat
up with woody allen too bad.
But like you're saying,
he looked like he knew what he was doing
and I don't know what I'm doing so who
knows?
But I think I could take them,
but he's older now and I think we can
take them.
Yeah.
And pushed both the public shame.
There's experience.
Probably fuck with the psyche.
Like he doesn't deserve to win.
I would fight him for money,
but I wouldn't want to hurt him.
I like him.
Oh,
that's sweet.
Do you still like them even though,
you know,
he's kind of a creeper.
Uh,
that really creeps me out actually.
But I still kinda like his,
uh,
his movies and stuff.
Yeah.
It's not a weird thing with the guy like
woody Allen.
It's like,
you know,
you gotta you still like Roman Polanski.
People still support him as an artist,
but then you find out he drugged and
fucked a 13 year old.
No,
it's horrible.
What Rosemary's baby wasn't that good
that I'm fucking sticking up for Roman
Polanski,
but.
But woody,
I don't know.
I have a greater connection to,
but I'm also completely grossed out by
the idea.
It's basically a step kid that he raised
and I think that's very strange where
there's an image of her sitting on his
lap as like a father figure or going to
a basketball game and then an image
later,
many years later was holding her hand as
a boyfriend,
girlfriend at a basketball.
I think that's really manipulative.
Oh,
100 percent.
But that's why I want to fight him.
He's got it.
There's a great comedy album that are
downloaded accidentally that I thought
was a.
I don't have that phone anymore,
so I don't have it on me here,
but there's a great comedy album that I
downloaded that I thought was woody
Allen doing stand up.
Yeah,
but it turned out to be woody Allen
giving an interview about standup,
so it was like woody Allen on Standup,
I think it's called and it's really
interesting man,
because it sort of applies to stand up
today,
a lot of the ideas and the principles
and leverage these talking about
performers versus writers and what's
good and what's not good.
And it was really interesting man.
He was good man.
When I first started doing standup,
somebody had like an open mic at the
coconut
teaser,
handed me a tape.
I had one side was bill Hicks dangerous
and the other side with some woody Allen
Stanhope record and it was a pretty good
fucking tape that somebody handed him.
Yeah.
It was not bad,
man.
I think this one,
this one audio thing,
woody Allen on standup a,
this one audio thing really should be
something that people should,
uh,
should play,
like a comics should play and listen to
it because just to get a historical
perspective of what it was like to be
kind of at the forefront.
I mean,
if you think about like you're talking
about the early sixties.
Yeah,
no,
it was before it was the,
you know,
the people talk about stand up in the
seventies and was like when,
when it got crystallized as what standup
is today,
but,
but those guys in the sixties,
like Woody Allen,
he tells jokes,
man,
it's pretty similar to what happens now.
Go to woody Allen.
Stand up 65 rare.
It's on youtube.
It's a.
He was in England filming.
What'd you go for?
Kangaroo.
Kangaroo may fight.
There was movies that.
Can we scratch that guy up?
Man.
There was.
Oh,
this is real.
Is this real?
It's like a movie about a guy for a
movie that's definitely breaks the legs.
Oh Jesus.
This is a terrible movie.
Kick him in the chest.
There was a lot of kangaroo boxing
movies,
I feel like.
Came out in the eighties.
Was big in the eighties that Cain rose
mean you just can't reason with the
kangaroo.
Terrible,
terrible fucking screen.
If that gets kicked off Youtube,
I'm going to be so pissed at you.
What's the video be like?
Oh,
a woody allen.
Stand up.
Sixty five rare.
It's a more subtle form of comedy.
This woody Allen,
but it'll do.
It's really good though.
It's really good to see like what comedy
was in 1965,
you know,
to see like this guy who is known more
of like as a film maker and play it a
little bit
and when I was younger I used to hang
out a lot the museum in search of a
meaningful social relationships.
So I used to look for girls.
We played this before the world was a
new group,
but our real succulent nude,
naked huntress stabbing to death,
a warthog and I got very emotionally
involved with the painting,
you know,
to God had to restrain me,
write the lyrics over the oil,
off the camera.
It's one of those things where like when
you know his history now it's kind of
weird.
Washington talk about sex and perversion
and giving into indulgence and idea.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
he seems obsessed with sex.
But yeah.
It's also interesting though to see like
just how physically was.
Yeah,
it's not over the top,
but he's doing like
his tricks that he's obviously learned
to make people pay attention.
Yeah.
He's moving around a lot.
That's a good way to put.
Yeah,
dance moves because some dance moves and
he used to do like cafe wha and that he
used to do like those folk scene.
Mike's really?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They'd be like,
what does cafe wall.
It's like we're a Hendrix and dylan and
everybody played in the village.
Really share the stage.
Joan rivers was there.
Bob Dylan was there.
It was nuts,
man.
It was this one venue where like people
tried out more artistic things.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's got to be really bizarre,
man.
And do standup.
The intermixed with all these other.
Yeah,
because yeah,
standup wasn't.
I don't think there used to be shows
where you go see a whole standup show
back in the day.
It was just part of the show.
That's why in Annie Hall,
Woody Allen Goes,
well,
I don't want to go on after a comedian.
You know why you have to be going on
after comedian.
Like that wasn't done back in the day.
It was more of a variety show thing.
Magicians jugglers,
hat tricks and yeah,
in musicians and makes you realize like
how young stand up comedy really is all
our,
all our forms of human expression.
Think about like films,
films only been around for 100 or so
years,
you know,
books,
literature has only been around for 100
years or something like that to people
and writing things down.
I mean there's obviously written
language from way,
way,
way back in the day,
like the cuneiform tablets and shit for
like 6,000
years ago.
But like how long has it been where
people have like acknowledged that with
their writing is bullshit.
Like this is fiction.
I'm making this up.
I want you to like I'm telling you a
story that I totally made up.
How long has that been?
Not that long,
right?
Not Long.
I don't know.
Obviously long time for like human life.
Sure.
But not that long in terms of
perspective of the age of the human
being or the age of the earth.
So all this is like super new,
super new,
and one of the newest is standup and one
of the newest of the newest is mediums.
Yeah.
Like jokes and form jokes in meme form
or less than a decade old,
right.
Cosby mean.
Yeah.
Right.
Like you just saw the bill cosby thing,
right?
Uh,
the,
the story.
Yeah.
The bill cosby meme.
No,
I haven't seen it.
Oh,
you don't know what happened?
No.
One of the greatest moments in internet
history happened.
Bill cosby.
Okay.
Yeah.
A little story about bill cosby and
accused of sexual assault and rape and
all this jazz.
He put a meme generator on his own
website that said,
go ahead,
meme me.
And the first picture is him saying
happy Monday,
you know,
like this.
And then just,
it was a rape fest,
like everything was raped this and
brophy's that and you know,
Jello pudding and roof fees and gel
putting in rape and fucking crazy idea.
They examples were my favorite because
they're like,
look,
you could make memes like this,
like,
hey,
nice hat.
And it just seems like a bill cosby
holding his hat when you see like the
ones that the people made was like,
Hey,
this is your dad or your mom,
or something like that.
It went from zero to rape in about eight
seconds.
Well,
what's interesting is there's the
conspiracy is that anybody who's smart
enough to construct a website is going
to be like in tune with the Internet.
Yeah.
Anybody who's working for him and he's
making websites,
that fucking person.
I don't want to throw this person under
the bus,
but that person has to know what the
fuck is going to happen.
Very attuned to the Internet.
You put a meme generator up after the
Hannibal burress video comes out and
after all these people are talking about
it,
you got to know that they're going to
meet him some awful shit.
Yeah.
This is the Internet.
People do all kinds of vicious things.
Spatially.
Anything's too funny and vicious at the
same.
Especially when they get the green
light.
Oh yeah.
If you're a drugging rapist,
all bets are off,
right?
Yeah.
But it's Cosby cosby.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
This is a weird almost epilogue.
I don't want to say his career's over,
but it's a weird,
he said such a long career.
This is a weird thing to be happening at
the last minute.
It's not just the last minute.
It was clear the last minute of his
life.
Yeah.
And if it was only like dementia and he
was doing things recently and you get
attributed to like,
well there's something wrong with them,
but then these people coming out with
the stories that he's been doing this
since the seventies.
Yeah.
And as late as 2004.
So after the cosby show.
Damn Damn.
What is it,
man?
That goes on in a person's brain that
makes them completely disconnect from
humanity that makes them just be able
to.
Fame can get you their candidate fame
and money.
Can you think that's it?
That's all it takes.
No.
Drugging women and raping them.
No,
but I think it can help you feel like
you're above the law or you're entitled.
Yeah,
I think it can,
but I don't know for sure.
Rich privilege.
Yeah.
Black privilege.
Now I can't say that Black Gypsy
privilege.
No,
you can't say that.
Can't say any of those things you just
said.
Giving famous.
Kind of make you go a little crazy.
Too famous too.
Definitely can make you go crazy and
famous can definitely make you think
you're different from other people.
Especially if you get fame when you're
young.
I think when you live like all
throughout your puberty and adulthood,
you're,
everywhere you go.
People Kissing your ass.
Your idea of how you interact with
people is you will literally think of
yourself as being like royalty or
something.
Right?
Can't there be a lot of suppressed anger
with someone like bill cosby too.
I mean he,
he had to um,
be a very like,
friendly black entertainer for like a
lot of white audiences even though
probably a lot of the venues he was
playing,
they wouldn't even let him go in the
dressing room and shit.
Like there could be a lot of suppressed
anger from someone that had to go
through something like that.
That's possible.
But I mean,
since the 19 eighties,
yeah,
yeah.
It's like you've got to feel like that's
a long time to harbor a grudge.
Yeah.
But 34,
35 years of like undeniable success.
Yeah.
I mean,
how many years has he been super
successful for?
Oh,
I'd say since at least the seventies.
Probably the sixties and all throughout
the eighties.
When I was a kid,
we played that Noah's ark thing like
Noah and talking to God.
We played that when I was a little kid.
Yeah.
You know Noah,
what God right.
That was.
That was a great bit.
That was a great bit and we played that
on a record.
You're like a fucking album.
We'd sit there with the headphones on
and listen to that.
Yeah.
That guy just doesn't seem right that
that guy was the rapist.
That's like the sweaters alone are
enough to make you think that's not a
rapist.
You know?
One thing that kind of leads me in that
direction besides all the obvious,
is that he always into like people being
clean and always into like yelling at
comics for using dirty word pressing.
Do you remember like the whole Eddie
Murphy thing?
Yeah.
I called up,
Richard just said I have a coconut smile
and shut the fuck up.
You know.
Did,
did the audience laugh?
Did you get paid to have a coconut smile
and shut the fuck up?
You mean that was Richard Pryor given
Eddie Murphy advice in which apparently
was a real conversation.
The next time he calls,
tell him I said,
suck
you gotta think like if a comic called
you,
you know,
like say if like Jerry Seinfeld called
you up and said,
listen,
you're very funny.
Yeah.
All you're doing is wrong.
You know,
you're always seeing you out there on
stage and talking about your Dick.
Right.
Stopped doing it.
You're making white America look bad.
Right?
Can you imagine if someone came up to
you and was like,
I can't imagine.
And I think,
I think Eddie was like kind of confused
now that you're doing this to me.
He was like,
his,
is he right?
I don't know if he's right or not.
Let me call Richard Skinner you to stop
swearing.
Mediamath Eddie Murphy back then was um,
so far like during delirious when he
would go on stage with that fucking
leather suit on and shit.
And Oh my God,
so funny man.
He was like the original arena comic,
you know,
he was doing back then and to get a call
from bill cosby telling you to stop
being dirty.
I think there's a little jealousy in
there and I think there's a little bit
of,
oh,
things are changing.
I better try to slow them down part.
Or he had this idea in his head that was
just immobile.
She's like,
dirty is bad and eat.
There's so many people that still think
that like that's an easy way out or
something.
It's like,
it's like saying rock and rock and roll
music is not,
it's not the way to go in all the drums
and heavy bass and classical music is
where it's at now.
Classical music,
classical music,
dirty comedy is comedy.
So it's like there's this kind of comedy
and those,
that kind of comedy.
This is comedy that's clean but fucking
hilarious.
Like Hedberg,
Mitch Hedberg,
squeaky clean.
Almost all of his jokes were clean,
still unbelievably fucking hilarious.
So funny.
And then there's Joey Diaz who's never
done a clean set ever in his life and he
makes me laugh harder than any person
that's ever walked the face of the
world.
I know.
It's just comedy,
man.
Yeah.
So if a guy like bill crosby calls you
up,
fucks with you like that.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Meanwhile it was a chick tied to his bed
and he's talking to Eddie Murphy.
You hear in the background mark,
good to you later.
Deb.
Barb it up.
Jello pudding.
Well,
didn't he?
By the little rascals.
He bought the little rascals and stopped
it from ever being distributed because
it was so racist.
That's cool.
Didn't Michael Jackson do something like
that?
Also wasn't little rascals,
but Michael Jackson did something very
similar where he bought good times,
right?
Was it good times?
No,
I don't think so.
I think you're thinking of the Beatles.
He bought the Beatles music,
the Beatles music.
You're just butchering history and then
you put it in a nike commercial.
Do you remember that?
Okay.
Snipes.
It might be a snopes,
rather it says it might not be true.
It's false.
Oh,
okay.
The bill cosby bought the rights,
the little,
the little rascals or our gang comedies
or to keep them off television because
they depict racial stereotypes,
false spanky,
Alfalfa,
buckwheat,
Darla,
just a few of the easily recognizable
names that were found were fond part of
the childhoods of generations of kids.
What the fuck?
Why aren't they on TV?
In 1989,
the began circulating the entertainer.
Bill cosby had bought up the rights a
little rascals,
bla bla bla bla bla bla bla bla bla.
Nothing to do with it.
Of course,
king world productions has owned and
licensed the rights to little rascals
for over 30 years.
This series has been syndicated
television many times in the video
rights to some episodes were licensed to
cabin fever entertainment.
Nineteen 97.
So bill cosby has never owned any part
of the right to little rascals.
Yeah.
So who the fuck owns that shit?
Cosby was one of the prominent names who
campaign to pressure CBS,
do withdrawing Amos and andy from
syndication back in the 19 sixties.
My mom loved that show.
Amos and Andy,
did she,
uh,
did she yell racial?
No,
no,
there was,
there wasn't a lot of racism in the
house,
but to facts name the cat,
sambo and uh,
said she liked Amos and Andy and even
used to do the voice.
Where'd you grow up?
And I,
I grew up in southern Maryland but she's
from New Jersey and that was like,
I swear to God,
these things I'm bringing it up,
make it sound crazy.
But these are like two isolated
incidences that never really added up to
much.
But I remember them because there was so
weird and out of place in my household.
What made you become a comic?
What went wrong?
Uh,
I dunno,
I just,
whenever I was school I always had smart
shit to say.
Just popped into my head and I had to
say it like smart.
I wanted the attention,
yes.
Smart as shit.
And I liked the attention and it seemed
like the easiest way to get attention
and it seemed like something that was
good at.
And listen,
I had an instinct not to be a part of
the group for some reason.
I don't know why,
but it wasn't about my mom like Amos and
Andy.
I don't think you're funny motherfucker,
man.
Joe,
thank you for coming on here man.
And tell people where they can reach you
and where they can buy tickets for this
fucking fantastic tour you're embarking
on.
Check out the full charge.com
and come out to the show.
Come out to the show.
So if you live on the west coast,
northern California,
Portland,
Oregon,
Seattle,
Washington.
I'm making your steam song the food
charge to,
to the food chart tonight.
Tommy store return of me.
Um,
that's a lot of other people on the show
to who's on the show.
We got a bunch of charge.
Will be charged on a couple of the kill.
Tony Girls are going to be there for me.
All right,
we'll see you fox.
We love the shit out of you and I'll be
back next week.
Lots of cool guests.
This thing keeps fucking moving along.
Train kept rolling all night long.
Much love.
Big Cast
Tyrell,
this Russian.