Four, three, two, one, boom. And we're
live. What's up brother? How are you?
Very, very good. Thanks for doing this
man. I'm very excited to have you in here.
I'm honored to be here man.
I was just thinking about
this. It actually, I was like
the fucking people that have
been on the show, man. Yeah,
I think about it sometimes too.
Freaks me out. Uh, Sam Harris,
James Hetfield. Uh, man. Yeah. I
was thinking about all the people,
man. I was like, how do I compete with
these guys? Just be Matt Brown. I know.
Talking about man.
I mean I could beat all their asses.
Well, in certain situations,
that's all the counts,
the situations that I
thrive in. Exactly. So, uh,
you are retired and now you're not now
he just signed a fight. Carlos condit.
You got it. Damn. That's a good
fight. Oh, like that. Yeah.
I think Carlos needed to fight
back to that fight with Neil Magni.
He looked like he was suffering
through some ring rust.
Yeah,
man timing.
I've talked to a lot of people about
that cause that's the first thing that
always comes up, right. It is how he
came back and looked in that fight.
And I've shared with Neil
a lot, man. I'll tell you,
Neil can shut a fucking game down
right away. Yeah. Very good. Yeah.
We can't take away from the Hitman.
Um,
Carlos didn't seem to show any sense
of urgency either though. So, you know,
I think it's both sides,
but I think he's also going to be
looking for redemption with me. Yeah,
I think so too. Yeah. He wanted
to come back right away actually.
They actually asked me to fight. It was,
would have been like six weeks notice.
What's the longest you've ever taken off?
Okay.
Uh,
after I fought,
cowboy got knocked the fuck out and
took a year off from five days ago.
So what does it like
coming back after a year?
Okay.
It felt natural to me
personally to you. Yeah. Yeah.
I didn't feel anything
different people, right. Yeah.
Someone was talking to me about this
Sarah Day ring rust and I was like,
you know,
everybody's different man.
Every single person is going
to react a little differently.
And I think also when you have someone,
you know,
John Danaher was talking about like
the different types of fighters, right?
I think he just group three
different types of fighters.
Uh, like a violence guy,
a tactical guy, and something
else. Well, I think it's gonna.
I think there's more types of fighters
and what he went through, but there's, um,
I think it's going to affect every single
type of person differently, you know,
and I felt like I fought,
for instance,
like I fought them much more tactical
fight against Diego. It wasn't, I mean,
you could,
you could easily go and with Diego and
just go to fucking war with him. Right?
I mean, he's Melendez style. Exactly.
He's totally down for that. Diego was,
you know, he will wake right up and
go for that. Right. I was like, man,
I'm better than him. Let's
just be tactical. And a,
I think that was part of why it
helped now that now I think, uh,
someone that goes in with
a more violence style, uh,
which I've done many times in
my life. Um, I think that's a,
a bit more complicated because there's
a lot more timing in reaction in that
whereas the strategy,
you have very clear path to victory,
you know exactly what you got to do is
just you just going in there and just, um,
you know,
connecting the dots when you get in there
and staying on the plan.
Exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
Now when you get a guy like Diego though,
that temptation has gotta be always
there, right? Because he's so willing.
Well, if a, if it is necessary
because you love that kind of fighting,
that's one of the reasons
why you're so loved.
Like there's never been a matte
brown fight ever. That's boring.
There's a lot of guys that
have because of styles,
because of whatever they've had fights
that weren't very crowd pleasing,
but your style has always been do or die,
seek and destroy.
That's one of the reasons
why people love you.
Yeah. Well, I mean,
that just goes back to my mentality of
why I'm fighting to start with, right?
It's not really about just winning.
I think that's sort of a western culture
thing. Sort of an American thing. Like I,
I kind of go back to the original pride
and it's like, look, just fight man.
You know,
this is a fun thing.
This is a bad ass thing we're doing is
an amazing thing. Go in there and fight,
test yourself, the Bushido
spirit, things like that. And not,
it doesn't have to be just win at
all costs, you know, this is, uh,
you know, to me it waters
down the sport. I mean,
that's not what combat is about.
Some, you know, it's not me.
Well, I mean, that's what
makes it interesting is that
there are different styles.
There's people that have safety first
styles where they're just fighting new
wind.
And then there's other people
like yourself that just
whatever's inside you that
comes out, you know, I always said
this, there's certain dudes like, uh,
because of your history, because of, uh,
I mean you had an overdose
where you literally died.
And there's the same with court McGee. Uh,
he had the same situation happened. Him,
I always said,
talked to him.
Dudes that have gone to the other side
are fucking terrifying inside of the
cage. There's like, there's,
there's a certain thing,
I don't know if it's just coincidentally
that both of you guys have that mindset
or let's forget about even core, but you
have this mindset. And I've always said,
I wonder if there's a correlation between
such extreme lows in your life where
you bought them down so hard.
Literally,
your body had shut down
and you were ready to,
you ready to pass on the doctor saved you,
and you've got a mindset going
into that cage. That's just,
it's just another notch more
intense than most people,
certainly. And that that's,
uh, you know, to be honest,
that's something I've sort of struggled
with a lot too because it wasn't
actually that specific moment.
The overdose that kind of
affected me the way it did.
It was more a long term life of a,
well I would say I've just
been an angry person, honestly,
like just since I grew up. So it was
all about channeling that anger. Um,
a lot of fighters like
that. Right? I think so.
I think it was one of the beauties of
martial arts that helps you channel that.
Yeah. I mean we all have
to find an outlet. Um, I,
I didn't discover martial arts,
uh,
until what, 2123 to 21,
22, something like that.
And, uh, you know, I said before, my
outlet was drugs and alcohol, you know,
that was my, my way to say
fuck everybody. Right. And, uh,
you know, just went too far.
But, uh, like I said, you know,
when a is expressed in the cage,
that's more of a longterm thing
growing up an angry person.
And then, um, you know, I always give a
lot of credit to Jamie Josta hate breed,
you know, uh, that's where
I'll walk out to nowadays.
It's a dream come true to have a
walkout song by them. And, uh, um,
that was like the first time that I was
able to find a positive outlet for that
energy. You know, I didn't know
what heavy metal was and growing up,
you know what I mean? I, I grew
up in a small farm town and uh,
I didn't know what that was,
but heavy metal gave me an outlet.
And hate breed was the first one that
gave me a positive outlet before it was a,
it was negative. Pantera,
slayer, like stuff like this,
it's all negativity, you
know. So this rage is,
is coming out in a negative sense and
get to express through drugs, alcohol,
hanging with the wrong
people and things like that.
And then there's a turning
point where I'm like, man,
this can be a positive thing and I
can use this energy directed towards
something positive. What were you angry
about growing up? A good question.
Um, man, that goes deep,
man, because, uh, you know,
I grew up in a very, very, very
small town, 200 people population.
I didn't see a skyscraper.
And until I was,
I mean like up in person, like
we drove by it in Dayton, Ohio,
which is in a big town in itself, um,
until I was like over 18 years old,
you know, so I was, I always felt like
there was so much more out there for me.
And I was kind of, expat grew up in a
machine shop. My Dad was a machinist,
so I was doing that from like five years
old. I was sweeping the fucking floor.
And I was like, I was like, man, this
is not what I'm meant to be. Like,
I'm supposed to be something great.
But, uh, but everybody around me is,
I know this is what you do.
You live in this little town and you do,
you follow the rules, you're going to
be a machinist or a farmer or you know,
whatever. And uh, you know, that
Shit pissed me off, you know?
And I never really found my niche.
And so I was homeschooled actually
for I think two years in junior high.
So I think that was sort of actually the
start because I went back to school and
when I went back to school, I was now
the outsider. I didn't have any friends.
Um, and then going up, uh,
all of a sudden I'm in high school and
I have no friends. I have no, uh, I,
I can't get laid for shit.
Um,
I think that's what causes you care and
a lot of people in the world, right?
Oh yeah. And depression.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And at the exact same time,
I'm starting to experiment
with drugs and alcohol.
So you put the two together, you
know, um, I was supposed to be, um,
the prodigal son, you know what I mean?
Like I was very intelligent. I was,
um,
you know,
I like I was doing things by the time
I was 15 years old in the machine shop,
that guys,
they've been working for my father for 10,
15 years, couldn't do. You know
what I mean? So I was sort of,
this product was saying I was
good at athletics and everything,
had no problem with all that stuff. So I
think, uh, it was just sort of a backlash,
you know? And then I let that
anger get the best of me.
So now when you were doing drugs and
alcohol, what were the drugs like?
What was the drug that
caused you to overdose?
Heroin and injection.
Yeah. Damn, that's deep.
When you're injecting it, that's, that's
when you're all in baby. And you know,
I didn't actually do it a whole lot.
It's kind of the funny thing.
A lot of people thought that I was
addicted to heroin and I wasn't.
I think that was probably
the fifth time that I did it.
Maybe six something like I
didn't count, but, um, you know,
that was sorta my fuck.
That was my step into the dark side,
you know, and it, and a blessing
and a curse man, you know,
it immediately he was like, oh,
okay. That's what can happen. Right.
It's the step back. Uh, and you
know, I was very naive, very,
uh, man, I was a fool really,
like, because what I did,
I remember leaving the, uh, uh,
the hospital and I was like, okay,
well I'm never doing heroin again,
but let's go do some coke.
Right? So I was just a dummy man. Um,
I think I was 21, 22, one of those,
I mean it was like 15 years ago.
There's a lot of stuff. I,
I, I was actually kind of
thinking about like, so again,
you know, on this podcast, I was
like, uh, cause that, you know,
there's probably going to come up on
it. It's a pretty intense story. Um,
I was like, damn, I can't remember
all the details of that shit.
It was like a long time ago. But
anyway, yeah. So I was like 21,
22 and um,
it wasn't too much long later,
you know, I'll live with this girl. And
you know, she was a drug addict too,
and she had a couple of kids and it
was like, it was like, all right,
well now I've got a place to
live. Like, let's get fucked up,
you know? And it was a, I never did
heroin again after that, obviously.
Um, I think I did oxies though.
Percosets stuff like that. He's basically
the same thing. Right? Yeah. Which, which,
I mean,
I didn't realize it at the time,
but really my drug of choice
was meth back in that day.
That was what I really liked.
And that was actually what I
was addicted to at one point.
And I ended up going to jail and that
was what got me out of addiction.
I didn't realize I was
addicted until I was in jail.
So what made you realize that when
you were in jail or just, you know,
just couldn't stop thinking about
it and just won it and just, I mean,
I didn't get to have like, like,
um, like cold sweats or anything.
I don't think that happens with uppers,
but, um, I mean, I was just, you know,
like the couldn't stop thinking
about it, man. I was like, dude,
like just a lot of that anger was
coming out. It was just like, God, like,
what the fuck I wanted to
fight. Everybody. I was like,
somebody gave me something,
you know, and wow. Yeah. It was
just really terrible experience.
But probably my lasted
three, four days. Not even,
maybe not even that. And then you came out
of it. Yeah. I mean, I was just like, eh,
able to accept my fate and deal with it.
What does it feel like to be on mouth?
You would take Adderall. I had
never taken an Adderall. No, I'm
pretty similar to Adderall. Right?
Yeah. It's like Adderall. I mean,
that's the closest I
would say. Um, I mean,
you're high. Uh, but
you don't have, I mean,
it says that euphoria more than
anything just to, excuse me.
Just an extreme sense of euphoria.
Just everything is beautiful.
But then men, soon as you start
to lose that a little bit,
you just itch for, it's so bad, man,
so bad that you just
want it again. You, you,
you don't want to sleep like your teeth
to be grinding and you're just like, ah,
you're just tensing up all your muscles.
I God. Well, I got to get more of that,
you know? Now, what are you working
out at all back then? No, well,
I take, well not working out
like it should be. So again,
I was angry a lot of times.
Like I'd be at a party that this was a
common thing I'd be at like a party or
just doing drugs, whatever. And I just
started getting look at everybody,
like I don't like none of you.
And I would just walk outside and,
and I would go for a run.
I'd run five, six miles, come
back and be like, all right,
give me another line or
whatever. Wow. Yeah. Um, and
run and then come back to the,
yeah. And then sometimes I would, I would
fight people, you know, that was common,
very,
very common if you call that working out.
And we,
like this particular time in my life,
I was living in a little town called
Jamestown, Ohio. And I had this buddy,
he was friend, his cousin,
his cousin was a fighter.
And this was kind of my first
foray into mixed martial arts or first,
uh, experience watching it and everything.
And, uh, they would train in the
grass in the backyard. You know,
I remember watching Ken shamrock
DVDs are VHSs back then,
um, leg locks. We'd go
on the living room floor,
like just be shit faced drunk and
login and tearing my ACL or anything.
Where I got, this is what he's doing is
how you do it. He'll, yeah, he'll hooks.
And I mean, I don't remember all the
techniques, but I remember it was like,
you know, pankration stuff, right?
And we just be laying there and
it was always a thought of like,
my dude is fucking awesome man.
Like I could beat tank habit,
you know? And we would joke
about it, man. We would say,
I remember specifically sitting in there
and be like, like, dude, like, you know,
we're going to get you a fight in, uh, you
know, the local Joe Schmo show. And then,
uh,
you know,
we're going to get you up and you're
going to go to a pride and then you're
going to go to the UFC. And I was like,
oh, cool. The hell yeah, let's do it.
And that was, you know, it
was like a joke kind of,
but I like that was what was in my head.
That's, so that's what we're going to do.
Introduction to martial arts. Yeah. So
what was your first real formal training?
Like what, what gym did you first,
so I fought before I trained.
She hit the fucking, yeah. Yeah. So,
so actually this, this guy that was a, um,
he was supposed to go fight West Simms
and his name was fat Joe has what we
called him. He was supposed to go fight
Watson fat sims West sims that day.
And I said, yeah, let's go, man,
I don't want to go with you.
I want to see that shit up close.
Right. And so we go there and, uh, I'm,
I'm doing a bunch of coke
on the way and you know,
to me it's just going to be a party.
Like I'm just gonna Watch my dude fight.
I get there and uh,
you know,
he signs up on the table and I was
like, dude, what is that? How, you know,
that's all you got to do. He's like,
yeah, he's like, you just paid 30 bucks.
And He'd come by. I said, man, maybe
I should do that. And then the guy,
and I'm looking inside and
I see the, uh, you know,
people sitting around smoking cigars,
like you see on a movie,
people smoked cigars, you see bets
being made and stuff. And, and uh,
the guy who was men,
you want to fight the champion,
like nobody wants to fight him. And I
was like, fuck yeah, man, I'll fight him.
You kidding me?
So I literally went across the street,
there's a sporting goods store across the
street or down the street or something.
Went and bought a mouthpiece, come back,
there's a restaurant across the street,
boiled the mouthpiece at the restaurant,
use their microwave, come back. And then,
uh,
and then we're at the fighters meeting.
So the fighters meeting back then was a
lot different. So there wasn't a way in,
it was like, you and you guys look about
the same size. You guys doing kickboxing,
okay, you guys fight, right? So
that's how the way it worked out.
And I'm sitting there and they're
like, okay, you're the champion.
You're fighting him. And I was like, Oh
shit. All right, fuck this motherfucker.
Right. And uh, you know, so,
um, [inaudible] this guy, he
taught me how to do a jab.
He's like, man, he's like, all you
gotta do to beat this guy. Just Jab him.
He's like, you see this, just don't
just jab. I was like, Oh, okay,
I'm going to do that. And uh, went out
there and I beat the guy. So he actually,
yeah, he actually quit, you know, so he
was a tough man. Champion is what he was.
And, uh, I actually do a jab, punch him
in the face and he went to shoot a on me.
I did, you know, uh, uh, playground,
guillotine choke, and he just quit.
I don't think I actually had
the choke in and I don't,
I highly doubt he tapped out
saying that his calf cramped up.
I have no idea. Like, wow,
it really happened. I mean,
I certainly didn't know a good teen it
even know the name of it. So, uh, anyway,
later that night, he was like, dude,
like your fight didn't go very long.
You will fight again. Yeah, whatever man.
And they said, well, this guy, you know,
he's going pro and his next boxing match,
your kickboxer let's fight him.
Said, all right, I'll fuck him up. Right.
Because Dude beat the shit out of them.
So that was actually the first,
the nice thing about that was it
actually made me realize how tough I am.
That was the saving grace.
I mean, he just, you know,
just pieced me up just one
punch after another, you know,
I'm just eating punch after punch and
then, uh, yeah, that was it. I said, man,
I gotta do this shit. And then, so
my second fight, uh, I, you know,
I didn't think I still yet needed
to train. Uh, my second fight,
I met a guy at a gym, so, you know,
I did go to this gym was a
Japanese Jujitsu Gym, and he
goes, and he goes, hey man,
you want to fight in like two weeks
in Moy Tai? Hell yeah. Right. Um,
so for two weeks, you know, I'd hit the
bag probably for five minutes at a time,
whatever or something. Um, I
go to the fight and, uh, man,
this is the worst part. So I get in
there, first thing he got does, comes in,
shoots on me. It takes me down. We're
in big gloves, uh, Shin pads on us.
It takes me down. I'll get up, look
at what the fuck he's taking me down.
We can't do this more time. Right. Uh,
music fight, you know, it comes in,
it takes me down again. I was like,
what the fuck man. So I was like, okay,
so we're fucking wrestling,
right?
So I come out and get in sort of a
wrestling stance, dropped my hands,
fucking kicks me in my head. So, uh,
we'll come find out later saying
Shao no tie. Scott Shealy show.
What are you studying?
I used to work with them a lot.
San Chow for people don't know was
a kickboxing with take downs. Yup.
Corner Corey Smith back in the day
when Maurice was doing that once. Yeah,
in Burbank, I think it was, it was
weird. It was confusing. It's like,
okay.
I mean it's interesting I guess.
I mean it's probably a
good skillset to learn,
learn how to do take downs and
throws with, with kickboxing.
But then you just let the guy up, which
was just weird. You didn't get it, Huh?
He was weird. Yeah. Yeah. I mean it
still goes on day. Sandon essentially.
I think it's amazing sport.
I love it. It's amazing.
And it's only a lot of times it's a
lot like throws in Moy Tai Cause you,
you know, there's a lot of
trips and throws and Moy Tai,
except you get points for
the throws up to five. Yeah.
Another variation. Yeah.
If like their feet go above
their head, it's five points.
So when did you get serious?
So you did this was right after that.
Cause I mean he'd beat the
shit out of me. Um, I like,
I remember walking out of there and
people were looking at me like, damn,
how'd you survive hat bra?
I mean,
and like people were actually
asking me how I like, Dude,
how'd you survive that shit?
I don't know. I had to,
I had to go to work that night and
I was like working third shift.
I got to go to work right after everybody
was looking at me at work. I did.
You got like two black eyes if,
anyway,
that was when I said to myself, you
know, I want to try this and you know,
I think, uh, you know, this is something I
really enjoy and I want to go for it. Um,
so I met this guy,
his name was Eli airs and he was
fighting and king of the cage,
one of the toughest guys I've ever met.
And then guy brainwork workman and uh,
they were training for, it was a
big show there in Columbus. Um,
I can't remember the name of show,
but I think like Lawler fought on it like
a bunch of military guys. Tim Silvia,
you know the name, if I said, I can't
remember. But anyway, um, yeah. And then,
you know, then I really got the shit
kicked out on me when I got in the gym,
you know, then I realized like, you know
what a real beating was and uh, yeah,
it just went from there man.
Cause I,
I just said I never looked back
and I thought, man, you know,
I want to change my life.
You know, I'm, I'm, you know,
I wasn't never actually a,
uh,
the type of person that fit in
with the drug user seen. Right.
Like that wasn't me. It was just a, again,
an expression of anger and
these things that, um, you know,
in my childhood just kind of came out the
wrong way. Right. So it wasn't really,
uh, like I fit in there.
So at this point, like I'm,
I'm really not fitting in anywhere.
And this was a quote that
I remember where I said,
I stopped trying to find yourself
and start to define yourself. And,
and I felt like the whole
time I was trying to find
myself and I said, you know,
I'm a, I'm a define who the fuck I am.
I'm going to say, this is what I am.
This is what I do. I'm a fighter.
Fuck it. Let's go. It's do or die. Um,
I've been to jail and dad, I've
been, you know, I've slept in on,
in the fucking snow, you know what
I mean? Like I've been homeless,
I've done every low thing you can do.
Like what's the worst that could happen
and get knocked out. There's nothing.
So I decided,
you know,
this is my path and I'm gonna carve the
path. I'm not going to search for a path.
I'm going to make the path and I'm not
going to look back and I'm going to the
top of that mountain. And, uh,
and that's something I still talk about
today when I talk to people is about, uh,
I didn't have any idea
how I was going to do it,
but I knew why I was going to do it.
And I knew that I was going to do it.
And I think I'm in my own personal
struggles and I think in a lot of people
struggle is they kind of get
caught up in the how, you know,
how am I going to do this? How am
I gonna win this fight, whatever.
And I think when you know
and understand your why,
I think the how becomes a
lot more um, clear, clear.
Yeah. More clear and easier. I
mean, it doesn't matter. You can do,
it's better to do it 100% wrong then 50%.
Right?
I think there's a balance to doing things
and it's highlighted by what you just
said,
what you've just said.
There's a balance and it's a lot of what
we were talking about earlier about uh,
Joel Jamison versus Louie Simmons versus
like someone who's like super technical
versus someone who's just a fucking mad
dog and just wants you to just go out
and do it and don't be a pussy.
Your,
your mindset that allowed you to take
that fight with no training and then take
another fight after that with no training
and then take another flight out to
that would know. T just this mindset
of fuck it, let's just do this.
There's a balance between that
and then you realizing, okay,
I got to really learn how to do this.
If I'm going to really be a fighter,
I'm going to be really be really defined
myself and I'll really go out and make
a mark. I got to learn what the fuck I'm
doing. Exactly this both things there.
That's that balance. Like you need both
things, you know, I mean it's, it's,
you have to have a certain amount
of fuck it in you, you know,
for a sport. I mean, is it,
he called an MMA a sport.
It always seemed to me to be,
it's too,
it's too defining.
It's its or to, uh,
it's, it's too limited.
It's not fighting is more than a sport.
It's an expression of what you're
capable of. Absolutely. It's,
you are you who you are as a human.
And that's where a one distinction I've
made over the years is the difference
between Marshall Skills and martial arts.
Everything.
Everybody always calls everything
and copies it into a martial art.
And when we go to the gym and we're
training armbars do a hundred arm bars.
That's not art.
That's not your expression of
your body in a combat scenario.
That's a, that's a martial skill.
Now when we go in competition,
now we're expressing our R and I think
this is an important distinction to be
made. I think it's something that, uh,
I get so tired of hearing, you know,
I trained martial arts and you know,
I trained martial skills
and then I express my art.
That's a very interesting
way of putting it.
How many years after you initially started
seriously training where you on the
ultimate fighter? Uh, four or five.
I remember when you were on the ultimate
fighter and they stole your chew
somebody fuck treat.
Everybody remembers him. Well,
I remembered that because I remember
like there's some dudes that,
there's some guys that play tough guy.
There's some guys that put on a show and
puff up their chest and say some shit
that they might not necessarily mean.
And then there's some guys that
say some shit and you go, oh,
this dude's fucking serious.
When they fucked with your
kid or with your shoe.
I remember watching that and go,
this motherfucker serious. I'm like,
Matt Brown is not a joker.
And then when you fought Matt Arroyo,
that was a another example of
it. I'm like, there's skill
wise Mike matter royals,
a very talented guy and
still is good Jujitsu guy,
good fighter. But there was
something that was a battle of mines.
I agree your mind,
I don't know if you knew that I fought
him before that too. Yeah. Yeah.
But the first time I fought,
and this is why it was such a,
a no brainer to say to fight. I fought
him the first time on 24 hours notice.
So I wasn't even,
I wasn't training her and I was training
a girl and she was going to Florida to
fight.
And when I got there,
we're driving to the weigh
ins and the promoter,
I heard him talking on the phone and he
goes, and I heard him say, you know, oh,
we don't have an opponent for
him. Uh, so I said, hey, you know,
what do you need opponent for? And
he's like, wow, this Guy Matt Arroyo,
one 70. And I said, dude, I'll fight
how much we pay me. They're like,
I have 400 500 bucks. I was like, dude,
I pay my rent. Fuck yeah, I'll do it.
And um, yeah, so, and I said, you know,
I can't make weight because I got like
one hour and uh, you know, he said it,
he said it's cool and fight them
on 24 hours notice and beat him.
So he wanted redemption for that.
Yeah.
That fight was an you,
one of the things about like watching
you fight to someone who's seen a lot of
people fight. There's, there's moments
in exchanges were after the exchange, uh,
gow tried to take a break or gow try
to catch his breath or move pace and
bigotry break. Yeah.
There's little breaks.
And then there's guys who recognize
those breaks and push in and you're a guy
who pushes in. Absolutely. When there's a
break you're like, oh no, mother fucker,
there's no breaks here.
There's no breaks here.
And you just get on dudes and it
makes things very intense. Yeah.
That's the thing about all your fights.
They're very intense. You know, there's a,
there's a certain level of violence that
you bring into the octagon that someone
has to be prepared for.
You know,
and there's some guys that are prepared
for it and it makes for amazing fights
like your fight Robbie Lawler. Holy
Shit. Was that a crazy fight? You know?
And then there's guys who just,
they just can't keep the pace.
They just can't keep that
than keeping you off of them.
Yeah. And uh, well I think what, um,
my goal as a martial artist,
as a fighter Marshall,
uh, you know, whatever you would
call a combat guy, you know,
I had to get my skills up to
the point where not your mind,
where it matches the mind.
Yeah. And crazy. Yeah. I mean,
a lot of guys struggle the other way and
I think one of the things that I talk
about a lot that you see, I don't think
that I was necessarily born this way.
This is where I think a lot of
people get confused. I mean,
I was certainly born with an
inclination towards a fighting.
I wouldn't be where I'm at
without that. But, you know, uh,
I work a lot on my mind.
I do a lot of stuff.
I've always been obsessed with
martial arts and combat as a whole.
And I hear other people say
they're obsessed. Like Connor,
you made it really famous when
he started saying it. Right.
I think my obsession goes far, far
beyond what anybody's even even close to.
I don't think they're there. A definition
of obsession even, uh, even, uh,
is comparable to mine at all. I
mean, I'm, I'm far more obsessed.
I've read probably I got a library
of sports psychology, books of,
of strength conditioning, books of a
martial arts, books, all this stuff. Um,
I mean it's literally on
my mind 24 hours a day,
but one of the things I really focus
on is the, the sports psychology part.
And I think that is why it's
expressed that way in the fight.
Um, and you hear a lot of people, they'll
say, how long have, have you heard like,
men, you know, my mind's already strong.
Like, I ain't scared when I walk in.
There are stupid shit like that.
And, and I always say, you know,
do you think Michael Jordan
stopped Paxton lay ups?
Do you think Jordan Burroughs
stopped practicing double eggs?
Do you think that on a shorts and niggers
stopped doing bicep curls because it's
good, doesn't mean that you stopped. Yeah,
it can be improved upon
it and you don't stop. So,
and I think the mind is one of those
things that can always be better.
Like we're not tapping into,
I mean,
what are we talking to like 10%
of our brains. That's all blessed.
Yeah, that's, yeah, that's bullshit.
You know, they used to think that.
They used to think that they used to it.
That's something they say.
But the reality is your brain has a bunch
of different quadrants for all sorts
of different functions.
So when you know you're utilizing
a certain portion of your brain,
that's the portion of your brain that's
responsible for those actions. Okay.
There's not either way.
I know our minds are certainly far more
unlimited and far more potential than
we're tapping into.
I think your mind is a lot like your body.
And it performs and it
does what you ask of it.
And if you just are lazy pitch,
he doesn't do anything but sit around
and watch TV and you don't ever challenge
your mind. I think your mind is weak
and it atrophies. Absolutely. Yeah.
When you say that you,
you have all these books and you
say that you work on your mind,
like do you have a, a daily practice
that you do? Do you meditate? I meditate.
Um, you know, daily is sort of a, uh,
I hate saying I do it daily cause
you know, I skipped days and,
and I mean I have three kids, which, you
know how that goes and yeah, it's very,
um,
but at the same time I try
to use everything as an
opportunity to practice on my
mind too. Right. Um, um, how you do
anything is how you do everything.
Right. Right. Um, and
so I think, you know,
we can use opportunities all
the time and uh, but yes,
I do meditate, I do tons of
visualization. I have a, um,
my strength conditioning
coach I work with now, he's a,
he's also got degree in sports psychology,
so we integrate a lot of that in the
training itself. Uh, for instance,
like doing,
we do these 200 yard sprints on the forest
treadmill or they're just miserable.
That, I mean, by the time you're done,
you just don't have anything left.
It's a complete drain. And then as soon
as you're done, like if stand attention,
right, I have to stay in, you know,
like a military attention straight
up and down and not let the, uh,
the,
the concept of your body's shutting
down affect your ability to maintain a
posture. Right? And that's
just a mental thing, you know,
100% right is solely mental. You
know, that's just one example.
We do a million things like
that. Um, but yeah, I do,
I do tons and tons of visualization,
which is, uh, uh, consistent,
uh, marker of high performers are
consistent thing that high performers do.
I think this is a well
known. Um, I have a,
a mental coach specifically that kind
of holds me accountable for a lot of the
things, you know, me and him,
we talk a lot back and forth
about the different, uh,
the different ways to create habits.
I think that's probably the number one
thing is creating habits. Right. Um,
you know, but, you know, he holds me
accountable for everything and not take,
that's probably the biggest key is just
being held accountable for every action
that you do. Have you ever used a sensory
deprivation tank? Absolutely. My, uh,
my strength coach has one.
Beautiful. Yeah, I love it.
And I go in about 45 to an hour,
um, to work on shit in there.
Do you think about techniques?
Um, you know, I don't really, uh,
I used that as a time, so I, I, I tried to
practice this form of meditation that I,
you know, I can't remember the name
of it. This dude, um, Kish tomorrow.
You ever heard of him? Krishnamacharya? I,
I don't know why it's not
coming to my head right now,
but he was one of Bruce Lee's guys.
He's an Indian metta meditation
guy and everything. And, um,
his form of meditation was to
completely clear your mind,
which is I guess like is
actually impossible, right?
Like there's no way to just
have no thought at all,
but that's sort of what I try to strive
for is go literally no mind at all.
What I do is think about only my breath.
That's it.
I concentrate on my
breathing in and not do that.
And there's a bunch of other
shit that gets in there,
but eventually I can kind of overpower
it and just think only about breathing in
and out. So that's what I do
to get to that state, right?
To get to a state where I can release
everything. But at that point,
once something, I'm relaxed, then
I go for the, uh, the no mine,
which again is that it's impossible.
But, um, my personal, uh,
system of visualization or relaxation
is I see the thoughts as clouds and the,
my mind is a sky or space. So, you know,
my mind becomes this gigantic entity and
the thoughts are just clouds that pass
by. But again, when I start
thinking about things like that,
now you're not in the know mine.
If you start thinking about your breath,
you're not in the know mine and I want
to get as close to it as possible because
in a fight, in a combat
situation, I want no mind.
That's the as the way that
Musashi talks about, right? Yeah,
and that's customer Sasha right
there. Oh fuck. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
This was a play on massage.
Have you read the Book Musashi?
Yeah. Yeah. Read that. You
put it on the day. Yeah.
I read that and I read the book of five
rings when I was 16 changed my life.
That's the one that Louie will,
if you work for Louis,
all of his staff to read it.
Yeah. You have to meet it, dude.
Once you understand broadly,
you could see it in all things.
I remember reading that when I was 16 and
I was like, ah, I get it. I was like, you,
when you, when you can get great at
something, you can get great at anything.
It's the same thing,
whether it's playing the piano or
writing books or fighting or anything.
It's the same thing. It's all about
figuring it out, understanding the way,
and that's a, the book, the art of
learning. If you read this one, no,
Josh Waitzkin the chess prodigy is
a black belt under Marcello Garcia.
Yeah. Beautiful. Amazing Book.
That's sort of a similar type thing.
He's a fucking wizard man. I've heard him
on Tim Ferriss's podcast. Super Smart.
God's where I heard of him from genius
and just so good at understanding how to
learn things and teach things.
I think that mentality,
that chess player mentality
cause chest assessor,
such a complex cognitive demanding game,
you know,
there's so much thinking and planning
and so many steps ahead that you have to
be in so many moves you have to have
cataloged in your head. And then,
and he goes into beyond
just the technical part too,
when he talks about how he kind
of lost his love for, yeah,
it was a great book, man. Yeah. Well,
he's a really fascinating character
and I love when a guy like that gets
obsessed with martial arts because it
changes the way people look at something
like Jujitsu because people on the outside
in particular, they look at Jujitsu.
It's like, oh, it's just a bunch of
fucking meatheads choking each other.
And then they see a guy like that
and they go, oh, wait a minute,
Josh Waitzkin his industry.
He's a black belt, huh? That's,
that's gotta be one of the
great things about Jujitsu is a,
the amazing people that do it. I mean,
he'd come out here to la and I mean,
I see these people doing Jujitsu.
I talked to him like, Hey,
what do you do? They're like, oh, you
know, I'm a movie, a top guy or whatever.
I'm an executive, I'm a, I'm
a CEO. I'm like, wait, what?
What are you doing in here? Guy Ritchie
garbage. He's a fucking black belt.
He was on the podcast. I was like, why
you're a black belt under Henzel? Like,
Holy Shit. Nice. Yeah,
that's legit, man. Let's go.
I'd ask God damn black and their Henzel
Gracie, they don't give those away.
Maynard James Keenan. Yup. Yup.
Oh, he's a buddy of mine. Yeah.
I mean I know him a little bit jealous.
Fuck that dude does Jujitsu
and he's got a fake hip.
I didn't get a hip replacement
from stopping on stage. You know,
he's always stopping on stage and he
choke someone out on the stage. Yeah,
he a hip toss.
Some dude took his back and got him in
a rear naked choke on stage and kept
singing and the dude was going like,
he wasn't hurting the guy. You know,
the guy was a,
it was the whole thing
was kind of crazy.
Like most on youtube or does it define it?
The guy comes up to the guy
runs up to months stage.
Maynard has the fucking microphone in
his hand. Mainers another dude. He's,
he's one of the smartest dudes I noticed.
Stupid,
smart to the point where he's kind of,
he kind of gets weird round people
cause it's so goddamn smart.
Everybody else like a baby.
So here he's on stage.
You got a big screen and some dude,
some dude jumps onto the stage
and rushes him. Where's it at,
Jamie? How long has this video
got to get to when the
dude runs on stage there?
Okay, get it, go before that,
cause he hip toss. He's like, look,
the guy runs up to me. He's like,
yeah, it made her hugs him. Boom.
Takes back season show kit and he keeps
singing and then he goes over onto his
back and pulls the guy backwards and
then keep singing while he's in full back
mount with the hook and they do.
It's its arms. I'm like, yes,
I do.
That is beautiful.
And he kept saying the song,
this guy's fucking hilarious
man is a god man. Yeah,
he's a the fucker and he's always
training. He comes out here,
he trains dot with them a little bit.
Henry Akins place and trades is
Dave Camera, Rio half Gracie.
He goes everywhere with
them a little bit out there.
We were drilling a couple of weeks
ago over at Henry's Robin muscle farm.
We did some training there
and most people, they get
their fucking hip replaced.
They're like, that's a wrap,
right? Yeah. And he's like,
I've got to get my black belt. Wow. Did
Mark Coleman had his hip replaced in?
He ain't even train
them right.
I think he may have had both of them
are the one where they call it had a
problem. Yeah. I got infected. I had
to get redone. Imagine that Shit.
They cut off the top of your leg.
They put a fake hip in there.
They put a bolt that goes through the
center of the bone all the way down
through the bone. Imagine have to
Redo that. They got to pull it out.
A new one in there. Fuck man.
Magic. Just doing it once.
I've only had one surgery in my life. I've
only went under Bob 100 twice now. So,
um, the actually so twice. Yeah. The first
one I had tore the ligament right here.
I remember that. Yeah. You
were talking about that.
That was fucking with you
for a long time, right? Yeah.
Probably about a year I fought like that.
You couldn't totally make a fist, right?
Yeah.
It was like this kind of,
so I was like frog and people would call
still like that Hema calls broke his
hand so much that his right hand,
one of his knuckles,
like his pinky or is a pointer finger
and it never curls past that. Yeah.
Well this wasn't broken.
The bones were all intact,
but the ligament there was completely
torn. So what they have to do. Um,
and I just went in like there's a decision
there and just reattach the ligament.
And I came back probably
four months later,
five months later maybe that's when
they were telling me you'll be fine and
everything. And you know it took
probably a year before was actually okay.
Wow. It's just Chris Weidman's going
through some shit like that right now.
He fucked his thumb up in the Kelvin
Gasol and fight and then had to get a
ligament from his wrist taken out and
attached to his thumb cause his thumbs
regiment was torn and he still
can't fully train. Still can't grip.
We're fully punch. Yeah, he's
waiting. Yeah. Mine. They
did have dude, none of that.
But they,
they said once they open it up,
there was a lot more stuff in there they
had to take out and a lot more that was
ripped that they didn't
even realize was there.
You know how it is with cord
Mris. Yeah. Well with fighters,
like so many guys have shit
wrong. They don't even know. Like,
did you ever see Jacques Arrays when
they had his, uh, elbows cleaned out?
He had elbow surgery and they found
chunks of bone and cartilage in his elbow.
Like, uh, like,
like a shot glass filled with like shit
really floating around inside of his
elbow just from hitting people with
elbows and getting arm barred and not
tapping and shit pop and snap and Taryn
loose and all of it is just fucking
mangled. Yeah. Cause he broke his
arm when he's hydro. Hydro. Yeah.
Broke his arm. He tucked it into his
belt and kept going. It's bad ass.
I mean that was a horrible
arm break to like, to me,
wrestling is the hardest
sport in the world. And I
love rest. I love watching it.
I love being a part of it. Yeah. Um, but
that doesn't happen in wrestler, right?
Very often. I mean, I guess
there's probably some, I know, uh,
Mike Passilla went to the
finals with a torn Pec.
Wow. Yeah. So thanks a lot. It takes a
lot. I guess it does happen in wrestling.
I shouldn't say that. That's a
different, that situation was just,
he was up on points and he just needed
to survive for a couple of the match,
right? Yup. Yup. One of the match,
but we'll remember when Jon Jones fought
Vitor Vitara completely hyper extended
his arm. That was when, I don't know if it
broke. It was fucked up for a long time.
I mean it was bent like this the other
way, just completely back backwards.
Like I was convinced he was going
to tap. I was like, he's got a tap.
I thought it was two v toward like, let it
go a little. Yeah. I think he let it go.
It was weird. Yeah, I remember
that. Yeah. And I'm like,
thank you. If it, if he finishes
that crazy, the world changes.
Yeah. The whole world of light heavyweight
changes be towards life changes. Yeah.
Everything changes. Veto becomes a
champ, you know, the whole thing changes.
John Jones, not the greatest ever. Yeah.
Which you know, is a up in the air,
whatever. But I think he's the
greatest ever performance wise.
We were talking about performance wise
earlier before the podcast started and
versus like we're talking about
Cain Velasquez performance wise,
like the actual results versus
what you think about their ability.
You know,
I think cane when he was at the time,
I never saw anybody with a cane when
he was in his prime, 240 pounds.
Unfucking godly cardio,
we just never stopped coming at you.
Excellent technique.
Take it tremendous.
My whole thing with it though is
as soon as you test positive once,
I'd take you out of the greatest PR.
It's just against the rules.
I'm not even against steroids. Like
take steroids, you know, like if,
if it's your endocrinologist tells you
to take steroids, go fucking do it. Good.
Good for you. But in our sport,
unfortunately it's against the rules.
So there's only a certain amount of
people doing it. So if you're doing it,
you're cheating. Right. And,
but do you think John was
taking steroid? I don't know.
I don't, I don't think he was, but to be
honest, it doesn't matter to me. I mean,
you know, I've said this for a long time.
I think it should be a lifetime ban.
First offense period. Yeah. And
there's going to be martyrs.
There would be guys like, I don't
think 10 means was taking steroids.
He certainly did not look like
it did. It wasn't, Oh really?
I didn't know what that far,
okay.
Okay.
So found the supplement that he was taken,
there was a totally legal supplement.
You get a bunch of shit,
but companies or these companies
rather than get it from China and they,
they have these bins and like
we had a problem with that,
with the Alpha brain when we first had,
not steroids,
but vitamins that were in Alpha brain
that weren't supposed to be there.
We have all our stuff independently
tested and when we had it independently
tested,
it turns out that the mixers then when
they were putting all the different
ingredients and they will be putting in
these vats and they had used these vats
for other shit and had a
completely cleaned it out.
This is a problem with companies that
sell steroids and also sell things like
creating like this is the,
this is the big story about John Jones.
This is the big rumor.
This is what their,
what they think is that he was doing
coke that had creatine in it. Yeah.
It was cut with creating that creatine
probably had trace elements of steroids.
The reason why that makes sense is because
he tested negative right before that
test and then tested positive and then
tested negative again a short time after
that. This is a steroid that takes
several months to get out of your system,
but it got out of his system very quickly
which would indicate it was a very,
very small trace amount.
Not An amount that you would take if
you were actually using it to try to,
you know, to get a performance
enhancing benefit. That's what I book.
It makes sense to me. And so
it makes sense. Nitsky too.
It's fair enough.
And I'm certainly,
there's cases so under in my world where,
okay,
first offense,
lifetime ban,
I take a lot of guys would be a lot more
careful with things like app for one.
And I think, uh, you know, there'll
be a due process. So, you know,
say he proved that or like 10
meetings, you know, prove it right.
He comes right back. Right. Um,
and I also think unfortunately there
would be people that would probably,
uh, you have no bad intention and
would, uh, have the, you know,
end up testing positive and having a
lifetime ban and there'll be martyrs.
Basically.
I am,
I can't sign off on martyrs,
man. 22 to have dreams
for sure. For sure. What about you?
Like what if you accidentally took some
creatine and bullshit and it personally,
I'm uh, diligent. I do my,
I do my due diligence,
man.
I worked with muscle farm for years now
and like I know that and they have great
stuff. Yeah, they may have nice
stuff. I know that it's good stuff.
That's my primary supplement
source. Um, I mean, I, I'm,
I don't go do coke.
You know what I mean?
Like if you do those things and something
bad happens to you, that's your fault.
You know what I mean? If, if,
if for instance, he was doing
coke and, uh, he, you know,
not knock on John Jones either. I mean,
I'm not living his life. I mean, it's,
he's in a difficult situation
as a young kid, uh, you know,
with God,
I mean,
I can only imagine the amount of people
approaching him for crazy things and
trying to talk him into all this. So I
have some sympathy for his situation. But,
you know, you make the choice, you have
to pay the consequences for the choice.
I agreed that you should pay the con the
choice, the consequences for the choice.
I just don't agree that the price
should be so high. You know,
like when you think about
a guy like Anderson Silva,
Anderson Silva just tested positive again.
Again.
Do you think that that takes him out of
the consideration for the greatest of
all time? In my mind, 100%.
See I'm doing it because he's old
and he's doing it because he said 40
so we again, we can feel whatever
you want to feel. Right. I mean,
I feel like he probably wasn't doing it
the whole time, but he might've been.
Yeah, but do I? No. Hell No.
You ever see his trainer?
Oh yeah. Yeah. I,
Eric Silva when I fought him and you know,
it's trader looks ridiculous.
He's set like 70 years old. He's
just flown. It looks like the hall.
He's got like 5% body fat at 60 years old.
Like I said,
a picture of Daniel, the guy to Dana and
I go, this is Anderson's trainer, lol.
And Dana sends you back. Holy Shit.
Are you serious? Like, Oh yeah,
that's his trainer. Oh
man, fucking guys. So Jack,
Dana's certainly seen him around
you. You have lots of guys. Is that,
that's just not, and that's a
different guy, man. He's younger.
He's right.
Book to the picture. To the left
is been left as the one. Yeah,
that's the picture I said.
I mean it's fucking abs
stick out like Blegh biceps.
Each one of his abs looks like a, a
bodybuilder's Bicep, which is glued to it.
That's great.
There's like,
you can get big at 60 you could be pretty
built at 60 you can't be that built.
It's not positive. It's like 0.01%
of the population that can do that.
Maybe then they all live in Africa.
Yeah.
They're out there all have
like super genes. You know,
they're all like Francis and condos,
relatives.
So few people that are built like that.
No,
not at that age. You know, at that age,
you know, the body starts to diminish.
There's just no if, ands, or buts about
it. Do you know that he's at old for sure.
Yeah. That guy's old. Yeah, he's in his
sixties yeah. That's funny. Yeah. He's a,
I think he's an ex GM, right? Is,
is that it? How do you train jockey?
I know he trained Eric Silva
who was at [inaudible].
He was in his corner and I was like, I'm
glad I'm fighting a little guy, not him.
Nope. Change boy. You want to talk
about a post Usada guy? Like he's,
he's one of him and Vito Vito,
obviously it was a testosterone
replacement therapy,
but I think Johnny Hendricks was
probably the most obvious. Right.
Formance wise for sure.
You got to wonder about Hendrix,
like how much of it was burnout,
how much of it was possibly
he was taking something.
You got to say it possibly because we
never tested positive for anything.
Absolutely. Yeah. But Dude, he
was launching people across.
I was the last fight before you saw
the, when I fought him, you know,
I felt a strength. I've
seen his body. I mean,
I felt it firsthand is a completely
different world. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
especially completely different compared
to now. He doesn't look the same.
He doesn't fight the same.
It's like, it certainly part,
part of that has to be motivation to,
I mean, he's just, there's no way he,
he's under the same, uh, mental,
uh, aspiration that he had before.
He's just,
he just looks at it differently.
It could be also because it's hormones
are all fucked up. Absolutely.
A big speculation. If he was on something
and then he's off his hormones crash,
there's no way they can't. That's just
hand that and that affects your mind.
Right. 100% now that I
never take it, but I mean,
I see people that go on and off of it
and they're like depressed and the tour,
remember when [inaudible] came back,
I mean there's so many pictures of
[inaudible] when he fought like Michael
Bisping and then you see v
tour after Usada and he just,
he's got that old man bod and he goes in
there and his body's kind of like loose
and it just is, your body's
not producing hormones anymore.
Details on that shit. When he was 19
man, well, yeah, I guess, yeah, yeah.
One of the last few Randy and he was 240
pounds. And his neck started up here.
His neck started about two inches above
his ears and just went down straight to
his shoulder.
He's so fast.
It's like ridiculously fast. Yeah.
Especially when he fought tank.
Well five ridiculously fast.
Yeah.
Cause I would have for is any like if you
slow down when you stopped taking that
stuff, like if your muscles
actually uh, you know,
your fast twitch muscles go away
or something like that, you know,
the body crashes right?
When you're that jacked up on steroids,
your whole body, first of all,
your, your balls are just like on
vacation. I mean, I know you get stronger,
but what about, you know, speed
though that's a different thing.
I said a lot of speed is
from a, a neurological right
is a lot of uh, you know,
the nervous system. So I wonder, you
know, about the effects on like, well,
I don't know, did you see the study, uh,
Andy Gap and just came out with which one?
He just posted it the other day about
a epigenetic memory of muscles. Yes.
So this is I think,
a big problem with the steroids because
I say I do steroids when I'm 19,
now my muscles get jack to now my muscles.
Remember
how to get that jacked again.
Um,
even though I'm off steroids for 10
years and then I come back at 30 and and
Redo it. That's a very good point. That's
a very good point. And a very real point.
Yeah.
You body has muscle memory and especially
if you do it when you're young and
then your body has an adequate amount
of time to rebuild and you start
developing a natural hormone level that
also increases your tendon strength. It,
it increases ligaments, strength.
I mean it just, your body changes.
It changes the density of your
muscles, of your bones. It just does.
There's a lot of bet.
I mean,
and then there's another argument for
women and women that have taken steroids.
It's even more intense argument because
you're putting supernatural levels of
testosterone in a woman's body.
They develop all this new muscle tissue
that never would have been there without
it. And a certain amount of
that sticks around and you know,
you might not even ever been able to
develop that kind of strength without it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's what that was the first thing I
thought of when I seen that study. Yeah.
And that was where I was,
I, you know, there's,
there's always a lot more to it
than meets the eye. Yeah. 100%.
Yeah. And you know, with uh,
the kind of cheating that they've
been doing in Russia, you know,
did you see that movie Icarus? No,
it's on Netflix. Right? Yeah. Gotcha.
Talking about what to say? It's fucking
crazy. I just watched so little TV,
I just miss everything. Yeah.
Every, every day. Someone,
did you see this on Netflix now? I
plan on it. It's on my cue. It'll make,
it'll make you, it'll make you
curious and mad at the same time.
Cause they had a state sponsored
state sponsored doping program.
Russia had a June, right? Yeah.
But this was proved the guy,
the guy who was doing it as in this
documentary and he was helping this guy,
Bryan Fogel,
do a bike race.
What Bryan Fogel did was he did a bike
race with nothing and then he wanted to
get juiced up and see what the
difference is, uh, with the next year,
do the same race,
but do it on everything.
And so he contacted this Russian guy who
was the head of anti-doping in Russia.
Well, this guy along the way
from doping up Bryan Fogel,
they all got busted and
when they got busted,
not Bryan Fogel does the
Olympics in, in Russia, the, um,
they had the Sochi Olympics.
They found out that people at Tam
tampered with samples and a bunch of shit
started coming out about it.
And then it became this gigantic scandal.
He'd fled Russia,
came to the United States and testified
and told everything that he did.
They opened up these supposedly on
openable sample jars and replace the bad
urine with clean urine.
They had frozen urine and then they had
a hole in the wall with their passing
urine and replacing the old stuff.
Was this specific to a certain,
a specific sports sports across the board.
And they had a record number
of gold metals that year.
Everybody's juice to the tits
and everybody's pissing clean.
That's the tough thing about everybody
goes into the Russian training methods
and how they're superior and everything.
And you're like a little
bit of that little bit
of this.
There's some great Russian
training methods for sure.
I mean the Russians
invented the kettle bells.
Russians have a super technical wrestling
instruction and there's some without a
doubt,
some great Russian training method.
But it's also because
sports means so much.
So then they say like they were there also
state sponsored scientist rather than,
you know, in America where it's, you
know, fear of professor or something.
You just do what you want to do for your,
for your athletes or whatever.
Well we have to realize that their
best athletes are all amateurs. Yeah.
They don't have professional sports
boxing. Yeah. But that's it. I mean,
and they don't have, well they have
MMA to fade or obviously right,
but they don't have like NFL,
NBA,
Major League baseball hockey.
Right. They don't have like this.
It's true professional
venue like we do over here.
So a lot of their greatest
athletes go into amateur Olympics.
And so their juice in these
fucking people up for Soviet glory,
they're doing it for the glory of the
country and it's sponsored by the state.
And they outline in this documentary
from Putin all the way down,
people working for Putin,
who this guy is Gregory Guy who was the
guy who was in charge of all the state
sponsored doping. It's fucking
madness and it makes you wonder,
you know what I mean?
Nobody wants to say like Faye door
in pride was the motherfucker, right?
I mean he was the love of fucker. I'd
love to an animal and it makes you wonder,
it makes you wonder like
what was going on over there.
Loved it, man. Yeah, I was one of
the best, I think a cro cop, fader.
Whew man.
That was like,
for me it was probably
like the most intense.
I had to stay up for it and
I just remembered waiting,
watching them walk out,
just eyes. Those are like, it's
three o'clock, right? Yeah.
I remember it was really late at night.
Maybe it was snowing and shit. That's how,
I don't know why I remember that, but I
was like, I'm not fucking going anywhere,
man. I'm sitting here watching this.
The eyes bulging out just, you know,
I didn't care man. Yeah. Feed versus,
no guara it's so rare that
fights are like that anymore.
I mean there's certainly some, yeah,
I come up here and there, but man,
those to me were the glory
days, man. Yeah. Cause well,
we waited how long to see the fight? Yeah.
You know, it's like three, four months.
There's no fights in between.
You know,
there's like one UFC fighter or
something and we're just like, dude,
this is the fight.
This is the Superbowl that everybody's
been waiting the whole season four is too
many fights now. I don't know. I
like it. There's a lot of fights,
but I also think that some of them get
overlooked. Absolutely. Absolutely.
And like I wish there's a side of me
that wishes it was the way it was back in
the day. And there's a side
of me that's like, I do,
this is what we all wanted
from the beginning. You know,
we wanted fights every
weekend. But uh, I again,
unfortunately it does take away
from that gigantic fight. You know,
those are harder to make these days
and think that's why they're doing
the champ versus champion. They're trying
to make those big fights again. Yeah,
I think so too. But if you only have
those fights every three or four months,
there's no way you're going to have
enough fights for all the athletes in the
UFC.
Absolutely.
That's a big part of the issues is 500
fighters on roster plus I think there's
more now actually
I, the only thing I, I, I mean I'm
the, I'm no one to say how to do it,
but I kind of wished there was like a,
you know,
the UFC fight night and then
the pay per view and you know,
they have all these different
things but they don't seem to,
I mean I think that may be moving towards
it where there's sort of a, you know,
the smaller fights workup like you,
you do like a UFC fight night three
or four times, build an audience.
Now we put you on paper view for the
big fight. You get what I'm saying?
Something like this,
like not necessarily like a feeder
but you know within the organization.
A feeder.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Yeah. Uh, yeah, more structured.
I mean I love the big events
that they have every year,
like the 4th of July event,
the new year's event,
the Madison Square Garden event they have
where they just stack it and just have
just a ton of, of big
time fights. But you know,
like I liked Eric Andrews Liotta Machida
last week too, you know, I mean I like,
I like that too, where it's maybe a fight
that not a lot of people are watching,
maybe less people are watching.
But it's an interesting fight still.
I didn't get to watch it.
I don't have cable anymore,
so don't donate to have cable.
Like we use Netflix. My wife does.
But do you have a, do you want to say
it? The UFC APP? I do have the UCF.
Was It on there? Yeah. Well it wasn't,
but it probably will be how long after
it will be and that's onto the wait
before from Fox sports one till
it's on the UFC. I don't even know.
I mean that's the thing though is
that I sit there and watch that.
If I'm watching anything,
it's always fights on there or youtube.
I just watch them. Boy Thai fights all
day. That's like my favorite thing. Yeah,
just look Sanchez latest.
Uh, the question mark kick
where he got pulled up his shorts
right after he did it to this guy. Man.
I love him. Wild Man. I love him. Sanchez.
So interesting to me because
he's different than any
other Thai fighter in his
movements.
He so light on his feet and constantly
switching stances and he's just as a
Floyd Mayweather. More Thai. Yeah man.
Yeah, that's the guy I'm going to
try to get out here for, you know,
like what I'm doing with muscle farm
is some things I could try to help them
build a team and everything and he's one
of the guys I want to get out for our
seminar and kind of be,
you know, Philly's let me know and we'll
have, I want to meet that guy. Yeah.
Really want to get him cause
it's not just the, you know,
the way that he fights in the ring,
but the way that
he trains man, he, I mean
he trains hard, hard,
you know you watch these videos up and
you're like dude, it is so easy for him.
That's the weird part, right.
They can be, he'll do it.
He'll do like 30 kicks in a row.
They do.
How did you just do that and
you're like smiling. Yeah.
Well he doesn't kick like he's loose.
He's not like a Liam Harrison.
Got It.
Yeah it is fucking 150% he's
like pop, pop, pop, pop,
pop, pop, pop, pop. And he just
keeps going. Just keeps going.
I don't know if it's something you
can even trade. I mean, he's like the,
I'd say more like the Loma
Chico of Moitai, right.
His eyes and he just sees
that question mark kick.
I mean he just knows where he is and you
look at his body man, and he ain't done.
It's scary. Impressive guy. Bull
cow, bull cows jacked, you know,
giant fucking ab muscles just ripped.
Sansai just looks like a guy.
Works out a little bit but me by,
he just fucks people up man. And
he's so slick with his move. I like,
even when he's hitting the pads who
hits pads like this where he's never,
he never stops moving his feet so relaxed,
so relaxed and so fluid.
What's interesting to me is the feet
just never stops moving his feet.
And that's just,
I don't understand why more people
don't emulate his style because he's
obviously a traditionally
trained tie fighter,
but as adapted everything to a
much more dynamic and fluid method.
Man, it's like you, you know, when
I watched Sam Chai and Loma check,
I'll watch the shit out of
these guys. Right? So I got
washed Liam Harrison, right?
Or John Wayne par. Uh,
Raymond deckers here,
these great more Thai guys. Right?
And they inspire me. I'm like, Jen,
I want to fuck it up. And then I'll
watch Sam Child Watch Loma Chicco my,
why do I do this? Right? It's
the next level I do. I show,
why am I even going to the gym? I can't
look at it. I can't do this flap flap Ma.
That's what I'm talking about right there.
And so fluid and just relax.
Look at him. He's getting tired. I mean,
look at his face. He doesn't even, I mean,
he could do this all day,
a whole day and I mean he could do
it in his kitchen while he's cooking.
You know, it's 36. Yeah, I
mean it's really incredible.
He's something special.
That's the most, uh,
most of the facial expression I've ever
seen. Hold, hold right there. Yeah,
it's probably been smiling 150
rounds at the end of the day. I mean,
guys constantly training,
constantly the gym.
And one of the things that I like about
the way the Thai spar too is that they
play like they're tapping each other.
They're just working on their timing and
their movement and they're not hurting
each other. They're saving it for fights.
Yeah. Well they fight every week. Yeah.
My coach Dorean prices over there
and right now, man, they just,
they fight all every week. I
follow him on Instagram. Oh yeah.
He's a bad motherfucker. Amazing,
amazing person, man. Just, uh,
one of the best guys you'll
ever meet in your life, man.
I like one of the things he said recently,
he's like, yeah, I'm wearing the same,
what a great t shirt and the same shorts.
He goes,
I'm going to here for a fucking fashion.
I'm here to train them in Thailand.
That's for you to get my work in.
Yeah.
And he goes over to Holland
with Ryan Simpson and
another guy I hope to get over here too.
He was showing one of his
Instagram posts posts. He was like,
these are my five star accommodations.
He has white plastic bucket.
This is how I shower, you know, like
he's over there doing the real deal.
It'll tie fighter. Yup. Yup. So
that's where he actually goes up to.
Um, don't, I don't, I don't
think he's still goes up there.
But you used to go up to a song,
which is the northern part of Thailand.
And originally they didn't
let foreigners up there.
He would go to sit in and shy.
He was the first foreigner that they let
in that camp. And that was his dream.
He wanted to live like a tie fighter,
like a savage.
And that's where I'm lucky to have a
friend like him cause he brings the,
the Thai style back to me. And that's
why I've never had to go to Thailand.
Like he goes over,
he will only come back for my camps.
He's had tons of people offer and
he won't come back for no one else.
That's awesome. It's been, uh, so when,
when I was telling you a story about
going know started his Japanese Jujitsu
Place,
the first gym I went into,
he was there and we both
started together and he wanted,
well he would,
he'd already started actually he was
out in Virginia and then just move to
Columbus. But he wanted, we both wanted
to do more tai and I was like, dude,
there's no money in what
time you do that shit. Uh,
so he went to my tie and I went with him
may of course he went with him may for
a little while. Did I wish there
was money in Moitai lion fight.
I love watching it and I preferred
that even over regular kickboxing.
I liked that. Yeah. Yeah. Just why they
limit it. Yeah. Why limit it? I just,
I mean I think they limited it for k one
cause they thought it would create more
action with less clinching,
but it's garbage. It is right.
It's part of not garbage.
I shouldn't say that,
but still enjoy watching
belt or kickboxing.
I love Laurie cause they just
have some wild ass fights.
But a lot of those guys that are the top
of the food chain guys are Moyie Thai
guy. Yeah. I mean Kevin Ross is in Beltour
now. I mean this guy elbow, the shit.
Everybody, John and Joe Schilling.
Yeah. I mean these are elbow guys,
elbow guys and a man.
I've always thought that if a marketed
more tired, like they do the kickboxing,
I think it would blow up a lot better.
But when you take Moitai
like lion fights in the,
they're playing the snake charmer music
and they got the Mon kongs and they're
dancing around why crew in and
shit. And everybody's like, dude,
I don't want to see this garbage
will see some fucking blood. Yeah.
It's hard for people to appreciate the
tradition, but I don't, you know, I,
I respect the tradition. You
know, when someone explains to me,
they said that what's beautiful
about the Mong Kong and the,
the why crew is that you get relaxed.
It's like you're out there dancing
and then you could put on your best
performance because you're already in
front of all those people and you kind of
loosen up. And then doing that. That's
one of the benefits of Hersa. I love it.
I think it's awesome and I'll
watch it all day long. Um,
but I don't think the casual American fan
is ever going to be attracted to that.
I wonder, you know, I wonder if
they could be talked into it.
It just seems like what happened with
MMA was like lightening in a bottle that
Forrest Griffin and Stephan
Bonner fight on TV on spike TV.
Nobody knew what the
fuck it was at the time.
You're watching MMA for the first time.
You see that crazy shit.
These guys just throwing down wild hay
makers and head kicks and takedowns and
Ah, and then exhausted. I mean these
guys just drain themselves out.
I think those guys made the UFC,
I think in that one fight.
It's one of those weird moments
lightening in a bottle. You know,
at one point in time they estimate
there was as many as 10 million people
watching that fight for. And it
started with just a couple of million.
Like the event started with just a couple
of Miami for gas. Is that watches too?
These guys are fucking going crazy.
And that one fight being so good,
I think made MMA, I think it just was
the launching point. And then after that,
people got into it and then they started
saying, Holy Shit, this is awesome.
And then all the other fights and then
it became the thing that it is today.
But I think that lightening in a
bottle moment, it's hard to recreate.
And with Moitai, it just
never happened. There's no,
there's no lightening in a bottle moment.
And I don't know how you
would recreate that today.
It seems like all the stars were aligned,
right?
Because now today reality
TV shows are kind of,
they're so saturated. There's so many
of them. Back then there wasn't as many.
So to have the ultimate fighter,
we got these guys in a house and they're
all competing and they're going to
fight for this six figure contract
on television. It was a big deal.
It was a big show to watch.
But now it's like everybody's watching
people fucking selling cars and pawn
shops and they're living in the woods and
people are making moonshine. It's like,
fuck man.
There's so many reality shows.
It's almost over saturated to the
point where if you had a Moitai show,
it's like, well, okay, here's another
crazy thing people are doing. Oh, this
Scott, the mood there, that more
Taika Tinder. That's right. They did.
Did that even air here? I wash
it. Did it air in America.
I don't know how I watched it.
Maybe on youtube or something,
but because the containment
was a boxing show, right? Yeah,
but they had the contender.
Was it good to call it the contender Asia?
Is that what it was called?
I don't remember.
I remember John Wayne Power
was on at Yeltsin cli. That's,
I don't remember it. That's another bad
mother fucker. Yachts and Cli. Holy Shit.
He just came back. Did he? Oh, he
retired for a little bit, right?
I think last weekend maybe, man. Yeah.
To me it's one of the great unsung combat
sports and you know all these people
that are watching boxing and I
love boxing, but you know if HB oh,
just really wanted to get down and dirty.
Come on Hbo,
show me some Moitai.
Absolutely.
That would be so amazing.
Have Sanchez ion or maybe
ESPN, you know, instead of,
instead of having these
commentators,
these narrators are just dip shits and,
and you know,
every time they talk about it in May,
I am most vomit.
I mean it's just ridiculous. And then, uh,
you know, instead of these garbage shows,
they have it. They have golf for, you
know, like, I mean some of the, uh,
they have like a darts,
darts on ESPN,
but you can't show a kickboxing match.
Come on. Well, you know what man? I think,
I think
there's a problem with commentary with
sports that leaks into MMA and I think it
belongs there. And I fought against it
from the beginning. And that's the, the,
the insult commentary.
There's a kind of like calling
people bums and calling people
losers and you know, and get
out, get out of the game.
Snoop Dogg that piece of shit. Do
you know what to call them out? What?
What's what, what don't you like
or what do you call a cutter?
Mary called him a bitch. That was a mess.
It was a man that's not cool either.
Fight. That was a mess. I think he was
fucked up. I don't care. Yeah. You know,
you'd be put it on public. He could
apologize, delete it, whatever, you know?
Yeah. If I go to the UFC,
Upi am I just punch him. If I
see him, I'm cool with that.
What else do you don't
want? None of that. Snoop,
I've just said, I really offends me,
man, because you know what, man? Connor,
you know people all have
their opinions about him.
I respect the shit out of that
guy. I love what he's done. I love,
I love his shtick. I think
he's a, he's a true, uh,
sportsman. I mean, I liked him.
He comes into the limelight for a little
while and then he goes back and I think
he goes back and he works his ass off.
I really think he does. Definitely does.
I mean, he wouldn't be where he's
at if he didn't write, you know,
but everybody judges him by, you know,
what he, he does out here. But listen,
what he did was make $100 million
fighting against the greatest boxer of all
time for is did wash, no boxing match
ended well and won a couple of rounds,
which is fucking crazy. You know, that's
fucking crazy. I mean, I think Floyd,
I think, I think the vast
majority of people could, uh,
of good fighters could win around.
So you against Floyd because Floyd,
I don't know if I'd say gives them away,
but you know, he's going to feel you. He,
you know what I mean? He's,
that's the way he fights.
He's he fuck everybody liked that and
he rarely wins the first few rounds.
Agreed. Yeah, but that's not taken
away. Nothing from Connor though.
He didn't want to get clipped by
that left upper cut. I wasn't not,
it wasn't on his plans.
You're right. Yeah.
I just think the,
what I'm talking about,
it's like the commentators and a lot of
the journalists and you see less of it
today because I stayed at a
Smith. Yeah. That kind of style.
There's a style and this is their stick.
Their stick is mocking people
and creating controversy. And I,
that's why I say I don't
think MMA is a sport.
I think it's more intense that's you're
empty and out out there. You know when,
when you see a fight, you
know, and it's a crazy ass war,
like Robbie Lawler Hofeld dos Anjos where
it's just five rounds of chaos to to
diminish either one of
these guys as a man,
as a human being based on
their performance to mock
them or belittled them.
I just don't think it has any
place in that. I think it's,
it's a way more intense and way more
personal experience for those guys.
It's not, it's not playing
baseball. It's not,
it's not fucking bill Buckner dropping
a ball. It's not, that's not what it is,
man. It's way more intense. If you got
a guy who was a lazy football player,
doesn't run fast enough, you want
to mock them tasks, whatever,
you go ahead and do that. I
don't care. It doesn't bother me.
But you want to make fun of a guy who
was literally putting his health on the
line in a,
in an occupation where you're competing
against a mother fucking trained killer
and you guys are going to throw bones
at each other for five minute rounds.
You've got to have some respect.
You have to have respect or you
shouldn't be talking about it.
You should have some understanding of it.
You should know what the fuck you're
watching and you should have some respect.
And if you want to say
that a guy should retire,
that if you want to say that a guy has
probably seen as better days, that's fine,
but have some respect. Is, is a different
thing man. It is not a regular sport.
I agree. And I think I
would say also the, um,
they have no right to be saying things
that they've never done. Right. Yeah.
I mean you, you just can't, you
don't have to compete. Right?
Like you do Jujitsu and more time shit,
and you get such a more in depth
knowledge about what they're truly going
through and what's happening by just
experiencing it a little bit. Right.
There's that.
And there's also,
I think if you've never really been
punched in the face and you're,
you're talking about guys
getting punched in the face,
like you really don't even
understand the experience
or if you never even worse.
I mean,
you've been never been punched in the
face and there's nothing you can do about
it. And I keep it, I mean,
the worst I've ever had a,
I went down to Cuba for a little while
and a train with the Olympic boxing team
down there, this, um, 2012 I then, yeah,
I think you're,
what was,
how did this come about?
Was that it was even legal
to go down there back then.
Did you go on a raft down there?
Um, I think I'm past the, uh, what
would they call it? Your limitations,
limitations. So it's actually
illegal to spend money there.
So I didn't spend any money there,
but I went there and I guess it's
not illegal to actually go there.
So we went through Mexico City.
He go to a mess you're stating and you
buy a flight in Mexico City. And My, uh,
one of my coaches I worked with for a
long time on and off as a Cuban and he
grew up there and he, we went there
together. He's a part of the, um,
he used to coach the wrestling team.
So I went there and train with
the wrestlers, uh, for six,
eight weeks and we'd go over to the
boxing team every now and then. Well,
I went with one guy, he was a
two time gold medalist, I think.
And I've never seen Boston.
I got my life. I mean,
I've never felt anything and there's
nothing I could do. Nothing. I mean,
I tried every fucking trick in the book.
I try every athletic move, I'd hands up,
hands down, here's the side, whatever.
Nothing. I mean, I've never seen Boston,
I mean two time gold medals. I mean,
he was an amazing, amazing boss.
I can't remember his name or anything,
but you know,
just never experienced anything like it.
And it was the same with the wrestlers.
I mean I went with,
uh, some guys that, um,
I've got to go with me hand Lopez,
his heavyweight of course, the Greco,
I don't know if you know,
he is greatest,
a Greco next to Carolyn rivaling
Carolyn and the greatest ever,
um, uh, you know, got this Guy Ivan Fund
door who you had been asking last week.
He was a guy who uh, I think, I
think he was the guy that asks me,
couldn't get past for the Olympics and
I know that a fund or beat him, but um,
he tacked him. So you know, as you
know, it amaze, as amazing as he is.
I mean that's how much better fun Doris
explain tectum for people. It's 15.
Was it 15 points? Um, I don't know
what it is in international actually.
I think it's, I thought it was
only like nine or 10, but whatever.
You got to get ahead of someone.
Yeah. I mean he worked him over.
Um, you know, so I got to work
with these, just a amazing guys.
But the boxing, you know, that's what
we were talking about. And I mean, I,
I've literally to,
to experience,
so like this guy is punching you and
there's nothing you can do. Nothing.
You don't have to.
We're in a little ring and I mean,
you don't have a choice so you can get
out of the ring or you can get punched
and that's your only choice. Just Kenton
boxed up, boxed up and I mean, and,
and he's moving, you know, like Sansai
relaxed and chilled and he's like,
what do you want? You know, you
go fucking do something, but what,
why you're not talking to me like that.
But they're doing it with his motions.
Yeah. Yeah. Terrible. But what an
amazing place of man. But you know,
I feel really bad for those
people. The wasn't experience, man.
Just a different world. You feel like
you're going back in the fifties.
What'd you eat over
there? How do you eat? Uh,
so we stayed with Ivan Fund door and his
wife would actually cooked for us every
day. Um, but there's restaurants and stuff
too. I mean it's like a dollar or two.
We went to this one place just about every
day there was a sort of a big bowl of
spaghetti,
like this big around and this bay,
just a gigantic bowl for like a dollar.
Wow. He had a chicken on top. They don't,
um,
they don't have really have red meat.
I guess it's only for the
wealthy are for the top people.
I don't know if it's illegal or something,
but um,
but why to witness the Lavonne
Lopez who we stayed with originally,
so to witness the way they live is
really fascinating cause so in their
wrestling dorms they have a,
it's like six stories high.
We had to walk to the bottom to get a five
gallon bucket of water to take a bath.
They had no running water upstairs. Take
a bath. That's how you brush your teeth.
That's how you do everything. The guys
on the top floor or the first level,
first team, the varsity team, so to speak.
I, you know, the first level guys, um,
they get a four meals a day and they
get, uh, air conditioning in the room.
They guys right below on the second team,
they got three meals a day
and no air conditioning.
So these guys are literally fighting
for their food and for a, uh, you know,
for the next level. And I mean,
I've seen fights break out.
I seen guys trying to hurt each
other in the wrestling room. Um,
I mean it's fucking intense day in,
day out man.
They have some incredible genetics
over there too. That's credible.
You are going to grow like Yoel Romero.
That motherfucker looks like he
was made in the lab somewhere.
Like some scientists just spliced
together all the perfect attributes.
It just to be clear,
like don't quote me on that.
I guess kind of high her through
translation, you know what I mean?
So I maybe if I got something
the with some, you know,
a bunch of Cubans trying to beat me up
for getting it wrong or anything, but um,
well like I said, it's amazing
place man. And those guys are just,
they're fighting for their food
man. And I seen, I seen one kid,
he was the cousin of
Lavonne Lopez Lavonne's,
a bronze medalist and probably should
have been gold medalist. Um, you know,
I don't want to,
the Olympics have a lot of kind of
behind the scenes stuff that people don't
know about that I'm not sure if I'm
really at liberty to speak out about in
public, you know, cause it's
rumors, right? No, there's
facts. There's certainly fast.
When I said I don't, I'm not sure that
I can really talk about it public.
I wouldn't want to hurt any, uh, any
of those guys. But, um, you know,
his cousin came from a Pan Yard del Rio,
which we went out there one day
and that was, that is a good story.
So we got to the peanut every,
it's like two hours from Havana and we
took a donkey cart to a fucking farm in
the middle of nowhere. We'd go back,
uh, probably five, six acre farm.
We walked back through this horse field,
walking over shit and everything
and in air and say, uh,
I actually all his pictures that
is too is fascinating. And, uh,
there's a forest and as soon
as you walk through the forest,
now it's a casino in the middle of a
forest. So I guess all Shit's illegal.
There's cockfights chicken fights
in the fucking middle of the woods,
which is illegal in Cuba. So I got to do
illegal. Yeah. So I got to, uh, you know,
experience illegal chicken fights
in an illegal country. And,
but yeah, we took the, uh, the
donkey cart out there and you know,
we got stopped by the cops actually,
as I'm sitting there, like, you know,
this is about to be really bad.
So I'd already told my wife that.
But, uh, so anyway, so
we had Pinar del Rio,
that's where Lavonne's cousin lived
there. He actually saved his money, which,
I mean, I think they get, like,
everybody gets like the same amount,
like the doctor and the,
the chef or like the waiter,
waiter or whatever they are, they
all get the same money. Right. Um,
I think it's 30 bucks a month. So he
saved all of his money, their entire home,
smaller than this room right here.
Uh, for people living in there.
Probably I would say about the size of
these tables combined. Wow. Um, anyway,
so I was trying to get his cousin saved
his money for like a whole year just so
he could come train with the
national team. He came out there, um,
didn't only had money to get there,
so lavonne was sharing his meals with him.
And um, so now he's only eating two
meals a day instead of the three or four,
maybe three meals out of the four,
something like that. But yeah, very,
very fascinating. Just
watching that, you know,
you would just forget what we have and
how blessed our lives are. And humbling,
humbling man. I mean, these and these
guys are just savages, men, uh, uh,
just hard, hard workers and getting the
job done, just getting nothing for it. Um,
you know, some of the guys at the
top, like Meaghan Lopez, he gets, uh,
some things like fun Dora for instance,
he got Internet access like that.
That was like a,
a blessing for him to have Internet
access because he had done so much for the
country in the Olympics. That's crazy.
I think he was a bronze medalist.
I think they hooked him
up with the Internet.
You get hooked up with Internet and
I still email him every now and then.
Like he'll send me pictures as a
family and stuff and, and you can,
and it at something like a,
you know,
fun dora@cubagovernment.net or something
like that. You know, maybe it's like a,
so it goes through the government,
so the government tracks every
email coming in and out. So yeah.
So he would even tell me like,
before I left, you know, like, like,
don't email me this or this,
then don't talk about this and why I
think it's maybe laxed up a little bit,
but I'm not sure man. So yeah, I can
tell you a lot of stories about it.
It was really a very
eyeopening experience. Like,
like I want to take my kids there
sometime. Like just to see the look.
You want to fucking, what if you grew up
here motherfucker, you know shit. Right.
You know, be happy. You know, you got what
you got and yeah, yeah. I mean as kids.
So one of the pictures I could show you
a be the wrestling where whom in Pinar
del Rio, I think he, Oh
Ramiro came from there,
actually may hand came from there and
Lavonne came from there and they're
wrestling room is actually probably
about as big as this room and it's a dirt
floor with the mats are, you know, so,
so if you imagine a Matt getting a
dissolved in water and like all the little
pieces just spread out.
So they sweep up all those pieces,
put them in a a,
it's about as big as this table here
that they sweep it all together and stack
it up and that's our mat. So
they just practice, you know,
basically take down stuff.
And that's why they're so hard to take
down that they learned from a young age.
And you get taken down and fucking sucks.
Wow. Actually a picture of it. I mean,
it's really fascinating. Wow.
How long were you over there for?
A six to eight weeks. I can't remember.
Something like that. That's a long time.
Yeah. We stayed for a long time and we
did basically the whole training camp over
there for which fight, uh, Jordan
mean. Wow. And that was, um,
so that's when I first started
working with our guide and you know,
the first thing he said was like,
you need better wrestling.
It's good to keep it holy shit.
I said, all right, let's go. Wow.
As I wrestled with those guys every day,
um, my wrestling came up tremendously.
Oh yeah. I mean, there's no way
sink or swim. Um, and then I said,
I've got to work with the boxing
team and the Boston team. I mean,
the wrestling is one thing, but, uh, I
seen a lot of the junior boxing team guys,
I see one kid get kicked off the boxing
team. Like they take their boxing very,
very serious over there. Right.
That's our national sport. Uh,
one kid got kicked off the team because
he wasn't keeping up and they were doing,
they had to get up at like 5:00 AM to
like an eight mile run or something.
And they put,
you know,
water bottles like this and they fill it
up with sand and that's their dumbbells.
And the kid didn't have any shoes but
he couldn't keep up and they were doing
hill sprints and he kept falling behind.
They're like, you're off the team. Wow.
So they would do like a am and then
they go to school and then they do an
afternoon workout and then they go back
to school and then they do an evening
workout. And I live in these dorms
and that's literally all they do.
That's their entire life.
They want to get out there or
live a better life, you know,
the be a champion or die. Holy
Shit. Yeah. And uh, again,
you know, um, I, I was looking all this
or are learning all this too translation.
So, uh, you know, I could have
some things not exactly right, but,
you know, I was, I was living
there with them for a little while.
Have you wanted to go to
Thailand? Absolutely. Yeah.
Yeah, I do too. Yeah. You know,
my thing is, uh, so like when I did that,
my kids were very young and it wasn't so
bad to leave them with their mom for a
little while. Now I have a, you
know, now I have three kids,
specifically my daughter. It's
just hard to leave and, and uh,
to fly to Thailand if you'd
ever been there. No, no. I
say to fly there, you know,
is expensive and um, you
know, I don't want to leave.
I just can't leave my family and,
but this place is,
you can go and bring them like cat
supposed to be nice. Right. And it's,
yeah. And getting the flights, you know,
is what's expensive. Once you get there,
it's cheap. Right. But the flight,
I mean, $1,000 per person, you know,
I'm looking at $5,000 just to
fly there. So, yeah, I want to,
but that's my, the nice thing about
having [inaudible]. Yeah. Right.
Right now you live in, in Colorado
still or are you here? Yeah,
so I live in Colorado right now and
then I'm coming back and forth a lot.
Come too late.
Yeah.
Doing a lot of work with the MusclePharm
cause mussel farms opening up their
main headquarters now in Burbank.
Is that what's going to be,
so they moved here to move here?
Um,
well the CEO lives here for
one thing and I think a,
they're going to attract a
lot more athletes here and
I think that they're going
to be able to do a much bigger thing.
And really what they're doing is they're
restructuring the entire business.
They're kind of moving away
from just simply being a, um,
you know, whether the change like
from muscle farm to NP for instance,
so that it's not just for the
body builder type crowd and the,
excuse me, the for the meat heads and
the, you know, and without, you know,
I mean it was certainly still
be catering to the crowd,
but now they want to open it up more
as a lifestyle brand, expand it,
and there'll be doing a lot more
stuff with a lot more athletes,
which I think there'll be able to do out
here better than in Denver. What now,
as a guy who's trained at sea level
and you lived in Denver, um, what,
how much of a benefit is it to be at
that 5,000, 500 feet? Pros and cons?
What's the con?
Well,
the number one con is that you can't,
uh, your Max capacity is lower.
So you can't work as hard. He can't work
as hard. But now you get adapted though.
You know,
I've,
I've been a little tour with that because
I tell you when I do my mass capacity
training,
um,
I don't think I've been able to reach
the same levels that I wasn't sea level.
Um, I've heard other people
say that they are able to, um,
my prs in terms of lifts
have been comparable.
Um,
but of course I
was at west side before, so it's not
right. You know, I mean, you're just not,
I tell you what, you walk into west side,
like you hit a PR period. Like you don't,
it doesn't matter. There's an
energy in there. There's an aura.
It's an intense place. Yeah, you've been
there. I mean, you probably hit a PR,
but if you work out, um, I get nervous.
But I suppose it,
cause I mean the obvious pro is a red
blood cell count and I think your lung
capacity goes up.
Um,
the idea they say is to sleep at altitude,
but to train example.
Exactly.
And it's so that you can push your Max
capacity at sea level and then recover.
So if like if you're in California,
you would live in big bear,
but then you would train
down in San Bernardino or
something like that. Exactly.
Yeah. And I don't know. I don't even
know California well enough to know that,
how that works.
But it's pretty close.
You get to here in two hours
you could drive there. Right.
It's funny that people out here say
that's close, like to meet two hours,
a long ass way. Well, yeah.
No, it's close as fuck here.
Two hours to take you that long
to get to Irvine and traffic.
That's what everybody says.
That's how I got to work in Irvine.
Like if I'm doing the Improv
and it's an eight o'clock show,
I leave here at four not bullshit.
I leave here at 4:00 PM and I'm stuck
in traffic for two and a half fucking
hours. No bullshit that
everybody listens to. Podcasts,
podcasts, audio books, you
know, anything, anything.
Just keep your mind off that fucking
those red lights in front of me. Right?
I'm from Columbus, Ohio. Like you can go
around the outer belt in like an hour.
Yeah. Yeah. You guys have
terrible traffic. It's like, Yo,
I was stuck in traffic for 10 minutes.
Yeah, that's exactly. Yeah. Well, yeah,
I mean diverse. Pretty bad now actually.
All that weed. Yeah. All the weed, man.
People just, everybody just went there.
Yeah. Last time I was there I was like,
what the fuck is going on here with all
this traffic? It's just wheat apparently.
I guess it's actually been
growing for years, like any way,
but the men when you go ski
and that's the worst man.
You come back from a ski resort
Sunday four or five o'clock dude,
it's like I just did the other week and
it took me three and a half hours for a
one and a half hour drive. That's
crazy. Yeah. Well Denver is just,
it's an amazing city because you're in,
you're in this cool city
that's a real city, legit city,
and then right outside is the fucking
rocky mountains. It's right there.
Right there. You drive an hour
and you're in the rocky mountains.
I mean fucking wilderness.
Jack Elk,
Screamin and bears running around.
Wow.
I said the city has that
an hour outside the city.
You were in the fucking mountains. It is
sunny too. Yeah. You get all four seasons,
which I like, and the people are
cool as fuck. Yeah. People go, yeah.
This is one of the few places I
would live outside of California,
but I used to live era. Yeah,
I lived in boulder. Yeah.
I'm not sure I would go bolder, but while
I was in the mountains above boulder,
that was like 3000 feet above boulder,
I was an 8,500 feet.
It was pretty interesting. And as you feel
a difference, man, going up the stairs,
it's crazy. But did you adapt to
it and fell? The difference was
only there for three months.
My wife got, yeah, yeah.
My wife got pregnant and it's
rough up there for women.
If they haven't adapted,
it's rough in Denver,
but then you go 3000 feet across
Denver. It's real rough. Yeah.
I go up there all the time.
Yeah. If you're a woman and
you get pregnant up there,
it's like having the flu.
It's real bad.
And they have a really high instance of
low birth weight and premature birth.
I did not know that.
Yeah, Denver does as well.
Denver has one of the highest rates
in the country of premature births.
I did not know that. That's
fascinating. Yeah. Yeah.
I was up at my friend's house out by
Edward School a little bit past veil,
their day and like you were talking about
the elk and bears and stuff. I mean,
at nighttime he said,
usually you shine a flashlight out and
you just see the eyes of the mountain
lions. He's got dogs and stuff and
they're just sitting there waiting.
He's got a fence now, but he's like,
you just see their eyes. There was one,
a store that I tweeted out
today in California where
some fucking mountain line
was banging on this screen door or this
a glass door trying to get at this dog
in California. Yeah, they
got pictures of this cat.
You don't want to mess with those guys.
Yeah. One of them ain't my dog. A bears.
One thing I'll really, yeah,
one of meet my dog in Gold Hill.
This fucking mountain lion.
Man,
right outside these people's house
trying to get at that little dog. Yeah,
they took pictures of it that,
and it's killed a bunch of
pets in the neighborhood.
Apparently they have a real problem with
them in California because they don't
hunt them. So they're not
scared of people at all. And,
and that's a problem with California
right there against everything that I'm
for.
They're against legalizing weed.
It's ignorant based.
They have an idea of what a mountain
lion is and that these are these majestic
creatures and they shouldn't be hunted.
And what they would like to
do is eliminate all hunting
and let nature sorted
out on their own.
But yet they have grocery
stores everywhere where they
have food that's murdered
animals that are factory farm. It's
the stupid, it's fucking shit ever.
You're not going to turn the
whole state and to vegetarians.
So this idea that you're not,
you're going to eliminate
hunting is so fucking stupid.
It's like you would rather
people try and do that,
try to eliminate hunting or the people
that are the most radical wildlife
activists would like to
eventually eliminate hunting
and have all these animals
sorted out with themselves
in a natural way,
but they're never going to
eliminate people eating meat.
97% of the people in this country eat
meat that, so that's a real number.
So this idea that you're going to somehow
or another change those 97% based on
the desires of the 3% which
fluctuate back and forth. By the way,
the 3% there's a lot of those 3%
that fall off and they eventually,
for health reasons,
go back to eating meat again or eat some
animal products because these fish and
animals are fucking awesome.
I've loved the fact that Real,
I love that they're out there,
but if you think that it's okay
to have tons of mountain lions,
I have a buddy who works at [inaudible]
ranch. They got a trail camera.
They are over a pond.
They got photos of 16 different
mountain lines visiting this pond.
Yeah. What fuck man. I
shouldn't say it's this,
this is all because in the 1990s they
outlawed hunting up. It doesn't make,
they didn't do it for any rational is a
mountain lion as an apex Predator. Right.
It's an apex Predator and that you
can eat them and they're delicious.
They taste the pork. Yeah. Yeah.
My friend Steve Shot one recently,
he said it was one of the most delicious
meals he's ever had in his life.
I have to try it. Yeah. They have
delicious fat that you, you cook them,
Cook it just like poor.
I never would have thought that.
I never would have thought the cat family.
Right. Yeah. It's weird eating a cat.
Yeah. But apparently they're
delicious. Probably have before. Yeah.
Well unknowingly, but there's just a
control the population to keep them.
Good luck finding a deer in California.
Just like when you walk into the grocery
store and you see the meat aisle,
like do you just see animals sit in there?
You know what I mean? Cause you see,
I mean the meat aisle is gigantic as big
as this wall. And like when I see it,
I just see a bunch of animals. My man,
like none of these were treated right.
Raised right, killed, right.
And now they're packaged
like there's some glorious,
amazing food. Well, let's just soup.
It's too sanitized and sterilized.
It's weird.
And especially as someone who's killed
animals and quartered them up in the
field and carried them away and cut
them up and put them and wrap them and
vacuum seal them and put them in my
freezer and then thought about an aid them
like I've been there through the whole
process. So I look at the whole thing.
Totally different. Now when I go
to the butcher section, it's just,
I did that when I was like 10 years old.
So yeah. So you've been doing it forever?
Well, I haven't hunted since
I was like a teenager, but,
but you have and you know it.
So I just think maybe we used
to raise chickens and like,
my dad would be like,
go kill a chicken for dinner.
Like that was like my job sometimes.
So yeah. Hey, same thing. You know,
especially when you raised the animal
to right, he become cut to, you know,
have some compassion for it. And you
realize the chickens in particular,
uh, I mean way more so
with cattle and pays like,
you realize pigs are very smart, you
know, they're, they're intelligent and,
and like a dog. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, I feel like, uh, I,
I know that technically
they're, that's smart, right.
But there's something different
about dogs, right? Yeah.
For whatever reason. Yeah.
There's something different about it.
Maybe just maybe just my bias
from what I've been taught from,
from a society or whatever, but
culturally, right? Yeah, yeah.
We have the animals that we like better.
Yeah, yeah, certainly. Yeah. I mean,
I felt terrible like killing some of
the pigs. Yeah, I'd imagine. Yeah.
And then you eat them and
you know, personally, I mean,
I always thought the grocery store
sausage and bacon tasted way better, but,
but I was like, man, that was
sorta my excuse. I was like, man,
this doesn't taste good.
I'm not sure if I want to eat it.
But in my head I'm thinking like,
man, I really feel bad for this guy.
I don't want to eat them, you know?
No, I know what you mean, man. It's,
we have a weird disconnect with food
in this country in particular and
especially in this day and age when you
have a majority of the people eating
meat and the majority of people never
seen any animal die and then get chopped
up and turned into meat and then eat it.
It's a,
there's always going to be this weird
disconnect and that's what you change that
though? Boy, I dunno. I Dunno if he can.
I just think it's one of the weird, it's,
it's the,
I don't think,
I think this society is an
amazing thing and what we've,
what we've accomplished where you
don't have to ever worry about food.
You can just go down the store right
down the street here and get a steak and
cook it and instantaneously
you don't have to kill it.
You don't have to dress it.
You don't have to do,
all these steps have been avoided.
They just give him a piece of paper.
That piece of paper gets you a steak.
It's just, it's amazing. You know,
you could go to a store down the corner
over here and you can get gasoline.
Some mother fucker had to go to the
Middle East, pull oil out of the ground,
refine it, put it in tanker
trucks, driving across the country,
pop it into a hole in the
ground. You Swipe up, swipe up,
piece of plastic through this
reader, the pleat, the it,
you punch in your area code or your
zip code, whatever the fuck it is.
Was it your zip code? Right?
You put the nozzle in your tank,
you fill your tank up with gas.
This fucking car that's designed by
engineers in a way you would never be able
to figure out on your own and you get
to turn the key and drive this thing
around and there's so many steps that
have been taken to make our lives way more
convenient. Yo, you'd have
to do all that anymore.
He had this thing in your hand and you
just push a button and some do shows show
for your fucking door with food or some
dude with a car and drives anywhere you
want to,
yeah. Drive where we go here. Yeah.
He shows up with the animal that's been
slaughtered and cooked and cooked and
sterilized and BA got worried
about if it's healthy or not.
Like when I was in Cuba, they
hit, like I said, the red meat is,
I don't know if it's illegal or are
just very hard to come by or whatever,
but so we went to this sort of
black market stand and I mean,
I've got a picture of it.
I mean,
it's a table bigger than this table of
just red meat sitting out and there's
flies on it and the people are just
like, they're, yeah. So I want some,
you know, and it's all the
different cuts and everything.
Not cut up just terribly.
Right, right. Wow. Yeah.
We're lucky as shit man. And this is
the easiest time ever to be alive. Yeah,
it really is. Yeah. At least in
America. Yeah. At least in America.
Maybe not in some places.
No. I think that's why it's
good to visit other places,
man. Just to, just to get a look around
and see what it's like. What am I,
the reasons I want to go to Thailand.
Like I want to go there and train,
but only so much. I mean there's
like, I think that so much of the tie,
uh, skill training is already in
America that it's not going to,
you might get some details or
whatever over there, but they're,
they're also so traditional and so far
behind us in terms of, uh, you know,
at least in strength and conditioning
and proper ways of training and things
like that, that I, I don't
know how beneficial that is,
but I want to go over there
and see how they live. I mean,
they eat spiders and you know,
these insects and most people are
ultra poor over there and you know,
but you know, they're, they're all,
they're really Buddhist. Right.
And then I guess they
kind of, um, you know,
they drop their kids off at the fricking
Thai camp and just leave. Like, you know,
it's very strange to us. Yeah.
Yeah. I find it fascinating. Yeah,
I do too. I find it incredibly
fascinating. You know,
I talked to John Wayne Park quite a
bit about his experiences over there.
He went over there when he was real young
and lived over there and lived in Thai
camps live like a Thai credible
stories, you know, so it's,
it's just a very unique culture.
It just,
it helps you appreciate where you
live and puts things into perspective.
Yeah. And there and the, we'll say Japan,
you've been there I'm sure. Right? Yeah.
I've been in Japan. Yeah. Fascinating.
Fascinating. The shit out of me
to people being in a foreign land.
It's also like on another planet,
people standing in line to the subway
to get on the subway train. Yeah.
I was there for it.
We did like a military tour and I was,
I think Todd Duffy was there and uh,
was it a CB the way maybe,
but yeah,
you could see Todd from over top
of the crowd from like a mile away.
Right? Yeah. It's hilarious.
Yeah, it's interesting. Um,
how polite they are over
there. So polite. Yeah.
It's like there's so much
order and disciplines.
It's just completely fascinating.
I remember him on the subway train
or they're standing in line. Yeah.
I just wanted to walk to
the funnel with you guys.
You probably could have done it and they
probably wouldn't even said anything.
Well then we did another
one in Iraq or Middle East.
Eye Rack was one of the places or did we,
I can't remember,
but the Middle East and man,
those people will,
they will shove you right out of
the way. Right. Like, you know, you,
you funneling in through
the airport or something.
They're the rudest people
ever when it comes to, you
know, standing in line. Yeah.
You don't tell him about right. Yeah.
It's ridiculous. I mean, you know,
you say something to them. No, I don't
speak English or whatever. I don't know.
I don't speak your language either.
So I guess we're fucked.
How many different countries
have you fought in? Um, only, uh,
only two. Yeah, I thought in the UK. Is
it a big transition going over there?
Like the weight cuts got to be harder.
And the finding the right
food when I fought over there,
um, yeah, the Waco wasn't that bad.
Uh, you'll be finding
the, my food was terrible.
You said you've been on a ketogenic diet.
We were talking before the podcast
for the last what, three years?
About three years.
Yeah.
It was after I fought Johnny Hendricks
actually and I suffered a concussion and
that was what originally got me on to
the idea of doing a ketogenic diet and
then I fought Robbie Lawler next.
And why did the concussion get you on
the idea of having is good for Tbi and
concussion?
I mean that's the theory at least.
I don't think they have a lot
of proof that I know they have,
they've done some research on mice
but not necessarily in humans.
But did you feel when you
changed your diet, um,
in wasn't like initially was
there a struggle? Oh yeah.
The first couple of weeks
is terrible. Keto flu thing.
Yeah. I had a really bad, uh,
but I didn't do it after the hinder is
five, but I started reading about it then.
And then when I fought
Lawler, I missed weight. Um,
I think it was I half a or something.
That was the only time I've
ever missed weight my life.
I did everything exactly like
I'd done a hundred times before.
Me and my coach Tom Barrier, a west side
Barbell, we had everything planned out.
We had a notebook of, you know, this
is what we eat this day, this day,
this day and this day, this moment.
And everything's planned out.
We did everything exactly the same. Um,
ended up, you know, still missing weight.
And um, I, that was when I
realized my metabolism had changed.
So I started looking more and more
into different, uh, types of diets.
So I've always been my own Guinea pig.
That's sort of a blessing and a curse
for my, um, well that's why, you know,
I want to be a coach because I've,
uh,
I think I'll make it 10 times better
coach than I was a fighter because I have
experimented on myself.
I've is,
why have all these books and everything
and the problem with that, right. Is it,
you know,
you get a bad info too,
or you misinterpreted misunderstand it
and maybe it's for regular people and I'm
a high level athlete, et Cetera,
et cetera. So anyway, um, I,
I used it for one for
the concussion and to,
to sort of a metabolic shift
into a more fats and, uh,
I haven't missed weight sense.
So did you feel any benefit of switching
to key to genic tie it in terms of
performance? Um, you know, actually
felt a lack of benefit actually.
So some of the Max capacity lowered
immediately, so my prs went down, um,
over time, back up. Yeah. They
came back up. Yeah. So how
long, when did it go down?
Like right away? Like within, yeah,
within the first week or two. I mean,
they're completely shot few months to
really truly adapt, right? Yeah, exactly.
Yeah. And then, and what I've done now
over time is I've adapted the Diet to, um,
you know, a lot of, I do a
lot of different things now,
so I'm not as Ketogenic as I once
was where it was all Kito Kito Kid.
Now I don't even pay
attention to my ketones. Well,
I take that ketone ester like we
took earlier. I take that a lot,
which I fucking love. You probably feel
it right now. I like Shit's amazing.
It tastes like sucking on
Godzilla. It does. It's worse.
Maybe it's like, whoa, it's
terrible. Terrible. But I use that.
And then I used a, you know, regular
Quito, salt supplements, but that one,
you know, for performance actually
brings my performance up higher than, uh,
than I would usually go take that
ketone ester before you train,
how long before you train. So I
take it with some glucose, uh,
usually about 20 minutes before a train.
And you use those glucose packets?
Who makes those packets? I just,
whatever at the grocery store,
power mar or whatever, you
know, it doesn't matter.
It's just a matter of sugar.
Yeah. You just had to make sure we have
some sugar because of the hypoglycemic
effects. I don't drop your blood sugar,
but it's so potent is very, very potent.
Like our key tones are
probably in the three. Like,
I actually have my blood meter.
Maybe we'll check, but, uh,
probably in the three to five millimole
range right now. Um, but yeah,
so, you know, I do that and then,
but now I've adjusted it where I'm not
as concerned with staying in Ketosis
because the main concern with that is I
want to get the benefits for the brain
and, um, you know, the Tbi and
things like that. Um, now it's, uh,
um, when I get closer to a fight,
it's more about performance, right?
So add in some, I use like a
Yukon Starch, um, I use, um, uh,
like sweet potatoes.
He at a certain starches that don't
really affect your ketone levels quite as
much.
Um,
so that can bring my performance
up a lot better. Well,
I think there's a real issue with high
level athletes with the amount of workout
put that you put in,
that you probably need more
carbohydrates than the regular person.
It's on a ketogenic diet. I've
been, I've been, uh, again,
I'm my own Guinea pig,
right? And I experiment with
that and I've been married,
I've been kind of torn with that. Right?
So one of the things that, that, uh, uh,
are a lot of people will kind of propagate
is that our sport is very anaerobic
and it's really not.
It's a lot more Robic and your
aerobic capacity will go up on Kido.
You're Rebecca,
you're my ability to recover
specifically without even with no carbs.
Ma My blood glucose could be a seventies
and eighties and not have carbs for
weeks at a time. And my ability to
recover it goes up tremendously.
We're talking about tendonitis. My
tendonitis goes away, my injuries,
my joints just feel better.
I feel better all the way around.
My brain feels better. And uh,
um, a lot of things like that.
But the,
but when you do need to
kick in that mass capacity,
anaerobic part of things, that's
where, you know, things suffer.
Suffer. Yeah. And that's where you have
to add in the carbs and, but again,
you know, the, the amount of
training that I do, I mean,
I can add in a lot of carbs and I
can still get away with it and stay,
and I can even stay in Ketosis if,
if I want to.
But I think a lot of people make
the mistake that I made originally,
again is my own Guinea pig.
And,
and I really focused on the blood ketone
levels rather than the performance.
And I wanted to be able to perform with
high key to genic levels, you know,
high ketone levels, um, and in my blood,
and it's not really necessary. Right.
I think it should be solely performance
based, but it did. It did help me. Cut.
Wait though, I thought it was fascinating
with Ben. Greenfield was saying,
we were talking about it
before the podcast about how
he would carve up and then
take ketone supplements.
So we had the benefit of having a
lot of carbohydrates in the system,
but also having a lot of
ketones in the system.
And he said he felt like a fucking
animal. Yeah. And that's pretty similar.
It's probably how we feel right now. I
mean, that's totally legal. Totally. Yeah.
I mean that's not, and I'll tell
you like when I take it, uh, it,
it does amazing things
for me. Um, men. I, I've,
so I've heard stories of people when they
take this Esther that they'll pull out
moves like they haven't done in 10 years.
Like they recalls these moves and um,
I've done things where when I do it, I
feel like I'm five, six years younger.
I mean it's done some fascinating
things taking that drink,
just taken the Ester with some uh,
um,
some get digging out of the trash,
pulling it out here. Yeah. It ketone aid,
ketone aid,
ketone Ester and it looks like you're
a scientist like this breaking bad type
shit.
The thing with it,
it's extremely expensive and they're
working on getting the, uh, it's,
it's like burnt rubber there. You
were working on getting the um, uh,
the cost down. I think he's thinking
how much of these things, I'm not sure,
but I think it's like $30 a
gram and that's like 40 grams.
I think that's incredible. I could be
off on that. I'm not sure. But, uh,
that's quite pricey.
I heard that the UK cycling team used it.
They paid like $6,000 for,
you know,
however much, just a small
amount. And they used it for the,
when they won the Tour de France actually.
Wow. I don't know how true it is,
but I believe it. I mean this
shit does amazing things for him.
But yeah, so the Kido, I mean again,
it can be used if used properly.
I think it can do a lot of benefits.
I would recommend to all,
um,
as a combat athletes and
NFL players over there,
they've taken concussions taking his
sort of brain or that are over a certain
age where your metabolism changes. I
mean that's where my biggest benefit was.
And even a Tj was talking
about the t TJ Dillashaw.
I was talking with him about it.
His coach had him switch ever cause he
was burning primarily carbohydrates.
Especially now TJ is going to try
to make one 25. And I don't know if
he was talking to me about long before
that was ever talked about. So, but he,
you know,
he did some tests on him and found that
he's burning all carbohydrate all the
time, which can be an issue in long
training sessions specifically.
So he switched it up a bit.
Yeah. And I don't, I don't
think he's going full Quito,
but I think he's doing something similar
to like what I'm doing, where the,
he's doing Kido with, uh, you know, some
carbohydrates still and he's using the,
so basically like the only carbohydrates
that we need as an athlete is for the
workout. Right. We don't need them after
that. Um, you know, maybe for recovery,
which is a, again, I think it's
debatable, but um, you know,
carbohydrate is not a necessary
substance to even live. You know,
you could live your entire life without
eating a carbohydrate and be perfectly
fine.
Yeah.
There's a lot of guys that are doing this
carnivore diet now I've heard of this.
Yeah. Mark Bell told me he's never felt
better. He's always doing that shit now.
Yeah. Yeah. He's, he's
eaten nothing but steak.
Steak all day. No sausage
or bacon. It's bacon too,
but it's mostly me and he's eaten
mostly me. Mostly me. So what,
no vegetables a little
bit every now and then.
But most of what he's eating
is just meets the eye.
I feel completely different
when I load up my vegetables.
Even if a day or two. I mean,
I don't know. Do you feel
this? I don't feel better.
Yeah. I'm a big family thing. I just,
I love drinking it too. You know,
I love getting like real rich
green leafy vegetable and a,
I drink a lot of Kale shakes while
I'll take a Goddamn Bushel of Kale that
you're never going to sit down and eat.
You're never going to eat that much Kale.
I'll blend that motherfucker up with
a giant chunk of ginger and garlic.
I'll throw an apple in there and a
bunch of coconut oil and I'll fuck on,
throw some salary in there and
I'll drink it and it's, Ooh,
I think I've seen that on youtube. You
put like a pair in there too, right? Yeah.
Maybe a pay or maybe an apple.
I'll mix it up.
Sometimes I put peaches
or pineapple in there too.
You put the whole day with
the seeds and everything.
A fucking throw that bitch
and grind it up and just,
it's all performance. It doesn't
taste good. It tastes like shit.
And it's like people try to
drink it and they're like, yeah,
oh I can't did I got to try this.
But dude,
I drink it and I feel like a
fucking gorilla. How much garlic?
You put it in a lot. Like four or
five cloves. That's, it's rough.
I just eat cloves now.
Yeah, I do that too.
I eat a lot of close work
burns when it's going down,
but you could feel it within like
an hour or two. You're like, damn,
there's something in there man.
Especially if I'm feeling anything,
like I'm feeling a little
sick and feeling funky,
like kind of feeling a little worn down.
Maybe it's going around.
I'll just chomp on some garlic.
You ever tried Chaga route?
No, I do this. I did it.
Well. I've only done it one time when
I was sick. My whole family got sick.
Kids that you've been there,
right? Kids are miserable.
All of this are laying down like we're
laying around like where in the hospital?
You know, every couple
of seconds here, cough.
And where I was laying there miserable
and I was the only one that did the
chocolate route. I put it in a crock
pot, put 10, a little chunks in there.
And I was the only one that didn't get
sick or didn't stay sick very long.
I stayed sick for like a day or two,
maybe Haga route.
What's supposed to be the
benefit of this stuff? Man,
I don't want to butcher this.
Google it. Yeah. Yeah, I can't,
I mean it's an immune system
enhancer. It's like, uh, it,
I heard it from my friend who's a
survivalist specialist expert and he like,
he teaches these classes,
you know,
where you go out and live off the land
and things like that. Right. And um,
you know,
he gets it from like Maine or Canada
and it's like his fungus that grows on
trees and it's really, really hard
and they chop it off and then you can,
you grind it up, put it in a tea or
something and supposedly, you know,
it's really good for immune system.
Why does it make you feel?
I don't feel anything. I didn't
feel any difference at all. I mean,
I'm sitting there drinking it.
It like it was some bullshit and
I'm drinking it anyway. I'll try it.
And you know, my guy told
me, so, um, you know,
nuts obviously it's very anecdotal and
it was like one instance and I just like,
I just got sick a couple weeks ago and
I completely forgot about and I was sick
for like two weeks.
But
you had a pretty significant back injury
at one point when I herniated disk.
How did you fix that? Um, I guess
it's never really fixed. Fixed, right.
Um,
I got an epidural steroid injection first
because I wanted to make the fight is
what I'm supposed to fight.
Conduct the first time.
It was like two weeks out
of the fight and does it,
what the epidural steroids does it relax
the area and loosen the inflammation?
A corticosteroid, right? Yeah. So it
gets rid of inflammation. It took mine,
um, and we did it on a Friday. This
was like two weeks out of the fight.
Um,
so what had happened is about four weeks
out of the fight is when I originally
heard it and you know,
how am I coming off fucking suck it up
and do I think you said you herniated
disc,
so you know what it feels like right now.
I'm a suck the shit up and I'm going
to get through it. And you know,
I couldn't do anything. I could
barely even hit pads. Right. Um,
well I eventually ended up, you
know, going to a, well actually,
so this is part of my problem
with Chiropractors, right?
So I went to a chiropractor first
and he's like, Oh yeah, you know,
crack it and it's all good, you know,
and all this kind of uh, garbage. Anyway.
I know I be seeing a pain specialist and
he knew what it was within 30 seconds.
Yeah. Anyway, so I got the epidural
steroid and it didn't work right away,
so I had to get a second
one later. So, Eh, yeah.
The second time, that's the issue,
right? Is it mass the issue?
I think it's due to some of
the inflammation. So some
of the problems of it. Yeah.
So that's it. I mean, he, and he
told me that he said, you know, look,
we're going to get you to the fight.
This is the best way to
get you to the fight.
But it didn't work well
enough the first time,
so I end up getting a second one and
it worked very well the second time.
But then of course as you know,
having a herniated disc, a,
it just took years to correct it,
you know,
and I mean I work on all the time
now if I, if I don't keep on it,
then I will feel the, the
fat, I'll fill the issues,
especially in Jujitsu as a worst time.
Is your lower back
l five I think.
Did you use Louie Simmons a reverse
hyper did use that machine to that?
Of course. Yeah. Yeah, of
course. I do tons of the
reverse hyper all the time. Um,
I mean I have a whole routine that I
do pretty much after pretty much every
workout. Just to strengthen your
back. Yup. Yup. Far Back and hips.
A lot of my personal problem
with my hip mobility and uh,
so I do the hips, a, uh,
abs obliques as gets real tight.
So I have to lay on a fucking
kettle bell, that thing, you know,
my hip flexors. But, um, you know,
I started working with this a strength
conditioning coach. Now that Amanda,
you know, he does, he
works wonders for me.
Now you have your own bind the shit
and you sent us a bunch of stuff,
some fucking cool hammers and,
and uh,
you got wheel barrels and a
bunch of different things.
What was your thought process behind,
what was the name of the company? Uh,
in mortal combat equipment?
Ice and there's it on a
online, the mortal Kombat, so,
well I have my website and mortal
kind of equipment.ceo and then, uh,
it's on west side barbell.
We sell on their distributed
to them an elite fts.com.
And um, basically the way
that whole started was go,
oh, there we go. Nice. Yeah.
The way that whole started,
the whole thing started was with the,
the wheelbarrows. Louie
had a, a wheelbarrow that
we was using all the time.
He's used for probably
20 years. And, um, we,
I was like, man, I, you know, I could
build, that thing's a piece of junk.
He's been around here like 20 years.
It's fallen apart. And I said, you know,
let me build one. And, uh, we built, one,
one person asked me to build
one for him is okay, cool.
And then another person asked me to
build one for him and then I said, man,
Oh man, I should just start making
these. And I'd had the ideas for the, uh,
so I talked to a engineer and a,
we just started manufacturing them and uh,
you know, just, it's sort of
like a side project thing for me.
So something I want to get into a post,
a fight career, you know, like I said,
he's a few things I want to do, you know,
for one strength conditioning, coaching,
martial arts, coaching, uh, you know, do
some stuff with muscle farm and, you know,
I want to, uh, you know, be able
to sell my equipment. Right. Um,
the hammers I thought for a
long time, um, I don't know,
like you guys do the Macy's, you know,
these are different than the masons.
The actually sledgehammer, right? I'm
sure if you swing a sledge hammer,
it just doesn't make sense that you go
to home depot and you buy a shit ass 16
pounds, 20 pounds, sledge hammer.
Our start at 15 pounds off,
probably make it a 10 pound at some point,
maybe an eight or seven or something.
And um, you know, they're usually
they're square. They're um, you know,
it doesn't make any sense. Right? So we
just made it specifically for swinging,
for training, for training and then, yeah,
good fat handling and you see also a,
it has a ball on the end in case it
slips out. So it keeps it in your hand.
And it never made sense to me that I
would see a 200 pound man and 125 pound
woman bus swinging the same sledgehammer.
Right. Especially these 200 pound men,
you know, like me. Like I swing
the 30, 35 pounds, such hammer,
which got to try is just insanely hard,
but you have to have it right technique
and everything. Um, but you know,
I swing that from my workout and uh,
for different,
I mean there's different things depending
on are you gonna expand your line
because you've got absolutely just the,
right now you've got the sledges,
those three in the wheelbarrow and the
grip balls. Now the grip balls, do they,
what do you put them on it?
Like a carabiner or something
like that and do chin,
yeah. Connected to anything. I actually,
if you see on that video who we connected
to the wheelbarrow and carry the
wheelbarrow. I love doing
that. Tons of things.
I mean there's just a tons of
options. That's that one. My kids,
they were little baby kettle bells. They
were doing kettlebell swings and shit.
Nice, Nice, Nice. Um, I have
some bad ass ideas, man.
We're going to build some really,
really cool stuff. Um, you know,
I don't know. I guess I could just say
I don't, I don't really care. I mean,
you know, like when you use the belt
squat before, right? We're going to,
I'm working on prototyping one right now.
I have actually about 10 prototypes.
I just haven't had the time,
energy to focus.
I kind of like almost don't want it to
grow too fast because like I'm still
fighting is something I want to
work on after fighting. And um,
basically we would do a belt squat that
you can walk with so it's just going to
have wheels and he'd just
walk around anywhere with it
and you could sort of, um,
you know, even like, you know, clinch
was somewhat aware of what she, I mean,
you can do a ton of things
like that with the west side,
a belt squat they already have.
And there is other belt squats
that can do similar things.
But the other west side one, they were
telling me you could hit pads for sure.
I have somebody on the plan,
which I do,
which I do thing just the way
it loads up your hips like that.
And it seems like one of the things I
think you'd, you'd probably really like,
we're going to build, um, and
they have one at west side.
You may have seen it when you went there.
The forest treadmill,
that's just the one at west side.
I mean it's just a basic tremor.
Like if you buy one off like Woodway
or whatever, they're like 3000, 4,000,
I think it would be like five or $6,000.
I'm going to build one.
You could sell for like
five, 600 bucks. You know,
like you just put it in your garage,
whatever.
Like you don't need to buy a
$5,000 Woodway treadmill. Right.
Why did you decide to start out with
the hammers and wheel barrels? Well,
the hammers I wanted for myself.
Is that something you use all the time?
Absolutely. He's probably my favorite
exercise. I mean, of course there's,
every exercise is a tool,
right? And you know,
you don't use a socket wrench on
screw. Right? So, you know, we have a,
there's a million different exercises
that we do for MMA. Everybody asks me,
what do you do? Like you name it,
I'd probably do it. Right. Uh,
my favorite hammers are probably my
favorite thing though. Um, if there's,
if I just had to pick one thing and
say this is what you need to do. Um,
I mean the dynamic strength that builds
is, is insane. The explosiveness,
the core strength, the shoulder
strength, that grip strength.
Did you start doing this? Um, four or five
years ago, because I remember, you know,
back in the day George Foreman used to
chop wood and I remember thinking like,
why aren't you, yeah, I was
like, why are they chopping wood?
Like Wah Marianna was legendary for
doing it or not letting her hear him.
He's legendary for other
things. He did a lot. Yeah.
So we actually built a 45 and a 50 pound
hammer to which became a really good
doorstopper but heavy. Yeah. So
we've maxed out, we stopped at 35,
but if anybody ever would want one, we can
still blows the Francis. I know, right?
I like to see him do it. Yeah. I mean, if
you just think about the way, you know,
the, the, the hammer
swings and everything,
I mean there's a lot of
different ways you can do it.
There's a lot of different exercises you
can do with them. I mean they're just,
I think they're most amazing
tool there is for framing.
May I've never used one really even
like a Home Depot Sledge Hammer? Nope.
Never swung them. No. I mean it'll
build your endurance up right away. Um,
well one thing that I love about the
endurance part of it is you'll sit there
and swing it and like
your body's going to like,
when your body gets so tired,
as long as you have decent techniques,
your body will get so tired. You
can still keep going though. Like,
cause it's a lot of momentum,
you know what I mean?
But you can keep going with the
momentum no matter how tired you are.
Now you sent me some,
so I'll start doing it here.
And what size tire should I get? A
tractor tire? Yeah, if we get, yeah,
just tractor tire. What do you get one of
those? Um, I know I just go to the, uh,
you could use a regular tire whenever,
like I go to like the uh,
you can get for free.
He usually they'll give them to you
because they just burn them. Okay.
You know what I have to like dispose
them like a tire shop. Tire shop. Yeah.
Junk tire shop. Yeah. I'll go a tire shop.
Yeah. Give me a big ass tire bitch. Yeah,
that's what I did. I mean sometimes like
they might give you like a regular um,
uh, tire. Also. You just bolt it
together, you know, drill a hole in bolt,
two of them together and you got it.
You do that way too.
But is that what you did?
You put stack I,
that's what I'm [inaudible] I've had
to do that before where the tire shop
wouldn't,
didn't have a big tractor tire and
I'd just get sick of looking for one.
Sometimes it hard to find
like farmers will have them,
I don't know about California. They could
be completely different out here. So,
you know,
I mean you can buy like off rogue or
whatever they have the things that you hit
with the hammers really broken.
So like other than a tire? Yeah,
they have an actual, so like if you've
ever seen the crossfit games, I,
they do the, the game, uh, I
dunno. Game, whatever it is.
It crossfit competition thing. That's
like a big piece of rubber. And then,
and they have to move it from one side
to the other, like 10 yards or something.
They have to hit with the hammer,
but their hammer.
So it's like rogue makes
a ham. Oh, there it is.
So it's like a big Hong Kong rubber.
Yeah. Yeah. Those are great. And so like,
rug makes a hammer, right? That's
adjustable weight too. But there's,
you unbolt it and poor Bibi's into
it. Oh my, this ridiculous. Right?
Like who's,
who's actually going to do that?
And they have fucking Bibi's everywhere,
all this kind of shit. So that's why,
you know, I was like, uh, you know,
I go to west side, I have a fucking,
Dave Hoff is there 300. Uh, you know,
those strongest man history. I'm like,
if he's going to swing a hammer, it's
not going to be fucking 16 pound hammer.
He'll do that with is
one handed. So, you know,
so I wanted to build something
that anybody could use.
And then the wheelbarrow,
you know, we had to put
where it can hold. I,
I've had over a thousand pounds on
it at west side. Jesus, you know,
I can't lift a thousand pounds on it,
but um,
we'll put over a thousand pounds on there.
We have different handles.
So that's what I changed.
So when Louise was just one handled I,
so we have d handles, right?
So you can grip it like this,
do like a clean pressed.
And he's like, uh, um, we have, um,
like turn into like a prowler
said it's got handles coming up,
things like that and just do laps with
it. You just do laps. I mean, like I said,
you use like a prowler. You can do
cleans a overhead presses. I mean,
there's a million different things you
can do with it. So when you're slamming,
when you do, when the hammer
workout and you're slamming a tire,
like where are you feeling it most in
your back, your legs, you know? Uh, yeah,
usually not the leg so
much. Um, you know, the,
that's more just you just kind
of stabilizing with your legs.
But a lot of times it depends
on your weakness too, right?
Some people feel it more
than the shoulders. Um,
I usually feel it more in
my grip, you know, because,
but there's a few different
ways you can do it too.
So like if I want to
feel it more in my grip,
I'll do a slam where I try to stop
it. Oh, right. So, you know, very,
at the very end,
as soon as it hits,
because the tire is going to bounce
it back and I'll try to stop it. Um,
but a lot of times I feel it
more than the core. Right. Um,
and then sometimes I do like, you
know, over the head, like this, boom,
bring it down that way it felt
way more in the core. Yeah.
We're trying to swing it sideways. Yeah.
I'm not quite as fun on that. I just,
uh, it gets a little dangerous and I
think he kind of, which I, I personally,
I would do it.
Like,
I wouldn't recommend other people do it
unless they've been swinging hammers for
awhile. I remember, um, um,
I've just seen people do stupid things.
Now.
What are the kind of Shit do you do for
strength and conditioning? You name it,
I suppose to say, you know, I mean we
followed the west side conjugate system,
so it's really, you know, things
change all the time. Um, I mean,
you know, it depends on if it's general
specific. So I always add in a third one,
there's, you know, there's Gpp,
general physical preparation,
there's SPP which has
specific physical preparation.
And then I add in personally,
my own was just a RSPP,
which is what I call like the hammers.
Like the wheel Barrow would be
more the war, I would call it.
The war wagon is more a general, right.
So it's just gonna build general strength,
you know, he's going to bring your
endurance up, your max capacity up,
things like that. The, uh, you know,
getting on the mats and you know,
doing 20 double legs, that's SPP
like very specific, right. Um,
the something like a hammer or maybe
a lot of a band type stuff. Uh,
like maybe shooting double legs
with the band on or something.
And I call that RSVP, which is
replicated specific physical preparation.
Some, you know, I could break down all
three of these and just go on forever.
I mean with,
when you're in the GPP,
you're going to get him like
build up your Max capacity,
you're going to build up your strength,
you want to build up your bone density,
your ligament strength, your
tendon strength. You have,
of course, I, any weaknesses?
Uh, I'm big on the neck, back
and posterior chain, right? The,
they say the fronts for show
the backs for go. So who are,
who have used the iron neck. Oh yeah. Yup.
We use it all the time. I love that. Fun.
Yeah. I love that thing. Nothing
amazing. Genius invention. I know, right?
I think it's really uncomfortable, but
yeah, I got one of those out here. Yeah.
I say I like it. I don't like, I
want it at home too. To be honest.
I think clinching does more than
anything else, man. For, for neck.
Like my neck just gets more sore doing
that than anything else. Oh sure. Yeah.
Yeah. So that's uh,
using, uh, my, my friends,
uh, at west side they do a
lot where they'll put a band
on the war wagon and then
carry it at the same time. Oh Wow.
It's pulling the neck while you're,
and you have to walk. So psych of
very dynamic workout at the same time.
So your grips given out your trap,
start giving out what kind of harness
or they're putting on their head.
Just like a, you know the leathers.
Yeah. Right, right. Yeah. And uh,
you know,
just to with the chain and then band
and say you're having to hold this while
you're walking.
It makes it much more dynamic.
So I liked that they come up
with some crazy shit there. Yeah.
Well that's where I'll go to
the iron neck, Instagram page.
They do a lot of crazy shit with the
iron neck on like a lot of medicine ball
shit, a lot of slams.
While you're, you know,
you're pulled back so you're on the
full full, uh, resistance with the band.
You're moving your head and you're
slamming the ball, the right.
And the last things on those
lines to check that out.
I've never tried out their Instagram
[inaudible] Instagram personally,
but why do you do that man?
For one Instagram to me is the
most mindless thing in the world.
Perhaps looking at pictures,
pictures and,
and half the time you don't even read the,
uh,
breakdown the captions.
Yeah. Um, so to me it's,
it's really social media is
first off is pretty dumbed down,
like read a fucking book,
right?
And then now you have something
that is not even a, you know,
been riding like it was just
pictures, like, you know, like the,
the people that are like, no, it
was a book. Every pictures, well,
I'm not going to read it or something,
you know. So to me, and I also,
I'm a big believer that a,
um,
and you know what goes in your brain
and your mind, what you let in,
it needs to be very controlled.
You need to be very specific and
careful about what you let in.
And you never know what you're
going to come across on there.
So it can be something toxic
that can be bad, right.
Especially if you're reading
comments. Right? Absolutely.
Yeah. It gets way worse.
Which, and you know, I used
it, uh, I mean I'm on there a
lot, but you know, I use it.
Uh, I like to, um, I remember back in
the day when I was, uh, coming up and,
um, you know, I would dream
of talking to a UFC fighter.
So I use it to interact with my fans,
right.
Cause I want to give some
kids that experience.
I think it's a very powerful
tool for that. Oh yeah. That's,
that's a powerful thing for a
young guy coming up, you know,
to be able to talk to Matt Brown and
you actually respond to them and say,
good luck. You're like,
Holy Shit. Yeah. I mean,
I probably do it maybe even more
than I should. Like I mean I,
I answered like complete
question sometimes. You
know, like people ask me the,
the wildest questions, you
know, and um, I like, I'll,
I'll give him complete responses,
but,
and I find that 90% of the time they're
like, oh cool man, glad you responded.
And then they forget about it most
likely. Right. And then, but you know,
if I can touch just a few people,
men, I mean that's really what the,
the whole thing's about. Do you have a
youtube channel? No, but I probably will.
That's maybe a good move for you
because you've got so much information.
Your head like just talking
to you before the podcast,
you're rattling off these different
training modalities and different recovery
methods and techniques and shit like that.
I was like,
my Brown's got a lot of information
in his head. Yeah. I'm not dumb.
I might be a savage, but
I mean, getting help,
people think those things are mutually
exclusive. Absolutely. You know,
like if you're, if you're a savage,
you've got gotta be stupid. Absolutely.
And my thing is my savage newness,
I approach all things with that
savage intent. Right? So when I,
like if I'm into a book,
like I'm reading a bad ass book right now.
And what is antifragile what does that,
um,
I'm trying to remember the name of the
author, but it's on my kindle. And, uh,
so if you think of the,
the, there's no term,
there's no definition of
fragility are antifragile right.
So he came up with this term,
he wrote the book,
the Black Swan also and
Nassim Nicholas. Yeah. Oh,
I've heard of that guy. He has a very
interesting way of writing. And uh,
so he really digs deep into this
concept of antifragility where, um,
it's not necessarily
robustness or things like is
God, I hate it because I try to
reexplain it cause I butcher shit.
I feel like I don't give it
justice, but, um, you know,
I'm only like halfway through the book,
but like I said, I've really attacked it,
like with that savage sort of a
mindset. Right. But, um, it's a very,
very long book. Well, it's basically,
you know, like, like our, um, you know,
he makes the case that a
fragility is, you know, good.
Right.
And it creates antifragility he makes
the case a antifragility is good.
Right. And not necessarily, like I say,
I feel like I'm just butchering it, man.
Just read the book fucking, but when he
says about, when you're saying fragility,
do you mean for agility in terms
of your mindset? In terms of just,
it turns out he's an economic
guy, so he's really, I think he,
I think what he's getting at get them
only half, like halfway through the book.
But I think really what he's getting at
is more economic and political is kind
of his a longterm thing. But he uses
a lot of examples. So it basically,
it what I've gathered so far,
it's basically like how stress
induces a stress response, which,
which induces strength and which is
the closest thing I would say is to
antifragility a strength.
Right.
And how anti fragility would
make the world a better place,
more or less and towards as a response
to stress, let's look training.
Exactly. Yeah. And, I mean, he even
uses that example, you know, how,
how we tear muscles down to build them
up. That's our entire purpose. Yeah.
So that's, um, again, I'm only
halfway through it, man. I,
I don't want to butcher it,
so fucking great book. But like I
said, I, I mean it's a long, long,
very long book and it's sort of,
uh,
he kind of digs into all these
different subjects on it,
even though it's really like he could
probably sum it up in about a quarter of
the book, but, you know, I would just say
to you, I just attack it like that, man.
I just, you know, um, like prince to super
training you, you know this book, right?
I've heard of it. I haven't read
it though. Well, it's the most,
probably the most difficult to read
book I've ever read and I've read it
probably four or five times now. What's so
difficult about it? Um, it's just ultra,
ultra scientific and it's
written by Mel siff and, um,
Burger Shamsky who was the
inventor of plyometrics. So the,
the fountain plyometrics and the Russians
and I'm Mel Siff is a biomechanical
engineer and the two of them
came together. And you know,
there's super training is basically
like the Bible of, um, of string,
the conditioning books
altogether, right? It's,
it's the original straight
that conditioning. But, um,
I mean there's also like science
and practice of strength training.
There's a science of sports training.
There's a lot of really good books,
but super training is like that,
just the pioneer, the premier book.
And it's all very, very scientific.
And a lot of the times, man,
I'll have to read the same paragraph
like four times, you know? And I've,
I've read the book like four times then,
and I still,
I'm going through the paragraph like, what
the fuck man, what is he talking about?
The son of a bitch. So anyway, so like
the, you know, the point, he's like,
I just attack it like that, you know?
And um, um, I think there's other things.
I think a lot of people, um, again, like
it's all about inspiring others, right?
And I think a lot of people
could learn a lot from that.
And that's what I tried doing my fights.
I try to inspire people.
I want my kids to be that way.
I Wa I wa I think it could bring
the world up that way, man.
People find something they want and
it's actually like a goddamn salad.
Well, when people see someone
that does really go for it,
it doesn't inspire them to go for it too.
They see the excitement in it and they
see the response that other people have
to that excitement.
And it just,
it just makes them want to up
their own life performance and,
and a lot of various ways, you
know, not just a in fighting,
but they might want to
up their performance from
watching you fight in whatever
the fuck they're doing.
And that's, to me, that means
more than anything else.
That's what a lot of people talk about,
the meaning of life.
I gotta think I gotta figure it out.
I mean,
I think the meaning of life is to give.
I think that's, if you look in in nature,
I know you're a big nature buff.
I mean that's what everything exists
in nature to do. That's what a,
that's what a tree grows fruit to
give more fruit, right? That there's,
this is the,
a natural process of the world and humans,
the human animal has become, uh,
to analytical to figure that out.
Right?
We think the meaning of life is all
these other things because we think about
other things, but really our,
our entire purpose is to give,
hmm.
I think there's a lot of purposes in life,
but I think that is one of them for sure.
I think giving is definitely,
it gives you a sense of meaning.
And when you help other people,
you feel better.
You know,
that's one thing that I think
people are missing out on.
They think that it should be all about
themselves and I'm just about succeeding
and getting by on my own.
Well, even what you
just said, uh, you know,
gives you a sense of meaning
or makes you feel better. Yeah.
So you bought it back to yourself.
Right. Right. And that's,
that's what I had to think as human
nature and that's easy. But, um,
I tried to get past that where,
where it's not about me,
it's not about how I feel about
it. So it's about just giving, um,
um, completely selfless. That's
a great way to look at it.
The way I described it that way though,
is to enlightened people to
this idea that I think Peter,
not nonlying people,
but I just express my own perspective
that I think people spend too much time
thinking about what benefits them and
that they don't recognize that the more
you benefit other people,
that is really what benefits,
not just those other people,
but you as well.
And that they think of like
helping people. Like, yeah,
it'd be good to help people,
but that's going to fuck me up because
then I'm going to spend less time on my
own self.
But it's not really the case.
You actually enhance your own
experience in life by hello
being other people, as we were talking
about before the podcast has, right.
The abundance mentality. And that is,
uh, specifically the abundance mentality.
Yeah, no, I'm,
I'm a gigantic believer in generosity
and abundance mentality and I'm,
I,
I'm a fucking ferocious
opponent of famine thinking.
I think that famine mentality, if fucks
people up so hard, you get closed up,
you get, you know, Pr, ultra
protective, you get ultra.
I just think that's a terrible way to
live your life and you're living your life
with fear.
The hard part is implementing it, right?
Like I can see her talk about it all day.
Like I don't give enough to, you know
what I mean? I don't give enough away.
That's for sure.
I've thought about,
sometimes I think about the crazy
shit sometimes and I was like,
I think the ultimate like coolest
thing in life. So I have to have money.
He's like for my kids,
unfortunately. Right. Not
Unfortunate but necessity. Yeah.
Necessity.
That's what the money is about.
I feel like if I didn't have kids I would
just give literally every dime away,
start from bottom and see how many times.
Cause you know, so there's like certain
qualities in people that they are
going to succeed no matter what. Right.
And I want to see like if I
have those qualities right.
So I want to give everything away.
Start that right now. You definitely do.
Listen man,
you can do whatever the fuck
you want in this life. But I feel
like a guy like you in particular,
especially right now when you're on this,
uh,
this fighting journey
and you're still on it,
I think what you give the most is through
the best possible performance that you
give.
And when you have these wild,
crazy performances like
the Diego Sanchez fight,
that shit inspires the fuck out of people.
I mean,
how many people watched that fight and,
and just wanted to go run mountains
and just get crazy. It's just
man, as, as cool you bring
that up. Cause I mean,
I never even thought of it that way.
Like I always see it again,
I always bring it back to myself and I
see it as an expression of my own art.
You're upon myself for the year,
not just an athlete.
You're not just a fighter,
but you're also a public performer
and an inspirational figure.
And when you are doing your best,
that gives a lot to people. I mean,
how many people have watched
great athletic performances
and it's given them the
fuel and the inspiration and do
great things in their own life.
That SQL, he said, yeah cause a man,
I might inspire me to fight
it a little longer. You know,
you weren't ready to
retire after Diego fight.
That was supposed to be your swan song.
What was it just too sweet? No, no, no,
it wasn't, it had nothing do with the
performance actually, uh, this year.
So I think when we started the podcast,
I was talking about the why in
the house a little bit. Right.
And this is where I think I got
a little confused was I, I think,
um, I mean for one, I, I was,
I was questioning a lot of things that
got knocked out by cowboy viciously.
I'm the worst. Not, I've never been
knocked out of my life. I mean,
and it wasn't too long after I just
got dropped hard by Ellenberger,
which was the first time my life had ever
been dropped in sparring or anything.
I never been dropped. Um, so I started
just kind of questioning, you know,
what, uh, what am I doing? Okay, well how,
and the first thing I went to was how
do I not make that happen again? Um,
so that gets very exhausting when
you just like how, how, how, right.
And I think through the Diego
camp, cause I, you know,
I announced her retirement long,
you know, very early in the camp,
like 12 weeks out or something like
that through the camp at men. Uh,
everything went so well. I, I, I
focused more on my own mind and,
and a lot of these things we're
talking about. And I started, uh,
getting back into the y and I started,
uh,
bringing a lot more clarity
to that side of things.
Now I know why I'm doing what I'm doing.
I feel much more comfortable and now
it doesn't matter on the performance
anymore. Now it's about truly going out
there and performing the best that I can.
And then the second part of the
whole thing is a, um, you know,
I was very scared of retirement.
I was very,
very nervous to be thinking like,
what am I going to do? You know,
like how am I gonna feed my
kids? And, um, fortunately, um,
you know, I, I was able to,
I realized once I announced it
and then after the fight, I mean,
it just a plethora of, uh, of, of,
of opportunities and a Mussel farms
probably been my best opportunity.
And that's why, um, you know, I,
I bring them up a lot, you know,
because they've helped me so much and,
and I think we're going to do amazing
things there, whether I retire or not.
And I think it's going to be
a big, beautiful thing. Um,
what do you do for them specifically?
Um, so I'm kind of tasked with, uh,
building the fight team and bringing,
um,
the athletes and, and communicating
with athletes and, um,
you know, just making it
a solid program there. Um,
whether I'm the coach or not, it
doesn't even matter. But, you know,
I want to make a, a great program
and make sure that, you know,
the facilities being used properly and
bring in different athletes. And, um,
that'd be kind of the first step.
And then beyond that, I mean,
the opportunities are endless. I can
do a lot of different things with it.
So what was the thought process that was
it immediately after the Diego Sanchez
fight? Cause I talked to
you in Denver, um, when,
when you came to my show at the Belko,
I called you up,
we were talking and you said, I'm, I
really sure I'm done. And I was like,
what's going on? That, so I don't
remember the exact date of that,
but that was probably, you
know, um, you know, I said
the retirement and then again,
like the camp just started going amazing.
And again, the why came back, man.
Like I knew why I was
doing what I was doing.
Like I was enjoying my time at the
gym again. Aren't you enjoying it?
Um, I, there's been a lot of times, I
mean, what do you think you, you know,
my man,
I've been around and I've had a lot
of different coaches and that's my,
that's my biggest,
if I had a regret in my career and said
I wasn't as loyal to one sort of system
as I should've been, I, and
I have a term for it now,
I call it the Unicorn Fallacy where
you're constantly chasing the Unicorn that
doesn't exist. Right? Or some people,
I've heard other people call it like
the greener grass syndrome, you know,
the grass isn't always greener on the
other side. Right. Um, and that would,
if I had a complaint about myself
or if you want to call it a regret,
like that's my problem. I'm
always like, dude, I just,
I just need to go over
here and I'll get better.
Cause I'm always searching that how
right. Not Forgot the Y. So, um,
you know, so again, you know, uh, this is,
I think a lot of fighters probably also
go through this where, where, I mean,
it's hard, but we do, and there's
a lot of pressure on her shoulders.
There's a lot of, um, um,
especially with a family,
I've got three kids, you
know, and it's like, I mean,
I got knocked out in front of my three
kids, like they were at the fight,
you know what I mean? Like I
had a, uh, I think they were,
I don't even remember because I was
fucking knocked out, you know, like,
like I don't remember anything until I
was waking up with the hospital, you know,
and Dwayne to sitting there, you know what
I mean? So like, I mean, looking back,
like I don't even remember
all this stuff. And, uh,
it's funny because I've seen videos like,
you know,
raising cowboys and I was like, I don't
even remember seeing that. Like, uh,
somebody told me that,
you know,
we were talking backstage and I seen a
video I should say, of is talking about,
I said, I don't remember none. Right.
So things like that. Uh, you know,
it makes you start questioning like,
dude, it's like, cause this shit worth it,
you know? I mean, um, you know, and
just a lot of internal struggles.
Right. Um, and again, you know, the,
the camp I had with Diego and everything,
just all the pieces fell into
place and it was like, dude,
if I can do this every time,
like I could do this for a long time
and I could smash a lot of people.
So that's where you're at right now.
Yeah. So you were reinvigorated.
Reinvigorated. That's
interesting. So this long career,
so many great fights and you still,
you still look fine.
I think I'm fucking hungry
than ever was man. I was like,
because of like a lot of stuff we're
talking about today is just wasn't clear.
You know what I mean? It was just
a, a scatterbrain like again,
it was all about the how.
I think I was like a kind of hyper focused
on that. Like how do I get stronger?
How do I get faster?
How do I throw a better punch?
How do I analyze this guy? And
how do I beat him? And you know,
it was just constant out and
then you forget like, why
are you doing this anyway,
you know, some, and then, I
mean, like I said, it's just a,
it's not an easy sport anyway.
I mean, this is probably
the hardest sport existed.
I don't think there's anything
harder. Yeah. I would,
I can't imagine what's harder other than
the actual war. Yeah, right. I mean,
maybe police officer, fireman, actual
war, uh, fucking trauma surgeon.
Even then, I mean, I mean,
it's harder in different ways.
Harder in different ways. Yeah. Yeah.
It's one of the most pressure filled
athletic opportunities that a person can
ever be involved in. And now, sorry, go
ahead. Let's just say, you know, the,
the hard thing is, uh, this is all I've
done. I've, I've, I got, I'm all in,
you know, from the beginning
I never gave myself an out.
And I think that's important to do. Also.
Um, a lot of the guys that have outs,
I mean I watch shark tank all the time
and you see, you know, these guys,
if they have an out then the, you know,
Kevin O'leary or whatever it is. I like,
you know,
fuck you.
I'm not rich kids don't grow up to be
world championship fighters except for Bj
Penn. Yeah, he's just a fucking animal.
But he grew up in Hawaii.
Hawaii. Is it different place?
Like you're stuck on an island with a
bunch of motherfuckers want to kick your
ass like it's do or die and why he is
a under appreciated place for tough
motherfuckers. You know, I'll have
to go there. My wife once again,
never been there once I lived there,
I was in like Waikiki the whole time
that I live on the big island. Yeah.
Fuck yeah. I could live there.
Yeah, you would get an island.
We'll call it island sick. Nope.
If I did, I get on a plane.
It's people who are awesome there, man.
It's just a different, more relaxed, more.
Um, I don't know. They're just more chill.
They say Costa Rica is a place to go to.
Costa Rica is pretty bad ass. I say
it's a best place to retire. Yeah,
that's what I've heard.
Cause it's like $1,000 a month.
He can live well or something. Yeah.
Mel gives us, got a fat spread there.
He's telling me he's got like
500 acres down there. Nice.
That was a cool podcast with Mel
Gibson. He's an interesting cat. Huh?
Here's my impression of Mel Gibson.
He just can't look in the fucking bed.
He was,
he just kept clicking the pen and I
didn't want to say anything. It was like,
what do I say? Stop clicking the
pen, man. I wanted to hear like,
I kinda want to hear you
interview him a little bit.
It was like all the stem cell guy.
Well he wanted to come on
and talk about stem cells.
That's really what he wanted to talk
about. And so I honored that. I said,
all right man. You know, that's
what you want to talk about.
You think he's your biggest
guests that you've ever had? Uh,
it was pretty fucking famous. James
Hetfield. He's pretty fucking famous too.
I mean, I dunno, they're up
there. Who else? Alex Jones.
He's the biggest valid stubbles downloads.
Alex beat everybody but didn't really
fuck load. Yeah man, it was interesting.
So here's my theory on Alex Jones.
Just if you want to go there,
I love going there. So I think
he's a government plot. He's not,
I tell you that for sure. I've known
him forever. I've known Alex since 1998.
He's not, but he couldn't because
she would tell everybody he's not.
I've hung out with that guy,
get high with him,
drunk with him and he's a fun dude.
He is a guy who started out, uh,
as a guy who was a against the president.
He was against George W. Bush,
w Bush. I don't even think he
was probably was running for president
at the time. Right. Where was he?
When was it? When did Bush become
no, Clinton was president. Yeah,
Clinton was president.
George W was the governor of Texas and
he was getting arrested for protesting
against them,
protesting against the global elitists
and all these different things.
He didn't really become a supporter
of any form of government until Trump.
I mean,
Trump is like the first guy and he may
or may not be getting played by Trump
where Trump's his buddy. And I
mean Trump is a, he's a slick guy.
In terms of how he, uh, cultivates
influence. Is it an anomaly? For sure.
He's, he's an interesting character
and a lot of ways. I mean,
if it wasn't shut down my theory to
a completed, they let me say, hey,
it's just a theory. I'm not,
propagate it as the factory then.
I've always thought the Alice Jones was,
was built by the government to make
conspiracy theories look like loons he
didn't use to make them look like
loons. He, no, no, he was much more,
uh, I started with nine
11 though, right? No,
no way before now and let,
I mean that with Waco,
but that's when he came to prominence.
Right.
That could cause he was the first to, to
calm down even before then. Man. You know,
I mean, nobody cared about it
before was an am radio before then,
but he's been around forever.
I mean, like I said, I met him.
I met him in 98 so it was
several years before 2001 and a,
he was doing the same shit back then. I
mean, he's always been around doing that.
He's, he's right about a lot of shit
and that's what's so confusing, right?
Like he is absolutely right about what
they're called agent provocateurs,
where the government will send in
people if they have a peaceful protest.
It's very inconvenient for them.
Like the WTO,
he did this whole video about how the
WTO was that in Vancouver or Seattle,
where was the WTO? I forget
where it was. Why don't want,
it was somewhere in the Pacific northwest.
I'm confused,
but I'm not confused about the story.
So what happened was they had these
peaceful protests against the World Trade
Organization and uh,
it was very inconvenient because all
these world leaders were coming to this,
this area for this meeting.
And they sent in government agents that
were dressed with blast black ski masks
and a government issue,
boots.
And these people started smashing
windows and lighting things on fire.
They turned into a violent protest,
which enabled the police to close
in and shut down the protest.
You'd WTO protests. Where did say Alex
Jones police state to the takeover.
Seattle. Yeah, we'll
Seattle. Okay. So they said,
but this is a real tactic that
governments and intelligence agencies use.
They have a peaceful protest and then
they have these people like these guys
dressed in black ski masks,
they start tipping over newspapers.
Like it doesn't even make any sense.
Like, why are they doing this?
There are government agents.
Meanwhile the,
these guys have government issued boots.
No, it further. So these guys all, um,
they all got together at the end and they
were cordoned off into a building and
then there were ultimately released.
They were never charged.
They were never arrested.
I mean,
the whole thing is incredibly
fascinating and, uh,
some of them have been
identified as government agents
and Alex and get way more
into detail about it. That's why I'm,
you know, I'm not a conspiracy theorist,
so to speak.
Um,
but the one thing I always say is I
don't put anything past our governments.
There's absolutely been conspiracies
that are real. For sure, for sure.
Whether it's the Gulf of Tonkin incident,
whether it's operation Northwoods,
there's a bin,
and there's,
I'm sure there's been a bunch
that we don't know about.
I believe that the government
assassin or somebody assassinated JFK.
I don't think it was Lee Harvey Oswald
acted alone. I think it's very possible.
Lee Harvey Oswald was a part of it.
But I know too much about bullets to think
that that fucking bullet went through
two people and wound up on Connolly's
Gurney in the hospital looking pristine,
cut the shit. That's all. I don't
think that's real at all. Nice. Nice.
I've seen the Zapruder film. I, I've,
I've read several books on the story.
I just,
I think it's very convenient to lump
all that into one guy with one bullet.
I think it's horse shit.
And I think they probably killed him.
See how he's always looking into a
little bit, you know, and then, um, my,
you know, uh, the government
probably did it. Shit, whatever.
They probably give a shit.
They probably did a lot of shit that we
don't know about that we're not aware of
it.
This is how governments work.
They've always worked like desert zone
intelligence agencies work. The uh,
smart criminals go to politics that
dumb criminals go to jail, right?
There's a lot of that. Honestly,
a lot of that. How many or,
or you know,
the most criminally saying people in
this world are attracted to politics?
I think what's going to fix human beings,
and this is a radical idea,
but I really think the same thing that's
going to fix human beings is what is in
a lot of ways,
disrupting the standards of our culture
right now and with the Internet.
I think technology is going to fix human
beings because I think what technology
is going to do is eventually there's
going to be a way to absolutely detect
whether or not someone's telling
the truth. I think it's inevitable.
I think as we dug up,
a lot of people's got to fuck up a lot
of people's lives and it's going to Hanse
most of our lives,
and I think people like you and
people like me who tell the truth,
it's going to be very good for
you because I think there's,
I think when you lie, it doesn't just
fuck up the person that you're lying to.
I think it fucks you up. I think it
fucks up discourse. It fucks up culture.
I think it fucks up human beings. It
fucks up our communities. It's just,
it's a,
it's an anomaly.
It's a thing that people have been able
to figure out how to do when you've been
able to say things that aren't accurate,
to convince someone of a reality
that doesn't exist. I guess where,
where I think it gets hard though is the
politic politician specifically are so
good at, not really lying, but like crow,
you know they're right on that gray area
where they don't know really lying to
you, but they're not. That's, but
that's also because you can lie.
So you'll be like a guy like Trump
who's been busted lying a million times.
It's still is a notch probably
every president for sure. Dot.
I don't think he does. I don't think
he's unique in that and that's,
well he's unique in his propensity for
it. I mean he loves it. He's a good,
I mean he had been lying forever,
but I think that without a doubt there
was going to be a time in the future,
whether it's in our lifetimes or after
where they develop technology that's
going to absolutely allow you to detect
whether or not someone's telling the
truth. I sent tense. Yeah,
I think it's going to be the future and
I think when that happens people are
just not going to accept all this shit
that we've accepted for so many years.
It could be an APP on the phone.
I think it's probably going to be
something that you wear on your body.
I think we're real close to that.
I think we're real close to embedded
chips that you wear on your body.
And I think those chips are probably
going to interface wirelessly and you're
just going to be able to read thoughts
and ideas that come from people that are
going to come and probably a new language.
I think we're going to,
to be able to develop a universal
language. I don't have a lot of,
a lot of religious people say it's
a mark of the beast. Right? Oh,
that's like a birthmark or some shit.
Like what,
what are the religious people think?
Like a chip and it's what your body
was raised in an ultra religious thing
environment, right. My mom
was, it was extremely religious
and I talked in tongues.
They probably thought they did or
said no, no, they uh, you know,
they're very fundamental.
Um, you know, my,
my brother could go away deeper
into what they were about.
I never even paid attention,
but,
but I remember them talking about like
the mark of the beast in, they're like,
it's going to be something
implanted in you.
And if you take it then
you're going to hell.
And if you don't take it
or something like that.
And maybe with just planning ahead,
they want to keep lying.
We've got to keep planning, we've got to
plan ahead for these. Chips are clever.
Certainly lying to me, but I think
there's going to be a language,
a universal language that they
figured out how to teach the children.
I'd be fast starting with children because
children learn languages very easily
and if they develop a universal language
that is somehow or another either
translated through computers cause you
know they have a thing now these Google
ear buds that you use
with a pixel two phones.
So if you were talking to me in Spanish,
I would hear the translation of
what you said in English in my ears.
That's fucking amazing.
When I saw that, I was like,
how has nobody noticing
that this is step one.
This is step one of a universal language.
The translation to English is fascinating,
but I think ultimately we're going to
be able to figure out how to communicate
with everybody with a new language.
And this, this, this is not hard.
Do,
I mean it's
obviously not easy, but it's not
impossible to develop a new language,
like a universal language that's
accepted by everybody. Yeah.
I used a, uh, I have a Brazilian
friend that comes up, uh,
to my house sometimes and we put the
Google translate thing just right in
between us and you can talk in,
it detects which language and it
says it. Isn't that crazy? Yeah.
That's crazy. So he knows which like you
don't know who's talking without even,
you don't have ear phones or nothing. All
to say it out loud. Yeah. That's amazing.
I mean it's not a hundred percent
accurate and sometimes you have to swipe,
I think this is one step and then I think
the next step is going to be some sort
of a way to detect whether
or not people are lying.
And then another step is going to
be more enhanced communication.
And then another step after that is going
to be some sort of telekinetic or some
sort of, uh, communication without
verbalizing, without words.
Fuck all that's comment. I'll
just be out in the woods. Yeah.
Y'All do your thing.
I'm going to hang out out here.
It might be the best way to live. I
mean that's how I want to live. I mean,
my wife is a more of
a city person sort of.
I mean it's got to get a weekend spot and
evergreen or something. Dude, I want to,
yeah, I supposed to do a thing with, uh,
what's his name? Um, uh, Denver work.
Oh yeah, the navy seal. He's
doing like campfire thing.
They're supposed to have
a nice chat with him.
Yesterday we were texting each other
at the campfire there. No, he's about,
he's going to come on and do the
podcast whenever he's in town,
which is trying to figure out
a time. Yeah, I was texting
with him. Oh, a Twitter.
He's doing, I guess it's called
like a campfire sessions.
So you go out there and hang out with
this campfire and he'd just tell stories.
Yeah. He's a fascinating guy. He's been
on my friend Steve's television show,
a meat eater. Okay. He's been on that.
Yeah. He's a fascinating, intense guy.
Nice. Yeah. Yeah. I wanted to
bring my kids, but he's, he,
he's a great guy. I'm sure he could
bring your kids, but I think, uh,
anytime you could get a place we get away,
we can get to nature to see the real
stars at night and have a campfire.
It's just reinvigorating.
It's just great for you and man.
Did you see the eclipse?
Did you know you didn't do
look a little bit my backyard,
but I almost burned my eyes.
I don't have the right goggles.
I tried to put two sunglasses on
the, I was like, that don't work.
That was like the probably the
deepest nature. Well my wife,
her family is up in Vermont, so we get
us a pretty deep nature up there. But,
but we were up in this
place in Wyoming where,
I mean there was a million people there
that weekend, but I don't think, you know,
there's probably not a hundred
people within a hundred
miles. Right, right, right,
right. And a man, that was the first
time I ever looked up in the sky.
Cause see the Milky Way though?
Oh, you know what you gotta do go.
If you go to Hawaii,
you got a planet for when there's no
moon and go to the Keck observatory.
There's the Keck observatory
on the big island. Fuck man.
Because the big island is designed the
lighting system. Yeah, it's darker,
but they have the lighting system designed
in the big island to have diffused on
the street lamps.
With that means is that the light
doesn't disperse it to the sky.
And so when you go up to the Keck
observatory, man, you see everything.
It blew me away. I saw it.
Yeah. That's what it looks like.
Like legitimately what it looks like.
Like you go up there and you look up,
you're like Ho Lee shit
because it's so high.
I think it's 13,000 feet above sea
level. Oh Wow. You go up there and um,
they had mountains at big up. Oh
yeah, they do. And on the big island,
the big island has like a different world.
They have a bunch of different ecosystems
up there. They have a rain forums,
they have a desert, they have mountain
ranges, they have lava. But it's,
it changed my life and I'm
not bullshitting. It's like
a psychedelic experience.
When I went up there and saw the stars
like that, I was like, oh, I didn't even,
I don't even,
I mean,
if there's something to make you
feel like a tiny fucking Spec,
you feel like you're on a space ship,
you feel like you're on a spaceship
flying through the universe.
That's how it felt when I was in Wyoming.
It just you that eclipse
obviously blew me away too.
You don't realize how many stars are up
there and how much our street lights are
fucking us over because it's changing
the way you view the cosmos itself.
It's changing your relationship that you
have with infinity, with the universe.
I mean it's changing it because we,
it's Dalling our perceptions by limiting
all of this spectacular light in these
stars that we, the meal, the
Milky Way, like this whole thing.
There's a reason why it
gives you this sense of awe.
Like it's a perspective enhancer.
It gives you this view of something
that's impossibly beautiful and also
impossibly huge and it just puts it
all in perspective. I think I made it.
That's why people are so cocky and cities,
they're just,
they're missing that they're
missing this re this reality check.
And the weird part is I that's small shit.
Like this is actually the milky way
is like a small galaxy, right? Yeah.
It's nothing.
It's one of hundreds of billions
of galaxies in the known universe.
And there's not aliens.
Well, I was talking to me,
I did Neil degrasse Tyson's TV show a
couple of days ago and he was telling me
that it's the most likely scenario is
that we live in multiverses and that our
universe,
which is impossibly large,
is one of an infinite number of
universes that are all in these bubbles.
Can you, uh, explain? Nope.
He said it to me and I was
like, wait, what is this?
It looks like googled it and this is
the images that pop up. He kinda got,
just trust him on that one. Right? Well
whenever he says something like Kinda Guy,
you like, you're the expert. But
anytime I talk to astrophysicists,
I just try to probe as much as possible
and just trust them that you can't argue
with them about it.
But the idea is that like how we have
a planet and the planet part of a solar
system and the solar system is a part
of a galaxy and the galaxy is a part of
the universe. The universe is a part of
a multiverse and then it's just as is.
There is a fractal nature to it all and
then it just keeps getting bigger and
bigger.
And the idea that's multiverse is that
there is infinite number of different
universe.
Now,
did he say that's a theoretically the
most likely or that there's some sort of
evidence or there's some,
some reason to believe it outside?
Because my biggest thing is we have all
these theories for all this shit. Yeah,
Big Bang, God, whatever. Uh, you
know, have a far the universities.
But can our minds really even wrap around
what the reality probably actually is?
Our minds may not even be able
to conceive the reality of this.
You know what I mean? We may not. It may
not. It may be beyond our imagination.
We, our imagination has kind of limited
to the things that we're supposed to be
experiencing. What we're here. You know,
we could abstractly think
about things outside of that,
but even when someone says to you like a
hundred billion stars, you're like, wow,
it's a lot. But that number's not even
getting in my head. Even after I've said,
yeah. Like I don't want to know what
that means. What does that even mean?
That to say there's more stars
than grains of sand on the earth.
That's what blows me away. Because I mean,
you just look at a jar of saying, yeah,
those are giant balls of fire.
Maybe more than a million times bigger
than earth is floating in the sky.
So we could see at the, at the
eclipse, I had a little observatory,
like all the colleges and stuff were,
were there where we were at,
and you could see, um, you come back in
like 10 minutes. I, in every 10 minutes,
come back and look through this one
telescope. You can see a star going around
the star. Wow. That
was fucking cool. Yeah.
I read something yesterday that Pluto
is so far away that one the time they
discovered it in 1930 it still hasn't
made a complete orbit around the sun.
Oh Shit.
How long does it take door of it?
I Dunno how long time.
Fucking time.
It is. The funniest part is the kids are
sitting there and they're like, oh yeah,
that's cool. Um, can we get some
fucking marshmallows or what?
Play video games.
Pluto's unusual orbit takes 248 earth
years for Pluto to complete one orbit
around the sun.
It's orbital path.
Doesn't lie in the same
plane as the eight planets,
but as inclined at an angle of 17 degrees
and it's not even a planet anymore.
Woo. Yeah. Mine fucker. Eric
Goes, how about Elon Musk's,
that crazy asshole shot of fucking
Tesla up in this space yesterday with a
mannequin on board singing a
David [inaudible] on board,
a mannequin dude sitting
in a Tesla roadster.
That's a like a mannequin.
Like it looks like a dude and he's there.
That's what it looks like. Yeah. Is this
live right now? You could see it yet.
It's songs on a billion time loop.
It's gonna play for a bill or how does
he have the battery for those song to
keep playing? He's got some sun and
he's lying. He's lying. The guys lie. I,
these batteries run out of go. You'd
go 248 miles. That car runs out of gas.
Straight explaining it. The
waiver. I thought, dude,
I thought he said actual fucking rockets.
Yeah,
there was an actual rocket
and the roadster with a
mannequin and it was attached
to the rocket. So at the very
apex of this rocket, as you know,
there's multistage rockets.
They pop this bitch out and
it goes flying through space.
He shot a fucking car and his space,
like imagine aliens
coming to earth and this,
and this is like the first thing they
finally like, what the fuck is this?
Is that a person? No, there's
the richest, craziest guy. Uh,
one of the richest, craziest guys
on earth, one of the smartest guys.
He just launched his cars in
a space for a good, I like,
these people are assholes.
You see a lot of rich people
that maybe want get richer,
they just want to get richer.
So the right thing,
just even how much money
is he blowing on this shit?
It's his main on earth by humans.
I think he blew $100 million to do this.
Click on that link of the image of the
Tesla with the earth behind it. Okay.
Who'd suits your brew man?
I mean that is just what a crazy image
did. I want to hear? I never
talked to Eddie about that.
I'll want to hear is real theory on that.
Eddie Bravo. Don't talk to him about it.
Did I want to hear it? They'll change
the way you think. It's got to change it.
Now there's a whole video of this going
from the bottom to no, it doesn't.
It's not based in reality, man.
It's not based in logic or reason.
It's basically has no logic behind it.
He wants to think the earth is flat. He,
he's like, you don't know. He doesn't
trust science. Doesn't trust scientists,
doesn't trust anybody. I mean, I get that,
but you got to have some logic
still to back it up. Right.
You know what,
one of the things that makes Eddie so
good at Jujitsu is he has an idea to get a
move on you and he's fucking completely
locked on that idea and everything
that's trying to shut that down is just
like he needs to come up with a defense
for that. He's good at that in a way.
That's how he looks at ideas as well.
So if he has an idea that the earth is
flat or that there's lizard people that
live under the ground, like
you got to move. I Dunno.
You got to prove that that's not real
to him. And if you can't prove it,
that's not real. And you say, well, look
at these pictures. Oh, that's bullshit.
They fake it.
They fake the moon landing six times.
Yeah,
you gotta get gotta Lot more than that.
I wanted to hear as a actual argument,
but I sit down with them. I'll film it.
I want it to turn the camera on.
I'll leave the room.
I went to his gym a couple of weeks ago,
I'd always heard that he talks a lot
at his gym or kind of goes on about
different things like that.
Yeah. And I was totally
prepared. I was like, fuck yeah,
let's go. Let's hear it. He didn't do
anything. He didn't barely even talk.
We just rolled the whole time.
He's probably happy. Were there,
I wanted to show you some
Jujitsu, Jujitsu wizard. He did.
He showed me some good Jujitsu. He
just, uh, I like his system. It's an,
it's an intense system, not, and you know,
the moves, I only know so much, but the,
uh, the concept of what do we
do at 99% of Jujitsu classes,
you go practice some new technique you
probably never did before and then you
start rolling and then you role and his,
the, when we went there, we, you know,
we drilled, drilled, drilled,
and this reminded me much more of
like a wrestling style practice.
And I liked it a lot in that terms.
That's why he,
that's why he designed it that way. He's
a real jujitsu genius. He really is. Yeah.
You know, I mean the, the conspiracy
thing, I think he just enjoys it.
He loves them. He loves it. You
Love Zoe sending me crazy shit.
I'm afraid I'll love it too much.
I once I actually have the time,
it's a giant distraction.
If you think Instagram is a
distraction, go, go, try to,
that's a problem. I mean, you
can't, like there's no website.
Maybe there should be where you
can just go on and say, okay,
this is what this PSI believes about it.
This is what this side believes about
it and you make up your own mind.
You got to dig through fucking Info wars.
And of course I give you, if you try
to tell someone, dude, it's true.
I said it on him for wars. They're
like, okay. Right. You're full of shit.
There's a few websites like
that, right? Like the Daily Mail,
the daily on the Daily Mail, your kids
though the radar or something like that.
There's a bunch of them. There's
a bunch of weird ones. Matt Brown.
I gotta wrap this up. I gotta get the
fuck out of here. But listen, man,
I appreciate your time. We appreciate you
being here as a pleasure. It's an honor.
When are you fighting Carlos
Condit? April 14th. Ooh. April 14th.
Motherfuckers tune in. Um, and it's,
I am the immortal on Instagram.
Bryant. Yeah. And what do you, what's
your Twitter? Same. Same, same.
I am the immortal and then in mortal
combat equipment dot. CEO. Thanks brother.
It's a pleasure.
Thank you.
Okay.