Sure,
thank you.
Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Boom.
And we're live Hawaii in the house.
Good to see you.
Thanks for doing this.
Thanks for him.
What a great place to be.
A Congressperson the best.
You're in paradise.
Yeah.
It's hard to leave to go to Washington.
I'd tell you what,
that's one place if it wasn't for the
storms and the fact that it's really a
volcano as we've seen all too evident
just recently.
Yeah.
I have a friend who goes to the big
island every year for Thanksgiving.
He convinced me to go two years in a
row.
It was awesome.
I loved it,
but then this year I might do.
It seems like it's shooting rocks into
the sky and a half of it's on fire.
Yeah,
that.
That's been a.
that's it.
So that's my district.
My district in Hawaii covers basically
the whole state except for the densely
populated urban corridor of Honolulu.
Oh,
so you're lucky you cover everything
except the problems bar
the city,
the city.
So no,
it's.
It's been tough.
It's been a tough year because of those
folks in the district to Puno at the
volcano.
We have gone through a few near misses
with hurricanes,
some big flooding on Kawaii and now
we've got another one that's knocking on
our door.
Yeah,
you guys just a,
what was it,
a level four just passed.
It was five.
They were expecting it to be kind of the
same intensity that Puerto Rico and the
Virgin Islands saw.
So we were really like encouraging
everyone to get prepared,
getting prepared ourselves,
like boarding up all the doors and
windows and then,
thank God it turned into a tropical
storm at the end and had some lot of
rain.
We still had some flooding,
but compared to what it could have been
very fortunate.
And then on top of that,
you guys had a false alarm where tax
went out to everybody in the island
saying that a nuclear missile was headed
your way.
And this was not a drill.
What the hell?
Oh my gosh,
I was in Washington when that happened.
It was a Saturday afternoon ish in dc
time,
you know,
early morning in Hawaii and uh,
somebody from Hawaii,
he sent me a screen capture of that
alert that went out to over a million
cell phones across our state saying,
uh,
you know,
a ballistic missile headed towards
Hawaii.
Seek cover.
This is not a good
drill.
Wow.
Yeah.
What does that feel like?
I mean,
until you find out that's not.
How long did it take before you found
out that it wasn't?
So I immediately started thinking,
I mean,
so many things running through my head.
I'm thinking about my parents,
my husband,
my family,
everybody's in Hawaii.
Start thinking about what's going on in
the state.
Is this real?
Is it not real?
So that was Kinda the first thing.
Like I kicked into gear like,
okay,
let's,
let's make sure this is legitimate.
I'm the actual threat from North Korea
is a very real one.
So it could very well be.
It was not obvious that this was just a
mistake that people should blow off.
And that was what I think most of the
people in the state understood as they
started thinking through what do we do
with the last minutes of our lives.
So I called.
The first person I called was our state
adjutant general,
who's also the head of our civil defense
and the national guard and a called his
cell phone.
Thank God.
He answered the phone and I said,
I got this message,
what's going on?
And he said,
uh,
it's a false alarm.
It was sent out as a mistake.
I said,
okay,
I'm going to blast that out.
So I got on twitter and I put that out,
just saying,
hey,
this is not accurate.
I forget exactly what I said,
but basically this is a false alarm.
And then just started getting on the
phone,
making as many calls as I possibly
could.
But as I was doing that,
I was getting text messages and emails
and things from people who were freaking
out.
Um,
as far as Korea from Hawaii,
um,
it's,
it's over 4,000 miles away.
That's not very far for a,
for an intercontinental ballistic
missile.
And knowing progressively,
just over the six years that I've been
in Congress,
and this was a major issue,
um,
that I've been bringing up since I've
been there in just raising the alarm
bells that North Korea is increasing
their capacity and their,
their ballistic missile capabilities
that put Hawaii closer and closer than
reach Hawaii and Alaska particularly.
And that's why,
you know,
and,
and after people started getting the
word that this was a false alarm,
I started hearing from folks who just
shared their stories of what they went
through.
And you know,
on the news,
they showed the guy who was lowering his
daughter down a manhole on the side of
the street,
his little girl.
Oh God.
I heard from another guy who said that,
you know,
I had one kid in town in Honolulu and
another kid and why and I over an hour
drive.
And he literally sat there thinking,
how am I going to choose which child I'm
going to go and spend the last minutes
of my life with?
Because you're either driving in one
direction or the other.
There are so many,
so many stories of what happen,
guy pushed,
clicked on the wrong,
uh,
on the wrong alert message on his
computer screen.
That's ultimately what happened.
Uh,
the one that said,
this is a drill.
Did he have like no glasses on or
something or was it just,
there's so many theories and his story
has changed a few times and of course
there's the subject of major
investigations and then after awhile he
got fired.
He's actually swings and he was
wrongfully terminated and almost stuff
going on.
And
if ever there was something you could be
fired for,
how could you be wrongfully terminated
for that mistake?
That's my question.
To understand the magnitude of your
decision.
I mean,
that is a giant fuck up.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
But it,
it,
you know,
I think it,
um,
it really woke people up.
There were clear vulnerabilities in our
state alert system that would even allow
this,
allow one person to have that power to
do that is not,
it's obviously not good.
And so there,
there are things that we're working to
just to strengthen our civil defense
alert system,
but also just to bring attention to
North Korea and,
and make it so that people aren't living
under this threat of possibility that
that could be a real thing and that
alarm could come through your phone and
know that you now have around 18 minutes
to find good cover or say our final
goodbyes.
Well,
it's so scary because it's such an
erratic and dangerous regime.
I mean when you see what that guy is
already done and the people he's
executed,
including family members.
Yeah.
I mean he's a quite a maniac and a
legitimate dictator in the old world
kind of sense.
It's very strange that he's still.
I mean you think in the age that we live
in that would be very difficult to
control the entire country the way that
they've controlled North Korea for so
long.
Yeah.
Since the Korean War.
But yeah,
they still can do it
that they are.
And I think that while it may be easy to
write him off as a maniac,
there has also been a very consistent
there.
There,
there has been a consistency throughout
the different regimes of the Kim family
as they've developed this nuclear,
a nuclear missile capability in that
they are doing it to protect themselves
against regime change,
war essentially.
And they have said it directly.
Um,
uh,
you know,
our,
our US foreign policy experts point that
out that this is the reason why they're
developing this capability because they
have seen how,
if you look at Libya,
for example,
when Gaddafi was looking at,
you know,
building and acquiring nuclear weapons,
um,
he was doing so also as you know,
to protect himself and his regime.
And then he made a deal with the United
States saying,
okay,
give up your nuclear weapons a program
and we're not going to,
you know,
don't worry about it.
We're not going to touch you.
And then of course we know what
happened.
The U S led this regime change war
toppled,
Gadhafi and,
and North Korea says,
okay,
so that's what you do when you have,
you know,
a leader of a country without nuclear
weapons to protect themselves.
Well,
it's also the consequences of that
regime change is a failed state and it's
more terrifying than even when Gaddafi
was controlling.
I mean,
I'm sure you've seen the,
uh,
the slave trade videos from their fine.
It's insane.
It is horrifying.
You're watching youtube.
Yeah.
Right,
right.
And in our lifetime and that,
this,
um,
this failed state has happened as a
direct result of our policy.
There are failed continuation of these
regime change wars that we carry out
different parts of the world.
Right?
It's almost like we don't learn from our
mistakes and I don't know what the
proper solution is.
I mean,
do you keep someone like Saddam Hussein
or someone like Walmart Kadafi,
do you keep them in power and let them
still be horrific dictators in evil
maniacs or do you step in and cause more
damage?
I mean,
it's almost a lose lose situation.
It,
it's,
yeah,
it's not a good situation,
but it's where we as the United States
need to be pragmatic about the situation
and the fact that we live in the world
that exists,
not some kind of idealistic world that
is a fantasy.
And then think about how,
um,
counterproductive our acting as the
world's police has been,
has proven to be,
in example,
after example after example.
So yes,
there are bad people in the world who do
horrifying things,
but
is it really in our place to go in and
take action and say,
okay,
we're going to remove this person and
then we're going to put this person in
and this is how you're going to govern
this country.
And,
and really acting,
acting as the world's police and
therefore,
and then as a result,
as we've seen in Iraq and Libya and now
in Syria,
the people in those countries are far
worse off than they were before.
We have an.
And it's counterproductive for our
interests as well because we have al
Qaeda,
Isis and other terrorist groups who have
been strengthened directly as a result
of our policies in these countries.
When you talk to people in the
intelligence community,
what,
what did they think,
I mean either off the record or on the
record,
what did they think is the solution for
situations like that?
Many of them are hesitant to share their
own opinion because,
especially in the intelligence
community,
um,
their job is to report on what they're
hearing,
what they're gathering,
the Intel that they're bringing in and
so on and so forth.
But you know what,
when you,
when you talk with folks who operate in
that space,
um,
the ones who are honest and not trying
to further specific agenda or cover
somebody else's bad decisions,
um,
there is a recognition of how our
policies of the past decades have
failed.
People in those countries and us,
they failed.
But have they failed as bad or equally
bad as if we did,
if we did nothing like worse,
worse for sure.
We,
yes,
mmm.
Worse for the people in those countries.
Worse for the people in those countries
as well as,
as,
as we should be thinking about before we
take any of these actions is how does
this best serve the interest of our
people in this country and these actions
have been counter to those best
interests.
And so your question about,
so why do we keep doing this?
Um,
I think there are a lot of different
things that go into that and to drive
that,
you know,
you have the military industrial complex
that benefits and makes a lot of money
off of our being in a,
in a perpetual state of war.
You have a lot of other countries like
Saudi Arabia,
for example,
who dump a lot of money into the United
States,
uh,
and,
um,
kind of try to use our US military as
they're forced to go in and do certain
things in the Middle East that's more
beneficial to Saudi Arabia.
Uh,
we see this happening in Yemen right
now.
Yet another example,
interventionist war jumping in there.
We're a supporting Saudi Arabia and
their coalition in this war that's
created the worst humanitarian disaster
in the world.
They just bombed a school bus and killed
40 kids a couple of weeks ago,
and Yemen Yemeni civilians bombed
weddings in Yemen and yet,
uh,
our US government is not saying,
hey,
we're,
we're gonna,
stop and Yank all of our support for
Saturday with their.
They're continuing to do it.
But you're a veteran as a veteran,
do you mean you,
you've served our country,
you've,
you've put yourself in harm's way,
you,
you were a part of the military,
but there's so many people that are
making these decisions that have not
done that.
Yeah.
Do you think that's part of the problem?
Yes,
and that was,
that was one of the main reasons that I
ran for Congress in the first place.
Having come back from,
uh,
my,
my own deployments to the Middle East at
the Hawaii Army National Guard,
I'm experiencing and seeing firsthand
the cost of war both on our troops,
on our friends who didn't make that trip
home with us as well as on the people,
the people in these countries where we
were.
And I came back and saw just the
cavalier attitude that a lot of
politicians take to making these
decisions.
And,
and I,
I worked in a medical unit and my
deployment to Iraq,
we were in a base about 40 miles north
of Baghdad.
And um,
our base where we were was,
was nicknamed a mortar Rita Ville
because of the constant,
almost daily mortar attacks.
And everyday part of my job was to go
through a list of all of the American
injuries and casualties that had
happened the day before to try to see if
there were any of our close to 3000
Hawaii soldiers who had been hurt and to
then make sure that they were getting
the care they needed either in country
or get them evacuated as quickly as
possible.
And just going through,
going through that list name by name
every day.
Um,
whether there were people on there who I
knew personally or you know,
people who I would never meet.
And knowing about the family members and
loved ones,
moms,
dads,
kids at home who were stressed out every
day,
fearing getting that phone call that
their loved one that had been hurt or
worse,
killed in action.
And I wondered then,
you know,
how many of these politicians who,
who make these votes and who make these
decisions actually think about this or
who lose sleep on this,
do you think a solution to that would be
mandatory military service for people
who are in those positions?
I don't.
You don't know.
What do you think?
Because as a soldier,
I don't know.
I don't want somebody in my foxhole
doesn't want to be there.
First of all.
I think it's,
you know,
having an all volunteer force which we
have,
um,
is a positive thing.
I think that the American people need to
impress upon their leaders,
um,
the importance of taking these decisions
very seriously.
That if they want to represent and make,
represent the American people and make
these decisions for our troops and for
our country,
they need to understand who pays that
price for the cost of war.
And yes,
it is every single one of our service
members,
both those who paid the ultimate price
as well as those who come home with both
visible and invisible wounds,
um,
and who will continue paying that price
for a very long time to come,
but also
every one of our communities filled with
people who may not have worn the
uniform,
but who've had trillions of dollars
taken out of their wallet to pay for
these counterproductive
interventionists.
Wars as we in Hawaii,
for example,
struggle to put air conditioners in
schools where kids are trying to study
in over 100 degree heat as we deal with
massive infrastructure problems.
People in Michigan,
they just shut down the water system in
a bunch of schools in Detroit because
they have lead poisoning the water for
the kids.
So the kids are not able to use the
water fountains at school.
So we have major infrastructure,
major cha challenges and issues.
And so making sure that leaders are held
accountable for the decisions that
they're making is ultimately what needs
to happen.
One of the things I learned about you in
one of the things I've liked about a lot
of your interviews is you have an
obvious genuine person,
like if you're not genuine,
I'd be very shocked.
That's very rare,
so when you're talking about these
politicians and having these people
being held accountable,
it's a real problem,
but one of the problems with politics
and one of the problems with public
speaking and being charismatic is a lot
of these people are just really good at
being full of shit and because they're
really good at being full of shit.
A lot of slack,
jawed dumb dumbs out there,
buy into it,
hook,
line and sinker,
wave that flag and kiss those babies and
they vote these dummies office and this
happens time and time again.
Yeah,
so saying you need these people need to
be aware of the consequences are that
need to be held accountable.
I firmly believe there's more associate
and we really think I really do.
I think if you look at the general
consensus is something like,
what is it one out of 100 or something
like that.
What do they think it is?
Maybe more.
I think it might be 10 percent.
I think there's a lot of people that get
through life doing things and getting
away with things and not doing things
that are going to cause them either
danger or social consequences,
but they,
but they managed to get through life
with a song and a dance,
but they're not genuine.
I think this is a giant problem with
people that want to be in a position of
power in the first place.
Yes.
Like why would they,
why does a guy like Donald Trump wants
to be the fucking president when you
have billions of dollars in the bank?
Like what are you doing?
Why are you doing that?
There's a weird motivation that a lot of
these people have and that motivation is
to be the uber they know,
to be the king,
to be the top of the heap,
to be the queen,
whatever it is.
Um,
I don't know how you change that in
those people.
I don't think making them aware of the
consequences of their decisions is going
to work.
It's just the type of people who they
are in the first place.
I don't.
Yeah.
You think you're not wrong.
However,
I've just seen over the last few years
the level of awareness amongst people
amongst voters has been increasing as
there are more and more kind of non
mainstream media outlets that are
shining light on these kinds of issues.
And
when you say non mainstream seating,
do you think that mainstream have been
holding back?
I think that especially,
um,
I think that you only get a certain
narrative,
right?
And it depends on,
it changes based on what channel you
flick to or whatever
because if you vary in that narrative
then you get less access.
Uh,
yeah,
I guess you could say that.
So you get less access to the people
that you want to have on those shows
because that's how you get your ratings
in the first place.
Yeah.
I mean,
and that's,
that's the problem with these,
with a lot of these news channels is it
is driven by ratings and if you're
bringing in different viewpoints and
different perspectives,
um,
I dunno,
maybe it affects their ratings.
I don't know,
I don't pay too much attention to that,
but I do know that when you look at,
uh,
you know,
guys like Jimmy Dore for example,
yes,
you know,
Jimmy Dore talks about a lot of things
that you'll never hear if you flick on
the TV on the,
on the cable news channels and has very
interesting conversations and again,
bringing facts and different things to
life that people don't otherwise feel
like they have access to.
Well,
there's way more of that today than
there ever has been.
That's where I see there's opportunity
and because the more people are learning
like,
holy crap,
this is what you're doing.
This is the consequences of those
decisions.
There's a ton of votes that happened
every single day in Congress that most
people don't know about unless you're
really following it closely yourself.
Just that,
that in itself of itself is a job that,
that,
you know,
CNN,
MSNBC,
Fox News,
they're not covering a.
So really a lot of kind of these
alternative sites and voices are coming
through that are helping to,
um,
helping to inform and educate people.
Yeah.
The,
the,
the idea of trying to educate
politicians on the consequences and what
that,
what that really means and this,
the,
the cavalier attitude that you were
talking about,
like what's a worst example that like
when you,
when you were talking about cavalier
behavior by these people that make these
decisions,
like what kinds of things have you seen?
Um,
I'll speak to something that happened
most recently.
I think there are probably a number of
examples,
but I'm just a couple of months ago.
And the big defense authorization bill
that,
that is kind of one of the,
the,
the only must pass pieces of legislation
in Congress every year there was a three
page provision that was kind of put in
there without really any debate in the
committee or anything like that that
would essentially authorize the United
States to go to war with Iran.
Now you would think something like that
with that magnitude would be kind of a
big deal.
You would want to have hearings,
you would want to have be a question on
strategy,
objectives costs,
like all of these different things that
didn't happen.
So when this bill came to the floor of
the house where all 435 members of
Congress have the ability to vote yes or
no,
I just put in an amendment that would
have deleted those three pages from this
big thousands page bill.
Um,
and,
and basically those provisions said that
Congress is authorizing the secretary of
state and the secretary of defense to
create and implement a strategy to
counter Iran,
not just come and,
hey,
bring us your strategy and let us talk
about it and see whether or not we agree
and improve.
It was giving the power to the secretary
of state and secretary of defense to
create and implement a strategy to
counter Iran.
Extremely dangerous and a blank check to
essentially start a brand new war that
currently has not been declared.
I introduced this amendment and if you
want to take a guess on how many people
voted for it,
how many 60?
60.
Why wouldn't they?
Why would they want that blank check?
There are some people who legitimately
do want to do,
want us to go to war with Iran or who
are those people?
Um,
you don't have to name names there,
there is,
uh,
there are,
I would say it's a bipartisan feeling.
And why do they want that?
Because Iran,
uh,
they,
they feel that Iran is a threat to both
the United States and Israel and Iran is
and has been for a long time.
They feel I'm a menace,
I guess essentially,
and our enemy,
even though Congress has not declared
war,
uh,
even though,
you know,
we,
our country just signed a nuclear deal
to make it so that they can't build a
nuclear weapon.
Um,
it's,
uh,
it,
it gets to a point where it seems like a
hysteria,
but again,
it's not based on an actual thinking
through tactically and strategically and
responsibly what we're actually doing
and what our policy is.
Are you one of the younger people in
Congress?
Yeah.
You could say that there's a handful of
us who are under 40,
not many small handful in.
Is that,
I mean,
you're,
you're a person who would you like 30,
37.
You,
you're not allowed to ask ladies.
Usually your congresswoman politicians
are an exception.
I guess everything has to be on the
table with,
we have to be a certain age to run for
office,
so,
you know,
well,
how would you have to be to be
president?
I'm 35 so you can get in there.
Yeah,
we thought about it.
Ah,
you know,
a lot of,
a lot of people have been,
especially with everything that's going
on,
I've been kind of urging me to,
um,
to consider it,
you know,
um,
I'm folk,
I'm focused on home and focused on
Hawaii.
I'm want to do my very best to be able
to serve them in our country.
And um,
yeah.
This seems like it's too much work too.
It's a lot.
It seems like too much.
It's a lot at age.
Is the shit out of those,
those more pictures are always
interesting.
George Bush was one of the weirdest
ones.
Whoa.
And Obama.
Obama was a rough one too.
Yeah.
I mean,
it just does.
There's no getting away from that.
And if it doesn't then they should
probably,
probably not doing your job.
Probably a monster somewhere.
Yeah.
I'm mean,
it's,
um,
you're in a crazy business,
but I think to that,
to that point,
just talking about,
um,
how few younger members of Congress,
there are a.
One of the things I did when I first got
elected,
I started something called the future
caucus and it was a bipartisan kind of
millennial focused caucus saying that we
as a generation,
um,
recognize the need to work together to
drop all the partisan hyperpartisan crap
that is tearing this country apart and
focus on solutions and actually solving
problems.
And so,
you know,
different people have come and gone in
Congress.
But I think what's,
what's exciting now is that there is a
lot more energy,
interest and activity.
I think from young people in this who
may fall in different places on
ideological spectrum of politics.
But recognize that,
you know,
there's no reason why I should give my
voice to someone from another generation
who has no idea what our challenges are
or the challenges that we will face from
the decisions they made in left behind.
When I see someone like jeff sessions
and then I see someone like you.
Obviously you're different.
You know,
different realms of the ideological
spectrum,
but there's a big difference between
someone who formed their view of the
world while the Internet was active and
that's you versus this crazy old asshole
who thinks that people smoke marijuana
are bad people.
I mean he.
There's a.
it's a weird thing when you see some of
these old guard,
they are,
they're relic of the past,
but yet they're still in a position of
power and control and they're.
They're making these decisions based on
this old world that really doesn't exist
anymore.
Yeah,
and there's so many different ways that
that actually has a very real impact and
I think the.
Some of the hearings that we've seen
most recently dealing with facebook and
twitter and Google are a perfect example
where you have people asking questions
and it becomes very obvious quickly.
Yes.
They don't like.
They don't know how to log into
facebook.
I've never sent a tweet in their lives.
Some of these people are very proud that
they either don't have a cell phone or
they still have a flip phone,
which is fine.
If that's your personal decision,
that's fine,
but if you're the the regulatory body
that should be exercising oversight over
how technology is rapidly changing the
world that we live in,
right?
You got to know something about it or be
surround yourself with people who do
well,
especially when it pertains to selling
people's privacy or using people's data
to influence elections and using.
You know,
the stuff that's been happening with
facebook is even more strange because I
don't know how you stop.
Like there was a fantastic NPR podcast
about these Russian troll farms about
their jobs.
People show up for work and their job is
to spread misinformation and propaganda.
You know about whatever the subject is,
whatever ideological point they're
trying to push through,
but they're trying to influence the way
people look at things in their targeting
people's comments sections and news
feeds and twitter feeds and they're
trying to do something that injects
ideas into people's minds and sways
their perception and their point of
view.
And it's very strange when you think
that a foreign country is doing this and
that people from a foreign country that
this is actually a job,
so it must have,
there must be some sort of a reason for
this.
And then when you see those people that
are questioning,
uh,
what's his name?
Facebook.
Uh,
Dr Berg.
Jeff Zuckerberg.
Not Jeff Soccer Birth Mark Sternberg,
Jeff Zuckerberg,
the guy runs NBC.
CBS.
Right?
But at NBC.
No.
Is it?
Yeah,
I think it's NBC,
you know,
Jeff Soccer,
soccer,
soccer.
There you go.
Anyone with the name of CSEC?
What a strange name.
But Zuckerberg's,
you know,
he was so guarded in that as well that,
um,
I,
I almost wanted to go,
hey,
stop.
This is not you man.
Where's the real you?
Yeah.
This is weird.
The way you're sipping water and you're
just the way you're talking to people.
So odd.
Yeah.
These,
the formality of it all.
Yeah.
Some of my friends on that committee who
actually are under 40 years old,
who were members of Congress and who
prepared and,
and you know,
went in and were asking some tough
questions.
Um,
were very frustrated just because they
didn't feel like they were getting,
they were actually getting,
um,
many answers,
first of all,
a lot of,
a lot of kind of legally speaking in
circles and that kind of thing.
And um,
I think when you're,
when you're talking about an and there's
so many,
I don't know,
I've kind of going in a few different
directions here with,
with these social media giants,
how they're being misused,
um,
to further certain agendas in different
ways.
But when you're talking about like these
Russian troll farms that you're,
um,
that you mentioned what is missing from
all of the news coverage around this and
all of the outrage about how this
foreign country is trying to influence
our elections,
which is wrong and which the American
people need to be aware of.
Where this information is coming from is
the fact that we.
And you're saying why,
why does somebody do that?
Well,
because this country does want to,
um,
influence who were electing,
right?
Yeah.
We'd rather work with this person.
We know that person's not going to be
nice to us.
The United States has been doing this
for a very long time.
Sure.
In countries around the world,
both overtly and covertly through,
through these kinds of information
campaigns.
Not,
not even counting,
like the outright regime change wars.
We're going to physically take you out.
And um,
I think it is.
I'm very hypocritical for us to be
discussing this issue as a country
without actually being honest about how
this goes both ways.
So yes,
we need to stop these other foreign
countries and Russia is not the only
one.
There are others from a trying to
influence the American people in our
elections.
We also need to stop doing the same
thing in other countries
without doubt.
Um,
but there's also the question is what is
Russia trying to achieve?
Like,
oh,
why do they want someone like Donald
Trump in office versus someone like
Hillary Clinton,
like what is to be gained and how much
you know.
I mean,
how much do they benefit from that?
Yeah.
This is what's really one of the big
questions it's going on right now with
all the Russian hearings and the Mueller
investigation and trying to get to the
bottom of all this and why they did what
they did and what they did,
and there's many people that are blowing
this off and they don't think that it's
important and you know,
the,
the president's claiming it's a witch
hunt,
but it's very odd that we're having this
conversation in the first place.
It's never existed before in any single
presidential election.
There was never been talk of us or any
politician that's running for president
being influenced by a foreign superpower
before today.
It's just amazing that it took until
2016 before this became a real issue.
That's true.
Well,
there's talk about Hillary and uranium
and all kinds of other different issues
and you know,
I mean,
I'm,
I'm not a giant Hillary Clinton fan and
one of the reasons why I'm not as.
I just,
I think she's a politician,
you know,
and I don't think she's a genuine
person.
I just don't.
I think you get to a,
a level of lying and the way they
conduct themselves in the way they've
been doing it for so long that they
don't even think it's a bad thing.
It's just a thing you do.
But one of the weirder ones that I ever
saw from her was after the Libya,
after Kadafi was killed,
where she was not on the record,
but she was still being recorded there
talking to her.
You know what I'm talking about where
she said we came,
we saw was we came,
we saw,
we saw him.
He died.
What was the,
I don't know,
the.
Yeah,
we came,
we saw and he's dead or something and
she was laughing,
like literally laughing.
But this is,
this is exactly what I'm talking about,
about that cavalier attitude within
Washington.
And for me that was,
that was really the main reason why in
2016 I was a vice chair of the
Democratic National Party.
Um,
as an officer of the party,
you're supposed to stay neutral in these
democratic primaries.
But it got to a point where I felt I
stepped down from that position,
resigned as vice chair to endorse Bernie
Sanders,
largely because of the huge difference
in their world views with Hillary
Clinton's very hawkish interventionist,
foreign policy.
And track record.
Libya is,
is a very prominent in recent example,
Iraq is another.
And Bernie Sanders,
who generally takes some more um,
non interventionist worldview a that was
an issue,
again,
like as you're talking to that people
weren't really raising the differences,
are saying,
oh,
she was secretary of state.
So she's great on foreign policy,
but not actually looking at what is the
actual policy.
Right and what kind of judgment would
either of these individuals have when
they're serving in that most important
job of commander in chief.
And that was,
that was,
uh,
a very key difference.
And that was something I talked about a
lot as I campaigned with Bernie around
the country.
And,
and that was something that I saw and
heard from people in big cities,
small towns,
Midwest,
north,
south,
east,
west,
people who appreciated.
I'm just being told the truth.
Well,
there was also the,
um,
the speeches that you gave where she
wouldn't give up the transcripts for
those gigantic paid speeches she gave in
front of bankers street.
Yeah.
Which is crazy that that's legal.
I mean,
that is essentially.
Look,
there is no way she is so entertainment
entertaining.
I mean,
we're not talking about a Jay z concert
or Kevin Hart isn't doing stand up.
They paid her a quarter million dollars
to talk for an hour.
Like,
that's not real.
Okay.
They're not really paying you a quarter
million dollars because you're so
awesome.
They really want you to talk for an
hour.
This is some sort of a bribe.
This is some sort of a deal.
You're making a business arrangement.
There's no question about it.
There is no way that it's that valuable.
It's just not her talking for an hour.
What a hot ticket.
Jesus,
how do I get ahold of that ticket?
I mean,
that is crazy.
Yeah.
The fact that someone could play that
off is if this is a legitimate business
transaction,
that's nonsense.
Yeah.
And,
and there's a direct correlation there
though,
with,
with Wall Street,
big money in general as you're talking
about that influence on politics.
I was talking with a guy who's,
when he comes over recovering kind of
finance guy from Wall Street who's left
and is now come here to la and um,
and,
and he talked directly about that and we
were talking about how even after 2008,
all the too big to fail banks,
they were bailed out and people are
suffering.
They're losing their homes or pensions
and all of this stuff.
These banks are bigger today than they
were back then.
And over time,
and even over the last few years,
Congress has slowly,
and this is not just republicans,
there are Democrats who are on the tape
too,
are taken this Wall Street money and
you're starting to see these bills
passed,
peeling away the very small amount of
regulations that were put on after that
crash to get us back to an even worse
situation than we were back in 2011.
Why?
How could we allow this to happen?
There's a ton of money that's coming
from Wall Street and funding
politicians' campaigns,
lobbyists who are there helping to write
the legislation or kill the bad bills
and again,
who's who's talking about this?
No one,
right?
Very few people.
How do you stop that though?
Like how do you stop the funding,
their campaigns a and then the paid
speeches be those two things alone.
If you could just cut that out and said,
no,
you have to be legitimate.
I mean that love or hate Bernie Sanders.
You've got to respect the fact that guy
never took any money from anybody.
That's right.
And he said,
I'll give you my all my transcripts
because I don't have any.
I didn't get paid to do any speeches and
he's clean.
Yeah,
I mean this is the reason why he can say
that.
And Hillary just ignored it.
I mean,
she just didn't,
didn't respond.
She didn't say,
I'll give you the transcripts because
all I said was I love America and we're
going to fix everything.
And you bankers are dirty.
It's just they don't pay you to call
them names.
Exactly,
but it's just strange that there that,
well,
it's not strange in terms of the real
obvious benefit.
If you're going to be a politician and
you want to run for office,
it's incredibly expensive to win,
so you need some money so you have to
make deals with people who are willing
to give you some of that money and
you've got to figure out a way to be
able to do this and still convinced the
people that have to vote for you,
that you're on their side.
Yeah,
and this is where that narrative is
being disproven.
That somehow if you run for office and
if you want to serve people within that
political realm that you,
that you have to go and Kowtow to the
corporate interests and the people with
the big money in order to be able to
fund a campaign in order to win.
So you can do good work for the people.
But also you kind of got,
you told these other guys you're going
to make them happy to,
um,
I don't take any corporate PAC money or
contributions from pax or lobbyists or
anything else,
and there are more candidates running
this year,
did over 100 candidates running for
Congress this year who have sworn off
any of those types of contributions and
who run their campaigns fueled by
individual donors where there's people
giving five bucks,
people giving more if they can give more
and that,
and they're winning there.
There are a number of candidates who are
showing that they're out raising their
opponents who are backed by pacs and
lobbyists.
Um,
they're raising more money from people
who are giving these small dollar
contributions and disproving that power
balance where the people really do have
the power.
If we stand up and get engaged and
involved.
What do you attribute that to?
What's the change?
Like?
What's,
what's causing this tank
change happened?
When Bernie Sanders ran for president?
I think he did a lot better than,
than he first expected that he would.
And the fact that he was able to raise,
uh,
in some cases more money than Hillary
Clinton in certain quarters,
he was,
he was very competitive and all of that
came from those small dollar individual
contributions,
you know,
he talked about it,
$27 is the average a contribution that
he got.
And that was kind of a rallying cry at a
lot of his events.
Um,
but people,
I think people through that experience
really woke up to their own power in
this democracy and that to have a true
strong democracy,
it really does take us all doing our
part in whatever way that we can.
If Bernie called you up tomorrow and
said,
I want you to be my vice president,
would you be down?
We'd have to have a conversation.
Come on,
man.
What would the conversation be?
Well,
you know,
he can't.
I mean,
he can't run again if he doesn't win in
20.
Right?
Yeah.
I mean basically do.
I mean,
unless someone invents some crazy new
medical technology that reverses aging,
you only have so much life in you.
Yeah.
But you on the other hand,
you can hang in there for eight years.
Yeah.
Not say anything,
which is a yes.
Your wheels are lady.
Look,
I,
um,
here.
Here's,
here's the way that I've always done
made my decisions from the time I ran
for the State House representatives in
Hawaii and I was 21 years old.
A lot of people said like,
what are you doing at 21?
This is crazy.
But I,
I cared very much for my home,
my community about environmental issues
and things that I saw were not being
addressed by many leaders in our state
who I felt were out of touch.
Um,
and joining the national guard and later
running for Congress,
I try to make my decisions based on how
and where I feel like I can make the
most impact.
So that's,
that's what I will continue to do.
Well,
you definitely can make the most impact
is vice president of the United States
from America.
Uh,
it depends who you ask.
Well,
if you asked me,
yeah,
your opinion,
I would say,
I would say that's a pretty big
platform,
although that pence guy,
you don't hear a peep of that guy.
He just kind of heightened.
It's what you make of it,
I guess.
Just like any job,
right.
It's what you make of it.
But it's like,
isn't that a joke?
Like if you want someone to disappear,
just elected vice president.
I think that's a joke,
right?
Oh yeah.
That's a different story.
Right?
Right.
Or um,
house cards too,
right?
Yeah.
I think that's next level.
They're going to keep going.
We're going to kill that guy off somehow
or another.
Somebody asked me when that show
for the first season came out,
like some of my family especially,
it may have been my mother like,
honey,
is that really what it's supposed to be?
Loosely based on the Clintons
there,
there are some quotes and some things
like that that Kevin Spacey had as the
whip in the house.
Like there was some things in there
like,
Oh wow,
I've actually heard people say that,
but all the,
all the salacious stuff.
Like I had to come from my mom's like,
no,
I'm not like catching the subway late at
night and.
Right.
Yeah.
Well that's,
that's a little bit was some of the top.
Yeah,
that was a little ridiculous.
Meet me by the subway.
Yeah.
Spoiler for anybody.
Um,
but as a long time ago.
Yeah.
But for a lot of people that is their
education on politics unfortunately.
But it's just such a complicated
process.
If you're a person that has a full time
job and a mortgage and kids and maybe
you got a hobby and you're supposed to
be paying attention to these people that
are running the country or running
whatever it is,
running the Senate or anything
political,
it's just too complicated.
It's tough.
Like what you were talking about with
these bills that get passed,
that have these hidden agendas deeply
written into a thousand page document.
How can a person who has three kids and
a mortgage and a 40 plus hour a week job
plus commuting,
how can they pay attention to all this?
No.
It's very hard.
And that's where you come in.
Yeah.
And,
and you know,
like I try to put stuff out on twitter
and facebook and Instagram,
social media because most of us are on
those platforms and as you're scrolling
through,
like maybe you're going to see that one
thing like,
hey,
you know,
Congress just passed this bill making,
deregulating a fracking and liquid
natural gas that's affecting your water
and your air and connecting the dots
between what can seem like very out of
touch policy,
wonky things too.
Okay.
How does this actually affect you,
your family,
your kids,
your house educated,
like the things that really do take up
most of people's time and consciousness
and care on it on a daily basis.
Yeah,
and that's one of the more dangerous
things I think about having a person
like trump as president is that it's
eroding people's confidence in the
person that runs the big show.
Is that your.
That's one of,
that's one of a number of things that
have eroded people's confidence.
I think if you,
if you take that one step further and
look at how people's confidence in our
entire election system has been eroded
a,
when you look at all of the
vulnerabilities that exist,
a lot of the stuff that's being talked
about now,
do you mean in terms of electronic
voting,
the machines or.
Yes.
I think overall people doubt whether or
not their votes matter.
First of all,
did you see the documentary hacking
democracy?
No,
I didn't.
It's fascinating.
And it was in regards to what year was
that?
I want to say it's 2008.
Was it eight?
Six.
So it was about Bush and Kerry,
right?
Wasn't that Bush and Gore?
Was it Bush and Gore?
Whatever it was.
Both of elections actually.
Okay.
But it showed how there is built in
third party access.
So it's literally built into the system.
Right.
That a third party can influence the
count and they showed how they did it on
the,
um,
in the actual documentary they used
these machines and influence the
results.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
What,
what to speak of the.
At the DEF defcon hacking conference
that just happened or happens annually
in Vegas,
but they just had one this year,
a couple of months ago,
maybe a few weeks ago.
We're an 1111 year old girl hacked into
a replica of Florida's,
uh,
election system and change the outcome
of their election in less than 15
minutes.
It is an 11 year old hacked into US
voting system in 10 minutes this
weekend.
Oh,
11 years old.
Well,
that's American engineers one ma'am.
That's what we do here.
We breed them young and smart.
Hire that kid.
Exactly right.
If there's tons more,
tons more like her.
Oh,
there's probably millions now.
I mean,
kids growing up with computers from the
time they're little and fit in learning,
coding like they're learning the English
language
and just like the drive and kind of the
thought process and that,
that kind of desire to take things to
the night and not just say,
okay,
this is an ipad.
This is how it works.
That's fine.
It's like,
well,
how do we make the next,
the next generation of this?
How do we break this and makes the next
better thing,
but we can bank online,
right?
Yeah.
Why can't they vote online?
Why can't they make all of this as
secure as they do banking?
Well,
you,
you still see every now and then fraud.
Well yeah,
there's bank fraud,
there's direct bank fraud,
but you also see,
um,
banks get hacked and yeah,
they've got,
I mean they've got,
you know,
their reserves and all that other stuff
and they try to deal with those
vulnerabilities and try to stay ahead of
them.
But even the technology that banks use
is not foolproof.
And when we're talking again about
voters having confidence that when they
take that time on election day,
take off from work or school or whatever
and go cast that vote that it's going to
be counted and counted accurately.
Like this is what's at stake.
If people don't have confidence in that
then then we are in serious trouble.
So one thing that,
uh,
I introduced a bill a few months ago
based on last year's defcon hacking
conference results that,
that really showed the best way to
secure our elections systems.
The actual systems themselves is either
used paper ballots or have a voter
verified paper backup.
If you're going to use an electronic
system,
so you have an electronic system,
then a voter verified paper backup,
so if there's any dispute whatsoever,
then you go to the paper,
go to the payment,
they don't correspond.
You can go to the paper.
So in Hawaii for example,
you can choose when I go vote,
I can grab a paper ballot,
traditional or I can go to the the
machine,
which I usually do go through and make
my selections and before I hit the final
submit ballot button,
there's a little printout that pops up
in a little window that shows a my voter
number who I selected to vote for so I
can actually check the paper myself
before hitting submit.
So we just did this.
Virginia has off your statewide
elections,
so they had theirs in 2017 and after
that defcon hacking conference happened
at last year.
They said we have to fix this before our
election,
and they did.
How did they mess up?
They implemented.
They did paper ballots or they did paper
ballot voter verified paper backups and
their elections commissioners came and
testified in Congress,
have after the elections were done and
they said that that was the first time
in their entire careers that they didn't
have a single complaint about the
accuracy of the vote count itself were
in previous years they had,
but they're proof that you can turn like
you identify the problem.
This is not going to take years to fix
like can action that within weeks and
actually secure the outcome of these
elections.
That's what I've been pushing for a in
Congress,
especially as we had to these midterms,
especially as we head into 20 slash 20.
But again it goes back to the point like
my bill hasn't gotten a vote yet.
Why is that?
It's a very simple black,
nonpartisan bill.
Here's a problem.
Here's the solution.
We can action this now,
but you have leaders in both parties who
are just continuing to fight and and
Fred and Moan and Groan about how we
have all these vulnerabilities in our
elections but not actually doing
anything about it.
To using it as a partisan kind of
political football,
but again,
why,
why don't you actually solve it?
Why do you think they don't solve it?
Because it's issues like this,
that it helped with fundraising and they
help kind of motivate people and they
worry people and they bring all these
fears about.
It's good for ratings.
It's all,
all these different reasons,
um,
that frustrate people frankly who know
about it when they're not actually
seeing,
you know,
deliver results.
You're talking about a problem now for
months,
congressmen talking about this for
months.
Whereas the results.
So you think that they actively are
ignoring the potential solutions or that
they literally want to keep this problem
going?
That's a good question.
But the,
the,
you know,
we have been talking about this a number
of outside kind of election security
experts have been talking about this.
Some of the hackers have been talking
about the fact that the only way you can
secure an election is by using paper.
I cannot,
I cannot come up with an excuse for why
the leaders in these committees and in
Congress have not actually.
It's like whether it's my biller,
someone else's bill,
why haven't they actually solve this
because it's something that could
potentially impact us in the coming
weeks and months.
Well,
I remember the,
the hanging Chad.
Yeah.
Controversy.
And how many different votes got thrown
out and then there was,
there was also so many people that were
denied the right to vote.
Was it in Florida because a,
they either have the same name or
similar names with people that had some
sort of a criminal record if somebody
made a typo when they put their name in
the system and then they were,
they were made ineligible.
And then there was also some concern
that some of that was deliberate because
so much of it was taking place in
democratic districts.
Yeah.
It's um,
it's very disconcerting the idea that
someone would try to rig an election.
Yeah.
I mean we would like to think that that
is an absolutely an American thing to
think of,
but people could,
isn't.
It is,
but people can come up with very strange
reasons for justification of a very
awful acts.
Yeah.
And this seems to be one of them.
They think their site is right.
Oh,
that,
that points to,
um,
the,
the super delegate issue that Democrats
have been dealing with were people who
have been arguing to keep the system of
super delegates were in a state like
mine in Hawaii for example.
We've got four super delegate votes,
uh,
to,
for the members of Congress in two for
the senator.
Explain that to people who don't know
what a super dog.
So this is something that is created by
the political parties themselves.
So the Democratic Party has,
has been using the superdelegate system
where,
um,
as people are running for president,
you have a certain number of delegates
that go to one person or another based
on that state's rules.
So some states say it's winner take all
other states say that it's proportional.
So if you get 60 percent of the vote,
that means you get 60 percent of the
delegates.
But then you have this special category
of super delegates,
which there are over 700 of them.
It includes all 435 members of,
of,
sorry,
all democratic members of Congress,
Democrats in the Senate and people who
are appointed by the party leadership
both at the state and the national
level.
And so,
um,
what we saw in,
in,
in my state of Hawaii for example,
is over 70 percent of the voters voted
for Bernie Sanders.
But out of those four super delegate
votes,
he got one which was mine.
So the superdelegates don't have to cast
their votes to reflect how the,
their constituents voted.
So of the rest of them vote,
they voted for Hillary.
So that puts you in a situation where,
and this is not about while Bernie would
have won without superdome,
this is not even what that's about.
This is about really looking at people
casting their votes.
And then you have this special group of
people who are either elected or
appointed who can then say,
Nah,
I don't,
I don't agree with the way that the
people in my state or my district voted.
So I'm just going to vote the other way.
And then shift a,
potentially the outcome of that election
for that state or for the country so
that it shifted for Hawaiian.
Yeah.
So Hillary won Hawaii's.
I'm a super delegates,
but the people voted differently and it
was 70 percent of the people voted for.
It wasn't close.
It was,
it was.
And that was how you,
how you saw that.
So in some states where,
you know,
I think,
I don't know for mod I,
there,
there are a few other states that I
remember looking at where,
um,
when they were counting the votes as
they were coming in,
they would report one number,
but if Bernie won the state,
his number was zero.
And then there was a certain number that
was already built in to Hillary's count
before the votes were even finally
tallied because she had already had the
declared supportive.
Those super delegates within that state.
So the Republicans don't do this.
I think they may have super delegates,
but those super delegates are required
to reflect the votes of their
constituency.
So they don't have the freedom to change
their,
change their vote or change their mind.
But um,
yeah,
this is uh,
this,
so this is something that I've been,
I've been fighting to,
to try to reform within our party is to
get rid of superdelegates to make it so
that we have open primaries so that you
don't have to be a card carrying party
member to vote in Democratic primary
because that was another problem we saw
across the country where people were
turned away because in some cases while
you didn't register with the party a
year ago,
which is the requirement and so,
um,
have open primaries and then you have
same day registration if you're not
registered to vote,
should be able to register to vote on
the day of the election so that you can
participate in our democracy.
So those things seem so clear cut but
seems to,
are drawing.
But the,
the,
the superdelegate issue in particular,
that's so disturbing.
Yeah.
But seems so dirty.
So there's been some progress made sense
then though,
just recently the DNC had a meeting
where,
uh,
it was a very strong majority of people
who voted to bar super delegates from a
casting.
They're their own free votes in the
first ballot in a presidential
convention,
so I don't know,
it's been a long time since,
uh,
it's gone to the second or third ballot,
but that,
that was a major step forward to make
sure that as people are going and
casting their votes in these primaries,
that they're not risking being overruled
by again,
a group of special individuals who are
elected officials,
who are lobbyists and who are party
officials and people who are coming from
all different backgrounds.
Is there any resistance to getting rid
of these super because the resistance
was very strong.
It was not a given that he's going to
pass at all people who are very,
very invested in this system.
It seems like they would have to be
invested in keeping the system rigged.
Like making it easy to influence
elections by having these few people
that you can control having influence
over these people.
These people have massive influence over
the results of the election.
It's,
it is,
it,
it's,
it's so counter intuitive to what we
stand for with our democracy.
And I think there is,
um,
I mean it's a fear of losing power,
I think ultimately is what it comes down
to.
And you have people who said,
hey,
look,
I've given my life to the party,
you know,
I've put in all of this time and energy,
I'm a volunteer,
I'm doing this and all of that,
which all of that is,
is fine and it's great,
but that shouldn't make it so that like,
you know,
as,
as myself as a super delegate,
I've talked about this,
I shouldn't have any.
My vote should count for any more than
yours or anyone else's and that we
should be strengthening and,
and empowering and uplifting the voices
of the people rather than saying,
well,
this small elite group has way more
power than you.
We'll see what they think about things.
It's so bizarre that that's a part of
the system.
It just seems like that's something that
should have been eradicated a long time.
I should have been now.
Bernie Sanders had to be fuming.
Yeah,
I mean from that.
And then from finding out the DNC
actively conspired to have him lose the
primary.
All of that.
Sorry,
one last thing on the superdelegates
that some of those who support it have
said is that it is their job to be able
to save the country in case the people
elect someone
who isn't good.
Really hilarious.
That is hilarious.
Justification.
Oh,
you know better than the whole country.
Yeah.
You must be super smart.
What kind of tests do you have to take?
Super Delicate.
Become a super delegate.
What do you have to do?
Yeah.
It's certainly not a written test,
you know,
it's,
it's really.
I mean,
again,
you're either,
you're either an elected member of
Congress or you're somebody who the
party chooses.
Wow.
The idea that the reason to keep that is
because you know better.
I mean,
that's essentially what they're saying,
you know better than all the people that
voted.
Yeah.
So disrespectful to it's crazy people.
It's really crazy.
Yeah.
MMM.
So I mean that,
that's been,
I think a positive thing that has come
through all of this is,
is more people are like,
you know,
I honestly wasn't paying a bunch of
attention to superdelegates before all
of this and a lot of people had their
eyes opened up to say,
okay,
this is clearly wrong.
Why was it there in the first place?
Let's do something to fix the process.
Well,
most people don't think until this
election,
the general public wasn't even aware
that that was,
that that was a case.
Yeah.
And then when people find out about it,
they go,
wait,
what?
What?
They can just decide to not vote the
same way that people voted.
Yeah.
And then the state can lose or I mean
the person could lose the state even
though 70 percent of the state voted for
that person.
Right.
That's insane.
Yeah,
it is.
Did you read Donna Brazile's book?
I didn't read the whole book.
I heard I got extra excerpts from it and
have it.
Um,
I will.
I was shocked that they conspired to
have hillary win the primaries.
I was more shocked that more people
weren't outraged.
Yeah.
What does that tell you?
It tells you that people have sort of
resigned to the idea that this is a
corrupt system,
that they don't have time.
It goes back to what we're saying
earlier that you know,
people are exhausted.
Yeah.
Most people,
most people are exhausted
and I think that's where you see a lot
of,
a lot of the energy that came around for
somebody like Bernie Sanders or somebody
like Donald Trump who are perceived as
being not of the system,
but it,
it shows us,
it shows us where we need to go
honestly.
And you were talking about authentic,
honest leaders who have integrity and,
and um,
I think people are not as blind to the
people can tell.
You can tell if you're being real or not
or if you're selling them a false bill
of goods.
I think they're better at it now.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Paying more attention.
Well,
there's also this,
there's enough footage of people now
that's.
Yeah,
everybody's a reporter now.
I mean,
so it's easy to go back and you say,
well,
look at this interview from four years
ago when they,
uh,
were,
were completely different.
Like what happened?
I mean,
there's also like calculated maneuvers
that people do politically to align
themselves with one group or another
where they realized like,
okay,
there's just a lot of money in being a
of this.
That's a,
that,
you know,
there's a lot of money and being a
whatever it is,
republican or Democrat or there's,
there's an angle for success,
right?
Yeah.
That's,
um,
all of those different labels and things
that people are capitalizing on within
the political world I think are the
things that are turning off more and
more people to the politics.
Because then it's like,
well,
if you're not branded with this label,
then I'm not going to talk to you.
I'm not going to have a conversation or
it's this camp versus another camp.
This tribe versus another tribe.
Rather than like recognizing even
amongst our own families and friends and
communities like we,
we figure out ways to talk things
through and find ways to collaborate and
areas where we agree we can agree to
disagree on certain things,
but we can do that with,
you know,
we in Hawaii called Aloha and with
respect and actually find a way through
to move forward.
There's a lot of things that have been
discussed in terms of the future of,
uh,
of economics in particular with regards
to artificial intelligence and
automation and these radical changes
that are probably coming whether we like
it or not.
And one of the things that's been
discussed as a potential solution to
some of the economic woes is a universal
basic income.
Have you studied this?
Studying it now I'm looking at some of
the places that have,
have or are currently kind of launching
pilot projects.
I know there's a European country that
did a two year pilot and then they
decided not to go down that route.
Um,
I think there's a.
so,
so yeah,
I'm,
I'm taking a hard look at this because
there are,
there are strong arguments I think on,
on both sides that we got to look and
see what,
um,
what would the effects actually be?
Yeah,
I'm torn on as well.
I'm very open to the idea of it because
I think that we,
we very well could run into a situation
where millions of people are almost
instantly out of jobs and there no
solution for that.
And then out of jobs by their choice or
out of jobs by automation,
artificial intelligence.
Exactly their position,
right?
Yeah.
I mean this is a real problem and I
don't think,
I don't think it's gonna I don't think
it's kind of happened slowly,
right?
I think problem's gonna stumble onto us
very quickly.
Yeah.
And we are not prepared for this.
And then there's a problem
psychologically.
People say that,
well,
if you just give people money,
you take away their ambition and their
will.
And one of the things that makes America
great is it people hustle and that you
give a bunch of people money but they
don't earn and they're going to be lazy.
Yeah,
I mean this is the front counter.
I think there's another one that points
to,
if you look at how much,
how much taxpayer dollars are spent on,
um,
like section eight housing or different
affordable housing programs on food
stamps,
on kind of these different social
welfare programs.
How much are we spending on overhead to
administer those programs?
And so would it make more economic sense
to just kind of compile all of those
benefits into one package and just give
people a check instead of piecing it out
through all of these different things.
And would we actually save money as a
country by doing so?
And the argument to,
um,
incentivize productivity even amongst
people that are accepting universal
basic income,
I believe is to let them keep it no
matter what.
So the idea is even if you make
$10,000,000 a year,
you're gonna still get x amount of
dollars per month as universal basic
income.
And you can choose to donate that to
causes of your choice,
but if you're a person who's concerned
that this is going to somehow or another
stifle people's motivation to get jobs,
because if you get a job then they won't
get that money,
which is the case with Welfare.
Right?
Right.
So the idea that you know,
you,
it's very difficult to get someone when
you're giving them free money to say,
look,
you're going to have to work harder and
then you're gonna get less.
They're going to go,
why?
Why would I work harder?
So the idea is,
and I believe Elon Musk is one of the
ones that came up with this.
Well,
don't take away the money.
Like everybody gets it no matter what.
You could choose to do whatever you want
with it.
But the way to incentivize action,
productivity is to make that money just
universally available to everyone.
Yeah.
Is this the universal aspect of,
um,
of that?
Yeah.
You know,
I mean,
I kind of,
yeah,
believe
that.
I mean,
just culturally people.
And we were talking about these young
kids for example,
you know,
I mean they're not getting paid one
thing or another,
but just their drive and their interests
and kind of their intellectual.
I'm a direction,
I don't know.
I think people are,
are,
are not necessarily lazy by nature and,
and I think there's something to be said
for wanting to actually get things done
and I think you,
you open up rather than saying,
well,
we've just got to um,
our,
our purpose is just to work in a job.
You,
you maybe broaden that spectrum to where
your purpose in life is not just to work
good paying job,
but actually have meaning and purpose to
what you're doing with your life.
That's best case
scenario,
right?
Yeah.
Best case scenario with universal basic
income is you give people the
opportunity to pursue their dreams,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
I think that in large part,
maybe the problem is planting the seed
in young people at an early age that
you're,
you're not supposed to just try to make
money to survive that here,
here's your money to survive.
Just what do you want?
What do you want?
What,
what do you,
how do you think you would best fit in
in this world?
Like what is your contribution?
What could you do?
And I think that's,
that's um,
that opens it up into kind of how we
view education in this country and how,
um,
you know,
there's all this,
this drive towards while you've got to
get a college degree,
you've got to do this,
you've got to do that.
But really there's a lot more where
people aren't asking those questions.
Like,
what do you really want to do with your
life?
Asking that that most important question
of purpose and seeing well,
getting,
getting a bachelor's degree or master's
degree or whatever that may not.
That may not be what you want or how you
feel you can best use your time of your
skills and whether it's vocational
training or,
or doing something else or be starting
up a business right away or,
or anything else.
I think there's,
we just have to broaden the spectrum
here so that we're not so tunnel
visioned more.
We're saying,
well,
you're going to have to go $60,000 in
debt because you've got to get a college
degree of which you will have no
guarantee that you will get this high
paying job that you were hoping to get
so that you make lots of money and then
you end up wasting your life wondering
what the hell did I do with myself?
That's a very good point because I think
the system that we have in place is not
perfect,
but yet we're not fixing it.
Right.
We're not changing it.
And College Education is essentially
subsidized and you have so much money
that these kids are in debt with.
By the time they graduate.
I mean I had a friend who made it
through medical school and by the time
he got out,
he owed more than a quarter million
dollars.
I was like,
that is fucking crazy.
And he's like,
when people talk about doctors and they
talk about doctors being greedy,
he goes,
you have to understand that.
So many of them are struggling just to
stay alive.
They're struggling just to pay their own
bills and keep the lights on.
The reason why they want to see 20,
30 people a day and just keep pumping in
the numbers and just constantly,
you know,
do whatever they have to do,
whether it's operations or whatever it
is.
Yeah.
And that they're not considering the
overall health and welfare of these
people and looking at all these
different solutions,
whether it's nutrition or maybe there's
a way to avoid surgery or maybe there's
a way to figure it out.
Always strengthen your body first before
we do this or maybe we all to your diet
and maybe not getting enough sleep.
Let's take that into consideration.
And what kind of pills do you want and
how are they negatively affecting your
health?
They don't have have time for that.
They have another person that's waiting
and then another person that's waiting
and they have to keep those people
coming in because they need that money.
Yeah.
But the bananas it is.
And that's where whether we're talking
about the cost of education,
um,
or the cost of healthcare for that
matter.
When we,
when we look at technology and how we
can both bring down cost and improve
quality in these areas,
um,
I think there's,
there's tremendous opportunity in
Hawaii.
There's a pilot program on,
on the big island right now called
paramedicine where current Medicare
reimbursement laws say that as our emt
is go out and ambulance to pick up
somebody and they will only get
reimbursed if they pick up that person
and take them to an emergency room.
So nevermind if that person needs to get
their prescription drugs refilled,
which happens,
they'll call nine,
one one for that.
They're living out in the boonies
somewhere and they can't get to where
they need to go or if that person needs
to see a mental health professional or a
social worker or anything else.
So this idea of paramedicine that we're
working on trying to build and,
and actually,
um,
changed in federal policy to help
support is,
um,
really look out for what does this
person actually need and not just shove
them into this healthcare system that
drives up the cost for everyone.
And also use technology to do that.
So I was asking him,
okay,
so you're not gonna be able to
physically bring a social worker with
you on all these calls,
like that's not how you're going to
economize your cost here.
He said,
oh no,
we bring an ipad with us.
So was a social worker at the clinic and
then we can dial them in and they can
facetime with the person whose house
that we've gone to,
if that's the service that they need and
they can start helping connect them to
resources.
So that's where you're able to help kind
of both bring down costs,
but also making sure that we have the
services accessible to those who need
them.
Well that's a fantastic idea just to
avoid the trips to the doctor for
rudimentary things.
Right.
But one of the things that Bernie
Sanders brought up when he was running
for president,
and I thought that was very,
very intriguing,
was the possibility of free education.
And you know,
obviously we have public schools when it
comes to high school and junior high
school and all that other stuff.
But the idea of a public full education
through university to your degree,
do you think that's possible?
Um,
I think you've got the.
I think it's possible,
but I think it doesn't get to the root
cause of the problem,
which is the cost of education.
And I think that if you write that
ticket,
then you are at risk of then these
education institutions just saying,
okay,
so if you are guaranteeing x number of
dollars for a student to go through and
get that education,
then we're going to adjust our cost to
make it meet that amount or if it's a
blank check then they'll know that they
have a blank check.
So we,
we,
we have to,
we have to get to the root cause of
these challenges.
Um,
whether it is education or healthcare,
um,
we have to get to the root cause of why
are these costs being driven up so
dramatically and not just say,
well,
we were going to pay for everything
without actually dealing the fact that
things are not affordable as they are.
Well,
how did education get to a point where
you could go bankrupt with any other
kind of debt and you're no longer
required to pay that debt,
so if you have credit card money,
you lose your house,
whatever it is,
but if you owe money because of a
college loan,
you owe that money until you're dead.
Yeah.
That is strange.
I mean it's one of the weirder things
that we have in our culture is that we
saddle these young,
ambitious people with insurmountable
debt,
right?
And that there are institutions that are
really making a lot of money off of
this,
right?
The interest attached to it.
They become addicted to this money and
this is a part of the system and they're
profiting off of it and they don't want
it to go away and somehow or another
they've talked someone into passing
these laws that make these kids duck
with this bill.
No matter what happens in their life.
Yeah.
You know,
getting a car accident.
No,
no longer take care of yourself.
Tough Shit.
And pay that bill.
I mean,
it's really mafia life.
Yeah.
Back into the financial industry.
It's so,
it's,
it's really,
um,
when you pull the veil back on kind of
the crony capitalism that exists in this
country,
then you start to see and connect how it
really impacts people's lives in so many
different ways and how it affects the
policies in our country.
What was Bernie solution for that when
he wanted to institute some sort of a
free education system for higher
education?
What,
what did he,
how did he envision
I,
and I don't know his bill chapter and
verse,
but I believe it was a focused on public
colleges,
not private institutions and that it was
by levying some sort of tax on Wall
Street to pay for it.
Yeah.
That was the big criticism that
everything was going to be tax,
tax,
tax tax.
But an inefficient system is going to
chew up a lot of your tax dollars.
So people were,
were thinking their hard earned dollars.
We're going to go to some bureaucracy
and a bunch of red tape and Horse Shit
and too many people that are working,
doing too many different things just to
try to keep jobs going.
Yeah.
That's the fear,
right?
Yeah.
That's the big republican fear.
The,
the particular.
I mean,
you know,
I think the,
the focus on,
um,
on Wall Street I think is,
is a very specific one.
However,
as you're looking at possible funding
and tax sources.
Um,
but again,
I mean I just point to soundbites can,
can be catch fire easily,
but I'm getting to the root cause of how
we solve some of these problems is
really what we need to do a how are we
delivering education to people?
Why is it that these colleges,
why is it the cost of education has gone
so far up and really in an,
in an uncontrolled manner?
Um,
we look at healthcare.
Why is it that,
uh,
you know,
prescription drug companies can raise
their prices hundreds if not thousands
of percent on lifesaving medication for
people.
Um,
why is it that doctors are not required
to go through any kind of nutrition
training as they get their
certification?
They go through their,
there are medical school.
When you look at how closely connected
diet is and what people put into their
bodies,
to the kinds of major sicknesses that
are rampant in our communities,
like diabetes for example,
you're not seeing that connection where
you have doctors who were trained even a
little bit in nutrition and how
connecting that kind of preventive
medicine and using food,
food as medicine is not,
does not even play a partial role in a
lot of the medicine.
The Western medicine is delivered today.
It is strange,
but is this,
is this the business of the federal
government to get involved in how
doctors are educated?
I mean,
how do you fix that without getting your
hands into everything?
Because obviously we would like to
believe that medical schools know more
about how to raise doctors than you were
I
[inaudible],
but when the government pays a lot of
money to help take care of people and
make sure that they have access to
education,
especially those who don't have money.
And so it is,
it is our responsibility to try to do
what we can to help improve that system,
um,
to make it so that it's affordable and
to look at these preventive health
measures.
I have yet to get a good answer from
anyone in a medical school or in,
in,
uh,
in that field about why eve,
I'm not even talking about you have to
become a licensed nutrition
professional.
But just having this basic education
that will help them better take care of
people.
Why that doesn't exist?
Well,
it's also bizarre that mean it's such a
complicated thing,
especially diet and nutrition.
It's so complicated that even
nutritionists don't agree.
I mean,
you have extroverts in nutrition that
I'm having a bunch of debates coming up
in the future to have them in at the end
of this month,
a one,
a vegan doctor versus a former Vegan
Paleo scientist who believes that organ
meat and in any eating animal meat is
the key to health,
health and happiness.
The vegan obviously believes that that's
not the case.
And you know,
there's people that believe in high
carbohydrate,
low fat,
low carbohydrate diets that are out
there.
It's so hard.
And then there's the reality that every
person physiologically very.
Yeah.
Oh absolutely.
But I mean,
I'm just talking about like the basics.
Sugar.
Yes.
Alcohol,
yes.
Yeah.
And there,
there are folks,
um,
some friends of mine in Waimanalo in
Hawaii who have a little cafe and a farm
and their is to be able to feed healthy
food to their community.
And so one of the things that they do is
they identify people on the island who,
you know are dealing with like 30 plus
year old guy who's dealing with major
heart failures already and who's obese
and dealing with weight and diabetes and
all these other issues and helping
people like him change her diet.
So they provide free meals to them for,
I think it was like three months.
And they have a doctor who's supervising
and monitoring what the effect on their
body is.
And uh,
my friend Malia,
she told me that one of these guys who
came in,
she's like,
you know,
you shouldn't,
you should try to eat more salad in your
diet.
You try to eat at least once a day,
you should have a salad.
And he's like,
oh,
no problem,
eight Mac salad every day,
like Mayonnaise,
macaroni,
Salad,
Salad.
Thought that was legitimately that.
He's like,
oh yeah,
no problem.
Like he really meant it was like,
no,
probably not salad everyday as a staple.
Right.
Wow.
He thought that's,
I mean,
that's what I'm talking about,
the basic level of just like eat foods
and,
you know,
cutting out sugar and you know,
minimizing fried foods,
like those kinds of things.
Um,
we can't take for granted that everybody
just knows this,
right?
Especially when you're brought up in a
certain way or certain kinds of culture,
whatever,
that,
that may not be something that you're
taught and,
but that,
that really does taxpayers,
is that you're going to have less health
care costs.
If you're preventing people from getting
sick,
then you are lowering the cost of,
of highly escalating healthcare.
Right?
And we're also looking out for each
other because there's information that
we're distributing that listen,
you want to have your loved ones live
longer and be healthier and not
improving quality.
Oh my gosh,
you know,
just the time,
get with your family and with your kids
and being mobile and getting,
getting out and around and,
and so you using the example of these
people in Waimanalo,
that's what they've seen with the folks
that they've been able to help is it's
about education and like here's how you
could eat in a,
in a healthy way that's good for you.
And seeing how that is impacting those
individuals.
Personal health and their families has
been really life changing for some of
these guys.
No.
As a congresswoman,
what are the bottlenecks?
Are you seeing that you,
you,
you see in the system that you would
like to change or fix?
A civil liberties is one that um,
I have,
I have and continue to be focused on and
an area where there is bipartisan
support.
Uh,
when you look at a lot of the abuses
that we have seen and continue to see in
agencies like the NSA and,
and in the post Patriot Act world where,
um,
laws were passed,
licensing warrantless spying on
Americans,
um,
that,
that is an area where we still need to
make a lot of changes.
Uh,
criminal justice reform is another,
and this is one where uniquely right
now,
I think there's a moment in time where
you have organizations like the Acl,
you partnering with the Koch Brothers,
very conservative Koch brothers,
uh,
coming at,
at and supporting the same pieces of
legislation to end the federal marijuana
prohibition to deal with sentencing
reform,
to deal with prison reform and to make
it so that we're not constantly cycling
these same people through our prison
systems and that we're not throwing
people into already overcrowded prisons,
uh,
who have no business being there.
Yeah,
those are really important points.
And,
um,
I'm glad you brought that up.
Um,
I've heard argument that the wire
tapping and that the surveillance
program is necessary to prevent
terrorist activity.
Does that make any sense to you?
Uh,
it is,
it is the most often used argument.
Um,
the point here is that it is illegal to
spy on Americans without a warrant.
So if you have somebody that,
you know,
has raised some level of suspicion than
as a law enforcement officer agency you
need,
we're,
we're protected by our constitution in
this way,
right where you have to do the tough
work of building your evidence and
actually getting a warrant to do this.
But there have been a example after
example how this has been grossly abused
and how,
uh,
you know,
whether it's our cell phone records that
were being gathered and mass by the NSA
or other things we're seeing that
because of the Patriot Act,
uh,
they're there the loopholes that have
been created that have allowed these
agencies to exploit that.
There's also some weird rules where like
if you get pulled over,
they can't ask you for your pin number
for your phone,
but they can use your thumbprint to
access your phone.
Hmm.
I didn't know about that one.
See if that's accurate.
Um,
I'm pretty sure it is.
I believe it pertains to whatever the
crime is.
I don't think they could do it if you
get caught speeding,
but I think if they believe that you're
involved in something that may or may
not be a felony,
that they can check your phone and
there's actually these devices that
they'd been selling to police
departments that allow them to crack
into iphones,
which are supposedly incredibly.
I'm sure you've heard of this.
Yeah,
I mean why else would they have that?
Unless.
I mean if you.
If you need a warrant to access
someone's Iphone,
I mean you're going to go to whatever
federal jurisdiction and that's involved
in that.
They would have some sort of device,
but police departments are looking to
get this technology.
How's it go?
I'm accurate.
Yeah.
Okay.
So they can access your phone with your
thumbprint so they can go give me your
hand.
Tulsi.
Bam.
And then they got into your phone.
Oh,
look at pictures of you naked.
I'm not to ignore those and I'm going to
look at this.
Please can force you to use your
fingerprint to unlock your phone.
Like what?
How is that strange?
Who were this?
No Difference?
Well,
the problem is,
and this is good and bad cops are
people.
Okay.
There just you and I and they're just
folks that have a very difficult job and
a very high level responsibility.
But why would you allow them to decide
whether or not they can go into
someone's personal property and view
their information and look at their
emails or their text messages and make a
determination as to whether or not this
person is involved in illegal activity
without a judge and a search warrant.
Right?
That's crazy.
And without cause.
Yeah.
I don't know if this is post Patriot
Act.
Is this because of this or is this just
one of the things that happen sometimes
is that technology accelerates at a rate
where we don't have laws that are
pertinent to that technology.
No problem.
Um,
and there there's some legislation that
we've worked on,
um,
that we are continuing to try to get
past to try to help get that technology
to help get the laws caught up with
where we are today.
Uh,
and there,
there's one bill that we have that deals
with,
with emails,
for example,
where,
um,
you know,
the car it is,
it's against the law to open up someone
else's mail,
but it's not necessarily against a lot
of open up someone else's email.
That seems crazy because the law,
the law was written back when,
you know,
Ha,
whatever handwritten letters or letters
sent through the US Postal Service was
the only way people communicate and it
has not been updated to this day.
That seems crazy.
Yeah.
What are you feelings on private
prisons?
Um,
when you're making money off of keeping
people in prison than you have a
serious,
you have a serious problem.
The fact that we have a criminal justice
system that is so broken that we're
allowing these corporations to make
money off of keeping their prison beds
filled.
We are doing a disservice to those
people,
to our communities,
our family,
and,
and every taxpayer who's paying money
for these private prisons.
I mean,
it seems an obvious conflict of interest
exactly that you have.
No,
you have no incentive whatsoever to
actually,
um,
you know,
help rehabilitate people,
help,
help provide people with transitional
training,
with the drug Rehab,
with,
with all of these other things that can
help people who have been incarcerated
for one reason or another leave and
never come back.
And that's one of the bills that,
that one of the,
one of the good news stories that
actually has happened recently in
Congress was we pass this bill called
the first step act,
um,
that deal specifically with this prison
reform issue to help make sure that
those who don't belong in prison,
like nonviolent drug offenders don't go
there in the first place.
Um,
and to make it so that those who are
there and those who are the returning,
um,
uh,
you know,
there were the returning inmates are,
we're actually addressing what is it
that is that you need to make so you
don't keep coming back.
Uh,
and that was something that faced some
opposition on both sides of the aisle.
But again,
it's one of those examples where when
you focus on,
okay,
we may come at this from different
directions.
Like some folks are more concerned about
the social cost and the impact on
families and communities and how you're
criminalizing people.
Others are more concerned about the
fiscal impact and how much money we're
spending on these people cycling through
our prisons regardless.
We both want the same outcome,
which is less people in our prisons and
bringing down the costs both economic
and social.
And so that was a bill that we passed a
through the house at sitting before the
Senate right now,
but it has support from the White House
and ironically there is a Republican
senator in the Senate who is the number
one opposition against this bill.
It passed like,
I don't know,
there were over 300 members of the house
who voted for it.
Uh,
so there's,
there's some hope there,
but there's some work to be done in that
area.
How did we get to the situation?
How did,
how did this whole private prison thing
happened before people even realized it
took place?
You know,
I don't know the exact history of,
of who made it happen or who you know
allowed for this government contract to
take place.
But I think the sick part about it is
that you have people who recognize that
they could make money off of people who
were going to jail.
I'm sure you're aware of that
Pennsylvania judge who sentenced,
who was,
um,
he was irresponsibly and a wrongfully
sentencing young people to jail for
profit.
Yeah.
And so people would think,
well,
you know,
you're never going to see that.
That's not going to be,
that's,
that couldn't be real.
But this is one of the real problems
with profit,
with the idea that you can make profit
off of having people in yourself.
Yeah.
Having people in your cell.
And when you look at all of the other
impacts of that,
and,
and this is,
this is what I often talk about when we
talk about ending the federal marijuana
prohibition,
is look at how it is impacting the lives
of those individuals who will not have a
criminal record and follow them
everywhere.
Look at how it's impacting their
children,
their family members,
their opportunities for their future and
how these impacts are often very,
very long reaching.
And I'm an impact a lot of these other
social systems and programs that exist
and how much more prevalent these
arrests are than most people realize.
Yeah.
And then there's the economic windfall
that takes place when you legalize it.
Right.
That's the only thing that you're seeing
where these states are voting for it
because they realize there's massive
amounts of tax dollars that they can
make.
I mean,
I think Colorado is 39 percent tax on
recreational marijuana and people are
like,
okay.
Yeah.
Like they just pay it because it's even
then it's still not that expensive.
That's true.
Yeah.
To speak of.
I mean,
you know,
the people who are actually benefiting
from the.
Especially,
you know,
these kids with epilepsy and those with
other medical disorders.
Um,
I've met with families in states like
Iowa for example,
a met with families and met with their
kids who,
you know,
they are breaking both state and federal
law in Iowa where even cbd products are
not legal.
And so they're having to find ways to
get it there and they're trying to fight
this within their own state to change
the laws.
But um,
you know,
these people who consider themselves
conservative Republicans are talking
about this issue that they feel is a
lifesaving issue for their children.
Well,
once you see people that have cancer
that can't eat and they're going through
chemotherapy and you realize that there
is maybe one of the only things you can
give someone that given their appetite
back when you see children that have
severe autism and one of the only things
that can stop their seizures is medical
marijuana.
I mean,
do you realize there's so many different
things that we could help people with.
It's not just about getting high and
there is personal freedom issues that
you really shouldn't be able to tell
someone that they can go get whiskey but
they can't get marijuana because it's
foolish.
Absolutely.
And it's ancient.
I mean it's one of those really were.
We're stuck with these legacy laws that
were perpetrated by people who were
doing it just for profit and mean.
It's not that this is a grand mystery.
The,
the writing is.
I mean,
you could read it all.
Yeah,
we know exactly how it all took place
and we know why prohibition was enacted
and it wasn't enacted to save the
public.
It wasn't inactive because we were
really worried about people,
just people trying to profit.
That's exactly right.
And the same thing is happening now with
this opioid epidemic,
how there are states that have legalized
either whether it's just medical or full
legalization,
there has proven to be a direct
correlation to a drastic reduction in
opioid related deaths in those states
where people have access,
again either to medical or nonmedical
use of marijuana and you see it.
You wonder,
okay,
if we know this and every one of the
leaders in this country are so concerned
about this opioid epidemic,
why hasn't this been brought forward?
You learn about the prescription drug
companies who make a lot of these
opioids who are now making the other
prescription drugs to help wean people
off of the opioids.
And so they're making money on both ends
of the spectrum without really any care
for the person.
They're uh,
and their welfare and their wellbeing.
And people are.
People are dying,
their lives are being ruined,
buy it women.
There's also things that are federally
legal,
like federally illegal,
like Ibogaine,
which has an incredible result ratio in
terms of getting people to kick
addictions,
whether it's alcohol,
heroin,
pills.
There's clinics in Mexico that people go
to on a regular basis to take this one
psychedelic medicine that's been shown
to have radical results.
It's not killing people yet.
It's extremely illegal.
It's a schedule one drug in America and
it's.
It's one of the best examples.
I mean,
they're also using psilocybin.
I mean there was a John Hopkins study.
There's several studies that they're
doing right now that they're trying to
show that there's a direct correlation
between use of Siliciden in these
clinicals situations where they're
curing cigarettes,
heroin,
all these different addictions with
different psychedelic drugs that are
scheduled.
One interest is a lot of work being done
right now.
Maps is involved with one thing that
they're doing that's helping a
tremendous amount of soldiers and people
with ptsd is with Mtma is assisted Mtma
therapy and there's a lot of these that
are being explored now where people had
demonized these particular drugs or
plants and they were thought to be
something that would ruin your life.
Another really realizing no,
these like many things can be used or
abused and that there's solutions for a
lot of our problems,
but there's a lot of resistance to this.
There's a lot of resistance in
particular from.
I mean the resistance about cbd is one
of the dumbest ones of all time because
cbd is addictive,
nontoxic,
not her end.
Massively beneficial to so many people,
whether it's helping them with anxiety,
alleviation of pain and stress.
I mean,
I even got Ted nugent on it.
Yeah.
Ted.
Ted's never done anything with anything
that had anything to do with hamper
marijuana and he's got bad knees,
so I got to rub and cbd lotion on his
knees and he was like,
this stuff's a miracle.
I'm like,
yeah,
here we go.
I mean,
if you could talk Ted nugent into using
cbd,
there's,
there's hope for the world,
but you just mentioned,
I mean,
whether it's cbd and hemp is another
example.
That's something that we're trying to do
in Hawaii.
I think a Kentucky,
I think there's another state that's a
leader in this.
Slowly
but surely the doors opening up with
that,
when they realize it's not psychoactive,
it's incredibly beneficial.
Whether it's for food,
whether it's for textiles,
whether that's for oil.
I mean there's so many benefits.
I mean you can.
There's a thing called hempcrete where
they're making concrete concrete at a
hand.
I've heard about some lighter,
incredibly durable,
flame resistant.
There's so many benefits to it and it's
so economically viable.
It's so cheap.
It's a weed.
It grows up.
I don't know if you ever really felt a
hemp stalk.
It's one of the most bizarre things
because it is as hard as this oak and
it's as light as styrofoam.
It's so weird.
It's such a.
it's an alien.
Plants are very strange plant.
Wow.
But you know,
demonized for so long and one of the
things that's kept it from being
economically viable and it's just people
that don't want it to become a part of
the competition,
they just don't want to compete with it
with whatever they're profiting from,
whether it's the people that are selling
pain pills are the people that are using
it for.
I mean,
it was initially made illegal because of
paper.
William Randolph hearst got involved in
it because he had paper mills and you
know,
he also owned newspaper.
So we started demonizing it to get
people to think that if we made hemp
legal,
we were going to have people running
around on the marijuana Kellen people
and jumping out of windows.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
We have A.
I'm working with a Republican from
Florida named Carlos Curbelo.
We just introduced a bill to essentially
commissioned a study by the National
Academy of Science made up of objective,
um,
reports and other studies that have been
done from states that have already
legalized to one extent or another,
uh,
marijuana to compile a fact,
an independent fact based report for the
federal government on,
um,
what,
what has come about in those states in
every respect,
uh,
whether you're talking about healthcare
economy or criminal justice and law
enforcement,
every single thing,
look at this in a very diverse way.
And,
and to have this entity do it that,
that sits just that sits outside of the
federal government because the challenge
that we keep coming up against both at
the federal level as well as at the
state level in some cases,
is they say,
well,
there are no studies that show the
benefits of what goodwill come about.
If you end the federal marijuana
prohibition as one example in Hawaii
just recently,
the state legislature house and Senate
overwhelmingly passed a bill to allow
opiod addiction to be added to,
um,
the acceptable things that medical
marijuana can treat.
So even though medical marijuana is
legal in Hawaii,
there is a limited list of,
you know,
the ailments or whatever that you can
prove your eligibility.
OPIOID addiction is not.
One of them.
Legislature said it should be,
which I agree it should be,
but it was vetoed by the governor who
said,
well,
those studies aren't proving that this
will help those who are opioid addicts
and there is a bureaucratic process that
takes a really long time.
If people really want this to happen,
what are the other things that are of
concern to you as a congresswoman that
you're seeing not addressed or that are
somehow or another still in place when
you feel like they should have?
Do you know there's,
there's,
there's a long laundry list of issues
and I think you can go through each of
the major issues that a lot of folks are
concerned about and pick those apart and
say,
hey,
here are the things that we need to
address and improve in each of those.
But I think the,
the conversation that I hope more people
start having is about how w why aren't
these things being fixed or addressed
and that's,
that speaks directly to people's
unwillingness to actually talk to each
other to stop demonizing each other
because you're from the other camp and
actually engage based on our common
mission of serving the people,
serving the people of this country.
And you know,
that's something I look back to during
my time in uniform serving in the army
national guard.
You got diverse people,
diverse opinions,
diverse ideas.
But ultimately,
you know,
we were the same flag on our uniform and
we are focused singularly on,
on that same purpose and mission.
And unfortunately that's what we're
missing a lot of in Congress is the
hyper partisanship and the political
winds to often take precedence over the
reason why people in our districts hire
us to go and work there.
And a lot of that comes from not having
a basic level of respect or Aloha for
each other as people.
And instead just saying,
hey,
it's us against them.
Pick your label.
And that's where the battles are fought.
And,
and who suffers as a result of this,
the people who are suffering,
who are dealing with a lot of the
challenges that we've been talking
about.
So that's something that you know,
I try to bring,
I try to bring Hawaii's Aloha to
Washington to try to bring that through
in the work that I'm trying to do on
these different issues,
in the conversations that we're having.
Sometimes it means you talk with people
who who you disagree with or you may
have different ideas than they have
about how you solve these problems.
But if even if you're able to come
together on one thing,
then we can start to see problems
actually being solved in and delivering
results.
Well,
what I saw from you and video is exactly
what I've seen from you in person.
You're very genuine person.
You're very intelligent and you give me
hope.
You gave me hope that there are
politicians that are legitimately in it
for the right reason and that they have
a real vision of how to fix things.
So thank you.
Thank you and thanks for being here.
Really appreciate it.
Thanks so much.
Tell people how to find you online.
I am on social media at Tulsi,
Gabard,
instagram,
twitter,
all of those things.
And uh,
you can go to my website which is vote,
[inaudible] dot com.
Go their vote.
Tulsi.
Thank you.
Should be president.
Aloha.
Let's close it.
Yeah,
there you go.