No,
it just seems the problem with the
marijuana is five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Dennis Mckenna,
ladies and gentlemen,
before we were just discussing how I was
saying that marijuana can be your friend
and it can enhance your life,
but if,
if you take too much,
it's such a seductive little creature
because a little bit of it as like,
Oh,
this is nice,
this feels good,
but if you get too crazy,
especially if you get too crazy with
edibles,
it'll take you and take you away on this
wild journey of paranoia and,
and,
and you'll,
it'll lock you up.
Like some people just need to take a
couple of weeks off,
just relax.
That's always a good idea,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
I think people underestimate cannabis.
I think it can be like,
hey,
couldn't really sort of knock you off
your center,
especially if it's edible and like all
these things,
you got to learn how to use it.
Yeah,
I mean it's basically that's what you
gotta do.
You'll have to learn how to use it,
but you know,
you know,
that's my raps rap,
but it's a great wrap.
It really is.
It's so important.
It's,
I think it's so important for people to
realize that he got to let like regular
you,
like you like natural sober you.
It's important to be in touch with that.
Like you don't want them always be high
or always be caffeinated or always be
anything like.
Exactly.
I mean we're,
you know,
people get,
to these places and they fail to do a
reality check on themselves,
you know?
I mean,
I get emails from people all the time
so.
Well I'm,
you know,
life's been pretty weird lately.
I took mushrooms five times last week
and it's like,
dude,
how about you lay off for a while and
give her a chance because you know,
they tell these stories.
It's like the idea of,
okay,
let's find your center.
Go back to baseline layoff,
the sauce,
whatever it is you're taking and just
chill out.
I'm trying to rediscover your center.
It seems like common sense advice,
but people don't do it.
Does he?
My common sense advice but common sense
is not common.
I think everybody knows that.
Yes.
All you have to do is look around,
realize what is it about people though
that one thing,
dosage in any sort of a minute,
it doesn't even have to be a substance.
It can be an activity like gambling for
instance,
like once it gets in your bones,
it just seems like you're so compelled
to just continue that behavior and and
the idea of stopping is almost more
painful than the idea of wrecking your
life.
This,
this,
this addiction.
This is basically these things are
reinforcing.
They activate those pleasure circuits in
the brain mediated mainly through
dopamine and all of these.
I mean the,
the so called drugs with abuse,
which I think is a terrible word,
terrible,
but
you know,
the reinforcing drugs,
the pleasure drugs work directly or
indirectly through the delta circuits
and the dopamine is like your,
your button for pleasure.
You know,
in the same way that Serotonin is kind
of on the opposite side,
it's your button for more like euphoria,
feeling good but not the.
It doesn't have the punch.
I guess that the,
which is why people can get addicted to
gambling.
They can get addicted to sex,
they couldn't get addicted to
television.
All of these things.
It doesn't have to be substances because
they all hit those same circuits,
you know,
except the psychedelics which don't work
on that reward circuitry.
They work on a different set of
circuits,
but yet even with those you are behavior
patterns can become addictive and then
you can start just doing psychedelics
too much and it's not even the
psychedelics that are doing it.
It's just this compulsive need to
constantly change your state of mind.
Oh yeah,
that's quite true.
And if people,
you know,
the way they use psychedelics is,
is
there are many ways to use it,
but basically use the thoughtfully,
you know,
I mean you can
all the question about recreational use
versus spiritual use versus therapeutic
use.
I mean these are all ways to approach it
and I am not a person who says you must
do it this way.
You must do it that way.
What I do say is do it from an informed
place and do approach it thoughtfully.
No,
because I mean,
in other words,
don't you know,
planned for it.
Respect the medicine in a certain way,
you know,
use it in a circumstance where you can
learn from the medicine rather than have
the medicine be sort of a,
you know,
overlay a but over whatever else you're
doing.
I mean this is something that demands
attention and I think that's the best
way to use psychedelics and for
whatever,
you know,
whatever spin you put on it is that
spiritual as a therapeutic is a
recreational as Shamani.
These are all labeled.
The important thing is that,
you know,
you have the,
you approach the medicine itself.
The medicine is the teacher,
right?
Not The sitter,
not the Shaman,
that's the psychotherapist.
If they're doing the right their job
correctly,
in my opinion,
their job is to let you have your
encounter with the medicine and the
medicine is what you learned from.
They're there to facilitate that.
They can intervene if you get anxious or
have things go on,
make sure you know,
nobody comes to the door,
that kind of thing.
But basically it's to facilitate a
learning opportunity where you and your
teacher,
which is the medicine,
be at Iowasca or mushrooms or whatever.
Can have this intense one on one
interaction,
you know,
I feel like with psychedelics as well as
with all these other
things that we're talking about,
any kind of drug,
I mean even coffee,
alcohol,
whatever,
and behavior patterns,
all these different things.
I think one of the things that happens
with human beings is you get so far
along in your life in these behavior
patterns become so tight grooves that
are carved into your psyche and then as
you become an adult,
then you start to learn like,
oh,
there's got to be a better way to handle
this.
Let me figure out how to do this.
And it's almost like getting a car when
you're really young and not learning how
to drive until you're like in your
twenties and so you're just driving this
thing.
It's smashing into trees and grinding
the gears and then somewhere along the
line you're like,
oh my God,
I'm fucking myself up.
I have to figure out a way to do this
correctly.
And there's two different approaches.
One,
the abstinence approach,
which is very popular.
People say,
well,
I'm,
I'm straight edge now.
I don't do anything and that's it and I
just,
you know,
just do wheat grass and I run hills and
stuff and like,
okay,
you could do that too.
I mean,
you can do it.
You definitely can do that too,
but it's.
I just don't think that there's anything
wrong with any of these things.
I think there's something wrong with the
way we use them and I think it's one of
the inherent problems with things being
illegal is that we can't discuss this.
We don't have people like you or centers
where people can go where people can
become educated on the proper way to use
these drugs or medicines,
whatever you want to call them,
these compounds and get something out of
them that can really be beneficial.
Right.
That's exactly right.
I mean,
I've said this many,
many times that,
you know,
drug education,
what they call drug education in this
country is a joke because the whole
emphasis is on don't use them.
That's absurd.
That's like telling,
you know,
an 18 year old guy full of testosterone
don't have sex.
Come on,
it's built into the genetics.
They're going to go for that.
What you have to do,
what they can bring themselves to
acknowledge in the drug education field
is it's not about telling people not to
use drugs.
It's about teaching people how to use
drugs
if they choose to.
Right.
I mean like any other skill,
people have to learn to drive.
They have to learn to do yoga.
They have to learn to do whatever they
do.
There's an educational process.
I tell people many times,
you know,
my shtick is there is no such thing as a
bad drug and that's another problem with
the dialogue.
The badness is projected onto the drugs.
The drugs are simply compounds with a
certain form.
Ecology.
There's no moral aspect to them.
The moral dimension comes in.
How do people use them?
That's where you know it's human
behavior that's moral or immoral life.
I say,
you know,
there's no such thing as a bad drug.
Plenty of bad ways to use drugs,
but that comes from the not the calm
town.
I've been really disturbed lately by
these new super potent painkillers.
Oh,
it's fentanyl.
All the stuff that killed prince and
carfentanil now,
as the big men say fentanyl is bad
enough,
carfentanil is something like 100 to a
thousand times more potent than
fentanyl.
What?
Yeah.
So as Spec,
literally a pinhead or less of the
Carfentanil is a lethal dose.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
So this is really not good,
you know,
because I am certainly not an expert on,
the sources and all this,
but apparently this stuff is being made
in China imported here and they use it
to cut heroin because it's so strong
that people are dying left and right.
You know,
because of Carfentanil is far more,
uh,
far more toxic than heroin or even
fentanyl.
So,
you know,
we're so,
there is so much,
I don't know,
so much confusing and,
and fuzzy thinking about the whole drug
issue,
you know,
for example,
as long as we're talking about opiates
for the moment,
which is not really what I came in,
talked about.
But um,
you know,
you've heard of Kratom yeah.
Right now the DEA and the FDA.
It's a plant.
It's used in Thailand.
It is an OPA.
There's no doubt about it hits the
opiate receptors and they want to
schedule it,
but the problem is that in Thailand
traditional areas,
it's often used to get off of heroin,
so it's potentially part of the
solution,
not part of the problem.
It's a,
you know,
it's relatively easy to quit and the big
thing about Kratom it doesn't cause
respiratory depression and respiratory
depression is what kills people from
narco,
from heroin overdoses.
It's the alkaloids and Metro Jina and do
not do that and Kratom is currently in
those weird semi illegal states and this
semi legal state,
but the DEA would love to schedule it,
but again they had plans to and there
was some pushback about this.
Some people were saying things like,
I'm saying,
wait a minute,
let's take a second look at this.
This may be part of the solution because
it could be a kind of a in a sense,
and the herbal methadone.
I mean Methadone's not the best way,
but something that people could
substitute and then gradually taper off.
Kratom has some weird sort of property.
We're at low doses is a stimulant.
Yes,
I've tried it before,
but only at low doses I've had,
um,
there's a company that sells it,
that we have it right here.
Oh,
there are lots of companies that sell
it.
Yeah.
His company,
um,
urban ice organics,
that's the name of the company.
Um,
but I've,
I take two or three of those and it's
like a cup of coffee and it's like no
weirdness.
No,
don't feel high that at a low dose.
It is that.
Why is that a stimulant?
Who knows?
Just unique pharmacology.
How strange though,
at higher doses it's a,
it's definitely an OPA.
And is it something that impairs motor
skills?
Uh,
well,
not so much.
I mean just in the sense that it's like
being high on morphine or heroin does.
I mean,
you know,
so it really can give you that kind of a
feeling.
Absolute.
Wow,
that's interesting.
You know,
it hits the opiate receptors,
but then it also hits few other
receptors as well,
which is part of the stimulating effect.
But you know why the pharmaceutical
companies are not all over this plan?
I don't understand because for a long
time the holy grail and drug discovery
when it comes to analgesics is fine.
The narcotic that is not toxic,
you know,
the analgesic that is not toxic,
hopefully not addicting,
but that's not gonna happen.
And is there an ld 50 for this stuff?
Old Short.
I mean there's an ld 50 for most things.
For people in a lethal dose at 50
percent it would be hard.
Yeah,
the full dose for 50 percent of the size
of the sample.
But in the herbal form it would be hard
to get anywhere near a lethal dose.
You have to giant brick of it.
Probably probably you throw up before he
ever got to the league,
if you,
if you isolated one of the alkaloids,
seven hydroxy metro is the strongest one
that's about 100 times stronger than
morphine.
Whoa.
You know,
so definitely effect.
So is there any issue with that stuff
though,
with people who have had problems with
pain pills in the past,
maybe they start indulging this a little
bit too much and.
Well it's a better alternative than the
pain pills.
It's very good for people who want to
get off that shit.
Sorry,
can I say that?
This is the Internet want to get off,
those kinds of things.
They don't,
they can't quit cold Turkey,
but they could go on Kratom and
gradually cut down because the
withdrawal symptoms for Kratom or much
less apparently than for heroin and the
and these things,
they just don't grab you.
So this is a gateway out of the
addiction,
you know,
or they could even just maintain because
it's not particularly dangerous,
dangerous or impairs function or so and
they could maintain,
as you know,
lots of people take heroin and managed
to maintain.
Well I know a lot of people,
not everyone can do that.
They find some really good
anti-inflammation properties and this
stuff,
like people who exercise a lot,
create them.
Yeah.
Wouldn't surprise me at all if that's
there.
Um,
you know,
most plants have multiple effects.
That's one of the differences between
plants and pharmaceuticals.
Plants have families of molecules and
they often have complimentary tie kinds
of activities,
you know,
so Kratom is one of these,
we've known about it for awhile.
It needs a lot more work,
but potentially it's very,
very interesting,
you know,
and of course the other one and in this
sort of universe of,
uh,
of OPA treatment is Ibogaine,
which is not a completely different kind
of thing I will gain is not itself a,
an OPA,
but people use it to get off opiates
because the experience is profound,
but then it does something that a lot of
psychedelics don't do,
which is it interrupts that craving for
opiates depending on how it's structured
anywhere from a few days to a few weeks.
And the thing I think that determines
the effectiveness of,
of Ibogaine as a treatment for opiates
is if the person has prepared for what
happens afterwards,
right.
You got to prepare for what happens
after.
If you go back to your old neighborhood,
your old buddies,
your old habits.
It's not gonna work.
You know,
you're not making a serious commitment
to make it work.
But if you have a plan going to go to
this clinic at this treatment,
get cleaned up,
then what?
You know,
and that's true.
I mean that's really.
I think that's the main factor that
determines whether Ibogaine is effective
or not,
and it is for a lot of people it works.
It's a problematic substance.
It's not,
it's a controlled substance in the
states,
but only in about six countries.
Is that actually prohibited?
Most countries it's either in a gray
area,
I guess it's a gray area.
It's unregulated is the term couple of
countries,
so put it on prescription drugs status,
uh,
Brazil and New Zealand.
But it's the framework is there.
That doesn't mean there's a rush of
people to go to Ibogaine clinics in
those countries.
It really hasn't created a rush.
But the framework is there of people who
want to want to do that.
So I began this,
another one of these that needs more
investigation than is potentially part
of the problem to the opiate epidemic.
There is a rumor,
I will.
They're more than rumors,
but uh,
some,
uh,
Ibogaine activists are trying to get
certain states to provisionally approved
the use of Ibogaine,
you know,
special lever from the federal
government,
Fremont.
And I think New York has now applied for
this because their problem is so bad.
It's like basically they're saying to
the government,
here's something that may work,
just grant permission on the state side
statewide basis to have this medicine.
We'll see where that goes.
You know,
as you,
I'm sure you,
I think we're all in this community
acutely aware of now.
The government is again rumbling about
how they're going to revive the war on
drugs.
I mean,
it was a stupid idea.
The end of.
It's even more stupid now,
but hey,
that's government did stupidity are us
kind of their,
their angle on things.
So this jeff sessions characters real
see how it goes.
I'm not too worried because I think
there's going to be so much pushback on
this.
Yeah.
And that's the other thing about trump.
He seems to be a populist and if there
is too much pushback from that
direction,
I think he's going to try to avoid that
as much as possible when they did a
recent survey of the United States.
And how many people,
uh,
think that marijuana should be legal
like recreationally legal.
It's 60 percent now,
which is for the first time ever.
Yeah.
And states have done it and I just don't
think you can,
you know,
you can't go back to the war on drugs.
I mean,
it was a miserable failure when it
happened.
There's no over 40 years.
They pounded over a trillion dollars
down this rat hole.
There are more drugs,
more kinds of drugs,
easier to get cheaper than ever.
So where's the success and more people
in prison as a result of this.
So where's the success drug?
There's nothing,
there's nothing they can point to.
It's not like anyone was saved.
It's not like,
right.
The problem is that these people,
you know,
facts don't carry much weight with them.
I mean,
they're kind of off in their own private
ideological fantasy and uh,
the fact that the war on drugs doesn't
work,
doesn't matter to them.
It's like these are bad people who need
to be punished.
That's their,
their stance on it.
It's not about anything other than that.
Yeah.
I think that's really important.
What you just said.
These are bad people.
They're really talking in these
simplistic terms.
That's one of the thing that session
said that marijuana is not something
that good people use.
Preposterous grandmas are out there that
are listening to this going,
what the fuck is this guy talking about
this?
This is crazy.
Well,
it is,
and it's clear that,
you know,
not a jot of reflection or,
or,
you know,
careful thought goes into these kinds of
statements.
This is what bothers me.
I mean many,
many things bothered me about trump,
but one of the chief things,
one of the major,
I guess you could say flaws in his
character among many,
but you listen to him talk,
he listened to his general thing and you
realize this is not a man who's ever had
a reflective thoughts in this life.
You know,
there is no there,
there,
there is no inner self,
uh,
you know,
people say,
oh,
just give that man some Iowasca and that
will straighten them out.
I don't think so.
I think there's,
you know,
there has to be something inside to
straighten out.
I mean,
he's,
I think that maybe I would like to speak
to him alone and find out who he really
is.
I mean,
you think when someone's speaking in
front of,
you know,
a big group of press or you know,
any,
anytime there's a camera on them,
it's really hard to figure out who that
person is.
Being alone with someone would be very
illuminating.
I would.
I agree.
Maybe alone he's different,
but he is such a creature of media and
television.
It's inexorable,
right?
Yeah.
So maybe there is a thoughtful person
there,
but I sure don't see any evidence of
that,
you know?
And that's unfortunate.
I mean because that's whatever you could
say about Obama and there's many bad
things that,
you know,
he was not a perfect president.
He was very thoughtful and smart.
You know,
I'm not so sure trump is smart.
I mean he's smart in a certain way,
but not the way that we need our leaders
to be smart,
you know,
in this age we need to,
anyway,
we could go on all day about this and
that's really what we wanted to.
We could go on about this all day and
let's definitely not.
Let's instead,
let's shift gears and talk about this
celebration of 50 years of psychedelic
research and what you're doing now,
and it's in Birmingham.
Hazara is.
It's in.
It's in Buckinghamshire,
England.
I knew it was a B.
Yeah.
One of those places.
It's not.
This is something that I've wanted to do
for a long time.
And what the backstory is that in 1967
there was a conference that was
sponsored,
believe it or not,
by the health education and Welfare
Department of Health,
education and Welfare,
National Institute of Mental Health,
US government paid for this symposium
held in San Francisco in 1967 called the
ethno pharmacologic search for
psychoactive drugs.
And all the biggies were there.
You know,
Shogun was there.
Andrew Weil was there,
um,
shelties,
of course he was probably the one that,
you know,
more or less around whom it coalesce.
But this was a chance for
interdisciplinary people to come
together in a private conference and
share knowledge.
And that was done.
And they published this symposium volume
called Ethno pharmacologic search for
psychoactive drugs,
which was us public health service
publication.
You could get it from the US government
printing office for a long time.
And uh,
but the originally,
the idea was that about every 10 years
or so late,
how followup conferences,
right?
Well,
67,
the war on drugs came along.
The government became embarrassed that
they had anything to do with this and
there was never any followup conference.
Right?
So I though that book that came out was
very influential to me.
It was one of the big influences in my
life as a 16 year old when I was just
getting interested in psychedelics.
So for many years I've wanted to do a
followup conference.
I wanted to do it on the 30th
anniversary back in [inaudible] 97,
but it never came together to do that.
So this is the 50th anniversary.
It's now or never.
And so it's now apparently we are gonna
do this thing and uh,
it's gonna be kind of much in the spirit
of the original conference.
Um,
we're not going to keep it completely
closed,
you know,
because we're not that kind of people.
There's not much,
not a lot of room for people to actually
come to the place that's going to be,
which is this place called tearing ham
hall.
It's like,
it looks exactly like Downton Abbey.
I mean it's a English country house,
beautiful place,
but not a place set up for a huge
conference.
They'll be maybe 10 guests stayed there
and a bunch of people staying close by,
but the point is not so much the people
attending.
It's going to be live streamed on
facebook,
which anyone can tune into that.
And uh,
then we're going to publish the
symposium volume for 2017 that everyone
who presents is going to submit a full
paper.
We're gonna publish that as volume two
will bring them out together as a deluxe
edition.
The first one which is available for
free,
it's in the public domain and then the
one from this conference and we'll,
we'll package them together as a
collector's edition and we're preselling
that now as part of the
strategy for I'm getting the money to
pay for this thing and we're doing okay,
you know,
so I give you the website,
it's Esp d,
fifty.com.
What is done for ethno pharmacologic
search for psychoactive drugs,
Fifty 50th anniversary.com.
And then there's also a facebook page
which were the live streaming is going
to be.
So if you go there,
you can order the book,
you can get the whole backstory,
you can sign up for the facebook live
stream and so on.
And uh,
that's what we're gonna do.
And we've,
I've been very lucky.
Have,
you know,
some people,
you know how these conferences are,
you don't do it on your own.
When I sort of floated this idea,
a lot of people stepped up and said,
yeah,
I want to be involved.
All be involved,
not only people that are helping
organizing it,
but also people that are providing some
funding.
So now we have the money to pay people,
bringing them from all over the world.
There'll be about
18 presenters,
um,
uh,
and some really good people,
some very high profile people.
David Nichols will be there,
Mark Plotkin,
who runs the Amazon conservation team,
um,
a number of,
you know,
those are maybe the two highest profile,
but people that are known in the field
and there's,
you know,
you can look at the website [inaudible]
dot com.
You can look at the program and if it
appeals to you,
get on the uh,
you know,
get on the live stream so that,
those technologies did not exist in
1967.
Right?
So they do now.
So why not let the world in,
you know,
we can't have everybody come to
Buckingham Shyer,
but we can have them all over the world.
So that's the idea.
Well,
I'm sure the response to this is going
to be tremendous.
If you can live stream it and live
streaming on facebook,
it's going to be huge.
I mean,
that's a great idea.
Well,
I hope so.
It is for sure.
It's an awesome use of the technology
because there really isn't something
like that that people can tune into and
watch 18 different people speak and of
course it'll all be documented so it
will be archived,
will generate a dvt out of it,
but mainly it's the ball,
it's the books.
I mean the idea of actually collecting
real physical books might seem like a
quite 20th century idea to people and it
is,
we have to do it while you still can.
I like the idea of having a nice box
set.
Yeah.
But uh,
people don't have to get that.
They can get the single one.
They don't have to do anything.
If they're interested they could do it.
And so,
you know,
thanks for letting me come out and let
people know about this and tweeting it
and so on.
This is all.
This is all very helpful and it looks
like there's going to be a lot of
response.
And then of course the psychedelic
science conferences coming up and we
have,
you know,
the symposium symposium guys there.
They're running the stage at the maps
conference,
the,
a stage in the marketplace.
So I'm going to be on there and they're
collaborating with us to on this
project.
So I'm pretty excited about it.
Now.
How do you organize the 18 different
people that are talking and the subjects
so there's no overlap and so that,
you know,
the,
the message becomes,
stays vibrant,
will it?
It hasn't really been a problem.
I mean,
for one thing,
you know,
I pretty much knew who I wanted to come
and I know what their specialty is.
So I invited these people and they cover
a variety of specialties.
So not really too much duplication.
Everyone brings something unique,
their own perspective.
Um,
you know,
so it's,
it's pretty easy really.
I mean,
the idea of the ethno pharmacologic
search for psychoactive drugs is the
apt,
you know,
we want it to focus on the frontier of
this.
This is still a very active area and we,
we don't want,
you know,
not another conference about Iowasca not
on the,
you know,
and that's all wonderful and I'm totally
behind it.
And in fact,
truth in advertising,
we got four talks on Iowasca,
but different aspects of Iowasca that
haven't really been discussed so much at
conferences.
And then we have,
we do have one gentleman talking about
Kratom,
uh,
and uh,
you know,
a specialist of ethno pharmacologist
talking about that we have,
can alper who is maybe the REC worlds
recognized authority on Iboga or
Ibogaine and from the pharmacology
chemical,
clinical side,
we've got him,
we've got to Dave Nichols,
uh,
we have,
another,
uh,
person,
another,
uh,
phytochemistry talking about Salvia
divinorum.
Um,
so these are things that we're not even
on the radar,
you know,
in 1967.
And that's kind of the idea that there's
been 50 years more work at a lot of work
and never any followup conferences.
So that's the excuse for doing this.
This will be the followup conference and
if it gets momentum then maybe we'll be
able to do number three and number four.
Well,
probably by the time number four comes
around,
I'll be drooling in my oatmeal,
so I may not have much to do with that.
There's going to be some new science.
It's going to kick you right back into
gear.
Let's hope so.
There's a lot going on right now.
Hold it on for.
I think you're catching the wave at the
right time,
Dennis.
Sometimes I wonder,
but you know,
I'm super positive for you.
Um,
what is the status of Salvia Salvia
divinorum?
What is the legal status?
Salvia divinorum is more or less legal
on the federal level.
It's still sold.
I think a few states have banned it.
Uh,
I'm not sure which states how funny that
it's the opposite way,
you know,
most things are federally illegal and
then the states legalize them like
marijuana at least,
but salvias for people to know.
Super Potent Psychedelic,
super potent.
And I'm super bizarre,
very weird.
And I think maybe that's kind of the
built in a built in
protection against abuse because a lot
of people don't care for it,
you know,
it's like once isn't enough.
Never again many pI.
mean,
this is not something that you're likely
to get addicted to,
you know,
unless you're just a very peculiar,
because it's dysphoric,
you know,
it's not pleasant.
Most people find it quite,
quite unpleasant,
even terrifying.
Um,
well,
years back.
But I think one,
one of the,
one of the things that protects against,
if people smoke it,
which is not the traditional way at all,
but again,
it's like it minutes.
The traditional way is you choose a
fresh leaves and it's the sage.
It's some variation of the sage plant,
correct.
It's,
um,
it is a sage or a mint.
It's in the mint family and yeah,
it's called the sage,
but it's really a mint.
I always wondered if there was some sort
of correlation between the name's sage,
meaning wisdom,
you know,
and then this stuff.
No,
just total bum luck.
Some would like you to think.
So I think.
I think Daniel Siebert,
who's one of the specialists,
he has a website called sage wisdom.org
or.com and good stuff.
He's,
he's into Kratom.
He provides,
I mean,
Salvia.
He provides good information on it
there.
Most people,
at least my own experience in many
people,
it's like,
well,
it's interesting.
It's profoundly strange.
And what do you bring back from it?
You know,
that's the question.
What do you bring back from it?
I think that's partly why,
you know,
most people are,
they don't,
they don't seek it out.
Particularly my friends are people that
do like it.
I know a lot of people that do.
Yeah,
I don't.
I only did it once and I had this very
bizarre out of body experience.
But,
uh,
I don't think I took enough.
I had a friend,
Ari,
who took a lot who over the course of 10
minutes lived,
maybe he,
he believes in the neighborhood of five
to six months and in this dimension
where you had a life and he had friends
and he had a job and relationships and
he went through this and came back and
you know,
10 minutes later he's like,
this is going to be impossible to
describe,
but I,
I,
I lived a life I had like this
alternative reality that I went through
for multiple months.
Those,
those kinds of experiences,
believe it or not,
are not that uncommon mountain Salvia,
somebody told me once they had the
experience where you know they were in a
place,
they were like seven or eight years old.
It was Christmas morning.
They were at the Christmas trees
celebrating Christmas,
opening the presents with a family that
this guy had no connection to the team
and like,
what do you make of that?
I mean,
I think Salvia is interesting in that,
in that regard,
in that,
you know,
some of these ones that
don't,
they're worth exploring.
Right?
I mean if you can distort time or
actually go into,
you know,
parallel dimensions or whatever that's
looking into.
I think it takes more intrepid
psychonauts than I am to look into that.
But I would encourage people to
carefully explore this.
You know,
years ago when I first explored DMT,
you could get five Meo dmt online.
There was a chemical company you could
buy it and I bought like a,
like a jug of it,
like a container of it,
like the size of this Stevia container,
which is for people don't know enough to
get high for the rest of your life.
DMT once a month for the rest of you and
that's all you want to do.
By the way,
especially five meo five meo brings you
to someplace that feels like the
ultimate center of the universe and
there's nothing and it's you.
You're a part of the whole.
It's,
it's also no visuals which is really
weird.
Or if it is a visual,
it's like these opaque geometric
patterns that exist in this bizarre
white and you just cease to exist and it
feels terrifying and strange and you
know,
again,
there's no accounting for taste.
I,
I agree.
It is like that.
There are no visuals so that's something
strange about it,
but many people feel like if it puts you
in this void place or the zero energy
point.
I don't know if you've had James Orac on
here.
No.
He wrote the book tryptamine palace.
No,
which is all about five methoxy dmt with
how do you spell his last name?
Uh,
Orac,
O r o c k,
I think the name of his book is
tryptamine palace.
And they,
you know,
his thing is five methoxy and has thing,
Huh?
Now,
uh,
and,
and it's an interesting book.
And now you know,
the Sonoran towed,
right?
You've heard that.
That's five methoxy toad.
You excrete something on like glass,
you excrete the venom,
you actually have to torture the toad a
little bit,
uh,
or squeeze the venom which is in the
parotid glands.
You squeeze it out on a slide,
dry it out,
and then you can smoke it.
That's about 11 to 15 percent,
five mil.
But it's,
it's a heavy hit.
Do they know why this toad produces this
in venom?
I mean,
is it psychoactive when you eat it low?
Who knows?
Most tolds
produced [inaudible],
right?
This is very close to five methoxy it.
And in fact it's named after the toads.
That genus of toads is Bufo,
right?
[inaudible] is found in most of these
toads,
but bufo our various is the only species
known that contains five methoxy DMT.
So it's got this Molech,
you know,
there's a probably single gene mutation
that lets it produced this methoxy
related,
a compound which is much stronger than
[inaudible] name.
Um,
and by the way,
just to caution people sometimes in the
media you hear about people are licking
toads.
That's not going to do it.
No,
they're not liquid and toads,
they're smoking isn't aware that it just
gets,
tend to lick him because they,
they're nasty things that will be,
that will kill you if you look at the
pie,
realized,
yeah,
these cardiac glycosides Oh God.
But pirate realizing it,
burning it destroys all those things so
that,
that it's okay to smoke it,
but it's definitely a dangerous tool.
Lick it.
Most people don't like licking toads
anyway.
That's probably.
Yeah.
That
various fairy tales is that the human
body produced five Meo DMT as well.
Oh yes.
Yeah.
And is it produced in the same area?
Like the liver and the lungs and
presumably the,
the pineal gland,
all of these things,
you know.
Uh,
yes it does.
There's a lot of controversy about
whether,
you know,
these endogenous tryptamines dmt
primarily,
but five vimeo is definitely there as
well until they have a function.
You know,
there is a lot of speculation and not a
lot of facts about whether they actually
have a function.
A,
I mean,
they're,
they're made.
And uh,
you know,
there's,
there's one school of thought that says,
yeah,
they're,
they're sorta like physiological noise,
you know,
they'll never reach a point where you
could actually perceive any effect
because the enzymes,
you know,
think kind of secular insight.
We'll just chop up dmt very readily.
It's so close to human metabolism.
It's not gonna,
it's gonna be very ephemeral in the
system,
even if it is released,
but other people maintain that under
some circumstances the DMT can be stored
in vesicles and neuro vesicles and
released on demand or when some stimulus
leads to its release like stress,
some stress of some sort will go out and
grab that painting that that young guy
sent the guy who has a pineal gland
tumor who makes this really crazy trip
to mean art.
This guy,
I've
this guy,
this guy sent me one of his pieces and
he,
uh,
he has a tumor.
Do you know his name?
Jamie will,
we'll find his name.
I'll give this guy some some love,
but he,
he look at his artwork and you go,
oh yeah,
that's what that is.
You know,
almost like Alex grey stuff.
But Alex Gray stuff is a,
it's art.
I mean,
it's definitely representative of the
tryptamine world.
It's beautiful and fantastic and
amazing.
Right?
But it's art.
This guy's stuff seems like a trip,
but it gets the chaos of the tryptamine
experience is sort of replicated in his
artwork.
Yeah,
that's it.
And so this young guy,
what we'll find out his name,
um,
he,
uh,
he sent this.
I first heard of have this gentleman
from the.
Holy Moly,
take a look at this.
Yeah.
I first heard of this guy from John.
Oh,
Hiya.
Who organized this?
Alex?
A up.
I don't think there is enough.
So I think this is a,
this is a zero gravity environment.
Any way that you want it to be.
This is pretty amazing.
That's amazing.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm waiting for the.
We're building a new studio and when
that's done,
we'll have this up prominently featured,
but this kid's work is just incredible.
Jamie,
see if you could find it.
Who He is,
but he should be.
Is He?
I hope he's healthy letting himself be
looked at by medical people.
I think he's just happy to be tripping
all the time.
This is going to leave about science.
Sean Thornton.
Shout out.
Shout out to Sean Thornton.
Yeah,
there's this work there.
It is.
Artists got cancer.
The pineal gland is paintings will leave
you speechless.
Yes.
They will say,
well,
Sean,
third storton.
Sean Thornton.
Amazing.
Yeah.
His stuff is incredible and apparently,
well,
he's in,
at least in some sort of way,
anecdotal evidence that it's produced in
the pineal gland.
Of course,
the Cottonwood Research Foundation that
Dr Rick Strassman is a part of in his
amazing work from DMT,
the spirit molecule,
of course,
the documentary that you and I were in,
his,
uh,
his work has shown that it's a,
it is produced by the pineal gland in
live rats.
So we know now for a fact that at least
in that mammal,
it's a,
it's produced in the pineal gland,
but that's always been for people that,
uh,
you know,
I went to the Vatican last summer and
I'm,
one of the really cool things was the
giant pine cone that they have in the
center of one of the outer areas.
And I was really lucky to have a very
good guide who is a professor.
And he was explaining to me that that
was representative of the pineal gland.
And uh,
yeah,
it was really fascinating because
there's this enormous pine cone and it's
surrounded by these two peacocks are two
peacocks on the side there where they're
supposed to represent a mortality,
some sort of a strange way.
So I don't know what that whole vision
was supposed to mean,
but he was very adamant that that pine
cone there,
you see it up there on the screen that,
that is representative of the pineal
gland and also in ancient Egypt and a
lot of the hieroglyphs you see that as
well,
right?
Well,
yeah,
pineal itself means because it is shaped
like a pine cone.
That's why,
that's why it's named that.
But I have no idea.
That is very interesting.
Yeah.
Was pretty fascinating.
What was also fascinating was this guy,
although he knew that that was
representative of the pineal gland,
he did not know that the pineal pineal
gland produce dmt.
He wasn't even aware of what the EMT
was.
Right.
So he and I had this really cool
conversation about it where it was like,
what know this crazy Italian accent,
this is amazing.
And he's writing things down and I'm
writing to telling him about strassman's
work and you and your brother and all
these different things to look into and
you know,
there is a.
my wife was rolling her eyes like,
oh Jesus,
not this shit again.
You just have happy taken out in public
joe.
You always embarrassed when she just.
She knew as soon as the guy said,
pineal gland in my eyes lit up and I'm
like,
here we go.
Let's talk about drugs.
Well,
there is a guy,
a couple of interesting people have to
mention in this context.
One of them is a researcher
guy named Ed Frick.
Ska Ska.
How do you spell that?
Good question.
Ed.
F R e e C K S K,
I think I may have to correct myself on
that.
He's a pharmacologist and a
neurochemical,
neuro chemist and psychiatrist.
But he is the one that's really kind of
leading the charge for endogenous
functions of DMT and has good evidence
which has been,
you know,
disputed by some.
I mean Dave Nichols is kind of on the
other side.
He's like,
ah,
dmt.
It doesn't have any internal function.
All these people are diluted,
you know,
that seems to me to be really cocky too.
Well,
I think that it's surprising that Dave
who's a very careful scientist would
have such,
you know,
such pre formed ideas,
very rigid idea.
Right.
There's a conference in the UK at the
end of June called breaking convention,
which you may have heard of.
It's a big.
It's like a psychedelic conference.
Dave and the Ed are going to be there.
I'm going to be there.
Hopefully keeping them up.
I don't want any.
They're going to be talking about this
and doing into Beta on it.
Breaking Convention.
You might tell people to Google that.
That's very interesting conference for
sure.
What makes Dave so confident?
I mean when you consider the potency of
it and the knowledge that that's
produced in the body and then also the
knowledge of the effects of it,
which are just astounding.
Right?
How could anyone say that you know for
sure.
Does he done it as David?
Of course he's it.
Could he do it and not go?
Okay.
What is this?
Well,
I think he does,
but then there's also this very
reductionist side to him.
Then basically just as a pharmacologist,
he says it's never going to reach,
you know,
sufficient concentration in the plasma
to have an effect.
However,
I think he's wrong.
And I told him,
I mean,
I was teasing him,
I was saying,
you know,
I,
I wrote back,
you know,
that famous phrase,
the Arthur c dot Clark once said,
you know,
when,
when a distinguished but elderly
scientists says that something is
possible,
he's very likely correct when he says
it's impossible.
He's almost certainly wrong.
Well,
when you're talking about that,
just general bio diversity of human
beings and how some people.
Let's talk about other human
neurochemistry,
like,
like depression,
like some people are super happy and
have no problem with their dope,
meaner,
serotonin levels and there's other
people that have real issues.
Yeah.
Well there is that,
right?
So just look at that,
the variability of that,
and then also how that can be
manipulated with exercise and all these
other different things that can raise
those levels up.
What about the other thing,
like in terms of like holotropic
breathing or all these different
shamonic breathing and yoga exercises?
Um,
Kundalini Yoga,
which I haven't experienced it and
couldn't let Jonah,
but I did have a very bizarre experience
fairly recently on yoga where I went
into class on a pretty pretty high dose
of cannabis and I started tripping in
the middle of one of the more intense
poses.
It was just something akin to the very
beginnings of a dmt trip where I started
seeing patterns and seeing things moving
and some sort of a.
It didn't go anywhere,
but I don't pursue it in terms of
attempting to make that happen.
But I would imagine that if it's made in
the body and then the,
the,
the effects of it are reproducible when
you take it.
I mean taking dmt is a very few people
was a very small percentage that don't
have an experience when they take it.
Right?
Very small percentage.
Do we know what that number is?
Probably something like.
I mean I would say a wild guess,
but a two percent or something
anomalous.
Why should there be people who don't
have any effect?
I mean,
that's a whole other question about
what's strange about their metabolism,
but it's interesting that you raise this
because a lot of these yoga techniques,
especially Kundalini,
is probably about inducing dmt synthesis
in the pineal or wherever it occurs.
There's also a very
interesting technology that has come to
light.
I just found out about it last summer
called the adage know light.
Have you heard of this age?
A J.
A N a.
So write down on the light.com.
The Sky who's developed this very
interesting fellow.
He's named a guy heroin and uh,
he used to work for apple.
He actually worked very closely with
Steve Jobs when Steve Jobs had next
computing.
So he's basically a computer programmer
and the engineer worked with Steve Jobs,
but then he,
for some reason he decided he had to
move to Thailand and become a zen monk,
which he did,
but he continued to work with technology
and he developed this thing called the
original light,
which he claims induces dmt synthesis in
the pineal.
And uh,
I was at a conference last summer
actually tearing him at this place where
this one is going to be and he was
there.
I tried it a couple of times.
And by Golly,
it's a lot like dmt dealing.
Yeah.
What is it?
It's,
it's just,
uh,
it looks like a floor lamp.
It's,
you know,
nothing.
It's got a,
it's got this array of ld leds on a,
on a holder.
You lie under it.
And if they're just white leds and they
programs that from his ipad,
I guess in different sequences,
but you lie under this thing for a few
minutes and pretty soon you get into the
zone,
you know,
these visuals begin to manifest and it
looks a great deal like dmt.
So them and he claims,
you know,
it's synthesizing dmt and the pineal and
it is very much like dmt would be if
it's released at the site of action,
because you know,
dmt is when you smoke it,
it brings some big body load,
which you have to wear that goofy
outfit.
What's with the orange outfit?
Seriously,
I can tell that they're in Thailand.
I understand that.
The expression of muchness the pious
outfit,
let it go folks just where wear a tee
shirt or whatever.
I would just have to get into a,
you know,
into an econ student to do it.
But I wouldn't do it a couple times.
How many times did you do it?
Well,
I was not there long enough to do.
I did it a couple times and this woman's
setting is,
is just effective sitting as it as lying
down.
Uh,
I couldn't tell you,
but I expect so you lie,
you lie down.
I laid down and close your eyes and know
it well.
Yeah,
you close your eyes.
Doesn't matter because it's coming
through.
You don't have eyeshades on
and usually he's playing some music,
but then you know in me like the
reductionist kicks in and says,
well guy,
this is interesting.
How do you know it's really dmt that
you're,
that you're stimulating.
And we've been going back and forth on
that and how can you test that?
And there,
there are ways to do it,
but most of them involve some fairly
drastic procedures like you can do that
you wouldn't want to do on people
because they wouldn't give you
permission if they had any sense.
But you could do two rats,
you could do something called micro
dialysis,
you can put a centrally,
a microscopic,
a
tube that's absorbed the next to the
pineal and you can collect samples that
you detect.
This is not something that people would
volunteer for.
How about just take,
take your word for it?
Well I just want to know does it really
reduce it or not?
I am not saying it does,
but it's a lot like dmt.
What about hovering something like that
over a sensory deprivation tank,
like being inside of it and having it
hover over your head so you have the
added experience of out of body with
that.
I mean I would think that'd be pretty
intense and not hard to recreate.
Probably not you.
Probably what you'd probably want to do
with that,
this to have some kind of goggles
essentially that could be connected to
his,
to his program by Bluetooth or
something,
so then you're wearing the goggles,
you're in the isolation tank,
but if you just hover it over your head,
if you just have an arm like a computer
monitor arm and just swing it over the
head and so you turned it on,
close the door,
the 10,
close your eyes,
lay back and maybe it has like a 32nd
window or lets you settle in.
You then begins the program.
Lots of ways you could approach it.
That just seems to me doing really ramp
it up.
Now here's the question.
Interesting though.
This is just one of an array of,
you know what you might call
neurotechnology is you know,
or even spiritual technologies.
Maybe this'll make psychedelics
obsolete.
Well,
this is a great way that you could do it
without actually having to hold onto an
illegal drug.
Exactly.
Does.
You're carrying your illegal drug with
you so far,
they can arrest you for that.
Although I'm sure they're trying to
figure out a way that was your brother's
classic line.
Everyone's holding everyone's holding
now with this stuff.
Um,
did you experience the communication
that you get with DMT?
Because that to me has always been the
most profound aspect of it.
Is this feeling that I'm in the presence
of something and then they sort of
telekinetic understanding the words but
not hearing the words.
Honestly,
I didn't get that because I think I was
not under long enough.
I didn't have much time.
So I was only under each time it was
under maybe 20 minutes,
which isn't.
I think if I'd stayed in that place,
if I could settle into it for an hour,
I think that probably would manifest,
you know,
and uh,
Diana is what,
why do you think this,
why do you think would change?
Takes Awhile for the,
for the thing to fully,
you know,
uh,
whatever the term is for,
if it is dmt for the DM t to reach a
critical level where you're seeing that
kind of stuff,
you feel this because it was ramping up
during your experience.
I felt like it was that if I had stuck
around,
I thought it would,
uh,
you know,
I thought it would develop and we've
talked about too,
we've talked about,
you know,
thinking about how to establish that
this really is dmt and other approach
that we've tried is to take a or the
guys tried.
I don't have access to the light,
I can't afford it,
but guys,
it costs about 3,300 bucks,
you know,
which is not bad,
but beyond my pay grade,
I'm going to buy for you for a present,
buy it and keep it.
You're going to buy two of them.
I'll buy one for you and me will
correspond.
All right.
All right,
well now we're going to do that.
I might mention that the guy is offering
a conference special here.
If you don't have to wear the outfit.
Yeah.
No you don't.
You don't.
You'll get a discount on it.
If you go through the facebook site,
which I'm about to put this beautiful,
we can talk about this offline,
but through facebook some portion of it
will go toward supporting this
conference.
So I would love that.
I'm very curious about this because I'm,
I know that I have a good buddy of mine,
my friend Danny,
who's done a Kundalini for quite a long
time and he can reproduce dmt states.
He's actually had dmt experiences
independently of the Kundalini and he
says it's the same thing.
He says he can get there and I believe
him.
I just too lazy or something.
I don't know what it is.
I just,
I'm not inclined.
Well,
I think there's a genetic component,
you know,
I mean like this gentleman,
although he has a tumor [inaudible],
I'm not sure why.
Maybe he doesn't want medical people
poking and prodding him,
but he would be a perfect subject to
settle a lot of issues.
She was willing to,
you know,
cooperate.
I mean just having a look at his
cerebral spinal fluid,
which would be the obvious,
you know,
fluid to sample for this would be very
interesting.
Yeah.
But I could understand his reluctance.
If he has reluctance.
People are drilling into your dome,
Kinda suck out brain juice.
Does it sound fun?
But it is interesting though,
that these compounds are in,
in some way a part of normal human
neurochemistry and why?
Right.
And Dave Nichols,
what does he believe?
Well,
I don't know if he believes anything.
He just,
you know,
he just,
just skeptical that,
that in normal physiological processes,
dmt has much of a function.
What about dreams?
Dreams are a possibility and that's
always been the big one.
Right.
That's always been the big one.
And it's totally plausible.
You'll have to get him on here.
Tim,
explain it.
I would love to.
I mean,
uh,
you know,
I'm not sure.
He just has this idea that I think for
one thing,
I think,
you know,
he's kind of a reductionist guy.
I think the,
all the new age stuff,
the new excitement about the empty them,
hi Neil and all that.
It kind of puts them off.
But on the other hand,
don't assume that we know everything.
In fact,
we know nothing,
you know.
And if it's there,
I think it probably does have a
function,
you know,
it's not surprising that it's there,
it's everywhere.
I mean it's,
it's DMT is interesting molecule because
it's two steps from Tryptofan,
right?
Tryptophan is an amino acid and the
essential amino acid,
one of the 20 that goes into proteins.
So tryptophan is an every living thing
on this planet and there are two enzymes
that are also pretty much universal in
cells that can convert dmt or Tryptofan
to dmt in two simple steps.
You know,
I don't want to get too into the
chemistry,
but basically you remove the amino acid
portion of the amino acid,
you get tryptamine and from there you
add the methyl groups and there you are.
You know,
which is why DMT is a very,
very common in plants for example.
And Anna Animals.
I mean I,
I tell people nature is drenched in dmt.
Drenched is a great transcribe DMT.
There are thousands and thousands and
thousands of species of plants that
contain DMT for sure.
You know,
I mean they haven't,
there hasn't been any survey or anything
like that.
But if you look at the gender that have
a lot of DMT,
like Acacia is a good example.
The Australian acacias are some of the
strongest sources of DMT.
There's 1700 species of vacation,
probably 75 percent of them contain DMT
and I'm sure you're aware of the Israeli
scientists that believe that the story
of Noah,
it's not Moses rather,
and the burning Bush was the Acacia tree
and they think that that was the,
the confusion of all the translations.
And of course the oral history passed
down over many,
many years.
Then finally written down.
But this idea of the burning Bush
delivering the word of God was most
likely in some way a psychedelic trip
induced by DMT and most likely because
of the acacia tree,
most likely the acacia tree,
because that was in the area,
the,
you know,
I mean an interesting idea.
And the,
and it's interesting that the,
uh,
you know,
sort of the way that the burning Bush
presented itself was like dmt presents
itself.
You cannot take your eyes away from it,
but at the same time you cannot look at.
But Pharma,
you don't even know what you're saying.
There was this something that he smoked
was in incense.
I was,
he exposed to this and uh,
you know,
because that will make a difference
because you can't eat dmt because it's
destroyed by monoamine oxidase.
Right.
That's the whole basis of Iowasca in
terms of these Acacias,
you know,
the question comes up also.
We'll.
Okay.
Most of them are native to Australia.
So did the aborigines know about this
and if you look at their art,
it's like,
looks like dmt.
It's very psychedelic art.
I haven't really looked at very much
point to list kind of designs in
aboriginal art.
I mean they're extremely psychedelics if
you could find some of that.
But they,
the uh,
the aborigines,
I think they had to know about it.
They're just not talking about it,
but one possible way that they could
have used it because the dmt and the
acacias is so high.
The leaves,
some of these cases there are two
percent dmt.
Wow.
So if you were to take leaves and throw
them on a fire in a enclosed space,
like a sweat lodge type space,
you could potentially get quite loaded
on dmt.
There's no indication that they smoked
stuff,
but they may have fumigated themselves
with tmt.
Oh,
that completely makes sense.
If you're talking about a burning Bush.
Yeah.
Well,
exactly.
And that's.
How does that make its way to Israel
though?
Well,
maybe this,
who knows,
who knows where anything makes its way.
Anyway,
these folks technologies,
it's interesting.
If you look at the,
uh,
if you look at the new world,
you know,
in,
in the,
in the historical sense,
people have remarked,
why are there so more so many more
psychedelic plants in the new world and
old world,
right?
It's something about people people's
relationship to plants in this very high
biodiversity environment.
People are mucking around with plants,
right?
Like a perpetual question that comes up
is how did they figure out how to
combine banisteriopsis and CITCO trick
to get the activity of Iowasca?
How out of 80,000 species and the Amazon
did they figure out.
Can you guys please,
to the uninitiated,
why,
why that's important with the model you
not?
Well,
it's important because banisteriopsis
contains these alkaloids called Beta
lanes that are monoamine oxidase
inhibitors,
and monoamine oxidase is the enzyme in
the gut that breaks down Dmt,
so you can drink tea with dmt in it,
you can eat it all day.
Nothing's going to happen because this
enzyme will inactivate it.
And that's probably a reflection of an
evolutionary process,
you know,
we've adapted to toxins in our
environment basically.
But,
uh,
if you inhibit that with the alkaloids
from the banisteriopsis,
they're very potent,
very selective Mao inhibitors that
protects it from degradation in the gut.
It can cross into the blood and into the
blood brain barrier.
So that's the basis of the oral activity
and people make much about how they sort
of stumbled on this combination.
Right?
And in fact,
one of our presenters at this
conference,
Manuel Torres as an archeologist,
has been looking at this for,
for quite a while.
If,
and this is a,
you know,
this is one of the sort of Gee whiz
things.
How did these primitive people figure
out how to combine these plants?
Right.
I agree with remarkable.
If you talk to the Shaman and they'll
say,
well,
the plants told us,
but what does that mean?
You know,
and but what,
what is interesting to me in a way or
what I've been thinking about lately,
if you look at the archeology of these
things,
the snuffs that there are two or three
different kinds of snuffs that are used
in South America that contain DMT,
the antigen anthracite snuffs and the
Varroa snuffs,
the antigen anthracnose knifes are
ancient.
We have archeological evidence that puts
that back to 10,
11,000 years.
They are by far the most ancient
psychedelics used in the new world or
these snuffs that contain dmt.
Nobody is asking the question,
what possessed these people to take the
seeds,
grind them up and shove them up their
nose.
I mean,
this is not something that intuitively
you would do,
and yet that seems to me as easily as
puzzling is how did they find the
combination for Iowa Ska?
Nobody's really addressed that.
My first impulse when I meet,
when I find a new plant is not
necessarily to snort it.
It isn't that the place of the
pharmacological daredevil.
I mean there's always this one person
who's out there,
dude,
Jack,
what I found,
you know,
and that,
that curiosity that need to explore
things.
Yeah,
that's exactly right.
Somebody stumbled on this and I think
the same is true of Iowaska.
You know,
because the fact dmt is not that
uncommon truth to tell made a carbon
liens are not that uncommon.
So sooner or later people are going to
stumble on this combination.
Once they did,
then you know,
they share with them knowledge.
It just took time.
Yeah,
it takes time.
Well,
do you think there's.
It is possible,
I mean obviously it's possible,
but is there any evidence that points to
the idea that primitive primates maybe
didn't have this monoamine oxidase and
their system and that or if they did,
they had it in lower amounts and it
allowed more dimethyltryptamine to enter
into the body from consuming plants.
Like is,
is there a potential link between
consuming various plants?
Like we're talking about thousands of
different.
Like you could eat a salad if you didn't
have model amy and oxidase and you've
got,
you can eat a salad and potentially
trip.
Yes.
If you didn't have it right is right and
when,
when you see Jaguars that do trip,
like there's,
there's all this footage of Jaguars in
the jungle eating these plants,
what are they doing?
Well,
do we know or we don't know what.
I'm not sure how much I,
how much credence I put into that
footage,
but it could be like catnip,
like maybe looks like happening,
you know,
but they're eating Bev stereopsis
apparently,
which doesn't have dmt.
It's got the Beta carbon blades but,
but harming alone contained some
psychoactive compounds.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And there are three main Beta car
bylines in baptistery stereopsis.
In fact,
this is what I'm talking about,
half the conference.
My talk is about Beta carbon cleans a
lot of activity.
The idea that they're not psychoactive,
that they're just Mao inhibitors is not
really true.
It's an incomplete picture.
There are a,
a lot of other activities with Beta
carbon,
so a lot of attention recently refocused
on harming,
which is the main Beta Carmelina and
three opsis.
Turns out it has all kinds of activities
that have been sort of overlooked and
now not least of all,
it stimulates a neurogenesis.
It stimulates a nerve cell growth.
This is big news because it's huge.
Yeah.
And potentially it,
it inhibits a,
a,
a kinase which has to do with the
kinases approach,
a protein that phosphorolates things,
right?
Very common.
All kinds of kinases around the body,
but it inhibits this one particular
kinase called our k one,
whatever that means,
but it is associated with the,
uh,
with the stimulation of a nerve growth
from neural stem cells.
This is all petri plate test tube stuff,
but it's not unreasonable to think that
this is going on in the bud.
So if that plays a part in neurogenesis
that could potentially have some real
benefits to people that have things like
Parkinson's or nerve disorders or
exactly maybe ptsd or a cte rather it,
it could add or you know,
especially dementia's like fog and
cognitive Alzheimer's or other types of
dementia that are not strictly
Alzheimer's that are just kind of senile
dementia.
Dementias.
Um,
well I hope it's true because this is
going to kick you right back.
This is my main prophylactic.
You get civility.
I figured if I take Iowasca regularly,
probably going to be okay.
Yeah,
right back in the game.
Imagine if that's the case.
What one of the talks that I listened to
have your brothers from way back in the
day.
He was talking about a scientific
nomenclature related to harming and that
before they,
uh,
one of the recent or one of the early
explorers to South America when they
found this stuff,
they were calling it telepathy.
Yes.
They were calling it telepathy because
it induced these groups,
states of telepathy because rumor,
rumor,
deuce.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah,
I mean if you want to get into the,
you know,
what you could call the sordid history
of the chemistry investigations of
Iowaska because harming and harm ilene
and Tetra,
hydro,
heart and Liza were originally found in
[inaudible],
which is where they got their names,
which is Siri unruh.
Right.
And a lot of people use that as an
alternative mal when they are making it
Iowasca analogues.
So that's how those alkaloids got their
names and then when chemists came along,
kind of all through the 19th century,
they started looking at banisteriopsis
and they would isolate things and they
didn't know what to call them.
Sometimes they call them to let the
theme because of the rumors.
Sometimes they were called a bet,
listerine and uh,
uh,
a hi iin and because they didn't really
know what the compound was,
right?
And then it turned out,
well,
it's actually harming anyone.
Harming was isolated earlier.
So then they got their nomenclature
right.
There was a long period where they'd
never collected voucher specimens.
So a lot of this work was in some ways
useless because they forgot to collect
the actual plants that they did to
isolation from.
It got a little more rigorous.
There was a group,
a couple of investigators that actually
thought to collect the plants that they
did the isolation with.
So then they could document the source.
Right.
I mean,
people think this is not important,
but an ethno pharmacology.
It's quite important,
you know,
for example,
for a long time,
just just a side thing,
you know,
for a long time there was a plan called
dystonia amazonic that was reputed to be
one of the sources of these alkaloids
and one of the components used to make
Iowasca fat got loose in the literature
and it took years to straighten this out
because it's not true and there was no
doubt there is no voucher specimen to
show that this was,
you know,
it was not Prestoni Amazonia got so bad
that shelties actually had to publish a
paper that said Prestoni Amazonia
Amazonian Hallucinogen or not turns out
not,
you know,
so you have to be aware of bad
documentation if you're going to collect
plants,
know what you're collecting.
So the chemists that might come along
and work with that can refer back to it,
you know,
otherwise you,
it's just good science and chemists
don't think in terms of the Botany Bay,
they just have something there and
trying to isolate something from it.
But you've got to be what it helps to
know what the identity of it is.
You know.
So it seems to me that that part of the
world,
the Amazon jungle and are really a
troubling relationship with it currently
is so it,
it's,
it's so analogous to the way human
beings are kind of interfacing with the
world.
Like that's a good way to look at it
there because there's so many different
powerful things that they're learning
about this one area while people are
chopping it down left and right and
slashing and burning and making room for
cattle grazing and all this other crazy
shit that's going on down there.
While you know there's so much to be
learned still.
Well yeah.
And there is a Mrs. This is a good
illustration of,
you know,
our sort of penny,
penny wise and pound foolish.
Less about these things.
There are literally trillions of dollars
if you just want to look at it in terms
of dollars and cents,
which is not the best way to look at it
because after all this ecosystem,
as you know,
the burning of the rain forest,
it's about 30 percent of human global
greenhouse gas emissions.
If you could just stop burning down the
data for us.
Thirty percent,
30 percent,
they figure.
Wow.
But then on the other side of economics,
and there have been assessments,
how,
what w,
w,
what use do you make of the Amazonian
biome to maximize its value?
Right?
If you do cattle,
it's worth so much per hectare if you do
a woods.
Well,
yeah,
it's a big issue.
That's the big issue.
Um,
but the thing is,
in terms of undiscovered potentially
undiscovered blockbuster drugs,
there's probably at least a trillion
dollars worth of undiscovered drugs in
the Amazon,
which will of course never be discovered
because we're going to wreck it and
they're already busy.
Recommend insane amounts of species of
plants in the Amazon has 80,000 species.
Yeah.
I mean there's about 250,000 species of
plants overall,
always revising this number and they
always seem to revise it up.
But between 250 to 300,000 species of so
called higher plants.
And uh,
in the Amazon it's one of the most bio
diverse region,
about 80,000 species.
Wow.
So,
and all of these,
less than 10 percent of this,
not even close to 10 percent of this,
this incredible molecular and bio and
biological diversity has been looked at
as potential sources of new medicines.
You know,
I mean there's a whole area of folk
medicine and folk knowledge,
but to systematically look through these
species and isolate things of interest
hasn't been done.
You know,
a very.
I mean,
it's been going on for years.
There's been a lot of work,
but it's not really touching.
A big proportion of
pharmaceutical companies are not
interested in this.
You know,
interestingly enough,
they want to
know their corporations and despite,
you know,
they tell you they're finding new
medicines that will cure people and help
people to a certain extent.
That's true.
But remember,
the bottom line is profit.
They want to own everything.
You know,
they don't want to share intellectual
property with the savages down there
that are the stewards of this knowledge.
You know,
why should we let these people have any
part of it?
So they want to make everything
synthetically.
They want it all to come out of vats
their laboratories.
But it's totally wrong approach because,
uh,
the frequency of compounds that make it
from discovery to the clinic are very,
is very low,
and when they abandoned natural products
about 25 years ago,
the frequency of drug discovery,
that pharmaceutical discovery pipeline
as they call it,
dried up and it took a long time for
pharmaceutical industry to realize,
you know,
essentially we threw the baby out with
the bathwater.
We need to go back to natural products
because that's where you find the
molecular diversity,
the scaffolds done,
which we can build these drugs,
right?
I mean,
you think of the complex molecules that
you find in nature,
uh,
it may,
that may not be what makes it to the
clinic,
right?
It may be a derivative of that or an
analog of that,
but it's still the plants that give you
the ideas for the structure.
If you can follow me.
It's not that you're gonna grow this
rain forest tree in plantations,
but you can go and isolate a compound,
determine the structure,
and then you can probably synthesize and
the analog.
But the idea comes from nature.
And this isn't part of the problem in
that isolating one individual compound
from a plant that might have multiple
compounds that work synergistically.
Well,
that's another difference,
right?
Right.
I guess the,
uh,
the FDA and just the whole drug
discovery process,
they like single compounds,
magic bullets.
They like the synthetic compounds that
is completely define molecularly and we
don't,
they don't like these all these other
related compounds like Marinol for
instance,
right?
Synthetic thc,
which is not nearly as pleasant for
people who have cancer or glaucoma or
any host of very good,
very good example.
Maryknoll,
it does what it does,
but the multicomponent preparations of
cannabis are much more effective.
That's true of almost all herbal
medicine now when they isolate thc,
um,
it's one of how many different
cannabinoids.
There's,
I think there's about 400 different
kinds of cannabinoids in cannabis.
So when you're getting THC,
you're getting one for
$400.
Lot of other things in cannabis as well.
But I believe,
I remember reading there were about 400
kinds of chemicals and cannabis.
So good example.
Incredibly complex plant chemically,
you know,
and as they all are.
But that's,
that's a good example.
I've never taken Marinol,
but everyone that I know that has said
it's just a pale imitation of what
cannabis gives you.
Yeah.
Well if it's for one particular for one
particular use,
which is what the.
I guess it's pain,
right?
Is that what it's used for?
But even then the people that take it
for that,
I've said that it's not nearly as
effective as just.
This is a good example of the sort of
cognitive dissonance of,
of the FDA and the whole regulatory
thing because for years the FDA has been
saying,
well,
cannabis has no medical use.
There's no recognize medical use.
Oh,
but there is this one drug that the FDA
has approved Marinol,
which has some small amount of the
therapeutic use of cannabis does,
but it's just so incredible with so much
information available today that they're
making such poor choices in that regard
that someone can't step up and logically
address this thing and say,
look,
we're.
You're getting a fraction of the
benefits of this just because of this
bizarre need that human beings have to
patent things,
to own things.
Right.
And it's not,
the plants can't be patented and they
can be formulations.
Cam,
uh,
I think,
gw pharmaceuticals which has brought up
sativas sits standardized a cannabis
preparation that you take orally as a
mouth spray.
So it's a natural product.
It's patented,
it has all the cannabinoids are well
characterized.
It's essentially a standardized extract.
So that sort of represents where this is
going.
Well that's a positive.
That's a positive branch of it.
Right?
That's a good thing.
That more reflects what cannibus should
be as a medicine.
And so it's essentially all the
properties of cannabis and what they've
patented is the formulization,
is that what it is?
They've had that the formulation?
Yeah.
And probably the use as well.
That's another way you can get patents.
So how is that formulation?
You need to know that.
I couldn't tell you.
It's just,
it's an oral aerosol sprays.
So there's issues that come up with.
Is that it?
That's a company called jumbo.
Makes us spray.
Okay.
Yeah,
it's awesome.
it's similar.
It's similar to that.
It's a,
yeah,
it's an oral,
it's an oral aerosol and insurance.
Well,
well standardized in terms of what
cannabis cannabinoids are in there,
I think they brought it out initially
for a
multiple sclerosis that was the
treatment and then for seizures and
they're gradually expanding,
you know,
I mean,
it's interesting how marijuana has gone
from,
you know,
this sort of reviled drug of abuse to
now it's the medicine of the future.
That's a good thing.
I mean,
I think,
I think that,
uh,
I think it does have a lot of
applications and why it should be
illegal.
There's no reason for this,
you know,
but obviously there is,
it's in someone's interest to keep it
illegal,
but that would be my only concern with
this patented formula formula that
they've sort of figured out is that
other people can't make a formula as
well as like in patenting.
Do they own the process?
Like what if it's a very obvious
process,
like,
you know,
like the IOWASCA process.
It's a very obvious process.
The monoamine oxidase inhibitor along
with the plant that contains dmt boiled
down,
everybody knows how to do it.
If somebody figures out a way how to
patent that,
does that,
does that become a real problem?
And that they own the rights to
something that's been around forever?
It does,
it does become a problem.
And,
uh,
I'm with,
as you say,
with something like that where,
you know,
it's pretty obvious how you do it.
It's not that complicated.
There's no innovative technology there.
There's no,
there's no art.
There's no art of innovation,
which is what would make it patentable.
There were attempts to patent Iowasca a
few years ago and it got to,
you know,
what actually it was patented and a
delegation of indigenous healers from
Ecuador,
Colombia,
and Peru came to the US patent office
and petitioned against this and said,
we've been using this medicine for
thousands of years.
How is it that,
oh,
it was a guy named Lauren Miller who
really didn't know what he was doing.
I forget what his company was.
This was when I was still doing my
postdoc at Nih.
So this was like mid eighties.
He tried to patent that.
Then what it turned out was it was a
completely specious patent.
Uh,
it was a patent on a particular strain
of banisteriopsis that he collected that
had an anomalous flower color,
I think.
And that was the basis of the patent
will.
That's absurd because flower color is
highly variable.
It was,
it was a useless patent in every
respect.
So yeah,
the Patent Ofa Office overturn the
patent as they well should have.
And then I believe it was reinstated for
some reason.
I haven't really followed this up,
but I think by that time everyone kind
of came to the conclusion that it was,
it was absurd.
There was no reason to do it and he
didn't really have the resources to
develop it.
So.
And he was not a,
you know,
he lost a lot of respect because it's
not so much that you can't,
I mean the intellectual property thing
is the real issue,
you know,
if you.
And that's why the pharmaceutical
companies want to stay away from
traditional medicines by and large
because it's like,
you know,
the enthesis people are,
that are the stewards of the knowledge.
They know how to use the plant.
They maintain the plant,
their habitat,
you know,
it's where the plant is found.
I'm so they rightly should have a place
at the table,
you know,
if you're going to commercialize this
traditional medicine,
they should get something back isn't
traditionally we've been ripping things
off from indigenous people for a long
time.
It's called bio piracy.
Right.
And that's how they operate generally.
So that's an issue,
but there are ways to address that.
Just basically,
you know,
come to terms with it and acknowledge
that their knowledge does count for
something and they should have,
they should have a part of the,
of the proceeds.
If you build a map,
if you make a billion dollar drug out of
this,
you should be able to give something
back to indigenous people.
You know.
So it's complicated.
It does seem complicated.
It also seems like when you,
when everything becomes commercial,
it becomes,
is it like when you look at the idea
that pharmaceutical drug companies at
all,
when you look at a corporation and you
think of this idea of infinite growth
and this is what they're subscribing to
and the constant trying to make more and
more money and then you,
you think about compounds and compounds
being legal and them trying to figure
out a way to market these things.
It seems to become.
It seems to be a big issue that we're
relying on that at all.
It's almost like the tail of the
Scorpion and the frog.
The Frog says,
tells the Scorpion,
Hey,
I'll give you a ride across the river,
but do me a favor and don't sting me
because you deal with both drowned and
then halfway through the Scorpion
stings,
the frog goes,
what the fuck?
And the Scorpion goes,
hey man,
it's my nature.
It seems like the nature of these
corporations is just to make money.
So relying on them to bring these
intense psychedelic compounds to the
market or to even saying the market's
terrible word,
to just bring them to daily use or bring
them to the.
Making them free to use.
I think the corporations,
you know,
as you say,
their main job as they,
as they see it though,
they don't say so in public is basically
they'll make money,
you know,
to patent these compounds and making
money and make more money every year.
And the best way to know there's no
revenue model,
psychedelics,
there's no way for them to make money
according to that mall is a way to not
make money.
Don't give that guy who's got a leaf
over his dick,
a billion dollars,
that guy,
he's been happy shooting arrows at
monkeys for 10,000 years.
That's kind of.
Yeah,
it's just not.
So they're not going to do that if they
don't have to.
Well they won't.
And you know,
these are,
they want these psychedelics if you use
them therapeutically,
these are things you might take a few
times in your life.
They want drugs you take four times a
day for the rest of your life.
That's the revenue model and the revenue
model,
if there is one with psychedelics is not
that because they have to be used in a
context,
you know,
set and setting,
right.
The revenue model,
if there is one,
is to have centers to have places you
can go and take psychedelics in a
controlled setting.
They won't look like clinics.
They'll look like spa was,
you know,
I mean,
take the family for a weekend and have a
nice,
you know,
silicide when vacation while you're busy
getting your massages and doing yoga and
whatever.
That's how it's gonna work if it,
if it's allowed to go forward.
That's the model.
Uh,
yeah.
Well,
we'll see.
I mean,
I've often said the very idea that you
could patent or prohibit a plant is
absurd.
It is absurd.
Especially one that's nontoxic.
What is not patented is prohibited.
That's,
that's,
that's the way they approach in most
circumstances,
which were real weird,
is that we give these caveats to
religions.
Like that's what's going on now with
Iowasca is that there are some companies
that have had an exemption through the
supreme court.
Right?
I shouldn't say companies,
but it basically that's what they are.
There are churches,
there are churches,
which is really just another way of
saying a company out there to their
institution.
So the question is,
and now people are beginning to sort of
recognize this or,
or ask the question,
so you've got your,
you've got the UDP,
which is one of these churches that's.
They're the ones that took their case
all the way to the Supreme Court and got
approved unanimously under actually the
first case that John Roberts decided
after he became chief justice.
So very conservative court that
unanimously ruled that yes,
the udv is a real religion,
which is fascinating.
They have the right to use it well.
It clearly is a real religion.
It is a real religious.
Just fascinating that a conservative
court would have,
would almost be boxed into doing that
because of their views on Christianity.
Exactly,
exactly.
They couldn't not do it.
And then the central dimey same thing.
They didn't have to go all the way,
but essentially they have the same
approval and they're piggybacking on
this and it's their Christian based
religions as well.
Yeah,
well they're Christian race religion.
So now the question is when you go to
Peru,
there's Iowasca.
It's used.
It's not as institutionalized.
It's kind of idiosyncratic.
You know,
you've got these practitioners that the
traditionals called vegetal small.
There's no institution,
there's no.
There's no doctrine.
There's no hierarchy.
There's no.
There's just freelance practitioners.
Question is,
is that a religious activity and should
it be protected and this is what some
smart lawyers are now addressing with
the use of Iowaska in the more
traditional way.
I tend to have essentially taken that
they've appropriated that tradition and
they say,
well,
we want nothing to do with these digitas
people.
Sorry.
This is our religion.
You know,
it's our sacrament.
They don't even.
They get upset if you even call it a
drug or a medicine.
To them it's a sacrament.
That's fine,
but elsewhere it isn't medicine,
but it is also a,
you know,
a religious activity of visually smell
has a spiritual aspect.
It should be regarded as a religion.
We'll see where that goes.
It's almost like with the UDV and these
other churches that what they've done is
they've used this scaffolding of
Christianity as a Trojan horse
that's allowing this Iowasca to get
through.
Strassman was telling me his experience
with it,
with them where they were all wearing
golf shirts and they have uniforms and
they're taking these insane doses of
super potent Iowasca and you know,
and then they're all singing and singing
songs about Jesus and strassman has like
a really like very mellow and easygoing
guy.
Really pleasant guy.
He was explaining how he sat down with
these people in the morning after all
this is over.
It's like,
what the fuck are you people doing?
Browser raised and he's taking about his
trip from the night before.
He's like,
these people are taking like super
potent doses of IOWASCA and they're
singing about Jesus with golf shirts on.
It's like what the F,
you know,
they have like plastic folding chairs
and shit and like on furniture and it's
like,
what the fuck is this?
What it is is it's a religion.
It's a religion,
that's what it is,
you know?
Um,
but I think it's okay.
Read it away,
spread it and spread it on.
I mean,
the thing is I,
I worked,
I haven't had much to do with central
Thai May.
Not that I just haven't had the
opportunity nor am I particularly
interested in going to ceremonies where
I am told that I have to dance the
whole.
Not My thing,
but I know the UDP well,
you know,
because we did the biomedical study with
them and the nineties.
So they're wonderful people.
They're very kind,
you know,
their families are good.
They're very nice people.
But I would never join.
They asked me to join.
I said,
look,
I don't do cults.
I'd be happy to come drink with you
anytime that religion or the Groucho
Marx one said,
I think to paraphrase him,
I would never be a member of any group
that would have me.
Yeah,
that's pretty much what I told them.
You know,
you don't want me heritage by nature,
but I'm happy to share your brew and
they do make fine brood.
No.
Does your organization tweeted out for
you?
But I'm not showing up at the
stockholders meeting.
I'm not good at joy,
but it seems to me with my experience
with dmt that it's so powerful and so
profound that I wonder if that's a way
that Christianity works.
You know,
like this idea of Jesus and the saints
in Heaven and God and all these
different manifested deities,
like people thumb their nose at it and
say it's ridiculous and preposterous,
but everything on Dmt is ridiculous and
preposterous and I wonder if under the
guise of the UDV and they're singing,
they're dancing,
if Jesus is real in a sense that you can
actually communicate with a thing that
takes the form of Jesus.
In that sense,
I wonder what they're seeing.
I mean,
I really wonder if they're going.
The whole idea of psychedelics for the
non initiated is a big
part of it is how you're going into the
experience set and setting and also your
mindset.
Also the,
the state of mind that you approach
these things can greatly affect your
experience.
Hence bad trips for people that have an
unstable psychological state of mind or
they try to fight the experience.
I really wonder if these people are
embracing the,
all the beautiful concepts of
Christianity,
the love,
the,
the family idea,
that blood brotherhood,
the,
the idea of brothers and sisters
together in this sense of unity and love
of the creator.
If this under this idea,
if Christianity is actually an effective
approach.
Well,
I think,
I think what your experience,
you know,
it is not confined to Christianity.
What you articulated is just basically
kind of the characteristics of a
religious experience or spiritual
experience without necessarily tying it
to Christianity.
I mean love,
compassion,
respect for each other.
You know,
I mean,
these are elements of a,
uh,
kind of the,
well,
I don't know what you call a generic
religion.
These are elements of the religious
experience.
The interesting thing about the UDV and
these other churches is that they have
actually created a structure where this
can happen.
Whereas most religions,
the last thing they want you to do is
have an actual religious experience.
I mean,
it's all made.
It's all set up to make sure that
doesn't happen because it just
experiences are dangerous as a very
profound thing.
You just said that most religious,
the last thing they want is for you to
have a real religious experience,
so it's all set up to make sure that
doesn't happen.
Only the priests get to have it or that
was the original thing,
and then of course they don't have it
either because they're,
you know,
I mean it's gotten a ways from that I'm
missing is that that they original idea
of the rules of Christianity might have
come from that.
The Moses and the burning Bush,
these ideas that are passed on,
love thy neighbor,
all that stuff might have been from that
very experience.
Might've been from that various that
experience.
But the thing is,
and this happens,
it's not just Christianity,
it's like it's like any powerful
spiritual technology.
Anything that is numinous,
right?
I talk a lot about the mysterium
tremendum,
right?
The DMT,
the psychedelic experiences,
a mysterium,
tremendum,
something that is mysterious,
tremendous,
terrifying,
spiritually powerful and must be
controlled,
right?
I mean,
it is.
All those things.
It's too powerful.
So in these,
in these power structure,
there's always someone who says,
who wants to sort of put a collar around
that,
put a lasso around that to seize the
reins if the,
if you will,
there's a temptation to grab it and use
it for your own purposes,
which is usually a man usually.
I don't know if any women women don't
seem to be,
you know,
that it's not in built to do the
dominance thing,
but there's very often a male figure who
can take it.
Any spiritual technology coopt at to
their purpose,
you know,
which is often sex or money or power or
all of those things.
Yeah.
That's always a man.
Now of course it's a man,
dammit.
Why do we suck?
We just do,
you know,
I mean,
that's why there's 7 billion people
because we're sneaky and we get your
pregnant.
Okay.
Sorry.
That's pretty much yet.
We're not,
we don't want to be like this ladies.
It's not our fault God,
but it's always a man.
It really is always a man.
I mean,
there's no arguing with it,
you know?
So you get this all the time,
you know,
in,
in any kind of quote unquote spiritual
tradition that happens in the,
in the IOWASCA thing,
as we know,
you know,
it's not uncommon to sexual abuse
sort of very common lately,
lately more and more so you hear these
stories of these guys.
Um,
my friend Amber Lyon,
had it had happened to her,
like on one of her first experiences,
Scott was groping her and where she was
under and she's realizing what's going
on and just realize like,
this is probably how some of these
people sort of like,
they found this technology and you can
call it technology if you want,
but this,
this pathway to this incredible
experience.
They provide it to people,
but they're not really much in into
taking that journey themselves really
into exploiting this thing for financial
gain and for power and influence.
That is what it's morphed into now that
there's the tourism phenomena and all
that stuff.
So yes,
they see it as a way to,
uh,
to exactly that,
to power influence and money,
which just illustrates,
again,
it's all about,
there's nothing inherently good or bad
about these technologies.
There
can be a wonderful thing if it's used
properly.
That can be a really terrible thing.
It's all about the use you make of it,
you know,
the moral dimension that comes with,
with how you use it,
you know,
I mean there are ios scarecrows that
have no,
I,
I say they don't listen to their
medicine since they,
they do these things,
they're not really absorbing the lessons
that they should be getting from the
medicine.
Others do listen to their medicine and
they're,
you know,
it's
not so easy to sort out who's the good
ones and who's the bad was sort of like
what you were talking about,
these people that have this simplistic
idea that all you have to do is get
Donald Trump high on dmt and he's going
to see the light.
That's not necessarily the case,
not necessarily the case.
I think it would be wasted on him.
I think we would have to do at least at
least an indwelling catheter,
maybe three hours of continuous
infusion.
Wrong,
wrong term,
intravenous,
but it's very,
very freudian decided to go through his
dick.
Right.
That is hilarious.
Not that we'll.
We'll,
we'll go through the vein.
No,
man.
I think he might have nailed it the
first time.
Might be the way to get it,
but maybe the way to get it to them as
some perfect Russian robot fucked off.
Just locks them up and you know.
Right when he gets inside.
There you go.
She gets them in full guard.
Locks them in place and catheter.
Like delivery.
Wow.
Yeah.
Maybe they can program at like,
like Dmt,
like little nanobots that go right
through the hole,
right through the penis hole,
right into the system.
They just run out of her right in there
and he's whole.
You just takes off.
But again,
there has to be something.
Somebody animated that have an effect.
Please.
So many anime.
I know there's somebody out there that
wants to do it
the way to do it.
Just some perfect,
super hot.
10 Russian hooker looking chick.
No offense to Russian hookers,
right?
Or Donald Trump or Donald Trump even.
Look,
Donald Trump was a baby at one point in
time.
You know,
and you and I,
we both have children.
We know this.
It's a delicate process of turning an
adult,
uh,
making it an adult out of a child.
A lot of factors come into play,
but almost all babies are born well.
They'd certainly have their own
personality in many ways,
a blank slate.
And so they're in a lot of ways,
a victim of the environment that they're
raised in.
And that's one of the weird things that
I've developed in my own self over the
last few years is just thinking about
people as babies.
I think if everyone has a baby now,
since I've had kids,
I don't,
I mean obviously I think of them as
being adults,
but I think of them as an adult that
used to be a baby.
And I never used to do that before I had
children.
I used to think of people as being a
static state.
I mean,
you and I go,
well,
this is Dennis Mckenna.
This is how Dennis Mckenna has always
been,
and now I go,
oh,
Dennis used to be a little boy,
you know,
Dennis was a baby.
He used to,
you know,
and then he saw a lot of songs and a lot
of things,
but you know what I mean?
Yeah.
Like trump,
he's almost as much of a victim as he is
a perpetrator in a way.
He is.
Trump's a good example of somebody.
I mean in some ways he's still a child.
Yeah,
I know.
He never
really grew up.
I mean that's part of the problem and
everyone,
because he has so much power and money,
everyone kowtows to his impulses,
but you know,
I mean somebody like jared and Ivanka or
maybe a stabilizing influence on him,
old or older,
even though I'm sure their agenda is
totally evil as well.
Confused.
No,
they definitely don't deserve the amount
of power that they're wielding,
nor does anybody.
What's more fascinating about him than
anything is that what he holds up to the
golden standard is success,
right?
I mean this is the guy that,
you know,
everything has to have his name on it.
So trump this and trump that,
and if you looked at the great American
vision of success,
it's to become some sort of super rich
ultra billionaire,
but even though everybody knows he's the
super rich ultra billionaire,
he still is deceptive about his own
success.
He still has to lie about it.
He still has to distort it far past,
whether it's the numbers that came to
the inauguration,
whether it's the numbers that he won the
electoral college by.
He lies about all these different things
and it's an.
It's inherent.
It's a part of him.
This intense lack of satisfaction with
any result,
even if it's winning by a mile,
he must win by 100 miles.
Right?
You know,
and that's childish.
That's like an intense,
but it's that same intense
dissatisfaction that's inherently very
dangerous in a leader because it's
leading him to make these,
these critical judgments that aren't
based entirely unreality,
but rather what he wants people to
perceive.
Right.
That,
that's quite right.
I think that's dangerous.
That's what we were saying before,
no thoughtfulness,
there's no thoughtfulness and the man,
there's no reflection,
reflection,
a lack of humility.
So this is a,
this is not what you want in your
leaders because we see what's happening.
Like,
no,
he's going back and forth with the
Soviets is going back and forth with
North Korea and it's like a schoolyard
spot,
you know,
but these people have nuclear weapons to
throw.
So we need to back off from that.
Donald,
you know,
it's just.
But he can't do that because he has to
respond.
He has this impulse to respond.
I mean,
I think that,
uh,
you know,
I don't know.
I mean if he's not going to be exposed
to,
I was pretty sure unfortunately because
it would help him and you know,
what,
what is disturbing to me.
Many things about donald and this sort
of reality distortion and has created
his people,
you know,
they take it seriously.
I mean they're sort of like intimidated
by it.
Not enough people are standing up and
saying,
well this is not true.
This is not true.
You're completely diluted about this
here.
You know,
I mean there's a some sort of impulse to
show some respect
when no respect is,
is do you know,
respect for the office,
for the office,
for whatever,
some,
but then when he comes out with these
things that are obviously not true,
I'm sorry,
there are no alternative facts.
Alternative facts are lies as our candy
coating of Bullshit alternative facts is
the muscle areas,
candy coating of bullshit ever.
My,
my hope is that we get through this
without nuclear war and then we realized
that we can't have a fucking president
and the idea of having one alpha champ
run the entire group of 300 plus million
people is insane and it doesn't work
when you have technology,
when you have this ability to
communicate instantaneously,
globally with everybody constantly.
It's just,
it's an archaic idea that served its
time but needs to be revamped.
How would you do that?
That's a really good question.
You know,
I'm not the guy to be the architect of
the future civilization,
but I would think that putting as much
power as we put into one individual is
insanely problematic.
It's just you.
You're dealing with all these ego
issues,
decision making issues,
and also the camps that two separate
camps,
the right left camp.
That's crazy too.
Right?
Right.
No,
I mean I think one way to approach it
wouldn't have to be such a such a
tremendous shift from what we've got
would be to go to a parliamentary system
like Canada has,
for example,
where you represent your party and if
the other party gets enough,
they can vote,
vote you out without going through the
whole impeachment process.
There is no impeachment process.
The parties can form a coalition and
vote the prime minister out,
you know,
and it's much easier to topple a
government and in some ways that's a
good thing.
You know,
it's more resilient and Canada's a good,
you know,
there are many parliamentary
democracies,
but that's the one that's closest.
I think there's also an issue with
dealing with the real problems of the
world in
the time where they're the realities of
say Syria,
what's going on over there are so
horrific and they're so far removed from
the realities that we deal with here.
You,
you almost need to have someone who has
some sort of experience with those
people in those lands to understand and
put it into perspective and I think
we're entirely lacking of that
perspective.
Like in terms of our culture,
I don't think we understand what a
brutal military military dictatorship is
like.
I think we see it on television and it
seems almost too abstract,
but the president has to deal with that
in a,
in a very real way
and no one person can,
but that's what advisors are for.
Exactly.
But if you don't have good advisors or
if you choose to ignore them,
then you're in deep shit.
Right?
I mean,
I mean donald appoints advisors who
already share his delusions of course.
So there's nobody there to say,
wait a minute,
you're wrong.
You know,
and based on experience and expertise
and all this,
you're wrong and you need to rethink it.
That's what bothers me about one among
many things about the way that he
proceeds.
I mean,
the thing that bothers me most about the
change in administrations is that they
basically looked at climate change.
They said,
we don't believe it.
It's not happening.
We're not.
It's not even on the table,
and actually that needs to be the thing
on the table.
That should be the primary thing we're
talking about.
All this other stuff is important,
but we're talking about the accelerating
changes that are,
that are essentially under,
under mining the mechanisms that keep
the earth habitable by life.
This is a pretty important issue.
And to have people that say,
well,
it isn't.
We don't believe in climate change.
Well I'm sorry,
climate change is real.
I don't care what the fuck you believe
it is real and free for this
administration to not only ignore it,
but then roll back all these other
measures that were put into place is a,
you know,
it's just the stupidest idea.
I couldn't imagine not just roll back,
but removing the funding for monitoring
removing is really scary.
Suppressing the inflammation and all
this.
So,
you know,
if you look at the people in the,
in the trump administration,
they're either from the energy industry,
Rex Tillerson,
you know,
I think the government has become
essentially a subsidiary of Exxonmobil
and not the other way around.
And so,
you know,
that's uh,
that's what they're doing.
And that's terrifying.
You know,
it's Goldman Sachs or Exxon Mobil.
I mean,
corporations around the world.
We've known this for a long time.
Governments are just,
puppets does this.
In some ways it's just too eerily
parallel to what we're talking about,
what the rainforest,
like with all these,
all this potential in the rainforest and
almost this race,
the race to see like,
can we get to these incredible new
plants that we haven't discovered
before?
We fuck it up by cutting down all the
hardwoods and burning all the forest.
Can we get to this potential future
utopia of people being able to read each
other's minds.
Being able to communicate simultaneously
all throughout the winter,
understanding each other regardless of
language.
Can we get to that before we blow up,
before we
get into a nuclear war with North Korea?
And it is crazy shit,
right?
This insane administration that's
existing in this sort of chaotic manner
alongside some of the brightest minds
and most innovative people that have
ever walked the face of the planet that
are influencing things in a way today
that it's really unparalleled in terms
of human history,
the potential that any new invention or
innovation can enact,
whether it's understanding new compounds
that we discovered in the rain forest or
some new technology that's made in
Silicon Valley.
I mean,
it's an amazing,
amazing parallel.
Yeah,
no,
I agree.
It does seem like it does seem like a
race in some ways between idiocy and
genius.
They're incredibly brilliant people and
they're developing.
I mean,
there are solutions to the problems that
face us.
Right?
But they have on the other side,
you have the know nothings,
you know,
who are marching into the future,
eyes firmly fixed on the rear view
mirror.
It's like,
oh yeah,
coal technology.
That's the greatest thing.
Let's go back to that.
I mean,
is that stupid or what?
You know,
cold technology is obsolete.
It's stupid and you know,
there are better solutions,
you know,
or the whole attitude towards drugs.
Oh,
the war on drugs.
The war on drugs was great.
Let's go back to that.
I mean these are people who are not
living in the present for one thing,
not planning for the future and they
don't really want to know.
It's like our minds are made up.
We know drug abuse has got to be bad,
so let's prohibit it.
Let's go back to the old model.
They're not capable of entertaining a
new ideas and that's a problem.
You know,
what do you think about the idea,
and I've heard this brought up and I've,
I've entertained at my own self that
maybe we need some sort of enemy or some
sort of thing to resist in order to rise
to the full potential of innovation,
of ideas of that we almost need some
sort of mountain to conquer.
We need some sort of a force to be aware
of.
It really makes people rise up,
but I've seen more,
more people politically active and
politically engaged now post election
than I ever did before the election
because I didn't expect trump to win.
Right.
And now that he did,
it's like it's raised up this resistance
to this insane level that I've never
experienced before in my life.
I mean,
it feels to me like Kent State all over
again.
It feels to know where it was a real
shock that he won.
And it's,
it.
I agree.
It's been a wake up call.
So now there is this strong resistance,
um,
movement,
and there.
And that's a good thing that that's
happened at also journalism.
How suddenly found itself again,
you know,
some journalists,
some sectors of it are beginning to,
you know,
for so long they were essentially
stenographers.
They would repeat whatever the
mouthpieces,
the government.
Now the journalists are questioning
everything and asking tough questions of
these clowns.
I'm expecting answers and it's kind of
like,
you know,
when I was young,
I wanted it to be a journalist,
right?
I thought Walter cronkite was the cat's
pajamas.
I wanted to be like him,
I wanted or I wanted it to be a foreign
correspondent.
I just admire journalism and for a long
time I have not found anything to admire
in it.
It's like they're,
they've all been lobotomized or
something,
but they're rediscovering it,
you know,
the good ones are rediscovering it and
the reemergence of investigative
journalism.
And right now I think that's the,
you know,
that's our best hope because I think
that,
uh,
these guys,
they'll just keep digging.
There's going to be so much bad stuff
come up about trump and the oldest
collusion with the Russians and,
you know,
um,
potentially enough to impeach him.
The question is,
will the Republicans find enough spine
to,
uh,
you know,
to do that.
But they did with Nixon.
Yeah.
You know,
and I think some,
I mean,
what he did was not nearly as bad as
what trump is doing and so we'll see
where it goes,
but shameless in a way that Nixon never
watch shameless.
And,
and,
uh,
you know,
I,
I take a certain comfort in the thought
that,
uh,
you know,
they have all these draconian things.
They want to do a rollback,
all the environmental regulations,
whole immigration thing,
uh,
you know,
a war on drugs,
but none of it is going to happen.
None of it actually will happen with the
immigration stuff is pretty real here in
California.
I mean,
they,
I see he is showing up at home depots.
They showed up at home people's.
I have a friend who was born in America,
he's Mexican and they asked him where he
was born.
They pulled me,
he's a veteran and he knew like how to
deal with this and he knew what's legal
and what's not.
And you know,
it's a grown man.
He's in his fifties and the citizen
citizen and a veteran,
he served the country in Iraq.
And so they're coming up to him and ask
him,
where are you born?
And he's like,
you can't ask me that.
Know was like,
you don't,
you're not allowed to ask me where I'm
born.
And then,
you know,
he says,
who are you?
And what were immigration and whatever
the ice stands for,
and he goes,
let me see some documentation,
and the guy shows him his badge and his
gun.
He goes,
that's not your fucking documentation.
Pull out your goddamn documentation.
And he pulls out his military id.
It's like,
look,
here's my documentation.
This is me.
Who the fuck are you?
Why are you asking people where they're
born?
I was born in California.
Okay.
You're not allowed to just go up to
people and ask them where they're born,
but people that don't know that they're,
they're getting arrested,
they're getting taken and they're
getting deported.
They're taking people that are dropping
off their children at school,
the grabbing people and there's a bunch
of cases of this and you're just hearing
about the cases that get to the press.
So many them that you're never going to
hear about.
And this is just rampant and this never
existed before.
Not In the Bush administration.
No,
I mean not in Bush.
Senior immediate just didn't happen
before in any conservative
administration.
They didn't treat it like this.
This is a weird time.
Yeah,
it is a very weird time,
but I think it's temporary.
Well,
I hope so,
but what you said about journalism,
I think it's important to point out that
the.
They're just as they fucked up,
just as hard with the left as they did
with the right.
I mean they,
they let the Clintons get away with a
lot of horseshit.
They gotta let Obama get away with a lot
of horseshit.
They,
they,
they said talking points.
They were given talking points and they
ran with those talking points so that
they would get access to the president
and they will get access to congressmen,
the senators,
and they did it forever and it wasn't
journalism and you're right and they're
the reason why this guy got into place
in this,
in this situation right now.
It's just as much of a fault of them
have not holding the left to the fire as
it is to,
you know,
what's going on right now.
Yeah,
I mean,
journalism has a lot to answer for it.
There's no doubt about it.
I just have a,
you know,
maybe it's a delusion.
I would just,
I,
I liked,
I would like to think that journalism is
finding its voice and finding its
function.
Again,
it's function is to,
you know,
as somebody said,
I think it was I have stone,
you know,
the function is to comfort the afflicted
and afflict the comfortable.
Right.
And that's essentially the journalistic
mandates or express the truth and the
truth,
see the truth and form.
Don't assume,
you know,
play the propaganda game,
be able to look beyond it and they have
to be in this environment and the,
where people keep calling fake news.
They have to be undeniable.
And I think in that sense they are
reinvigorated,
you know,
I mean that's one of the things that,
you're,
you're seeing that's one of the things
that the times talked about like after
it was over,
after the election was over,
they were like,
we are,
we're going to reinvigorate,
refocused our dedication on journalism.
And I think that's a good sign.
Then the other side of it is that we can
just,
you know,
the way the trump administration
proceeds with all these things,
they wanted to,
the inevitably just get bogged down in
litigation protest to the,
you know,
at some point they do have to answer to
Congress.
So I think,
you know,
I mean the wheels were already coming
off before he even took the oath of
office.
They've continued to come off and it's
just gonna get.
It's just a sort of a degenerate into
litigation acrimony and the ability to
get anything passed.
Uh,
you know,
which is all good.
I mean essentially in this case,
chaos is our friend because they won't
be able to advance this draconian
agenda.
Thank God.
And you know,
hopefully circumstances will enable us
to get rid of them quickly.
Yeah.
I don't know.
You know,
I'm,
I'm not entirely confident in that.
I just.
The whole thing to me when I'm looking
at these protests,
like what was going on yesterday where
people are just beating the shit out of
each other in the streets is people with
red hats.
Like the red hats are the bad people.
It's so strange.
Scene people,
these make America great again.
Hats fighting with people that are
wearing masks and motorcycle helmets and
their sticks and people were throwing
smoke bombs.
I'm like,
this is crazy.
I really never thought we'd see such a
clear right versus left civil war.
In fact,
like these little battles,
it seems to be ramping up and becoming
more and more common and,
and,
and becoming more and more violent.
Yeah,
it seems that it is,
you know,
but so what can we do?
You know,
we're not out on the streets protesting
on one side or another.
I mean,
I,
uh,
you know,
and then basically I think for me,
I continue to do it what I'm doing
because I think,
I think these plant medicines are the
single most important catalyst for
changing consciousness on a global level
and that's what has to happen.
So I'm not saying I have nothing
messianic about it.
I,
you know,
I tell people I work for the plants,
but I think it's valuable to bring
people to that experience in a place
that is safe.
They don't have to worry about those
issues.
They can have this direct download with
the mysterious tremendum,
if you want to call it that,
that can change hearts and minds.
I think that globally,
I think that Ios is a catalyst for that.
You know,
why has it suddenly gone global in the
last 20 years?
I think,
you know,
I think that it's a sign that Gaia,
if you believe in that concept that the
earth itself is an intelligent entity is
give them a little bit hysterical and is
trying to get our attention,
you know,
wake up the monkeys and this is the way
it's.
So ios gives an ambassador from the
community of species to what I call the
programmatic primates.
You know,
this out of control species that,
uh,
needs,
a good talking to say,
wake up your recognized place.
You know,
and you don't have to.
Well,
it seems like so
systems always tried to balance
themselves out,
you know,
whether it's through warfare or disease
or some new government,
you surfing the old power or whether
it's through predators and prey and
there's always some weird sort of
reaction to some thing gaining too much
power and whether it's ideas or
ideologies or patterns that they gained
too much power and then something shows
up that sort of tends to diminish that
erode the very foundation of it.
That's,
that's what I feel
about psychedelics that in many ways
what they're doing and even the sneaky
door,
like the people that talk about cannabis
being a,
you know,
some sort of a gateway drug.
It's not a gateway drug to the bad ones.
I think if anything,
it's a gateway drug to the ones that are
going to change the world.
If it doesn't do it on its own it,
you know,
I mean,
this concept of a gateway drug is,
you know,
it's just stupid.
In sense,
this is something that the drug warriors
have come up with.
I mean,
I'm here to tell you,
coffee is a gateway drug.
Probably chocolate ice cream is a
gateway drug.
We've all taken these things and you
know,
look where we are now.
We,
you know,
so gateway drug,
it's just the concept is absurd.
What's it?
If it was sold in the,
in a environment where there were a
choice to have all sorts of other
illegal drugs,
they wouldn't be a gateway drug,
but it no.
Well the alcohol one is the most
ridiculous one because it's everywhere
and it's the one that inhibits your
really loosens your inhibitions more
than any other drug may is responsible
for the most foolish behavior.
Yeah.
It's everywhere.
You can get it at every restaurant.
You can get it almost everywhere you go
this way.
Even to the point where it's not even
recognized as a drug.
Exactly.
Cognitive dissonance for years,
you know,
the FDA could not classify tobacco as a
drug because it was a different
regulatory framework.
Well,
of course it's a drug,
you know,
and somebody said,
yeah,
it's the only drug you can use when used
as instructed will kill you.
That's hilarious.
Isn't it funny that the word drug,
I'm not funny,
but it's,
isn't it problematic at the very least
that the drug is sort of this gigantic
blanket that we throw over all these
things that perturb consciousness,
right?
Wrong,
good and bad,
positive and negative.
No beneficial effects whatsoever.
And this is,
this is another reason.
This is another example of why this
conversation about drugs is so shallow
because we're talking about drugs.
Completely scary.
You say people don't use drugs.
What about what about which drugs?
When we talk about which drugs,
because there's thousands of drugs.
So which one are we talking about?
Or we just battled drugs.
Just calling them drugs is a problem.
Could you call dmt the same thing that
you call alcohol?
It seems to me to be so crazy.
It's just not a useful term.
Right?
You know?
Um,
and then also,
I mean the problem that they're facing
and that we have to acknowledge,
which I've been saying a lot lately,
as you know,
we're made of drugs,
right?
Drugs,
work.
We are made of drugs,
right?
We're biochemical engines that run on
trucks which are neurotransmitters and
hormones.
And enzymes and all of these things and
biochemical system,
they're involved with signal
transduction with organisms are networks
of communication.
They're mediated by neurotransmitters,
neurotransmitters,
if you isolated them from the brain,
put them into a bottle and sold them.
That would be a drug,
will they?
These are drugs.
So this idea that we are inherently
biochemical systems and people don't
want to acknowledge that,
but that's the truth.
You know,
we're made of drugs.
So the people that want to have the drug
free America,
I'm sorry,
we're made out of drugs.
Drugs are built into who we are.
That's why drugs taken from plants or
from the outside have the effects that
they have,
you know,
because they affect these systems that
uh,
you know,
our,
our big brains.
This is kind of a consequence of
evolution.
You know,
we have these enormous brains that
evolved very quickly and we like
novelty.
You know,
we have all of these brain receptors.
We like to.
We'd like to stimulate those receptors
because it makes us feel good or it's
interesting or for all sorts of reasons.
We like to tweak our states of
consciousness.
It's just built into who we are and it's
not a bad thing.
Well,
this is a problem with the way you're
thinking.
You have too many facts and use too much
science and you don't have enough Jesus,
Jesus in your life.
If you have Jesus,
you wouldn't need all this nonsense,
and then that jeff sessions would make
sense to you.
Right?
That may be true,
but unfortunately I don't.
So yeah,
I'll just continue to be diluted.
Believe in science is so important,
so that makes that so important that you
embraced Jesus and you just
can't do it.
I mean,
I know I'm a recovering Catholic.
I've been there.
I know.
I know the drill.
I know the territory,
but it's really.
In all honesty though,
it's so important that you are saying
these things so people can change their
perspective.
When they realized that,
oh yeah,
we are really just water balloons of
drugs were just filled up with it.
I mean we're,
that's what operates the whole thing.
That essentially is what we are.
That's what adrenaline is.
All these different things are.
No,
I didn't say it first.
You know who said it?
It was Salvador Dali.
They said,
so how do you come up with the ideas for
all these crazy art do you do?
You must be on drugs,
right?
He said,
no,
I am drugs.
Which I guess that put the conversation
to an end.
So if you think about it,
it's quite true.
I'm speaking of are,
you know,
without.
I don't want to get too far down this,
but a lot.
The problem with organized religion I
think is that it denies biology,
right?
Right.
The idea of students.
Yeah.
Somehow being in the body,
being this chemical system and enjoying
what it is to be that is forbidden
somehow,
and this is partly a reflection of our
devaluation of nature,
you know,
which is at.
That includes our own nature as well as
nature out there.
Psychedelics are the antidote to this,
right?
They make you appreciate your
relationship with nature so they they
can catalyze changes.
A consciousness.
That's why I say the most effective
thing that I can do as somebody who's
concerned with the planet is bring
people to situations where they can
encounter the medicine and make of it
what they will.
I know I'm not there to tell them what
to make of it.
I'm there to tell them this will be the
most intense personal experience that
you'll ever have.
It's up to you how you evaluated it and
you can't tell them because in all
honesty,
you're still working out yourself and
I'm certainly,
I don't want it.
I'm a big believer in use your own mind.
Use Your own brain to work this out and
that's what we have it.
You know,
that's one of the most important things
about recognizing someone who's a,
you know,
a quote unquote fake shaman or someone
who's using it wrong.
Someone is telling you exactly what it
is and what you're going to experience
like no.
One of the most beautiful things that
psychedelics drugs,
psychedelic drugs do as they dissolve.
Any notion that you might have that
anyone has a hold of this thing.
Yes,
very much so.
That is exactly right.
If somebody tells me I'm a great
showman,
I'm gonna lead you through this,
I'll,
you know I'm out of there because they
obviously have not understood what it
is.
If somebody says I'm not a shop and I
just helped,
I just held.
I just want to facilitate,
you know,
it's the medicine that there's a shaman
will say I'm not a showman.
I just know a few tricks.
That guy is the guy.
I want a drink.
Yeah.
I just got a few tricks.
Tricks.
If you have trouble,
I can help you.
Otherwise I'll just step back and let
you do it.
You know,
and that's,
that's the essential thing because the
medicine itself is the showman.
While I have you here,
I have to ask you two questions because
I keep forgetting to do this.
Do this.
First of all,
cannabinoid receptors,
what is the relationship between
cannabinoid receptors in human beings
and the actual use of cannabis or the
evolutionary use of cannabis?
Like over the course of human
development is our cannabinoid receptors
in place because people have consumed
cannabis throughout history or they had
just a natural function of biology?
No,
there a natural function of biology,
like a lot of these things,
you know,
like opiate receptors,
the same thing,
cannabinoid receptors and there are many
kinds and they're all over the body.
They're not just in the brain,
they do all sorts of things.
They're involved with immune functions
and inflammation and it's quite
complicated,
which is why cbd oil works and it's not
psychoactive,
not psychoactive at works on different
receptors.
There's at least three kinds of
cannabinoid receptors and evolutionarily
they,
you know,
they're not contaminated receptors.
There's the endocannabinoid system.
They are,
they are responsive to things that we
make in the body.
Like a Nanda mind and there's another
one who I always,
which I always forget,
but these are indogenous compounds that
bind to cannabinoid receptors,
so just like their endogenous compounds
that bind to the opiate receptors.
These are peptides like endorphins and
enkephalins,
those sorts of things,
you know,
but the receptor is just happened to
bind these plant alkaloids,
but that's not why they evolved.
You know,
they have functions in the body related
to analgesias and sleep and that sort of
thing.
Same with the contaminated receptors.
They evolved not because they were
cannabis plants out there,
but because the body made these
endocannabinoids and they mediated all
kinds of functions like Amanda,
my,
these things,
uh,
you know,
can I mentally,
it's a little different than something
like a,
like a dmt or Psilocybin,
which work kind of very specifically on
the serotonin receptors and that's how
they mediate their effects.
The effects of cannabinoids are more
widespread.
You could say more multi,
multi valence is maybe a good word,
but it's not because the plants were
there that we've,
all these things.
We had this,
we were neurologically,
no modern humans you might say,
and curious,
right?
Sampling and everything we could get our
hands on in the environment,
whether it's stuffing ended up,
our nose are usually drinking it or
whatever.
Naturally you're going to stumble over
these compounds because,
uh,
you know,
the bio is,
is these are just abundant in the bio.
So it's not really a chicken or the egg
sort of situation.
Like what came first,
the cannabinoid receptor or the
consumption of cannabis receptors were
there first.
How do we know that,
uh,
how do we know that?
Because we can actually trace,
we can trace the phylogeny of these
things,
you know,
we have molecular methods now where we
can actually traits the ancestry of
receptors,
right?
For example,
we have ways to measure this.
So,
you know,
cannabinoid receptors,
you can look at the phylogeny and,
and you know,
they were present in the president in
mammals long before we were around,
you know,
and Tryptofan.
It's the same thing.
Tryptophan,
which is the amino acid we were talking
about,
precursor to many of these psychedelics,
right?
So how old is tripped a fan as an amino
acid?
You can look back at the phylogeny,
turns out damn old,
possibly three point 8 billion years
old.
The genes for Tryptofan have been found
in phylogenetic groups that go back that
far.
The so called trip oppor on.
So,
you know,
so these things have been around for a
long time.
And uh,
you know,
in the most primitive organisms,
Serotonin is another good example.
Serotonin is,
which most of the psychedelics work on
Serotonin is thought to be the oldest
neurotransmitter phylogenetically older
than dopamine and norepinephrine.
Some of these other things,
Tryptofan,
Serotonin is receptors are very old,
uh,
phylogenetically evolutionarily.
So how does that correlate with a
runner's high,
um,
when,
when people have this runner's high and
apparently it has some sort of an effect
on cannabinoid receptors,
what is going on there and does it
actually mimic the high that someone
gets from consuming cannabis?
It May,
I've heard the runner's high discussed
in terms of the,
of the opiate receptors,
the endorphin and so on.
Maybe cannabis to what we do know is
that in states of high stress,
you can boost the production of these
indigenous compounds,
which is why high stress is one way to
induce altered states of consciousness
on the match.
Right?
Oh,
I don't need drugs because I can,
I can run and get high or I can do
meditation and get high.
I'm sorry dude,
you're still on drugs.
Cars were made,
were made of drug and he figured out a
way to boost your endogenous DMT
cannabinoid.
So when PA getting crazy,
they're actually in some way doing some
sort of a natural drug trip.
Yeah.
Essentially,
because we are drugs,
there is no state you can experience
including the state that we're in right
now,
that is not a reflection of our
neurochemistry.
We're in a hallucination right now.
This is a,
you know,
this is a reality that our brains take
information in from the environment
through our sensory neural interface.
They combine it with
what we know from memories and
associations and the Cortex,
and they essentially create a model of
reality and that's the reality we're
inhabiting,
you know,
and a lot of what the brain does,
it receives information,
but a lot of the brain's function is to
filter stuff out.
You know,
if we received everything from the
environment all the time,
we'd be nuts.
We wouldn't be able to take it.
So there are these gating mechanisms,
it's called neural gating and we are
genetically programmed to and through
experience as well,
to,
uh,
to have these gating mechanisms that
filters a lot of stuff out so that we
can function.
Otherwise reality would be a blooming
buzzing confusion all the time.
We wouldn't be able to focus on
anything,
you know.
So a lot of.
So for example,
gating is,
you know,
it's malleable,
it can change depending on the input.
So you're in a crowded restaurant for
example,
and there's,
it's hard to hear,
there's a lot of noise in the
background.
You adapt to that by filtering out most
of what's there,
right?
You just,
you can suppress it to some degrees so
you can talk to the person across from
you,
right?
You're not paying attention.
But at the next table you hear somebody
say your name,
suddenly you're gating mechanism,
you know,
you get that,
that gets through the filtering
mechanism itself.
Somebody is talking to me,
I wonder what they're saying about me
over there,
you know,
that kind of thing.
So it relates,
but a lot of what the brain does when
you essentially create this
hallucination,
if you want to call it that,
a,
of the reality that we inhabit,
you can call it a model of reality.
It's not reality itself.
It's a reasonable facsimile of reality
that we inhabit and everybody's is
different.
Hence different views.
Everyone is different,
but close enough that we can talk to
each other and all that.
It's,
you know.
But it's not the pure objective reality,
you know,
which doesn't really exist.
Well it exists out there,
but we don't know what it looks,
but it doesn't exist to humans doesn't
exist to us.
We don't perceive it.
We receive our own art,
you know,
our own a model essentially of reality
and I think you explaining that
different experiences create literally
drug trips also can explain love affairs
where people become incredibly addicted
to each other and addicted to the
experience of being around the person
and what that does to you and that
literally you are on drugs when you were
someone of course.
And you know that's been studied,
right?
Yeah.
I mean oxytocin and probably opiate
movies in Saratoga mean all of these
things are part of what mediates
relationship,
including sex hormones.
So all of those things,
all of those things,
sex hormones,
tour psychoactive drugs in a certain
sense,
which is not to say,
I mean this is not saying that these
experiences are genuine or valuable or
anything.
They are obviously,
you know,
personal relationships are important.
It is not a to my mind,
it's not an evaluation to say we'll it's
chemically mediated.
Okay,
great.
It's chemically mediated.
That doesn't make it invalid.
In fact,
it means that,
well,
these molecules are pretty amazing.
They couldn't do that.
Well,
the feeling is fantastic.
Like why would that invalidate it?
It's still real.
It's still awesome,
but people,
you know,
again,
they have these artificial distinctions
about,
well,
you know,
my mystical experiences more valuable
than yours because you had to have
silicide and then I got there on that
couch,
but it wasn't on the match.
You know,
you're still a prisoner of your
neurochemistry.
No matter what.
It just so happens that silicide been,
is it drug taken in the right
circumstances,
in the right amount will reliably induce
a mystical experience.
Nothing wrong with that.
You don't.
You could even study it.
Suddenly science can study mystical
experiences because we have a reliable
trigger that will nine times out of 10
induce mystical experience in the right
circumstances.
So then we can take somebody.
Maybe somebody is meditated for 20
years,
are done yoga or done other things,
hoping that they might have a mystical
experience,
good for them,
but then you know,
you can take me an ordinary schmuck or
somebody like me who hasn't
particularly,
not particularly spiritually evolved,
but I can take solace Simon then.
Yeah,
it works.
That reminds me of a great story that
your brother told once about a,
uh,
a monk who studied a city of levitation
and uh,
he did it for like 30 years and then met
the Buddha and said,
look,
I can walk on water.
I've studied the city of levitation for
30 years and now I can walk across the
river.
And the Buddhist said,
yeah,
but the ferries,
only a nickel
30 years,
man,
you could've just taken mushrooms for
speaking of mushrooms is this is
something that I get wrong all the time.
It's one of the other things I wanted to
ask you.
What,
what is,
um,
there's some very close relationship
that mushrooms have and the absorption
of mushrooms have to dmt.
What,
what is the chemical differentiation?
Okay.
Very good.
Very,
very slight actually.
Um,
the temptation to start drawing
structures is almost irresistible.
Write some stuff down.
Go ahead.
Awesome.
Here has,
do we have a visual?
Now?
We don't,
but I'll save that piece of paper.
Okay.
Well,
uh,
I don't want to get too far into it,
but basically.
Okay.
So you've had organic chemistry.
Oh No,
no.
Okay.
Well then this spam organic chemistry,
you are what you are.
Organic Chemistry.
Well this may be a useless thing,
but
we could see it up on the wall here.
We've got it up on the screen.
Oh,
there you go.
okay.
Well there you go.
Yeah,
we don't have to draw,
Struck.
You can look at it right here so you
don't have to turn around.
Look to your right Dennis.
Turn test.
Well,
so.
Right.
So you can see if you've.
So there's Serotonin,
silicon and dimethyl trip to me.
Wow.
You can see that silicon and domiciled
trip to Maine are very close in
structure.
The only difference is that hydroxy
group,
that age group,
that's the only difference.
So with the silicon is exactly the same
thing as an end dimethyltryptamine.
That's correct.
Why that single trivial difference is
what makes tillison orally active and
I'm a whole trip to mean there's not.
Wow,
wow.
Because what's going on with that?
This static diagram,
the different molecular model would show
up,
but what's going on is that that
nitrogen there in when tillison's and
physiological solution,
the nitrogen is charged,
has a positive charge.
The oxygen doesn't have the h there,
it has a negative charge,
so the nitrogen curls back and is in
close association with the oxygen.
If this makes any sense,
so the enzyme can't get to it.
That's why it's orally active because
essentially it can't get to that
nitrogen.
What that enzyme does is cleave off that
nitrogen,
mano aiming oxidase.
It takes away that nitrogen and it can't
do it with allison,
so that's why I sold.
Listens orally active.
It doesn't require in them mail
inhibitor.
It's just in some ways it's the perfect
psychedelic because it,
you know,
no preparation needed.
You just bend over and pick the
mushroom.
They'll preparation is required,
which is probably why very ancient man
knew about psilocybin.
They couldn't.
They couldn't not have,
if they were living in an environment
where it was found.
That's amazing.
You know,
what's really incredible is that,
uh,
people are using suicide and these days
in what they call micro dosing,
taking very small doses and seeing these
profound benefits.
And uh,
one of the things that I'm aware of is
kickboxers are using it and kick boxers
are using it in a good buddy of mine is
using.
It says that he can see things happen
before they happen.
And like it was almost like he's reading
people's minds before they're about to
do something even on micro toast.
Yeah.
That's very interesting in the intense
environment of sparring and,
and the,
the intense physical Connecticut
interaction of kickboxing is that he's
seeing what people are going to do
before they do it in a way that he's
never able to do quote unquote on the
notch.
Right.
No,
I'm not surprised at all.
I mean,
and why?
Why aren't you surprised?
Like,
what do you think is happening?
Because I think that,
uh,
these things let you step out of your
box a little bit.
They let you step out of your usual
reference frame and notice things going
on in the environment that again,
this gating mechanism you were talking
about,
we're programmed to filter stuff out.
Psychedelics temporarily disrupt that.
They let the background come forward and
you notice things about the environment
that we're,
that normally you would suppress because
they're not relevant to immediate
survival.
I don't know if you've read some of the
work by Simon Powell.
He wrote the silicide been the solution.
He writes very intelligently about
psilocybin.
In this latest book,
the Magic Mushroom Explorer,
he talks about how psilocybin is a lens.
Essentially you can think of it as a
lens through which you can look at the
world.
You can look at natural phenomena and
you will notice things about that,
those phenomena that you normally
wouldn't overlook because we're
programmed to do it.
So in a sense,
he talks about how silicide but is a
scientific instrument.
You know,
it's a lens through which you can look
at the world and see aspects of it that
are always there,
but you've never noticed them before
because we're programmed not to.
For example,
um,
you know,
Kary Mullis is famous because his
discoveries in molecular biology,
he attributes to his insights about
molecular processes that he got from lsd
that he could get down with the
molecules as he put it and see how all
this is working.
And obviously he invented a preliminary
chain reaction which she got the Nobel
prize for.
So it's not like this is a delusion.
It's a real thing that he was able to
notice that no one else,
you know what I'm saying?
He was able to put himself in a place
where he could notice these phenomenon.
And I think,
I think that's really true.
If you,
if you go to take a walk in the forest
with an indigenous person,
you know,
who in some ways as in this less of this
sensory gating in a more open place all
the time.
They will notice things about the
environment,
you know,
that you are completely oblivious to
until they pointed out,
you know.
And then they'll say,
Oh yes,
I never noticed the leaf cutter ants are
behaving this way or these different
things.
Their sensory,
a sort of experience of a environment
like the forest is very different than
ours because we're used to.
We're just not out in nature the same
way.
And I daresay I think one of the things
that in some ways inserts a barrier
between us is literacy.
You know,
we're all literate,
right?
And we like being literate.
It's good that we're literate,
but in order to be literate,
you have to have this separation between
the self and the external environment.
You know,
you have to pick up a book and read it.
I am here.
I'm the point of view.
Here's the book,
you know,
so that creates that relationship and
you sacrifice,
you focus on one particular sensory
modality and you sacrifice all the other
input that is coming up.
I don't know if I'm making say no,
you absolutely are.
You absolutely are.
But,
but that's,
that's what these substances can do.
They can essentially reverse this
background foreground relationship that
we're so used to suddenly what's right
in front of you is not so important and
you can pay attention to the things in
the background that you're normally your
program to suppress and ignore because,
you know,
you have to be ready for the saber tooth
tiger to come across,
you know,
over the,
the mountain or whatever,
you know what I'm saying.
But,
uh,
it's good in that sense.
They teach different ways of perception,
you know,
and I think that's a very useful thing
to learn.
You know,
indigenous people call these
psychedelics plant teachers and they
call them teachers for a reason.
You know,
much of the,
what you experienced comes directly from
the experience.
But much of it also comes from your
change perception.
And suddenly you realize there's a
different way to be in the world.
There's a different way to perceive what
you experienced that normally you don't.
Uh,
you know,
we're programmed to filter out.
I don't know if you've ever read or had
Stephen Buhner on your show.
No.
He writes very intelligently about this
stuff.
He's written a book called a plant
intelligence on the imaginal realm,
and it's all about this,
you know,
this,
uh,
essentially let his rap is you can learn
this,
you know,
you can learn this way of perceiving
whether you do it with psychedelics or
not.
You can actually learn it and it's a,
it's an interesting.
It's a better way to relate to nature or
more an alternative way to relate to the
insured in any way.
I feel like we have these pre assumed
definitions of things that we rely upon
instead of seeing things for what they
really are.
And you,
you Kinda,
yeah.
You box them up and you package them and
you go,
oh,
well there's a car,
there is a.
and then one day you look at the car and
you go,
that's a box that has a controlled
explosion in cased in iron and that
rules on rubber tires and see exactly
what they're talking about.
There's a different way to look at
things if you step out of the box.
And yes,
it is all those things and it's also a
car and it's good if you did that all
the time,
you'd never get anything done.
That's right.
But I mean it's interesting in that
respect,
you know,
with psychedelics,
because we're verbal people and we're,
you know,
were inhabited,
inhabited world of language as much as
the physical world and we're almost
compelled to try to put some kind of
linguistic wrapper over everything.
And which is one reason why if you smoke
DMT,
right,
you have a complete revelation.
It's amazing.
That's all of these things.
But it's in most cases you aren't even
down yet before you're trying to explain
it to yourself.
You know,
you're trying to stuff this thing in a
box because it was so impactful.
It's inherently in the EFL bowl.
You know,
you can't really describe it in
language,
but boy is there a desire to somehow
tame this thing which is
incomprehensible,
totally transcendent.
But that doesn't stop you from rapping
about it immediately to try to stuff it
into a box because it's too impactful.
And so on the individual level,
this is what people do.
Well,
that's what religions do too,
right?
They try to take something like this and
stuff it into a box because in and of
itself,
without that wrapping or that
linguistic,
you know,
filters to somehow tame it and,
nullify,
neutralize its power.
These things are very dangerous.
There are,
there also seems to be some sort of a
physiological component to the,
uh,
the DMT trip where once it's over,
you have a very limited amount of time
to hang onto those memories.
Yes.
Well,
exactly.
So this is an attempt to entrain that,
to grab it and I think put a linguistic,
uh,
you know,
tag on a certain way so that as a way to
not forget it or,
or try and,
you know,
both reduce its power but give you
something to hang on because right.
The memory and flooded actually is it's
going to fade very rapidly.
Why is that?
What is,
what's the physiological.
I don't know what the physiological.
It's like a lot like dreams,
dreams.
It's a lot like dreams.
I think that it's just,
I don't know,
it's a,
it's something like that you could
probably train yourself to remember it
better,
just like people can train themselves to
remember their dreams.
Uh,
but it,
it's ephemeral,
you know,
it does tend to evaporate,
which is why it's important to go to the
well once in a file and take a drink.
Right.
I am not one of these people that says,
once you get the message,
hang up the phone,
that's a model that doesn't work for me.
Actually,
it might work for some people,
but I feel like this is not,
this is not an answering machine,
this is a teacher.
This is something that is intelligent
that you have a dialogue with,
you know,
and you don't,
teacher teaches a lesson.
You don't say,
thanks very much.
We're done.
Now.
It's an ongoing process.
I've been taking psychedelics for most
of my life,
a good part of my life.
I feel like I've only learned a fraction
of what they have to teach me,
you know?
Um,
maybe I'm just dumb.
Maybe I don't get the message as well as
other people,
but I don't think so.
I think there's a lot.
They're full of surprises.
You know,
I've taken Iowaska,
Lux,
lost track a long time ago,
but probably 500 times or more and
people say,
well,
you know,
surely you've learned everything there
is to learn.
Actually No.
You know,
I always learned something new
and I learned certain basic things to
that.
It always reminds me about,
well also remember that you don't know
any chief and you're also acquiring new
data constantly in the natural world
that needs to be processed and sometimes
you process it with the tools of
civilization versus.
Yeah.
Versus the psychedelics.
It's A.
Well,
you know,
it's just interesting.
Yeah,
it keeps me off the streets.
A lot of people can be great.
Yeah.
No,
I'm grateful.
Listen,
I think I've taken up plenty of your
time here and this is an amazing
conversation.
I really appreciate it.
Uh,
I,
I'm always happy when we can do this.
I wish we could do it more often.
We should do it.
We definitely should.
Let's do it.
I can come,
um,
you know,
there are many people I can recommend.
I'm sure you'd get hundreds of requests,
but certain people you ought to be
talking to you.
Let's do it.
So please one more time.
Tell people about
this conference and um,
when they can watch it on facebook.
Okay,
well it's the e,
s,
p,
e d [inaudible] dot com.
That's,
that's the key thing.
Esp d 50.
The conference will be June sixth,
seventh and the eighth in the UK.
You can go there if you want to attend
it.
The cost is high to actually go there
and do it,
but people could access it on facebook
and if you go to that website then
there's a link through to the facebook
page and we'll be live streaming it,
you know,
on the sixth,
the sixth,
seventh and eighth of June at.
It'll be archived.
So I don't expect people in the states
to get up at three in the morning,
you know,
to watch it.
Although they could,
if they want to watch it live,
but it'll all be,
you know,
archives.
So they can look at it at any time and
will you transfer it over to other more
accessible that people that don't have
facebook maybe on youtube or something
along those lines of Vimeo?
Eventually.
We haven't made plans to live stream it
on vimeo.
I don't know how you do that.
I think you can live stream it,
but you could definitely take the video
recording.
Perhaps if you have a physical
recording,
it'll.
It'll all be up there eventually,
but just live stream real time.
Facebook will be where we do it mostly
because everyone has told me this is how
you do.
Okay,
well I will definitely tweet that out to
everybody and I'll let everybody know
and I'll put it on all the available
social media.
Fantastic pages and and ordered the
book.
You can go to the website and order the
book and the book will come out probably
the end of November and it's going to
take a few months for everybody to get
there.
You know,
they have to not only make a
presentation,
they have to submit a paper for this
book and I'm,
you know,
I'm dangling a certain rewards out to
them to make sure that they do in fact
submit a full paper in the spirit of the
first conference,
but it's going to be an amazing book and
it's something I've wanted to do for a
long time and uh,
I can check this off the list now and go
onto something else.
Beautiful.
I hope they do it more.
Thanks Joe.
Thank you,
Dennis.
I appreciate you very,
very much.
All right.
Thanks folks.
See you soon.
Bye.