There it goes.
Now it's recording.
Alright ladies.
Gentlemen,
what's up?
Welcome to the weekly podcast.
I think it's like week 2000.
What week is it Brian?
Twenty fourth week.
Brian is on top of shits on 24th week.
And join today is a Jujitsu master
musician,
best friend Eddie the twister.
Bravo.
Ladies and gentlemen,
how about a big round of applause for
Mr.
Eddie Bravo.
Joining us here today.
Eddie just had some pizza.
Fuck that.
Diet up son.
Fucked it up.
Yeah,
I got a hold of.
Got Real.
We've got a real mix now,
man.
Solidarity if you want.
Cool.
When you talk right into it,
it makes it so much better.
We were having problems when we first
started doing this.
We just figured out how to do a podcast
basically without asking anybody.
We just trial and error and we fucked a
lot of shit up and.
But the biggest thing we fucked up in
the beginning was the sound.
The sound was really bad at first,
but now we've got that shit locked down
so that's good.
What are you doing?
He's practicing.
Hold the mic like this.
It's like smoking a cigarette and
France.
What movie is this front?
There's a movie where a guy singing
karaoke and he's holding the mic like
that.
There's a many used to hang it in front
of his face like this.
I don't remember who it was like you're
sucking a cock right here.
Well,
I've never said it.
That flashlight.
Yes,
it was.
Before we go anywhere.
We're sponsored by the fleshlight.
This podcast is a sponsored park at
podcast,
but I'll be quite honest with you,
if we were not sponsored by the
fleshlight and um,
we just,
we just became a subject of the
conversation of the podcast.
I will tell you,
go buy one of those fucking things are
awesome.
Don't be embarrassed.
Everybody jerks off.
It's silly.
You know,
if you jerk off and you wouldn't fuck a
rubber pussy,
you're crazy all.
It's just pleasure.
And it feels way better than jerk.
I got
a good flashlight story.
Yeah.
Oh,
let's hear.
It's about when I bought it about maybe
like,
I've,
I've had it for awhile.
I haven't.
I've used it maybe a 20 times right now.
It's fucking pretty good if you're going
to jerk off something about your own
hand touching your cock,
cancels out some feeling or something,
it doesn't feel as good as someone else
jerking you off or whatever.
So that's where the fleshlight comes in.
I mean,
that's it.
It feels pretty fucking good.
You got the right part or whatever.
But anyways,
about three years ago,
maybe two years ago,
I met this girl,
uh,
when we were on the road in Texas
somewhere,
maybe Houston or Dallas or something
like that.
I was on the road with you met her and
um,
we kept in touch.
She came out to La and um,
hung out for a weekend and for some
reason she wasn't down at all.
She wasn't,
she wasn't done at all.
She didn't want to.
She didn't want me to touch her.
Now she's staying at my fucking house
and she doesn't even want to touch me
and kiss her or nothing.
So I decided to take her to the hustler
store and go shopping for a fleshlight
this thing.
So she couldn't fucking believe that she
thought I was kidding.
Then I went to the store to buy a
flashlight.
I'm like,
Hey,
if you're not going to give me the
pussy,
I got to know this is the second best
thing.
Can invite another girl over here.
So,
um,
that's my fleshlight store.
I used it that night too while she
passed out and in.
Just cool.
It's pretty cool.
It's better than using your hands.
It's better than using your hand.
If you had,
if you could hire a Mexican to clean it
up afterwards,
then it would be awesome.
It's just the cleanup Mexican.
Why does it have to be a Mexican man?
They worked cheap.
You're going to put a white male,
white dude to clean up your flashlight
when you're done.
You got to go to home depot and pick up
a couple of guys and they'll switch off
target the other day.
And there was these things called magic
microphones for kids.
It's a kid's toy that looks just like a
fleshlight.
If you look at it,
you're like,
oh,
the same company that makes flashlights
must also make this mike on my God.
And so I pick it up and I go to my
girlfriend,
like,
look,
they got flashlights here and right.
I look.
I'm like,
oh stupid.
I look around.
There's kids everywhere in mom's looking
at me and if I cough,
fuck yes.
It's funny how it's got a bad,
like,
you know,
there's a bad feeling attached to it
that there's something wrong with this
rubber pussy.
There's something wrong with pleasure.
If it was just a massage thing,
it was just like,
look,
I got a massage and makes your backfill.
Awesome.
Everybody be like,
oh cool guys.
Making is backfill.
Awesome.
There's something about making your dick
feel awesome.
That freaks everybody out.
Which would freak out if your son.
I was using the flashlight at 11.
Would that be bad?
No.
Right?
No,
not at all.
First Birthday,
right?
I would say,
listen man,
you're body is a biological organism
that doesn't understand you know,
your life.
It wants you to make decisions for it,
not for you.
So it's going to try to trick you into
fucking someone with no condom and
having babies.
I mean,
that's what your body's trying to do.
And it can get real confusing who you
actually like as opposed to like who
your Dick is telling you,
you like,
you know when you're horny all the time,
you,
your Dick convinces you that you like
people you don't even like just because
you could fuck them,
you know.
And for a kid when you're just learning
how to get into relationships,
that shit's very tricky.
I think every young kid could benefit
from.
They should teach kids how to jerk off
in school.
They should teach kids how your Dick is
going to confuse you and how it's going
to send you all these messages.
And being horny is actually a baffling
thing that takes years and years to
master.
And they can make.
Hannah Montana flashlights came at
$20,000,000,000
industry.
I wonder if that would be illegal if she
sponsored a fleshlight for high school
kids.
And she's not saying it's safe sex.
Would that be insane?
Why not,
right?
Yeah,
that'd be so smart.
I mean,
we really pretending the kids aren't
fucking,
you know,
kids get to be 16 years old.
She's like 16 or 17.
They're fucking man.
They're fucking,
the problem is even if she wants to like
talk about it and shit,
it's still illegal,
you know,
it's still,
it's,
they're not supposed to be fucking and
no one's supposed to be fucking them.
That's like older than them.
I think they go to jail.
You know,
if you're,
if you're 18 and your girlfriend is 17
years and 10 months and you fucker,
you go to jail.
Is that really happening?
Yes.
Yeah.
And people have gotten that bad.
It's real.
God Damn it.
Know what's happening.
That's even scarier than that is a gang
of kids are getting popped for child
pornography for taking pictures with
their pussies on their fucking cell
phones.
Oh Shit.
Those are dicks.
That's really what's happening,
man.
Down to getting in trouble,
going it criminal tools.
A girl was arrested on child pornography
charges because she sent.
She's 15 years old.
She sent pictures of herself to a bunch
of kids in their class and they
eventually dropped the child pornography
charges,
but they charged with one count of using
criminal tools.
The criminal tool was a cell phone.
That was a account they had against her.
She took a cell phone to take a picture
of her pussy.
So that was a criminal tool.
You that guys delete all that shit.
How crazy is that man?
Think about what it would be like.
Was your daughter and you found out that
your daughter was doing the same thing?
I think we talked about guys here.
You guys talk about the exact same
thing.
The flashlight.
Sorry guys.
Just love talking about it.
Denies The fleshlight store.
Sexting.
Oh,
the sex thing we talked about last time.
It's still fascinating.
Very important part of it.
Pay attention to that twitter feed.
Brian,
I don't really want to know what people
want us to talk about.
Shut that shit off.
That shit drives me crazy.
You freaking me out,
son.
Wait,
isn't that what we got here?
Yeah,
this is freaking me out too,
but I don't read it.
Don't read it too much,
man.
Then you're going to change the subject
of your conversation.
Listening to what they're saying.
You're getting too serious about this,
Joe.
No,
I'm not getting serious.
It's distracting.
It's distracting for good conversation.
So what'd you guys think about the new
iphone that just was announced
yesterday?
It was pretty crazy that the iphone is
a.
is going to change a lot of Shit,
man.
First of all,
everyone's going to be using it for
phone sex because you could see the
other person.
You could see them.
That's what's fucked up because I was
thinking about this the other day.
You know how texting and twitter and
everything's fucking up.
People's games are just lies in general.
Now people are going to be like,
your ex is going to call you or your
girl is going to call you go,
where are you at right now?
You're like,
I'm with my friends.
Oh yeah,
we'll turn on your video.
Let me see where you're at.
You know,
and that's going to happen with boss,
which doesn't have any Wifi.
Well that's the only.
That's only for 2010.
That's just because att and t is trying
to build up their network.
The network is ever going to get built
up where they can handle two way phone
calls with everybody because you know
people are going to leave that shit on
and they're going to.
You're going to come to work with me.
Okay.
And they're going to be walking around.
People aren't going to be watching where
they're going.
Absolutely.
That's why your phone,
that's why a t and t regulated their
data plans the other day because they
know that that shit's going to happen.
So do you think they're just building up
to it?
How are they going to be like when
texting first came out,
when you first got texting,
everyone said this is not going to work.
No one's going to ever do this,
but in texting plans are really
expensive and ridiculous,
you know,
because all these newcomers are,
used to get jokes about texting.
I just hit my fucking 2005 showtime
special.
There's a joke in there when I'm like,
it takes you four presses to get an s.
Why you?
Why don't you just fucking call me?
What are you doing?
Are you making me read?
Right?
You know,
this is going to be exactly like,
just think about how much that's changed
in five years.
You have video content,
video calling in five years from now is
going to be the norm.
You,
that's all it's going to be.
It's not going to be.
People are gonna Laugh at you from
normal calling,
you know,
I think.
I think that's,
you know,
we're going towards star trek.
We are,
we are.
It's going to be called something to
like when someone like a girlfriend
calls you up and facetime,
I need a Web,
a web cam scan,
you know what I mean?
Okay.
Here's the way.
So you've got to tell all your buddies
that used to be at a party and go web
cams.
All the girls duck under and go,
look,
honey,
I'm here.
Boom.
Oh look it.
Then Bam.
A quick little ones over to you just
have the whole Party spin behind you.
Just move really slowly.
It's the web cam scan.
Fucking moving fast enough.
Okay.
You better web cam scan right now.
Inner Circle.
As quick as you can show me after a
while.
You're gonna have to do a quick,
it can't be fast,
but then people are just going to get
faster.
They're just gonna be.
It's going to be a sport.
You know,
you will have gambling to see whether or
not you can tell those people in the
room.
Okay,
let's go into the bathroom.
It's to look behind the curtain.
Okay,
now let's go to the back.
Cool fucking game.
How about this game?
How about you?
You have a game where you bet whether or
not someone is in someone's house and
someone takes you on a tour of their
house and you bet whether or not this
other people in the house hiding.
How about you have every recorded
prerecorded fucking scenarios.
You have like 30 of them,
your house one,
you're at your mom's,
you have all these files and then you
know they think it's live,
but it's really a a video.
We got to get on that.
You don't have a problem with it.
You would have to show your face too.
You're supposed to show your face
talking environment.
They're going to have to.
It would be like almost like a green
screen.
The great joy ideas.
When I was talking to him about this,
Joey Diaz says he's going to be like,
imagine calling your girl and go,
let me see your pussy right now.
See how red it is.
I know what it looks like after you got
fucked.
Hold it up against white.
Let me see
the color
showing her pussy.
Yeah.
Yeah,
because then we.
Because seriously,
that's how it's going to come down to.
You're going to be able to just go,
let me see what your pussy looks like
right now.
I can tell you that statement.
That that just shows you the mentality
of Joey ideas.
How Funny Joey is.
Joey is thinking about tricking girls in
the show and their pussy.
You know,
he's all about.
No,
no,
no.
I need to see it right now.
Come on,
let's go.
What do you got?
Like it's all about.
It's all about like trapping them in the
show,
in their pussy.
It's not even really asking them.
It's like part of the hustle for it.
For Joey.
You trick them.
I think it's gonna.
I think it's gonna make people a lot
more faithful because I really believe
that like twitter and facebook and
facebook has really.
It makes it so hard to cheat.
People are like,
okay,
if I'm going to,
there's a lot more single people because
it's way too hard and a cheat,
but if you decide to have a girlfriend
or boyfriend,
you're like,
fuck it.
I ain't even going to try.
You make a comment on one person's
picture.
Everybody knows that you just commented
on
some girl's picture,
you know,
so it's like you don't even,
you don't even bother,
so you might as well be faith and it's
not going to stay where it's at.
It's gonna,
it's gonna move on to some next
craziness and I,
I think that has to do with this iphone
camera.
I think that's the next stage of
craziness.
The next stage of intrusion into
people's lives and some people are going
to reject it.
You know?
Did you do just like textbook?
Just like texts,
just like picture messages.
So like everything.
That's why when people are freaking out
about flash,
it's.
I feel the same thing about that.
You know,
you people are freaking out because
you're not thinking ahead,
you're not,
you're not thinking about what's next or
what's going to be the future.
You just say freaking them out.
Flash for the non technologically a
macromedia flash what?
Macromedia flash is a program on your
websites when you see like animation and
different kinds of like,
you know,
you put your cursor over something and
it does some funky thing.
Most of the time you're dealing with
flash and a lot of these sites and
apparently flash crashes a lot.
I've had a crush a bunch of times on me
and Microsoft has their own version of
shit.
What is it?
Silver Light.
So yeah,
but what's cool is that there's actually
companies now that have software that if
you put it into flash,
and I guess flash is working with this
company that if you go to this website
and it has flash,
flash will detect that you do not have
flash on your ipad or whatever and it
will convert it into an html five point.
Oh uh,
a program or whatever.
So that's what youtube does.
No,
I think youtube just uses a different
CODEC.
There's some websites where you can go
to on the IPAD and you can still watch
videos and that's html five.
You're watching,
you're watching it.
Just a flashes has moved on from our
youtube.
Doesn't use flash as much anymore.
It uses I a Codec h two point six,
four,
I believe.
Uh,
so it's not even in flash anymore.
You're watching it.
Just,
you're just watching a video file.
I think you're right that people are
hesitant to change and then they worry
about flash falling apart and you know,
they say,
oh this is crazy.
You know,
my website is coded like this and that's
just how it should be.
But when new shit comes along that's
better.
You just got to accept it,
you know?
I think what's more fascinating to me
than anything is a facetime thing and
the,
the rise of the droid phones do a droid
phones or luck an infection.
There's like so many Goddamn droid
phones now and they do everything the
iphone does and more like,
you know what the iphone has,
you know,
the front face feature.
That's a camera.
Come on.
Blackberry,
blackberry,
blackberry.
Still number one droids nothing new.
It's just an operating system like
windows mobile wise.
These are dope ass phones.
Dope.
As phones that are doing something
that's trying to be like an iphone now,
you know,
I mean,
and it's not doing it as good.
If you use any application on a droid
and compare it to the iphone version,
almost 99 point nine percent of the time
it falls a little short.
Okay.
If,
uh,
you're saying this based on the little
experience that you had.
No,
no,
no.
I've had it for a month.
I used to straight for a month and I
know from that operating system what
they were doing back then is the same as
now it's all the same.
It's the exact same.
I use the newest one that had the newest
version.
It's the to Motorola
droid.
Right.
Which is not supposed to be as good as
this htc evo.
You're talking about the hardware
though.
You're not talking about the operating
system.
Yeah,
but I mean didn't,
didn't the,
I'm just an htc alter the operating
system a little bit.
It puts a skin on it that just makes it.
That's all it is.
It's just a skin off the operating
systems.
We make your work more effectively and
some say that hurts.
Some say it's better.
You know what it does is it gives you a
nice little widget at the front that has
the weather and a bunch of shit.
Okay.
Well just saying that the iphone is
better.
Okay.
I'll agree with you.
You believe the iphone is better,
but it's still a fucking amazing phone
and if it was.
If it existed a year ago,
you.
You'd be freaking the fuck out of
existed five years ago.
It'd be world changing.
Five years ago.
I would probably be freaking out a year
ago.
I doubt it.
It's a very impressive phone.
Yeah.
That phone hardware itself is great,
but when you compare like somebody was
going off on the other day about how
like,
Oh yeah,
this has an eight mega pixel camera or
the new iphone only has a five megapixel
camera,
and I was like,
mega pixels don't mean shit.
That's why like every year we've stopped
like at 12 megapixels for most cameras
and if you notice like most Sony cameras
that were 12 megapixels last year,
now 10 megapixel.
Okay,
well why doesn't mean shit?
I mean those guys.
Mega pixels doesn't mean much
information is in the photograph and
mega pixels don't mean shit.
It means something.
Camera sucks.
We know that 12 megapixel cameras,
awesome.
You could blow up giant bill bright's.
So it does mean something.
It means something to us,
it means something to a point.
But the most important thing is the lens
and the actual,
the,
the quality of photo.
That's why.
Okay,
that makes sense.
That makes a new.
The new iphone camera has a,
what most normal camels are just
switching to.
It's this a coil that goes around the
lens and it used to be where the coil
was in front of the lens optics.
So when you take a photo,
uh,
the,
the light has to go through all these
coils in order to take a photo.
So now they found out how to fight the
coil on the back.
So the light,
there's more light that goes in that
goes in there.
So many calls that the Xmo our lens,
whatever it's called,
but now so now this new iphone's going
to have better low light just because
they decided to do this new coil
technology.
So that alone photo,
quality megapixel doesn't mean shit.
It really means something.
Now Brian,
you're getting crazy.
No,
no,
no.
I'm being serious.
Megapixels did not mean shit anymore
when it comes to like five megapixels
and above eight megapixels,
like 10 to 12 megapixels.
There's nothing.
Eight to 12.
There's barely anything,
but it still means something.
Unless you're doing billboards.
It's what's important is the lens and
how important the software they use.
It's also important.
You know what kind of,
you know how the.
That's why you have these Carl Zeiss
lenses and shit on all these different
phones.
You know,
they're trying to get the dopest lens as
possible.
Yeah,
I agree.
Over a certain point it's negligible and
you're a bad motherfucker.
You knowledge of all this shit is
unbelievable.
You frequent it comes to this stuff.
But what I think of the iphone,
who knows when I get it,
but God it,
they just solved everything.
They got the video camera sucked.
I use it all the time,
but it's not now it's HP.
It's.
Yeah,
that's still true.
for sure.
But it's even,
you know,
for me,
I barely talk on the phone anyways.
I really don't give a shit.
What I care about is video pictures and
texting.
That's huge.
And emails and stuff and then you get on
twitter and all that stops to a
credible.
I don't care about talking to Peter's
applications
on your phone that you can time rounds
with.
It was like a gym boss where you can
time your workouts,
you can,
it's a free application to you.
You could set it so that it'll like,
it'll put interval training into your
workouts and give you like different
alarms like when you run and when you
stop,
when you rest,
when you go.
I mean the flash,
that Webcam at the HD video,
five megapixels,
God damn think
these,
um,
these new droid phones are catching up
though.
They're totally catching up and I hope
they beat the iphone,
but the problem is if all these droid
user saying,
Oh fuck,
fuck,
iphone,
no,
get this.
How's your facebook and you want to do
like a comparison.
How is your facebook on your application
facebook and compared to iphones,
apple,
twitter in a while.
Right?
Don't they update those food?
I am on every single website everyday on
both the joy and everything.
I know exactly what's going on with
android versus iphone every day.
Oh no,
totally common.
Is that a common argument?
Dude?
It's common with down the line.
Every program that you get for the
iphone is it's way more fine tuned on
the iphone for some reason.
I don't know if it's on purpose or if
it's just the length or the,
you know that developers or what,
but like even the twitter applications
and the same with the palm tree.
The palm pre should have been fucking
the number one phone.
That should have been way bigger than it
was,
but the problem is every single
application like their facebook,
their twitter and everything,
it doesn't even come close to the iphone
and it's still
killed them.
You don't think that it was on sprint.
I can tell you as having a palm pre plus
that every single program that you can
download for that thing sucks.
Shit.
Compared to the iphone versions and the
pump has been out for a year plus longer
than the web.
So that'll be doing shit doing shit.
No,
they are.
It's interesting because the palm pre
was like the number one selling product
that a sprint that have launched as a
phone until this a htc evo came along
and they're saying this pump everything.
It's really what's.
What's interesting about it was it was
like the number one thing,
but then it petered out and nobody gives
a fuck about it.
You know,
like no one's like in line to get palm
trees.
Not at all.
Actually.
Remember the trio,
the trio with the trio.
You gave me a second.
The trio was the was.
That was the original trio was a brick
bro.
I remember wanting to bother me.
I remember when you gave me your trio,
dude,
that first day.
I couldn't believe it,
man.
I thought I was just.
I really thought like I had a fucking
time and watching.
I swear I thought.
I said,
look,
I just think it's so awesome.
I remember I had,
when I first got it,
I got it out of the box and everything
that I was playing with and I was like
looking at Wayne.
I was like,
this is the ultimate piece that's like
star Trek.
It's like a fucking computer in my
pocket,
man.
Never good thing.
Is the texting on the or
that.
Just the keyboard alone.
Have you ever used the keyboard?
No.
You know what I did use though,
that was pretty dope and I wish someone
would figure out how to do it.
I found sorta doesn't,
but I had with my Microsoft phone,
I had a windows,
windows mobile phones.
It knew the words that I was going to
use,
like if I would press a and then B,
it would.
Right,
absolutely.
If I've said that a bunch of times and
text before and then you just hit the
space button and you keep going onto the
next predictive texting.
Yeah,
but like,
like crazy good man.
It was really good.
It was really interesting.
The iphone always gets things wrong and
never wants to accept my swears.
I still wasn't changed.
Fuck to duck.
I mean,
how many times do I say this?
There's ways around that.
There's something like you just make a
new contact and you just put all the
cuss words you want in it or something
like I forget.
Something like that.
And so it looks it up.
Yeah,
I do.
I think you just make a contact and go,
fuck cock suck Dick Piss.
You know everything you want.
Yeah.
You just do it once a.
yeah,
I know,
but it's so silly.
Like why can't it remember swears?
Well,
the new operating system,
I guess as 100 times better when it
comes to all this,
like the Vocab,
that dictionary that everything and it's
got.
Now we finally get multitasking.
Now Brian's got an apple phone or on
your fan.
Boy,
I'm not a fan boy because I'm with any
kind of technology.
I try them all and I.
I picked my man.
I'm just teasing you.
How many phones,
how many phones have we both between
you?
Haven't we always go right back to the
iphone.
The iphone is most certainly the best
all around device without a doubt,
but my main phone,
I use a blackberry because it's verizon
because verizon is way better for me.
I need,
I need to make calls like that game's
over for me now.
Really?
I have no problems with a t and t
anymore and in Los Angeles.
Well my problems with a t and t are
driving,
driving from my house into legends.
Others.
There's three places where I would lose
people,
so if I'd be in a big conversation I'd
have to pull over because I didn't want
to.
I didn't want to lose the call.
If it was something that was,
you know,
it was serious.
I can't talk in my bedroom on the phone.
If,
if I,
if I want to talk,
I got to go to my living room if it's an
important call.
I walked down the street,
I actually,
I'm,
if you see me talking on the phone,
walking at some important as shit right
there,
don't bother me.
Eventually there's going to be no home.
Phone's right.
There is barely any home phones.
I hardly know.
My,
my dad doesn't even have a home phone
anymore and it's like some ancient shit.
You know,
home phone doesn't send no tax,
can't get pictures.
Just some stupid line where people call
you.
It's funny.
My mom lives in the middle of the
country.
Urgency in case the world ends.
You need a landline solar flares.
Fuck,
fuck up those satellites.
There was an article I was reading about
that about.
We're at a moment of the sons awakening
and that the next couple years is
unprecedented solar activity.
That's they predicted so unprecedented
solar flares that could wipe out
satellites and so what they're trying to
get really good at is predicting these
events so that they can shut down or put
these satellites on safe mode,
which is pretty nuts when you think
about how much we're reliant
on the satellites and you know for,
for satellite radio.
I can listen to it every day for,
you know,
for so many different things.
For GPS,
we're,
you know,
we're reliant on fucking satellites and
those motherfuckers can get cooked,
they can get cooked.
I mean,
at any time the Sun could just make some
hiccup,
a Burp,
a Fart,
and it just barbecues every fucking
satellite at cs.
They got to have backup satellites and
like just slow out there and protective
cases.
So if anything happens,
the other ones they just press a button.
That shit.
Yeah.
That opened the new case.
Boom.
What if they're gonna do
put shields over satellites like big
radiation shields that's going to have
to be the next field,
something like that before it's filled.
It's got to have something to do with
magnets and force fields.
Well,
yeah,
you're right.
Because that's what our gravity is,
right?
Our,
our,
our magnetosphere,
right,
right.
And the,
um,
the,
the gas that surrounds the earth and
you know,
our atmosphere,
we just suspend some gold dust particles
in the atmosphere will be fine.
Zacharias stitch and style.
So Eddie's a big proponent of the
ancient alien theory and a Eddie's the
first person that ever got me into
Zacharias Hitchin and we've had dude,
how many bones have we smoked?
Fucking talking about the auto lock.
We've had more,
more ridiculous
spaceman alien auto knocky
conversations,
ancient ancient tribe theories.
Shit where,
you know,
civilizations died off and left so much
information that was just last forever.
Like the Mayans and of course the
Sumerians and now sand the Sumerians
talk of an even older civilization
before then.
So Eddie,
Eddie's the one that got me into
the first.
Scott,
right?
It's about Redondo,
No,
no,
no.
He actually,
he brought it up to me.
No,
he brought it up,
but I didn't.
It never registered.
He goes,
dude,
listen to this radio station coast to
coast.
There's like 10 years ago.
And I never listened to Scott.
But Gina,
the first girl I produced musically,
she's about as crazy as they come.
And she's.
She was talking about a party,
talented girl,
super,
super talented singer,
but crazy.
She goes,
oh my God.
I was at this party last night and this
guy was talking about how we recreated
as slaves to mine gold for aliens on
another planet.
I'm like,
oh my God,
shut up.
Shut the fuck up.
Because no,
everybody was tripping out on this guy
talking about this.
This.
I'm like,
aliens made us as slaves to mine gold.
Shut the fuck up.
Let's get to work.
So I thought about it later on that day,
that whole day I thought about it and I
and I,
and I thought it was weird that it's
crazy as all that sounded.
It is weird that the one thing that we
all agree on,
every culture,
every race,
we can agree on shit,
politics,
religion,
nothing.
But we all agree that gold is worth more
than money.
That gold is the universal money.
And I thought that was weird.
I go,
hmm.
And then I thought about how the Aztecs
thought Cortez was a god and they gave
them gold and then the people,
the pharaohs that die and they get
buried,
they get buried with gold and like
thinking about this and like this.
Can I call Gina Gina?
What was this guy's name?
Do you have his number?
Because that was Jodie or some guy,
I think his name was Jodie,
so I called this guy and go,
hey,
I'm,
I'm a genius because what you were
talking about some gold and some slaves
and aliens.
What the fuck was that about?
And he didn't even really know.
He said,
you know what?
Yeah,
yeah,
I was talking about that.
Some guy told me it was weirdest thing.
I think his name is Syed Gen or are such
an or something sits in or something.
So I looked it up and I just got on the
Internet and I looked up sitch and
started getting into it and it blew me
away.
It's pretty fascinating shit,
you know,
as crazy as that sounds,
if you really look into it all,
all the basically it's,
it's this at Zachariah such as this guy,
the transcribed,
the ancient Sumerian text for like
20,000
tablets have all these stories and all
this shit.
Who knows what they really say because
very few people can actually transcribe
it.
Uh,
some people think Zacharias stitching is
crazy and he just making shit up.
Um,
some,
a lot of people believe him.
I mean,
he's got this,
a lot of smart people.
Well,
the interesting shit that he uncovers
and shows in his,
um,
in his videos that's just indisputable
is the images that the Sumerians left
behind.
That's where it gets really crazy
because there's images of a big giant
person with a small person.
It's a person,
but it has a tail like a monkey.
And you're like,
what the fuck is that?
They have the double helix,
the DNA double helix is there caduceus,
you know,
they have that in,
in their images.
What if it was just like a Fez ben guy
that walked around the tribe,
you know,
that it's dressed up as a cat in
somebody's true.
Oh,
you know what I mean?
It could,
it could be.
But here's the other thing,
they also had a detailed depiction of
the solar system.
They had a picture of the sun and then
they had the picture of the planets in
the,
with the proper size in the proper orbit
orbit.
And on top of that,
their,
their whole history there,
you know,
there's the,
in the Sumerian text it talks about the
different planets,
it talks about your readiness and it
talks about Neptune,
you know,
it talks about the creation of earth.
They have the exact same theory that we
have as far as the creation of the moon.
The theory is that Earth one,
there was an earth,
it was like billions of years ago,
it got hit with a planet and created the
moon.
And now we are earth to post impact.
Now this is something that scientists
had just recently embraced over the past
few decades,
but sitch and wrote about this shit way
back in the seventies.
I mean,
this was,
this was at the Sumerian said,
you know,
the guy,
if you watch his,
his documentaries and you listen to such
and talk and get his shit online,
it is fucking fascinating.
You know,
and I'm not saying that,
you know,
some aliens made us as you know,
as a race of slaves.
But I am saying that the world is so
crazy as it is the,
the fact that we could send photographs
to people and you can get video,
download it from your phone and you can
basically answer any question that
immediately by pressing,
you know,
google or are they
the Google thing where you know,
you talk into it and you say,
you know,
what year did Columbus sail,
blah blah blah,
and it'll give you the information.
Like instantly this has never happened
before.
Man,
there's this crazy shit and it's only
gonna get crazier now.
If we live a 100,000
years longer and stayed alive and
managed to keep evolving,
for sure,
we would get to the point,
would be able to travel to other planets
and find other species that we thought
weren't advanced enough and fuck with
them if we decided a certain point in
time with all this investigation that
we're doing into live,
like what they're doing right now with
synthetic cells where they are creating
cells,
creating cells,
and eventually creating living
organisms.
This is all really going to happen.
If we get to the point where we realize
that life itself is just a code that we
can manipulate and change to our will,
well when that happens,
man,
you're not going to think anything's
wrong with taking some monkeys and
making them smarter and having them work
for you,
you know,
and if there's a super intelligent being
or,
or race of beings that's thousands of
years advanced from us or millions or
perhaps even a billion,
you know,
what if they live in a protected solar
system where they don't have to worry
about asteroids,
what if the asteroid impact is,
is not a common thing would if,
you know,
all this shit that happens in our solar
system is kind of rare.
And in other solar systems,
they don't have media problems.
I mean,
if that's the case,
if that's true,
they could be a billion years older than
us.
We don't fucking know.
We have no idea.
Yeah.
Uh,
basically switching was one of very few
people,
again,
that transcribed over 20,000
tablets and these tablets were all like
in detailed descriptions of how they can
down the names of the rulers.
And the South American ones,
they real technical shit about how it
all went down.
He transcribed all that shit in the
seventies and uh,
and he put all this information out,
all this information that he wasn't,
he's saying that he wasn't making it up.
He was just transcribing all these
stories and people are,
or a lot of people,
you know,
his daughters were like,
well,
he's full of Shit.
How could he know this?
And how could he know that?
But the few things that he did know in
the seventies that,
uh,
we were just figuring out now,
one in his transcriptions,
he talked about how the Sumerians knew
that Uranus and Neptune were both water
twins and we just found that out in the
eighties that they actually are water
twins.
That was new.
How the hell did such a know this?
Another thing is such.
And the basis of the story is aliens
need our acumen.
They look just like us.
They're just,
they're supposedly.
And uh,
we'll,
uh,
maybe taller or whatever.
But are they way better looking than
they need our gold to ces to turn into
gold dust,
to suspend in their atmosphere,
to protect their atmosphere.
That's what they need.
He's talking to them from radiation.
Yes.
That's what he's talking about.
And the seventies and the
transcriptions,
he's not an astrophysicist.
We just found out like in 2001,
2002 that that's exactly how you protect
atmospheres.
You take metallic particles and you
suspend them in the atmosphere to,
you know,
either keep radiation and or out.
We just figured that out.
How the hell did this guy figure out
through the.
And he's saying,
well,
he didn't know he transcribed.
He,
he did.
He just guessed that that's the way we
protect atmospheres.
He already talked about that.
There's a lot of.
I mean,
he gets into details a lot of shit that
makes it like home.
Wow.
There's a lot.
There's a lot to.
It sounds crazy and we don't have all
day to talk about it,
but have an open mind.
It's fascinating stuff.
I thought it was towed to the thinking.
There's a,
there's a bunch of debate about this
planet Nibiru and there's a guy who's
got a website called [inaudible].
Sitchin is wrong and his website is
stitching is wrong.com,
and this guy does not believed that
there was,
that there's this planet Nibiru and he
has the quotes to tax.
It's really involved and I haven't
really looked into it.
I don't know who the fuck is right and
who's wrong.
I really don't,
but I do know that the,
just all the shit that came out of that
one area is really fascinating and when
you find out that one part of the world
is responsible for the first
mathematics,
the first astronomy,
first astrology,
first written language first,
use the wheel first.
Everything first agriculture was Iraq.
It's Iraq because Iraq.
Yeah.
Crazy fucking nuts.
First organized.
Well,
that's why they're so fucked up.
That's why I've always said that that
part of the world,
the reason why there are laws are so
archaic.
They're like the townies of the world.
Those are the people that were there
when civilization was created and
they're still rock.
They're still rocking that ancient law.
You know,
you dance,
we throw rocks at you,
you fuck someone from the other tribe,
you show your ankles,
we throw rocks at you.
Why is.
Why is an agent that's smart though have
now has not progressed like they
stopped.
Everybody moved out to California,
left like,
what is California?
California is the group of people that
landed somewhere else new.
It sucked and move to the best box.
Eventually you figure out that the best
Bot of southern California,
you're figuring out,
wait a minute,
there's a spot where it never gets so
cold that it's knows okay.
There's no hurricanes.
You have to worry about earthquakes
every now and then,
but there's no lightning as worst
traffic in the rural.
It was the worst traffic in the world,
but like as far as rules that climate
has nothing.
It has nothing to do with climate.
Yeah.
It's like the climate here is the reason
why everybody flocks to this place.
It's way easier to live here.
No,
that is true.
It's like a club promoters.
When a club in La,
when a club rises and falls,
the club promoters don't die with the
club.
They just find a new location and they
just keep moving the original club with
some area.
It was blowing up,
it was going off.
Then it closed down,
the promoters moved to Egypt,
they blew that up for awhile.
That shit close down.
People got tired of Egypt,
then they blew it up in Israel that have
change all the names and in all their
uh,
um,
their stories of creation.
Then it went to Rome and then it split
off and then it ended up in England and
Germany and the united.
It's totally okay.
That makes
sense of that part of the world is
backwards because it's just like going
back home.
I mean,
that's what I'm talking about.
It's like going back home,
if I went back home to Boston and hung
out,
I would think like,
God,
like the dudes I went high school with
like two,
you're,
you're still living in this fucking this
crazy land.
Like why didn't you escape?
And that's like what it's like in air.
It's like Sumir,
you know,
it became Iraq and everybody eventually
moved on to other places of the world,
people who weren't satisfied with where
they were and how life was,
if that's where all human beings
supposedly came from,
everybody who left as a people that were
trying to find something better.
It kind of makes sense.
It kind of makes sense that if
everybody,
if that really is the cradle of
civilization and everybody left from
there and trying to find something
better,
of course the people that are remained
suck just totally make sense.
Dom didn't suck.
How dare you,
how dare you,
how dare you.
How dare everybody listening to this at
this point in time stolen.
Motherfucker get him to the Greek.
Eddie,
did you like it?
I loved it.
I love.
What would you rate it as?
Five stars?
Not quite as good as hangover,
but right under hangover,
like,
uh,
it was,
I thought it was really good,
man.
I laughed out loud.
At least 10.
There was a good 10 times where I was
like,
aw,
they killed it.
That dude,
the main dude,
the fat guy,
he's awesome.
I love that guy.
He is pretty good.
That guy is bad.
He's funny and every they must let him
go off because it's not a coincidence
that he always has great lines and you
know,
who impressed me fucking p diddy is
acting was like 80 percent on.
It wasn't,
but it was way better than fifty cents.
It was an academy award winning
performance.
But he pulled it off and he made me
laugh too.
There's an argument with that one rnb
singer member with the pink shirt.
What's that guy's name?
That was hilarious,
dude.
That was funny dude.
It was so funny that putting it in,
putting it in the previews now that's
part of the pre.
So don't,
don't give any spoilers away.
But uh,
I love that Russell brand go to diddy
was the probably the best part about
that movie though.
He was good and I posted that on my
twitter.
That was one of the worst movies I've
ever seen in my life.
It was so ridiculous.
You can splice.
No,
you could tell.
She didn't think I could tell.
I thought that made me look bad.
Bad Ass.
I was so looking forward to that movie,
I was like,
did it die?
A horrible death at the box office.
It actually didn't do that good.
I wasn't in the top.
It got 70 something percent on rotten
tomatoes.
But listen how crazy this movie is.
Okay.
This guy has his girlfriend,
they're both scientists.
They're doing all these experiments with
human DNA and they figured out how to
synthesize human DNA with a animal DNA.
I phenols lizards or some shit.
I don't know what the fuck I spliced it
with.
So uh,
they just wanted to see if they could do
it.
So they.
So she closes the door and does it,
you know,
like,
like.
So he like,
he can't stop her and he runs in and she
presses the button.
It's like really ridiculous and she
makes this half human being half animal
lizard fucking thing.
Whatever the fuck it was.
It's the source.
So goofy.
So they raised this is,
this is a person.
Yeah.
All spoiler.
Like a motherfucker
plug your ears.
Yeah,
I'm still gonna.
See it.
You're you to see this.
Okay.
Because I have a feeling that I'm going
to like it because I've,
I've read,
I've actually,
because after you made me not see
it,
and then so then I kind of got angry and
then I said I was talking to him with
some friends of mine and they said,
dude,
what is he talking about?
That movie was fucking awesome.
Oh my God.
You like Nacho Libre?
And we walked out.
No,
no,
no.
That's a libra was just you guys walking
now.
So dumb in three minutes.
No you don't.
No,
you don't know how dumb this will.
This movie makes Nacho libra looked like
it was awful,
but you guys only gave me like three or
five minutes or something like you're
like,
was bad,
was offensive.
It was hurting my hand.
There's no way.
There's no way they had.
They had like 20.
I gave him 20 attempts at jokes to
people in the front lap and I'm like,
damn,
these are their drugs.
Like if you're waiting this long to
throw in some funny shit,
there's no way that ending's going to be
good
black fan.
I think he's hilarious.
I love his movies.
I love that rock and roll high.
Whatever the fuck it was rock school.
That was good.
It was really good and he was excellent
in tropic thunder.
Green that King Kong.
I haven't seen tropic.
Still haven't seen tropic thunder.
It's one of my,
that's for sure.
Hangover.
Tropic thunder is a for sure.
Hang on.
Okay,
I'll see it.
I keep fucking putting it off.
But um,
yeah,
I mean that movie was whatever this,
the splice is way worse.
Just the splice.
Pluggers bitch.
I will see it by this.
This is how crazy it is.
They make this thing okay.
Grows really quick.
Okay.
And all of a sudden it's from a baby.
It grows like almost instantly to a
grown woman.
So they have this grown woman alien
thing and they don't know where to keep
her.
So they keep her in a storage room.
They're like,
nobody goes down there.
So they set up a bedroom in the fucking
storage place where they work and the
fucking alien.
They're okay.
The thing's only been alive for like a
couple months and then Adrian Brody
fucks it.
No,
now I got to see it,
so fucking not only is it an alien,
like we'll crazy.
It's got a tail,
a fucked up legs and everything,
but it's also three months old.
He's fucking this thing.
It's three months.
Her body,
she's got tits and she's kind of like
sexy looking.
It's like they took a sexy chicken.
Just did some CGI on her.
Wow.
Yeah.
She escaped and eats a rabbit.
She escapes and she can fly.
She's got wings.
She flies.
She lands in Eatsa fucking rabbit and
then not even freaking out.
They're like,
why are you doing that?
Don't do that.
Stop.
It's ridiculous.
It's so bad.
I'm going to see it.
That sounds good,
Brian.
So you know why you know why he did.
He has to go see it.
Yeah.
It has to be.
I'm not hurting it.
Let me tell you something.
Don't you wish that this movie is so
goddamn bad?
I think it might turn into one of those
movies that's like a cult hit because
it's so bad.
People are going to go see it
again.
I.
This is what I did hear about it.
I heard that there was actually
personally that we're supposed to be
funny now.
It has nothing to do with it.
Like a humor to where I try to be funny
if they were there,
they said it in an interview that a lot
of people aren't getting the humor of
the movie.
Oh my God.
You mean the whole movie,
the whole movie.
It's like,
are you sure that you weren't baked and
you didn't get like the humor like
serious or something?
I wasn't big at all.
In your defense,
Brian,
I think he might like it because you're
like crazy shit like that.
Nobody liked him.
If you go in wanting to see something
ridiculous,
you're going to like it,
but if you go in thinking you're going
to get the shit scared out of you.
Like some new alien movie.
That's what I thought it was going to
be.
When I saw like it was just like she was
threatening the in in the previews looks
like she's threatening one of the
scientists.
I'm like,
oh,
they create something and it's fucking
crazy and it gets out of control and
it's scary.
I'm to see it this week and I can't wait
to discuss it.
I can't wait to discuss it with you.
I might bring a bag of rocks thrown at
you because there has been.
There has been movies that,
that,
that we totally disagree.
It's kind of funny how people get upset
when someone likes something.
They don't like iphones yet.
Like anything.
What about my group or did you like the
group or.
But I,
when I first saw the preview,
I thought it looked like the dumbest
fucking movie I've ever seen in my life
and I heard his awesome dog shit.
I heard it was awesome.
No,
I heard of dogs really like group.
I haven't heard a thing I haven't heard
of.
It was stupid on snl.
How the hell did they make a movie?
Review looks retarded and SNL is like
one of those things.
It's really been kept alive because of
youtube clips.
You know,
when a good snl sketch gets on youtube
and makes you want to watch snl again?
It was,
I would have no notice are kept alive by
Andy Sandler,
whatever his name is,
who's at the young guy that makes all
those skits like on a boat and stuff.
That dude's hilarious.
Oh,
is he the one that's.
I've never seen that sketch,
but I heard that song.
Yeah.
He's,
he's.
He does all these like little skits on
Saturday night live and it makes the
show in my opinion that in that one main
girl on there.
That's hilarious.
Dude.
I haven't watched that live in years.
I haven't watched it in so long.
A good monologue on youtube or something
like that.
There's just certain shows that after
awhile I'm like,
that's it.
Done.
I can't.
I can't keep coming back to that.
Well,
you know,
you fucked me too many times.
Andy Sanberg.
That's why I got into.
Just got into true blood.
You guys.
Oh No.
I watched half an episode and I was just
silliness to watch it from the first
time I've watched.
I've won so goddamn tired of vampires
don't eat people kind of nonsense
people.
Barely.
Well,
they got to do,
you know the premise of it?
Yeah.
They have some fake blood that they use
and they finally came out.
Vampires or it's like,
you know,
it's like,
why do you like that show?
I did get bored.
I like,
that's like mixing vampires with Gilmore
girls.
That's the worst shit ever.
Man.
That's so gay.
I only watched someone.
You got to see if I've seen.
I've seen the first whatever season,
two seasons or whatever,
two seasons and stop after five.
There's been many shows where I've
watched because of my girlfriend,
so that's one of them,
that bandwidth to see sex and the city
to 50 times better than that show.
But no,
that show to me was just,
I can't,
I couldn't even.
I was amazed that people like that show.
I thought I liked the purpose.
I like it a texture and the other guy,
I never watched that show.
I watched dexter.
I never watched the show,
but I did watch half an episode and I
was like,
you know what?
I have just hit vampire overload.
Too many fucking vampire shows.
Man.
It's too silly.
There's too many different rules that
people are making up for vampires now.
Like,
oh,
they can go on the light,
but they just sparkle like,
fuck you,
man.
No,
there's some rules for vampires.
All right.
The rule is if you're gonna,
drink people's blood.
When the sun comes out,
you fucking die.
Bitch.
You supposed to hide.
You hide in the dark.
He can't be going to high school walking
around with everybody because it's
cloudy.
That's retarded.
This is stupid.
This is fucking.
You can't keep doing this.
And it's like it's.
It's to me,
it's a symptom of our culture.
All these vampire movies are a symptom
of our culture.
We live in fact empires for real.
The reason why people are so into this,
it's like when you,
when,
when you look at like how infantiles our
culture is,
we want to believe that you know that
there is silly fake shit out there like,
like vampires.
We believe so much retarded shit as far
as just what the government feeds us.
The news feeds us and with corporations
feed us and you know our,
our perceptions of how we have this
world under control and everything's
fine and no wars are just and all the
crazy shit that we justify ourselves
doing.
If we can believe all that shit,
you know,
why not fam powers?
It's a fucking half a step away,
step away.
Is there a movement or their websites
about people that really have evidence
that vampires really.
There's people that.
People who've committed murders because
of that,
because they believe they're vampires.
Totally.
There's people that think they're
werewolves.
You know,
they take their fucking clothes.
Oh,
the yellow.
There's,
there's people that shaped their teeth
and fangs.
Eddie.
There's people that shaved their teeth
and fangs point in time.
It's like,
yeah,
okay,
look,
the guy's not undead and yeah,
he's not.
He's not going to live forever and he's
not going to drink people's blood to
stay alive,
but people are crazy enough to think
that they are vampires.
Truly to truly believe it and actually
go out and murder somebody and drink
their blood.
People are that nuts,
man.
What if that's real shit?
If you're a fucking complete and total
loser and you have nothing going on in
your life,
your life is unbelievably bad and the
only thing that's exciting is the
thought of biting someone's neck and
sucking their blood out and kill them.
Do you guys look at that?
Buyers are have hockey blood and they.
Did you hear about.
Did you guys hear about that case in
Texas?
I think it was 2006 slash six slash six
slash 2006 with a woman named her kids
after Satan.
Like they were named after like satanic
names and then on that day she murdered
them on and I drank their bladders.
Oh my God.
Really?
I think it was 2006.
Oh Man.
That Satan thing is the surest sign that
you're fucking bananas if you believe in
Jesus.
That's one thing.
It seems like,
you know,
I mean maybe there was a real person
that existed,
but all the magic things attributed to
him really.
And you're gonna believe that just
because it was a long time ago.
That seems to be,
to me completely silly,
but it's acceptable.
It's like,
okay,
I understand where you're coming from.
I understand that's what you believe.
I understand.
You know,
everybody has their own point of view,
but when you start talking about
devil's,
you started talking about Satan like
Jesus Christ.
Really you think there's a fucking bad
man who's pulling strings and tempting
you with pussy and cigarettes and you
really,
you think that's real.
That is a devil makes you make bad
decisions and and it makes you rape and
beat people up and you think the devil's
doing that tempting.
You Die.
That's so infantiles.
It's amazing that people even consider
it and we know that there's,
there's a part of us that knows that
talking about the devils.
Ridiculous.
That's why you don't hear the president
talking about it.
The president will always talk about
God.
He'll never talk about the devil,
the president that may God bless our
troops.
You know,
we believe that God is on our side.
Like Bush said,
a bunch of Wacky God shit.
Never once did he say,
we have found Satan and he's in Iraq.
We know where Satan is.
What we're going to drill to the core of
the earth until we find tracks.
Say You met,
you've met him at all.
You mentioned st at all and you're
fucking crazy.
You can say,
you know,
we believe we have found the actual
cross that Jesus was nailed on and
people will go,
wow,
holy shit.
You can say,
we think we've found where Satan used to
live.
They'll get the fuck outta here.
You what?
Huh?
You could actually say you can be an
archeologist and you can say,
we believe we found the cross that Jesus
was nailed on.
But if you say,
we think we found the box where Satan
lived in,
people would go,
shut the fuck up.
They wouldn't even talk to you.
They wouldn't even take you serious for
a second.
There we go.
This is crazy.
Asshole thinks he found where the devil
lives.
Isn't that crazy?
Satan is a force.
Dude.
It's not a person.
It's not a real guy,
man.
Isn't he a fallen angel?
I'm confused.
I mean isn't he supposed to be.
He used to be cool and they touch a
shitty with God.
I'm sorry for going off on true blood.
I'm on just on team Jacob and it kind of
gets to me
brother.
It's all right man.
Again,
Werewolf.
So don't eat people.
That's another thing.
We want our Goddamn cake and we want to
eat it too.
We want all the sexy and none of the
murder were willful.
Stupid,
right?
Or Wolf or you know.
One of the wolf man was stupid,
but I bought it on DVD because I'm such
a sucker for fucking horror movies.
That's how much I love horror movies by
mediocre horror movies and watch them on
DVD fighting it.
They put it on the background while I
was writing nightmare on elm street.
The new one.
Did he it?
No,
no.
Brian.
Now like that actor though.
That's that dude from the watchman.
He's a the new Freddy Kruger.
The dude who played a roar shark,
but why?
What's wrong with the old Freddy Krueger
Dan?
You got an.
You've got an actor just to look like
Freddy Kruger.
That's one character you can play until
he is 98 because the older he isn't real
life cut out the old freddy when he was
the shit.
There was no one.
The problem is he became a joke or
money.
You want it too much money.
Maybe because I mean seriously,
the new guys just had makeup on to look
like the old guy,
you know,
so there's not really any reason other
than that.
He looked a little different.
Yeah,
it looked a little creepier.
I saw some pictures of it online.
I didn't see the movie,
but it looks a little new guys.
Is he young?
He said No.
Well he's a little younger player
himself.
Was this like a preschool like they
showed?
No,
no,
I didn't
see it as that may have been tasked with
Robert England in [inaudible] 75.
I thought it was just a Redo.
I just thought it just rebooted it.
Maybe it is Robert England.
Is he in bad shape now?
I mean,
I think I saw on the news he was upset
about it was like,
why didn't you just.
You're saying,
well,
when you try to reboot something,
you want to do a different actor.
I mean how many goddamn times they got
to do the hawk,
you know,
they did the Eric Bana One and they
liked.
What about,
what about Captain America?
Why aren't they doing it again?
Or they're trying it again or I don't
know.
I know they did one back like what?
Ten years ago.
We're just one though because they did
it like a couple of years after the old
one.
The Eric Bana came out and then like two
or three years later,
the fucking Edward Norton one came out.
When is wonder woman coming up to play
wonder woman for Scarlett Johansson too?
She's got some big titties though.
She's got it.
She's built like wonder woman.
She's got that wonder ass.
Just am a woman.
Got to be tall.
Yeah,
but you can make a tall.
Just put her with a bunch of short
people.
You put up with a bunch of short people
and you give her high heels and that's
how Tom Cruise rocks in his movies.
You know,
you just give a little lift and put them
around people that are installing them.
I wonder what the tallest guy has to
start with.
Tom Cruise.
Probably Brad Pitt talked about how they
had scenes where he.
Tom Cruise had to like stand on planks
and shit.
Really try to make them appear to be the
same height pit.
Let's throwing them under the fucking
throwing them under the bus,
but they were talking about it in the
interview and Brad Pitt was confirming
it.
What about advantage Lily Lily doing
that?
Make that up.
I might have made that up.
Wonder woman,
the girl from last kate from last.
That'd be hot wonder woman.
Yeah,
she's pretty hot.
that would work.
Megan Fox got to be wonder woman for
sure.
That no one.
No one would question.
It was interesting.
An interesting conversation I read with
Brad Pitt talking about Tom Cruise,
about working on that movie together and
something about.
Yeah,
yeah.
Interview with the vampire is saying
that he wished that something that he
wished Tom Cruise wasn't so competitive.
Something that you wished they could be
better friends with.
Tom Cruise was a more competitive,
I wish I remember the quote,
I hope I'm quoting it correctly,
but uh,
that's fascinating,
you know,
for sure because Brad Pitt was just
coming up.
That was the new guy just coming and Tom
Cruise,
like he,
you know,
he um,
a campaign for that role,
you know,
he wanted that role.
A lot of people did not want him to play
that vampire,
you know,
like the,
and the,
and rice people didn't take him
seriously because her work was so
serious.
It was such good writing.
And they thought Tom Cruise's,
cheeseball actor who did top gun,
all these stupid movies,
you know,
like this guy can't play lists.like
this,
like really intense vampire.
But goddamn that little free connect.
He pulled that shit off strong man.
How good was that?
A great movie.
One of the greatest Goddamn vampire
movie son.
That's the real shit,
you know?
I mean,
that's,
those are scary monsters trapped in a
person's body.
They're a person,
you know their,
their,
their soul is trapped in this scary
monsters bought and it needs to eat
people.
That's that movie was bad ass.
The little girl.
Kristen dunst.
How fucking creepy was she?
That little chicken act man in the lost
boys.
Dude.
C'Mon Bram stroker's was the past.
Come up with a good one,
man.
Gary Oldman,
the motherfucker crushes.
He's the motherfucker dude.
He's that guy.
He's the best.
I think he,
he gets into roles more than anybody.
Does he like transforms like that when
we played that fucking drug dealer and
true romance.
Oh good.
Was that shit?
Fuck yeah.
That movie was the ghetto white guy.
Yeah.
To do with the dreadlocks.
Have you been following Gary Coleman?
Shit around lately.
I've been.
I've heard Anthony from opie and anthony
say that he thought that Gary's wife
killed them.
Well,
she was trying to sell photos of him
laying in bed uh,
minutes before he died to tmz.
Did you?
That got photos and she sold them.
Somebody bought them,
but she was shopping around.
She took a bunch of photos of him in
bed.
Like,
I guess I'll fucked up right before she
died.
The nurses and doctors all solid and
then she shopped around the photos and
somebody just bought him I guess today
or yesterday.
How fucked up is that?
Oh my God.
He must have had a real attorney deck.
Huh?
Sometimes short guys.
It's like mini me sometimes.
Short guys have big ass Dick.
So it balances itself filed,
but he probably was short.
It doesn't,
it,
it didn't matter.
Even if he had a big Dick,
he's,
he,
you know,
he's just got it helped.
It would have helped the troyer is
hanging in there.
He's partying.
Oh,
that guy's depressed.
As celebrity rehab show.
That was horrendous.
Celebrity Rehab.
Troy,
who was the biggest disaster of all
time.
Not bigger than Tom size.
Oh my God dude.
Because I only saw last season that is
the best show on TV,
celebrity rehab,
but I haven't seen anything from troy
was like pissing in his room.
Like what did,
he was crawling and celebrity rehab.
What was it that was,
um,
that was uh,
the one with the,
uh,
the time is a guy,
right?
Like all the,
all the level of celebrity celebrity
house or someone's going to talk about
it.
It wasn't celebrity rehab.
I saw what you're talking about.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He was pissing all over himself.
He's on this little buggy driving around
a little buggy.
Anyway,
the point is,
I don't think that guys that happy.
I think he's a mess.
Thank God we have webster.
I follow him on twitter.
I follow.
I'm going to follow him today.
What is it?
Something like that.
It's surreal life.
Thank you everybody there.
Yet@twitter.com,
backslash tiny poop,
I think.
Yeah,
man.
I think that's,
that's gotta be one of the greatest
tortures in life.
To be deformed.
Trying to make fun of your deformity to
make a living.
You know,
but think about that most.
Most people,
you look at someone with no arms,
no legs,
and really like our first instinct is
like,
damn,
he's never going to be truly loved.
He's not going to be desired.
Like Q.
Imagine being this person who is not
desired.
No one wants to sexually,
you know,
but really when we're all eventually
going to be there because like,
like I'm sure a hot 22 year old
supermodel would rather fuck a gray
maynard.
Not Gray maynard.
What's his name?
Uh,
what's that?
The guy
with no arms,
no legs.
Oh,
Kyle.
Kyle maynard.
Some 90 year old man.
You know what I mean?
We're all good at.
We're eventually going to get there.
We're going to be just so it's how much
people want to fuck you is the quality
of your life,
but that,
that's the instinct.
That's when you look at someone who's
deformed or like,
oh my God,
no one's ever going to love them because
girls are programmed to stay away
sexually.
Generally for burn victims.
People who are amputees,
we all are.
Cripples.
Yeah.
We are the natural things that when we
look at someone who's in a wheelchair,
we think,
fuck,
that sucks.
He's so young and he's fucked,
but eventually we're going to get there.
They just got it in advance.
We're all going to walk through that
fire unless we die early,
but we're all going to be just as
desired as that person,
so it's something to think about.
It's like really?
What's life all about?
You got to,
we're all going to end up living half
our lives at least where no one wants to
fuck up.
How are you?
How are you going to handle things?
Bigger issue is that they don't have
freedom.
They're locked in a trap of a body and
they never get to be a normal person.
They're surrounded by other people that
are normal.
That's the torture man.
It's not just whether or not people want
to fuck them.
Yeah,
but Eddie isn't in that like you're.
You're going to get.
It's hot in here.
If you're going to get married though,
you're again,
50 percent of that time,
you're going to be with somebody.
Maybe that doesn't want to be desired by
most people either,
but you both are undesirable together.
I do.
You know,
you go 20 years without having sex.
Twenty years it desirable
bolting is,
is as much of a,
you know,
as a factor with those people as why me?
Why did I get fucked?
Why am I the person with this terrible
situation when,
why can't I just be normal?
I don't even.
I mean sure,
everybody wants people to love them,
but I think what they really want is to
just not be a mess,
you know,
to not be a physical mess,
not be some sort of a genetic
aberration,
like the,
you know,
that's what the,
the feeling of,
the terrible feeling of pain is.
You know,
that's why these guys are all fucked up
and angry.
And Gary Coleman was angry as fuck
before he died.
You know,
you always hear about stories about him
yelling at people like he was.
He had to work a regular job.
Man.
He was working as a security guard.
Could you imagine people would just come
up to him and fuck with them all day?
Yeah.
The only reason I know that is because
the Dave Chappelle sketch that he did on
Gary Cole never saw.
Oh,
it's amazing.
It's amazing.
What did he do?
He plays Gary Cole and so he plays the
whole sketch on his knees.
Oh,
security and then some chicky chicks,
chicks fighting and then they cut to
like the chick biting into all bad.
It's so bad.
A Dahlan is security outfit and she's
tossing.
Gary called Raj.
He throws in the minutes.
His show is so ridiculous.
What was the one one,
a sketch where he was fighting King Kong
and hit King Kong or Godzilla.
Godzilla with it
for cutting down.
What the fuck was that?
It was so ridiculous.
Which was that sketch?
I don't know,
but remember when he.
He has that sketch.
It was the last season,
the unfinished season where he goes back
and.
And he fucks with everybody who told him
that the people that didn't believe in
them,
like club owners and all that stuff.
He blew up like the old club that he was
banned from any.
He fucked up his old acting teacher who
told him that he would never make it.
So it's like a sketch where he goes back
and then at the very end when he goes to
the comedy club to blow up the comedy
club,
he blows it up and he walks out and
there's like a,
a lady walking across the street and he
so on fire that he blew up at the club.
The club owner was in a wheelchair and
he threw him down the steps and let the
place on fire.
He takes his baby.
This random ladies cross the street,
takes Texas baby and punk kicks the
baby.
Right?
Just out of nowhere.
That's how to sketch Ed's like he was so
happy that he got his revenge.
He grabs this newborn baby kicks it.
Nothing to do with the Scott.
Plus his show was so ridiculous.
Remember the first episode of different
strokes with Mr.
Drummond took his two new boys,
Willis and Arnold and got it.
They all got in the hot tub together in
a.
we're all wearing tighty.
Whities.
No,
it was really creepy as a kid and it's
haunts me everyday when I.
Wow.
How weird is that?
Different strokes.
That was one of my favorite shots.
It's gross that up.
Todd was on fear factor and you know,
he's,
he's an angry dude.
He's got A.
I mean,
he kept it together for the most part up
until the part where uh,
he,
he lost,
he got eliminated.
He didn't even want to shake my hand and
walked away.
Wouldn't shake my hand.
Yeah,
he was upset.
He thought it was some sort of
conspiracy to make him lose.
I don't,
I don't exactly know what the fuck he
had to do or what it was,
what he was upset about.
But he decided he didn't want to shake
my hand.
I'm like,
wow,
now you see why this dude,
you know why his life is kind of fucked
up like his,
his automatic way of looking at things.
It's like negative is automatic way of
looking at things was like,
someone's out to get me.
Someone's fucking with me.
Oh,
it ain't going to be fair.
I'll,
I see how it is.
You know,
it's like automatically like,
dude,
this fucking six people on the show,
five of them have to be losers.
You got,
you're one of the five.
Shit happens,
man.
You got to move on with your life,
but not for him,
man.
He's an angry dude,
which is kind of interesting,
man.
We were talking about this before,
that toxo plasma.
That's that cat tranquilizer or are they
the cat parasite rather?
Um,
W,
we,
we talked about this on other shows
before,
but I watched a documentary yesterday.
I read some articles about it and this
thing called toxo plasma is a very
common parasite that human beings get
that completely alters our behavior and
get this in Brazil,
66 percent of the population is infected
with this toxo plasma.
And it does two things.
It makes women submissive and it makes
men reckless.
Jerks makes men assholes,
and it makes chicks submissive.
It sounds like,
um,
like Brazil ecstasy,
dude.
No,
no,
not like that.
It makes reckless.
It makes them cope and shit,
but no,
no,
it,
it reprograms the mind.
It's a parasite.
This is the crazy thing.
The parasite exists first in rats and
what it does with rats is it gets rats
convinced that rewires their,
their sexual brain,
the sexual aspect of the brain,
and it gets them to be aroused and,
and,
and connect it to cat piss.
So
these rats,
it hijacks their sexual system so their
sexual system all of a sudden become
sexually aroused,
like their testes swelled or ball swell
because they smell cat piss.
So these motherfuckers are searching
after campus.
So they're going towards where cats live
be were cats mark their territory.
They're,
they're attracted to that and they're
not afraid of cats anymore for whatever
reason.
So the cats obviously eat these rats
because the rats are retarded.
They stand there where the cats there
with their balls all swollen and a heart
on the Khakis.
Some the cat eats the rats than the cat
hangs around with people and we have to
clean the cat shit.
And when people clean the cat shit,
sometimes people touch the cat shit.
And if you touched the cat shit and it
gets inside your bloodstream through
either an open sore or maybe something
in your food or maybe an open,
you know,
your touch your eyes or something like
that.
That shit gets in your body,
man.
And $60,
million people in this country are
infected by it and it affects your
behavior.
It changes your behavior and get it from
low jobs.
Maybe you could get it from reading.
You can get it from touching raw meat as
well.
The um,
yeah,
it's 60 something million people in this
country are affected by and they said a
disproportion amount of people who die
in motorcycle accidents.
One of the things he was talking about
was that they would test motorcycle
accident victims for toxoplasma because
the toxo plasma,
this parasite that is,
you know,
this cat parasite makes people do
nobody.
Shit makes people wild.
Cats used to rule the rural and maybe
they used to like,
this needs to be bigger than it is.
And how.
Maybe that's what the thing is.
That's why we're getting rid of their
cats.
Are you getting rid of your cats from?
He's also maybe,
but then he'd be a woman pyramids,
but look,
if you think about Brazilians,
Brazilian men are notoriously
aggressive.
Brazilian women,
notoriously submissive and sexual.
You know,
maybe that's what it is.
I mean,
66 percent,
two out of three women of childbearing
age are infected with this parasite.
I wonder about something to do with
their assets if there's a connection.
Do you think that's quite a bit there?
They're asking.
I mean there's a reason.
There's a reason that 85 percent of all
women between the ages of 18 and 48 have
great assets in Rio.
There's,
there's got to be something and it could
be kept paths.
It could be the milk and why do cats,
but they're up in the air when you tap
on it because they want you to get that
dirty shit.
Yeah,
that's right.
It's like,
no,
look,
I got for you.
That's an interesting thing that you
said that because that's one of the
things that this one of these articles
were saying was that people who are
normally polite people when they sneeze
will sometimes inadvertently or
unconsciously turned towards people and
sneeze like they don't even realize why
they're doing it.
Like they.
They almost have an instinct that turned
towards people in Sneeze.
I've seen people do it before.
Wow.
Where they go like this,
like you're standing,
you're hearing,
you have like your body is trying to get
you to fucking blow a sneeze on
somebody.
This is the theory.
How many cats do you have?
Any possible?
If you think about what it does to cats
and what it does to people,
it's very possible that some viruses
could try to get you to be attracted to
people when they expel how many cats you
have.
I have to,
but
Joey Diaz has 10 or nine.
Fuck Cock sucker stopped bringing up my
cats.
Got a good amount.
Y'all need to get tested.
So here's the thing.
I'm being real here.
Oh totally,
dude.
If you think about that,
if,
if your cat has ever been outside and
you think your cat may have eaten a rat,
you know my cats,
I've never been outside of Brazil.
They leave those cats out a little bit.
What's the curator anyway?
You're fucked.
You might have to change the cat box
with condoms.
I.
No,
that's not a cure.
What would keep you from infecting other
cats from getting in your poor Cuba.
That's a preventive method.
Once you get it.
I don't think you could do anything
about it.
It's just a water bottle that you spray
yourself with.
Like,
you know,
it's fascinating.
We think about that your whole life
could get hijacked,
like some parasite could literally take
over your body and talk to your body and
to living a totally different life.
And what the doctor was talking about
this,
the scientists Soplasky I believe his
name is.
What he was talking about was that the
idea of free will is really an illusion.
Like there's a bunch of mitigating
factors that caused you to move in one
direction or another and it makes
certain decisions.
You know?
And so the thing that you have complete
free will,
is kind of silly if you go on Amazon,
there's a urine detector for cat urine
and if you ever buy it,
just be worn.
It doesn't just detect urine.
It detects a lot of gross shit.
So,
uh,
it's kind of cool.
What I like calm,
like if you put it on your bed,
it's just like every,
all this shit comes up.
It's pretty scary dude.
But you've seen those inside edition
things where they go to hotel rooms and
check the covers.
Oh Dude,
dude.
Just judges all over the covers.
It's like a Goddamn Jackson pollock
painting.
Every time you walk into a room with a
black light,
just loads everywhere.
Loads all the floor loads on the wall.
You'll find loads everywhere.
I have,
I've several times I've pulled out a
load and just just let it drip on the
fucking carpet in a hotel.
Have you ever thrown your just build in?
Might have.
I'm just not thinking about it.
I'm not judging.
You might have for sure,
but I can't remember any.
Do you ever throw your come on the wall
at a hotel room?
No,
never try it.
It's so awesome.
Just take a look.
Just throw it on the wall.
Spiderman is wrong with you.
Never done that to it.
That is the nastiest fluid.
It's really pretty much the same thing
as it's not,
you know,
phlegm,
but the fact that it also can make
babies,
you know,
it just makes it ultra nasty.
It's weird how some girls love the taste
of it and some girls don't get to choose
between eating a dude's snot and neat
and dudes load for sure.
You're going to go with snot as chicks.
Say if a guy's got a gun to your head
and you're either going to eat this
load,
are you gonna?
Eat some snow.
Like all right,
I'll eat your stock out of not.
It's just rude,
but what if this is not what's coming
from the guy's Dick?
Awesome.
That doesn't even make sense.
Somehow they put it in their ultimate
world.
Pack out like a pastry,
right?
Brendan?
Come from a tick or not from a dick.
Which one would you take?
One of those pastry things called let's
pastry scribes off cook measure.
You could do that stuff,
stuff so on.
Snow up your load of your Dick like that
and then squeeze it out.
Dick spit spit out like that one.
I'm going to use that.
Have you guys been to six flags lately?
No,
I just have.
I just found out I went.
It was like I live like 15 miles away
from it,
so I got a season pass to the pool when
stuff.
Fifteen months.
It's amazing though if you go on the
rides during the day i.
it's amazing like how like the people
that work there roller,
like if you go on the highest biggest
roller coaster,
you get the best employees I guess at
work,
at six flags.
But if you go on like that one boat that
just rocks up and down.
You obviously have the worst employees.
I had one guy and I swear to God I'm.
He might be like mentally handicapped by
that,
so I don't want,
you know,
but he's literally like,
like,
like seriously he's operating the
operating the right.
Like I don't even,
like I looked at him,
I'm like,
can I put my water bottle on the ground
here?
And he was like,
glassy stare.
Like he had no idea he was even there
and I recorded.
He's operating the ride.
Yeah.
Every will have a video of this video
but have his voice of hope of us getting
on the ride.
Oh my God.
And I'll play through the second year.
But it.
By the way,
Ben,
have you been on the roller coaster?
If they've been playing or that they
have out nowadays?
I will never do that extra.
It's not like.
It's not like a regular rollercoaster
around where you see where you're going.
You see the loops,
they flip you upside down,
you're upside down,
you're going bash.
Start out backwards.
It's fucking hard.
Rough all.
Yeah.
You guys,
there's no way you can't be sued.
My toes were curling.
Yeah.
That's the one that does like five
different,
like five dimensions or whatever they
say.
Is that the one you're talking about
where it's like spins up and down?
Why you're going upside down.
Got the video.
Here it is.
Alright.
Explain this again for people just
tuning.
All right,
this is the swing ride where you get on
like you know,
like to get on the ride and this is the
guy that knows a guy operating the Rod.
That was really dumb.
Scary.
I'm very scared though right now.
Listen.
Oh my God.
It's pretty incredible.
That's insane.
That guy is the guy who's operating this
fucking death machines and I,
like I had said,
I had said something to him and I had
said something to him and like he looked
at me right in the eye,
but it was like glass.
It was like,
wow,
this guy is not like this murder guy.
I mean,
you know,
maybe the dude is super responsible just
because he has this tremendous speech
impediment.
Maybe he's a super responsible super
conscientious guy.
May have ever thought maybe it was
death.
Maybe you can't hear people screaming to
stop the ride.
That can't be good if you're.
The fucking dude has got the hand on the
ride button.
Do that.
Ride was nothing.
Babies go on those lines.
I like.
It's like a merry go round with swings.
What was it?
Which one was it?
That one?
That one is the one we're just spinning
in a circle,
which is swings,
but,
but still,
I mean it's a ride,
you know,
and then.
Okay.
So you still think it's too dangerous
for retarded.
It's something.
Where's that happened?
Was,
do you think he got it?
What do you think was wrong with him?
I think he was special.
Maybe special,
special,
special Ed.
Special Olympics.
There's no way.
There's no way magic amount would hire a
retard.
Okay.
But with what?
If there's,
there's,
there's all sorts of levels of
impairment that human being suffer.
Maybe he passed the test,
like with colors and stuff.
Is there a test?
Probably.
What do you think the test is?
Like?
Colors and shapes and those shapes that
you put in,
like the circles.
That's why it seems like the test
wouldn't be there.
You know,
the odds of getting killed in one of
those accidents is very,
very slim.
But what had happens,
God town that must suck.
You know,
you put yourself on some wacky
rollercoaster,
flips you around,
you wind up dying.
He imagine hanging out with a dude,
we got to get a depth dude and on
crystal meth where he just can't shut
up,
shut up.
He's got so many stories to tell you.
By the way,
that guy was not deaf because when I
asked him that question,
he turned around when I asked him about
the water bottle,
it's way hollow,
so he's not,
he wasn't deaf.
So you think he maybe had some sort of
autism or something like that?
Maybe,
but impediment for sure.
Right.
How ridiculous is that on another ride?
Again,
it wasn't like the biggest,
right was like a,
it was called the Ninja,
which is a rollercoaster,
but uh,
they were going to check everybody's
like straps and stuff and the guy just
like,
you see them checking it.
Then he goes to mind.
You just touch it.
Like he just tapped it.
I'm like,
you weren't even lifting or any that,
you just touched it.
Just touching.
It does not check anything,
you know,
I think I was like,
did he just touch it?
Know what I mean?
Like how they lived it.
They assume that it's,
it can be loose and you can go flying
out.
Yeah,
and it would have fucking scary way to
die.
That must be.
And then there was this like this guy
that like he kept on Splat,
like we're waiting in line for like a
raft ride and it was really hot and so
every couple minutes he would like
splash.
Everybody that's in line with water.
Like he was the lifeguard.
Now he's the one that pushed you down
over the side in this raft for every
couple minutes who like splash you.
And he kept them like fucking kicking
water in my face.
So when I got up there I just started
fucking kicking water back at him and he
goes and he blew the whistle.
Go take.
We've got a problem here.
And I'm like,
wait,
I can't splash you.
You just got done fucking splashing me
for 15 minutes.
So now I'm feeling like I'm getting in
fights with people that are here to make
sure I'm part of the ride.
That he splashes you.
No,
no,
no.
This is while we're waiting in line and
he just being a dick,
he's just being a ticket,
like spraying people with water and he
was doing it like three.
He hit probably hit me like three or
five times.
While.
Did you ask him to stop?
No,
everyone.
Everyone aligned was like,
what the fuck?
Stop.
You know,
like there was like parents and stuff
and kids and the kids were.
The kids were liking it,
but you know,
it's like,
hey,
you're the kids will login.
Yeah,
but you know,
I splashed them back because like,
hey,
here's this thing that you have to
consider back to the subject of
parasites when you're at those water
parks,
man,
you have to be real careful of
swallowing that water.
That water is funky as fuck dude.
I saw and heard in the water.
Oh do no doubt there.
There's like a pool,
like a wave pool and then they have like
the small,
like pool for just like kids and stuff
like that.
I know a woman who was a nurse and her
daughter went to one of those parks,
swallow some water and got horribly sick
and became paralyzed.
She got some sort of terrible infection.
She was deathly ill and she wound up
with a limited use of her legs.
Man.
Wow.
These serious infections can fuck with
your.
Your whole system.
That's horrible infection.
You know Cole Escovedo,
you know,
call us,
can veto.
He had staff and he was paralyzed.
Man.
He almost couldn't walk again.
It took him like over a year to recover
from that shit.
You can get an infection,
dude.
That just wrecks your whole life and
those water parks are prime.
That water is not clean at all.
That water is death.
You swallow a mouthful.
That water,
like if you go to a water park with your
kids,
you got to be real upfront with them
about this.
You've got to say,
you cannot take this water in your
mouth.
This is bad.
Dangerous for real.
It sounds ridiculous,
but you really shouldn't take your kids
on those slides.
Are Those water rides?
They get a mouthful of that shit.
Your little four year old who doesn't
know any better.
They could get fucking deathly ill.
They could die.
Did you know you're not supposed to
swallow even eight drop of toothpastes.
Yeah.
Toothpaste has.
Fluoride is poisonous.
Yeah.
Fluoride is bad for you.
I used to as a kid when I was like drunk
driving.
I'll keep toothpaste in my car now like
put it in my mouth and switching between
mouth and swallow it dying now.
That's why you're rotting out from the
inside.
That's why you got that cat piss gone.
It's fighting the cat piss dude.
It's no joke,
man.
Fluoride is scary shit.
Yeah.
That's the reason why it kills
everything in the water and everything
in your mouth.
It just seems like you should tell
people that,
hey,
this thing that you put in your mouth
don't swallow it.
Yeah.
No one ever told me that,
that I buy hippie toothpaste.
I buy that uncle Tom's of Maine stuff.
It doesn't have any anything or Tom's of
Maine.
Uncle Tom.
I made him uncle Tom Guide us to eat TV
Guy TV guy.
I would send out pieces of paper I call
complete
page,
but I would snack on little pieces of
it.
Are you fucking serious?
Seriously.
He had like this with this.
I guess I was mineral deficient or
something and needed fiber or something.
I see the TV guide.
I sleep buggers.
You guys.
Everyone needs to eat burgers,
right?
No,
it wasn't.
I was in the building with dirt and
grass.
I like taking.
I like taking like a real wet sloppy
booker.
And did you just keep rolling it?
Working,
getting your finger until a solid ball,
like making bread.
I know what I mean.
Fighting back at dry heave.
I used to eat grass so much time ago to
grasp so much as a kid that now I could
get wheat grass juice and I love the
taste of wheat grass just because I used
to eat so much grass as a kid.
Oh,
I fucked up Jamba juice on me to do
this,
but there's this girl,
she.
She got me my wheat grass juice and she
goes,
do you want to Orange chaser with it?
And I go,
no,
I'm okay.
I'm like,
oh,
this stuff is nasty,
and I downed it and she goes,
she goes,
do you think it's nasty?
I love the taste.
I go,
oh,
that's because you're a cow.
Oh,
you really did mean that though.
What?
Are you a cow pig?
No,
she wasn't because every girl.
But if it was a dude,
you know,
we were joking around before that,
it was all friendly talk and I just
totally didn't.
You can't call it girl cow.
You could tell it to cow like of a guy
said,
you know,
Oh,
I love to taste sweet grass.
Like what are you a fucking cow?
Like joking around with them.
Like as long as you're laughing and
smiling it will be all fun.
But with a girl you can never call her
cow.
I could call you a cow eating grass.
I'm like,
what?
Are you a fucking cow?
Or You could call a white guy.
Like if he's a beast,
motherfuckers a gorilla gorilla all the
time.
Yeah.
You can't say that about a black.
They get mad.
Do you guys saying.
What are we saying?
How would they get mad?
What the fuck,
Brian even bringing it up.
I totally right after it came out of my
mouth.
I wanted to take it back,
but then I told him I want to address
it.
I didn't want to.
I don't know.
I really don't mean you're a cow.
I was just a.
It was a terrible idea to joke that I
wasn't thinking.
I just set it and then after this kate
my mouth,
I was like,
oh you dick,
but it didn't mean to be a dick.
So I'm in this new part of our
relationship where when I fart,
I can't say it's a fart yet.
So how do you get to that part of the
relationship where you could just be
like,
oh,
I farted because I'm so tired of
blaming.
Don't go there.
It'll kill everything.
Be Honest.
Is the sex drive exactly where it was
was from the.
From the beginning to the way it is now.
Same thing.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Has tapered off at all for good reasons.
The other day it was so bad.
I had no excuses.
I couldn't say the cat did because I've
said it so many times.
Luckily she didn't say a word,
you know,
you should just ignore it.
No,
just,
you know,
in the middle of the night while you're
sleeping,
punch her in the nose and then her nose
will swell up.
She'll get a deviated septum and it
makes it much harder to smell farts.
Flirting
in your sleep and then you,
you ever fired so loud,
you wake up in your sleep.
You okay to Fart in front of your girl?
I don't.
Just out of respect.
Do you leave the room or do you have
like if she walks in,
like she'll walk into my office.
I'm like,
you better back the fuck up.
I just farted in front of extent.
I wonder if Fart in front of me.
This is what I'm thinking is there's
times where I have to fart really,
really bad,
but I'll just hold that motherfucker and
then I fall asleep.
Is there any way you hold it while
you're still asleep?
No.
No,
no,
no way.
I had an ex girlfriend wake me up
because she was farting.
She farted it so loud.
It woke me up and I was like,
what the fuck did I hear?
I was like looking her ass.
And then a second one came out loud one
and then she woke up.
She was like,
what happened?
I go,
yeah,
what happened?
Then I went back to see,
you know,
those vacuums that they have at the car
wash places,
you know what I mean?
If they'd have one right by your bed.
So you just kinda like a smoke smoking
going.
You'd always have to think about it
getting stuck to your ass.
When I did,
what I did last night is I got off the
Internet is that you take a little bit
of Vicks Vapor Rub and put around your
asshole.
So even if it does far,
just much like Vick's vapor rub.
So the Internet got a tip to do that.
Yeah.
You tried that and your asshole is going
to light on fire.
That's terrible advice to put capsaicin.
Rubbing your butthole is like open
source.
It's like an open wound,
you know,
it's super,
super open skin.
It's incredible airtight.
It is because you know there's like a
gigantic explosion like right there at
the end of year you can smell it,
so what can you do besides vapor?
Rub that with you,
like if you rub like shaving cream or
alcohol,
aftershave on your hands.
It never bothers you at all,
but if you rub that shit on your balls,
it's going to fucking hurt.
And your balls dip your Dick in it.
If you dip your Dick and that stuff and
touches like that soft tissue,
you put that around your asshole.
What about just some bubble gum or
something?
Just plug it up with some bubble gum
before you go to bed.
Put roses around it like glue roses
around until took us through a rose
filter.
Some lemon juice.
Maybe that's what you could do.
Make a filter out of roses like a
diaphragm as little stickies on it on
the side,
and just stick it right to your
butthole.
So it's like a filter.
So when you fart,
it goes through an snl sketch like maybe
15 years ago with commercial parody
where they go now you can,
you know.
No more embarrassing farts.
What are they?
Take a big horn and he stuck a big horn
in your ass and then when you were at
park,
that'd be an electronic voice that said,
how bout them doctor?
That was all about them dodgers and then
it did filter out your farts smell.
It is pretty incredible when you think
about all the technology that we have
that we have zero invested in farts.
We have nothing invested in cleaning up
the smell of forest.
There's no product farts or like a
normal part of everyone's day and yet
there's no technology that exists to try
to deal with.
Be like a Fart sucker built inside the
seat cushion where you sit down and it's
like right there and you could secretly
just press that button.
Why don't they have writers?
They have a filter on the top of my
litter box so that I don't smell my
cat's shit.
There's a charcoal filter.
Why don't they make filters for your
underwear if you like.
If you like to eat a lot of Mexican food
or if you're going out drinking and you
know you're gonna be farting,
why don't they have some filters?
That's a good idea.
Like a fart.
Kotex?
Yeah,
exactly.
Like the FARC,
Kotex build into your underwear.
Your Saturday night party in short and
he your Saturday night party and
underwear and they have built in
charcoal filter in there to sent it like
strawberries or something like that.
Like a butt plug to take because you got
to fuck with the noise through.
The noise is going to happen,
so you need to stick something in your
ass like maybe a couple inches and then
it just got something real list.
The knowledge will be way muffled if
you've got a Kotex over your bundle.
How much?
Not a real loud one.
Right?
Well,
I'll tell you what,
Tate Fletcher would be their fucking
product management guy.
He'd be the one to test to see the
efficacy of their individuals.
Filters.
Sounds,
sounds with a clipboard like organizing.
He's like head of the science team,
but it's and it's all built around his
gas.
Put the stethoscope notice stomach to
try to determine whether that is ready
to fart.
Fart.
No,
it's hot as fuck.
It's hot.
I got to my ac broke and the side of the
house.
I got to get it fixed.
Get some Mexicans to fix that.
Hey,
what the fuck again?
With the Mexicans?
Man.
Jesus.
So speaking of Mexicans,
the Gulf of Mexico,
the fucking oil spill,
they've just determined that the oil is
coming out in multiple locations.
They've just confirmed that it's not
just this one spot.
So even if they dig this relief,
well it's still might be fucked because
the oil is coming out from all these
different spots like very far away from
each other.
It's a fucking mess.
Dude.
Fucked up Cancun yet.
I don't know.
Once it goes around the Florida and goes
up the code,
that's crazy because I mean just think
myrtle beach,
Florida,
beaches,
all that shit's not going to get a swim.
Then beach on the east coast,
all those beaches of Jack duty might go
to England.
Yeah.
It's the whole thing.
It's so incredible that they don't have
a way to stop the oil,
that they're allowed to make these
things and not have fail safes.
You would think there would be a bunch
of set failsafes if there's a rupture in
this line.
We shut it off here.
There's a rupture here.
This way we can absolutely ensure that
will be no pollution comes out of this.
Well,
animals are going to evolve and thrive
in the oil.
Probably not going to happen.
What's probably gonna happen,
we may be millions of years from now if
I kept talking to what's going to happen
to kill all these animals off.
Oh,
make belief.
Mon Southern Fire Monster.
Some fucking dragon that eats the oil
and that stores in like a special gland
has got rocks in the back of his throat
and so it sparks up the flame to how
many dragons are there an ancient
cultures and where the fuck that come
from dragons.
Does that still exist?
Man?
I went to the zoo and some of these
lizard things,
those looked like fucking like Komodo
dragons.
That shit's crazy.
If you just have you seen it?
Yeah.
I think Komodo dragons were just like,
you know,
dwarfs of the big old relative to
Chinese dragon came from someone saw
like a crocodile or a Komodo Dragon.
I just drew it in the story.
Went back and forth,
rawlings being misinterpreted.
You know,
like when you were saying that dude,
like there's drama that people tales and
stuff.
That's just some gay guy that depth.
Some dude was drawing,
you know,
like he was dressed up as a dragon or it
could have been like,
you know,
the national enquirer for 6,000
years ago.
They were just making shit up.
Exactly.
Yeah.
That's possible.
Okay.
If you had to believe in one.
Dragons are vampires attitudes.
One Dragon Dragon's dude.
Vampires are so stupid to think about
that.
Think about that.
I believe.
Will.
Where will this be for bleeding?
Cool Dragon?
No,
I believe vampires before.
I believe where will,
because I've seen vampires.
What could it be is it could be some
sort of a parasite,
something that hijacks your system,
but vampires is supposed to be dead and
you can't.
But what if the parasite hijacks your,
your aging system too and keeps you
alive,
but it makes you feast on blood.
It could be just the idea of a blood
sucking person,
a person that lives off blood that a
parasite could trick you into doing
that.
That is way more possible than a
werewolf.
Some of the changes back and forth to
another animal.
And then back again.
That's ridiculous.
So you're saying that Sun can burn
people during the day?
No,
but I can't say that if they,
if they had some sort of a crazy,
a blood problem,
you know where they may be in intensely
anemic,
they might have like a real aversion to
sun.
They might lose the pigment in their
eyes.
It's possible,
man,
if you think you see the shit that
parasites do do to different insects,
different caterpillars and bugs and ants
and all sorts of different things.
Their whole bodies get hijacked by
parasites,
completely rewires their entire system.
It happens to frogs and happens to
lizards.
So many different animals exist in the
animal kingdom and it just recently
discovering new parasites that hijack
new hosts caused them to do.
Let's get this straight.
The cat parasites make women more horny.
It makes women more submissive.
It makes.
I mean,
there's all sorts of interpretation of
what,
how it exactly affects them,
but it seems to make men and women the
opposite makes men more aggressive.
Women.
They going crazy guy with a beard down,
calm down.
Brazilian women aren't calm.
Well then that doesn't make sense
because they're wild too,
and they have to deal with all those
wild men so it makes them extra wire.
What are you saying,
man?
This is all based off the research guy.
No,
no,
no.
Toxo toxo plasma is a very well
established overtaking.
No,
no,
no.
This.
No,
no.
It's not.
This says 6 million people or or 60
million people rather than America
habit.
This is the CDC there.
If you look online,
there's many different studies,
many different ports,
many different scientists working on
this.
Toxo plasma is a very real parasite.
That is his actual d actually detectable
and people that they know is responsible
in part or connected in part to uh,
all sorts of different psychological
ailments.
Yeah,
but the part that it.
Schizophrenia making girls submissive.
That part of this whole.
I know one guy saying this.
No,
it's a bunch of.
It would also train.
It changes all sorts of animals.
I said it changes.
Rats,
makes them attracted.
Cat piss changes.
Men makes them assholes.
Makes him reckless.
It's really fascinating stuff.
And when you research and you think
about how many different parasites might
exist that we don't even buy my shit
don't work.
Check,
check,
check.
Okay.
How much was out just for 20 seconds
talking about campus anyway.
We know.
We know that these parasites exist and
we know that these parasites affect
people and if we know there's just a
couple of them,
how do we not know that there's a bunch
more that we haven't detected yet?
What about use as a kid?
He used to eat those green weeds with a
yellow flower on the top.
Did you ever eat those?
Dogs would piss on them.
Dogs a piano,
um,
and I would eat them.
Oh,
dandelions.
The green stocks with a yellow flower at
the Dandelion.
Dandelions you eat,
eat the grass.
Dogs piss on them all the time.
I got take a piss is good for you.
Oh Man.
You have some sort of crazy pissed
parasite.
Have you ever thought about that?
How crazy that is though,
that if there really is a,
an animal parasite that makes people
like aggressive,
it makes women's submissive.
Like that is Brazil.
Like dudes are super aggressive cocaine
that makes cocaine,
makes women's summit,
so it makes them drop to their knees
immediately.
That's just because they need that.
They're just happy to get that coke or
coke.
Makes them immediately submissive.
I think it's cooked.
Definitely.
Remember Larry used to have coke around
just anybody spot.
No one knows who larry is.
The cable guy.
That's one thing I've never fuck with
and I'm very glad I never tried that
shit.
Never fucked with it.
I knew too many people that had real
problems with it.
I've done coke maybe five times in my
whole life.
Maybe three to five times sucks.
Scary pussies.
They say you got to get that Rockstar
Cook.
That's what a Tom Sawyer from cobb's in
San Francisco.
He's always saying you got to get that
Rockstar Coke Shit.
I read somewhere.
Something about coke.
How there's bad coke going around now
that like will eat your skin.
Like it has some kind of fucking
chemical in it that just starts burning
your skin.
Fuck,
I don't know.
I ain't got a google list now.
Bad cocaine.
What was it?
What you were telling me about tylenol?
What the fuck is going on with?
So there was,
if you try to get tylenol right now,
I guess there's this huge tylenol like
where they pulled it from the store
shelves and what's crazy is that I did
some research on it and it seems like a.
So they
did all these like things where they
went to the factories were tylenol is
made and they found a like,
like a bacteria inside tylenol.
They found like the chemicals that were
being made to make tunnel were off.
Like there was too much of one chemical
and not enough of another chemical.
So it could possibly have got,
you know,
made kid's sick and so they,
they pulled off tylenol off the shelves
I guess,
but then the other day a monitor,
there was this report that came out,
there was this report that came out
that,
that Johnson and Johnson,
the company that owns tylenol or
whatever,
hired this third party company from San
Diego to act like customers and then go
into grocery stores and buy all this one
product off the shelf.
Like they're doing a phantom recall,
meaning they didn't want to tell anybody
or anyone to know.
So they hired a company to go into
grocery stores,
into pharmacies to take this product off
your shelf.
And then they got caught and then a
month later they,
they recalled,
uh,
this other drug.
It's just like Tylenol,
I forget the name of it,
but it was like another one and they're
like kids tylenol or something like
that.
How much have you looked into this?
Seriously?
It was like a half hour today.
I just read around today,
but a tylenol Johnson Johnson was
supposed to give over to the FDA like
this report about their findings and
stuff like that and they missed the
deadline.
I think the deadline was yesterday or
two days ago.
They missed the deadlines is something
might be up at Tylenol,
so if you have any tylenol from 2008,
you might want to go check it out,
throw it away or do whatever you have to
do.
Because there was another report I was
reading as say something like there was
30 deaths related to tylenol in the last
two years and they don't know if that's
connected or not either.
So I don't know.
Google search,
tylenol recall.
There's some crazy shit going on with
some tylenol right now.
Wow.
They're saying that the pharmacist that
we were at today said that there might
not be tying on until 2011.
Damn.
Who is fuck.
Who's who got in trouble for cyanide?
They're saying there's potential
criminal charges and indictments.
Yeah,
that's what they're saying about
tylenol.
Yeah,
and it's crazy because you pay extra for
Tylenol,
you know,
your,
your tunnels,
like more expensive than like the
average brand.
Right.
And you would think that they would have
their shit together a little bit better
than fucking
buffering first.
Toyota.
Now this,
what's next fucking cup of color.
Imagine that.
Well,
as the economy starts to fuck up,
as people start to make less and less
money,
you're gonna see more and more problems.
I'm sure less and less research is going
to be done less and less,
you know,
fail safe measures.
Did you watch the last comic standing
last night?
No.
No,
I gave up on that show a long time ago.
I didn't watch it,
but I heard it was okay.
Wow.
Fucking fascinating.
Yeah.
Last comic standing,
man,
I,
I just don't like the fact that they
make them sit in a room and do standup
comedy for three people.
You know,
that to me it's just like what?
That's how they're going to audition.
They're going to stand in front of three
people and one of them was going to try
to pretend that there Simon,
is that what happens ones runs really
mean.
Is that how they do it?
If you got a tremendous migraine
headache and you had,
you only had two things,
tylenol
or cocaine,
what would you do?
You trust cocaine that you don't even
know where it came from.
It could come from some fucking greasy
immigrant.
He going to trust cocaine for a nice
American name brand like Tylenol,
so they made a few mistakes.
Brian,
how many good pills they put out?
Huh?
Millions and millions and millions of
people all across the world have had
relieved headaches because of tylenol
and you want to hate because they fucked
up a little bit here and there.
That's deep.
Come on,
man.
That's deep.
Tylenol doesn't get you laid cocaine
does.
Wow.
Just got a good point for your baby.
If you crush up tylenol,
the powder like joey does,
that'll get you laid.
The girls that you can only fucked
because you're giving them coke.
You really shouldn't fuck them.
What models know the fucking people
don't really want to fuck you.
That's what I'm saying is,
you know they fucked the tylenol.
You should only fucked girls who want to
fuck you.
You shouldn't fuck girls who want to
fuck you for coke.
I mean you got to do what you gotta do
it.
That's the only way you can get laid.
I understand your position.
I got cocaine or got my personality.
Which one do you want?
Maybe if you have two possibilities.
One fucking girls who actually wanna
fuck you.
And two fucking girls that you can only
fuck because you give them drugs.
I would say go with number one.
Yeah,
right?
Yeah.
Everybody wants the person who's fucking
them to like the fuck them.
Nobody wants to be fucking some cooked
up checkers.
She's got her half an eye on the
nightstand at all times.
Looking over at that mirror while you're
banging her.
Just wants another line.
Yeah,
but what if you're noise with the chick?
You just want her to fuck out,
but you want to drop it.
Load first.
Then coax.
Perfect.
I guess,
but doesn't she want more coke?
There isn't that.
The thing about coke is never get rid of
them.
There'll be cool for like two hours.
You can.
You give them a little bit and they'll
think it's enough.
You just give them the token.
Tell them to leave with some coke and
you're telling Yo meet him at the club
and you got more coke.
You're gonna.
Bring all the coke.
Who has.
Who has more aspirin stories that joey
did.
Fucking crushed up aspirin.
Tell us a joey story.
Let me tell you something.
There was this one time.
This chick was like,
I just need to get a line.
Like I just need to get my dick sucked.
What a coincidence.
So we go back to my place.
I'm telling US pitch.
I got the best fucking coke ever.
This shit's coming straight from Pablo
Escobar.
He deliberated himself.
It came over on a fucking donkey with
some bread and a fact pack of coke.
Hold on honey.
I'm going to get it.
I'll be right back.
I went into the bathroom.
I started fucking chopping up all these
different pieces of fight of his fight
up and fucking be fucking talcum powder
and shit.
I laid a couple of lines.
I stuck it in her mouth.
I shot off a load before she even knew
what hit her.
I was gone.
You know what I'm saying,
Dawg?
Fuck.
Oh Shit.
We gotta get out of here.
I realized the cops are coming at noon.
Run.
I got to the fucking front.
I got in my car.
I told her take a left at the light.
I'll meet you down the street.
I took a right fuck her.
I'm gone.
I got on the freeway.
Got Off the first exit.
Fuck you.
I when away to whip ponies dead.
Nice.
That's a good job.
Joey Diaz and pressure like such a good
impression.
Okay.
Review reviews.
Joey.
Joey,
what do you think about this whole,
uh,
a cat piss thing?
The parents.
That's a soft spot in my heart.
You know,
I got cats,
you know,
I love him to death.
But the bottom line is I'm an asshole
and I live with a bunch of fucking cats.
I think he's probably got it totally,
totally,
totally brings in cats from outside.
Yeah.
He brings in like monster cats.
Like remember he was always talking
about the Samurai that,
that at the big scars all over his face.
That's a wild tomcat.
He is one of the guys that's a grown
adult that subscribes to cat fancy
magazine that actually keeps that
magazine in business,
which I can't believe cat.
Fancy still has a drive to cat.
Fancy.
Yeah.
But then you get like real magazine,
so you know,
like whatever Time magazine or whatever
that they're hurting because of the
economy by yet.
Cat Fancy.
Julia would freak out if we wouldn't
watch that DVD and I don't think you'd
read that article.
You'd have to show them a documentary on
the cat parasite.
Have to be a documentary.
Are you concerned at all about the oil
spill or anything?
How does that affect your life?
Directly effects me because I think it's
going to be.
Oh,
oh.
I was like,
where the fuck's this?
You listen to any Bravo look at me.
Do I look like a look like I get in the
fucking ocean and sharks?
What am I fucking Cock sucker.
Listen,
this is what I'm going to do.
I'm gonna.
Walk down to the weed store.
I'm going to roll a joint.
Say a prayer to the mother.
Fucking clean this shit up.
If not,
I guess I'm not going swimming.
What did he say?
What the fuck?
I got enough problems in my own life.
Give a fuck about a greasy Pelican.
You got oil on you.
You Fuck?
Oh Man.
Oh Shit.
Fly Away motherfucker.
You got wings.
You're gonna.
Sit there and let the oil hit Ya.
Fuck you.
You finally got texting about six months
ago.
You're by.
You're busting my balls that he
probably.
You think about the iphone and the
camera and all that shit.
You're going to go into the iphone now.
I do.
You think Julie would go into the iphone
but I don't know.
You tell me he wants an iphone back.
Listen,
no,
he's too old school for that.
Now he wants to iphone.
He just got a iphone.
Uh,
you know,
like one of those phones that are acting
like the iphone,
he did sprint,
iphone,
some sprint,
sprint.
He was supposed to be here.
This with Joe.
We're going to get an iphone.
He would.
Eddie Bravo.
Listen to me.
I'm old school.
I barely,
barely get on that fucking thing to text
to you.
Me,
you think I'm going to get there and
we'll get a fucking do apps together.
Oh,
let's play donkey Kong will fucking come
on.
Get online with my laptop through your
asshole.
And you're gonna fucking connected with
a USB cable.
I don't need all this nonsense in my
life.
I don't need all this aggravation to the
weed store.
I'm going to roll a joint.
Walk down to the fucking store.
Alright.
I'm not hurting nobody.
I'm not bothering nobody.
Did you?
Did your.
We'd start close.
No,
no.
My closing.
They're closer.
A bunch because they're too close to
churches.
Parks or schools.
You have to be within a certain feet
from a church.
A Parker school.
I don't know how many it is,
but it's like a thousand or some shit,
which is pretty pretty far.
I checked all my places and none of them
are closing so that you can't be near a
park because that's where all the
illegal dealers.
It's almost like the illegal dealers got
in on the action.
Yeah,
probably at the top of the weed
movement.
And like,
especially the guys that own the most
successful at dispensary's,
I think they'd like these stores that
have been rated guys fuck up when
they're going against the,
uh,
the regulations is we had a conversation
with a,
a idleman because we got our,
uh,
you're right,
there is radio,
the um,
uh,
the,
you know,
uh,
the dog,
he went to jail for it and an item and
was talking about the November election
and were like,
you know,
if this stuff becomes legal in November,
like,
what are you going to do?
You're not going to be able to give out
prescriptions anymore.
And he's like,
yeah,
well it's actually kind of a dilemma for
me.
Like,
wait a minute,
what are we doing?
If that guy,
if we became legal,
his whole business shuts down.
What the fuck is you do?
Then that's a tricky situation for a
week,
Dr.
man,
it's gonna be wild.
If it gets through though,
if it gets through in California and it
becomes absolutely legal,
it's gonna be fucking crazy.
It's going to really change the culture
here because people realize how much has
changed the culture since medical
marijuana became legal,
but that's just the beginning man.
When when it becomes legal legal,
when it comes,
you know a personal use issue when you
just have to be over 21,
you just go to the fucking corner
drugstore and they're selling weed or
selling weed everywhere.
It's going to change things,
man.
They're going to start selling weed at
bars.
They're going to have weed,
smoking sections at bars for sure.
They'll have like a back patio where you
can smoke weed.
It's gonna be nuts when they allow you
to buy a joint at a movie theater,
like at the arc light smoke because they
have like a movie theater designated
with a bar.
You have to be 21 to get into this
theater at the top.
They're going to have a weed there.
That's what.
That's what the problem is.
You can't even smoke cigarettes indoors
because it's a personal.
It's other people's health that you get
to choose.
You get to choose,
you get to choose.
They don't let that.
Don't let that happen in.
In California,
you can't even smoke at a bar.
It's not even an option.
You have to go to a cigar bar.
I,
I belong to a cigar bar in beverly hills
and you go there.
Yeah,
but so god bars like a bunch of stuffy,
rich dudes and it's got a thousand
dollars a year.
Something like that.
Maybe more.
That's the gayest thing I've ever heard.
You take a failed cigar bar.
The licensing for smoke Brian and
convert it into weed barn.
I don't know.
I wonder how many cigar bars there are a
bunch of cigar stores.
Alicia,
small right next to the Improv.
This one vending everywhere.
That's what you would have.
Like a store that lets you smoke there
and in Canada they got spots.
It's weird because in Canada you can't
buy the weed there if you're going to
smoke,
but they have places where you can smoke
weed.
You've got to bring your own shit in
Vancouver,
and in Toronto there's places where the
bottom floor is a restaurant and like a
snack bar cafe.
And then you rent these rooms.
There's rooms like as big as this giant
screen tv,
xbox,
playstation,
dvds,
couches.
Well,
you know,
who's taken us coover.
We're going to Vancouver this weekend by
the way.
Yeah,
we Friday night.
Um,
if you want to come,
I'm hanging out with Adam score.
Gee,
the guy who produced the union and uh,
we're gonna do another documentary
together and one of the things that
we're going to do is dispel a lot of the
myths about people being lazy and uh,
you know,
marijuana smokers being lazy and how
much propaganda has been distributed to
people about marijuana making you lazy.
And one of the things I want to do is
feature your school and feature,
you know,
you teaching and you how many times
you've done this,
where you teach class,
you go,
how many guys are high,
like 30 dudes who raise their hands.
And I don't think I've,
I've taught a night class,
not stone.
They classes too.
I go and stone too,
but I used to not get high for the day
classes,
but night class,
I mean my classes are at 8:30
at night.
There's,
there's no way I'm going to get to that
class and not be stone,
you know?
Yeah.
And you know,
there was one of the things that came up
in the UFC q and a.
They asked me about weed and about
whether or not I think weed is an
enhancer,
a physical enhancement,
you know,
whether or not I think that it's a
performance enhancer and this guy said
that he thinks it is and he was talking
about him doing Jujitsu and I said,
I agree.
I think it is.
I go,
I feel like when I'm.
When I'm stoned and I did Jujitsu,
I feel like I focus more.
I can see it clearly.
I'm,
I'm more,
I have more tunnel vision as to what I'm
doing.
My movements are more precise.
Yeah.
There's so many Jujitsu players.
I mean,
I'm sure in all sports,
the same thing in basketball,
but you just bought huge too for sure.
There's so many pop jujitsu players that
are stoned out of their fucking minds
when they roll,
including the Diaz brothers.
They admitted Bj Penn.
There's no,
and then when people come one guys and
it goes,
and then they say that it cuts down on
your reaction time.
That's impossible.
If anything,
if you're doing jujitsu and your
reaction time is slowed down in any way,
your jujitsu is going to suck.
Totally.
Just there's no way you can do anything
that's going to slow your reaction time
and be really good at it.
It doesn't work that way.
There's no way you can have slow
reactions like when you know there's a
reason why rappers always get high.
When they wrap their flowing,
they got a million words a minute coming
out of their mouth.
There can't be any slow reaction time.
Yeah.
A,
it's a myth.
There's no slowing.
It doesn't slow anything down.
It's a not at all the mikes on different
levels.
people are complaining to on different
I turned yours up.
I took yours down when you were doing
the job ads because it was okay.
Yeah,
dude,
it doesn't slow you down at all.
People that say it does or silly,
it's,
uh,
if,
if anything it just puts you in a
different state of mind.
It puts you in a very creative state of
mind.
If,
if it wasn't for pot,
I would say 80 percent of my material
would be different.
I think 80 percent of the things that I
write,
I write while I'm high and that's being
very conservative because it could
easily,
could be 90 percent,
can be 90 percent of all the things that
I write,
I write under the influence of marijuana
and I think if it wasn't for the
marijuana,
I think the material would be different.
It's much like that fucking cat parasite
changes the way people behave.
Marijuana changes the way you behave,
but it changes it in a good way
sometimes.
Sometimes.
There's been many times where I've been
stone where I look back at shit I have
thought or done while I was stoned.
I'm like,
what the fuck was I thinking?
Like what?
All the time.
Usually when it comes to like making
videos or just anything,
it doesn't give you great ideas.
It just gives you more of the energy to
do the ideas,
more ideas that you would already come
up with,
but you're getting them all at once and
everything is.
Everything is supercharged and it's
really fast.
It doesn't.
That makes dumb people smart.
It depends on a bunch of things.
Depends on first of all how high you get
because if you get too high and you can
get too high where everything spirals in
front of you and it becomes like.
IT's like you have millions of dollars
flying around you but you're in the
middle of a tornado and you can't grab
any of it.
You know,
and sometimes you get to that super
paranoid super high state and like
that's not manageable and you have to
wait until you come down from that super
high to a more manageable place.
Then you can become creatIve.
Then you sit down and write and you can
keep a thought going and you,
you say that like maybe sometimes pots
made you make shitty decisions,
but that's just making you take chances
when you're sober,
you know,
and you go back and you look at it,
maybe you're just not seeing it in the
way that you were seeing it then and
there wasn't complete,
you know,
do,
you didn't fight a complete division.
But look at how much cool shit that you
have created from pot pot has been
responsible for a lot of your really
good editing too,
don't you think?
Yeah,
definitely.
But I mean,
I'm just saying,
I'm just saying it's not 100 percent,
like nothing's 100 percent,
but you gotta remember you want it,
you want to keep track of all that dumb
ideas you come up with not stoned and
then compare.
Right.
That's also what's your state of mind
too?
It's like,
how are you coming to the creative
table?
Are you coming to the table tired?
Are you coming to the table in a good
mood?
You know,
I could have some personal issues going
on,
I could have some things that are
bothering me or some,
some unfinished business that I need to
get taken care of before my mind can be
a piece and then you get high and then
you don't have a good reaction,
but you could be in the best state and
when I'm in the best state,
when I'm feeling the best that I'm the
most loose and my mind feels free and
I'm happy and I'm positive and then I
get high.
Then she Just feels like it all just
tunes in.
then I feel like I'm wide open to the
point where there's nothing that's
bothering me,
nothing that's,
that's tightening me up.
So I'm wide open and loose and then the
weed hits and it's just like,
it just washes you in this crazy energy.
It just hits you with this blast of
light perception in this new way of
seeing things that,
you know,
it sometimes can fuck you up.
But I think when even when it fucks you
up,
like there's lessons in that shit.
There's lessons in why it fucked you up.
There's lessons in where your head was
at when you weren't in the right place.
You know,
it's just,
it needs to be fucking.
Someone needs to teach us how to do it.
That's what it is.
It's a very complicated thing using any
entheogens,
losing marijuana,
using mushrooms.
There should be people that are
professionals that can talk people
through the use of these things.
Like how you were talking last week
about the shermans and fuck yeah man,
we need that.
We need that.
If we had that with,
I hope that's something that comes out
of this whole marijuana legalization
thing.
I hope you know,
marijuana therapy therapy for people
that,
you know,
look,
people need gambling therapy.
You don't,
I don't,
you know,
we can gamble and quit and so big deal,
but some people get knocked up on
gambling.
They had fucked up and they can't stop
gambling and I think there needs to be a
therapy for weed people too.
For some people that Just get fucked up
on weed and it's really just therapy
they need,
you know,
most of these addictions,
addiction to masturbation,
addiction.
These are all psychological addictions
are not physical addictions,
but they're still there,
so they're going to have to have that.
They're gonna have to have therapy for
people to get fucked up on.
We'd,
you know,
if we want to keep it healthy society
during the transition,
but it's no different than therapy for
guys that cheat on their wives for
therapy,
for,
for masturbation or therapy for
anything.
It's like you just got an error,
right
guys?
I got take off.
We've been on Two hours,
right?
It's 5:00
on the button for two hours.
It's perfect.
Holy shit.
That was quick,
man.
That's the way to do it,
son.
Awesome.
Austin.
We had some great interesting
discussions.
Yeah.
You know,
a good time for anybody who,
uh,
is interested in following brian's shit.
More brian stuff.
Go to red band.com
for eddie bravo.
Go to a 10th planet.
J.
J.com.
What does that,
bruh was pointing to the bottom jump on
the nibiru forum.
The forum on my site is pretty key.
Very Just like you're talking about it.
Oh,
oh no,
no,
no.
I'm just saying go to a.
His website's on there,
so it's just pointing to the name eddie
bravo.
Oh,
I'm sorry.
I don't know what the fuck you're done.
Um,
yeah.
You were,
I thought you were finding something and
then you're dividing rod.
Anyway.
The um,
uh,
the 10th planet jiu jitsu website is
10th planet.
J.
J.com.
Yes.
and if they want to like,
ask questions and show you got a forum,
what's the forum?
it's called call it the nea bureau
forum.
The template.
The but new newbie.
Oh,
by the way,
10th planet jujitsu.
Even the name 10th planet.
Jujitsu is all from the zechariah
stories.
Yeah,
that's funny thing about 10th planet jiu
jitsu was I decided to,
uh,
when I first decided to open the school,
I needed a name for the school.
I needed a name for the style and I
wanted something.
I definitely wanted something in the,
in a style I want it.
I was thinking nibiru
to did.
I was actually thinking that it's like
nibiru jujitsu.
Will people get that something I knock
you jujitsu or something.
Joe goes,
right.
We were en route.
We're entering your security gate.
You said why not just 10th planet jiu
jitsu stupid.
No,
no,
no.
Something like rocky sitch.
And you thought about a 10th planet
jujitsu,
huh?
Fuck yeah.
Fuck yeah,
that's it right there.
Fuck me bro.
Jujitsu.
That sounds good.
You know,
um,
we're,
we're good friends and so I don't
necessarily talk about you too much just
because you know,
I kind of take it for granted because
we're good friends,
but I've done the forward to two of your
books and we've been friends for 10
years now.
Like strong.
And the weirdest thing about this whole
a jujitsu thing is watching it blossom
out of just hanging out when you were a
purple belt and just talking about
different techniques to now this nobody
fucking thing where you've got
affiliates all over the world and other
countries and shit and you're traveling
all over the world doing seminars and
teaching people this shit.
All the while it's this weird
combination of like stoner sensibility
and openminded creative jujitsu and you
know,
even the fucking name is hilarious.
10th planet jujitsu.
There's something.
I mean,
this is like some crazy alien,
you know,
hybrid system,
the,
the whole,
the whole thing is in the world of
martial arts is a very unexpected to
have someone who's got this sort of
silly,
like goofy outlook on so many different
things and,
and,
and has got a sense of humor about so
many different things and smokes weed
and it was always playing pranks on
people like prank people all the time.
Well,
people don't know where's the best place
to see some of those because some of
them are fuckIng hilarious.
He's got jujitsu students who pretend
that they're angry brazilians who come
to fight eddie and they come to
challenge them like they're karate
masters or you know,
they're different.
Different
thanks.
Sometimes he's not a burden.
That was never a brazilian.
It was always just the expert.
Now he's adding a brazilian accent.
Okay,
now he is,
but at times he's just a random karate
guy.
Orange.
He's been like days of our lives,
very talented,
hilarious actor slash comedian.
He was tech tech on days of our lives
years ago and he's so fun.
He Trains with us at 10:30
planet and they set it up all the time
where he comes in and whenever there's a
new person there,
they did it with alan belcher.
They did it with the tim lee did it with
a bunch of different people.
Whenever someone's there that doesn't
know that
bag,
we got tom lawler with it.
Good.
We got tom lawler hook,
hook,
line,
and sinker.
How about when you get seasick?
People's cecil piece of people's freak
the fuck out.
now they get to the point where they do.
It's so ridiculous where eddie chokes
these guys out and pretends to kill
them,
and then a students dragged the guy off
into the garage,
into the backyard,
to a total douche bag.
Premises premises were signed.
Comes in.
We give each other a wink.
He starts doing karate kata on the
disrupting the class and the crazy thing
is I'll get the camera.
Men usually they'll be pumped to.
I want to.
Denny percopo is my one of my black
belts.
I went up to him a few years ago and
when,
when he walked in,
he never saw the response sketches
before,
so I went up to denim denny,
you got your camera on you,
and he goes,
yeah,
what's up bro?
I go,
get it out.
Keep the kicker on this guy might have
to fuck this dude up.
He's like,
okay,
okay.
Okay.
Video taping.
And I tried to sell it like we get into
like an argument or a discussion for a
couple minutes so you know,
we don't want to get too crazy.
We slowly dragged people into it.
We start arguing and then we just start
fighting and then I get crazy.
I tried to kill them.
I'm a total douche bag.
I actually tried to kill the twitches
and shakes and shaded kicks his legs and
then people drag them off into the back.
we just did it at the ufc expo in front
of a lot of people.
Got it on.
We got tom lawler and vinnie my.
That is fucking hilarious.
What's so hilarious about it is it's
completely unexpected.
How many people would think that a
jujitsu master would also be doing
pranks like on a regular basis?
Most of those pranks or on my dvd,
mastering the rubber guard,
a bunch of them.
And the original one,
the original bag that I got on video is
in 2010 years ago as quad tooth when I,
when I,
uh,
put some black makeup on and another
time I was a black guy,
I was scaring my friends.
That's my mastering the rubber guard
dvd.
that was the original one.
That was before punk.
And that's,
I've alWays had that in me for some
reason.
You have a very strange sense of humor.
It's like my default setting is
constantly saying like inappropriate
things and the wrong things and I don't
know what it is.
You have been like that since I met you
and that's why I tried to talk to you to
do stand up.
And he did it for nine times.
Yeah.
Damn.
Standup is way harder than jujitsu.
That's for damn sure not to spend a lot
of time perfecting.
Stand up.
You can't just go up there and tell
jokes.
Jujitsu wasn't in the beginning.
It's no different.
I think it's just like anything else to
get great at anything just requires time
and effort and thought and concentration
and evolving.
That's all it is.
And comedy,
you know,
you got to bomb.
You started off terrible.
If you saw me when I first started off,
if I had some video,
I got some somewhere,
some vhs tape of me on stage,
like,
like the 10th time I was ever on stage
or something like that.
Dude,
I was fucking terrible.
you know,
one's good in the beginning.
It's like everything else.
I mean,
you got good at jujitsu.
You aren't good at jujitsu when you
first started and thinking about you
now,
you know,
that's a,
I think about,
you know,
since when I tried stand up for the
first time,
I had never.
It was before I had a school.
We were hanging out at the comedy store
every week and I'm seeing all these guys
go up and bomb and I thought,
you know,
I could do this shit.
And um,
you know,
I went up and I realized that if I put a
lot of time into it,
I might be able to be okay,
but I had to,
I was spreading myself too thin.
I had to really think about what I was
at,
what was I going to be a comedian,
a jujitsu flair and end of musician.
I had to figure it out.
So I just decided to not pursue common
anymore and just focus on jujitsu and
focus on my music.
And who knows,
maybe one from,
from
teaching the last seven years I think
I've gotten a lot more comfortable
speaking in front of people when before
I was teaching,
that was the hardest part of comedy is
getting up and talking to a crowd that's
stopping you crack jokes when you were
on stage at the viper room.
Yeah.
BuT you know what,
when people are aren't paying for
laughs,
it's easier to make them run pan to it.
It seems like it's a little different
finding.
So it's easy.
I could well coming from someone who's
done it.
and this is why I told you in the
beginning that you could do it.
It's just a matter of effort and
concentration.
You have a comedian sense of my sense of
humor.
Now days with youtube,
eddie could make a video that's probably
a million times funnier than him having
to go on stage for three years just to
get a joke out,
you know?
Right.
But it won't be standup comedy,
you know,
the differences,
standup comedy,
you can actually have a bunch of people
come to see you in a place.
You can make a living off it.
Yeah.
But he can make a living off of these
videos if you wanted to do the same
shit.
You know what I mean?
Like today,
how do you make a living off youtube?
really weird.
Are you making a living off youtube
videos?
I could if I wanted to.
Probably.
Really?
How much do you make off to people make
off youtube videos.
There's people have whole careers based
on youtube videos.
Look at taylor.
Look how much.
Okay,
but how much money can you make off of
youtube video you're saying from
advertising?
Are you saying from people coming to see
you and I'm saying now I'm saying back
in the day used to be you had to get on
stage to not become a standup comic and
really work to get like 30 people in a
room where nowadays you can take these
same bits and jokes,
make it into a youtube video,
get a billion people and if you keep on
doing that then you could have a whole
career based off either advertising or
you could have like a show on crackle.
I mean there's a lot of websites like
crackle that have sitcoms are tv shows,
web based series that are all based off
people that did it and I understand what
You're saying.
however,
what you're saying diminishes the idea
of the artist standup comedy and that's
why it's silly.
I'm telling him thAt he could be an
artist,
a standup comedian.
He can go places and perform and do
stand up comedy.
What you're saying is he can instead do
videos.
I think a lot.
I think a lot of standup people that
want to be standup comics are now
changing how they're getting their
audience.
You know,
I Think I definitely think can be people
want to be.
Comedians were getting a lot of
audience.
I mean that bob burnham kid,
he,
he got a huge following from his youtube
videos and you could definitely get
people attracted to stuff that you put
online and they want to come see you
live.
But what I was saying to eddie was that
he could be an artist,
so stand up comedian as an artist.
He could do it.
He has a sense of you're welcome.
He has that sense of humor.
He's got that way of looking at things.
He's always looking at the most
ridiculous side of things when whenever
there's a subject that comes up with the
news,
he's always looking at the most
ridiculous aspect of it.
LIke automatically.
And that's,
that's a comedian sensibility things
that funny guy looking for an audience.
So yeah,
he is.
But that's what I'm saying.
like stamp comics seems kind of diluted
nowadays because I think if you're a
funny guy looking for an audience back
in the day stamp comedies that like one
of the only few options you could do
because you couldn't get tv show.
So now these people are like,
hey,
I'm a funny guy.
I want an audience.
You know?
I think a lot
of these,
I think stamp comedies probably getting
more and more diluted as more time goes
on.
What don't you thInk?
No,
I disagree because I think the art of
standup comedy,
to me as a patron,
as a person who goes to see it,
is still the most fun thing to see.
I went to see a louis c k the other day
with ari.
I fucking loved it.
I had a great time.
I sat in the audience or the day when
aziz ansari was working out of shit for
the mtv music awards.
I was on that show,
don't you?
And I enjoyed it.
I,
I still enjoy the art of standup comedy
in a,
in a crowd with a bunch of people there.
It's funnier,
you know,
it's like the,
the comedy club atmosphere.
I like.
I like sitting in the crowd.
I like drinking.
I like how everybody's laughing
together.
I think that art form to me is insanely
satisfying.
Way more satisfying than watching a
video clip on youtube.
I haven't used the same thing.
I mean you said that there's a little.
There's barely any real stamp comics
nowadays,
but have.
There used to be a bunch of real standup
comics and nowadays there's.
That number seems to be a lot smaller.
Well,
it's just because there's less places to
work.
In boston where I used to be mad,
there was so many different comedy clubs
in boston,
so many open mic nights that there was a
real community developed around it,
but then as the economy tightened up and
as you know,
a lot of these comics that were in that
area moved out and the guys that had
been there for a long time really didn't
write any new material.
Does the scene died out?
But if there was more comedy clubs and
it was a thriving community,
they'd be more comedians.
The real Problem is they don't have
enough places to perform.
There's not enough open mic nights and
you know,
comedy comes and goes,
man,
there's,
there's waves.
But I think right now is a very good way
for like established guys.
Like if you look at all the guys that
are around like louis c,
k,
and a chappelle,
chris rock,
dave attell,
nick depaulo,
jim norton a patent oswald,
of course,
he's one of my personal favorites.
And you see all these different guys
that are out right now.
If you're a fan bill burr,
of course,
if you're a fan of standup comedy,
there's so much good comedy going on,
right?
francisco,
I think this is one of the best times
ever for standup comedy.
I think what's happened with the youtube
and the internet and my space on the
ship is that people have had a chance to
extend their careers and,
and,
and make their careers like penetrate
further in than they would have
ordinarily.
Not having any television shows,
not having any movie credits.
You know,
now people are gettIng big audiences
just from stand up comedy just from
using the,
uh,
the youtube clips.
Why wouldn't you think that most standup
comics are in it just to become actors?
No,
dude,
no.
Really.
There's nothing more fun than real
standup comedy.
I guarantee you jim norton is not in.
It's just become an actor,
a guarantee you louis ck is not in it
just to become an actor.
They're really good guys or not.
There's so much fun in doing standup,
but that's just like a couple people
compared to the thousands and thousands
of people that are in it for standup
comedy to become what we're talking
about the best guys,
but we're talking about.
I just think that a lot of people look
at the idea of doing standup comedy as a
lot of pressure and that because of that
pressure,
they looked to get off that pressure and
that a television show is like a relief.
Like,
oh,
I'm free of the pressure now.
If the show bombs,
it's not me.
That bombs is to show if the bad writing
was there when I got there.
There's nothing I can do about it.
If I do a movie and the movie doesn't do
well,
but the next month he does fine,
then I'm okay and so it becomes less
responsibility on their back and a
little bit easier and they look at it as
a steady income as opposed to like
something stand up comedy.
It's like,
you know,
no one's really going to be sure that
people are gonna.
Come see you next week.
You know,
you could only assume that you're going
to continue to have an audience and you
have to continue to produce and continue
to do a,
you know,
new sets on television,
new comedy,
central specials.
Continue to write new material after
that gets released so that people could
come see you a year later and they know
you got all new shit.
So there's a lot of pressure and a lot
of people don't like that.
Maybe one day we'll do a,
we'll do a b.
Brian will get up and we'll battle
onstage.
Battle battle battle.
Yeah.
Why can't you just go up?
How about this?
How about we do a 10th planet show and a
jovial host.
Guys will go up.
Fair battle.
No,
we don't have to.
no,
no.
What I'm saying is do it
planet.
Show joe.
He goes up and host brings aria.
Brings one of you guys up for,
you know,
five or 10 minutes.
Whatever you're comfortable with.
Brings.
uh,
the other guy up.
And then,
uh,
and then I'll go up.
We'll do it.
I'll do a show.
I could do five minutes.
Yeah,
I think you're both could do five
minutes.
Brian fucking killed it in,
in atlanta when he hadn't done comedy in
years and he got talked to the june it
during the nighttime show filled with
ufc fans.
All fucking hammered on a friday night.
Sold out.
You were killed.
Not only did he do good,
he went into the abyss and pulled
himself out of the flames.
He did good in the beginning and then he
did a couple of jokes in a row that
tanked.
And you were starting to fucking freak
out and he kept it together.
Yeah.
But you know,
I started doing it a lot and I did a
whole bunch and I started doing it
almost every week,
a few times a week,
but I got to a point where I'm just,
I just didn't have it in me.
You really have to give up your life to
be a standup.
Well,
you know what,
man,
you don't have to have it in you,
but just because you don't have it in
you,
it doesn't mean that the art form is
something that people should pursue if
they want to be a comedian.
What you're saying though is that,
I mean as a comedian,
I mean I know you're not trying to
offend me,
but as a comedian it's kind of offensive
because you're saying that like somehow
or another that someone if they wanted
to,
should just go and do youtube clips now
and not become a standup comedian
because it's too difficult.
No,
I'm saying that if you are a uP comic
nowadays that it seems like youtube
would make a lot more sense.
This boolean howard's target.
You know what I mean?
To be an artist as a standup comedian,
to be a real comic,
you have to do it in front of an
audience.
It's the only art form where you must
have an audience to practice.
If you do not have it all,
what's the difference between not going
to be good?
Because you don't have immediate
response of people laughing at you.
Whether you know whether or not.
It's funny.
Why don't we ever made ever.
Now you
don't though.
You're not hearing these people laugh.
I don't hear shit.
you just have people staring at you in
texting things,
right?
You know you don't get the same kind of
direct,
immediate,
tangible response that you get when
you're going on stage.
Well,
you know what?
Very asked various aspects of a joke or
funny how the transitions work.
You hear yourself and the recordings you
need to know this part sounded falls or
this part.
How too many words and it's an art form.
Just piecing it all together and
performing it in front of a live crowd,
but when you nail it,
dude,
when you're on stage and you fucking
nail a joke where the audience is dying
and you're like,
they're dying now,
and I got like five more levels to this
joke,
this joke,
like I'm hitting them now and I'm like,
I got some shit coming up to that,
to this.
I can't wait to get to because I know if
you think this is funny,
this next part is my favorite part,
and then boom,
boom,
and it piles on.
There's nothing like that that you're
ever going to get off youtube.
There's this.
You're not going to get that feeling.
You're not going to get that sort of a
response from the people and as an
audience member you're not going to get
something that's that much fun.
There's nothing to me,
more fun still after doing comedy for 20
years,
there's nothing more fun than watching
comedy.
It's the best man.
It's so much fucking fun.
It's the,
to me,
the most fun art form and that's why I'm
a comedian.
What I was trying to say is that eddie
could have done that too.
The only difference between me and him
is that he had other things to do is
focusing on and he he went and pursued
those,
but if he didn't,
if he wasn't thinking about pursuing a
career in jujitsu and wasn't thinking
about pursuing a career in music and
have the kind of time that I had when I
started out doing comedy,
for sure,
you would be just as successful as me
for sure.
You'd be able to do everything that I'm
doing come true come true.
You'd be able to do everything that I
did.
Everything.
It's not hard.
It's just a matter of focus and if
you're an honest person and you evolve
and you you your objective and you look
at your shit and you keep working at it,
that's all it is.
Maybe one day I'll call you have the
sense if you don't have the sense of
humor,
okay.
if you don't have the mind for comedy,
that type of person who looks at things
goes,
everybody else is agreeing,
and you go,
wait a minute,
what the fuck is that like?
That's how I was my whole life and
that's how you are,
and brian,
you are to a certain extent too.
I mean you have a different sense of
humor than I do and brian and eddie has
a different sense of humor that you and
we're all different,
but we all have the same thing where
brian like you,
your sense when it comes to technology,
you're always doing this.
Someone to bring up a point and you'll.
You'll always be like,
no,
everybody just thinks that because this
bubba,
you'll go against the grain right away
and pick out the flaws.
That's the idea.
That's the mind of a standup comic.
The person who stands up as the person
who's functioning societies to stand up
and look at things besides being funny.
Stand up and look at things and goes,
what the fuck is this?
That's what the comic does.
The comic looks at something.
He goes,
what the fuck is this?
When everybody else just takes it for
granted,
there's a lot of comics out there.
They just never become comics.
That's what I'm trying to say.
There's guys that work in gas stations
that could be one of the funniest guys
that have ever walked the face of the
earth.
Just no one ever talked them into
getting onstage.
They never directed their life in that
order.
They never had the discipline to follow
through.
You know,
there's so many people like that that I
met out there.
My friend johnny b,
my friend who was a pool player that
died.
That guy could have been one of the
funnIest fucking comedians that ever
lived.
That dude could read.
Human nature knew when people were full
of shit,
knew,
knew what people's insecurities and
weaknesses were,
and always knew the funniest shit to say
at any given moment.
There's a lot of people like that out
there and that's what a stand up comic
as you both are.
You both could do it.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
This fucking shows over bitches.
It's five.
Oh yes.
thank you for sponsoring us.
Fleshlight.
Please don't.
Don't be a pussy if you are a pussy and
you know,
and you want to lIve your life,
just pretending you don't masturbate or
pretending that it's something shameful
about getting pleasure on your deck,
then don't order the fleshlight,
but everybody else go order one of those
things and fuck the shit out of it.
It's awesome.
I'm red band.com
from my friend brian reichel.
10th planet j.j.com.
If you're in hollywood and you want to
get some jiu jitsu instruction,
plus some weed,
shamanism,
there is no place better place to go.
Then legends in hollywood.
What's the number there?
10th planet you get through hollywood
located inside of legends,
nma,
51 76 santa monica boulevard.
And to find you online,
you can go to twitter.
Uh,
it's uh,
eddie bravo.
It's up there on the screen if you were
a,
a ustream guy.
E d d I e b r a v o.
Thank you very much everybody.
We love you bitches.
We love doing this.
This is a fun fucking show.
Um,
I'm excited that we've continued to do
this every day or every week rather all
year and we're going to keep going and
as long as we have cool friends,
it's going to keep being fun.
Eddie bravo.
Brian red band.
What about next week?
Joe?
Next week.
Joey coco diaz.
Hopefully nothing crazy.
Comes up.
The columbia knocked on my door.
I had to go on an adventure cat virus.
Joe.
It's that fucking cat fibrous cock
sucker.
I can't concentrate.
my feet stink.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that's the end of this week and we will
see you next week.
Thank you.
I love you bitches.