Yes.
And we're live.
Mike Baker,
how are you sir?
I am too.
I'm very well thank you.
Very happy to be coming back,
man.
Appreciate it.
Good to see Ya.
This world's in chaos.
We need to talk to a rational man like
yourself who's got the inside scoop.
I have never been built that way before,
but thank you.
That's a bonus in this irrational world.
Your rationality,
you,
you're,
you're deemed a rational man.
That's what we,
we've been lowering the bar,
lowering our expectations.
We were talking before the show started
about the current cover of the economist
that has Donald Trump dressed up like,
because Uncle Sam and it just says
really,
it's perfect.
You know,
and it's what you want to say to
everybody who has jumped that chasm.
Right?
I had a stand that everybody's upset.
People are angry people if for whatever
their motivation,
right?
So there,
you know,
they get Jones got up,
look at that fucking cover.
This is what we're down to.
That's brilliant.
But how do you get to,
how do you get from,
okay,
he's entertaining and I understand that
everybody wants to be entertained.
To some degree,
but how do you get to the point from
saying it's entertaining to leader of
the free world?
And that's the part that I can't
understand when I talk to people who
are,
are absolutely supporting him.
Well,
you as a man who's been deep in the
world of security or CIA operative,
you,
you've got the inside scoop would,
how this machine runs to a certain
extent.
Don't you think that at this point it's
so,
it's so complicated that almost no one
wants to be president.
Like the,
the,
it's not a job that like people are
scrambling to get any more,
right.
Nobody in their right mind would want to
put themselves through it or,
you know,
unless you're independently wealthy.
Yeah.
Um,
and,
and uh,
and just don't care.
And there's,
there is,
I think you're right.
There's,
there's a,
you think about the kid who wants to
become president of the young
Republicans club right in,
in,
in middle school,
and then,
you know,
all through his life,
that's all he wants.
He wants to be an elected official
somewhere.
So he goes maybe to the town council.
Then eventually in his big goal was to
become a congressman and God forbid,
then he gets that and he goes on,
there's a certain personality type,
right,
that's way up its own ass that allows
you to think that.
Yeah.
So I sh I should be president of the
United States.
I look in the mirror every morning and I
think,
yes,
I should lead the free world.
So right there,
I think you've got a flaw in all the
people who are pursuing elected office,
but then you've got the money that's
behind it.
You've got,
you have to be independently wealthy.
I watched,
and not to disappear down a rabbit hole,
but,
uh,
I lived on the east coast before we
moved out to Idaho,
which is a great state.
Oh my God.
It's a great,
beautiful.
It's,
it's,
no,
no.
And if we probably shouldn't say
anything
orphans,
I think it's flat or something.
If I had this conversation with these
two guys,
yeah.
About it.
And they were like,
well,
you know,
it's mostly farms,
like what it is.
I mean there's a lot of code,
there's a lot of agriculture,
but you know what,
he has more,
if you,
here's a,
here's an interesting fact about Idaho.
People can write this down.
If you took an iron and iron,
Idaho flat and then you did that with
all the other states,
the only way the state that would be
bigger would be Alaska.
And the same for river frontage,
right.
The river miles of rafting is,
is insane out there.
So,
but the point being,
I suppose it,
before we moved out there,
I was on the east coast and um,
my wife is involved in politics to some
degree,
but we spent some time in Connecticut,
right watching,
uh,
the,
the governor race there.
Um,
and they would have to go from town
council,
the town council,
it workspace that way.
I mean,
you have to get the vote of the
Republican Party of the Democratic Party
in the town council.
And the first question any of them would
ever ask was,
can you self fund?
Basically,
you know,
how much money do you have?
And so you put that together with the
idea that nobody wants to open their
family up to the ridiculous scrutiny
that's involved and you,
yeah,
you did.
We get what we get.
We get this,
this crazed campaign season.
Yeah.
It seems like we're down the assholes.
It's only people who want to be it and
Bernie Sanders is just,
I mean,
he's kind of an old Kook.
I don't think he's an asshole.
I think he's got all these asshole.
He seems like a nice guy actually with a
lot of good ideas socially and I dunno.
I Dunno.
It just,
it's like,
it's the biggest example in my opinion,
of picking the lesser evil.
That's how I'm looking at this campaign.
It's like,
what's the lesser evil?
It's going to be Hillary Clinton who
basically I just,
I can't,
I don't,
I don't feel any sincerity from her at
all.
It's so hard.
She's been in the business for so long.
She's been involved in politics for so
long.
I don't know if she knows how to be just
herself.
That's a good point.
I mean,
I,
my problem with Hillary is it's purely
an operational one.
I know that if I had handled,
I mean even in a conservative way,
if you look at what she did with the
email server and her colleagues or
cohorts did,
uh,
and,
and you say,
okay,
it's,
you know,
it and conservative way I'm looking at
at how bad it was.
If I had done that,
I would have been sent to prison.
And I know because we had various
counter intelligence operations and else
or you're,
you're trying to find the lake,
you're trying to find the problem.
And I,
you know,
you watch people get banged up for less
egregious acts then what she's been
involved in.
So my problem with Hillary is looking,
you know,
you one set of rules for everybody,
right?
And you know,
David Petraeus is a good example.
He hands over some,
uh,
of information to his mistress who had a
security clearance and uh,
he gets a couple of years probation,
you know,
a large fine has to plead guilty.
Um,
she literally handed it over to the
Chinese,
the Russians and any other state and non
state sponsored a hacker out there and
explain which again,
for people who don't know,
she for whatever her motivations,
she initially said it was simply a
matter of ease after saying that she
didn't really know because it wasn't her
gig.
She set up a,
uh,
a private email server in her bathroom
and the bathroom in her bathroom at her
house in,
in a server in their bathroom.
I know that seems like a weird choice.
Well,
you know,
you're multitasking.
Maybe you don't have that much time in
the day.
And she's constantly,
she did not use that excuse as I recall.
It still doesn't make sense.
It doesn't make any sense.
I know they like,
they'd have no extra rooms in the
Clinton House.
It's a small place.
You made about $190 million over the
last couple of years.
So we're supposed to believe she's
living in a one bedroom,
one bath place,
you know,
800 square feet.
And so she,
she used this and essentially the
problem is she traffic was directed
through this unprotected,
uh,
server that now,
you know,
and she's arguing semantics,
she's saying,
well,
I never saw that it was classified and
yet it's either classified or it's not,
and you know it at when and when you
sign on to be,
whether it's a senior official at her
level or,
or some milk that's walking around just
carrying papers at the agency,
whatever it may be,
you sign agreements,
you that you will protect classified
information.
And it doesn't say it has to be more
classified.
It says that you are aware because you
go through a briefing about what is and
what is and,
and how you look at a piece of
information to determine.
So she's saying it wasn't classified
when she saw it or when it hit the
server,
but what they were doing is essentially
cutting and pasting from classified
documents so that they could bypass
traffic and what their motivation was.
I have no idea whether they thought it
was quicker,
whether it was easier.
You know,
I don't read a lot of nefarious intent.
I just read,
uh,
an egregious mishandling of classified
information that anybody else would be
punished for.
And it's,
you know,
I don't think it's going to happen.
I think the bureau is engaged in a
couple of different investigations.
I think they have all the information
they would need to put the ordinary
person,
you know,
uh,
or move for an indictment.
I just don't think the DOJ is going to
do it.
So what is their motivation to ignore
it?
Well,
I think it's,
I think it's political top cover because
there's not,
there's only one other person running
for the Democratic Party.
Right.
A lot of people aren't too excited about
having Bernie Sanders become the
president.
Right,
right.
And I mean,
again,
it's sort of,
you know,
the,
the left makes fun of the Republicans as
they should because look what we've got
is our front runner.
But,
uh,
you know,
they make fun of the idea that,
the Republicans were all upset because
they're anointed one,
whether it's rubio or whomever you know,
is,
is in the dust right now it's the same
way on the other side.
Right?
I mean they,
you know,
there's a lot of people,
with our knickers in a twist on the,
on the,
on the left upset that perhaps they are
anointed one isn't going to get in.
If if whom Abbott in or one of her
cohorts who was involved in this who
also were being looked at in a very,
very serious way.
If one of them gets banged up for this,
then I don't know how it doesn't spread
to her.
She was in charge and you know,
I understand that shit rolls downhill.
But anyway,
so that seems like the only way it
wouldn't is the whole thing that we're
talking about her in the first place,
that she's just so deeply entrenched
in the system.
She's so political and she's washed so
many hands and you know,
they're,
they're all tied in together and this is
the fabric that sort of keeping her
afloat right now.
Her whole sort of,
you know,
political operating mechanism.
I mean,
she's just so deeply entwined in the
Washington system and that seems to be
what's keeping her from,
I mean,
if this was going on and if somehow or
another this was someone like trump,
someone who is an outsider,
Jesus Christ,
they would chase him down.
Yeah.
Forget about it.
I,
this is,
this is a remarkable situation.
Um,
somebody who's is a,
from it and I get it not taken away.
She's got a lot of experience.
Okay.
I understand that.
Um,
I liked,
you know,
Bill Clinton,
I liked the guy.
I thought he was a,
you know,
there was,
it was a lot of good things about him.
Uh,
it's just,
it's,
it's pretty,
it's pretty fucked up.
And I don't know how else to put it.
We've got trump on one side.
We've got,
we've got hillary under investigation on
the other side.
We've got Bernie Sanders and I get it.
I understand why people like Bernie
because,
hey,
who wouldn't you like free stuff?
Free stuff is,
I'd give me some of that.
You know,
I've got three little boys I've got to
put through college.
I mean,
so people feel like there's an imbalance
and they feel like this is the only guy
that's saying,
hey,
it's imbalanced.
And the,
the people that understand economics or
apparently upset at him,
I don't understand economics.
I'm lucky I don't have to,
but the people that,
you know,
if I was a fucking accountant and shoot
myself,
I jump off a bridge.
But it,
the people that understand that are like
this guy's policy,
this is not going to work.
Like none of this is gonna work.
So that's an argument for other people.
But the people that feel like we got
screwed in 2008 with the,
the,
you know,
the whole bailout and the,
the banks and all the craziness with the
economic collapse,
they feel like at least some guys coming
along,
this is addressing that.
And he's the only one.
So that's what people are gravitating
towards.
And there's a lot of social stuff like
his gravitating towards the black lives
matter movement and wanting to make
medical marijuana legal and all that
stuff that I understand too.
But it does not one person that stands
out where I go,
there's my guy,
there's my God.
Yeah,
I agree.
100%.
Yeah.
I mean,
if you could take Bernie,
cause I think I,
I think one of the things people like
about Sanders's,
he's been consistent over the years.
Yes.
Right.
So he's not,
he's not changing.
And,
and,
and again,
there is something to be said here or
this political system where apparently
you're not allowed to evolve your
thinking.
Right.
So the,
I flip flopper yeah.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Well you can't do that.
Or it's so that part of it or you can't
negotiate a compromise as if somehow
that's a weakness.
Negotiating and compromising is how you
get shit done,
whether it's in government or business.
But,
so anyway,
I had to stamp people like sanders.
They like his,
his,
uh,
his consistency.
Um,
I understand the social side of it.
I think it makes good sense.
I,
you know,
I'm like you,
I don't,
you know,
I've,
I've spent most of my life overseas,
some of them in some pretty crappy
countries where socialism has been
tried.
And I understand he's a democratic
socialist and so it's a kinder,
gentler form.
Uh,
but I've
seen some pretty harsh results from
those systems overseas.
And I,
uh,
I'm surprised that,
I'm surprised that there,
I understand young people jumping on
that train.
Um,
and I'm just surprised that the,
uh,
the other folks who are on board,
you know,
there's a lot of people up in Wall
Street that are saying,
hey,
Bernie,
Bernie is going to tax the shit out of
those people.
Uh,
and he said,
he said as much so I don't know how much
he's going to tax people.
I've tried to pay attention to how the,
I mean,
essentially what he wants to do is
anyone who makes more than a certain
amount,
he wants to impose a very large tax
above that certain amount.
You know,
Phil figured out whatever that number
is,
whether it's $10 million a year,
whatever the hell it is,
anything over that,
he's just going to attack the fuck out
of it.
But the problem is that's not going to
pay for everything he needs.
He needs to,
he that tax is going to roll down to the
middle class and the lower middle class.
And that's sort of the elephant in the
room that nobody wants to talk about.
I mean Hilary's ben talking about it a
little bit.
She's been bringing this up but,
and I,
the Republicans have been talking about
it cause I don't think they view him as,
as anybody that they're going to be
facing in the general election.
But you know,
taxing,
taxing that 1% the 2% to 3% whatever it
is,
you know,
you could raise those taxes up to 99%
you're not going to pay for free
healthcare and education for this,
this country.
It's not only that,
everybody's always complaining about the
government.
There's too much government.
The government's intruding in our lives.
The government,
this government is that when you charge
more taxes,
you take more taxes.
What are you doing?
You creating more government.
That's just what you're doing now.
The money's not going to go or directly
to people.
You're not going to get a check in the
mail folks.
It's going to go to the government and
then the same incompetent fucks that are
handling the irs and all the other shit.
Those are the people that are going to
be handling this money.
What do you think they're going to do?
They're going to create more jobs.
They're going to have more people
working for less.
They're gonna make more money and work,
get less shit done,
and it's going to be more catastrophe.
And it's,
it's a cluster fuck.
There's too many goddamn people is too.
And you know what,
when 2008 hit,
when the,
when the economy really went in the
Shitter,
you know,
growth in terms of employment,
where it happened.
Uh,
most of this country was in Washington
DC.
I mean,
you saw the growth of government as,
as the economy was absolutely heading
south.
And that's just,
that's the way it works.
There's certain,
there's certain things about,
uh,
big government that hold true,
whether it's here or outside this
country.
But anyway,
so I,
you know,
I look at Bernie and I think I hate,
yeah,
I get it.
I liked,
I liked the fact that he's been
consistent.
I think it makes sense.
But then you look at the Republican side
and then we go back to that picture of
trump and you think,
how does that,
how does that fucking happened?
How do you get to this point?
And you think about poor,
what's his name?
Scott Kelly.
The astronauts coming down after a long
sleep up in the space station.
I hope to hell that they haven't told
them shit about what's happening.
Cause how funny would it be for him to
land and trump is the leading candidate
and nobody said anything to him yet.
And he just comes home,
turns on the TV.
It's Super Tuesday,
trump's one everywhere.
And he's going to be,
I mean,
he's dealing with gravitation and all
that stuff.
I guess this isn't
his biggest deal.
Don't take kid like Internet up there.
I think he's got something.
I'm sure they do.
He's got satellite pregnancy and
delivery.
I mean,
he's got to know,
you,
you'd go crazy if you're completely
removed from life when you're up there.
Yeah.
I think,
uh,
I,
I'm,
I would love to think that he doesn't
know and he'd be the one person who'd
you get gobsmacked when he shows up here
and finds out what's going on.
You could run last minute.
Yeah,
look,
stop,
stop.
Well,
here's the thing.
It's,
it's,
there's no one else.
If Hillary gets tossed up in this email
exchange thing,
if she gets in trouble for this and you
know,
it's,
it's Bernie.
That's it on the,
on the democratic side and on the
Republican side,
it's essentially down to mean cruise.
Seems like he's fallen out of it.
It's Marco Rubio and Donald Trump and
rubio is a distant second and people are
so excited about trump because he talks
shit.
He's,
he's bold and brash.
He insults people and he's got his own
money.
He says a bunch of crazy shit.
Like this is a great picture of him
where it's,
it's a photo shopped picture of a,
somebody made a picture of him and he's
got a gun and he's pointing it out of
the window of a car and it says,
get in Pussy.
We're going to make America great again,
but it just seems like there's so many
like goofy white guys who are ready.
They're ready and psyched to have trump
as president.
Like some insulting reality star,
kind of a president
who wants to impose trade sanctions.
Yeah.
That's what you want to do when when the
economy is troubled and weak,
that's a great idea is to,
is to shut down international trade.
That's,
that's always proven to be right.
Smart thing to do.
There's the picture.
Look at this picture.
Oh God,
look.
That was my screen saver.
See as a comic,
I should be excited about this.
Yeah,
you should be.
I should be like,
I am going to have a great four years
when you have to do anything.
You wouldn't have to,
there'll be no work involved in that.
They would just go on the Internet and
it would be a rush to get to the stage
quickest with the material.
That's,
that would be the problem because
everybody's going to have the same jokes
is the folly will be outrageous.
I think people are excited though that
he's got his own money.
He's not entrenched in the system,
the Washington system.
But God dammit,
no it can't.
We can't,
uh,
we can't have this happen.
We have,
we have more crisis around the world
right now.
More hotspots,
more potential,
very,
very serious conflicts going on.
And now is the time you would think,
whether it comes from the left or the
right that you want really clear minded,
strategic,
smart,
pragmatic,
reasoned leadership.
An essay that,
I mean,
you know,
trump isn't,
isn't the guy,
um,
a hey great that he's insulting people.
Great that he's talking outside,
but he doesn't,
you know,
and I'm sure this is going to piss off
the,
I don't know how many trump supporters
you've got listening.
Uh,
he doesn't stand for anything,
right?
I mean,
he stands for what?
I suppose the sport has,
would say stands for winning.
Uh,
but what the hell does that mean?
Tiger blood.
That's it.
I had a tiger.
It's got Canis Panther bits.
Maybe Charlie.
She could be his running mate.
We'll fucking,
he'd win for sure.
Thank God.
But I mean,
but the fact that we've been having a
conversation about it,
what we're talking about,
whether a guy like trump is,
is,
is suited to be president is astounding,
right?
We,
we get that far in the weeds.
We shouldn't even have that
conversation.
You should be up at the 30,000
foot level.
Says,
now let's push that to decide.
Well,
you know,
who oddly is impressive to me is Ben
Carson.
I know he believes a lot of wacky stuff.
Like he's not entirely convinced that
evolution is real.
He's got,
he's quite wrapped his head around that
one.
Yet he's got some wacky ideas.
Like he's got a great picture of himself
that he's painting,
that he had done at his home where it's
him and Jesus is behind him and Jesus
has his hands on his shoulders.
It's,
yeah.
Okay.
Um,
and that is this.
Oh,
hey.
We found it.
First of all,
if I was Jesus,
I'd fucking smack him.
Why is my head so small?
Why are my hands so big?
Why am I wearing a bathrobe?
What the fuck you and I can extenuate
that weird evil widow's peak thing going
on.
It took a crease in his head like a pit
bull.
Look.
He looks,
he's ready to bite your face off the
clean line had.
You're right Jamie and he's wearing it.
Comfy hotel bathroom.
That's what that looks like.
It doesn't look like,
uh,
you know,
garb from,
from the Middle East.
Necessary at all.
Looks like he's just walked out of the
[inaudible].
I talked to your hair.
I don't even think they have bleach back
then.
Did they have bleach in the Jesus days?
I mean things were like natural cotton
call it.
I'm pretty sure they had no tide
capsules or even though I don't like how
he made Jesus smaller than him either.
That's kind of weird.
Yeah,
that's rude.
You know,
who knows who painted it for him,
but I agree with that.
I liked the fact that I get and get to
talk about someone who's reasoned.
I like the fact that he's reason,
but he's not,
we got to a point,
he's not presidential and we've gotten
to that point where there's so many
problems with our system.
But one of the problems is I think that
people are,
are hell bent on finding the candidate
that they agree with everything on it,
agrees with them on everything.
And I've got my three little boys are
what,
eight,
six and four.
And they know they're not going to get
everything they want,
right?
But they also know that if they,
if they work at enough,
they'll get some of what they want,
right.
And then they're going to be happy
enough and they'll go off and you know,
the day continues,
adjust their expectations,
their expectations.
But nobody wants to do that anymore.
Been in politics.
And so you're,
you're getting everybody's splintering
off.
And so,
you know,
the worry obviously,
and it's not an epiphany,
but people talking about all the time on
the republican side,
it's just,
you know,
people throw these verbal hand grenades
out and there's no way to repair the
damage once there is some nominee,
if there is a nominee.
And he's trying to do that.
Now,
Chris Christie's now friends with Donald
Trump,
he's endorsing Donald Trump,
jeff sessions and Donald Trump.
Newt Gingrich is reportedly talking to
Donald Trump.
How,
how much,
and I don't,
this sounds wrong,
but how,
how do you get to the point where you
can set aside,
um,
all your concerns and agree to step
forward and say that he's the guy?
Um,
I don't,
I don't know how that works,
but yeah,
there's,
there's not one person that,
and that's fine.
So what you have to do is you have to
look for the combination of character
and experience.
I think that's what we used to do.
And,
but it's all bread and circus now.
So it doesn't,
that shit doesn't matter anymore.
I don't know.
I think we're going towards the third
party at some point.
We can't,
you can't have a president that is,
has any secrets.
They can't have any,
any sort of a weird kink or weird
background.
Like could you imagine if JFK was alive
today?
What kind of shit they would dig up on
that guy's alive.
Oh cause he was at free.
Great.
Great President.
But he was a freak.
The guy was a sexual freak and,
and the press corps kept that segment.
They do it just like what they did with
the Roosevelt and being in the
wheelchair tacit agreement.
We're not going to bring this up.
I mean that was how they did it back
then because they felt like they had a
duty to keep America strong and they
just,
everybody just kept it to themselves and
kept their mouth shut.
Yeah.
Well I mean taft taft was crazy and you
know,
with the Preston and bring up any of his
shit.
How about when Lyndon Johnson literally
was doing a press conference while he's
taking a shit?
That's right.
That's a true story.
Yeah.
Press conference on the toilet,
taking a shit in front of a bunch of
reporters.
He would talk to his cabinet guys or
guys would come in and,
and he would be dictating notes and he'd
be,
you know,
squatting on the,
on the pot there and you've got to
admire,
they,
the guy was comfortable in his own skin.
But,
uh,
I think that,
you know,
everything's gotten sliced and diced.
Um,
and which is by itself also very
divisive.
So the more that you do that,
the more you take,
you know,
the country and say,
well,
we're going to,
we're going to slice this up in the
various demographics and sectors and
groups and opinions and we're going to
go after this one.
Well by definition you're going to end
up pitting groups against each other.
And that's what we've been seeing.
And I think that's in part why we're,
why we're so fuck now.
You know,
and,
and it's not,
it's not a new phenomena.
I'm not going to throw all that on the
current administration.
You know,
they've been,
I think they've been more divisive than
they have been unifying.
But you know,
overall as a country.
And part of it may be the speed of
information and all the rest of this
shit,
but it just seems like,
you know,
we're,
we're getting to the point where I think
we're going to have to get rid of the
two parties,
says,
Hey,
we'll keep the two party system,
but we're gonna have to have a third,
maybe a fourth.
There's got to be more potential
opportunities for people because that's
what they're demanding.
Yeah,
I agree.
Yeah.
Anyone else?
I think,
I think there shouldn't be a president
anymore.
I think it's a ridiculous ideas to
cabinet.
Just a committee.
Just having one guy that's in show me,
we know he's not really in charge.
We know there's just too much shit going
on.
There's no way he could be.
There's not mean when something happens,
if something goes wrong,
like someone,
someone said to me something,
a drones,
they were talking about drones and Obama
has blood on his hands.
Mike,
do you really think he's in charge of
all that?
Do you really think there's any way this
guy could be on top of the economy,
can be on top of international trade?
It could be on top of international
relations.
And he's also piloting drones.
There's a lawyer in the White House
basically,
by the way,
who makes that call on high value
targets and whether we get to go or not
go a lawyer,
a lawyer does.
Yeah.
Go figure.
How does it know with no real national
security experience?
Who's The guy?
Don't even say his name.
I won't say,
I won't say the name,
but,
so this guy decides whether or not it's
worth the potential casualties.
Yeah,
there's a,
there's a shitload of work that goes on
in,
uh,
in getting to that point where you can
say,
we've got the target package.
We,
uh,
can we go or not go?
And people,
you know,
and again,
I understand,
you know,
when people think that the,
the agencies out there,
you know,
look at the,
create a one world government,
a screw everybody over.
But,
um,
how the fuck could that ever happen?
I had all that shit
drives me fucking crazy.
The FBI and CIA can't even get along
long
and you can't,
well I mean,
and sometimes you don't get it right.
Right,
exactly.
I mean there are so many,
and maybe cause we talk about checks and
balances,
we talk about the Intel committees and
you know,
the sort of that nature,
but maybe what maybe what really keeps
us safe from the one world government
has affected,
you know,
there's so much territorial pissing that
goes on between the different agencies.
But the point being is that once you get
that target package and you,
and you,
you,
you've got to go get approval and the
approval is not housed in the,
in the agency.
It's not housed at the Pentagon final
decision makings over at the White
House.
And it's,
it's,
it's basically a legal perspective.
And so once that's done,
then yeah,
sure you can,
you can fire a rocket up their ass if,
you know,
if they're still where they are and you
can get the decision made quick enough.
But it's,
uh,
yeah,
I,
but I agree with it.
So your,
your,
your point is correct.
You know,
the president,
you know,
it's like a CEO of a company,
he didn't know what the hell is going on
past his division leaders or no,
he could,
there's no way he could possibly know
all the things that are going on that
the United States is involved with all
over the world.
There's no way.
I mean,
what do we have?
How many different paces don't we have
like bases in more than a hundred
countries?
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean if you just define a base as the
u s you know,
permanent or semipermanent presence.
Yeah.
It's,
it's a,
it's a lot.
But there's no,
and then,
and not just that,
but I mean every,
every other operation that goes on,
every other activity that goes on,
every,
there's,
you know,
that's why,
but I will say that's why you want at
the top while we still have a president.
That's why you want someone who's very
reasoned and,
uh,
clear-eyed,
not thin skinned.
She wants someone who can negotiate.
You want someone who doesn't think
they're the smartest person in the room
and then they need to be able to pull
together the cabinet that is going to
actually start making decisions.
And I think presidential candidates even
at this stage,
should be required to WHO's going to be
in their cabinet.
Who would be your choice for,
for these various,
but yeah,
I think,
you know,
that doesn't really get brought up,
right?
No.
Oh No,
no.
I and I,
I,
you know,
I think it would make a big difference.
You want to know who their team is going
to be and you know,
who knows?
Maybe that would cause a scramble for
top people and then you'd,
I don't know what that was all that
would mean,
but it,
it's a,
let's just say it's a very disappointing
political season.
My big fear is that we're going to have
artificial intelligence and then one day
artificial intelligence is going to
govern world policy and world world
issues.
I really believe that.
I know I'm a Carter for thinking this,
but I think that there's a co was going
to come a point in time where we
establish rules of operation,
you know,
do no harm or do the least harm
possible.
You know,
these are the laws,
these are the parameters that we need to
uh,
operate in.
These are the rules that we need to
enforce.
And this is when something gets like,
like something like Isis,
when it gets to a point where everyone
agrees,
okay,
we have a,
we have a tremendous issue.
We've got to do something militarily,
strategically.
Some,
some choices have to be made.
What do we do?
And that you could punch this in somehow
or another to something,
some sort of artificial intelligence and
it will dish out some sort of a decision
based upon the rules of engagement based
upon the,
the agreed upon parameters that we have
set.
Yeah,
I mean,
yeah,
we're kind of marching it,
I know what the world would get to that
point.
But you know,
we certainly work games scenarios out
where you're,
you're running a large number of
potential possibilities,
um,
through the system.
And it,
and it is literally like you said,
it's spitting out,
you know,
likely outcomes.
And you're weighing that against me
because one big part that it's always
missed because you know,
again,
there's this tendency to think that,
you know what,
people are just out there doing shit for
the hell of it,
but there's a,
there's a big risk versus gain
calculation that goes on,
whether it's at the agency or the
military anywhere else.
And so you're constantly evaluating this
and part of that eventually becomes
political risk,
political blow back.
Um,
so yeah,
that's like the Benghazi thing.
How did I end up on that?
Um,
but you look at Benghazi and you think,
um,
here's the part I don't understand about
that.
And not that you asked,
but all they had to do during the course
of that attack and they had no idea how
long that attack was going to go on for.
All they had to do was put the birds up
with the guys in them and head towards
Bengazi.
That's all they had to do.
And then this would not have ever been a
story.
They probably wouldn't have gotten there
in time to save lives,
but they would've gotten there.
They would have been there,
they would have secured the facility,
they would have helped with the dust to
clean up and they it,
and it wouldn't have been an issue.
But the idea that they could all be
sitting around in the war room watching
this and not have that,
you know,
pop in their heads because three to four
weeks down the road was a national
election.
And all I could imagine was who's going
to be some goat rope.
And they couldn't get the,
to the point where they thought there'd
be zero risk,
but it doesn't any sense.
All those guys on the ground wanted was
to know that the calvary had been
called,
they didn't expect to be saved,
but they thought that help would be on
its way because that's what you do.
And,
and it's a,
it's one of those strange.
So when you talk about,
you know,
scenarios in war gaming and potential
political blow back and all that,
it's a fascinating world where you sit
in a war room and all these different
sides are being debated.
My perspective on my gaseous,
I just don't understand why they didn't
just try.
That's all they had to do.
And so we would have been a stories
because of the election.
I think there were,
I think there were more political
operatives in that room then a then
tactical operators.
And I think that somebody got jammed up,
um,
who wanted to spin them up and send
them.
And I think that it was probably
because,
and again,
I understand it's speculation and I get
it,
and I'm not one of those people that
said they could have saved those lives.
That wouldn't happen.
But I just don't understand the simple
concept that one of those political
operatives who said,
you know what,
if we don't try,
yeah,
we might get fucked on this.
Well,
shouldn't there also be a scenario or at
least a,
just a rule in place that whenever
there's an attack you send in the
troops,
that's,
that's the component that you're
supposed to be keeping.
That's a promise is supposed to be
there.
And that's why I promise that's a great
way of putting it.
And that's why all those,
all the guys have been,
you know,
in the folks that were in that program
and,
and everybody I know was,
is people say why,
why would you be fixated on this?
Why,
why,
you know,
why is this important?
It doesn't mean,
you know,
like Hillary Clinton said,
what Ma,
what difference does it,
yeah,
exactly.
And for that reason that you said there
is,
there is this understanding that you
will make the effort,
you'll try and nobody out there on that
pointy edge of the spear expects that
there'll be saved.
But they do expect that someone's going
to call the calvary
and throw the idea that you're left
hanging to be hung out to dry with an a.
It's not like there's no resources.
That's where it doesn't make any sense.
You know,
we have no sources.
Yeah.
That's why it's so disturbing to people.
It's like if this was a political
decision,
it's like to try to minimize blow back
because of the election coming up.
So let's just not do anything.
If that was the decision,
well that that's contrary to the whole
purpose of having military in the first
place.
Like if there's a fucking attack he
supposed to send in the troops,
particularly attack on your facilities
and particularly to make sure that that
fucking never happens again because you
know that every time there's an election
coming up and well they're not going to
do shit because there's an election
coming up in two weeks now we can go in
and it's time to do it.
Yeah.
That's a crazy precedent to set.
Well it,
it,
it is.
And again,
I wasn't there.
I don't know.
I just,
in looking at it all the various
scenarios and knowing what resources
were available and knowing what the guys
expected on the ground,
I just don't,
I don't,
I don't get it.
And you know,
for a group,
meaning the administration that's
supposed to be so clever and politically
savvy,
it just didn't make any sense.
And now they've been having to suffer
with it ever since.
And aside from the fact that they did,
judges didn't fucking make the effort to
try to save these people.
And again,
not that they would have,
but how do you not,
how do you not try?
I don't,
I don't understand that.
I don't understand any of it.
I don't understand.
Whenever they're making decisions based
on whether or not there's an election
coming up and you would do something
differently if there was and in people's
lives could be lost because an elections
coming up versus how you would behave.
It was first term or first year,
first term.
I think it's all madness.
Well,
there's a risk aversion,
um,
that that takes hold.
And we got to a point,
and it's not just a recent thing,
it's not just this administration,
you know,
to be fair,
but there's this,
this understanding or this belief
somehow that we can get to a zero risk
on a military operation or an
intelligence operation.
And you know,
so show me that we won't have
casualties.
Well,
what the,
what the fuck does that mean?
You're at a risk taking business.
You want to try to minimize that risk
for sure.
But when,
when,
when your decision making gets to that
point and you start,
then it starts feeding down through the
ranks and you start getting mid level
managers rising up who believed that,
you know,
uh,
a good watch is when nothing happens on
their watch.
You've got a real problem because it's
unrealistic.
Yeah.
I mean you don't,
again,
you don't,
you don't want to rush you out there.
You know,
until you,
you,
you want to have a game plan,
right?
You want to know what you're doing
operationally.
But you know,
there,
there are certain things that are worth
bend and you spear over now for a guy
like you
that was in the CIA for so long,
it's been involved in this stuff for so
long.
How exhausting is all of this because it
seems to me that like,
it seems like it never ends.
It seems like you
like
is step back for a little while and it
just piles up more.
It did.
Indeed.
If you retire,
the new guy comes in and you look at the
new guy doing it and like the same
shit's happening and it doesn't seem
like anybody put a dent in anything and
it continues to go on like the Middle
East at one point.
What point in time?
I mean how I know what you're getting at
there.
That seems pretty buttoned up.
I think we've got that under control.
It's the craziest fucking place in the
world.
It's the if the whole world,
okay,
let's put it this way.
If the whole world was serious,
right?
Yeah.
It was just one big one.
Big series.
Syria.
What,
what the fuck if the whole world he was
Olivia.
Yeah.
Imagine the whole world was Libya.
What?
Nah.
You know what?
I,
um,
if you had told us,
we spent a lot of time trying to get the
Soviets out of Afghanistan during the
Soviet occupation of Afghanistan and the
Soviet strike.
I spend a lot of time trying to get
themselves out of there.
About four years into their occupation,
their,
and they realize,
and we know this because we've seen the,
you know,
the Kremlin papers and we've had,
access to a lot of their,
their thinking at that time.
Uh,
they,
after about year four,
they said,
this is fucked up.
We gotta get Outta here.
But what could they do?
So they spent the next five years or so
try a variety of things.
They tried to,
first of all,
they tried to find a government are
individuals that they could,
they could leave and place that we
continue to push their agenda.
They couldn't find anybody.
They were dealing with corruption.
We know that they couldn't,
you know,
they couldn't get past a lot of the
corruption.
That sounds familiar.
They retreated from the countryside and
decided,
well,
we'll just hold the urban centers.
So that's exactly what we did.
So they went through the same problems
that we did.
If you would said anything when we were
out there handing a weapons systems,
the Musha Dean,
and in retrospect maybe that wasn't a
good idea.
Um,
but if you had told us that we'd be back
two and a half decades later,
doing the same thing that the Soviets
were doing,
you know,
trying to,
I don't know what,
what we're trying to do,
build a nation,
you know,
uh,
sell democracy where they don't have a
fucking clue what we were selling.
Um,
so we don't,
part of it is what,
what you were saying.
We don't learn from our mistakes.
So that's why that's the probably the
most tiring part is watching shit happen
over and over and cycles and every
generation thinks they can do it better.
And so that's,
and that's a good thing probably,
but there's a lot of Hubris involved,
right?
And thinking that you're going to do
this somehow,
it's going to be different this time.
I had a guy debating this guy who,
uh,
will remain anonymous.
She was in the military and,
um,
we were in,
we were in Afghanistan,
um,
at that point already with trying to
nation build.
And I was very pessimistic about the
whole thing.
And I kept saying this a fucking,
you know,
uh,
this is not what we should be doing with
our boys are women as well and the
resources and everything else.
I said,
they don't understand what the fuck
we're after here.
And we did a great tactical mission,
you know,
right after nine 11 we did a beautiful,
I sound like trump.
Beautiful.
That's the mission.
And that's what we're good at.
What great attack,
tactical missions.
But then you know,
about springtime in 2002,
we should have gotten the fuck out so
that if you do it again,
we're going to come back.
And we didn't,
we stayed because we wanted to build a
road or improve their literacy rate by a
couple of points.
So this guy said,
well,
it's different this time,
because I was saying,
look,
it didn't work for the Russians.
Why do you think it's gonna work for us?
And he said,
well,
they hated the Russians.
And I thought,
wow,
that's,
that's your reasoning is because somehow
they like us,
they or they,
they're gonna,
you know,
we're going to fill chocolate bars out
to him and they,
you know,
they're going to end and stockings and
they're going to come running.
I mean,
what the Hell is that point?
But we have this,
this mentality that we're going to do it
better this time.
So you look at,
you look at,
uh,
you look at Isis for example,
and I mean,
who couldn't have guessed if we
completely walk out,
you can debate all sorts of things about
Iraq,
but who couldn't have seen,
if you'll walk out of that place,
it was going to devolve into chaos.
If you leave a vacuum,
it's not good.
And so that's what we've got.
But we keep doing the same things over
and over again.
And you could argue what we've doing in
Iraq.
We did all those years ago after the
Soviets left Afghanistan.
And so we left and it evolved into what
it devolves into.
And oddly enough,
there were a lot of neo cons who thought
that was terrible.
We felt guilty about that.
So now we're going to get it right this
time.
We're going to stay not thinking about
what happened to the Soviets.
I Dunno.
I remember when Mccain was debating
Obama when they were running for
president and Obama was
talking about going into Afghanistan.
And uh,
I remember this is a very sobering
moment where Mccain said,
what,
what are you talking about going to
Afghanistan?
You just going to send troops in.
Do you understand that place?
And it was clear that Obama didn't,
you could tell by his body language.
You could tell by the way he was
speaking about it,
mccain had this really clear sentence.
He said,
that plays hasn't changed since
Alexander the Great was running it.
And when,
when he said that,
I remember thinking like,
Whoa,
what the fuck?
So then I started researching
Afghanistan,
then I started researching the terrain
and how crazy it is.
It's like literally like trying to
control like the rocky mountains,
like the back country out of hell.
It's so remote.
It's so impossible to get to.
And then you find out that there's
really only one city.
There's Kabul in the entire country.
This basically,
you know,
it was a few little towns.
There's one city.
Yeah.
And it's just warm.
Don't know what they don't know what
we've been trying to sell them.
And it's the same with,
with Iraq.
It's the same with Libya.
Libya's a complete hot mess.
Now,
isn't it crazy that getting rid of
Qaddafi made Libya
worse?
Well,
it,
it Kadafi here's the,
that wacky thing.
Kadafi was kind of our guy,
uh,
on counter terrorism for a few years
before he got,
you know,
got pushed out.
And because he had,
he had found Jesus and you know,
not literally I guess.
Yeah,
whatever,
however they put it.
Um,
and he had started to cooperate with us
and then the Arab spring happened and
then there was this bizarre belief that
democracy was going to sweep through the
region.
And the Italians and French came to us
and said,
you know,
we've got lots of interests there in
Libya,
widget back us up.
We had no national security interests in
Libya and yet we went in and we did what
we did and now it's a shit hole.
It's 130 some odd tribes in Libya,
and we're still talking right now.
We're still talking as if somehow we're
going to find a federal government and
that's what's going to help us.
Because then one of the genitals just
came out yesterday or today or whenever,
and he said,
well,
I don't think the Olympian Olympians are
gonna be able to take care of isis
themselves because Isis,
now you've got a very strong,
uh,
holden in Libya because they're smart
because they realize they're having
problems in Syria and Iraq.
They've been looking for another place.
Libya is chaotic.
So the general says,
I,
you know,
what?
You know,
so once we get this unified government,
then we can work on training and
assisting and providing resources and it
just over and over.
So to answer your original question,
but in a very roundabout way,
yes,
it's,
it's tiring because you see the same
shit
over and over again.
Yeah.
I can only imagine.
I can only imagine just trying,
just trying to nation build the scene,
seeing these people that,
first of all,
you're dealing with completely different
cultures,
completely different cultures.
Completely different educations.
People who are so backwards so far gone
that taking a 45 year old man who is so
fucked up and crazy and religious and
trying to convert him to the ways of the
west,
like these,
these fucking people that executed that
kid the other day in the middle of
Iraq's yeah.
For playing music.
Yeah.
Because he was playing western music.
They beheaded him.
Yeah.
Probably don't understand that.
We can't process it,
but we have never been able to,
you talk about the Viet Cong and we used
to go in and you know,
we thought we were helping a village and
go into the hockey league village and
the Viet Cong in to come in there and
kill them because,
you know,
they'd had contact with us.
One of the first people that we hired,
uh,
sometime ago from my company and
diligence,
uh,
for all your information and security
needs a little plot.
I don't blog.
One of the first guys we hired was a
Russian came out of the,
their gru.
And,
uh,
right after we'd gone in for the tour
bore operation,
he came to me and he had been a tank
driver out in Afghanistan during the
occupation for the Russians and,
and,
uh,
and he came and he,
you could just see,
he was like the intensity on his face,
you know,
and,
uh,
I had known him for a while and so
anyway,
he grabbed me and he said,
he said,
he said that was brilliant.
He said,
meaning Tora Bora,
meaning what we have quickly,
we had acted.
He said that was brilliant.
He says,
don't stay.
He said,
They're like cockroaches.
He says [inaudible] meaning you step on
them here,
they show up over here and you could
just see in his face and that,
that son of a bitch was right.
And if I'd been smart,
I would have dragged him back to the
states and taking them into the Pentagon
and had them say that every hour on the
hour,
you know,
until somebody figured out what the hell
we should have been doing.
Um,
but yeah,
we don't,
we don't seem to listen.
Sometimes you got to jump in.
Sometimes you got to take charge and
sometimes you need somebody who's in
charge.
You need a leader at the top of this
food chain around the world because if
you don't have,
when you get what we get now,
I would argue that part of the problem
we have is the administration for
whatever their motivation,
whatever their reasons.
And again,
you know,
fine,
they want to do it.
That's their,
that's what they're gonna do.
They've stepped off the world stage to
some degree.
They don't want to be the world's
policemen are the world's lead or they
don't want to be at the top.
And when you do that,
it's not as if suddenly a community of
nations fills that void.
Some other interest is going to try to
become the top dog.
That's just the fucking way.
So it's almost like there's a balance
that's already been achieved and you
have to maintain that balance some way
in some way,
shape or form.
I would respond to us,
be at the top of the food chain because
I think,
and some people will argue and there's
always,
you know,
the folks who think we never act in
[inaudible] best interest of anybody and
you just
pretend I'm them.
Sure.
It's the greatest terrorist
organization,
the world,
man.
Don't you know that's,
you know what?
That's exactly what I'm talking about.
Spin invading countries forever,
man.
Why don't you just leave them alone just
for oil.
Yeah.
All we want is oil and gemstones,
diamonds.
We definitely want that stuff.
We didn't want that stuff.
Sure.
Yeah.
The problem is we want that stuff too,
right?
So it's,
but it's not that cut and dry.
You've got some fucked up parts of the
world and the more I talked to people
that have been the fall,
those fucked up parts of the world,
the more that picture is starting to be
clear and clear.
The Mar Mar,
I talked to guys like Jocko willink
who've been over there,
seals,
people that have served over there.
You get this of this place that's
not America.
And you get a lot of people that are
talking about the rest of the world as
if we're talking about America,
like bad spots in America,
like oil.
We need to fix Chicago.
Well it says fucking fix in Chicago's
Goddamn cake walk compared to fixing
Cabo or fixing any of these spots in the
world.
Syria.
Yeah.
And by the way,
we could,
we could be at the top of the global
food chain and still fixed Chicago.
Yeah.
We can multitask.
But in,
I guess that,
yeah,
I spent enough time behind the curtain,
a of the u s government and that,
you know,
my,
my view was his college somewhat.
Right.
And I understand everybody's got their
opinions based on their,
their experiences,
my experiences,
what it is.
I don't,
I,
I don't believe the US government is out
there to fuck everybody over.
They,
sometimes they make a mistake.
We tend to be a pretty self correcting
nation.
We try,
sometimes it takes awhile,
whatever.
But you know,
we,
I would rather us be the ones up there,
uh,
trying to,
to uh,
direct traffic.
Then some other nations like China or
Russia or Iran for the Middle East just
make decision making and we don't always
get it right.
Absolutely not.
And you do have to have checks and
balances of course your fucking toe.
I mean it's,
you know,
that's,
that's where people always,
you know,
fall on one side of there while you're
just,
all you want to do is steal oil and
treasure.
No,
I just want,
I want to try to ensure that we've got
some good intent at the top of the food
chain and I think the u s is,
is well positioned for that because we
try,
and again,
we don't always get it right,
but we make that effort so people can
disagree and I'm sure they are right now
saying,
ah,
he's got an opinion,
but well,
yeah I do.
Well you,
you,
you actually have a qualified opinion
and that's the difference between your
opinion and someone who's going,
the United States.
Man,
we need to stay out of other countries,
man.
Th I think we need to pay attention to
what's going on outside of the United
States for sure.
I just don't know what you could
possibly do to sort of smooth over the
Middle East and bring them up to date.
I just don't know how you could,
how do you bring Isis up to date?
How do you say,
hey guys,
you really,
you can't execute 15 year old kids for
listening to rap music.
You can't,
you can't negotiate.
it's not an organization that we're
going to be able to deal with in,
in,
in a,
in a manner that would make us all feel
happy because we talk them down from,
you know,
from the ledge and,
and,
and then I could have committed violence
anymore.
That's,
that's not going to happen.
Um,
and you can't also kill your way out of
it.
There's that,
that's the other part of it.
So how do you do it?
Well,
you try to,
you try to manage it and you manage it
in part by not allowing the extremist to
have their own fucking territory because
that,
that caliphate that they'd been Jonesing
for all this time.
That's one of the reasons why they've
been having so much success in
recruiting foreign fighters.
And that's when a shit load of people
going into that place and they do it
because,
hey look,
we finally got our own turf.
Now we can take that turf.
Uh,
it's,
it's now much more problematic because
we sat on the sidelines for some time
and the Russians are in there and nobody
wants to get into a shooting match with
the Russians at this stage of the game.
But denying them territory and then
realizing that like with cockroaches are
going to pop up over here and then
they've got a more fun,
they're going to be over here.
We're just gonna have to play whack a
mole for the rest of our lives.
Probably this doesn't go away,
but we can minimize it.
And we can be aggressive enough without
saying we're going to try to nation
build and also sell them something that
they don't understand.
So I don't know.
I just,
but,
but I can't,
having sat on the sidelines for a while,
we've created more of a mess,
um,
at this stage of the game,
the Russian and Iranian influence,
uh,
in Syria,
the neurons have more influence in the
Middle East now than they've had in
modern times.
And this is this.
They can't imagine their good fortune.
And so now what are we doing one?
Now the headlines are,
look,
they just had elections and the
reformists are winning as if somehow
Rod's going to change its tune.
It's insane.
We've had that hope for decades and
decades,
and every time there's a little glimmer
of,
you know,
maybe the reformist,
the moderates,
you know,
are going to rise up.
It,
it doesn't happen.
Well,
didn't we have a part of that too
though,
right?
Like we're,
we,
we brought in the ayatollah to get rid
of the shah.
Yeah.
I'm,
they're like,
uh,
well we,
we,
yeah,
we didn't,
so much foam ended as we just stood by
and watched it happen.
And so what happened,
I mean,
it wasn't sort of influenced that at
all.
Now the shot was our guy,
the Shah was our gunshot was our guy.
We brought in the shot though,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean we,
we,
and the Shah was a son of a bitch,
you know,
just in the same,
he was,
yeah.
Frankly,
it was not much different than Bashir
Assad or Assad's Dad.
I got it confused.
So the ayatollah came in and how did the
ayatollah get into,
oh,
he was in exile in France and,
um,
there had been for some time because of
the brutality of the Shaw,
there had been a hard line,
a clerical uprising,
you know,
sort of directing traffic amongst the
population.
And so the Shah who was our guy was
brutal and he was fucking up.
Right.
And he had it,
he had a very brutal intelligence
service.
And,
uh,
so that was,
yeah,
that wasn't a happy chapter in the sense
of,
um,
you know,
was the Shah our guy?
Well,
yes,
but have we had other guys that were,
you know,
dead spots or,
or not,
not so much.
Desk spots is just really unsavory.
People that in an ideal world you
wouldn't want to associate with,
but the real world doesn't work that
way.
There are some fucked up people out
there.
And the fact of the matter is sometimes
you got to deal with a person that's
there.
Oh,
that was the argument about,
but what's going on in Iraq,
right?
No,
that was the audit or the argument about
Saddam Hussein.
It's about Saddam Hussein was a horrible
person.
He's a dangerous guy.
But getting rid of them might be worth.
Yeah.
And then there were a number of people
that said that and what turned that tide
and people will,
you know,
people like trump himself,
ah,
you know,
Bush lied.
People died.
You know,
it was only George Bush who thought
there was weapons of mass distraction.
Lady shifted.
He said,
if he gets an office,
he's going to find out the truth about
who brought the towers down.
Oh my God.
No,
he's a fucking truther.
He's a truth or not.
Not only that,
he's also remember,
remember he's a birther,
he thinks Obama was born in Kenya.
Do you remember that?
Everybody's conveniently ignored this.
I know.
Yeah.
Nobody is going after the obvious shit.
I didn't know,
but I didn't know about that.
The truth or bit.
Oh my God.
It just keeps,
it keeps,
keeps piling on.
This is a recent statement that he made.
Um,
yeah,
I,
you know what?
It's a,
how does that,
how again,
how does it,
how does it happen that this country is
fantastic country?
Again,
I spent most of my life overseas.
I can go to the deepest,
darkest shit somewhere out there,
middle of nowhere.
And someone will,
will say,
if I go to America,
I can work this hard and I can do really
well.
I just have to,
I,
you know,
if I can get to America,
they still people out there in the
middle of nowhere,
still believe the American dream.
And yet you worry about it because I
think we seem to be given up on it here.
If this is the best we've got,
if we're willing to follow this guy,
you know,
down the down the tunnel.
I don't know.
I know where we're heading,
but it's not good.
And you know,
and I also worry about part of it with
Bernie Sanders going back to him is I
think sometimes the young people who
support him,
part of it is sort of being
disheartened,
you know,
since 2008 they don't see themselves as
being part of the American dream.
And if you don't imagine yourself
working hard and becoming wealthy,
then you don't give a shit whether tax
rates go up to 85% or not.
It doesn't matter to you because it's
not going to be you.
It's going to be somebody else.
Well,
it's just so confusing to people that no
one can get it.
Right.
I mean,
everybody had these hopes and dreams for
Obama and he was going to get an office.
I remember this,
this lady that was when Obama got
elected,
she was,
uh,
she was so happy and she was saying,
I'm so happy because now I know that if,
uh,
my mortgage needs to be paid,
he's going to help me.
And it was like,
there's this really weird like moment
where I realized like,
wow,
these people don't really understand how
complex this entire system is.
And you dealing with a guy who's
stepping into the office,
right?
When all these banks are failing,
When all of this collapse is happening
and people think that all of a sudden
this guy's gonna come in and he's going
to have a completely different set of
priorities and he's going to find all
these people,
you losing your house,
we're going to fix that.
We're going to get that guy to that.
There's 300 million people in this
country,
ma'am.
And there's not enough money to buy
everybody's mortgage back and fix it.
It's just not going to happen.
We voted the guy into office who had no
experience.
He never had a job.
And yeah,
and,
and so you get what you get.
And I understand.
Okay,
everybody was excited.
Sure.
Hope and change and all that idea.
It was,
it was very powerful message that they
were delivering.
It was a smart,
smart campaign,
but you would think that over a period
of time then what we'd really
want now is somebody,
and again,
I didn't know where to find them,
but if somebody with that combination of
experience and character and a proven
ability,
a track record to work both sides,
right?
To say,
look,
we're going to be able to negotiate.
We're going to compromise.
We're going to find,
you know,
it's not rocket fucking science to work
out some of these problems.
Right.
But the more problems we get and the
more negative we get about them,
it seems insurmountable.
But we should be able to find somebody
in this massive country of ours who,
um,
you know,
can propose some,
uh,
clear-eyed ideas.
I don't know.
Well,
for me it almost seems like taking a guy
who,
this is analogy that makes sense to me.
Taking guys never fought before and
then,
um,
make him run for the UFC and now all is
you're going to fight in the UFC.
What was your fucking experience
Fridays?
I,
you're welcome.
You don't have any experience.
Like,
you know what I'm saying?
Like all of a sudden this guy gets his
job.
It's the most complicated an impossible
job in the world.
And he's,
he's never,
he's never served.
He's never been overseas.
He's never experienced combat.
He doesn't know what it means to be
involved in a war.
He's never been there physically boots
on the ground.
Okay.
I'm not saying he has to,
but I'm saying in that help,
but what wouldn't that flavor,
how you would understand and consider
military action if you had actually been
there,
whether you'd been there like at least
Bush senior had been in the CIA.
He had been the head of CIA.
Bush Jr was class senior was a World War
II.
Yes,
that's right.
Right.
This guy shot down,
it's Bush senior was probably the most
qualified guy and to shut up,
asked her to China,
China,
head of the CIA.
A war hero.
Uh,
I mean look the guy,
you know,
but yeah,
you're right.
Shit on now left and right and,
and that's where we're at.
You can't,
you can't disagree with somebody's
opinions without crapping on them.
Right?
Yeah.
You can't just say,
look,
I get it.
You've got different opinions than I do.
Yeah.
Okay,
fine.
Let's talk.
Let's figure out where is the workable
solution that you have to have this.
Speaker two,
this is the other thing.
You have to be this engaging,
entertaining individual who I'd like to
hear talk.
I want to hear like one of the things
that was so great about Obama was how
good he is.
A giving speeches.
It's brilliant,
brilliant orator.
I mean,
he had me,
I was like,
this is my fucking guy.
Yeah.
I listened to him talk,
finally got a smart guy.
And as opposed to Bush,
who was Bush jr who was an awkward sort
of a guy.
I mean,
w just wasn't that good of a talker and
you know,
people would say he's stupid.
He's a dumb guy.
Go back and listen to him when he was
running for governor of Texas.
He's not a dumb guy.
No you don't.
You're tired and overwhelmed.
You don't get,
you don't get to those positions.
You know,
by being an idiot.
You made disagree with people's
positions.
Like I disagree with Bernie Sanders.
I don't,
I don't wish him any ill will.
I'm not horrified that he's running.
I think that's the way it works in this
country.
Um,
I disagree with the concept of,
of socialism or democratic socialism,
but at the same time I understand and I
appreciate the fact that that's what he
believes and he's believed it for a long
time.
So great.
Let's,
you know,
and,
and you're right,
we should be trying to,
to,
to help people that need a leg up.
We should be trying to provide a safety
net,
you know,
for the,
for the people that need it.
We should be trying to at the same time
promoting the concept of hard work and
success.
There's,
there's nothing wrong fucking it all.
There's nothing wrong with success.
You work hard.
It's like,
it's like monopoly.
Monopolies decided they're going to,
I don't know whether for all their board
games now,
but monopoly is going to take away the
paper money and give you a bank card
wide.
Yeah,
yeah.
That sets,
I couldn't believe it when I saw Hasbro,
which owns when offaly they said,
well,
we're going to use a bank card for now
on.
So all those kids out there,
because I don't know,
maybe they don't want them to learn how
to count paper money because maybe it's
unseemly.
I'm reading something into it.
It's not there obviously,
but it just did not.
Yeah.
It's part and parcel of my kids.
You know,
they started a,
they started playing basketball a couple
seasons ago and uh,
I remember the first league,
they didn't want to keep score.
Oh yeah.
That's a big one.
What the fuck?
Yeah.
You're not allowed to be a loser.
And we don't want to put these kids
through stress,
but you know what?
I was playing softball.
Nobody.
One,
what the fuck are you doing?
Why are you playing?
Get off the field.
Let's go do something else.
If you,
if nobody's going to wink out to feel
bad,
that's part of being a kid.
Feel bad.
And you go,
did fat fucking sucked and then you
practice.
And you know what?
And those kids know I could ask my six
year old,
I could ask,
I could ask sluggo way into the third
quarter of a basketball game and say,
what's the score?
And he would know the scores.
All the kids knew the score,
they all all keeping score.
And so we're just blowing smoke up,
you know,
the parents asked and,
and,
and consequently,
we think we're being clever with our
kids.
The saying,
Hey,
you know,
this will be fine.
They got,
but I don't know how I got off on this,
but my kid walked off the scooter,
the oldest one walked off the lacrosse
field,
uh,
and looked at me and he said,
so how'd I do?
And I said,
well,
yeah,
I don't honestly,
do you want me to be honest or do you
want me to blow smoke up your ass?
And I,
I'd said it and I didn't realize it,
where the parents around and they were
horrified.
And then I got a dressing down.
And,
uh,
anybody said,
God bless him.
He said,
I want you to be honest.
And I said,
well,
you didn't,
you didn't really try as hard as you
could.
I said,
you know,
you don't have to be the best,
but you got to try really hard.
And the only reason that other kid was
with scoring on it was because he wanted
it more.
And I said,
and you can do that,
you know,
and,
and you,
you can tell kids that they're,
they're not playing their best.
You can in a nice,
you know,
constructive way.
But God forbid we should,
we should hurt any of these little
snowflakes,
right?
By telling him this crap,
and now what do we get?
All those kids that started years ago
when we started this movement to not
keep score or anything.
Now they're all at Yale or Amhurst and
they,
they think that being contradicted means
they're being persecuted.
And so we created this monster
ourselves.
And now a lot of those people that,
you know,
they,
they look and they don't believe because
they've been told they're victims and
the system's rigged and they're getting
fucked every day.
They don't believe they can be part of
the system.
So sure.
They look at Bernie and they think,
yeah,
that's about right.
That's what we need.
And they find likeminded people.
They band together,
they all agree on the same thing,
and they're,
they're,
they're having a battle right now to try
to see who can be the most open minded,
the most liberal,
the most accepting.
And that's where the competition is.
The competition is being the most left
wing,
the most progressive that they're,
they're fucking each over other,
over on progressiveness.
Yeah.
I just asked progressing even the words
of justice,
it's not even know.
It's,
um,
it's madness.
It's so,
Madison isn't even a word.
I can't even have a word for it.
Yeah.
Progressive.
Making the word.
Yeah.
George Bush made that up.
We're getting to a weird porn point
where we're trying to coddle people and
we're not allowing them to experience
defeat.
We're not allowing them to experience
discomfort,
which is how people grow.
When if you don't feel uncomfortable,
you don't learn.
You don't learn from every mistake that
I've ever made made me feel like shit
and that's how I get better at things.
Yeah,
cause you learned.
I don't want to feel that way again.
So how do I get better?
How do I,
how do I do this?
But if you don't do it with wrestling,
that's a good question.
That is,
he can get pinned.
You don't get pinned.
Okay.
Shit.
You know,
I mean how the fuck they call up before
you get pins and say,
Oh hey were okay.
You look like you're approaching a pin,
so let's stop it.
How are they going to do it?
Because I'll tell you what,
man,
I,
this fucking times I got pinned when I
was 14 years old.
It's still fuck with my head.
Cut me.
Carry that.
All these years in the gym,
lifting weights.
Think about some kid pinned me fucking
high school and I'll get angry little
Bobby Schwartz.
That's father fiber.
I'll start doing extra chin ups for that
prick.
I'm going to go find.
That's what motivates you,
motivates you,
you know?
I mean,
getting tapped out in Jujitsu there,
there are guys that have tapped me out
that are literally like,
when I'm tired,
I will think about them tapping me out
and I will push further.
That is the only thing that motivates
you is that fee.
What's one of the only things that's
really a powerful motivating factor that
everyone can relate to is that feeling
of defeat,
that horrible feeling where you go,
you know what?
I got to get better.
I got to get better because someone's
better.
And the idea that you're saying that no
one's ever better,
you're perfect.
That's not true.
It's not true.
You get better at stuff.
There's always somebody that's always
just like,
I tell my kids,
because always somebody is going to be
bigger than you.
There's always somebody that's going to
be smarter than you.
That's fine.
All you can do is the absolute best you
can do.
And you work at it.
And if you fall down,
you know,
if I could lose,
yeah.
You got to learn how to lose weight,
how to lose as an important part of
being a grownup.
But we've got,
I mean,
look at it,
look at it again.
Look at this.
The,
the,
the irony of,
of kids and expensive colleges,
um,
denigrating free speech because it,
it,
it upsets their feelings.
Rest the fucking kidding me.
Progressive aggressors.
We've got to look that word up.
Can we get some help on this?
My God.
Yeah.
Well,
the idea of being a progressive is a
great idea.
You know,
you want everybody to be equal and you
want equality as far as law and how
people are treated and how you address
people.
And no one is,
no one starts out in a worse spot.
But once that's established,
then you've got to compete.
Yeah.
And you have to,
and it's good for everybody.
It's good for you.
It's good for me.
It's given,
as long as you're competing fairly,
it,
it generates that competition.
Generates a lot of good things.
First of all,
it generates ambition.
It generates success.
If you overcome these,
these obstacles that are created by
competition,
you understand what,
what needs to be done in order to
achieve things.
You,
you,
if you're going to go through life and
you're never going to have any
obstacles,
you never going to have any character
testing moments.
You're not even gonna know what you're
capable.
No,
I just started,
I mean,
and that's not much of a life lived.
at the,
at the end of the day,
if you're not tested and you,
and you're not pushed and you don't,
and you don't fail,
I mean,
I remember times when,
yeah,
it just,
it didn't even,
uh,
you,
you knew it wasn't going to work out,
right?
Yeah.
But you just,
it like you said,
it made you work harder.
It made you push harder and you
realized,
uh,
it's like,
you know what it's like,
it's like interrogation trading.
I don't know.
I don't know why this popped in my head,
but it's interrogation training.
The whole point of interrogation
training is to break you down.
So that you realize you've got a point
where it's just going to happen.
So an interrogation training,
like is it training you to be able to
deal with being interrogated?
Yeah.
So what are they doing?
But you also have the other side of the
coin,
which is,
you know,
learning,
learning how to navigate and negotiate
and all the rest of it.
We like to call it negotiation.
Um,
so,
but the idea being is that,
you know,
when you're in,
in a,
in an interrogation training,
the idea is you have to understand that
at some point,
no matter who you are is you're,
it's gonna fall apart.
And then what you need is you need to be
able to pull yourself back together
again.
So the idea of interrogation trading in
part is to show you that hey,
you can go farther than you thought you
could,
but also at some point you're just going
to say,
fuck it.
I May.
Because,
uh,
you know,
depending on where we're at,
you know you're going to break.
I mean,
it's going to happen.
And when you do,
you've got gotta be able to,
otherwise you're just a puddle of Goo,
right?
You've got to pull yourself back
together again.
So it's a bit like that failure.
Like you said,
failure teaches success.
Failure drives success.
Unless,
you know,
unless we teach waning a culture of just
fucking mediocrity and what we are.
Yeah,
we are.
Yeah.
Well that's a happy sign.
I have to learn the consequences.
We Egan,
no,
you can't nerf the world.
You have to learn the consequences of
fucking up.
And if you don't learn the consequences
of fucking up,
you never understand what it takes.
There are people that work harder than
you.
There are people that are smarter than
They're people that want it more.
There are people that are more
ambitious.
There are people that are more intense
and more focused and more disciplined.
And if there are not,
then somehow or another,
we're all perfect and equal.
And that's not the case.
Well,
this,
this competition fuels everything.
We have like,
look,
here's a perfect example.
Every year cars get faster.
Why do they get faster?
Because they're fucking competing
against each other.
Chevy is competing against this company.
They're competing against forward and
they're all trying to make a car that
goes zero to 60 and a half,
a second night,
and every fucking year they get closer
to that.
I mean,
there's one reason for that and it's
because there's other cars out there
that are doing a better job there.
Skid pad and numbers are getting higher
there.
Quarter mile numbers are getting lower.
They're getting faster,
they're handled better,
they're getting safer.
All they're doing this because of
competition.
And that's the only thing that fuels
innovation.
Competition fuels innovation and this
desire that everybody has to,
I want to get the newest,
greatest shit.
Right.
You know,
and that's where they talked about cars.
We were talking about phones where
they're told what it doesn't matter what
it is.
Yeah,
it's everything.
Human beings look whilst they have the
Olympic records,
why?
Why is everybody trying to break
records?
I mean in the UFC we're constantly going
over statistics.
This guys,
one more fights.
This guys landed more significant blows.
This guys landed more submissions.
These,
these,
you're,
you're competing.
This is why people like watching things
like the UFC is because it's contrary to
this participation shit that's going on.
There's a participation trophy bullshit
that's going on with little kids.
And,
and like I said,
I go back to that same point,
which is it,
we're not fooling any of them in a
sense,
over a period of time,
we create a bad precedent and a bad
mentality.
But at that moment that kids know what
the hell this score is,
they know what the hell is going on.
And they,
you know,
and they know that it's,
it's bullshit when you tell them they're
wonderful every time that they're not,
I mean,
if I told my kid,
you know,
every time he finished a practice or a
sports game,
you know,
hey,
you did great.
I mean,
it would,
it means fuck all.
It means nothing to them at a certain
point.
And then he loses when he loses respect,
but he looses also motivation.
He thinks,
well,
fine,
if I'm great all the time,
what the fuck?
I don't,
you know,
better thing to tell them is you know
this horrible feeling that you've got in
your stomach right now.
Use that as fuel.
Fuel yourself with the fuck ups.
Fuel yourself with the failures,
but it doesn't mean we love you less
like your,
your parents and your friends are going
to love you no matter what.
You know,
Randy coture said this to me once.
We were talking about fighters and how
he talks to fighters that he's training
and he said the most important thing is
you can't be afraid to lose.
It's going to happen at one point in
time.
If you keep fighting,
everybody loses.
But you have to think to yourself what,
what is important in life?
Your family loving you,
you're friends loving you,
they're still going to love you.
They're still you.
It's still going to be all,
all those pieces are going to be in
place.
If you lose except that,
and then go out there and do your best.
And as long as you've done your best,
you can keep your chin up and you can,
you can understand that whatever failure
that you've experienced there,
whatever mistake,
this is a,
this is like a mathematical problem
you've learned,
well you can't throw a one,
two and then drop your left hand.
You get hit with a counter right now.
You know,
but if you don't get hit with that
counter right,
you'd never know.
If you go through life just throwing a
one,
two and winning every time you think
you've got the perfect game plan,
then you,
you,
you teach that to someone else and that,
that person realizes,
well no,
this game plan's no good.
You got to keep your fucking hands up.
If you don't keep your hands up,
you get hit these,
these,
there's a certain reality is,
it's one of the reasons why I keep going
back to fighting,
but it's one of the reasons why people
like fighting cause it's so absolute,
right.
Absolutely.
Going to decisions because decisions can
be fucking bullshit.
But other than decisions,
when someone hits you,
they hit you and they don't hit.
You know,
it's very clear.
It's very decisive
for the most part.
And you know,
there,
there is no fucking about,
it's,
it is what it is as opposed to so much
of the rest of the world or what you're
trying to find examples of whatever
words
gray and murky and I don't know if they
same as a score of all goes in the net.
It goes in the net.
That's it.
It goes in or it doesn't go in.
And to raise kids to this,
to have this foggy concept in their head
that it doesn't matter.
Well,
no,
it does matter.
It fucking matters a lot.
Right?
Here's what does,
here's what doesn't matter.
Your parents are going to love you.
Your friends going to love you if your
parents don't love you because you
didn't drop a ball in that.
Your Dad's a piece of shit.
And that's something we all need to
laugh.
Yeah.
And there are there we all experienced
folks.
Yeah,
we've all seen,
I mean,
I've,
I've seen him on the side and one of my,
my kid was going to soccer practice.
I was watching his dad screaming his
daughter and it was like,
God damn it,
dude.
Don't do that.
Go.
So let's go hustle.
Let's go hustle.
And you're like all the fucking sports
terminology.
Let's get that one.
We can get need to get that one back.
We gotta get that one line.
If you're a parent and you're living
your life through your kids,
sporting exploits,
go,
go fucking do something else.
Encourage them and give them what they
need to succeed.
But don't,
don't value yourself through what your
kids are doing and sports.
And there's so many parents out there
that did that.
I,
I coached for a while.
Uh,
my daughter,
who's now in college,
she played a lot of softball.
And so I was coaching at one point,
you know,
before she got to the point where I had
nothing to offer.
And so they had to actually get coaches
who knew what they were doing.
But I remember at one point there was
this one dad who was just like,
he was just a complete douche and he was
always a Douche and he'd just show up
and he'd,
and he'd berate his kid and his kid was
fantastic.
She was a wonderful,
and one time she actually walked up to
me and she was as she was,
you could tell she wanted to cry,
but she didn't choose it.
She was a great kid and she apologized
for her dad's behavior in the dugout
because the dad,
she's like leaning over the fence and
screaming.
And how long was he at that time?
She was 14 I guess.
And it was just,
and I said,
look honey,
it's not your deal.
Your,
it's not your fault.
And then I had to go over and I said,
look,
you have fucking Douche.
And I said that to him and he was eight
and I thought he was going to try to
take my head off,
but he was a,
he was a big boy,
but he couldn't argue with me.
I think he knew deep down he knew.
Yeah,
okay,
the guys right.
I am a Douche.
And I said,
you've got to leave.
You can't come back.
And for a kid to apologize for their
parent's behavior,
but yeah,
you're right.
You see it,
you see it fairly often.
Parents get fucking heated up.
There was a crazy story about a dad who
killed a another dad in a hockey fight.
Yes.
You remember that?
I remember that the kids were playing,
the kids apparently had got into it on
the ice and this fucking big giant guy
beat a guy to death,
beat the guy to death in front of his
kid.
There was another guy,
this guy,
I think it was in Connecticut,
softball also.
It's girl's softball,
you know,
they get very competitive,
but how the fuck do you get so wound up
about,
about any really,
really anything.
But so this guy,
this dad went after,
literally got upset because their kid
wasn't getting enough playing time and
so the coach turned and walked away.
The picked up a bat and went after him
and hit him in the head with a bat and
put them in the hospital.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I remember that.
Yeah.
He hit the coach,
right?
Yeah,
he did.
Yeah.
Cause kid wasn't getting enough light.
I mean,
okay.
Yeah.
Have you ever,
my daughter needs more plain
competition then that's,
that's what people are afraid of with
competition.
That's why they're coming up with this
idea of participation trophies.
There's a lot of people that are moving
away or trying to move away from this.
They want a kinder,
gentler world and they think that that's
the way to do it.
I,
that's why I'm,
I'm happy to be out in Idaho.
We don't,
we don't necessarily go for the kinder,
gentler world outside.
It's too fucking cold.
And Yeah,
I can call you got coyotes and wolves
and bears and shit that I got to eat you
and uh,
and yeah,
so it,
it's very much just sort of pull your
boots up and just get on with it.
It's a,
it's a very good,
uh,
culture out there and it's a great place
to raise,
raise kids,
you know?
And,
and I couldn't be happier because it's,
the outdoor activities are just
fantastic.
The climbing and the rafting or
incredible skiing is obviously great
fishing and hunting is fantastic.
I mean,
I sound like the Chamber of Commerce,
you know,
you do,
but it is a beautiful place.
Yeah.
I have a friend who has a house in Coeur
d'alene and they send me pictures and
you're just like,
Jesus Christ.
That's real.
That's a real place.
You can fly up to spokane and that's the
easiest way to get to quote Atlanta.
Yeah.
You drive beds.
It's about 40 minutes or so.
That's it from spokane.
But if you drive from,
if you fly into boise and you drive up
to core Delaney to take you about a
century and a half,
it takes a while cause it's got to big
fucking state.
Yeah.
But it's a,
it's uh,
again,
it's,
it's interesting because that Wyoming
and Montana,
that whole part of the country or the,
yeah,
it's just still a little bit different.
You know,
the urban centers are all starting to
kind of unify it and become a little bit
similar.
But I think when people,
we'll have to deal with nature when
they're dealing with winter and storms
and,
and just the reality of being in nature.
It humbles you.
And it also hardens you a little bit to
the realities of changing climates and
the realities of just wild life and all
the dangers and all the wonderful things
that come from nature
and,
and that's it.
And the expansiveness of it.
And it kind of humbles you a little bit
and you can you drive up what got we,
we're not,
we're very fortunate.
We're not that far from yellowstone.
I mean not far being,
you know,
a handful of hours drive and you go off
to a place and if people haven't,
their listening haven't been to
yellowstone,
good guide.
You know,
do yourself a favor and go there.
Don't go during a high tourist season.
But if you want to see something that
just is stunning,
spend a few days up in yellowstone and
it really does,
it puts you back a little bit and it
makes you realize a how,
how amazing,
you know,
this,
this planet is b,
how incredible this country is.
And it,
and it also kind of puts your priorities
a little bit more in shape.
We try,
we attract a bunch of grizzlies up there
for a travel channel show.
And there were times when you just,
you'd forget what you were doing.
You just stand there and just stare out
there at the,
at the scenery and you just,
you know,
there was,
and of course it was a travel channel
show.
I was supposed to be co hosting and,
and yet I was just gobsmacked.
I didn't have the,
you know,
which is not good for a cohost.
Apparently you're supposed to be able to
describe what you're seeing.
And I would just say,
man,
this is fucking incredible.
They say,
okay,
you can't say that and say that I
allowed to travel journal and beep.
But yeah,
you would think so.
I don't think they wanted,
you didn't want that impression.
Um,
so,
but yeah,
getting,
just getting out,
seeing,
seeing that environment,
seeing the wild bison and buffalo and
wolves and all the,
just the,
the landscape
and you learn also where your food comes
from.
Right.
And I think that's part of it too.
And that,
that tough,
it's like my kids,
you know,
they know where their food comes from.
They know,
you know what it takes to go out
hunting.
They know what,
what fishing's all about.
They understand it.
You develop a respect for it.
You understand that the world's not
equal,
you know,
I mean,
all those precious uh,
animals out,
those bison are going to get a baby
bison.
I watched the baby buys and get dragged
down and you think,
you know,
and I was with somebody who was on the,
on the production team that was like,
well we should enter,
we should,
you know,
get in there and help that.
What does it getting dragged down by
getting dragged down by walls and it
wasn't,
you guys were there while this was how
they've actually yellowstone's did a
wonderful job of bringing back a number
of things and there it says a fairly
active wolf population up there.
The bears are looking great,
the grizzlies and everything and says,
but the point being is that,
you know,
if you grow up out there I think,
or if you spend a lot of time out there,
you want to stand that yet life isn't,
isn't fair.
Right.
And if we just keep telling our kids
that life is fair and everybody gets to
be equal and it's not the way it works.
And even in the human species,
it's not the way it works.
Like you said,
somebody is always going to be harder,
tougher,
smarter,
more intense.
And that's a good thing.
Well it does.
It is.
Here's the thing though,
it doesn't make you less of a person.
It doesn't make you love the less,
and I think people value there.
There's a,
there's a real problem when people think
that winning is the only thing,
cause this is not the only thing,
but there's a,
there's a giant spectrum of things that
we value.
We value comradery,
we value friendship.
We value intelligence in a sense of
humor.
And someone who's interesting and
fascinating to talk to.
Well,
there's so many things that people value
out of a human being that being the best
at one thing that you compete in is not
the only thing in life.
And this is a real problem with athletes
once they retire because all of their
sense of self worth a lot of times is
wrapped up in competition and they have
been obsessed with greatness and then
afterwards they feel this like hollow,
sad life.
It's a big issue with fighters.
A gigantic issue with fighters
[inaudible] fine.
Something that that takes that over
right?
A lot of times they turned to drugs
because the,
the high of competing is so intense.
Like so many classic situations were
great fighters turned to drugs.
Joe Lewis,
um,
Sonny Liston,
I mean there's,
you can go down the line,
Aaron,
prior,
there's a lot of great fighters who
turned to drugs later in their life
because they just didn't know what the
fuck to do.
Right,
right.
You're always looking for something
that's going to fill that void,
I think.
And then one of my brothers is a flew f
four is in Vietnam,
uh,
for a couple of tours.
And,
and he was one of those guys,
he was like,
that was it guy's name,
Robert Duval's character and apocalypse
now.
Just one of those guys that,
you know,
he appreciated the moment.
Right.
And he appreciated the rush that he was
getting smell flying home in the
morning.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
and so,
you know,
and by the point being is that,
he came back and it was like,
you know,
now,
I mean,
he's a great guy.
He ended up being a senior pilot of the
commercial airline and he's never had an
issue.
But at the same time,
you can always tell that when you sit
down and you know,
over over some drinks,
you know,
there's always that that was,
that moment in time,
you know,
that was that event or that was that
activity that I don't know what you ever
fill that again.
You don't ever get to that point again
where it's you're,
you're experiencing that same sort of
rush or that,
that,
uh,
that challenge when you get addicted to
hitting 11 when everybody else is
hitting six on a good day,
a crazy day.
Today I got up to six,
you know,
imagine if your truck with Dell,
he's like,
oh,
what did you do today?
You did a fucking mile.
You ran a mile.
You fuck.
You know,
it's like the,
the idea of danger and reward of
consequence.
These are,
these are all there so intense to
someone who's been involved in like
really heavy competition.
I see with fighters all the time,
this very reluctant decision that they
have,
they're very reluctant to step away from
the game when they've been knocked out a
bunch of times and they start to lose
their chin and they start to experience
some cognitive issues and it's so hard
for them and they need someone to step
in and grab them and go,
listen to me,
man,
if you don't get out now,
it's going to get real ugly in the next
couple of years.
And you could,
you could reach a point where you're
never going to bounce back.
You get a few more knockouts,
three,
four more knockouts and you might be
fucked for the rest of your life.
And we see it now with a lot of NFL
players.
We,
we've definitely seen it with a lot of
fighters.
I mean,
Jesus,
look at the greatest of all time,
the greatest boxer of all time is a
physical wreck.
Mohammed Ali is in the worst shape of
like literally any public figure that
has ever been so graceful and beautiful
and as Moose Mints and the weight talked
and so charismatic and now you look at
him and he cannot talk at all.
He cannot walk.
That is a direct consequence of boxing.
Like you said,
look at the NFL and look at what they're
finding now.
And that's,
you know,
that that's filtered down to the youth.
You know,
you don't have a full contact football
at an early age.
That's a good move.
It's a good move.
Yeah.
A lot of parents are just refusing to
have their kid play,
play football.
Well,
I have friends that you know,
they,
they'll,
they would let their kids fight,
they'll let their kids fight,
but they won't let the kids get involved
in,
in football because they're like,
look,
if you fight and you get
really good,
it's you and one guy and you might get
hit and you're probably going to get
hit.
But if you do your diligence and you
work on your technique and you
understand footwork and you understand
the rules of engagement and you
understand like correct strategy as far
as movement and do all your work in the
gym and understand how to defense number
one,
that's the number one most important
thing.
If you do that,
you're going to mitigate a lot of that
issue.
You're going to the,
there's a lot of fighters that walk away
from the game and they're okay.
It is possible to do look at Floyd
Mayweather.
Yeah.
Fucking guys 49 and,
oh and he's fine.
You might not like them but Shitty,
right?
He doesn't get hit.
I mean the difference between him and a
guy who decides to bite down on his
mouthpiece and just slug it out and to
see whose last man standing.
There's a giant difference in his
strategy and the consequences of his
strategy versus a guy who just likes to
put on a show for the fans.
Well that guy is going to be in a
fucking wheelchair when he's older.
Yeah.
But I just,
the other day I had to deal with the was
sluggo the middle boy who said,
you know you want him cause he's been a
Johnson to play football.
And so then he found out that the only
league available was flag football and
he looked at me,
he's not that he's what?
He's almost seven.
And he says,
well what's the point that was,
that was his comments.
What's the point?
I said,
well honey,
I don't know what the point is.
Yeah,
you raised an interesting question.
I said,
so let's,
let's just focus on on other sports,
get them involved in Jujitsu.
That's what I always tell someone who's
gonna,
who's got it
kid and they want to get their kid in
martial arts.
I got involved in martial arts at an
early age,
but I got involved in striking,
but it was because there was no Jujitsu
when I was a kid.
But if I,
if I had a child that was interested in
competing,
I would get them involved in Jujitsu
because you might get your arm broken,
but guess what?
The fucking put you in a cast.
He'll heal up.
You learn to tap.
Next time you know you'll,
you'll,
you'll get John Broken falling out of a
tree.
When did you start?
How old were you when you started?
I got sick.
Well,
I started my first,
I took karate when I was 14 but I really
got serious when I was 15 I took it a
little Kung Fu when I was younger than
that,
but I didn't get serious until I was a
soft my right before,
like from the summer of my right before
when freshmen to sophomore,
so forth.
There's something team during that time.
Was there some reason why you got
interested or why?
I've been interested because I was small
and I didn't want to get picked on.
There was definitely that.
But the big thing was,
it was just straight luck.
I was a baseball fan and went to a red
sox game at Fenway Park.
I was walking home and I was,
so I was walking home,
me and a buddy of mine,
we're going to the,
you know the,
the t,
the public transport,
there's a dry line cause it was the
baseball game we could let out.
So we were walked by this taekwondo
school and I walked upstairs and it was
as long staircase up to the Jay Hahn Kim
Taekwondo Institute.
And as I was walking up,
just by luck,
there's a guy named John Lee who was the
national taekwondo champion,
national light heavyweight champion.
And he was training for the World Cup
and he was in just peak for the World
Cup.
And I,
as I got up to the top of stairs,
this,
I heard this sound,
this lump,
and then there's like chink,
like these chains,
like chains,
like shake womp,
Chink.
And I was like,
what the fuck is that sound?
And as I got to the top of the stairs,
there was this era you had to take off
your shoes and you had to walk in.
You could watch these guys train.
And John Lee was kicking the bag and he
was doing this spinning back kick on the
bag and bending this 100 pound bag in
half and sending it flying.
And I remember thinking,
I got to learn to do that.
I couldn't believe anybody could hit
anybody that hard.
I'd never seen anything like that in my
life.
Did jump,
did the guy that you were with the buddy
that you were with,
did he go up there too?
And he quit?
He started for a little,
but he,
he was a buddy of mine,
still a buddy of mine actually.
We're still friends.
Um,
W we watched it together and uh,
I became obsessed.
I joined right away.
Interesting.
I joined right away that that guy,
because that Guy John lead became like
a,
a big influence on me.
He taught me a lot.
He was living in Boston.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And uh,
he wound up having,
um,
a lot of drug problems himself.
Um,
it was crazy to watch as well,
but that guy taught me,
he took me under his wing.
It was crazy.
You know,
just a total random turn of events.
Me Walking up those stairs at the exact
right time that that guy was there.
I mean,
who knows,
I could have walked up the stairs.
It could have been a children's class.
Right,
exactly.
Exactly.
The up there and the baddest
motherfucker in the country was killing
this bag test.
It was just perfect timing.
Yeah.
And it life's a lot like that.
I mean,
you know,
there's this shift that happens and you
think,
wow,
that's,
you know,
whether it's happenstance,
coincidence,
or it's supposed to be that way,
who knows?
But,
uh,
yeah,
I don't know why
you could add all this meaning to it and
you might be right.
Or you might,
might just be guessing.
But to me it was a,
a gigantic moment and decision in my
life to go up those stairs and to see
that guy doing that changed my whole
life because that became my life.
And from 15 to 21 that's what I did
every day in my life.
I mean,
I trained every day
and that's what you got to find.
You're gonna find whatever's going to
spark it.
You see parents do that all the time
with their kids.
So,
you know,
I want him a kid to be a baseball player
and they just push and push and push.
Instead of saying,
look,
I want,
I want to expose these kids to various
things and see if they spark the find
themselves,
find the thing.
And because it's got to be part of,
it's got to be internal.
You can't,
I mean,
you can for a period of time and then,
then you know,
that's it.
It's not,
it's only gonna go so far.
But if you could find that thing like
you did,
but that sparks something and the kid
realizes,
you know,
I could become really good at this and
we're in.
I enjoy it and it sets me apart.
It makes me different.
It makes me special.
And God bless,
you know,
if you can,
if you can do that with your kids,
you're halfway home.
I didn't even know if I could be good at
it because I didn't have any talent.
I mean it wasn't like I walked up there
and all of a sudden I was the right,
you know,
I walked up there,
I was like,
Holy Shit.
I was surrounded by black belts who were
kicking people's heads off and I was
like,
this is insane.
It was just,
to me it was,
it was so terrifying,
but it was also in a good way.
It was very much like a cult because it
was in a good way.
Like they didn't take advantage of you,
but you had to bow.
You had to say yes sir.
There was some intense discipline and
you got to see some intense consequences
to fucking up.
Cause I got to see a lot of guys get
knocked out.
You know,
I,
I saw a lot of guys get knocked out and
tournaments and start guys getting
knocked out in practice and there was
also the belt system.
The belt system,
I think in martial arts is very
important for kids because like you
started out as a white belt and you get
that blue belt like you tie,
like here's a perfect example,
Anthony Bourdain's 58 fucking years old.
He just got his blue belt and he told me
it was the happiest he's ever been in
his life.
More,
more important than anything other than
the birth of his child.
It was like,
to him it was like,
I fucking did it.
And here's a guy who like used to be a
heroin addict,
smoked cigarettes,
just drinking all the time,
was at a terrible lifestyle.
His wife who's obsessed with Jujitsu got
him to take a Jujitsu class and then all
of a sudden for whatever reason that
switch goes,
I look at them,
they're very,
he is getting his blue belt.
And for people who don't understand that
is a very difficult to accomplishment.
To get your Booba is not easy to do.
It's very hard to do.
And that if you can get your blue belt
and he's like,
I'll never get my black belt.
I'm like,
bullshit.
Listen to me,
man.
If you can get your fucking blue belt,
you can get your black belt.
It just keep going.
Yeah.
But it said,
it said,
like you said for kids,
it's that success,
which runs counter to sort of the
concept of team sports right now anyway.
Right.
Kids.
So you give them that opportunity.
And uh,
I've got again,
the middle boy who's,
who's,
uh,
you know,
six and right now he's,
he's that kid who likes to know what,
what the,
uh,
what the parameters are and likes to
know that there's a system in place.
Right.
So he's the kid have all been,
he's very aggressive too,
is,
he's very physical kid.
So that's,
we've been looking at what's out there
and where we live to see where would be
a good spot for him.
But,
but he's definitely the kid of the three
that he looks at that and he goes,
I get it.
I can go from here to here to here to
here,
and that's a good thing.
Well,
if you want to get them in more involved
in martial arts,
we'll talk afterwards and I'll find out
what,
what's near you.
That would be good.
That would find out what's good.
But I can't recommend that enough for
kids,
for young boys,
especially because it takes away this
fear of engaging with other kids.
It takes her with his fear of getting
your ass kicked,
a fear of the unknown.
If you don't know how to fight,
you wind up getting involved in fights
accidentally because your posture,
you stick your fucking chest up and you
don't know the consequences are so alien
to you that you,
you wind up talking too loud or trying
to bluff someone and you can fuck up and
run into the wrong dude.
It in a way,
it's like a,
it's like a concealed carry permits.
If you don't know what the hell you're
doing and if you don't have the
discipline and if you're not constantly
training.
Yeah,
there's,
there's a serious potential for fuck up.
What's a serious potential for fuckup
and that's my own issue.
My personal issue with all these fucking
states that are,
that are there open carry states.
Yeah.
Well you don't even have to have any
training.
Like I think it's kind of crazy.
I think first of all,
I'm a big sport is second amendment.
I have guns so let me get that out of
the way.
But I think you should learn how to
fucking use a gun before you should get
one.
Yeah.
How can you,
how come I can get a car?
I have to go through all this shit.
I have to learn how to drive.
I have to fill out forms.
I have to learn the rules.
I can just go get a gun.
Yeah.
All you do is just not be a criminal and
you can get a gun.
That seems crazy to me.
The training aspect of it.
Is it anybody who's serious about,
about weapons?
Anybody who's,
who's dealt with them,
anybody who's had to carry them for,
for a livelihood,
you gained a real appreciation for how
quickly things had south and,
and,
and the idea that I agree with you on a
percent.
Uh,
and I'm a huge supporter of the second
amendment.
Um,
and,
uh,
I got,
you know,
they go walk in safe and happy to have
it,
but at the same time,
if I just can't get behind the idea of
people going out and,
and not training,
not practicing.
And that's a large,
not a large,
but I,
and I,
you know what I'm about to speculate,
so I probably shouldn't,
but there's a,
there's a decent percentage of people
who go out and they buy it and then they
put it in a lockbox.
Hopefully they put it in a lockbox and
then that's it,
you know,
and then they,
maybe sometime they're gonna need it and
they don't know what the fuck they're
doing.
So it's the,
it's the training and you just have to
be constant repetition,
constant repetition.
Cause if you do need to use it,
everything else shuts down.
And you know,
haul your little,
you know,
controls go away and you're,
you're depending on your big muscle mass
and,
and repetition and muscle memory.
And if you haven't been practicing,
you're fucked.
You might,
you might as well turn it on yourself.
And that's the same thing with fighting.
It's the same thing with everything.
When you're,
when you're nervous,
all the training comes out and that's
what you're going to fall back on your
training.
If you train incorrectly,
you're going to perform incorrectly
under pressure.
And that's the same with firearms is
same with everything.
Yeah.
If you don't prepare the,
but see we have this country where
everybody's like,
you tried to take well goons,
which will do well.
No one's trying to take away your guns,
but I think it should.
The idea of firearms owning a firearm
being a right,
I think it should be a privilege.
And I think much like driving a car is a
privilege.
I don't think you should keep anyone
from doing it just arbitrarily,
but I think you should prove that.
You know what the fuck you're doing
before you put other people in danger.
That's what we have with cars by the
way.
It's speedboats too.
Yeah.
We got not a lake.
He gets up
gasol who's never gotten behind the
wheel of a boat before and all of a
sudden he's doing 30 down the lake and
you think,
what the fuck?
Some rich dick head of buys a fucking
one of those cigarette.
Yeah,
exactly.
You ever seen those videos of those
cigarette butts that go a hundred miles
an hour?
People flip 'em up in the air and
everybody dies.
Yeah,
I like it.
Like A,
like a fountain boat.
You know,
those things are insane and yeah,
you'll get some,
you know,
get somebody or buy one and then they'll
show up on the lake.
Next thing you know,
you know your kids out water skiing and
you're,
you know,
fearing for their life because,
yeah.
But so point taken,
I think,
you know,
uh,
I don't know how you would tie in the,
the purchase with the training with the,
uh,
showing approving,
the ability.
Uh,
I don't know how you'd do that,
but it's extremely difficult.
Yeah.
Psychological evaluation as the bad idea
either.
I don't think it's a bad idea to ask
people a bunch of questions,
you know what I mean?
Just try to get someone who's a
qualified individual to,
uh,
talk to this person.
I mean,
you're not going to,
you're going to have some fucking
psychopathic going to be able to trick
you,
but that's just,
you're going to weed out some folks that
could be a problem and people have a
problem with that.
Well,
you're trying to take where it guns.
One of these liberals get involved in
this process and they say,
no one's qualified.
That's what they want.
Don't you understand?
Don't you worry
burry slope.
It's a slippery slope.
Do one thing and it's all gonna fall to
hell.
Yeah.
No,
I,
it,
that's a hipaa issue.
How do you,
as Addie is,
share medical information?
How of you share is share information
from a [inaudible] office and,
um,
I,
you know,
it's,
again,
never had medical attention.
Yeah.
It's definitely like a nuts out there
that haven't had anybody look at them.
Right?
No,
I haven't.
You know,
one of the other things,
I've never woken up in the morning and
thought to myself,
good God,
I gotta get myself another 45 or I've
got to get myself in another ar 15.
I gotta have it now.
I,
I have no problems with waiting and I've
got teams in my company that do nothing
but,
but due diligence on people,
right?
And No,
it's not,
not for purposes of,
of a weapons permit,
but um,
I know how difficult that process is
even for relatively straightforward due
diligence.
And so the idea that I have no problems
with expanded background checks and I
noticed that a lot of people,
you know,
right now a screaming and saying,
oh my God,
the drug,
and again,
I'm a huge supporter of the,
of the Second Amendment,
NRA member,
all the rest of that shit.
And I,
and I and I,
God bless it.
But at the same time,
we have to be able to,
uh,
find those,
those,
those ideas,
those answers or at least talk about
them without immediately started to pull
the pins on the grenades and thrown in
each other.
And that's,
you know,
going back to the earlier conversation
about politics and the yachts and so,
you know,
it probably no other,
well there's other emotive issues,
but certainly with the second amendment,
you know,
the idea that you're going to spend a
little bit more time on a background
check,
you know,
if you got to rush into the store and
buy your,
your,
your handgun and get out of there as
quick as possible.
What's up?
I mean,
just take,
yeah,
you can take a little time.
Um,
so otherwise to kill yourself.
Yeah.
So I dunno.
It's um,
but again,
nobody,
nobody exists in the center anymore.
Nobody exists in the middle.
So.
Exactly.
Even if guy who supports a second
amendment saying something like that
could be problematic and you're going to
get criticized.
Oh my God,
if I run for governor out in Idaho,
I'm sure someone's
going to pull that one up.
Did you see what he said?
And you're thinking,
how is that a problem?
Yeah.
I just don't understand how anybody
could be against background checks.
Right.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
How could someone be against training?
How could somebody be against firearm
education?
How could somebody be against that?
Yeah.
Well when you,
when you get a hunting license,
you have to go through a hunter's safety
course.
And the hunter safety course is pretty
extensive.
It takes a long time.
There's a lot of questions you have to
answer.
You have to know why the fuck is that
the case with hunting,
but it's not the case with a gun.
Yeah.
What about self defense?
So it shouldn't,
you have to have all these junior have
to have an understanding of how to use a
safety.
Shouldn't yet have the variations in
training for uh,
or classroom work for concealed carry
permits.
You know,
you got,
you got great training programs and then
you got less than,
less than great.
Significantly less than.
Great.
And you're talking about carrying a
weapon out in public.
And that is an enormous responsibility.
And,
and I think it's important,
you know,
and,
and I think it's,
it's just,
it falls in line with what we're talking
about.
How do you have,
but how do you get to that point if as
soon as you raise that issue again,
people start throwing hand grenades
agile and you'd think,
well,
wait a minute,
I'm just,
I'm raising this as a possibility.
Maybe there's something,
some other tact here that we can take
and not,
you know,
not just the second amendment,
every,
every fucking thing out there,
right.
Uh,
Obamacare,
I'll let you know.
I,
you know,
it's,
it's either all this or all that.
Instead of saying it the early outset,
we,
you know,
what would have been wrong with saying,
hey,
you know,
let,
let's,
let's do preexisting conditions.
Let's keep kids on their health plans
for their parents a little bit longer.
And then let's try to figure out where
else we can make improvements.
But it's all one thing or the other.
I think one of the things about owning a
gun,
and this is,
it's very important to anybody that has
a gun.
You should want to be educated in proper
firearm safety.
If you have a gun,
you should want this.
So training shouldn't be something that
you would fight.
It should be something that everybody
would embrace.
If you have a gun,
you understand the dangers and the
consequences of having a gun.
You also understand that you need
someone to show you how to do it right.
If you don't have anybody who puts it in
your head,
you know,
always have your finger off the trigger.
This is the safety.
No it no it when it's pushed back,
you know,
you're,
you're here.
When it's pushed forward,
you're ready to rock.
Like no,
these things understand these things.
Well I think it's,
it's,
um,
yeah,
if you live out west and not,
again,
not dead,
dead.
I mean cause down south you could argue
to say anything,
mountain culture and everything else,
but there's a certain appreciation for
both the use of weapons and the
responsibility involved because there
are so many people out there that a hunt
and there are so many.
I mean,
I the,
you know,
I,
I would suspect that,
uh,
I mean everybody I know that that owns a
weapon,
uh,
goes to the range they,
or they're out practicing their target
hunting
and you know,
before hunting season,
Shari shows up there.
They're working the problem.
Uh,
I don't know that that's true in,
in a major urban centers.
I don't know.
I mean,
I have no idea,
but,
um,
there's a few people,
I mean,
there's ranges that you can go to where,
you know,
I mean,
you can take firearms lessons.
The thing is that it's not mandatory.
And then there's also the variants,
the different rules that you have in
different states.
Like Arizona is an open carry state.
Right?
Right.
So you just go to the store,
you're not a felon,
you get a gun,
just walk around with a gun.
Yeah.
You have it.
Got It.
Yep.
Okay.
You don't have to know shit.
And it causes problems.
I mean,
depending on who you're talking to in
law enforcement,
it's,
you know,
there's,
there's a lot of folks in law
enforcement,
they look at it and go,
yeah,
I mean,
it's not,
it's not what they would prefer.
It's not up to them to,
to make that call.
But at the same time,
I,
you know,
I look at it and then I think if,
if there's one issue that probably
summarizes,
um,
the,
the sort of,
the emotive nature of,
of politics nowadays,
it's probably,
it's probably this one.
I mean,
I think that's a big,
we've gotten past the whole gay marriage
thing and you know,
the abortion thing always flares up and
always will probably,
but,
but the,
the second amendment,
you know,
and so you do think,
okay,
well how do we can set the default
position for the administration is
always,
you know,
um,
it's always,
you know,
blowing it up.
Right?
And so,
you know,
they misplayed as well.
I think if there was more compromised,
more discussion in the center where they
had this quietly outside of the,
you know,
the,
the realm of media,
but they just seem to be unable to do
it.
So every time there's an incident,
the first thing you see is somebody from
the administration up behind the podium,
you know,
making statements and talking about gun
control.
And that fuels the other side that fuels
the right where the side with thinks
they're just trying to take away all our
weapons.
And because they see this and there's
nothing reason to going on
right here.
There's no reasonable consideration of
the pros and cons of this issue.
And no one's,
there's no one's stepping in the middle,
right?
It's like the FBI and apple dispute.
That's what it's like.
It's not the same thing.
You got it all on one side.
You've got all on the other.
And the reality is,
you know what,
we could have found a solution here
somewhere if,
uh,
you know,
if,
if we'd been at,
and I,
although who knows,
I don't know.
Apple seems to be inclined to draw a
line under this particular,
she was there trying to get into that
guy's phone.
The killer who killed those people in
San Bernardino.
They want to get into his phone and uh,
they,
FBI wants apple to engineer some sort of
a back door.
Well,
here's,
here's what it is.
So this guy,
uh,
side for had,
he had,
uh,
three phones,
at least that we know about two of them,
he destroyed,
he completely destroyed him.
And,
and the,
the bureau has been looking,
they take nothing recoverable off those
systems and they've asked a lot of
people for assistance.
So they had the other phone,
which was in his truck,
which is his work phone.
It was belonged to the county.
And so they went to the county bureau,
did they went to the county,
uh,
when they pulled this phone out of the
truck and they said,
we need to get the information off of
this thing because you know what,
a phone,
a phone nowadays everybody keeps
everything on their phone.
Right.
And so they,
uh,
they got the support they pulled and
they found out that he had shut off the
function that a uploads data to the
cloud,
uh,
in October.
And so they were able to get everything
up to October,
but then that's two full months prior to
the attack.
So they said,
okay,
well we can't get this.
And the,
and the,
the,
the phone has,
you know,
this default position where if you try
the password 10 times and it erases
everything.
So they took the phone,
the bureau took the f,
the phone to apple and this was well
before they had to go get a court order.
Well before it became public knowledge.
They actually went and had numerous
quiet conversations with apple and they
went to apple and they said,
literally said,
you can take the phone,
keep it on your campus,
keeping in your facility,
put it in a,
we don't,
you know,
wherever put it in your lap.
All we're asking is for you to create a
systems information file that you can
force on that phone,
that one phone and pull the tech,
which then allows you to brute force the
password and get the texts off of there,
get the data off of there and exists and
then you can destroy the sif,
the systems information file.
You can keep the phone.
We don't even need to touch it.
We can,
you know,
whatever you just give us the shit
that's on the phone.
An apple has has been helpful in the
past.
They've been,
they've been helpful in the past and
this time for some,
for whatever motivation they've decided
to draw a line in the sand and say,
no,
we're not going to do this.
And it's not as if they haven't been
helpful.
And there's an ongoing dialogue.
And so it's,
it's disingenuous to say that apple is
now,
you know,
uh,
the bulwark for privacy because they
have been helpful in the past and they
will continue to be helpful,
I suppose in their own way.
But for this particular phone,
for this one time where they could have
held onto the phone,
created that Sif destroyed the sif at,
at that moment that they've pulled the
texts off.
So that's it.
That's done.
So now what Tim Cook is saying is not
that it's creating a back door.
He's not saying that he's saying it
creates a precedent,
but the precedent was already that if
the bureau goes through the,
the,
the process the congress has set and
then goes through that process and gets
a court order and the court,
then it looks at it and says,
yes,
you've got probable cause you've got
reasonable concern here.
Uh,
they provide a court order,
then they go and they make this request
for assistance.
You're also talking about a dead guy
talking about a guy who shot 14 people,
14 people killed,
14 people.
Um,
I've heard all sorts of things.
I've heard people say to me and I,
and again,
I understand,
don't get me wrong,
because I understand fully the
importance of finding the right place on
the pendulum for Security and privacy.
I get that.
And that's an important discussion.
I'm not saying it's not,
it's,
you should always have that
conversation,
but part of that is then during the
course of that conversation,
Congress and the courts,
they make those decisions.
Where does that pendulum,
you know,
settle between security and privacy and
that settles here.
Okay,
fine.
Then that's what the bureau or whomever
has to go through to get approval to get
some assistance and that's where it
stands.
But you know to say that because now
you've got all,
all three branches of government have
said,
yeah,
we think that really we could use this
information off of this phone.
But I've heard everybody say,
well,
why don't they just do the rest of the
investigation?
Well,
of course they fucking done the rest of
the investigation.
They done all the other investigative
steps.
So what are you saying in a situation
like this?
Uh,
you just want them to do 80% of the
investigation.
And if you've got,
you know,
that you've got material on here who,
which may lead to operational activity,
uh,
in,
in finding other people who were
involved or finding people overseas who
were in somehow assisting or whatever it
may be.
If you're saying,
well,
just now,
you know what,
for the sake of this,
we're not asking for a back door.
They're asking for that,
that,
that one phone.
And that's where this whole thing is,
is really headed south and it's become
this idea that,
you know,
which is erroneous.
But I understand what Tim Cook is saying
about the precedent,
although not really,
because again,
they've done this before.
For some reason for this one,
they're drawing a line.
So anyway,
I,
but I've heard that,
why don't they just do the rest of the
investigation and skip this part?
What I don't,
I don't,
I don't follow that logic train.
And then the other people,
other people were saying,
well,
why don't they just get it off the
metadata?
And that's another one of those things
where people never believed what the
government was saying.
But the metro fucking data was numbers
and volume.
That was it.
There was no information to be had
there.
You could sit in a fucking room full of
metadata and not know what the hell
you're looking at.
You had to go through the court process
to then get that particular numbers
information.
So here's my question,
because this is what came up with the
Edward Snowden thing.
They were saying that the government is
monitoring all cell phone data
constantly and they can get information
all the time.
Well,
this kind of proves that not to be true.
Yeah.
But people don't look at it that way.
They don't,
they don't.
They don't make that leap back and say,
oh,
well maybe that was a fallacy.
Yeah,
sure.
The metadata was sweeping up all that,
that those numbers and volume.
But again,
it's not enough to what end.
Yeah.
And so some people would say,
once they realized what it was actually
doing,
then they say,
wow,
but that's so what?
So they're just collecting the shit in
the basement.
It's not doing any good.
So they shouldn't even collect that
information.
So what Edward Snowden was talking about
is essentially just when it pertains to
email,
I mean,
he said they're collecting all this
information that the NSA is collecting
all this information in regards to cell
phone data and the recording.
Every phone call,
the recording,
all these text messages.
Yeah.
Um,
so is that not true?
Well,
no,
I frankly,
I'm here.
Of course nobody's going to,
again,
this is a very emotive,
right?
So there's all these people out there,
they're going to say,
fuck you.
You don't know what the fuck are you
talking about?
Yeah,
no aluminum.
There is nobody right now unless you're
a terrorist,
a terrorist suspect or a criminal.
This,
nobody in the government hooks up.
Fuck you.
I'm here to tell
you your Dick pics or safe ladies and
Gentlemen,
Dick Pics are absolutely Jina pictures
that had been floating around all your
boyfriend.
Okay.
Goes a secure,
nobody's going to route those around
that you would rat you out for those as
a piece of shit and unamerican in the
first place.
Yeah.
So that's a,
that's a really eyeopening thing though,
because this case kind of throws that
all into jeopardy cause everybody was
like concerned.
Like,
Hey,
the government can check in on all your
phone calls and all your text messages.
Well this would clearly be a case where
they would want to do that.
So they don't,
they can't do it here without the,
did the judge granting this order and
what,
so tell me why did,
there was a recent court order right
there ruled in favor of apple.
They did.
And that was in New York.
And that was an interesting case as
well.
And that's probably going to set a
precedent for maybe,
maybe we'll see cause it's a little bit
different what the judge essentially was
saying in that case and it involved,
uh,
narco trafficking investigation that was
going on.
And by the way,
this isn't just for terrorism.
Imagine what if this was for pedophilia?
I mean,
I imagine a large Pete Ophelia ring,
what are you going to say?
No,
we don't want to catch those fucking
Douche bags that are involved in that
because privacy,
you know,
I understand the privacy aspect,
but each case has to be looked at on its
merits and if,
and if you say through the courts and
through the,
through the congress that these are the
hoops that the bureau has to jump
through and they jumped through those
hoops,
then then what?
Then it's up to each company to decide
whether they want to support it or not.
I don't know that,
that seems strange.
But anyway,
the point being is that the one in New
York,
the judge essentially was saying,
well look,
you want us,
you want the courts to make a decision
on this for something that Congress
should really make a decision on this.
And so in a way,
his decision was a pushback against the
concept of that,
that the,
uh,
the bureau was basing this on,
which is a very old law.
And so the judge is saying,
look,
you relying on a law that's a couple of
hundred years old or whatever.
Um,
maybe instead we should be having this
looked at it through the legislature.
And so there was a,
there was an interesting sort of
legality to his,
his response to this,
but it definitely a favorite apple and,
and,
and and sure.
That's great.
Let's legislate it.
But do you think that just maybe,
um,
there are times when from an operational
perspective,
you might want to move a little bit
quicker than asking Congress to take up,
uh,
an issue and debate it and then maybe
eventually come up.
So maybe occasionally you're going to
have moments like this,
the San Bernardino shooting where you've
got a phone in your hand and all you're
asking apple to do is take possession of
it.
And who knows?
Maybe their problem is they're worried
that if they create the sif at that
moment,
someone's going to steal it from them,
one of their employees.
So maybe they've got an internal
security issue because then they can
destroy it.
The bureau's not asking for that phone
back then,
not asking for that Sif.
They're not asking them for to do it on
any other,
what is a sif,
but he says systems,
information flour.
So you just force it onto that phone.
And that bypasses the,
essentially what the court has done is
made a very conservative,
conservative interpretation of
the law.
Right.
And basically saying that this needs to
blame.
This is a place where the courts should
be deciding,
we believe you should be taking this to
Congress.
And so therefore I don't see why you're
legislating or asking us to make a
decision on this.
See,
I understand the common person's
perspective.
They don't trust the government,
the whole Edward Snowden thing.
And the next thing.
Everybody's freaking out about that.
And then they look at this saying,
well,
this is the slippery slope.
Again,
this is the thing that if the government
has access to your phone play,
we're talking about a fucking mass
murderer and a guy who's already dead
and we have one phone.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's,
and,
and so to say that you're going to only
do a limited investigation,
even though you know you've got
potential information and a way to do
it,
like on an individual basis,
just one phone only.
That's what the cover,
that's what they're asking.
But can it be that you could never grant
ag?
I mean it's,
it's,
it doesn't make any sense to me.
Well,
it wouldn't want to get access to that
guy's fucking data.
And here's where,
and I think going back to that
overriding theme,
which is nothing resides in the center
anymore.
Uh,
you're right.
We do have to be concerned about
privacy.
And I agree.
Okay,
what happens if you don't?
Big Brother.
But there are times when,
you know,
operational concerns probably override
at least an element of this where you
have common pr or a reason to,
people can exist in the comment in the
middle and say,
yeah,
on this occasion,
because you've gone through all these,
these orders and because we've set up
this protection now,
meaning,
you know,
apple holds onto it and it,
but you know,
that's not the way it works.
And so therefore apple comes out and
says there and then the misinformation,
oh,
they trying to create a backdoor to all
our apple devices.
By the way,
what do you think apple does with their
devices that they sell in China?
You think that Chinese government would
allow apple if someone got a talk about
this in the media,
do you think the Chinese government
would allow apple to sell devices that
they can't get into?
I,
uh,
we could ask apple,
well,
Ascap,
I'm sure it would be an issue,
but I can speak from a friend that I
have that worked at Google.
They had a gigantic issue in China with
Google because,
you know,
they have android phones.
And that was,
that was a big part of the issue is the
government wanted to have access to
phones.
They also want to have access to what
you're searching.
They wanted to know what people are
searching.
They wanted to limit google searches.
There's this gigantic issue they were
having.
Then on top of that,
Google,
uh,
was having to deal with the fact that
China was kind of ripping off their
system and creating their own version of
it.
And is China,
is these tactics state sponsor of uh,
economic espionage and cyber crime and
shit and counter fay openly support
counterfeit shit to the point where
there's entire stores that have apple
logos,
they sell apple products and none of it
is legit.
All the computers are fake.
All the phones are fake.
All the laptops are fake.
None of it is created by Apple.
It looks exactly like this shit right
here.
And it's just all man,
they don't have laws to stop that.
Now.
There's not a rule of law there.
Even though they'd been to,
they were talking about this for a
while.
They've been saying,
oh,
you know,
it's a new,
and
this is again,
this is why you're going back to that.
You know,
everything goes back in circles.
But the idea that we need a leader right
now that's,
that's reasoned and pragmatic and smart
and you know,
clear eyed is,
is a look at.
You look at China and you look at a look
at their economy and their is is heading
south and if using ping their,
yeah,
their economy's not doing well,
their growth projections are way off.
There's always been this belief that
their numbers have been cooked in
numerous ways.
A G that the head of China has been
consolidating power.
He's been creating new security
apparatus.
He's been hiding behind this
anticorruption drive to some degree,
which is again,
part of is consolidation of power.
Um,
and this idea that Oh,
somehow this rule of law is coming up.
Nobody actually believes that.
And they are continuing to be incredibly
aggressive in economic espionage.
I mean they're not the only ones that
have these,
everybody acts in their own best
interest.
But the,
the Chinese have,
I dunno,
four dozen plus academic institutions
that have funded by the Chinese
military,
the PLA and have a responsibility for
uh,
economic espionage,
developing new,
new new means of basically stealing
shit.
They've got a couple dozen,
at least information warfare units that
we've identified run by the PLA that are
specifically designed to hoover up
intellectual property and research and
development and all the rest of that,
not just from us,
I mean from around the globe.
And you know,
we,
um,
so the idea,
yes,
the idea that that we would do business
there,
uh,
and,
and believe somehow that the,
uh,
the authorities there in China aren't
going to have our shit.
They're not going to have whatever it
may be.
A pharmaceutical company that sets up a
facility out there isn't going to lose
their R.
And.
D of course they are.
Everybody knows anybody in a serious
manner who is doing business out in
China.
Knows as soon as you set foot in there
and you establish yourself,
you know,
manufacturing or just a sales,
whatever it may be,
your information becomes their
information.
It just going to work that way.
So,
well,
that's a problem too because our shit is
made over there.
A lot of Shit's made over there,
including stuff from,
from Donald Trump.
Um,
but who knows,
maybe he's going to bring it back to the
states.
Well,
I have a friend who works for the bureau
and he was explaining to me how Chinese
espionage works in the United States and
how they catch people that a guy will
come over here and live a completely
normal life and won't look like there's
anything going on with him whatsoever.
Family Guy,
no weapons,
no crime,
no nothing.
Be Friends,
someone who works in some sort of an
intellectual capacity,
whether it's for some sort of a
corporation that makes computers or
something that works for the United
States government that the wwe and
rocketry or whatever,
they'd be friend that guy and then
slowly make their way in to the point
where they say,
listen,
I know people that can pay you a lot of
money for some of the information that
you have.
And by the way,
this information is out there anyway.
It wasn't information and it can be much
less.
It oftentimes as much less threatening
than that.
It's just like,
you know,
I,
I need,
you know,
maybe I could,
I could have you consult with me on a
paper that I'm writing for a very
legitimate organization.
I mean,
how do these,
a lot of these folks come over here and
they start going to school and then they
get a grad degree and then they get a
job and then what do they want?
Well,
the Chinese would always want them to
get another job and then they get in.
Eventually they end up at Northrop
Grumman or they end up at Lockheed or
they end up,
but you know,
so it doesn't matter.
Dupont,
Dow,
wherever it is,
information is of interest to them.
The Chinese are a little bit different
than,
than we are.
We,
we tend to be very targeted,
very specific in our tasking and part
because we're a smaller operation than
they are.
They devote a huge amount of resource to
this,
but they just hoover up whatever's out
there.
And then they make a decision as an
interesting or valuable to them or not.
And you know,
again,
people will say,
well,
you know,
you can't be coy about this.
We do that too.
Well,
you better hope we fucking do it because
it's otherwise,
it's a,
uh,
it's a hugely unlevel playing field.
It,
we're sweet angels out in the field of
murders,
criminals,
right?
And we'd,
all we're doing is,
you know,
yeah,
we're all snow precious snowflakes.
I'll just try to get together and not a
not keep score.
This is where Hillary's email problem
becomes a real issue,
right?
Because she,
by doing this and this sort of in a
roundabout way,
we're bringing it all back,
puts it in perspective why it's so
dangerous that she had this unprotected
email because by copy and pasting
classified information or deciding
through her own decision making process
with the people that were with her,
what's,
what's okay to copy and paste and what's
not okay to copy and paste and not
whether or not you go by the established
protocols of top secret or not top
secret clearance or whatever clearance
level you have.
You're handing that over.
And,
and,
and the,
the interesting thing is they don't
necessarily care.
I mean,
obviously they,
you know,
they,
it blows her skirt up to get top secret,
you know,
information,
but they'll take anything,
they'll take it all,
they'll take a,
you know,
the daily,
dribble that goes on through her email
and,
and just to gain a better understanding
as to what makes a person tick or who
are the people around her.
They're looking for potential targets.
And that's,
that's part of it.
You're looking for,
you know,
where is there a chink in the armor
where there's an opportunity to,
uh,
to get in to her organization?
Is there somebody on the periphery could
be a landscaper.
Hey,
I,
now I know who landscapes,
they're great.
You know,
it's like,
it's like you're targeting a company.
Well,
who are you going to target?
You're not going to target the CEO.
You're going to target the cleaning
service.
We're going to target the secretary and
the caterer.
You know,
you're,
and so,
yeah,
I,
and again,
you know,
I get it everybody,
it's like with Ben Gazi,
people roll their eyes all the private
email server era.
But if you've been involved in this and
you understand how aggressive it is out
there,
you know,
and not,
again,
not just the Chinese or Russians that,
you know,
everybody's,
everybody's added.
Um,
that,
you know,
we,
we need to understand that it was,
it's,
it was,
uh,
it was a serious problem.
It was a breach.
And,
and,
and again,
going back to the same thing,
if it had been me,
yeah,
sure I would have been done up and all,
if it had been somebody else,
they would be backed up and probably
done time.
So it's a little,
it's a little discouraging.
That's kind of that it is something that
someone would go to jail for and yet
mishandling classified information.
Yeah.
I mean,
you can't series of facts.
It's a very serious offense and it,
and in particular,
when you're,
when you're a senior official,
yeah,
good God.
You know,
she's a very smart person and she
shouldn't,
you know,
so this idea that somehow she just
didn't know or,
you know,
she was,
I was too busy or I don't know how by
blackberry works or whatever.
What a load of crap.
Anyway.
Yeah.
Well this whole,
this brings us back to this whole Edward
Snowden thing.
What,
what is,
what's your position on this and that
guy and what he did and sort of exposing
the fact that the NSA was involved in
this wide scale,
this gigantic sort of information
gathering process,
the hoovering up of,
of a metadata program.
It's gathered me this stuff up.
Well,
first of all,
again,
I think,
you know,
everybody should have spent more time
understanding what the actual technical
aspects of it work because he gets it
though was problematic.
He was saying the people that worked
with him were accessing the emails of ex
girlfriends and they were,
you know,
there were,
do I buying on,
maybe that might've happened.
Well,
yeah,
it's a human system.
So yeah,
there's gonna be some fuck ups.
There's no doubt about it.
So he has a problem.
Well,
I mean,
I don't know what the INS and outs of a
NSA are,
you know,
in terms of their protocols for,
uh,
protection firewalls on,
on systems at,
uh,
you know,
it at government agencies tend to be,
if they're used properly,
are pretty robust.
But at the same time,
you know,
any human system,
it's like,
it's like Tsa is someone going to be
asleep at the wheel and somebody gets
through with a shoe bomb?
Well,
it could happen because the human
system,
but where do I stand on it?
And no surprise.
And you know,
um,
again,
it's all based on what your experiences
are.
And I'd get the fact that people
consider him a hero or a whistle or
whatever they want to call it.
Um,
you know,
he's signed paperwork that said he was
going to protect national security
interests,
that he was going to properly protect
the information that he was given
responsibility for seeing.
And he didn't,
he didn't do that.
And he also,
despite what people may want to believe,
um,
he caused a lot of damage.
It's a tremendous amount of damage in
terms of information that was released
about the way that we do things here.
Uh,
sources and methods that were of extreme
interest to not just a terrorist
organization,
but extreme interest to Russian
interests,
extreme interest to Iranians.
And it's weird that he's in Russia right
now.
Yeah,
I know.
Go figure.
Huh?
Uh,
yeah.
so did he do any good?
I don't know.
Did he do any good?
Well,
you know,
having that conversation is always good,
but we can have that conversation
without him doing what he did and um,
and,
and we should,
in part of that responsibility lays on
a,
on a,
on an aggressive and inquisitive.
I'm constantly aware,
um,
checks and balances that exist within
government,
so the Intel Committee and then that
would send it in until committee and,
and all these people that need,
they tend to play a game in Washington.
They know what the fuck's going on.
Like with the interrogation or rendition
program,
these people were briefed,
they knew what the hell goes on.
But there's a political game in
Washington where they,
they get to express outrage when
something becomes a political football
of course.
So,
um,
but yeah,
so I did he do any good?
Hey,
we're talking about it and that's
important.
I,
again,
I keep going back to that.
I'm not,
um,
I'm not an,
what's the word?
I'm not unsympathetic.
Doesn't sound right.
I understand.
I appreciate the importance of finding
the proper place on the pendulum,
but I have probably an overriding
appreciation for security because of
what I did.
And I understand that other people have
an overriding appreciation for privacy
because they didn't have the same
experiences that they've had,
different experiences.
And so that's great.
I appreciate that.
And all I'm saying is I look at it from,
from my perspective,
uh,
I don't look at him as a hero
whistleblower in any way.
Um,
I,
you know,
I signed same agreements and,
uh,
I'm expected to live up to those just
like anybody else who does.
He didn't,
he found a way that he thought was
appropriate to make his point.
I don't have no idea what goes on in his
head.
Um,
I w I just would've thought it would've
been nice if,
if,
uh,
I dunno,
we've made the point in a way that also
protected our national security
just a little bit better.
How could that be done though?
Well,
without exposing what he,
what exactly did he expose?
He exposed the fact that they were
gathering up metadata and that,
but there's been people that have said
that it was more than metadata.
Well,
there's eight.
It talks about,
you know,
surveillance programs and here's his,
his,
you know,
there's lots,
there were lots of little bits and
pieces because he,
he,
uh,
he misappropriated,
he stole a lot of,
a lot of information.
That was then essentially,
if anybody thinks that,
that Edward Snowden was smarter than the
Chinese authorities or the Russians and
that they didn't get a hold of
everything and that somehow he just
secreted that information with Glenn
Greenwald and a couple others are those
who have interests that are completely
against ours,
didn't get ahold of that information is,
it's a pretty naive thought last time.
I don't believe that Edward Snowden is
smarter than the PLA and the resources
of the FSB and Russia.
I just,
maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe he's like the lex luther of it.
I don't think so.
But uh,
as an example is the surveillance
programs supposedly that we had against
a European leaders.
Remember the outreach with Angela Merkel
and the fact that,
you know,
we're listening in on some of her
conversations,
the ones that we would have access to,
uh,
oh my God,
really,
because you know what they're doing.
They're listening in on the
conversations of their allies and the,
I mean the French,
the former head of the dgse,
the French Intel service turned to the
head of France at one point when the
head of France was secretary blue and
seek the Lord and how could we be doing
this?
And the former head of the Intel service
looked at them French guy and said,
are you fucking kidding me?
What do you think we do?
This is what we do.
So this is just always what he's
exposing is something that everybody
knew.
So the mock outrage,
you're saying it's like
walk out.
It was,
it was Kabuki theater in Europe for
sure.
I mean all they asked mostly theater.
Yeah.
I mean they,
the hand wringing and all the,
all the,
Oh,
I can't believe that they are Americans
would be allies would be doing this.
So they kind of assumed that everybody
was doing it already.
I guarantee you what was going on in the
back rooms was the Intel service
directors were all,
you know,
sitting down.
And I would hope to think that our,
our director was looking at them and
saying,
what the fuck?
You know?
And they were probably having a,
you know,
having a drink and saying,
yeah,
okay,
we get it.
We get to joke,
you know,
everybody's doing this.
And so the idea that somehow we're the
bad guy,
uh,
look to French Intel services,
incredibly aggressive as an example.
And there had been numerous cases where
they've targeted a u s corporations for
economic espionage.
And the idea that somehow,
you know,
people should be shocked that one nation
is,
is acting in its own self interest in
listening to other nations.
Again,
same theory with economic espionage.
We better hope we're playing offense and
defense in the way the world actually
works.
It'd be great if we all held hands and
whinging monkeys on Unicorns.
Fluid are acids and we could all sing
songs together,
but it's not how the world works.
So we,
you know,
anyway,
so that's me disappearing down a rabbit
hole.
But,
but this rabbit holes kind of important
to talk about because you actually have
some pretty deep knowledge about this
rabbit hole and this is some of the
things that get speculated left and
right and back and forth.
And either you'd take one side or the
other and everybody argues about it.
I mean,
no one wants to government to have
unchecked access to your emails,
your phone that,
yeah.
And that's what people are worried
about.
Again,
that slippery slope that is headed
towards that.
But what you're saying is that everyone
is always spied on everybody's phone
calls.
They've always been involved in
monitoring leaders whenever they could
and that it's not just,
it's standard,
it's standard protocol.
It's every nation acts in its own best
interest sometimes.
It seems like the u s is the only one
that apologizes for it.
But if you,
if you did nothing else other than
approach foreign policy from the
perspective that every nation action his
own best interest,
we wouldn't get caught short as many
times as we do.
Look at Putin.
I mean,
Putin absolutely is,
is,
he's an old school kgb guy.
He's,
he's always regretted that the Soviet
Union fell apart.
He considers it a huge catastrophe.
Uh,
probably the biggest catastrophe called
it of the 20th century.
And he's been busy ever since.
Trying to figure out how to rebuild at
least,
uh,
influence,
if not territory.
And Eh,
2000,
whenever it was five,
he made us a,
one of his first statements about how it
was a,
it was a horrible thing that the Soviet
Union fell apart.
And then a couple of years later,
three years later,
he,
the troops rolled into Georgia and they
still own territory and Georgia and
people don't talk about that.
Uh,
Kazia in South [inaudible],
they've still got a large numbers of
Russian troops in there.
So he got that.
He got Crimea.
Um,
you know,
eastern Ukraine is for all intense
purposes going to become part of Russian
territory.
And he's always been the same way.
He says what he means.
He acts in Russia's best interest.
Chinese are the same way.
We always seem to,
to feel like that's,
that's unusual.
I mean,
I remember times when we'd be engaged
in,
in some counter insurgency operation
overseas and um,
we'd address him up and we'd give them
money and party hats and we train them
and then they go out,
meaning the,
the,
uh,
foreign service foreign military and
they wouldn't act like we would write.
There would be problems.
So there'd be,
um,
human rights abuses or whatever.
And you know,
the Senate,
the Intel Committee,
which say,
I can't believe this.
How come they're not well,
because they're a fucking different
culture,
just like you talked about earlier with
the Middle East there.
You can dress them up and give them
money and training and they're always
going to act differently.
It just the way the world.
But we never seem to quite get that.
And it's sort of like this acting in
your own best interest.
We always seem to be what we do it,
but we feel like it's unseemly.
Somehow every other nation out there is
doing it.
Allies and others,
everybody.
So is this a part of the problem with
people getting access to information on
how the world works?
As time goes on,
that information becomes more and more
accessible and people get more and more
upset about things that essentially have
always been like this?
Is that what's going on?
Yeah,
I mean,
I think it's an interesting way to put
it,
but people have a problem with it,
but they don't offer up a solution or
what,
I mean,
the,
the argument is always United States
should do better.
We should be better.
We should inspire.
There are American citizens.
We shouldn't spy on foreign leaders.
We should be the shining beacon of
democracy and of honor throughout the
world.
But,
you know,
that's a lovely idea.
And we try it.
And it's kind of going back to what I'd
said earlier.
I,
you know,
and people would disagree,
but I,
again,
I've spent a lot of time overseas
dealing with these issues and we try,
right?
We don't always get it right,
but we try to do that.
We try to be that,
that you know,
that that bright beacon and we try to be
the right direction,
all those things.
And,
and sometimes it works and sometimes it
doesn't.
Um,
we had,
uh,
I remember one time I had a guy in a
foreign service,
a foreign military.
We're sitting having a drink and,
uh,
and they've been engaged in a long
conflict.
And anyway,
this guy says,
Hey,
he says,
uh,
thank you for,
for bringing us democracy.
And then he paused for a minute.
He says,
please don't do it again.
I always thought that was a great line.
I always thought,
yeah,
I get what you're saying.
Um,
but yeah,
it's,
it's not that easy to bring democracy.
Democracy doesn't really work.
It doesn't really work.
And,
and you know what we,
so,
yeah.
So what do you do?
You end up dealing with people that are
unsavory end up dealing with,
with countries that,
you know,
hey,
we'd love them to be more in step with
us,
but it's just not the way,
it just not the way it works.
It seems incredibly confusing and I
don't think anybody's ever offered up a
reasonable scenario where you could take
places that I liked the Middle East and
straighten it out like no one's offered,
like some sort of a step,
like a or a program.
Or you can say,
well,
here's where they are now.
Here's the rights violations,
here's the,
the real problems they have with
religious freedom and this is how we can
get them out of that.
And we can get them to a place where the
United States is right,
where people have much more freedom.
We know it.
States isn't free.
Freedom is an illusion.
It's an illusion.
We're not totally free.
No,
it's totally free.
There's no,
there's no total freedom.
But it's also,
uh,
it's also because of the way the world
is.
Yeah.
I'm telling you,
I'm,
I'm here to die again.
I've,
I've been to a lot of places and,
and,
uh,
we won the lottery and I realize
everybody's coming from different
positions and you know,
places in life and,
and,
and you know,
it's pretty fucked up for a lot of
people here sometimes.
And,
but this is a good place to be overall.
And there's still as the potential,
even though it may seem far off
sometimes for some people,
but there's still the potential if you
work hard,
you can,
you can do really well in this country
and,
and you know,
and even those times when,
I dunno,
maybe,
maybe I'm just kidding myself.
Maybe I'd like to continue believing
that and maybe who knows?
Maybe it's not true.
I,
you know,
I got young kids so I'm going to,
I'm going to continue to believe it's
true.
I think it's true for the most part,
but I think it's complicated.
And I also think this is a very unusual
place.
This country's only a couple hundred
years old.
And that's weird.
It's weird to believe that.
We mean really essentially founded in
1776.
I mean,
th 200 plus years is not long at all.
Hear you talking about it's going to
what you're,
I mean,
1776.
Yeah.
George Washington knew the importance of
intelligence.
He talked about the importance of
intelligence in the revolutionary war.
I mean,
the first,
and I'll probably get this wrong,
but the first entry into the,
uh,
the,
what do they call that book of
expenditures,
you know,
that the accounting book that they kept
anyway,
basically the first entry was to pay for
spies.
Um,
and,
and it was,
it was to establish a spy network,
I believe,
outside of Boston.
And so they understood even at that
time,
the importance of it.
So,
yeah,
to your point,
it was,
this has been,
telephones has been people listening in
and,
um,
and you need to check and balance that
and you need to ensure that it's not
overreaching.
I get all of that.
Uh,
I'm just saying that when you do find
that point and congress enacts a law and
the courts,
you know,
go with it and say yes,
when you do that then and you're jumping
through the hoops that have been put in
place and you've got to theoretically
again the place to,
you know,
you would always like to think that we
have committees up on the hill that are
inquisitive and aggressive in their
questioning and you know,
are paying attention.
Um,
but when all that is done,
then you'd like to think if you have an
operational concern and you go through
those hoops that yeah,
you'd be able to get the job done.
Kind of bringing it back to the apple.
So I think kind of in a lot of ways
we're talking about,
we're talking about a lot of
similarities that we have.
On one hand we have the,
the ideal utopia,
we have the shining light of honor and
dignity and then you have the dire
of the worst case scenario,
right?
And we're trying to,
we're kind of in the mix,
right?
And that's,
that's sort of life
slowly off.
And I think that's people it,
you know,
there's one thing you learn in the
agency is that it's not black.
There's nothing black and white about
the,
about about the world.
And you learn the CIA is very good at
teaching you how to sort of exist in
the,
in the gray areas and understand that
you're never going to get all the
information that you want.
You know,
if it's not,
it's not like the beach books for the
feature films where they get all the
details and okay now it's time to go,
let's do that operation.
You know,
I remember most of the stuff that I was
doing,
most of the operations,
you know,
in the back of mind you're thinking,
boy,
I hope this isn't getting fucked up.
You know,
because we're,
you're not,
if you wait for all the information,
you know,
before you,
before you do something,
something bad's going to happen.
It's going to,
it's,
it's going to be a fucking go up.
You've got to get off the exit a certain
point.
And usually that's before you have that
full comfort.
And so you,
they teach you very well how to do that,
how to do risk versus gain calculations
and how to figure out,
okay,
this is what we're going to have to,
but you got to make a decision at some
point the world like it to be,
you know,
again,
sort of a zero risk.
That's why we always talk about counter
terrorism and they say,
well,
what am I going to get this over with?
We're not,
you know,
it's just a,
and you evolve as a species.
Yeah.
I,
that's really what it's going to cry.
It's going to have to come down to
something pretty fucking astronomical to
have no more violence,
no more crime,
no more espionage,
no more,
no more hate.
Yeah.
I don't,
you know what I suspect I didn't in,
in your lifetime.
In my lifetime.
I know.
It's so disappointing.
Uh,
what do I give everybody?
Mushrooms.
I might do the trick.
I don't know.
That's it.
Mike Baker for president.
Give everybody mushrooms.
That's,
that's your tagline.
That's it.
You don't want to be president.
Nobody wants to be fucking president.
And I really think we should get rid of
presidents.
What would we have instead?
I think a giant committee of super
intelligent people that aren't entirely
responsible.
One,
not one figurehead.
I think that figurehead is a primate
thing.
I think we always want the one alpha
primate,
they had a big silver back.
Yeah.
The wanting to watch the whole leader of
the tribe thing.
But that shit just can't work with 300
million people.
It's just too crazy.
And they all go gray so quick.
They get so fucking old man.
There's so much pressure on those guys.
Yeah.
And it's,
and,
and you know what it's,
it's also uh,
yeah,
I mean yeah,
President Obama.
Yeah.
He writes a good looking guy.
Smooth faced,
handsome young,
vibrant looking guy and now he light
hair.
Yeah.
Not only that,
its face has fallen off his bones.
Yeah.
The Guy,
he's,
he looks so tired.
Well,
slept in years.
Say It,
the weight of that job.
Um,
but you know,
someone who has always shouldered it and
somebody is always watching it,
the job.
But wasn't it a different weight?
Was it different?
He was
dealing with depression,
the recession,
the,
and dealing with world war two.
I mean,
I think it's always been,
it's always,
it's just a terrible job.
Terrible job.
Part of it.
I think that the biggest problem now is
the speed of information,
right?
So everybody's a fucking journalist on,
on twitter.
Uh,
everybody's a judge and jury and all
through the speed of information,
uh,
nobody bothers to check facts anymore.
Everybody's racing to get ahead of the
news cycle,
which exists in,
in minutes now instead of hours.
I mean,
remember we used to be white,
you know,
like the five o'clock news,
the 11 o'clock news all day long.
Journalist had time to check their facts
and their stories and their sources
because they just had that one newscast
or two newscasts in the evening.
And now let's fucking throw it out there
and hope that,
you know,
we don't get it wrong.
So I think that weighs on,
on anybody who's in politics.
Uh,
maybe it serves a good purpose as well.
It keeps,
who knows?
Maybe it keeps them more honest.
I don't know.
But,
uh,
anyway,
I think that has something to do with
it.
Looking at Obama then and now look at
this photo.
Look at this.
Geez,
that's incredible.
That's a 20 year difference.
That's a 20 year difference in less than
eight years to 2006.
January,
2016.
You can throw up like a seven year split
on trump now and see what trump will
look like after seven years in office is
going to look like Jabba the hut.
His face is already fighting gravity.
Wow.
The poor guy.
I so rich to one,
Jesus Christ.
What are you eating then?
None of them are healthy.
How about Bernie Sanders?
Bernie's Bernie Sanders is going to look
like a question mark.
He's going to like Ben completely over
his posture.
So awful already.
Like someone should teach.
That guy had a stand up straight and
he's not that old,
much older than Clinton.
Right?
He's only a couple of years older than
she was like,
Shit.
Yeah.
Well she's not holding up that well.
She doesn't look good.
Yeah.
Well they did this bill.
You look at that.
I look out,
he was like,
Shit.
Oh Geez.
They rolled him out.
I think they realized right away.
That's a bad idea.
Well,
didn't he have,
he had like some serious heart surgery,
right?
Yeah,
he did.
Yeah.
But he's a smart son of a bitch and he
was,
you know,
he,
he was fortunate in a lot of ways.
And He,
and he governed well and he,
he understood the,
the,
the importance of compromise and
negotiation,
I think.
And that was still at a time when you
could do that.
I think,
I don't know whether it's still
possible.
I mean,
look at the,
some of the shit that comes out of that,
the Capitol Hill where,
you know,
I mean,
it Scalia is barely dead and people are
saying,
we're not going to listen to anybody who
gets proposed a,
you know,
come in here and replace them.
And you think,
well,
you probably could have held off on that
statement for a little while.
Democrats were so excited to get a
liberal in their,
oh,
Bama can appoint a liberal.
Yeah,
exactly.
And now he's throwing a left curve and
said,
well,
maybe I'll,
you know,
who knows?
Maybe somebody who is a Republican and
you can imagine that's,
is that what he said?
That's what he said.
Yeah.
What's it?
I forgot what the guy's name is.
He's a former governor and is a salad.
What about hope and change and now we've
got to get Bernie in there because
he'll,
he'll hold the flag.
I love to go camping when Obama just
spent a week with them just to get drunk
with them every night.
Just tell me every day.
Yeah,
what the fuck is going on?
What does that kid like?
The guy is only three or four older than
me.
It's gotta be a good feeling to have
that last day.
I mean,
I know this probably,
there's obviously a lot of sadness and
there's a lot of worry about,
well what,
how am I going to be remembered?
But that last fucking day when you
finally get to hand over the keys,
get the hell out of there and go have a,
you know,
a few pops and not have to worry about
waking up in the middle of the night
because some disasters going on.
Yeah,
but he's still got,
he knows too much.
So the consequences of all that
knowledge,
you've got to been weighing on his head.
All these pieces that are in play,
where are they going to wind up in a
book or the book deal,
a book deal and his own conscience mind.
And then also the fact that he's got to
have secret service for the rest of his
life.
He was driving around and bulletproof
cars forever.
That guy can't go to the fucking mall.
He'd give up your right to go to the
movies.
Well,
I wouldn't mind if I didn't ever go to
the mall again.
Quite frankly,
I'll be pressing if that means I can't
go back into a mall so much he can do
though.
I know you're right.
You can't go to the ball game,
buy a ticket at the last minute and go
in and just sit in the bleachers.
You imagine if you do that and say Obama
comes and sits down next to you with a
dog and a pretzel and it's a Co parent
who would be sell feed Nachos.
Yeah.
They would swarm him.
If he didn't have secret service,
they would smother him with selfies till
the,
there was no air and suffocate died of
selfies.
Hey,
you probably should have held off on the
whole selfie thing when they was in the
White House.
So it'd be fair that walking around the
White House with a selfie stick was at
and selfie sticks or unpresidential.
Yeah.
I think there's certain things you do
and you don't do and whether it's him or
whether it's any other president,
I think there's,
there's something to be said for
maintaining the dignity,
the dignity of,
of an office there.
Yeah.
There to fucking take a selfie just by
yourself and you need a camera to do
that just seems weird that I uh,
eh,
that's odd.
And what a sign of the Times that is
though.
Seen him there with a magic wand where
the fucking phone and well did you see
him before when he was like a pure and
around the corner with his sunglasses
but tending to be James Bond and you
know what also,
I bet he has the iphone six and not the
six plus because they,
well we don't want you to look
excessive,
Mr President.
It's probably a decision.
Go with a smaller phone.
Mr.
Preston.
A little bit more approachable.
We don't want you outrageous like I want
a viper.
You can't try the viper.
Not Fiber,
but it's an American car.
I can never have a fight for,
I can imagine.
Drove a viper on at Ford 158 corvette
convertible.
Oh Man.
Fucking big elvis sunglasses.
Yeah.
I'm afraid you fucks.
If it was me and I finished up,
I would drive away from the White House
in my last day in an El Camino.
This is,
this is the fact that drives my wife
crazy.
I,
I've always always wanted an El Camino.
I've always kept my eye out for,
you know what,
uh,
you give me an El Camino every year.
Uh,
it was manufactured and I would be a
happy boy.
I don't know why it's,
it's,
it's irrational.
And my wife hates it because she thinks
it's a,
it's a horrible looking car.
Do you have one?
I don't.
I've got my latest,
my latest by was a as a,
uh,
a wagon
here.
Remember the old jeep wagon?
Yes.
With a wood panel on the side I bought,
I bought one of those and it's uh,
it's uh,
actually being redone at a,
at bucks four by four.
And uh,
in Idaho for all your,
all your automotive needs.
So you bought it and you're refurbishing
it or is it the last year they
manufactured it?
91 91.
And it's got an original Shag carpeting
in there and it's,
uh,
it's just,
it's a brilliant vehicle.
I've got the big bench seat.
Remember the bench seat you'd have and
cc that was,
those are good when you went around
corners just slid all over them.
Now that it,
depending on if you had to girl by your
side,
then you take a hard left turn.
Oh,
what are you doing over here?
It was bench seats.
It is.
Yeah.
Almost like that.
Huh?
I ain't even one car.
That's a piece of shit that is done.
I can you say that,
look at that son of a bitch.
That's a fucking ugly.
God is a car right there.
And you know what that thing weighs
about 400,000
tons.
It is solid steel.
I tap you tap.
That's been,
yeah,
that's weird.
Yeah.
That shouldn't happen.
You want it classic classic test,
right?
You keep it classy and like the wood
panel.
Oh,
are you kidding me?
Of course.
Yeah.
See that's validate all the common sense
that you've laid out on this podcast.
The less,
there's a lot of people out there that
they would look at the woodside wagon
here and say,
yeah,
I get it.
That's a great vehicle Camino,
to be fair.
A lot more throwing up in their mouth.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
thank you for that.
Um,
but yeah,
that's,
that's sort of the,
uh,
I know.
And then another thing that the 57 Bel
Air,
I'm a big Belair Belair.
That's a beautiful thing.
There's no doubt about that.
I sit and watch for entertainment and my
two older boys will sit there and just
be as happy as clams watching with me.
I'll watch Barrett Jackson auction and
meet too fancy.
See,
look at me.
Come auction.
One time I got caught in a rabbit holes
sitting in my house and it came on.
I watch it for two fucking hours.
Just watch people buy a car.
It's all you do.
It's insane.
And you know,
and,
and it's just so much,
I look at that whether it was a 1970
challenges.
Oh that's,
that's a beautiful car.
Damn car right there.
Wow.
What our car,
what a shape.
I know that a 55 and 57 the old days
when it was,
what they would do is,
I mean it was all based on aspiration,
right?
So we had the space program,
you know,
there was starting to build and you
know,
and you could see it in,
in the vehicles,
you could see,
you could see what that,
what that time was like by looking at
the cars under the excess of it all.
And then the dreaming.
It's special.
Yeah.
Bumper.
Oh God.
The shyness.
It's such a strange shape too.
So gorgeous.
Anyway,
and then there's five mercury,
a Sun Valley's mercury.
Sun Valley's are another good guy.
Could go anyway.
Nomads.
I mean just,
it's just so many good cars
out there.
But um,
yeah,
I went to high school with her dad had a
55.
Oh my God.
It was gorgeous.
It was one of those cars to drive it.
No,
no,
I didn't know her that well and he would
never probably let anybody drive it,
but he would just drive by,
you know,
it was,
there was two cars in my neighborhood
when I grew up that were one,
one,
uh,
my,
sister's boyfriend's brother had a 65
gto convertible,
cherry red.
That was,
he was the king.
This guy was the king.
He would drive down the neighborhood
neighborhood.
Cliff's June was his name.
It said Chirps on his bumper.
Stickers.
License plate was chirps and he would
drive this thing and he would slam
through the gears and the wheels will go
cause they had a little skinny ass
fucking shitty tires back then.
And then there was another guys car.
So,
oh my God.
Yeah.
There's something about those cars to
this day,
like commanding the top dollar now.
It used to,
it used to be,
you know,
you'd get,
you'd be into the 50s and,
and that was when the big dollars where,
but now that they've gotten back into
the muscle cars,
you know,
there's a year that they go the get to
where they're not worth anything.
Like the 1980s shit.
Well you remember that point in time,
there was a very sad point in time when
all of a sudden you realized that the
trans-am,
the Camaro,
the Mustang,
they all started to look just the same
and you started,
it fell apart.
Oh,
mustangs were pieces of shit.
Now they,
they've,
they've done a good job of trying to
revitalize that.
But there was that period of time when
cause everything,
that Camaro,
he used to be 68,
69,
remember [inaudible] 69 Camaro was one
of the greatest looking at muscle cars
of all time and hugger orange they had.
And they made a hugger orange.
[inaudible]
fuck.
Yeah.
It had me and I know that with orange
you saw this thing.
No,
it's a special,
it's a special color.
Oh,
hugger orange.
Look that up.
Anyway,
so,
uh,
yeah,
so I'm not sure how we got into that.
Not Bad.
That's actually not bad.
But you know what,
that 69 camaro shape is so fucking
spectacular.
It is the perfect muscle car shape.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's hard.
It's hard to beat.
It's hard to beat that.
That's about as good as it gets,
man.
And that's pulled top dollar now.
Oh,
well they're taking those now.
And they do what they call a pro street
conversions.
You know,
they take a car like that and they do
everything.
They do a resto mod.
Right.
So all the breaks are new.
They have modern suspension,
you know,
they have these um,
uh,
art morrison chassies that are custom
built for those things.
So they take out their funky frames and
they put in like a really spectacular,
well-designed frames,
specifically me.
Look at that for those seats.
Those seats never used to show up at
auction because it was like,
yeah,
look,
it's not,
you know,
it's not original,
but now.
Yeah.
Well people saying there's still a lot
of people that like original,
they're assholes.
They want,
they want to die in a car accident.
Those fucking things.
He,
he hit the brakes and it's like,
you better be ready.
That way I can hear redone.
Yeah.
Cause I got dragged those kids around in
there and when you're going to get
modern breaks,
put in it and everything.
Yeah.
The whole thing has been been a,
basically,
you
know what got everything except the
wood.
Are you going to do the engine?
Yeah.
Well the idea was a complaint,
read belt on the engine fuel injection
because first of all,
that's what you want.
You don't want to go on a carburetor.
Oh my God.
Personally in Idaho while I had it for a
while before I put it over at,
uh,
at bucks four by four for all your
automotive needs,
gas and the carburetors.
I'd run out there,
I'd be in a hurry yet jumped in and I
think anyway,
my faculty out there,
I was looking to sell their El Camino.
You get in touch with me really that
deepen and,
Huh?
I don't know what I didn't know.
I remember part of it is,
I remember as a kid I had know I had a
great hot wheels collection and I
remember the El Camino was one of my
favorites back then.
Anyway.
So to me it looks like a pickup truck.
Fuck the Chevelle.
Yeah.
Basically.
I can't argue with it.
Yeah.
I could have Chevelle.
So that to me is like,
why would you have that when you can
have a Chevelle and 69 Chevelle and one
of the most beautiful muscle cars ever
created,
but a 69 el Camino like wow.
There it is.
There's the hot wheel.
Yeah.
That's nice.
I think.
I think that's mine.
I think you've got a picture of my very
own hallway.
Ooh,
I got one of those sit on my desk in the
office.
People walk in,
they start and they go,
why do you have this fucking toy?
El Camino.
Google of real 69 El Camino.
Jamie,
let's see what a real one looks like.
Not a hot wheel one C for a nice looking
car though.
The,
you know,
it's,
the front is so good looking like don't
go down that one.
The one the black and white right below
that.
Ooh.
See The bay.
The back looks like shit though.
That's fraud is so good.
Look in the back.
Doesn't look that bad,
but you know it's a place to put your
dog and you know.
Anyway,
I forget that you can't drive with your
dog in the back of your truck out here.
We do all the time.
Can,
it wasn't illegal out here.
I suspect somebody would turn your in
right now.
How could you dare put your dog out in
the back of your truck and drive down
the street?
That's,
I was in northern California this
weekend.
Some guy was driving around this dog in
the back of the car and my daughters are
freaking out until like he just has to
tall.
The dog is just running around in the
back like that's what they do.
We drive down the street and I see kids
in the back of pickup trucks.
I mean,
do you remember that car though?
Remember that car or that car that had
the plastic seats when the handles in
the back facing facing.
What the hell was that?
That was,
it was like a Subaru.
Yeah.
There was some kind of guard.
It had fucking black thing,
little seats in the back.
We could put the kits and they had
little handles.
That was the safety feature.
This little plastic handles the kids get
a hold onto as you drove down the road
and the highway doing 70 miles an hour.
I have to have it.
A couple of Martinis at the old club.
What is that?
A Subaru pickup truck thing.
I don't remember it like it was lacking
station wagon that had,
I got a picture of one but a Volkswagen
station wagon.
Wow.
Well,
yeah.
Facing seating now.
Yeah.
My,
yeah.
My Dad had a chevy that had the rear
facing wagon seat and we also used to
fight with me and my brothers would
fight over it and you know,
we literally would go to the officer's
club.
My Dad would have a few drinks and then
the pile,
all the kids back in the,
in the,
in the Chevy wagon and,
and barrel down the highway as we're all
flying back
and forth over the seats,
argue with each other and fighting about
who gets the rear facing seats.
And there was not a fucking seat belt to
be had.
Well you remember those Toyota land
cruisers that had the seats that face
each other side facing Jay's Fj he's
forties what it we,
yeah,
it was Fj 40 right.
I forget what it was,
but it was,
yeah,
it was not that long ago that they,
they,
they had those in the,
in the Land Rovers for years and years
and years.
And including,
you know,
I want to say like 10 years ago,
they were still building those things in
the back.
Yeah,
I think so.
It's not that long ago.
It was,
it was an option on a cause.
I got a like got a land rover one time
and it was probably okay to be fair,
it's more than 10 years.
There's probably 15 years ago,
but I remember that was an option to get
was the the back seats face and I
thought well at what point am I ever
going to use these?
Yeah,
maybe the F's Fj 40 but that was way
more than 10 years ago.
See the F Z J 80 was a classic Land
Rover and now I was like,
I think they stopped making that 97 or
98 and that's a classic one because it
has a solid front and rear axle and
those motherfuckers can drive over
everything.
They just,
you know,
to this day people refurbish them.
Land cruisers are a great vehicle to see
those.
I mean those,
we used to put those things to all sorts
of,
she'll come up in London special.
Exactly.
All the Taliban had those land cruisers
because they never broke down.
You build that exhaust pipe up over the
top of the roof for the crossing the
fjords,
fjords towards in the desert,
the fjords,
the snorkel,
the desert snorkel,
the safari snorkel.
They would call it a lot.
And we've just released more documents
from bin Laden.
More documented.
The CIA released about 110 documents
from the bin Laden raid.
Oh,
that's right.
It was also about like what he wanted to
do with his money.
He died.
He wrote a will for his $29 million.
He had 29 million when he died.
Yeah,
I'm surprised.
Yeah.
I'm surprised he didn't have more.
Frankly,
it's days dad was worth billions.
Well,
this is weird that he was living in some
fucking strange compound and everybody
kind of knew it.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I know.
Well it was bizarre.
We haven't done it tonight.
Should we didn't fight Osama I that I
no,
you're kidding me.
And he was in that weird compound in
that ha like hiding out.
Yeah.
It's so,
it's so strange.
And we got lucky because he was,
he was looking to move.
It was looking to get on the move again.
I think he probably sensed in part
because he,
he'd had some problems with one of the,
one of the facilitators that he had and
he was looking actually to,
to,
to replace one of his people that
actually dealt with them sort of as
liaison guy between the Pakistanis and
al Qaeda and him.
And so it,
you know,
we,
if we,
if we held off,
if we hadn't found him and then only had
a month to plan,
uh,
you know,
it could have gone completely the other
way.
We could have shown up and it would have
been an empty place because he was,
he was actively looking to move to a
different location.
Well,
it's kind of funny that the way they had
to do it was doing in the middle of the
night land helicopters,
one of them crashed,
break and then
shoot him that way.
What really,
they knew where the house was.
If we were really evil,
if we were able yes,
drop one right on that house and fucking
incinerate and they talked about that as
a scenario.
In the end,
the decision was looking,
he's got,
there's women and children in there and
how many people were in the house with
him?
He had his extended family with them.
I'd effect,
you know,
there were,
uh,
I dunno,
seven or eight plus guards,
but the women and children were there
and so,
and the decision was made,
no,
we can't do that.
We can't,
we can't fire a rocket down there
because we don't want to take out all
those people.
That's an indication,
you know,
I can't,
I mean,
people are to say,
wow,
fuck you.
You just want to go after the oil.
But um,
you know,
trying to do the right thing.
So to signing a,
an insanely complex operation like that,
just to save those people that were with
him essentially.
Right.
And to do,
and to do the right thing and the idea
of being,
well,
maybe we can,
maybe we can recover them alive.
Maybe we can actually died in that rate.
Or other people do it too.
Right?
Guards died.
Yeah.
Did you ever see photos of them?
Did they let you look at the photos?
A body allegedly?
Is Anybody listening?
Um,
no.
No.
It's just between you and me.
Just don't know.
I didn't say no,
but if you did,
you could do something to let me know
that you did.
You could just to like just my last act
weird act like you're trying to hide
something right as I ask you a question,
like he can't fucken answer this
question,
but no,
I would say,
I mean there's a insanely complex
operation,
um,
you know,
full size mock ups,
put together of the,
of the,
uh,
of the facility of the [inaudible]
compound.
Um,
again,
talking about,
we were talking about before muscle
memory,
right?
You know,
how many fucking steps do I have to go
here?
How many steps do I have to get to the
end of this wall?
Right?
You have to know exactly how is places
laid out,
where he could possibly be and how do
they do that?
Well,
they,
I mean,
that's all that work.
People think that somehow we just rocked
up on his place.
That was,
that was eight plus years of insane
effort trying to locate him and then
confirm it was him and then,
you know,
design this operation.
And so there were a lot of,
a lot of moving parts.
It wasn't just like we said,
oh look great.
Now we got them.
And that was an impressive that he was
able to hide for that long.
Yeah,
it is.
But there was a lot of,
uh,
accomplices and mainly like the
Pakistani Intel service,
the incredibly duplicitous had someone
actually,
uh,
as his liaison officer within the packy
Intel Service and,
and there were a lot of people yeah,
that,
um,
had a very invested interest in making
sure that he,
uh,
stayed hidden.
And so,
uh,
I know people say,
well,
he was,
it was a tall bearded dude.
You should've been able to find them.
Well,
it ain't that easy and all,
and you know,
it's not as easy as it in the feature
films.
It just doesn't work that way.
It's not,
no,
I know,
I know that's disappointing for a lot of
people to hear.
But,
uh,
it was a great operation and it's
interesting that they've released these
documents and,
and uh,
at this point in time,
and it is,
it's fascinating to see kind of inside
his mind a little bit more and
understand to what degree he did or
didn't have a sort of operational
understanding of what al Qaeda was doing
at the time.
Um,
yeah.
So anyway,
for those of you that are looking for
something to read,
zero,
dark 30,
that move,
how accurate was that movie?
Um,
they make day people.
Yeah.
The girl who was in charge of everything
and telling navy seals.
Yeah.
It's a composite of people.
It's like,
it's like Hollywood does,
they do some things really,
really well.
They do the military a recreation's
very,
very well.
I mean,
he's incredibly well and um,
and then they take bits and pieces and
turn them into a character.
Right.
Which is what they do.
And that's,
that's the nature of it.
Yeah.
A dramatic representation of what kind
of went on,
but not really
good.
Juicy or so they have to make an entry
door.
You got to condense it down.
You know,
if you,
if you showed what actually happened,
the audience kill themselves out of
boredom because you'd be watching eight
years worth of,
of surveillance in eight years worth of
struggling and understand what one
credit card receipt meant in relation to
something that was happening over across
the other side of the world.
All these things that go into this that
nobody ever sees.
So they,
they,
you know,
they condense it down and it turns into
a movie and then,
and then,
you know,
up on the hill in Capitol Hill,
they get confused and they don't realize
that maybe it's a,
maybe it's a movie,
you know,
and so they,
I don't know if you remember that
kerfuffle they had after they released
it where they called them back and said,
well,
you know,
maybe over the interrogation program,
maybe you didn't tell us everything,
you know,
and you think,
well,
no,
they just made a fucking movie.
You know?
I mean,
because there were people that were
upset with zero,
dark 30 because I thought it,
it put too much importance on
interrogation.
And there were people that thought it
didn't put enough importance and I'm
thinking it's a fucking movie.
You know,
it,
part of it's just entertainment.
You know,
you're not watching a documentary.
But anyway,
well there's a,
there's a movie that they made,
I don't know if you saw the,
um,
Fox catcher movie that's based on Mark
and David Schultz.
The wrestlers.
Yup.
That movie is just filled with bullshit
and it's a real problem for Mark
Schultz,
who was an Olympic gold medalist,
one of the best wrestlers the United
States has ever produced.
And they,
they,
and that's that guy's alive.
Okay.
His brother got shot by that crazy
dupont fuck right.
But mark's alive and they changed all
sorts of Shit in that movie.
That doesn't make any sense.
Historical Shit about his career as a
wrestler,
his career as a UFC fighter,
they put the,
they even changed the time where the UFC
was invented.
They made the UFC,
they made him watch the UFC like almost
like six or seven years,
I think before it ever really existed.
And then on top of it,
the guy he watched fight,
was it historical character?
Big Daddy Goodrich.
Gary Good rich was one of the original
pioneers of MMA and he in the movie
watching Gary Goodrich fight,
Paul Herrera when in reality he fought
Gary Goodrich and his first UFC fight
also in the movie Mark Schultz is in
fighting in the UFC.
In his first fight he's fighting in some
small organization and it's like kind of
sad and he's fighting a white Russian
dude.
He fought a black guy named Gary
Goodrich.
Gary Good,
which is a historical figure.
It's like it's historical fact in the
world of mixed martial arts than Mark
Schultz was like one of the greatest
talents from wrestling to ever compete
in MMA.
And Gary Goodrich was a real pioneer.
A guy was very dangerous and mark took
them down at will and it was kind of
crazy to watch like how good of a
wrestler he was.
Well,
in the movie they bullshit their way
through all that.
He didn't even fight.
Gary was there.
Was there somebody who served as a
consultant,
who knows,
but mark went crazy after the movie's
released and one of those twitter
rampage and we were supposed to do a
podcast about it.
But he's,
he's an odd guy,
you know,
he's just,
he's,
he's very elusive and he's talked about
doing it and I said,
look man,
let me know when you want to do it.
I'll fly you out.
We'll talk about it.
But he went on this rampage about it on
twitter.
And then someone compiled a website
where they talked about all the things
that they got wrong in that movie and
all this stuff they made up in that
movie to make it more interesting.
But the story itself is fascinating that
anytime,
but he releases a story or anybody,
uh,
you know,
signs over something or anybody,
it picks up a book and says,
I'm going to make a movie out of this.
And,
and that's it.
It's,
it becomes an editorial process.
It's like saying,
you know,
how does raw intelligence get out of the
field and then suddenly becomes
something that's not,
well,
it gets into this editing process and
you've got a bunch of people taking a
whack at it,
you know,
over at the National Security Council
and eventually,
you know,
they've got to spin on it.
I can kind of understand that.
If you're talking about someone who died
before things were recorded,
right?
Making a movie on Lincoln,
you don't really know what he said.
You've got to kind of put words in his
mouth.
It's in a little bit.
What did he say to his wife?
Let's make up some shit.
He said to his wife,
but Lincoln's Lincoln's dead.
Mark Schultz is alive and he's not that
old.
I mean he says,
I think he's probably 50 they talked to
him about it.
Did they?
Oh yeah.
Well,
whatever.
They talked to him about it.
He fucking wasn't happy when the movie
was released,
so I don't,
I don't know.
Right.
They made him look gang in the movie.
They made it.
They alluded to some sort of a weird gay
affair with him.
And Dupont.
It was frosted tips.
It was very odd.
Very odd what they did.
I'm impressed.
You know what frosted tips are.
Oh,
they're out there.
So I was like,
I know a lot of things.
Strip club,
no saying or his hair.
Yeah,
I know,
I know.
You know,
we all know who hasn't had frost 10 we
don't know.
I don't know what the hell that is.
Yeah,
when I had hair,
it's not about Camino.
I never had frosted tips,
but I could have,
I could have been talked in.
I've could have gotten to,
I've could have fallen into the wrong
crowd of people in my twenties and I
could've wound up in rocking tipsy after
that game at fenway and found a
hairdresser upstairs,
do a hairdressers and said,
that's it.
That's for me.
Anybody saw the perfect guy
with frosted tips and it,
this would have been completely
different conversation that you and me
are having.
Right?
Ice Man from top gun,
Val Kilmer,
kilmer kilmer,
he's not looking as good as he did back
in the top gun days.
He kind of slimmed down a little bit.
He got back to like a more manageable
form.
Okay.
But for him,
he definitely shape.
He went,
he went full trump for awhile.
He just ballooned up to this strange
sort of,
that's odd because he was a fucking
beautiful man.
That was alien movie and he did.
He did a tombstone.
There's the frosted tips.
Dad is nice man.
Fuck it in the air force were in that
hairdo.
How does a guy go from that to,
have you ever seen that photo where it's
like lol?
I used to remember when I used to be
Batman.
Ever seen that picture?
His fucking face looks like a giant pie.
Yeah.
I saw him one time over at the Chateau
Marmont.
I was sitting there,
uh,
working on my laptop and I look up and
he's across the room and I thought
something familiar,
but it was during his,
a large stage.
I remember staring,
thinking there's something familiar
about that dude.
And it took me forever to figure it out.
I finally,
I was about to close my laptop at that.
Aha.
It's,
it's a,
it's a huckleberry guy.
There he is.
Hey guys.
Remember when I was Batman.
What the fuck did he do this?
Does he just boozing it?
Oh,
nuts,
donuts and booze and bring a lot of
people doubt.
Stop.
Stop doing this.
Spring up some pictures of the Camino.
He got so big belly up there.
Look at that one.
Go Up.
Look at that one right at his belly to
the right.
Oh my Jesus Christ.
Stop turning that roll down.
I don't want that role.
Well,
actually look at his face there.
He's in the,
not as fat with its face as he was in
that.
Remember when I was Batman?
He all by God Travolta.
Look,
they're a little bit,
what the Fuck,
man?
I wonder what he did.
We'll need to age better out in this
town.
People need to age better.
They need to learn to age gracefully.
It's hard.
Well,
you know what the doctor just tells you,
hey man,
I'm just give you a little,
a little nip,
a little talk and we'll be fine.
Tell you what I'm talking about.
A slippery slope.
Good looking man,
but thank you.
It a little better.
It gets some frosted tips and pull those
eyes up a little bit.
Just it's gonna make your mouth.
Sorry.
That's a weird one.
That's not a good one.
Make your mouth a little bigger.
That's the weird one that women develop
this mouth that looks like they could
eat your head.
Yeah.
There they're fucking choke her mouth
because they're pulling your face and in
pulling your face they stretch.
They do something crazy where they're
stretching your mouth.
They tightened the,
uh,
they tightened the Jina and they enlarge
the mouth and nothing wrong with Titan
and China.
I know,
I guess I,
I just realized what I was saying.
I think that medical responsible mass,
yes.
Fight of a,
John,
I'd want to tighten.
I know this is exactly what people would
expect to us to be talking about when I
come in on that afternoon on this
podcast.
Yes.
Because this one guy,
this podcast will go south.
Well,
we'll as
well it has.
I think it might have.
I wanted to ask you one question before
we get out.
I can get,
I think we're closing in on the three
hour mark.
The interrogation school that you were
talking about,
like what do they do to you when you're
in an interrogation school to try to get
you to understand what it's like to
break?
You'll have to talk about that to some
degree.
Yeah.
I mean what you go through is a lot of
what the waterboarding,
Nick's work.
So yeah.
I mean waterboarding has done to,
to,
to us,
to our people.
So you've got waterboarded uh,
is anybody listening?
No.
Okay.
Just keep telling me that.
I keep imagining because we'll probably
actually just recorded this.
You're just being nice to me there.
It actually,
you're not even recording it.
This is just happening and it's going to
go in the dump lot.
Yeah.
Anyway,
the point being is yes,
that enhanced interrogation techniques
including sleep deprivation,
which is probably at the end of the day,
uh,
sleep deprivation,
white noise,
stress positions.
Um,
a,
an interrogation facility is a very,
uh,
finally controlled,
very labor intensive place.
And it's not like people think,
ah,
it's like a apple grape.
Well,
Abbott,
Greg wasn't an interrogation facility.
I have them grade was a military holding
cell run by uh,
you know,
uh,
people that didn't have the experience,
they basically turned it over to junior
officers and people that shouldn't have
been in there running a facility like
that and it was completely wrong.
But an interrogation facility,
you go in and it's,
it's,
it's all about doing your homework.
You don't ever go in and sit down with
a,
a detainee unless you have done all your
homework.
You know where you want this
conversation to go.
You know the questions you want to ask.
You don't want to appear to be wavering.
You didn't want to appear to be unsure.
And if you don't do your homework,
it's like a,
it's like a polygraph.
If the polygraph operator doesn't do his
homework,
lie detector,
if he doesn't do his homework and that
exam is fucked,
do polygraphs work?
Uh,
you know what,
in a way,
it's not a science.
So it's not,
it doesn't work in the sense that yes,
it will tell if you're lying or not.
It's a tool in the kit bag of
understanding what,
what kind of person you're dealing with.
So for some people it works because they
feel guilty about everything.
Right?
Right.
And so they remember that in 1902 they
stole a pen and now they feel bad about
it.
So they're gonna,
you know,
and so the physical,
the physiology of it is,
it is starting to react.
And that allows for the operator to go,
well,
there's something strange about that
question.
They reacted a little bit differently.
They're breathing,
whatever it may be,
the sweat,
they how to react.
She had a reaction.
Now,
let's now let's go in on that a little
bit,
but I guess my point being is that,
or interrogations or even negotiations
or interviews,
I mean,
if you're out there and your,
your job is to interview people,
well then,
you know,
you know what it's like,
you gotta know who you're talking to and
that's how it becomes effective.
But in,
in training,
yeah.
You go through all these things,
um,
and it,
you know,
it can be,
it can be fairly intense.
But the idea,
again,
part of it is to show will look,
this is,
this is what it does.
This is how you can deal with it.
This is how you,
you know,
you stay close to some something that's
um,
that's,
that's plausible.
You know,
it's like a,
an alias or a,
a backstory or whatever you want to call
it.
You don't want to treat it.
Try to keep it close to the truth.
You know,
the problem that people have in
interrogation sometimes is they'll say
something that's not true.
Now they got to remember that.
Then they go back in for another
session.
They got to remember what they said
before.
Now if they say another line,
now they've got to remember those two
things and they was pretty soon after
three or four interviews,
they're trying to remember this string
of lies where what you really want to do
is you want to try to keep it as close
as possible to whatever the truth may be
so that you don't have to spend all your
time struggling to remember what was the
hell I said last time.
So like,
if you lie to someone that you're
interrogating,
that's you're saying,
not if someone's being interrogated or
someone's,
I mean,
that's an or,
or you know,
in the interview process.
I mean,
it's just,
so anyway,
I,
I don't know where I'm going with that
other than to say that it's,
uh,
it's,
and whether it's military,
whether it's mild outfit or whomever,
um,
it's an important,
uh,
part of training because,
you know,
again,
you have to understand what's possible.
Now it's,
it's a changed world,
right?
The Doj and the White House and
everything came out and tortured people
in the mall.
Well,
you can't use enhance techniques,
you know,
and,
uh,
yeah.
So,
Hey,
go and how people are screaming and
sexy.
That's fucking torture until I your
dope.
But I mean,
the idea of being is all you can use.
This is the field manual,
the military field manual.
And what does that mean?
Well,
it means I couldn't break my,
my daughter with a military field
manual.
You couldn't,
I don't think so.
What does the military field and what I
mean by that is,
I don't mean to be,
uh,
I don't mean to be flip or dismissive.
What I'm saying is once,
once people out there know what can and
can't be done,
they know how much they can take.
They know exactly what they can take,
they know what exactly what's coming
down the pike and they're just going to
keep their Yap shut.
And people say,
wow,
but you can develop a relationship with
them.
That's what we did.
You know,
most of the time,
all the information we got basically if
people took the time to go through Dlj
memos and look at the,
the actual information,
most of what we did was based on
conversing,
based on knowing who you're talking to,
doing your homework,
figuring out how the pieces fit together
and talking to people.
Um,
but those people don't have much
incentive to talk sometimes if they know
that,
well,
you can't do shit to him anyway.
Right.
And so I'll have to do is keep their
mouth shut and you're,
you're saddled down by the rules.
The advantage of,
of,
uh,
enhanced techniques.
You should do air quotes when you say
that it's tech.
And what I mean by that is,
yeah,
and it has techniques.
Let's see,
as a perfect representative.
I know.
And,
and you know,
and there you go.
And I know that was,
that's also,
it's like everything else,
right?
It's like the,
it's like all the other discussions
we've been having in terms of people
based on their experiences.
And so those people that you're never
going to shift off this position.
You're not going to shift off of this
other position.
It was all torture or it's not.
And there's some things that exist
between talking to a detainee and what
is torture?
The United States is noble when we don't
torture people.
Yeah.
Well,
um,
yeah,
I want them to,
that we do.
I don't want to,
but I want them to not know what's in
the kit bag.
Okay.
So enhanced techniques.
So like when you say enhanced
techniques,
is sleep deprivation and the enhanced
techniques to sleep.
So you can't use that anymore.
What?
No.
What if you read,
read what,
what took place?
People read those deal memos and realize
how much it wouldn't take it if they
actually took the time and understand
all the back and forth that took place
between the field and headquarters over
at,
well,
can we do this?
Can I put my hand on his chest and push
him up against a wall?
Well,
okay,
build a fake wall.
So it's not like,
can you do this?
Okay,
no,
can I,
what can I do?
And there was back and forth and back
and forth over what could be done and
yeah,
okay.
It's not supposed to be nice and it's
not pleasant.
And we can argue and I,
and obviously people do,
I don't,
torture is wrong and we shouldn't do it,
but do I think that there were some
things like a sleep deprivation or
stress positions or truck noise,
you know,
like,
uh,
put your forward against the wall and
walk back,
you know,
and then,
lean,
lean your head against the wall and walk
back and,
and stay in that position for,
you know,
15 minutes or whatever.
You make them do that.
Uh,
what if they don't in the old days?
Yes.
Yeah.
I mean,
you know,
people are pretty compliant in an
interrogation facility back when they
didn't know what was coming down the
pike.
Right.
And that's why I keep saying the same
thing.
I don't,
I agree it shouldn't be torturing,
but at the same time,
we shouldn't also be telling the
hostiles what we can and can't do.
All right.
You say you shouldn't be torturing,
but what if you have someone who knows
that a nine 11 is about to take place
and you've got to get information out of
them.
What other ways are there?
If you have a small window of time?
It's not really the unsatisfactory
answers.
There's not really,
torture doesn't really put through this
information.
I agree with Senator Mccain and lots of
other people about that people will say
whatever they need to say to make
whatever that horrible torture is to
stop.
And so it's not from an operational,
I,
you know,
again,
I understand that some moral aspect to
it.
I tend to just look at things from an
operational efficiency point of view.
And it's not good.
You can't,
you can't count on information.
So beating somebody up doesn't get
information off their fingers,
doesn't get information out of them,
but does sleep not that,
not that are not,
that are hostile is out there and not
to.
The people that are after us wouldn't do
the same.
Of course they do that,
but they're not really after accurate
information.
They don't care.
It's a different,
it's a different world that they
existed.
If we're after actionable intelligence
that you can count on,
then it's just a very,
very labor intensive sources.
Well,
there there's ways to get people to
talk,
right?
Well,
yeah,
I mean this gets to a point
psychologically speaking.
Sure.
I mean there's ways to get them to
comply,
get them and that's,
that's part of the processes,
you know,
uh,
in a well controlled environment,
sleep deprivation or,
or,
or a white noise.
How do you keep them awake?
What do you have to do for sleep
deprivation?
Ah,
you keep him standing or you,
uh,
you know,
keep moving them from place to place or
you pump in some,
uh,
you know,
Arabic music or a baby crying or
whatever it may be.
Um,
and it just keeps them awake.
I mean,
it's,
again,
it's labor intensive because you got to
keep checking on them,
making sure they're awakening.
But you do that in under a controlled
environment.
You don't,
you don't,
you know,
we're not talking about,
five days of this.
And,
and again,
if people took the time to understand or
read,
they would realize that we're a lot of
doctors,
psychiatrists involved that were saying,
yeah,
you can,
or you can't do this.
Um,
it wasn't,
you know,
I,
again,
you know,
I get conflicted because I understand
why people are so emotive about it and I
get that.
Um,
and I do agree there's,
uh,
you know,
you have to look at what you can and
can't do and you have to be very,
very critical about that.
And you have to be very careful.
But I guess I keep coming back to the
same thing as we've kind of given up the
ghost from now on going forward.
Everybody out there knows what we can
and can't do.
And so whether we were going to do it or
not,
which we wore in terms of the torture
side of things,
they didn't know that.
And so you could speed the process up of
getting them to comply to some degree
because they didn't know what was coming
down the pike and you keep them on the
back foot and you keep them guessing.
And that's your advantage in a,
in a,
in a situation like that.
So,
um,
but yeah,
I again,
I keep going back to the same thing.
I get it.
I understand why people are so,
uh,
you know,
and,
and to be fair,
the left really did a great job of
framing the argument.
You know,
they really took it and said,
you're either talking to somebody or
it's all torture.
Well,
if torture doesn't really produce
actionable information,
then it makes sense to not torture
people.
Right.
Absolutely.
That's my point.
And I agree from ecstasy and hookers
either.
No,
it's not.
It's not supposed to be a pleasant
situation.
And so people say,
well,
I can't believe you would,
uh,
you know,
put somebody in a stress position or you
would,
you know,
make them uncomfortable or you would
keep them awake for 36 hours.
I can't believe you would do.
Well,
really,
I mean,
what the fuck you want to,
of course.
And we'd always try,
you'd always try to develop
relationships with people that is in
fact the best way to do it.
Develop,
try to Pry,
you know,
find out about their psychology.
Try to find ways to get them on side to,
to get their sympathy or to bring them
on board.
Whatever you can do.
But um,
to just say we're taking all these other
things out of the kit bag,
whether we ever gonna use them or not.
And here's all we can do.
You're pretty much guaranteed that
there's a lot of people out there who
are walking around on Syria and Iraq for
Isis carrying a field manual in their
back pocket who know exactly what we can
do.
What we can't do now,
but isn't there a ways we circumvent
that by not doing it on American soil?
No,
no,
no.
I know people would like to think that.
I like to think that there's like some
secret CIA holding place that you take
people on the moon of question get stick
rockets up the ass and they start
talking.
I'm moon.
That would be you gotta be sign.
That'd be a lot of money.
Too much money on moon station.
Um,
no,
like one Tahmo for for instance,
like a lot of dark shit has gone on and
Guantanamo,
right?
Um,
no,
actually,
you know what,
here's where people will say,
ah,
I can't believe it.
Uh,
Watada Mo,
uh,
has always been more about,
um,
uh,
a holding facility.
And you could argue that though the,
the,
depending on how you want to frame it,
if you want to say it was all torture,
fine,
then the torture or the enhanced
techniques,
whatever,
uh,
for the most part took place overseas in
a facilities that,
you know,
we were running that were temporary or
our host countries were running.
And that's where I would much rather
have,
we treat people a lot better than some
of our allies do,
frankly.
And particularly a lot of our Middle
Eastern allies.
I could only imagine there are a lot of
guys in,
in,
in Guantanamo who would like to stay in
Guantanamo right now,
frankly.
Um,
then go be repatriated to the Middle
East and really?
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
you're kidding me.
Rather than if that didn't go back and
face a Egyptian justice.
Yeah.
Or,
or the Jordanians are.
Yeah,
absolutely.
But I mean,
I again,
I know people are going to say,
well,
they don't actually want it.
They're not clamoring to stay and get my
dog get me wrong.
I'm saying that they are treated better
in that facility.
Then they would be,
if they find themselves suddenly in an
Egyptian prison,
if they were interrogated by our allies.
So,
but having,
there've been people that have been
found to have been detained there that
really were innocent.
Let's put it this way.
Uh,
did we throw out a big net and uh,
err on the side of caution when we were
picking people up off the battlefield?
Yes.
Um,
did we do a lot of good by removing a
lot of these people and some of the key
players off the battlefield and out of
the operational system within al Qaeda
and some of their,
their supporting elements.
Yes.
So it's not,
you know,
it's not satisfying answer because it's
not black or white.
It's not all bad.
It's not all good.
Again,
like we were talking about before,
the gray,
it's the gray.
It's unfortunate,
but a part of reality.
It's the way that,
you know,
I don't know.
And you know,
and yes.
What are you going to do it?
Close it down and say,
well,
we're sorry.
The recidivism rate for people coming
out of a Gizmo is,
is up in the 30% outright.
It's,
it's,
it's a third plus.
And will you actually going to get my,
would probably encourage them to want to
fucking hate America more.
Well,
you wouldn't.
Yeah,
I got,
no,
don't probably that.
I think that's probably a fair
statement.
Um,
do I want them back out on the
battlefield looking to kill us or our
allies?
Uh,
no.
I think we,
you know,
but again,
what's the answer?
What's the area we've got to close Gitmo
and bring,
you know,
the 46 or so that we're never going to
repatriate over to us soil.
Who knows?
I mean,
as a president gets his way,
I don't think he's going to get passed
congress,
but it,
again,
it's one of those things down,
right?
He wants to close it down and this is
probably want to do with this 46 people
that are being told is 91 there.
But by the time you get to the ones that
just aren't going to find at home,
I mean,
look,
the Bishop Bush administration and the
Obama Administration,
we've spent years and years trying to
find places for these people.
It's not like anybody,
you know,
didn't want to try to get these people
sent somewhere else.
That's been a goal of,
of this administration and the previous
one and it just some folks who just
aren't going to find another home.
So there's about 45,
46 of them.
And the idea of being,
bring them back to the states,
I guess,
how do they catch these people?
And then it's all various different
ways.
Right,
right,
right.
And,
and that,
that was,
I was old days.
You don't,
you don't,
you don't hear us talking about catching
a lot of people anymore.
And part of the reason why it's because
you'd rather just paint that target and,
and blow the fuck out of him then risk
your career,
uh,
picking up somebody and then getting
accused of,
of,
you know,
mishandling a detainee,
um,
or,
or all the crap that can happen because
suddenly they've decided,
you know,
a program for capturing somebody and
bringing them back to go autonomo
wherever is not appropriate.
So what you've found over the years,
recent past is it's a lot easier to just
smoke them then to pick them up.
I hate to say that.
I mean that's a,
that's a,
that's a sad thing to say.
But that's,
and so what does that mean from an
operationally efficient point of view?
That means your pipeline of potential
intelligence is drying up because you're
not,
you're not picking these people up live.
It's just easier to,
to,
to whack them.
So it was a harsh reality.
Well,
it's,
it's part of the way it's part of the
way it works.
Nobody wants to,
everybody was getting their ass kicked
for being,
you know,
involved in,
uh,
a,
approved program of whether it was
rendition or the interrogation program
or,
you know,
whatever as part of that or the
periphery.
And,
you know,
people look at the,
the drone program and think,
wow,
that's really expanded under Obama.
Well,
no shit,
because it's just,
you know,
just take 'em out
the heartburn.
So that's why the drone program has
expanded because capturing detainees,
administration,
administration wants more people to put
in Guantanamo.
Isn't that fucked up?
That it's easier to kill someone
politically,
like to have civilian casualties and the
civilian casualties are pretty fucking
high with drones,
right?
Well,
uh,
yeah,
I mean this,
again under the theory that nothing's
going to be perfect.
They try everything they can to limit
that.
But yeah,
of course there've been civilian
casualties,
no doubt about that.
But then it's something crazy like 80%.
No,
no,
it's not that high.
It's,
it's,
you could argue even once too high.
Right.
I mean it,
but it's not,
you know,
again,
once again,
the same thing.
Numbers get thrown out on one side.
So it's not a,
it's not zero.
It's,
we've had,
uh,
we've had unfortunate instance,
there's no doubt about that.
And like I said,
one is too many,
but at the same time,
I guess my point being is the drone
programs expanded,
um,
in part because it's perceived as a
cleaner,
which sounds awful.
And it is awful because again,
from an operational perspective,
I'd rather have my hands on that
detainee to know what they know.
And once you smoke them,
you're not going to know that shit.
So what
if they come up with a way one day to
actually,
I mean,
I know that they have something called f
Mri,
functional magnetic resonance imagery,
I think it's called,
where they've used it.
I believe in India it was a real
problematic case because they convicted
someone for murder because they had
functional knowledge of the crime and
people who I talked to this
neuroscientist who was,
she was kind of an expert in Fmr I and
she said that's a huge,
there's a huge problem with them that
would never fly in the United States
because functional,
functional knowledge of the crime could
have been established through her
interrogation process,
through questioning,
through asking her about the case.
She could have functional knowledge of
the crime scene.
So like proving it through an Fmri she's
like,
is not,
it doesn't work.
So what they're convicting someone on is
something that would never fly in
America.
But what if they could,
if they could one day figure out a way
that one's like minority report or
whatever that movie was with Val kilmer
before he gained weight?
No,
I was Tom Cruise.
Same Guy.
Yeah.
They think it's the same one.
We never seen him photograph together.
You don't even notice that.
It's like Yasser Arafat and Ringo Starr.
I think you were in a movie together,
man.
They weren't top gun.
Of course they weren't.
But what am I talking about?
I forgot.
I was,
I,
I had my memory wiped clean by seeing a
deicing fat val kilmer.
Oh,
well,
uh,
you know what I got to tell you this has
been,
I'm sure the viewers are tired of it,
but I've had a great time.
Great.
John to thank you very much for doing
this.
I really appreciate your,
your candor and your openness and,
you know,
exploring some uncomfortable and
difficult subjects and uh,
and given us some inside information
that it's very difficult for people to
get any other way unless they're talking
to a guy like you.
It's a lot of it is speculation and,
and bullshit and posturing and reading
websites.
It might be completely inaccurate.
So I think you've,
you've,
you've helped us a lot.
Well,
I really appreciate,
I just encourage everybody,
just read everything you can.
Don't,
don't settle on one source of
information,
right?
I mean,
that's the right and the left.
Make that mistake again.
You know,
we're,
we're getting to a point where it's
pretty fucked up,
right?
We've got to find a way to get back to
the center and get shit done.
Otherwise,
I don't know where we're heading,
but anyway,
that's,
that's my last little bit,
but this has been a great experience.
Loved the show and,
uh,
really appreciate it.
I'm going to check with you about my
middle boys martial arts.
Yes,
please do.
Please do.
I'll help you out.
Thanks brother.
Really appreciate it.
Thanks.
See you.
Tomorrow.
We'll be back with the Ian Mccall.
We're going to preview this weekend's
UFC and have some fun.
See that bike?
Okay.