And what's up man? How are you?
Good. Thanks for doing this.
Thank you for having me on.
I was so impressed with your performance
from that past UFC that I had to had to
talk to you. I was like, that
was what I've seen guys make.
Like you were always a very dangerous
striker from obviously from the gold
gokarn Saki fight ever got.
Everybody got to see that.
But to see how fluid you were
against a beast like Eric Anders.
I mean Eric Andrews is a scary cat. Yeah,
he's, he's coming from blood. Right?
And you were so fast, man. It was crazy
to watch. It was really interesting.
Thank you.
What if you had to give
yourself a percentage leap
that you've gone up over the
last year, what do you think it
would be compared to like, well,
who you were before that?
Not that high of a leap. I mean, the high
light, that performance for me was like,
I feel good about it, but that
was only four months. So I'm like,
I know that there's so much more for
me to gain. That's what I'm like, yeah,
I gotta go back. So the leap, not,
not too much because I know there's still
a lot more to go a lot more. Yeah. Wow.
So you've decided, so for people who
don't understand what we're talking about,
you went to Thailand, he spent four
months down in Thailand and um, you,
you were fighting like a Thai box.
It was crazy.
Like Mark [inaudible] who works in the
production truck and he's the guy picks
out the insert replays.
He and I talked back and forth sometimes
while the fights going on and mark mark,
you know, with his heavy Boston
accent, like, dude classic,
he's classic Chi stance and you would
just, the light on that front leg
inside leg kick was so far
rochus it was fun to watch men.
So it's just usually wherever I go. Um,
I've always been good at just like kind
of absorbing the culture. I'm a guy,
like I can go into a room full of people
and I can just kind of pick up what the
energy is like. And that's another
reason why I wanted to go to Thailand.
So just the way that they
train and the discipline,
the power, but the relaxation, like
everything I was learning, just like man,
there's so much more to Moy Tai.
So I would just,
even the days that I didn't train,
I just sit around and just watch these
guys because moy ties more than just
punching, kicking elbows, men, there's
balance. You know what I mean? There's,
there's repetition. Like how many
kicks are you throwing? You know,
the guys at the stadiums, they're
like their Kik, Kik, Kik, Kik.
So I was able to learn a lot, my
aunt, and there's still a lot to go.
It's beautiful to see that someone on
that pursuit. And I think it's, um,
it's much like Roger May,
whether said about boxing,
like most people don't
know shit about boxing.
And you know what he said that was like,
if anybody is going to say that he's
going to say that because there are levels
and layers and there's,
there's paths to go down.
And it's interesting when you see
someone like committed with a very,
like a very specific style, like your
like adoption of that Moy Thai style.
So if it's so effective
as a striking style,
it's really interesting when you think
of all the different ways to attack with
striking that one way became
very particularly successful.
You know what,
before I even started
training MMA as a whole,
um, my first mixed martial, my first
martial arts class was annoyed tie class.
I knew that I wanted to train
Moitai or to learn when we tie. Um,
and so since I've started I always
thought like, yeah, I want to go there.
You know, just maybe it's cool. But um,
moist has always been my thing,
but I had never really learned it like
the actual way, you know, like from,
from the root of, uh,
of where it comes from.
I always just kind of like pass down or
like Brazilian style, Moy, Tai, you know,
like shoot the box type stuff.
So that's completely different from
stadium we tie and most people don't know
shit about stadium way tie.
Right? Like unless you go
to, unless you go to Bangkok,
let's characterize it for people.
You,
could you say that that core of Tiva
style is just way more aggressive,
different a different way
they utilize techniques? Yeah,
it's light on the front leg.
So sometimes the are like more shogun
would be light on his front leg a little
bit. One thing that they were doing
a lot that it's pretty similar.
It's just that they go at it,
shoot the box, they'll go at him.
You just go until the other
guy stops. Pretty much. Um,
but from the shoot the box,
I was like very combo based like
punches and kicks are like one,
two like you have to memorize these
crazy combos accord arrow. Is he like,
I think he is one of the guys that
just passed it down along Diego.
Lima think guys like that.
But yeah they have this system and
it's very like combination based um,
memory slipping Punchkick all this stuff.
But the ties are just like,
it's just straight kick,
you know, like punch view.
You fall down on that front
foot, elbow, knee. It's just,
it's broken down completely differently.
It's just a whole,
whole different style. Yeah, it is like,
so the shoot the box stuff has punches,
kicks, knees, elbows, combination, same
tools that you're going to use in Moitai.
But when we tie has got a whole different
game plan, you know, the clinching,
like I've never trained as much clinching
in America as I have in Thailand in
just four months. And I've been fighting
our training now for like nine years.
So just in four months I've gotten more
clinch time in Thailand that I have in
my whole career. And that's because
it's a whole different game.
You got to master the clinch and t in
Noida you have to for effective like real
true. Moitai uh, you getting a
lot of wrestling over there. Yeah.
So that's one thing too. I heard, um,
I heard shop talking about it. Um,
tiger has amazing,
it's an amazing gym,
40 to 60 guys on the mat from
everywhere. Chechnya. Wow. You know,
in everywhere, in everywhere. Man. Those
guys, they come there maybe for a week,
maybe two weeks, maybe for a
month. But you're getting constant,
um, good training, grappling,
everything, MMA, boxing, crossfit,
ev, everything you need is in one place.
It's, it's a blew my mind being there,
honestly. Um, that's
fascinating. And your,
are you the coaches that you
were working with before?
Are you still working with them and
Thailand? Are you just going to,
I know you talked about actually
moving to Thailand. Yeah. Yeah.
The plan is to move there like as
soon as possible. Really? Yeah.
So I was like hitting you up like Joe,
I want to get on your show.
I want to talk a little bit.
Um, but yeah, I want to, um,
the plan is to move to Thailand like with
the next couple of weeks for at least
a year.
And I want to go there just because
I can just train. The
lifestyle's completely
different. I can walk to the gym,
hop on a motor bike. It's
just, it's so simple. Um,
but to answer the question
about my coaches, um,
I always have my brother and my corner.
He's just kind of like moral support.
We started this together.
Um,
I had a conditioning coach slash friend
slash mental type of like support,
um,
Lorenza Patrica and then my head coaches
have switched probably two or three
times in the last couple of fights I
had Kenny Johnson from black house, um,
John Wood from syndicate. And now I have
George Hickman from Tiger Moy. Tai. Yeah.
And so this change that
you decided to make a,
did it come after the Johnnie Walker
fight? Yeah. So the Johnnie Walker fee,
like that camp was tough man.
Like I was doing so much to try to improve
in my wrestling and grappling because
that was always like a
big hole in my game. Um,
so I spent so much time wrestling over
at Black House with Kevin Casey and this
guy that I fought Blake troop.
They're huge and these guys are great.
Grapplers telling Casey's a powerhouse.
Yeah.
He'll put you into the ground and he feels
like cement block on top of you sells
old school. Hixon Jujitsu.
Exactly. How pressure, man. So, um,
yeah,
I would,
I would just grinding myself into the mat
every day for that camp expecting like,
okay, I'm comfortable on the feed. If it
goes to the ground, I'm ready. And um,
I, I think I just completely lost sight
of like my striking my Muay Thai in that
fight, his size, everything. I just kind
of froze up man. I was just like, ah,
I didn't know what to do, how to get
there. So let's all part of the education,
right? I mean this is what does
this career of fighting that you're,
you're on this path is
what it's all about. Yeah.
And fighting for me is like big
self awareness too. You know?
I think it's always important though
when a guy has set setback to see how he
responds. Some people get discouraged,
some people get encouraged,
some people just decide like they're
going to be much more committed.
And that's what you did.
You just mean making that move to do
your camp and Thailand and seeing how it
paid off.
I mean,
Eric Anders is a very tough customer
and you essentially shut him out. Yeah.
I mean, it was very, very
impressive man. That was the,
that was the plan though
because I knew he was tough.
He's tough with them before I sparred
with him before everything in like he's,
I've watched all of his fights.
The guy's hard to put it away.
We're making a case for the fight being
stopped. Yeah. We were making a case.
I mean DC was saying like we could stop
this fight. I was saying it, I was like,
you are fucking his legs up. I like,
this is about it. During the fight.
I wasn't like, I'm sure you weren't, but
that guy is so damn tough. He kept coming,
man. I mean he never stopped
trying to win that fight. Yeah.
There's no quit in him. None. I mean
even in the, in the Santos fight,
remembering that it was just
do or die tweets. He's like,
I haven't been that tired since like my
wedding night or something like that.
He's always got good good tweets after
the final shout out to Eric Andrews.
I love what Jon Anik said too.
He loves what he fights cause then
Bruce buffer has to say, your boy
boy, hey, why does it,
where does keep a suits? Man, he's got a
new suit. Oh, does a bad mother fucker,
dude. The insides of always has
like different decorations. Shit.
They commemorate different places
where we're at Bruce Buffer, he's,
he's got style. I just imagined him
have a level on his house just oh yeah.
You know what I mean?
Like you go to Nordstrom or something,
but his is just all the suits that
is warm before. I mean I'm less,
he donated so he might donate them
to charity. That might be one of the,
or auction them for charity or something
like that. That'd be good. Yeah. He's a,
he's a fun dude. He's the best
ring announcer of all time to me.
When that guy starts wailing and he gets
so pumped up serious, it's fucking hard.
Gets right. He's so intense, man.
Like if you watched boxing,
they're much more smooth.
Bruce buffer and do it, man. He digs in.
I remember seeing him first yelled at
like at Tj Dillashaw and he was like, oh.
I was like, Oh shit. It gives
you goosebumps. It really does.
It gives you goosebumps. Yeah. You just
feel as energy, right? You're just like,
I'm there waiting, ready for a
fight. Like I'm kind of nervous.
And then Bruce comes over like,
yeah, out of the blue corner.
You're like talking about dude who blew
his ACL out from jumping up in the air
while he was reading that name.
Oh my God.
She gets bruised here is fucked his
knee up from just getting crazy.
Oh Joe, really quick.
What do we got? Okay,
so remember I told you to turn
your air drop off during the show.
So I didn't want to
come here empty handed.
So I haven't slept in probably
24 hours more than 24 hours.
But last night I was drawing and I
know you like art. So I was like,
let me draw these illustrations for you
so I just want to send them to you. Okay.
So turn your air drop on. It's on. And as
soon as it comes through I'll send them.
But yeah, I really just
like, man, I just want to,
if you want to keep them, use them
for like wallpapers or post him up.
Whatever you want made this.
Yeah, I did all these man too.
That's what I look ridiculous.
Yeah, I did the little like
I'll put it on Instagram later. Cool man.
It's very cute when it looks like me.
I'm getting ugly as I get older.
I see pictures of me when I was younger.
You in the gym and you had this like
crazy for is I'll actually show you the,
the um, the actual one is really like
know what you're talking about. Yeah.
I was going crazy during the stupid chat
fitness challenge I was having with my
friends.
We were working out to six hours of
cardio a day trying to beat each other and
it's so stupid. That's what I was taking.
That patient has a good one. I was like,
yeah, let me, let me copy
that. So when you uh,
decide to move, you take it,
anybody with you, you go solo.
I'm going to start off going solo.
Um, I would like to get, you know,
my brother to come visit.
I'd like to get my mom to come out really
as many some out there. Yeah. Yeah. And,
and just cheap and just kind of
simple living. My, and my mom,
I don't think she's ever left the country,
so I think it'd be really
cool for her to go out there.
But at the moment I'm just really like,
this place is great for my career
right now, Greg from my training.
So I just want to get there asap
and get back to work. Sorry.
How do you account for
jetlag? Like, do you,
do you just,
uh,
like do you give yourself enough time
to adjust to the time difference?
You know what, the whole time I was
there I would, my sleep schedule was off.
I never adjusted,
so I was going to bed maybe 2:30
AM every morning then like get up,
run at five and then, you know, just
tired later. Get tired later. Yeah. Weird,
right schedule is all off.
And then when I came back it took
me like a week or two to adjust,
so I was disappointed how stupid
my body was, man. Hey dummy,
go to bed now. I'm telling you,
you just go to bed now. Like,
like I didn't know my body
had such a rigid schedule.
When you jack that thing sideways and
you're on the other side of the planet
that your body just really doesn't know
what the fuck is going on. Seriously.
And then for me being stuck in that
plane for so long. Yeah, it's like, yeah,
you too big for them.
A little seats too when you do that.
If say if you have a fight in Vegas,
I'm going to go from Thailand to Vegas.
Do you show up two weeks early?
Yeah. Well this is my first time.
I'm flying back to the states after being
in Thailand and I flew a week early.
No,
I flew two weeks early.
One Week I stayed in Vegas and then
fight week stayed in Atlanta and I think
that was perfect timing. Oh that's
good. So like you get a little,
a little difference in time between
those, whether two minutes, it's so hot.
Like we train outside and
it's humid and hot. So, um,
between every round it feels like, you
know, like the third round of a fight.
If we're going into the championship
rounds, I've never been there,
but I'd imagine that it
feel very shitty and uh,
that's how it feels
every round in Thailand.
It's just like you're covered
in sweat, hot, thick. Yeah.
That was probably like my fifth round
or something like that. And we do it.
I'll be dead by this point.
Shout out to the editor for making
me not look as tired as I was.
Yeah.
So what we're looking at folks for the
people who are just listening and it's a
bunch of videos of you training,
strength conditioning,
palling up against the the wall. So you
getting everything down there. Yeah.
And that's Joseph Hanley right there. He
was on the, uh, on the ultimate fighter.
I forgot what season they called them.
Leah Unitus,
he's a black belt out there and he
helped me out a lot. Man, there's,
you run into so many different people
and he's like, yeah, like black belt,
any type of grappling you want,
any positions you want to work,
like we'll go over it,
we'll create a system whenever.
And so he was really big help in this
preparation for this fight. Yeah.
A bunch of free spirits live in
that. Right. So many, so many.
But everybody's down there with a goal.
If they want to get in shape,
they want to get healthy or spiritual
path, whatever it may be. Yeah.
There's something romantic about the
ex pat living in Thailand having a good
time, you know, something romantic
about that. So it's interesting.
That's really cool. Yeah, I mean
that whole culture man, I mean the,
the tie and Moy Thai culture.
What a phenomenon.
If you look at combat sports and the
this one that it's so tied into these
stadiums, it's so tied into gambling
and netting. It's so, I mean,
kids get indoctrinated into it at a
very young age for young, super young.
There's, there's guys at the gym
that I was at, um, little kids.
They'd come right after school and they
go to Moitai training and their training
just like the older guys and then
they go right back to home, like home,
eat dinner. But that's just their
lifestyle. So it, it starts as a kid.
It's like go to school,
Moy, Tai, go sleep.
And then as an adult it's like Moitai feed
your family, Moy, Tai, feed your family.
These guys live at the gym at Jesus.
They live at the gym and they go home
maybe two days after a fight just to take
care of their families and then come right
back to the gym and get ready for the
next height. Now of course at Tiger
Moy, Tai, you know, you've guys,
everybody knows diff,
various people in different organizations,
UFC Bella tour, what have you, uh, one fc,
but what about those guys
that are fighting in those
little small tie gyms and
stadiums?
Like how much access do they have to
grappling or how good do they ever,
did they, are they satisfied to
just do more tires here at all?
Like a movement in Thailand,
especially at tiger. Um,
a lot of those guys are coming
over to the MMA and learning,
Jujitsu and wrestling. One of the guys
I was learning to clinch from, um,
he was like, um, he's got
probably 300 fights, um,
300 Moy Thai fights and he started
training MMA and taking him and may fight.
So it's death there. They're definitely
opening their mind to it and, and,
and hopping in there and there's access.
And Bangkok, it's a little different. Um,
cause that's very like stadium
based, you know, like high level Moy,
Tai and uh, they're not too focused on
in May, there are a couple of MMA gyms,
but if you want to do that, if you want
to get the best of both worlds, it's in,
it's implicate a tiger. So, uh,
is there any MMA at all in Bangkok?
Ah,
they got a couple places but nothing with
like at like pro fighters or any high
level fighters.
But they do have,
they do have maybe three or four MMA
gyms there with just guys stopping in or
guys who practice, you know,
a little bit of everything.
I'm always really interested in countries
that figure something out better than
everybody else when it
comes to leg kicking in.
Like nobody figured it out
any better than at the time.
It's like no one argues that right
now. Seriously. And their shins man,
like I think they're just,
that's done for,
they don't even feel the front of their
legs anymore because they can kick
anything and they're getting kicks
checked. There's guys that Joe,
they'll fight one night at the stadium,
go five rounds and then sleep and maybe
the next day go fight like another small
event or a smaller event sometime even
in the same night. And it's like, man,
aren't you like your shins?
Don't hurt your elbows. No
hurt, nothing in these guys.
They're just like, they're bulletproof.
They're used to this man. It's crazy. Wow.
And their first time in my life,
I go into a locker room and the red and
blue corner as both in the same room,
probably as big as the studio and
they're all getting their hands wrapped
together, getting massaged
out together. Everything,
no weird energy in the room like you know,
and UFC like they separate us. We have
to kind of be separate whatever purposes.
But like in Thailand, they're just like
hanging out in same room, you know,
talking, whatever, and then they just
go fight right after. It's so weird,
like the piece, it's, it's so weird man.
It was the first time I
experienced that and I was like,
maybe I can start lightening up a
little bit. Like that's only a fight.
And that's kind of something
I had to tell myself. Um,
for this one I had to like really fall
back and rely on my training because I
was really nervous. I
was nervous to start, um,
to try the new stuff that I learned out.
I never through many leg
kicks in any of my fights. Um,
I'd never really did that stance.
Everything that I did was pretty much
brand new. Um, and I was really nervous.
I was like, what if it doesn't work?
You know, like so many different,
so many different feelings.
And um, for this one, I,
the only thing I can tell myself was like
rely on your training and a few other
things. I actually got, um, I got
like hypnotized to before. Yeah.
Two who did too. Um,
and my friend Dominique,
he has, he has this, like I
met him through one of the,
um, one of the other UFC fighters.
Like Julian Marquez. I met him,
I met him through him and he's like, oh
yeah, I do like hypnotism, all this stuff.
I'm like, okay cool. I've done it
before. I did it in California and um,
so I think three weeks,
two or three weeks prior to the fight,
we had a few sessions a week where
just like helped me to really get that
visualization clear cause we have so
many thoughts all the time. Right.
And everything,
just like thoughts are constantly coming
in and to stay focused and to really
like,
like
get the outcome that we know, set
our intention to. It's Kinda hard.
So many distractions.
So when you go into his office in or
wherever you do it and you guys talk about
it, do you set a goal before
you start the session?
We do this thing called timeline therapy,
so it's like,
I'm just kind of sit in there
with my eyes closed and, um,
we kind of just do this,
we'll pick a subject, whether
it's like, you know, pain,
fear, you know, nervousness, something.
We'll just pick a subject, a feeling,
whatever's going on.
And um,
it's kind of just like a visual
timeline of like, where did this start,
where it come from, what's
the event, whatever.
And we kind of just talk about
that for awhile. And, um,
I just kinda dig to this place of where
the nervousness is coming from or where
the, you know, where the fear is coming
from or whatever. I kind of just,
I find a place on my timeline and I dig
from it, whether it's in the future,
the past, whatever, and then
when you get things clear.
And then, um, and then after
that he kind of helps me,
guides me into this like hypnotism,
which is really just like
a really deep relaxation.
If I wanted to open my eyes or something
like that, I feel like I could,
but I wanted to relax. I
wanted this to help, you know,
I wanted my vision to be clear.
So I did my best to just like
surrender to the process.
And I'd say it's not something where
I woke up and I was like, oh yeah,
my life has changed.
But um,
I can definitely remember the thoughts
that I had so that I can stay more on
like in that,
in that lane of what I wanted in my,
in my hypnotism actually visualized,
not winning the fight because I
didn't want to strive too hard to win.
Like it's just something that
I've been kind of studying.
It's like the outcome is not
really like the winning or losing.
I don't want to base too much on that.
I just want to put on
like a great performance.
So I visualized after one thing hand,
like just having my hands in the air,
seeing my brother smile,
my coach a smile and then slapping hands
with the crowd, um, on the way out.
And then I was also like,
and I want to see my wind bonus and my
show money and these are the things that
I wanted to see.
These are the outcomes that I wanted.
Not so much just I want to win the fight,
but the things that I like,
how I wanted it to happen
and having that vision clear,
it helped me.
And so like everything that I visualized
before that it happened, I was like,
cool, hands raised, slap hands with
everybody on the crowd the way out,
sign both my checks.
And that was like,
that was the end of it for me until the
next session until I want to get clear
on something else, you
know? It was cool. Wow.
So had you didn't
anything like that before?
Any mental coaching before the go comes
hockey fight? I did something very,
very similar. Yeah. With um,
with another guy I was at the
first time you'd ever done it?
First Time doing hypnotism.
Yeah, definitely.
And um, yeah, my friend
Matthias, he's here and uh,
he's really good too. And he
was just like, take some notes.
You kind of just have a conversation in
the beginning and everything comes from
your unconscious mind.
It's not somebody telling you something.
I just dumped out whatever my
unconscious mind was telling me.
He was just helping me to like relax,
be at peace and just listen
to like my unconscious mind.
Just unfold all of these kind of
like hidden answers that we all have,
you know?
So that's it.
Now when you get hypnotized and you're
thinking about a specific fight,
do you think about specific things
you're trying to accomplish?
Things that you think you'll do to him
that you'll have an advantage at or
strategy or like how do you,
those were thoughts that were
happening before my hypnotism,
but then all of those thoughts were
coming from the anxiety coming from the
nervousness. You get what I'm
saying? Yes. So it's like,
let's go back on the timeline to
why you're feeling nervous. Yeah.
Like all these things are happening.
They're going to you,
you're anticipating all of these things
happening and it's making you feel
nervous. So let's go back
to the nervousness and
revisit that. Why, you know,
and then when my subconscious,
my unconscious mind is just
like spewing things out.
And then after the process of
that mixed with the hypnotism,
I'm not even thinking about, oh, I'm
going to hit this arm drag or whatever.
I just, I'm thinking about having
my conscious clear in my mind,
clear and everything so that I
can get the expectation that like,
or the visualization that I created.
Yeah.
So have you tried different versions of
that or different styles of hypnosis?
Mm, no. Not that I can. I mean,
I've done a lot of just like closed.
I like emotional intelligence
type of like exercises,
you know,
like where I'm just like,
my eyes are closed and I have someone
helping me visualize internally,
you know,
like just whether it's dreams or
emotional pain or whatever it may be.
Yeah. I've had people just like
guided meditation almost. Yeah.
But the actual name, like hypnotism,
I've only had it done by two people.
Well, it as when you're
watching fighters, if you are,
I think fighters or one of
the most complex puzzles
for psychologists because I
think it's a super rare state, like the,
the rare state that someone gets to the,
where they can be completely calm
and see everything in the heat of a,
a dangerous encounter with
another train fighter. Yeah.
And when you're watching
these things play out on TV,
and you often times see how much
anxiety plays a factor or doesn't play a
factor,
how much someone having the,
I don't give a fuck attitude
for real at Ken play.
It can be a benefit and it
can fuck you up sometimes too.
And to see these complex psychological
puzzles play and see fighters struggle
and then regroup, have a bad fight and
come back better. All that stuff is like,
it's, it's really like a giant
microscope on the human character,
you know?
And like a guy like you who comes back
from the Johnnie Walker fight and looks
sensational against Eric Andrews.
Man,
it was like that was one of those things
you're like, I like what I'm seeing.
This guy, he figured some shit out
man. I mean like does that was,
that was incredible.
It was really fun to watch.
Matt is the guy who really loves Moy
Tai. It was fun to watch. Thanks man.
That was,
and that's,
that's kind of the goal too going forward
is that I want to continue to like put
on stuff like that,
continue to learn more Thai and then
cause that fight kind of raised the bar,
right? People are like,
Oh man, this guy for sure.
It kind of put me back on the map. So now
I'm ready to just go back and you know,
how many guys use mental coaches now?
If you had to guess.
A good handful. Good hand.
Yeah, a good handful I think.
I think a long shoreman Vinny
shoreman, he hypnotized me and he, uh,
he open houses a lot of fighters.
Yeah. Yeah. He's, yeah, it was a trip.
It was very strange. It was like, oh,
this is real. It's a weird feeling. Right.
How long ago was it?
It was the old studio,
so it had to be at least a year and a
half, maybe two years ago. Okay. Yeah,
it was pretty weird. But he's a
great mental coach too, though.
He knows like what's creeping around
your subconscious just waiting to pop up
and play tricks on you. You
know, you shouldn't eat. Sure.
You're putting enough rounds. Where does
he live? A, he's a UK guy. Okay. Yeah.
I kind of get linked up with him. I'm all
about it. I don't care anybody. I'm like,
yeah, whatever. You got any short
man? Let's go. Yeah, he's a good dude.
I'll connect you guys.
I think it's a,
probably one of the least trained aspects
of fighting is the mental aspect of
it. You know, you realize how good
guys are just by watching them train,
you see them spar, you see them
do all these things. Y'All have,
Tammy's got this guy's fucking good,
this guy's got great Jujitsu Guy,
great kickboxing. You ever hear
about the people that like they're,
they're saying's, right? Like,
man, that guy's amazing in the gym,
but when he shows up to fight it,
like he just doesn't put on like I've
been that guy multiple times. And like,
yeah, a lot of it has to
do with mentally. Yeah.
That's almost like an unaddressed
giant chunk of the puzzle.
Like a third of the puzzle I grew,
it was a pie.
A third is keep it
together. You know, like,
you know when it's ready to go
and now and it's all happening,
don't freak out. And you
never like, here's kind of
something that I think about.
You never know everybody's situation,
right? So the day before the fight,
we have weigh ins and then Dana comes back
and like, he gives us this, our speech,
right? So everyone there, you don't know
what life position they're in, you know?
So it's like, hey, there's a
potential, we can get a bonus.
So all those guys are affected emotionally
somehow. Yeah. You know what I mean?
Some guys, maybe they don't
care. Some guys, maybe they do,
but then like we walk out and then
there's a crowd, 15,000 people sold out.
Look around. We got Joe Rogan
sitting here, we got Mick
Maynard. Say We got Dana.
Why we got everybody sitting around
and then like, we're still human too.
So we're thinking like, this is
kind of like a test, you know?
It's like we got all the, we got the
whole board right here in front of me,
ready to take my test. You know,
like, yeah, it really depends on like,
there's so much that goes into it.
Like mentally,
you gotta be prepared for a lot of
things or some guys block it out,
but it's just like,
like anything else you had to know
about halfway into the first round,
some special shit was happening
though on this fight. Yes. Uh,
after, so after the first
round, I was very happy.
I sat down and my coaches were like,
okay, this is good. This is good.
You're doing this. And I was like,
listen, I don't want to know what's good,
what should I expect the next round.
Like I was ready to go.
I told us straight to George,
I'm like, dude, I don't care.
What do I need to do next? What
should I prepare for? And he's like,
prepare for a little bit more pressure.
He's probably going to try to shoot for
the take down this route. And I was like,
okay, cool. So that, I was just looking
for that and using my tools to kind of,
to just prepare for that. But, uh,
definitely midway through the
second round I was like, okay,
like I know he's still got a lot of power,
all this stuff,
but I think that that leg, I
should be able to, you know,
buy some time and take away a little bit
of damage, like coming at me forever.
He mean he had to be an agony and he
never stopped coming. Yeah. I mean,
like he didn't wince at all, like
even on the cage when I was just like,
when he was on the back and I was trying
to kick his leg, he just, his face,
his facial expression never change.
Fucking savage man. That's crazy.
He's a bad man. Respect that guy.
Yeah, for sure. For sure. For sure.
Even before, like even before
the fight. Before and after.
Yeah, for sure. Yeah. No,
maybe even more so man, not everybody
can do that. Not Everybody can take that,
you know? And to do it the way he did it
with 100%, it was a character in tact.
Never shirked never shied away from it.
Kept moving forward.
That's a dangerous person and he's
still getting better. Oh yeah.
Hell that guys just getting better.
Oh yeah. When you were doing,
how much do you think
the hypnosis helped you?
A really good amount, man.
How much different did you
feel like in what way? Um,
I just, I felt more clear. I'm,
I feel like a lot of times I can be just
kind of like an anxious guy. I just,
I feel like I feel a lot of just
energy, the kind of like, I don't know,
I go into a room and I'm
just like, eh. So having,
having the focus on having my intention
set on what I wanted to happen
was
70% like I know 70% of like the hypnotism,
all that stuff to just help me
to keep my thoughts on track.
Something never fall back onto every
single time if I felt like I was getting
distracted or getting nervous or
whatever, I would remember, you know,
the things that we went over and the
hypnotism and so every time just kind of
like the hit that reset button
or just a delete button on,
on thoughts that I just didn't want to
have or that would make me feel anything
other than happy and ready to go.
Now how often do you practice is
to practices outside of hypnosis?
Is there like some things you
concentrate on or meditate on? Yeah. So
I do my best to just,
it's Kinda like the weird thing about
me is fighting is something that is just
kind of happened by accident, but it's
caused me to search for so much peace,
like inner peace because of everything
that I go through emotionally being a
fighter. So going from this,
I know Shab told you about it,
but going from this kid who was just
like super overweight my whole life,
never fit in with anybody, I was always
just like this introverted, Gothic,
weird kid that nobody,
you know,
nobody ever talked to Dee
never even wanted to fight.
I've always been nonconfrontational,
but somewhere in the journey
of becoming a fighter,
I was like, ah, this is cool,
but I need to find more
peace because this is like,
it's bringing up way too much,
just like,
just way too much. My, of my
anger kind of like, you know,
from everything that I held onto.
So, uh, practice meditation,
a lot of meditation. I read a lot of
different, I'll study different religions,
whatever, wherever on that. Um,
all just to find peace,
man, confrontational guy,
wind up being an elite cage fighter.
Stop and thinking about what I know.
Yeah. It's, that's a very strong,
still trying to wrap
my mind around it, but I think that, um,
internally there's just a lot of,
there's a lot of expression for me it's a,
it is a big expression man.
It's an expression of just
my, my danger, my ferociousness
this, the, the, the,
the part of myself that I've
always held back. You know,
it's like I have to hold back. I'm, I'm a
big guy, you know, like I, if I get angry,
I'm afraid I can, you know, break
something and you're like, you know what?
It's like, it's crazy. So fighting for me,
like when I trained after training,
I'm super peaceful right after I fight,
I feel like I've grown.
I feel like this guy is trying to hurt
me. All these things, like it's, it's,
it's just a place where
we both agree like, Hey,
I'll give you my strength versus your
strength or whatever. Whatever power
is that strength is what we meet in the
middle. And so it helps me balance, man.
It does. Yeah. Because when I'm not
fighting, I'm, I'm so relaxed. It's crazy.
We'd make sense. And I think that
something that could aid a lot of men.
I think just at least training,
just a spa.
I think there's something particularly
soothing about hitting a heavy bag.
There's something particular
like when you're done, man,
you feel so good when you're done
hitting pads. We've done sparring.
You feel so just peaceful.
Yeah. You've got it all out.
You don't have anything
left in your mouth.
A lot of men carry a lot of
extra bullshit. Yeah, man.
A lot of dashes extra for no reason.
You got to let it out.
Let it out. Yeah. Some guys will
build it up in the gym. Right.
And they're super huge and it's like,
hey, you gotta let it out. Right.
They gave him swing those
arms. We didn't do it. Yeah.
You see less of that now too, it
seems like, but you know, it just,
it would be nice if,
I really think they should teach kids
how to fight at a very early age.
That'd be cool. I think it's the opposite.
It would have the opposite effect.
I think people would fight less.
I think if you taught kids how to fight,
they would just train and spar and they
would get it all out of their system
there and they'd probably
fight a lot less. It's an,
it's kind of like in our
nature, right? Like everybody,
everybody's kind of like a curiosity.
Like I wonder what it's like. Yeah.
The closest they have to
it is the wrestling team.
You can join the wrestling team and they,
they will teach you a very important
part of fighting. But other than that,
like they're not going to teach
you how to fight, but wrestling,
he's kind of like,
now at least it's kind of a loophole.
Like they don't teach
boxing in high school,
but they'll teach you how to wrestle
and that they're pretty crazy man.
And wrestling is getting rough. He seems
like, fuck yeah, yeah, yeah. I will swell.
The high school kids are savages.
I remember being a high school kid
and the high school wrestling room,
it was awful.
And those kids were trying to kill each
other and they work on the hardest to
running with plates over
their head and all that stuff.
And football teams just lifting
weights and running practice.
Those guys are doing ridiculous shit.
Slaven everybody's seen that move vision
quest, right? No, I've never seen it.
Never saw it. I've never seen it. Dude.
Oh it's Matthew Modine and Matthew Modine
plays this bad ass wrestler and he's
going up against this dude who's just
other bad ass wrestler and he comes to
visit the guy while the guys training
and this dude's got a log on his back and
he's walking up stadium
stairs and then he says,
you think you make the weight?
Cause he Matthew Modine's character
should have cut weight. And he goes,
I hope so. I hope so too. And
he keeps walking up the stairs.
Like when did this come
out? A long time ago, man.
Back when Madonna was young.
Oh cause that's the restaurant.
So He's walking up the stadium
stairs carrying a fucking log on.
It's a great movie, man. Every wrestler
that I knew when I was in high school.
Everyone worshiped this movie.
What year did the shit come out?
It's probably like 85 or so. That's
not the cover for it. Is it 85 Bam.
I nailed it, son. Is that
the cover for it? Yes.
You have anything to do with a wrestler?
I definitely would not click that
on Netflix thinking and I was around
restaurant movie at all.
She was hot as the sun to fun times,
but yeah,
that was like the quintessential wrestling
movie because he just was dedicated
and then it was his friend who lied
about being native American. Oh,
is that what that is?
I'm going to say what's that vest he's
got going and just wanted to be different.
Stand out. But it was a,
it was a fun movie, man.
It's so fun movie to get
into that for sure. Yeah.
Not a whole lot of movies about wrestling.
That's the least glamorous,
but probably toughest sport for high
school kids to get into. Definitely.
You know, that's why I stayed away
from him. You know, I tried out for,
I tried out for volleyball in high school,
actually made the team, but my grades
were terrible so I never got to play.
But I was like heavyset dude.
And I tried out. I made it.
I think it was just kind
of like a joke though.
I think the coaches were just
messing with me and my friends too.
When did you get involved in martial
arts? Uh, when I was 20, so 2010.
So it really quick.
Right after high school I started,
um, I started traveling. So
I used to play in a band.
I used to play a mini bands and willing
guitar. I play guitar, I play drums,
I play keyboard,
a little bit of everything.
Every Christmas my mom would just know
that just get me a new instrument and I
had locked myself in my room
and teach myself how to play.
And that's just always how like music
was my first love, my first love.
So I taught yourself.
Yeah,
I would just put on headphones and I
would just match the sounds and then keep
restarting the songs over and over again.
And then if it were like a keyboard song,
I'd play it like just on
the CD player and you know,
as it evolved and for
some reason I can just,
I can match tunes with
whatever instrument it may be.
You've always been able to do
that since a kid. Wow. Yeah.
So no formal training.
Nothing. That's great.
I've tried to take, I've tried to
take guitar lessons before, um,
but it didn't work for me and my mom
was just wasting your money like I was
learning, but it was kind of like
school for me. Like I had a teacher,
he saw me okay, this court and this
court and I was like, God, like,
just let me feel it. Like I gotta I gotta
feel it. You know, like I can hear it,
I can, I can feel it, I'll get
it. And so I stopped going.
But how many people do it
like, like that? I'm not sure.
I know there's a lot of people that
can just kind of play by ear, but,
so I'll like,
I just love instruments.
I'll pick anything up and
just start playing it and
ended up teaching myself how
to play drums,
bass guitar keyboard.
I played the standup Bass
and uh, in middle school, um,
I've got like a little home production,
like beats studio at home, all that stuff.
So after high school I
started touring and uh,
that's when like I started
getting my heaviest.
We were eating fast food every single
day, three times a day, never drank water,
soda,
only smoking like a pack and a half of
cigarettes a day and just on the road
traveling. And then, uh, by
19, I got up to 305 pounds,
19 years old.
And I remember one night laying down
to go to bed and I just felt my heart
pumping ridiculously and I was
just like, no way. This like,
I think I'm going to die.
And like I woke up in a panic and
weird thing is I got up and I went
outside for maybe like 10 minutes and I
smoked another cigarette and I was
just like, this is the problem. Like,
I'm coughing up stuff my hardest going
to give out and I'm only 19 years old,
you know?
So around that same week is when
I discovered MMA with my brother,
just like watching ultimate
fighter on TV. And so, uh,
I went on my last tour and
uh, I told the guys like, Hey,
I'm going to go train him and made it
look, oh, you're going to be a fighter,
like you think, you know? And I was just
like, I don't know what I'm going to be,
but I'm going to go train and get
healthy. And they're like, okay, cool.
We'll see you in a couple of
months. You know what I mean? Like,
no one really believed that I was going
to go and actually train and fight.
I told you, I said, well,
he's been like this big quiet
nonconfrontational guys. So,
um,
yeah,
I went and took my first class
Moyie Thai and March 1st,
2010 it took my first Moy Tai class and
then after like a month of doing Muay
Thai,
I started to see progression.
I started to see like my face
was slimming down all this stuff.
So it gave me motivation to
keep going. And then, um,
I remember going to a MMA event amateur,
and I saw really big heavyweight
guys going at it. So I was like, ah,
I think I want to do it. I want to give it
a shot. And uh, some of my coaches like,
okay, if you lose a hundred pounds,
I'll like, I'll find you a fight.
And I was like, a hundred
pounds. He's like, yeah,
I'll find you a fight if you
lose a hundred pounds. So, um,
I just kept training within 11 months,
lost a hundred pounds,
and then took my first fight.
And then she got like every fight has
been until now because it's like now I
have like more of a drive and a passion
for it, but all the way up until then,
everything kind of happened. By
coincidence. They're just like, I just,
I didn't really want to fight, but I had
a lot of people like, oh, you're so good.
Like keep doing it.
And I was a first time in my life.
I've ever had people supporting me to
like really do something that was big and
I was a new guy and I was in shape and I
can, you know, girls are noticing me now.
I'm like all either my whole life
changed within a year of training MMA,
like wow. From going to this
guy that nobody even paid
attention to, to just like,
oh hey, how's it going? Are you
know, like, oh, you're so in shape.
And I was just like, oh, this
is weird. It's still weird.
It's only been nine years,
eight years, you know? So everything
is still very new to me. I've only,
my first day stepping on the mat
was like, you know, nine years ago.
Dude, that's an amazing story. It's crazy.
That's like a legit success story. Yeah.
You know, it says that you will get a
ridiculous ring tone. Do you have sir?
Is that so I thought I turned it off.
What is that?
It's just like stock iPhone,
Apple Rico.
You ventured into the options? Yes, sir.
Um, so yeah, that's like, that's
kind of how everything started.
And then with three,
five,
three or four fights and then I tried out
for the ultimate fighter so I had like
three or four fights in one year of
being a pro and a and then the ultimate
fighter trials came out and I like tried
off of that and made it on and I was
like, Oh shit. So most of my career
has been in the UFC. Wow. Yeah.
Is that like when you hear about fighters?
Uh,
particularly boxers you hear like a really
well managed boxer will get fights to
test them but with a guy that you could
beat and you learn it in a different
thing from each different fighter as
you move up the ladder and way more of
them are undefeated when they finally get
a shot at either a title
or a top contender,
but an MMA you could be fighting the top
level guys within a couple of years of
joining and he could honestly be a
couple of years prior to that if you're
particularly talented where you
picked up martial arts like in Ghana,
perfect example. Perfect.
Francis and gone.
It was like an incredible example because
he's really only done and then a for
five years and he's still right
now the scariest guy in that cage.
When he act, when he's throwing
bombs away, it's like you just,
you just let go hook up.
When he knocked out Overeem that was a
UN un that was an unheard of knock out.
Yeah. I sparred with him and like
in preparation for that fight, oof.
And I actually almost got hit with that
same punch. But yeah, we went, Frances,
I and I went three rounds in the cage
and then I remember a forest was there
and, and, and John, the head coach of
syndicate and uh, they were like, okay,
you guys tone it down because we were
going at it and I'd be like, oh, it's fun.
Like I like to go hard, but um, how often
though, how often? I like to go hard.
Yeah. Every now and then. Yeah.
Every time to mostly technical.
Yeah. So like entirely right now
it's like everyday technical,
one day sparring or one or two day
sparring. And when you say sparring, MMA,
sparring, sparring. Yeah.
And then the other days are just like
technical grapping grappling and technical
striking and then, you know,
wrestling and then uh, yeah,
well spot on Fridays now
when they break it up. Um,
did you have someone who makes your
schedule for you? Like for the week,
do you have all your training routines?
Like what,
what your schedule set up for
morning, evening. Do you have that?
Yeah. So advance. So they
had like, so for instance,
like the gym has a schedule of
all the classes, but um, the,
the head MMA coach George
would help me out. Like, Hey,
if you're getting ready for a fight,
show up to these,
these and these and I'll help you. And
almost like a curriculum. Yeah, yeah,
exactly. So that actually helped.
And the cool thing about it is like,
everything was in line.
So like whatever I worked with
him personally in the morning,
we'd still be going over and practice
and even in the night practice,
so getting the same
things, like, you know,
multiple times a day instead of just one
time and then you'll get it again later.
Yeah.
And when you're your training over there,
you said you like 50 to 60 professionals.
I've seen so many guys on the
mat. Yeah. And I'd say on a very,
very low day,
20 like so many people,
so many people, guys and girls, man.
And how much your time are you
spending striking versus grappling?
Do you specialize in one
thing or the other? Well,
I can train grappling all
day and never get bored.
And like even if I'm tired
I can still do it. Um,
but then like grappling, I do it a
lot of the times because I like it,
but it's mandatory and it's, and
it's my job, so I like, okay,
I'm going to go to grapple and class.
But um,
it seems like it's an even balance,
but I love to go to striking
more because it's just like,
that's my favorite thing. Um, yeah.
So one striking class
one grappa and class one,
him and may class all in
one day type of thing.
So like two hours a piece
and then conditioning and
running and all that stuff
in the Middle East. That's one
whole day. Yeah. Jesus. Yeah. Well,
the MMA classes more like,
so there's a class of MMA,
one personal going over like my specific
things that I like to work on and want
to work on. And then maybe
whoever's mimicking the opponent.
And then in the morning,
Moy, Tai, some. For me,
it's always great to start the morning
off with more Moitai wake up first thing,
have coffee, do my five,
sixK run, train way,
tie for two hours, eat, go do
MMA personal and then do the MMA class
at the end and then go relax after that
routine for me can work every day.
And he does. Everything's disciplined.
Like to do the same thing every
day is very common in Thailand.
And I think that that's why
I was able to put that, um,
that performance on and use that many
kicks because we throw so many in one day,
you know what I mean? What's different
about the training then? There's not,
there's not really class.
It's like for MMA,
there's not much talking and tie and
Moitai there's no talking, you know,
it's like they tell you what to do a
little bit like Punchkick knee deep five
times, 10 times, 20 times, you know,
like it's a lot of repetition and the
same thing in the, in the MMA class,
George gives us a lot of um,
time to drill and drill out our own pace
and things like that before we go live.
And I think that that's what's
helped me the most, is less talking,
more drilling, show me one or two
things were mixed martial artists.
We're going to create something
off of it. It's okay. And um,
and just let us drill it. Let us drill
it, walk around co correct if you need to,
but I think people need to spend
more time drilling on the mat,
go live every now and then just
so you can feel what you're at.
But the only way you're going to get good
is by drilling. It has just not as fun.
Exactly. It's training. I don't
think training should be fun.
You could tell a dog to sit a hundred
times, you got to give him something like,
you know, some type of
treats, the promise, certain
parts of training our fund.
Right. Which is probably one of the
reasons why you like striking. Exactly.
It's fun. That part for me. I can
just, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. It's um,
it's,
I really believed that psychologists
should study fighters study high level
fighters had,
try to figure out what makes them tick
because there's all these different
versions.
You're a different version.
You the 300 pound God had sides lose all
this weight and now you one of the best
fighters in the 205 pound division.
And it's crazy, man. I mean, that's a,
that's a wild story at be really cool
though. Yeah. Yeah. Maybe you'll get one.
Psychology studies on fighters is almost
mandatory because there's certain guys
that like, they're just impenetrable.
You know, there's certain guys that just,
they just like could beep the
Zim. Penetrable yeah. Like
you're not the more shit.
You talk more. He's gonna fuck
you up when he gets a hold of you.
Like it's not working, man.
It's not getting in there.
And then there's certain guys that like,
sometimes they're hot and sometimes
they get rattled and you know, it's,
it's a crazy endeavor what you guys do. It
really is. Yeah, it definitely has been.
I think a documentary or something
would be really cool too. Yeah.
I think a lot of people in the fans need
to see kind of a little bit more of the
inside, the real stuff, you know?
Yeah. The, the, the real stuff.
Like one of the craziest responses that
I've been getting lately is people have
hit me up on Instagram and like,
I can't believe you're just a normal guy.
Like you're posting songs and, and you
know, like doing all that, I'm like, yeah,
I'm,
I'm a human just like everybody else.
Like I think a lot of
fans kind of forget that.
I think we as fight or
sometimes forget to like, hey,
like for a little bit you can shut
it off and get normal. You know,
it's uh, I mean the, the balancing act is,
it's a strange thing to ignore,
you know,
the balancing act that a
fighter has to have with their,
their personality with training and
competing and then just being a normal
person and the highs and the lows and
managing all the stress of an upcoming
fight. And you just sort of asked to
go it on your own like, hey, good luck.
Keep your shit together.
Yeah.
And the face of flying fists and it sucks
too because the higher we go up then
it's just like, it's Kinda hard
to go anywhere behind. Right.
It's like we're working to get to the
top as fighters and when we want to be
known and, and but like
the more, the more,
the higher that we go,
the more like obligations media people
want to talk to you, all this stuff.
So your time kind of gets short. I was
thinking about it last time, like damn,
like getting to the tops going to
kind of suck media like, you know,
media week or fight week
for everybody at the top.
They're like press conference,
this, that, that. And I'm,
I'm the type of guy where
like just like relaxed,
so I'll definitely need like
a psychologist or something
that helped me out with
me more hypnotism for sure.
I would,
I don't know how much they do at the UFC
performance institute and t for as far
as mindset training. Do they
do any of that over there? Um,
not that I'm this guy that I've
seen when that place is insane.
If you have chance to train there at all.
I did it. I did to fight camps there. Oh,
when I used to live in Vegas. Yeah.
And it, it's amazing. It's crazy play.
It was like,
it was like a little too good for me.
Like I started feeling like a little
bit spoiled, you know what I mean?
I was like,
I got to go right out in the street.
Like I can't run out of
these nice treadmills, Moon.
I mean to have a place like that where
the company creates this super high level
training environment that there's not
another gym like it on the planet earth,
on the planet. So I just decided like,
hey, go ahead and work out there for free.
Seriously. It's pretty, oh, you want a
protein shake? Okay. Want the food? Like
whatever you need, just
live here. Yeah, it's, look,
it's a great way to keep guys on track
with their weight cuts to, you know,
I'm very informational that place. Like
they, they've taught me so much. Yes.
You know, just about recovery
and what to do afterward.
Um, you know, they're,
they're investing a lot in just like
different programs for us to take home so
that we can make sure that, um, like our
nervous system is good for the next day.
Like they're putting so much stuff into
figuring out how to help the fighters.
You know what? I was tripped out by man
that uh, that underwater treadmill. Jamey,
isn't it an amazing, did you want on it?
No, I didn't know how you got to do it.
It's sick. I was, I was wearing my
clothes. I wasn't going to jump in there,
but I was like, what? Look at this is
crazy. This thing. It's sick. Yeah.
I did it a few times. What does it
lose it good for your cardio? Uh, it's,
it's low impact on the joints, right?
So like it's all, yeah, you'll,
you'll get it real good cardio.
Really real good cardio push on it because
there's jets blowing at you and the
the truck terminals on the bottom.
So you're trying just to not,
you're running against the water.
Oh Wow.
And so like depending on how deep you
go, your arms, that's all resistance.
Oh show. You can go just waist
level and it's a little bit easier.
But the lower you go, the harder it is.
Wow. Cardio. Did you do the zero gravity?
I didn't do any of the things there.
I just looked at him that he just gave
you the door Chris and gave me the four
one one. Yeah, they've done a lot.
It, when's the last zero? Grab it.
It's been awhile maybe.
Or what was the zero gravity.
So there's a treadmill and you put these
pants on and then you just zip into
this like you zip into it.
Oh, I did see them in the,
you turn it on and it
fills up with this air.
And then you can run up to
like 10% of your body weight.
So you, it's just like, it's another
zero gravity, like the treadmill.
It's not low impact, low impact,
super low. And you can get all the,
so you're just like tippy toes just
like, oh, that's so weird. Yeah. Yeah.
That's really weird. Yeah. They
got a lot of cool stuff, man.
While they're at the forefront of all
recovery methods and training methods and
Tricia. Yeah. And you see what
they're doing for us on fight week.
What are they doing? So this last
fight, um, they were like, Hey,
do you want any help? Do you have your
meals prepped or anything of that?
I was like, no, I don't. So
I guess for people that are
fighting within us for now,
um, they'll, they'll prep
and make everything for,
for fight week when you're cutting
weight and I'll make sure, wow.
Like you stay in contact with, with the
guys, Clinton, them, and they'll, uh,
check your weight and then they'll
make meals according to you.
Like whatever you need, deliver them to
your room. That's understanding. It was,
it was the best.
And then the recovery afterwards,
they give you these drinks all like
Usada approved, all that stuff.
It's like no problems.
They help,
they help so much with that last
weight cut and uh, and rehydration.
How much do you cut this fight?
I cut
1919 pounds and that's a lot.
Usually I usually cut
maybe four to seven pounds.
The last couple of fights I've just,
I would just coast it,
but when I went to Thailand,
there's a lot of sugar and a lot of
stuff that I was eating out there.
Is that really what it was?
Yeah,
when I was in Bangkok for a long time
and it's just a lot of street food,
a lot of fried food and stuff.
And I was just there and I'm like,
I'm going to try everything.
So once I got to Pooh cat,
they actually have like health food stuff,
Vegan stuff.
They have a lot of tourists there.
So especially on the street.
So the street that Tiger's on all gyms,
it's like five or six crossfit gyms,
maybe 10 restaurants, health,
food, restaurants, everything.
So I was able to stay on track there. So
just, I was just back just a few weeks.
Yeah. But I still may weight,
so that's good. That's a
lot of weight to cut though.
Right? You like to cut look about five
or six is that what yeah, yeah, yeah.
No more than eight.
Like eight is pushing it for me.
So like what difference do you feel?
Uh,
the day after I didn't with their
rehydration method, I felt amazing.
Usually if we're cutting that much,
I'd feel a little bit bloated,
little heavy sleep, beer, all that stuff.
But this, when you, you're talking,
did you ever do ivy or
would you did do ivy? Yeah,
when I used to fight in the RFA and um,
at one 85, I used to fight and win 85.
Oh my God. Yeah, that's
ours. Oh, I used to cut from,
I tried to get as close to 200 as possible
and then cut the 15th super skinny,
200, two terrible. Oh, terrible.
I'm struggling to make two or five
[inaudible] not struggle, but like,
it hurts to make two or five now. So I
couldn't even imagine like, oh it sucked.
So what would you think about if
they abandoned weight cutting?
Mm, they just opened up more weight
classes and abandoned week cutting.
I mean I wouldn't mind it. I
would, I would like to see that.
Do I think it would be
better for the fighters?
I think it'd be better for the fighters
and we'd see some really cool matchups
yeah.
You know what I mean?
Cause there's some guys I cut a lot of
weight and there's some match ups that
would be really cool at,
at different weights too.
I think it's one of those dumb things
that's existed in the past and we never
corrected. I think, I
think we should stop it.
It's not helping anybody to lose weight
for a fight so that he could be fit and
in great shape. Yeah. Okay, sure.
But how do you go about that?
But I mean losing weight,
like losing weight and training,
not like massive dehydration for weight
cut day and then rehydration to the next
day for fight day.
I think it's,
it's a crazy strain that guys are doing
to their kidneys. And their bodies.
I mean,
many fighters have told me that they
don't feel like they can take a body shot
as well when they cut a lot of
weight sometimes the your head,
my head, I remember on the Johnnie
Walker fight, I'd cut, excuse me,
it could have been from the Weight Cup,
but that morning,
like if I've been tapped on my jaw just
felt like my head was just like off like
randomly, you know? Yeah.
It felt very sensitive and he does from
the weight and the same night I get
knocked out.
I don't know what it was from,
but I remember that morning when I
woke up because usually I like a shake
everything off. I'll like, you know,
like punching myself in the jaw,
all that stuff just to
get ready for the fight.
And I remember that that morning when
I was like tapping myself on the jaw,
my head just didn't feel right.
Dude. That's not a good feeling. No,
but I got to checked after I didn't
have any like concussion or anything.
Did you have some particularly
hard sparring session or
something close to that?
Uh, I don't think close to
it during that camp. Uh,
like I said, I didn't feel it all the
way until I didn't have it. The only,
the only time I ever felt it
was like after the weight cuts.
So it could have been
from that. Right. Yeah.
And I think that morning I actually ended
up cutting the last little bit of my
weight, the morning of weigh ins
too, which is not usually like me.
I'll usually cut it the night before.
So you said you like to start
your day off with a run. Um,
are you doing that every
day? Yeah, definitely.
So that's one thing that I learned too
is just training every day. Not Learn,
but it just feels different now I have
to go and train every day when I was in
Vegas, like, oh, I got to drive 30
minutes, you know, all these things.
I had a lot of excuses to make up.
And now with the convenience
of how training is now,
I don't even make up excuses. I'm like, if
I'm tired, I still, it's two minute walk,
get your ass to the gym. You
know? And so yeah, every,
every single day training and
then weekends off for sure.
So you're running every single day,
then you're training every single
day before Moitai it's mandatory.
You run like the train, train, train and
we'll see. You run first. You show up,
you run the day. The first
day I showed up, uh, at,
at Tiger's Moy Thai class.
I didn't even have tennis shoes.
I just showed up with my flip flops
because I was staying right across the
street and I showed up. I start wrapping
my hands and the trainer, he's like,
are you going to train? And I was like,
yeah, I think so. He's like, you think so?
We'll go run. And I was like, I don't
have shoes. I only have my flip flops.
And he's like just pointed like so go run.
And I had to run like,
I think it was like eight kilometers in
flip flops before I can even train. Yeah.
That's like four miles.
Yeah, right. Somewhere around
there. Five and a half. Yeah.
It's like for like four miles, something
like that. We just had to run, run, run,
run, run, run. I asked the girl
was like, how long do we run? Four.
She's like usually like five to six
kilometers or something like that. Yeah,
it was like five ks. Like three and half.
Yeah. I'd say like just cutting it short.
Five K wow. And in, in flip flops and
I was like, okay, cool. Yeah, I never,
I never forgot my shoes again. I would
always show that that fuck your feet up.
It wasn't too bad. Actual, no, cause I
wasn't wearing shoes a lot anyway. Oh yes.
Thailand sometimes you had to take off
your shoes before he entered the store.
So.
So they're,
they're hard assed in their discipline
with the wanting you to get serious about
it. Yeah, they're just serious about
it. They're like show respect, you know?
And when you're running and you're
running with a group of guys or everybody,
guys, girls, whoever shows up to
class. But is it is like, okay,
so that when they're running,
are they running like a organized,
like in a group or are they just,
is everybody running a few miles
before class every time? The first,
the first Moy Thai gym that I trained at
the straight Moitai. Hi Jim. In Bangkok,
they run as a unit every
day 5:00 AM. Wow. As a team.
They live at the gym, they eat of
the gym, they sleep in the gym.
They are like,
they don't have homes there.
Home is the gym and their job
is just fight and eat, sleep,
train, fight. That's it.
It's crazy when they, they even take
on the name of the gym. Yeah, exactly.
And that's a whole different life.
Like that is what made me respect and
learn and love Moitai so much as how these
guys trained in just, they lived
together, everything. It was amazing.
So they run as a group,
but the other like the other place
we all start off. But if you,
if someone's laughing you and they
just want to run fast, like it's,
it's totally fun. But before the
class everybody has to go. Yeah. Wow.
That's a smart way to do it,
man.
I mean if you could really convince
them to be conditioned all the time and
there's no like you have no option.
You can't be out of condition if you're
going to run five miles every day,
no five miles. And then hitting, kicking,
hitting and kicking pads for five to 10
rounds a day, clinching 45 minutes a day,
like clenching at after every session.
It's like you run knee bag, sit
ups, all that stuff. Second,
second session is um,
kicked the bag three to five rounds until
a trainer picks you up. Like for me,
I had to wait for a trainer to actually
even like want to hold pads for me.
If you just show up, you'll
just be hitting the bag
until the trainer was like,
Hey, okay, I'll hold for you.
And then once you actually find a
trainer that wants to work with you,
then you kind of,
whatever their schedule is for you that
they'll create it though you'll hold,
they'll hold pads, you'll kick
the bag, you'll do pushups.
He'll do sit ups and then clench 30 to
45 minutes after and it's the same thing
every single day.
Wow.
Do you ever worry that this might be
something that would be monotonous because
he doing the same way every day?
Or did you think we just concentrate
on excellence? No, because it's also,
uh, like going to the fights and
there's so many different styles.
So like people are doing the same
thing every day. The repetition,
but the styles are completely different.
You know,
like nobody fights like
San Chai. Right, right.
He does the same thing everybody else
does. But he has his own style. Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Or some guys will do the same thing,
but they don't even like to kick or knee.
They just like to throw elbows and hell
plenty guys like that where they just
like, you know that when
he goes, he's just throwing
elbows all five rounds. Yeah.
This guy's just going to
throw. Nice. So it's just like,
which tools do you use the beds? Like
are you a near, are you at a kicker?
Are you an elbow guy? You left
cake, are you a low kicker?
It's kind of like what's what
strikes are your are your thing.
And then you go watch the chaos and
these guys are getting split open every
night fucking on the stretchers. They
take them stretchers on the ring, man.
It's amazing. Wow. It's like
not to see someone get hurt,
but like just the fact that like these
guys are all out brawl in every night.
Every single night there's a
fight at the stadium. Sure.
Thursday nights are the nights that like
the like the higher guys go and they're
packed with people. Thousands of
people. Like the one I went to,
there was a few thousand
people there for the stadium.
It looked pack and
everyone's betting like Ah.
And then when the kicks land I'm
like, oh hey. And the energy is crazy.
They never showed up, man. I'm
getting hyped. Thinking about again,
going back to Thailand right now,
how did San Chai figure out how to do
more different than anybody? Ah Man,
he's so interesting with as quick switches
of the feet and like even the way he
throws kicks is yet Skyler a little
different flavors, everything.
He doesn't think he can help it,
you know what I mean?
There's just something about the
guy's character. It just like his,
his fighting is him. Right. You know,
like he's just, he's kind of outgoing,
like this is a weird, funky guy and it
makes sense that he fights like that.
You know what I mean? It's not like
he's just like serious, like stern guy,
but then goes out there
and fights on crazy.
Like he seems like his fighting is
definitely an expression of himself.
He's so good, man. Yeah. He's so good. I,
I like watching him just warm up sneakers
on outside sweat and thrown elbows and
knees and everything. He's a bad
motherfucker, man. And he's, you know,
he's not young. No, I think he's in
his forties is he? Yeah. Really? Yeah.
Can we look,
help hold Sanchez 38 he's getting there.
It's getting there. But
meanwhile, I was in his prime.
He's still fighting people up all the
times a month, multiple times a month,
have fight. Good luck that
shows this and like dynamite.
This Instagram was awesome,
man.
And he's got these great videos of
him warming up and you watch him,
his movement, man. It's like, wow,
that guy's, he's something special.
It takes a lot of fucking energy to
move around the way he does too. Yeah,
I'm sure he still shows up to
the gym every single day to,
she's like holding pads for
foreigners and all that stuff.
I stopped by y'all couch him. He
wasn't there. But I hear like there is,
I look at that guy,
the fucking man right there.
He just posted a video the
other day where this crazy wig
go to CP. If I have video of him. There
it is right there. Look at this guy.
Ah,
even how he throws his Kik. It's
different. It's so different. Yeah.
Like he doesn't really like turn all of
his upper body. Like a lot of them went.
I've seen, right. He's, he's a volume guy,
but he knocks guys out with one shot to
look at that catch instinctual, you know,
like he didn't even think about it. Didn't
even flinch. He's so jacked up swipe.
It's interesting.
We think of how many different people
are doing it and that this one guy stands
out. I love outliers, man.
So that's one thing that I learned
compared to like watching Moy Thai in the
states and then going there at the amount
of kicks and knees at they're throwing,
hmm,
okay.
I'm looking at fighting like, okay, like
what does the next punch going to happen?
These guys thrown kick after
kick after kick for five rounds.
I was like, okay, I'm, I'm
definitely not kicking enough
so I got to start kicking.
So I they like being in Thailand.
Definitely.
I'll be to learn the
importance of kicking.
So we were talking about the shoot
box style Hockfield Cordeiro who is
absolutely one of the best
striking coaches on the planet.
It's funny that he's such a nice guy
and he trained the most murderous crew.
Angela
could not be nicer.
They had Anderson Silva,
they had Vandelay and Vandelay shogun.
Look at that photo. Yeah, dude,
that's a fucking Timbo. Another
one. It's got like Pele. Everybody.
That's where I said pay like two.
They were so I'm the guy
who taught Michael Costa. He
was, he was from that same,
that same group
to this day.
Do not understand why more times not
more popular. I've never understood it.
It's so exciting to watch.
Yes.
I was like if we had a league in America
that people understood who the fighters
were,
got to know him and root for him and see,
you know like you see with boxing with
Terrence Crawford, you know, he's like,
is that this piece of prime right now?
You know, he's on top of the world.
I want to see a guy like that in white
tie and I think it would be the same
thing.
I think Americans would jump on board
if they understood how exciting it is.
Yeah. You see a lot of, you see
a good handful of foreigners and Americans
in Thailand to go watch Moy Tai and I
thought the same thing like man, they
got to get this. Let's figure it out.
Let's figure it out. What is
he missing? What's missing?
Dana white has a good point to things
that culturally we won't accept kickboxing
after PKA karate from like the 1980s
remember before my time, but that's it.
This town was born 90 it was guys would
throw like these little kicks so they
had to throw like eight kicks around,
you know,
and then they would have
like a sloppy boxing match.
Some of the time there's some really
good guys that fought in there too,
like real high level guys like penny jet
or Kitezh Font Pka and you know a lot
of like really, really
good strikers. But it was,
there was nothing compelling
about it. Yeah, it just wasn't,
it wasn't something that you
wanted to watch all the time,
but if you could watch some of the best
Muay Thai fights that you've ever seen
and you could watch them on television
just like it show people on television,
some crazy wars that you and
I have seen from the past.
Like how could you not like
that if you like striking.
How could you not like guys who are
experts in bone smashing? They would.
That's why
I have a lot of love too for like I'm
a huge one championship pin. Me Too.
I'm a huge one championship.
Yeah, I like what he's doing. I,
luckily he's mixing all
three of them together too.
It's amazing because like you
can literally go to a fighting,
see the good MMA match. You if you, if
you like grappling and file and striking,
obviously,
and you can see legit Moy Thai fighters,
like my friends from the stadiums
are fighting in Bangkok on the 10th.
So like really
like I can't wait because I really want
to get there by the 10th to go see this
one championship event in Bangkok. Wow.
That guy, one of my friends like pet.
Damn. He's uh, he's a,
a stadium like champion and he's fighting
one championship again. And it's like,
it's, it's just sick to seaman. Yeah.
I don't think people understand how
big it is an Asian either. Well,
there's a lot of American fans that are
just really, they're missing it. Yeah.
It's like Asia Asia's version of the
UFC. It's gigantic vigor. Yeah. Yeah.
The numbers are insane. And they got
some fucking killers over there. Yes.
They got some legit killers.
Yeah.
That's like that Guy Nasty Ucan who
just knocked out a Eddie Alvarez. Yup.
I tried to tiger dude,
that guy's legit. Yeah,
I remember to train with him at
all. No, I would like alongside him.
I didn't personally try it with them,
but I remember one day we were doing a,
we were training and he was the last one
on the mat. And uh, our wrestling coach,
frank was like,
he's like,
he said something like 10 more sprawls
and like you beat Eddie Alvarez or
something and the guy's just grinded
like he's just digging himself into the
Maddie. It was, it was cool to watch
him prepare for that fight. But there's,
there's guys like that that's like,
yeah,
he trains there all the time and he'd beat
Eddie Alvarez. Like that's a big deal.
I think it's a big factor over there too,
that they don't cut weight.
I think that's a big factor if you're
used to being the bigger fight or all the
time, and then all of sudden now you're
not now, no one's cutting any weight.
I mean, they, they have
some sort of a system.
Ben Asked her and was explaining it to me.
I don't really remember how it works,
but there's some sort of a system where
they stop you from white cutting. Yeah.
Like they check your hydration,
check your hydration levels,
yet you gotta be a way to do it. That's
the right, he's correct. He's smart.
It's the right way to do it. We should've
done it a long time ago in the UFC.
I really think that all the
weight cut issues, all that
stuff, like ruining cards,
all that, it would all be
eliminated, right? Yes.
Ruining cards and even more importantly,
I think causing fighters to fight
it less than their full potential.
How many fighters got hit when they
shouldn't have gotten hit because if they
were recovered completely,
if they didn't have to a,
not recover completely, but if they
didn't have to recover from a weight cut,
I mean who knows?
Maybe there's shots you ate because that
you wouldn't have eaten. Yeah. Right.
Especially if you were some guys
cut in a brutal amount of weight.
It's entirely possible that you could get
hit with something you wouldn't if you
didn't have to cut weight. Yeah.
Right. We got five more often.
The training would be a lot better
too because we wouldn't like a lot of
fighters spending the last three weeks,
four weeks of their fight or their
cap just trying to weight lose weight.
It's the whole way that
project of learning and
building strength and all that
stuff that you could do. So I
dunno. I think it'd be awesome.
The only argument for it is that the
guys are tough enough to do it and cut a
shitload of weight,
have this massive size advantage and
sometimes it allows them to win and they
think they should be able to do it because
they're tough enough to cut all that
weight. Yeah, I get it. I mean it
does. It's hard to do. You have
to be a strong person, but I just
don't think it's good for anybody.
I don't think it's good for the athletes.
I don't think it's good for the sport.
I don't think it's good for anybody.
It's just an old way.
It's just an old thing that people are
doing so they don't have to fight the
bigger people.
You know?
It's crazy because I have to answer that
question a lot for people who don't,
like, some of my friends are just
like, oh, like they'll hit me up like,
hey am I can't talk this week.
Like I got to cut weight.
Like it's not a good time.
And they're like, how do you,
how do you lose 20 pounds in a day
and why do you do that? You know?
I'm just like,
I don't know how to explain it.
It's just because that's what we
do. You know? There's not really,
it's just what I have to do.
When you see certain fighters get on
the scale though, like Conor Mcgregor,
when he made one 45 crazy,
looked like a,
like a Zombie mass walking dead character.
I was like,
Holy Shit Man. He looks like the ice king.
Yeah. What's that? No, the winter king.
He said, what do you call them? The, the
night came the nightclub, that night cake.
He did look like the Nike. But did
you see him when he fought at, uh,
when he fought Nate? Nate, that once Tony
look great, you look great. Right, right.
There's a difference.
Yeah. I mean there's wow.
Sane and happy right there.
He's just like, yeah, I just,
I just had a burger. I know what to
sleep good. And then what's the math?
The other one he's like, yeah dude,
he's on death's door right there.
Only three months apart.
Four months apart for 2015 and March,
2016 is that right? Wow. Wow.
You know what's crazy too?
Sometimes it's like weight cutting messes
up the mind to cause you see yourself
so shredded,
right at one point in your life.
And then like I can get maybe
like five pounds. I'm like,
ah man, I'm out of shape.
I got to get back in shape. Yeah,
you get accustomed to it. Yeah. You,
you'll never allow yourself to get back to
300 pounds can oh, never. No, no, no, no,
no.
I can't go down that road yet.
Crazy transition though to go in a 10
year span from being a guy who's like
really overweight and worried you're going
to die to being an elite UFC fighter.
Yeah. Like life life for me
is as is happening now. Like,
this is kind of the beginning of
everything for me. You know, it's,
it's really cool.
It's really cool and I'm glad that I
found mixed martial arts just because it
just, it gives me, it's a
journey man. It's not just,
UFC is just like finding MMA and diving
into different cultures and lifestyles
and understandings and
sometimes philosophies, all
this stuff. Just to understand,
just to put it all together,
just to have it all make sense
at the end of the day. Like it's,
it's been a beautiful thing, man. I've
been able to meet a lot of people,
go a lot of places,
like I'm very thankful and very just like,
like I'm okay with life, you
know? It's very good to hear, man.
That's a cool thing to hear. I love
hearing that. You're cool with life.
Yeah. You're, um, you're on
a great path, man. It's a,
it's also what's inspiring about it for
other people is your story of being at a
place where you weren't like that before.
And then your story of being overweight
and smoking cigarettes and feeling like
shit.
And then now you're like for so many
people out there that gives people hope,
it gives them a thought. Like maybe if I
just figure this out, I actually can't,
maybe life doesn't suck.
Maybe just sucks the way I'm living.
Maybe if I could just figure out
this path in a positive direction,
I can change everything I can. I could be
a happy, I could be like you right now.
What was the exact quote? I'm happy.
Happy with life. Happy with life. Yeah.
You were cool with life. I'm happy
with life. That is a great quote.
Most people don't get to that spot
and you know the crazy thing is too,
I didn't have this dream to be in the UFC.
I made a choice to just go get healthy.
You get me a short,
just a short step in the
right direction and I just,
what propelled you to take the first
fight if you were just trying to get
healthy?
A lot of encouragement and the
first time really hearing people
like
being good at something that like
I was like surrounded by fighters and
guys who believed in me and like who cared
and like wanted to see me get better and
tougher and I was getting my ass kicked
every day and that was something that
wasn't used to just being in that
environment I had at that time learning,
I had a very strong team.
Like I started at Vandelay school
when he was still fighting.
So a lot of the guys that
was like shoot the box style.
It's like everyone's getting knocked out.
Every training somebody gets knocked
out really very hard and that was,
that was new for me to get and things
like that and doing that in Vegas.
Oh yeah man.
I remember helping him get ready for
the
either it was like Brian Sander,
Chris Leben and throwing full on
the elbows in the cage. No Pad.
Like we're going at it.
I'm like my jaw was dislocated everything
but it was just like what we learned
was just always fight in
Brasilia they pull Hada everyday.
Wow.
Everyday pull Honda
little Ohad the think about that.
Um,
it definitely made me tough
in the beginning. Now I,
I realize that like I've only been doing
this a short time and I already feel
like aches and pains and stuff and I
don't want it to be like that when I'm
older. So I'm a lot more
smarter about my training.
And uh, do you think it was a critical
aspect of your success though?
I needed gone through the fire like that.
I needed that because different guys,
you know what I was made of being,
being a guy who's overweight, insecure,
all these things,
never going on hikes or my dad
passed away when I was younger,
like very young.
And so I never had my dad to encourage
me to go throw a ball or anything,
play sports or be a man, be
a boy, be at, you know, just,
I was always like kind of sheltered by
my mom and she was more like protective,
like, ah, I don't go do that.
And then she finally learned
to just like set me free,
but I needed to know what I was made of.
Man,
I needed to know what I was made of in,
in the realm of men
fighting, whatever. It took,
blood tears, sweat had the
same thing. They say like,
I didn't know what that was like.
I never got a taste of it.
And so going through it in a real way,
like actually getting my ass beat and
having to find my way out of it and can't
run from it and still like it's people
that cared about me too. It was like,
it was just a great thing to
have and it now I enjoy it.
I enjoy really good, hard fight.
You know something about it. That's,
well you're,
you,
you're enjoying your progress to your
change of who you are as a person.
You're strengthening.
How far into your training was where you
like 100% all in committed like that?
Uh,
I think it was after my loss to Tyson,
Pedro,
which was my second fight in the UFC,
um,
before everything was still kind of
very fun and games and I was like, oh,
I get to travel,
go to Australia to fight in Australia.
So it was a big shock to be in the UFC,
especially not even expecting to be
there and within just a few years. So,
uh,
after losing that fight is when I met my
friend and at the time my strength and
conditioning coach Lorenzo
and he had been through um,
like pair rescue school
and things like that.
So he helped me to just
develop this mentality of like,
how far for your mind take you,
how big is your will?
And when training with him and doing
kind of like pararescue survival training
for conditioning, that, that was a,
that was a point where I started
to like say it like, okay,
I'm going to take this full on.
I know I can fight hard,
but now I know how far my will can
go in the face of the elements and
everything. So like putting those
two together, going after it.
And then the fight I took after
that was Daniel Jolly and then I,
I ended that in the first
round with the knee.
And then I fought Paul Craig in Scotland
and I had the same mentality. Like,
I'm going forward, I'm getting better,
I'm going to sh grow stronger, better,
harder, like everything. And uh, then the,
the fight to the Polish guy, uh, Michael
Alexei junk. Have you seen him lately?
He's been,
he's been a,
he just beat like John Volante
and I forgot. Oh, that's right.
Yeah. With a body shop. I
lost it. Or I lost to him,
but then it got turned
into a no contest. So, um,
after that was the [inaudible] fight.
So it's been,
I'd say maybe a team to know no contest.
He tests positive. Yeah. It tested.
But he was also, um, uh, uh, last minute,
uh, last minute fight.
I was fuck his name up.
Michael l Alexi joke. Alexi. Chuck.
It's a rough one at the Williams.
I was butcher it terrible. But
some of those fucking name.
Ah, sage. Yeah.
So like three or four years, man. And
how many fights you have professionally?
Uh, Dang. What's my work?
Eight three 83 and one
that's funny that you know,
you don't really know your record. I, hmm.
I don't remember. Eight. Three in one.
I think it's a three in one. Wow. Yeah.
That's amazing that you've been fighting
for a relatively short period of time
and have a, achieved some pretty
fucking spectacular results, man.
Do you have anybody in your past that
was into martial arts? Do you, uh,
is it in the family?
My brothers,
my brothers were both like just
athletes in school and they were like,
they were always getting in fights
and stuff at school. Like I said,
I was nonconfrontational so that was like,
they were the biggest
fighters to me growing up.
Were they stunned that you're
a fighter now? Now? Um,
my other brother has actually a fighter
too. He fought for like the world series,
a world series of fighting one 25
belt and Andy contender series,
things like that. He still fighting, still
training. And then my oldest brother, he,
uh, he doesn't fight. He used to play
like college football and stuff. But yeah,
so I got one brother.
And so it's in the family a little bit,
at least a little bit.
What do you think about the world
series of finding that which became the
professional fighting given away $1
million to everybody who wins whatever.
They're respected weight
classes, right? Yeah.
And then you fight two times
in one night. Yeah. Yeah.
What do you think of the cool, but I
don't know. Two Times in one night.
I don't want it two
times in one night sucks,
but I don't know if they get
paid to show up and then,
or it's like you just fight and
then hopefully you get that meal.
I don't want to see a guy who goes
through a three round war fight.
A guy who knocked out in 10 seconds. Yeah,
because that can happen. It does happen.
It just seems, it seems
so unfair. Did you see a,
I thought Vinny Magalhaes was going
to take it. That last one too. He's,
I remember seeing a lot.
He's really coming to his zone.
His striking is caught up with a lot of
his grapple. Oh yeah. And he's fantastic.
This bass very dangerous. I've never
seen a guy that big, that flexible.
He can do everything.
When it comes to Jujitsu,
do you ever see when the flying arm
barred paid upon? Oh, nope. It's crazy.
Like who the fuck does that? Nope. I was
at that match. The uh, the Metamorris,
I think it was a w w was it metamorris
when he, when he grappled with Keenan.
Was that Metamorris if like a few years
back, maybe like four or five years. Yeah.
It could have been metamorris
Ebi, metamorris matchups.
He had some good ones,
but I forget all the matchups.
Yeah, those are good events,
huh? Yes. Yeah. More. Huh?
I wish there was more
of those, man. I mean,
I'm happy Eddie Bravo's sort of taken
over that space with the Ebi and a combat.
You just who now have
you seen that lapse or
great idea? Right. It's nice to great. I'd
sometimes, like you might be holding on,
but that slap and then that
might cause a guide to like, oh,
something changes the game.
There's things aren't available anymore.
You can't just allow yourself, it's
just too hard. You could somebody like
somebody stopped somebody Wagner
roadshow stop. Somebody's got on top,
mounted them and just blasted
them with pumps. Their head. Yeah.
It was pretty rough, man.
It's like, it's almost like
you can do ground and pound and we
learned from boss Rutan way back in the
Pancrase days. Do you
remember those days? Yeah.
Bas Rutten figured out how to pull his
hand back way further than other people
and Bas Rutten would smash
guys would palm strikes.
He was throwing like uppercuts and hooks.
Like he wasn't just like slapping.
Yeah. These are really high level
Jujitsu to with smacks. Look at home.
What? Yeah. Do you know that guy's
not used to getting slapped out?
Not by a guy with a nasty
guard like Wagner roadshow. Ah,
he wants to tap his nose fucked up.
Can you tap from this lap? Yeah, you
can tab. Oh, he's getting beat up,
Mike. Maybe I'll try and seed enough. See,
once he starts dropping those
palms down, Boy Paul, Huh?
Yeah, it's a forehead. It's
a reality check. You know,
it's a reality check about how
dangerous this position is.
You can't really just sit and let a guy
mount you to do something desperate to
get out of that. But in Jujitsu,
if the guy's just mounting you,
you can kind of chill out figuring out
how to escape the leg or something like
that. Shit, combat Jujitsu, you
got to get the fuck out of there.
That's a terrible place to be safe.
They were like Amy May right be mounted.
So it's, especially when he tired. Well,
the difference between MMA grappling and
regular grappling to used to always be
with the, one of the big ones, at
least I should say, was leg locks.
They thought you really couldn't get
away with leg locks in as much in MMA
because as you're going for the legs,
you have two arms committed to the leg.
Someone's just going to punch you in the
face and you don't have defense for it.
But now you're seeing when God's like in
minority burst on the scene and started
ripping guys knees apart and you see
how effective that is. And then Paul,
Horace [inaudible] no, you
don't like, like less scared
of it. It's they're scary,
Huh? Yeah, I've ever so infatuated three
knee operations and to reconstruction,
but are like, do you like to watch? Oh
yeah, yeah, like a drawn down to her dude.
He's so interesting Brian,
and you know. Yeah. Yeah.
I remember just like kind of looking
into a little Edie Cummings. Yeah.
Those guys are savages. Gary, Tony,
fucking people's legs up and you know,
and then Craig Jones and all these other
guys that are coming from all over the
world that are leg lock,
special style,
they all have these complex leg lock
systems now. It's a total thing holders.
A shitty fuck up.
You go zig when he should have zagged.
Like when Brian Hall fought
Bj Penn, right? And he caught
him in that. I was like,
no, no, no. Not that way.
Yeah, you're just trying to
get out. He tried to get out.
Ryan Hall just locked it up.
I just imagined the field
right now. I always say,
oh well it's once that stuff gets chewed
up inside there, that's the problem.
I mean,
some people could just take it,
but once you start ripping
meniscus apart and cartilage apart,
once that stuff starts happening,
ligaments starts getting stretched out
and rip a little bit 10 they're always
going to be wiggly. I mean even Gordon
ride just ripped his fucking leg apart.
Did he really? Yeah, he
just had surgery. Um,
I think he did it in an actual
grappling match. So I think his foot,
his leg moved weird and it just,
it popped his, his knee apart.
But the guy had a hold on
it. I don't think so. No, no,
I think it was in a scramble.
I think it came a in a scramble but
there's a lot of those leg lock experts
right now that scare the shit out
and everything came from dean lister,
which is crazy. Lister t on the story. No,
John Danaher was talking
to Dean lister and uh,
Dean lister was talking about leg locks
and John Danaher said something inquired
about why you do leg locks. And he goes,
why would you ignore 50% of the body
and John Don heartbeat and it fucking
crazy wizards. He is like, why would you,
why would you it all these meetings?
Here's a fucking hilarious meme of John
Donna her in bed next to a woman and it
says,
why would you ignore 40% 50% of the
body of man and then other guys?
Yeah. Well Don, hers,
a guy who understands things like he
sees them on a very complex level,
like he understands all the various
possible exchanges and what's the best way
to mitigate like stop the defense, push
the offense, control the situation.
What is, what is the ultimate control
position? I have to get to it.
Do I have to get on the inside? Do
I grab it this way? I do. I grab it.
And then they,
once they started really experimenting
and putting it together and putting it
into a system and you see how these guys
who have only been doing Jujitsu for a
few years like Nikki Ryan and Gordon,
right?
They start tapping all these like
really legit guys. They're like,
what the fuck is happening?
Yeah. Those systems,
it's got Kamora system that
blocks us from everything. Huh.
I think that helps a lot.
It just when it comes to training,
learning things in systems, you
know what I mean? I think 10 plant,
it has like their own system.
Right? For sure. And it helps.
It helps to go to another state. Like
it's the same. Yeah, same system. Right.
They'll all systems help. Yeah. You know,
I mean and then fighters devise their
own system really often, you know,
have their own entries and their
own ways of defending things.
But the leg lock games so unexpected
because I always thought they were a good
technique if you can get it,
but it's not that high percentage in MMA.
That was Kinda how I felt. You didn't see
too many of them. I don't know why. Well,
I think it was,
we didn't,
we had a few guys that were really
good in the early days like, oh look,
tuck tar off and you know some other guys
who are really good but we didn't have
the level that you have what like
a Paul Harris dive in on things,
transitioning from one thing to the next
and then locking you up in a position
where you had a tap quick. Cause if
you don't, you're gonna be screened.
Do you think a lot of the times it is
those guys like the other guy's fault or
does he really just hold too long?
He definitely holds too long. He has,
there's one fight from Brazil where
it's crazy. He's just not letting go.
He's just holding on to something,
I forget what it was,
but he was not letting go and they were
trying to separate it when he was still
hanging onto it.
I think he came from a really,
really bad childhood and he's talked
about it in depth about growing up on a
farm and being forced to eat pig slop
was pig slop when he was a little boy,
that cut that he has on his chest, that
big scar. He had sealed that up with glue.
Yeah. Like crazy shit
man. Yeah, he's actually,
I've met him before a few
times, like through a, yeah,
there's some friends and he
seems like a cool guy. Yeah,
he does. You know, genuine.
I just think when he was
killed in competition, man, he,
he just doesn't want to let it go.
He wants and they make him let it go.
And He tried,
even though he knew that they were
gonna get mad at him if he didn't let go
still in quite let go. Yeah. And they
were like, get the fuck Outta here.
They kicked him out of the UFC,
the first guy ever to get kicked out of
the UFC for holding on submissions. Oh,
he got kicked out. Ah, okay. Do you
know who he, who he held it against?
I don't know, but I'm pretty,
I don't want, I want to
make sure that that's true.
I think it is that who some are.
Paul Harris was the first guy to ever
get kicked out of the UFC and I think the
last one that got kicked out for it was
like any normal person wouldn't even
gotten in trouble for that
one. Yeah. It was like normal.
It was like maybe a little bit too long,
but it was on that borderline edge.
But because it was him,
people like enough, you know,
he's it. Was that what it
was? It wasn't in the UFC,
but it was a controversial
submission victory ever.
Jake shields at the world series
of fighting Jake Shields, I think.
Yeah, but I think he did that too. But
that was a Kimora. Yeah, that's right.
But I think before that he
got kicked out of the UFC,
released in 2013 Oh, Mike Pearce. Yes.
Referee interviewing. That's right.
Yup. So that's what it was. Yeah.
Okay.
That's what it was.
He was released after holding onto a
heel hook of Mike Pierce in 2013 yeah.
But look man,
that guy was,
was particularly scary when he fought
because he was so strong and his body was
so well designed for. He'll hook, right.
He just could grab a hold of you and to
rip your shit apart. Man. Look at that.
Oh my God. Look at this now
look what he does here. See,
he grabs a little bit. My
peers, dawn is tapping, tapping.
Tapping is still holding. Still holding
on. But that's all in slow motion.
But it looked to me like he was still
ripping the Nia part even though he knew
that the guy tapped. Yeah,
he had it. He knew he had it.
He's just punishing that guy.
You know?
He makes it scarier for other people
and he's probably used to doing it.
You know, he had this psychological block.
They all say that. He's like a really,
really nice guy. Yeah. He just become
that guy that nobody wants to fight.
You can't get a moment.
But I think in the Jake shields fight,
there was other shit that was happening
too. I think there was high pokes.
I'm pretty sure he said dirty fight.
What are you here?
Yeah.
What are we hearing?
Something bleeding through into our
microphones. I've heard this before.
I've been trying to catch what it
was. Go Sprout. Know what it's from.
It's some interference.
I see.
Okay.
This is like, um, so I don't know if the
people can hear it. Can the people here,
all right. It was not as this, what is,
what is it? The file? Pull up the fight.
That's how you left.
[inaudible] it's very low.
It's me just debunk ghost bro.
Which fight was it that you pulled up? Uh,
that, that fight that took, you know, oh,
what do you guys near Park? Yeah. Yeah.
He was the first guy to be like super
scary and a elite modern level with heel
hooks. Where did he start off?
Do you know what promotion? Well,
he's a [inaudible] guy. Okay,
so he came out of Brazil.
Probably cage warriors. I don't know man.
I don't know where, where are we? What?
He was fighting and in Brazil, I don't
remember seeing cage worries is the UK,
is it? Yeah. That's where
Anderson came from. Well Anderson,
when he made the jump from pride,
he did cage warriors for a while and
then came over to the UFC and I think
that's when he started working with uh,
the new guerrez when he started
fighting in a cage fighters. Oh.
So he fought in a bunch of fewer
EFCs fought a bunch of stuff.
Storm Samurai 12 Tom, Tom, ouch.
Storm Samurai 12.
I want a t shirt for Storm Samurai 12
throwback. Yeah. Real throw back. Yeah,
he had a great um,
it goes to show you how good Gary
tone is as a submission grapple too.
Cause they had a great submission,
grappling match put, keep,
go back to his record there because
I think that was listed there.
I think it turned out in a draw and Gary
[inaudible] is so much smaller than him.
Draw. Yeah. Gary Tone. Oh
yeah, that would reset. Yeah.
But is that really 2016 I think it was
because I remember now that was Craig
Jones. Okay. 2018 was Craig Jones. Yeah.
Cause [inaudible] was posting
pictures about like how he looks now.
Keep me know he's got like,
he's got a high fade and like this big
mustache banalities all it looks like
jacked up a thousand pounds. Yeah, for
sure. So he's running through walls. Yeah.
Is He fighting MMA anymore? Is,
are you just doing grappling?
I think he might just be doing grappling.
I haven't heard of d. If it made news,
that's something extra scary about
a guy. I'll fuck your knee up. Yeah.
You know what's up?
Look at the size of him now.
He's with hic Hickey Monster.
Whole farm
you side and not want to get my,
my heel caught in that armpit.
Yeah. Look at those, that
picture above where he's
screaming. Look at that picture.
Like what in the fuck man.
Oh look at Craig Jones
show that is a body designed
to rip your legs apart.
Do you know the hill hook came,
uh, not enough to really play it,
but um,
spent a little bit of time picking,
picking the brains of people who are
getting them. Yeah, I like it. I enjoy it.
Yeah. I think I could, I think I
could actually get pretty good at it.
It's like the basics of
it seems pretty simple.
It's just a matter of like getting
comfortable there because I feel like my
knees are just, I don't want to risk it,
you know what I mean? All I can do, oh,
let's play this game a little bit.
Yeah.
But if I find a partner that's not an
asshole and just like really wants to like
learn together or whatever, then
I'll, I'll do it. I'll go after it.
Do you ever see yourself doing Jujitsu
matches or anything like that? Yeah,
I've only done maybe three of
my life. Yeah. Yeah, I did one,
my last Jujitsu competition
was probably two years ago,
two and a half years ago.
Naga, just like, it was random,
just like a random like, oh,
okay, I'll do Naga today.
Well there are some MMA fighters that
are at a high enough level of grappling
and they can compete against really
elite grapplers and Jiu Jitsu matches,
you know, like, um, Chad
Mendez member, he had that, um,
that match with, um, Jeff. Fuck,
why am I blanking on his name now?
Jeff Glover. Jeff Glover. Really? Yeah.
I didn't know that. Yeah.
I think he choked him out.
And thank you Chad Mendez choke out.
Jeff Glover.
I think he took his back and
tapped him. Yeah. Oh, ah.
I think they were using
the Eddie Bravo uh,
invitational rules make,
make sure that's true. Ah,
which you start on someone's
back. Yeah. You know,
in over time you go to a certain distance.
Is that chail son in Schmidt is
it's chill Sonnen's organization.
And in which case, I'm pretty
sure they use a, the Ebi rules.
So he got his back through sort of
an one of those over time positions,
but he's still tapped him.
And the other one is Uriah faber.
Uriah Faber is pretty fucking elite.
Pretty fucking elite.
Like Jen Glover's animal. Oh my God, I
love that guy. Super, super technical,
you know, and very dangerous
and relaxed. Right.
Big Time stoner. Yeah. So he,
they must've set him up on his back.
This doesn't show it.
It just shows him have the back man.
That's a hell of a fucking ruined
and right there that works all day on
everybody. Even a Jeff Glover. Wow. That's
why Jiu Jitsu works, you know it will,
if you're a lead, it'll
work. Save your ass. Yeah.
Three by overtime submission.
So we were correct. Yeah.
Yeah. There's, so there's a few guys,
but it's really hard to be the master
of everything. Right? Yeah, for sure.
So for you,
is there a balance where you're like,
am I spending enough time grappling? Am
I spending enough time striking? Do you,
do you ever like wonder what the correct
formula is or do you tinker with it at
all?
Okay.
I have wondered and I always wonder,
but
I can't like so a long time ago,
maybe like a few years ago,
Anderson told me like, listen,
just you need Jujitsu. Like you need
it. And he's like, it saved my life.
I love to strike too. But when I
learned Jujitsu, it changed my life.
So you need to learn it.
Put on a g,
let's roll like it right
there in the living room, you
know? And I was just like,
okay. So one of the things that
I learned from him is just,
he's like,
learn the basic stuff,
like learn the basic stuff. Get
really good at it. And then,
and then like use it to save yourself
and you'll, you'll end up growing.
He's like,
just keep training Jujitsu.
You don't need this whole crazy
secret system at the moment.
Just make sure that you're training
Jujitsu and continue to learn Jujitsu.
You know, like, so that's kind of
my takeaway from the conversation.
So I just make sure that when I'm
training, at least I'm doing Jujitsu,
you know,
like,
okay,
I focus on it,
make sure that I'm getting better,
make sure that I'm going with
guys that are way better than me.
So I'm always getting my ass kicked by.
At least I'm always going with guys that
are better than me all the time. Um,
and like I enjoy it, but I'm a
striker. That's it. Like, I enjoy it.
I know that I need it.
It's my job.
I know that it can get dangerous
if I go against, you know,
if I go against the guy who was a
high level Jujitsu, I know that,
I understand that and I'm very aware
of it every time that I trained and I,
so I make sure that I do my
job and I go to Jujitsu class,
but I'm a striker and I'm
always going to be focused on,
that's always going to be what like my
Goto, anybody, whether it's a striker,
a grappler,
I don't care.
I'm going to train striking and
I'm going to train Jujitsu too,
but I'm going to my striking always.
Do you think that that is like
you letting everybody know,
are you trying to trick
people and then next,
next fight you're going to shoot on folks,
I don't need to shoot.
I'll shoot if I need to.
Like if I'm getting my ass kicked
and I needed take a desperation shot.
But you would rather just let them know
that you're coming out striking because
one of the things that I believe
you do and you're very good at it,
but one of the things that's
interesting about real high level MMA,
when you look at the guys who were,
who had been like legendarily successful
like George Saint Pierre or mighty
mouse,
two great examples.
One of the things that you never knew
what the fuck they're going to do to you
and that overloading the mine with
possibilities is a part of their success.
It's like how much of a part,
it's a good question.
Do you think that there's an argument
for using the skills that you have which
are quite spectacular with that sort of
style sort of style that incorporates
way more take downs, way more take
down attempts, way more faints.
Just just different
combinations of things.
So you never know what the
fuck is happening at any
given time or do you think
that it's better to just be the best
striker you can and that'll be enough?
You stop those takedowns
that'll be enough for me.
For you or just in
general? For you, for you?
I think for me it would
be the best to just
be the best striker. Did you enjoy it
that much more? I enjoy that much more.
Um, you know, I think yeah,
I enjoy that much more.
I still have a lot to learn,
a lot to grow so that it's always going
to get better. I don't think that it's,
I don't think that's going to get bad.
I'm still learning a lot,
especially with what you guys got
to see like a few weeks ago and it,
that's the only at the beginning, like
everything, even before that was like
nonexistent compared to like the type
of training that I've been doing.
So I'm like, I'm really
excited. So I'm like, ah boy.
He ties a lot more than just punch
kicks and elbows, you know? And that's,
that's all the striking game. It's
infatuated by it right now. Yeah.
Just want to focus on 100%.
Yeah. Like there's guys like,
uh, think about like
Michael Van and page, right?
Like before he fought like Paul Daley,
I'm sure that guy trains a
lot of grappling as well.
And it shows like if he gets in positions,
like he's knocked out guys from weird,
you know, we're positions, but
when people watch him fight,
they want to see like they trust
in his stand up. They're like, oh,
this guy's going to do some crazy stuff.
Yeah.
And I kind of want to be
able to do the same thing.
Not Crazy like you know,
worldly stuff,
but when people watch me fight,
they know what to expect and that's
just like bulletproof striking.
No.
Yeah.
That fight was a very unexpected,
the way Paul dealer decide to take him
down. I was like, I was pretty stunned.
Yeah. I didn't think we're going
to see that. Let me, Paul Daley.
So dangerous is fucking left.
Hook is one of the best in all of the
business is lefthand period. Anyway,
throws it. Both of them knew what they
were going up against. So like Yup.
Even behind the shit talk they knew like
it was a tough fight for both of them.
It was.
But it was interesting to me watching
page use his distance and that crazy
karate point style and that,
you know,
we had to hit a really
look out for that stuff.
I mean he had a head of make sure that
he wasn't getting dinged by that stuff.
Yeah,
well he's coming in with a high cause.
Venom throws all this wild stuff like a,
almost like a fencer like dives in on
you and pops you and you could tell Paul
Daley was like really having a hard time,
like finding that range. Yeah. It's,
it's hard to,
to,
to fight against guys that are long
and know how to use their body like
athletically.
Is He fighting
Douglas Lema? Next is, that's
what's happening over in Beltour.
I remember seeing that
Douglas Lema had a fight,
but I don't remember who the opponent was.
Who's Michael Venom page fighting.
Find out that he's a spectacular
though, man. Right. You need that.
He landed on Cyborg was holy shit.
He caved the man's head and skull.
He's never seen that. I've never
seen the razor. Just insane.
Like you got hit with a media.
Imagine the pain.
Imagine Matt and he was hanging out with
a headache, the bed like four months.
He's like, I'll be fighting to get in four
months. And they were like, Bro. Yeah,
I met that guy in Brazil. It's tough, man.
Yeah, he's tough. He's been around it.
That's why when you see a guy like that
cover his face and then fall down like
that. Oh, it is Chandler
versus pit bull. Uh,
Lima versus MVP. That's
it. Tagless Lima's no,
11 he's no joke. That's a dangerous
man. Lima, the opportunity to head.
He's a fucking enormous
welterweight to Lima is easy.
I've never seen him in person is
a big frame for, for one seven.
Woo cuts a lot of weight. But he's
so powerful when he gets in there.
Dangerous fucking striker.
Lima's he's for real.
That to me is as interesting, if not
more interesting. The Paul daily fight.
I want to see what happens. Yeah. Lima is
a little different than like, he's not,
he's not gonna trash talk a lot. Like he
knows he's dangerous guide. So there's,
Michael is going to be a good one.
That's a real good one for sure. Yeah.
Well fights like that really legitimize
Beltour because these are fights that
they can be easily be a main event
in the UFC. Talent wise. You know,
unquestionably that
fight oof venom page is,
he's a real fucking hard pill to
swallow, man. Figure that guy out.
Who the fuck can you bring in
a train that can move like him?
No one you can try but you're not, he
doesn't even know how he's going to move.
You know? I think that guy just puts out
music and just whatever happens happens.
Yeah. That's why this fight
is so interesting because
Lima is like way more like,
uh, has, uh, just a rock solid
traditional stance. You know,
he moves real well.
Devastating power that's going
to be a really good fight.
Where does it leave a train? Do
you know? It's a good question.
Where's the Douglas Lema
train? Um, Jamie's going to
find that out for us. Yeah.
Yeah. I'm very happy that there's
a bunch of good organizations like,
like one and you know, like the
Pfl now and Bella Tor. It's,
it's great that 5% of
options. Super good. Yeah, it
a lot of times too. Like I like
to just watch whatever's going on.
You never know who you're going
to come across. Where is that?
Where's that American top team?
Similar is it to this terrifying
nasty combinations,
man.
He's got ruthless leg kicks to man att.
Where?
Which one? There's a bunch of
those. Right? On top teams.
You might be att Florida. I Dunno it
was he, it didn't look like the Florida,
but att,
how many ATPs are there?
I have no idea.
Is there a bunch I should know that
I think of a training two or three.
Who? Cat Fight Club? I guess Thailand.
Oh really? In this article right here.
That just came out, uh,
yesterday. Okay. Fight Club.
Maybe saw your fight and it's like,
fuck it.
I'm going to Thailand to
bringing everybody. Everybody
come Joe when you come in?
Huh?
Wow.
Since he's been a lot of places
recently for this fight. Honestly,
nowadays my life was a camp.
Lima stated it's been like six or seven
months and I haven't stopped trying to
improve. For me, this is a
lifestyle. Yeah. It's, um,
the only thing that really bothers me,
the only thing that bothers me is that
it's difficult to get a champion to fight
a champion,
like a champion from the UFC to find the
champion from one or to fight a chance
up with that. Yeah. I think that would
be good for everybody. That'd be so sick.
Yeah, it'd be good for, we should find
out who the fuck who's running shit.
Exactly. Yeah. Make that happen. Or how,
also how UFC fighters can do
like Muy Thai fights on the side.
Sure.
I would love that.
That'd be hard for them to do though
because you'd have to justify it.
Like what if they got hurt and they
couldn't fight in a car and then the UFC
like loses an asset. You know, they
would think of it in terms of like a,
a possible main event like player.
Like if there's a guy who's a top
of the food chain dude, and he says,
I want to say one more tie
fight and the terraces, MCL,
and then six months later it's still not
ready to fight, but they should do it.
Like, if you're not, like, if
you're the top 15, you can't do it.
Yeah. That's not a bad idea. If you're
not even ranked, go ahead. Go crazy. Yeah.
One more time. Going to be a while
before they'll let you do what?
Jujitsu tournament though,
right? Jujitsu's fine. Yeah.
Did you just fucking
dangerous too. Yeah. Yeah.
You can go against a guy like Paul
hour is. Yeah. Um, yeah. You be cool,
man. Shop father. The other Cyborg Brazil,
uh, Ricardo brew. Oh,
that guy. Yeah. He's,
he was one of my Jujitsu traders at
the Angeles. Yeah. He's a beast. Yeah.
Was a big man. Yeah. And the
shock basically kept him away.
Just pushed him away from him. Yeah. Yeah.
He didn't want to get his legs ripped
apart. I think I remember that.
That might've been the time where
shop was over at Black House.
I think he was gonna he was
gonna go do that. Well, his,
his point of view was like,
look,
I have to fight because I'm not going
to get my leg torn apart. Take me down.
Do something. You're not even
doing anything. It's not worth it.
Then later he did sit in his guard,
but he couldn't do anything to them.
It's mostly defensive. He basically shut
his, his Jujitsu down though. I mean that,
that he really did do that. If you
really stop and think about it, I mean,
Cyborg wanted to do something
and we stalled them out.
It's not a fun thing to watch and
it's not good if you're a cyborg.
Yeah, but if a guy could stall
you out, like that's a weird,
in a grappling situation, that's a weird
situation. Someone just defenses you.
It just pushes you out. Never attacks.
Just keeps pushing you off. Yeah.
What do you do? What do
you do? Yeah, I mean,
and how much of your Jujitsu is based
on someone that's willing to engage?
That's a problem with, you said big
problem. When guys go to the ground,
oftentimes you'll see them almost
not even securing a position.
Just sit thinking this
position will maintain this
way because it isn't training
all the time because guys are just lying
on top of you and your and your guard
instead of just jumping out of
your guard going need a belly.
And smashing you in the face.
Exactly.
You think you can catch a little break
because you do all the time and training.
You really see that with Jujitsu
players sometimes, you know,
they forget they have to hold on.
Like especially guys who used to train
with the g and then in an MMA fight and
the guys on top of them and they think
they're trying to set up an arm bar or
something like that and that people are
just like, nope, I'm just to chill it.
You'll get out of the spot. Decent
Trainingi yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Where do you tread John? Jock. I'll,
last time I did it was two weeks ago,
three weeks ago. It might've even been
more me and a Russell Peters. Okay.
You've done it a couple of times. He did
it in Malibu too. He's a good dude, man.
John John Machado is awesome. Yeah,
I heard good things about him. He's,
he's awesome. Couldn't be a nicer person
and uh, just really, really tactical,
really good at breaking things down.
Really good at explaining things.
The big gym, it's a good
size. You know, he's,
he'll get like 60 people there and a
noon class sometimes. So it gets packed.
Yeah. Yeah. Is it the heart of the
city or what? And I was in Tarzana. Oh,
it turns out that, yeah, there's a bunch
of Machado. Jim's still though I think,
I think they have one in Redondo.
Hey, it's me and Russell.
Um, but uh, he's just got,
there's just perfect basics.
Perfect event.
I mean, everything he does, he's
always in the perfect position.
His defense is always PR.
Like when you wrote with a
guy like that, it's like, wow,
there's so many levels to this thing.
Like it just lets you know what
this is just level after level.
He's never in danger, ever.
Never. He's always laughing. Oh,
Joe Hogan and Joe Joe Hogan and
you're trying to get them out.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah. He talked to
that guy. Yeah, sure. Hassan. Yeah.
It's pretty cool. Hilarious man. That
character is one of the most weird,
obscure,
like,
think about it that it's a character
that he developed that's a fake Brazilian
multiple time world champion.
But the dude who plays it is like he's
legit. He's a guy [inaudible] he's,
he's one of Eddie's black belts.
I think he got his back,
but I'm pretty sure he did. He's a
really good grappler, man. Really? Yeah,
but he pretends to be this guy.
[inaudible] yeah, I remember. I,
I met him one time at Ebi needed. He
wouldn't come out of character. Yeah.
That was fucking give me a hard
time about James Brown or something.
I think I forgot it was. Oh, we,
but he's my friend. I've been friends
with him for a long time. He's a great,
great in real life. That's not,
that's character. It's just,
it's see so committed to this character.
He's been doing this character
for like 10 fucking years, man.
Does he do it just like in
public? Oh, fuck around with you.
He'll bust out the character.
He's always on.
It's gotta be fun though if
you've got to have the character.
Some people got really mad at him though.
Like Nate Diaz got legitimately mad at
him. Was that at the, at the booth? Yes.
The OTM booth. Yeah. Something like
that. Yeah. Something happened.
I saw the video they got into, Nate was
like, get the fuck Outta here, bitch.
And he was like, ah, Hey,
I'm just fucking around.
This is what in the hell Bro.
Is that as IGA right there.
You got to have to turn away because
of the girls, but not necessarily,
but he does have a couple, got a lot of
marks on his character, so he's hilarious.
Character hates child support
and is always attracted to buts.
It's Alice have porch.
I mean it's a crazy character man.
It seems like something that someone
would have on a television show or
something, you know? It's ours.
It's only for like only MMA.
People in Jujitsu. People know about
it. Exactly. Oh, what does it get it?
You go try to hit the streets with that
Joe. They'd be like, what do you say it?
I'm almost positive.
He's a black belt and the bees
are very legit martial artists.
That's pretty cool. His Dad was a karate
instructor too. He's a bad motherfucker.
Zoom real martial artist. It's funny.
The character is just so funny. Yeah.
I got to meet him. We could arrange
that. That's true. Cool. Shit.
So what is next for you after this
past fight? Um, what they do they do,
they give you some time to recover
and then hit you with some options.
Does your management contact the UFC?
How does it work?
Uh,
yeah,
it could be management contacting them
or just UFC reaching out just to see when
I'll be ready. Um, but since the fight,
like I just took a little bit
of time off to see the family.
It's been a while since I've seen them.
Did they ever offer you
like a short notice fight?
Uh,
I've gotten offered a short notice.
Five before I got offered that I'll,
I'll,
my a long time ago I got
offered that Gustafson fight.
It was like a long shot. Didn't think
I was gonna get it, but I was down.
I was like, yeah, I'll take it. And
it was like, I think 10 days notice,
seven days notice that the at the, the
one in La. Um, but it didn't happen.
And then I offered to be the replacement
for the fight and Sao Paulo that Eric
Anders stepped in for.
But against Tiago, he,
it was either going to be
against him or Manuela,
who was the first who is
supposed to fight first? Tiago.
He was like someone pulled out of
that car, I'm not sure of that fight,
someone pull out of it. And then they
offered me since I was already in Brazil,
but um, I think they needed a
Brazilian to fill the card, so, um,
I couldn't do it.
So yeah,
there's been times that I've been willing
to step in short notice, um, buffer.
Now I'm like,
if what I've learned in four months has
been able to get me this far and a lot
like in my last fight,
then I'm going to go back and just get,
get back to training so I can
be ready when they call me.
So what do you anticipate, how many
times would you like to fight a year?
I want to fight at least two
more times this year. Yeah.
So I've,
I've got to learn what works for me,
just based off the time,
put it into this camp and kind of this
new system that I can start to develop.
So now just get back, start training
it, and then get into a fight camp.
So, and like, typically what do you
like do you like eight weeks, 12 weeks?
Like what do you, what do you,
what do you need to provide?
I think eight weeks is perfect.
Yeah. Eight weeks is perfect.
I'll take six weeks. Um, four
weeks feels kind of like,
you know, like everything's Kinda
gotta be rushed. But uh, yeah,
I think six to eight weeks is perfect.
And what do you do on from
recovery while you're out there?
You're doing Thai massage. Gentile
fair massages are so cheap. Yeah.
Like you can get two hour
time massage for yourself.
You can get two hour time
massage for maybe like 10 bucks,
two hours, full body, like elbows and
feet, everything. That's incredible.
Amazing. And then, um, they knew the ice
bath, but they put like big blocks of ice.
They don't put bags. So there's a bunch
of this ice baths and massages. That's it.
The stretching. But uh, I really, uh,
I really want to do something down there,
like save some money and maybe get
like recovery place going. Like,
what kind of recovery? Please? I want to
bring something down there. I didn't even,
I wasn't going to get him out this
idea, but whatever. Who Cares? Um,
I think because there's so much
stuff down there, uh, gyms, crossfit,
restaurants, all that stuff. Uh,
I think the only thing that's
lacking is a proper recovery.
Crile called punch hot tub.
No massage.
Just like speedy recovery.
You've been in the Cryo, right?
Like, yeah, man,
you can go after a hard session and go
cryo and go take a nap and you'll feel
pretty good. But the icepack
good. Just getting out of it.
Do you feel the same way from
ice baths? A cold plunge? Yeah,
like the one of the Pie.
That one's freezing cold.
I do a couple of minutes in
there and yeah. Um, the ice bath.
So in Thailand because
of the bricks are so big,
it takes a long time to really like fill
up and stuff so they don't get as cold.
So I think I would love
to just to help out,
like help that little community and just
get something really like really good
in there for just recovery and
have, you know, maybe some,
some type of smoothies or something
to help boost everything up,
get the system running again so that
we can train multiple times a day.
Now do you do anything to monitor your
heart rate or heart rate variability to
see if your overtrained or undertrained
see how you're feeling? Uh, yeah,
not as much as we did here at the UFC pie.
But uh,
I do have a heart rate monitor and for
this fight camp I use it only to um,
make sure that I can get my weight down
because I got up to like two 35 and I
did this like the o two Max test
and I did all this stuff and this,
this clinic down there helped me to um,
just understand when
my body's burning fat.
So where to keep my heart rate and how
to monitor like when I'm actually working
hard enough to, to lose the weight
and it worked. So it was good.
It's such a different world now with
all these scientific inventions. Yeah.
Different ways that they can make
sure that your body's in a good space.
It's not guesswork anymore.
Make sure you're not overtrained or
hundred percent dealing with the same time
off.
The same time I was doing vo two Max,
they had a like a EKG going on everything.
So I'm like running,
they're making sure my heart's
pumping and my lungs are functioning,
everything all in sync.
And they gave me this whole big printout
of everything and everything seemed to
be working perfectly. So
they were just like, okay,
well in order to lose this
much weight by this much,
this is what you need to be at.
And when your body's at the highest fat
burning stage is when your body's at or
when your heart rate's at like 178 for
me it was 178 ppms and so I did my best
to push. They're just, and I
at least know when I'm there,
I'm burning the most fat so I'll try
to get there as much as possible.
You got to try and not do that again
as far as like get that heavy. Yeah,
100% but getting,
getting that heavy too.
It was like I had lost the Johnnie Walker.
It got to Thailand. Oh, food sugary,
like all this stuff. So I just Kinda
like, I dunno what I'm fighting again. So,
but now I'm ready to be active.
That was a big part of my
decision to go there too. Uh,
and stay there a year is I want to be
active this year to two fights, but
training. Where did they have you
ranked now? I don't think I am.
You don't think you're ranked even
Tom 15? No, definitely not. Hmm.
What do you think you should do in
terms of the next level of fight?
Are you face? Like what kind
of guy would you like to fight?
Yeah.
Hmm Man,
that's crazy.
I don't even ask myself those questions.
What do you do you just wait for
the call? Yeah, I usually just, I,
oh wait for the call and whoever they,
they usually offer to, they
had like two options. Really?
Yeah. Like how do you choose? Uh,
usually they offer like,
like the last time it was okay,
there's Eric handers or there's a guy,
like, I didn't even know his name.
Like this guy is going to be new coming
into the UFC and air candor's is like
coming off a loss, blah, blah, blah. And
I'm like, okay, well socks. I know Eric,
all this stuff.
But I'd rather fight Eric because I've
already lost three times to guys who were
making their UFC debuts and it's just
not good for me. You know what I mean?
Like obviously they're tough.
They're hungry, they're
trying to get into the UFC,
it's going to be a really tough fight.
Um,
and so that's Kinda how I made the
decision. The last one I was like,
I don't want to take the risk of losing
another fight to a guy who was making
his debut because three
times it was enough for me.
That's refreshing to be honest.
Yeah, that's what I mean.
It's like we were talking
about earlier about boxers,
having managers that have a strategy to
keep them undefeated as long as possible,
give them tests,
have them decide like,
when's the right time to take
this fight once you know what's,
what's the right thing to do.
And as a professional,
how much of an advantage is it to
know what a guy does? Know who he is.
I've seen him fight a bunch of
times. Been around them. Uh, it's,
I just like, just for instance, um,
like I fought go con Saki and then
they offered me Johnny Walker.
And so like Johnny Walker was coming off
contender series, but still nobody knew.
Like not even, we knew we saw his
highlights, but we're like, oh well,
like this look at the competition
that he's faced. Right. You know,
so we didn't really get to see much of
what he was capable of. So I'm like, ah,
okay. If that's all you got,
then I'll take the fight by then.
Here comes Johnny Walker. This like
raging beast. You'd only be like,
the guy's huge. So, um,
yeah, it was just, it was weird. Like,
so I went from beating go
hockey to losing Johnnie Walker.
Thank God Johnny Walker
has been as good as,
he hasn't has made a name for
himself, but still like, yeah,
I just didn't want to be like a,
I guess like a a foot in
or what do they call it?
Like a a journeyman. Yeah. Not a
journeymen, but like when they said like,
you're trying to get like your foot in
the door or something like that, like
someone said it on, on Instagram, I
saw it like a few times, but um, yeah,
I just didn't want to like
just be another guy that,
you know, what could possibly
give somebody their shot
into the UFC. I was like,
Oh, let me fight a guy that's
in the UFC this time. Well,
so now that you did and you had
the fight with Eric Anderson,
you have this spectacular result and now
you know, people recognizing that you,
you, you've made some big improvement.
Like what caliber fighter, like who, who,
who do you think would propel your career?
Like what would be the best next step?
Uh,
I mean definitely I think it's time for
me to break somewhere into the top 15
you know, for sure nowhere in the
guys that are at the very top because
they're all kind of tie it up. They're
all pretty tied up, you know? And I,
I definitely think it'll be a while
before I can actually fight Jones because
just like how things are,
how things are laid out.
Like I know for sure Johnny walkers
ranked and he's already kind of like in
talks like he's the guy to be Jon Jones,
so sure they're going to
try to set that up right.
And then there's like kind of the
set of guys in the middle, um,
to Johnnie Walker fucking shoulder
up and who's doing that worm thing?
Supposedly. Supposedly.
But I think he's fine.
I think he's fine because I've had
people call me in like, Hey, I just
see this Johnny Walker guy down down,
like on the street everyday.
I guess he's back in Thailand now.
So he did that flop around
thing and then he could,
when he got up he couldn't move.
His shoulder dislocate is
located or something like that.
I think that's what happened.
That's so insane after, right? Yeah.
I think you called it out like most like
what's going on, man. Yeah, he's um,
I hope he doesn't, didn't permanently
injured his shoulder. Nah,
I think you might be
fine. I hope so. Yeah.
He's not walking around in a
slag or anything right now,
but he could have a little, but
yeah, after your fight with him,
he's made quite an account of himself.
Yeah.
That last fight with that flying
knee was insane. Yeah. So I'm sure.
I'm sure before I get to the top I'd have
to find a game. Right. What's up Jim?
Yeah, I would imagine. Yeah.
Is currently recuperating
from his shoulder surgery
after dislocating shoulder
surgery. Dude, two shoulder surgery.
That's fucked up.
Crazy.
I've never known anybody to have shoulder
surgery and come back like with a full,
fully Andre Ward.
Andrew Ward had shoulder surgery
and came back better than ever.
But he's also got the best
doctors. Sure. To make a long time.
Two months from a comeback
because what he says,
he hopes to fight the Winter
Gustafson, Anthony's, Thomas Smith.
He better take his time. It doesn't
want of a fucking shoulder up forever,
you know, if it rips again, that's a
great fight. Anthony Smith and Gustafson,
that's a great fight. And you
know, Anthony Smith Account, he,
he really held his own, like he made a
good account of himself in that fight.
He didn't win the fight, but you know,
he showed everybody how tactical he is,
especially in that first round.
Yeah, for sure. Real good and sharp.
John's just pat her. It was just,
John's just better, you know,
I mean for now he just has his number.
I mean,
in the John Jones that you're
seeing now is a Jon Jones.
It sort of has like a real goal in mind.
But yeah,
he's had it taken away
from him and it gave,
they gave it back to him and now he knows
he has it and he's capitalizing on it.
It seems like it, it's just like he knows
what it's like to be, to be the best,
but not be able to, to really
like do anything about it. Right.
For a long amount of time.
Yeah. So I think it's,
I think it's pretty cool to be able
to see this version of them and,
and to be active around
this time. Maybe, you know,
maybe I'll get a shot or maybe
he'll still be around at the top.
Like whenever I get my shot.
When you see how it goes.
If you had a timeline in your head of
when you think you'd be ready to challenge
for a title,
when do you think it would be?
Uh,
oh,
I can give it another year. Yeah.
I think I can get one,
one more year,
a year and a half of good solid fights
in to really solidify myself and just in
the UFC and uh,
and just put in the work and
everything that, that it,
that it takes to really embody what I
think it would be like what I think it
would take to be a champion as champion.
Not just like get the belt and lose it,
you know, like give the
bell and then, and then, uh,
just be a champion for,
you know, a couple months.
Like not to actually be a champion
and, and, and hold it down.
I think little ovary,
well it's an unbelievably
talent rich wig class. Right?
Cause to me a still kind of in it
[inaudible] Jon Jones is the champion.
You know, he just got off the
Anthony Smith Phi Anthony Smith,
Gustafson Gustafson,
still a beast.
But no one is like really standing out
as being like this person that everybody
wants to see challenge for the title.
You've got worthy challengers,
they're good fights,
but there's no one that you're seeing
them except Cormier was the only one we
seen him versus John, you're like, Whoa,
what the fuck is gonna happen here?
What's going to happen here? And that's
what the division needs I think. Yeah, no,
definitely.
And that's something that,
that I can also see and that's something
that I also want to do that for myself.
I just,
I want to be the best version and I'm
starting to find out what that's like,
especially with like the happy,
like being able to do what I,
what I want to do and strike high.
I want to strike itself.
So now like let's get some, some
fights in there to mix it up. Yeah.
Really like test that
test. If it works, test,
if that's really going to be able to,
to sustain and,
and what it takes to get to get there.
You know what I mean?
Like I'm willing to test it. Like if
they want to put me up against the,
the best grappler in the world and things
that I'll have no chance on the ground.
Okay, cool. Or if they want to put
me against, well they already did.
They thought I wouldn't stand a chance
against Gokhan Saki and like I was very
happy for that because I go,
I'm like okay cool.
I get to test the best of my abilities.
Like there's like against a legend. Yeah.
I didn't like, I knew that I had
everything it took to beat him but I,
I didn't think like Ah, he's going
to destroy me. No, never. Like,
so I want to continue to be tested.
It's an interesting your approach because
I wonder if the fact that you were
such a non confrontational guy and you
are really easy going helps you and that
you have like less conflict in your head.
I also,
I'm also wander because even the way you
approach like these different match ups
and everything you like,
you kind of put your ego aside,
you're looking at the like what
does the smart thing to do here?
A smart thing to do is not take this
fight against this newcomer guy where he
lost a newcomer guys.
The smart thing is,
okay we realize that Thailand
was extremely beneficial.
Let's fucking move to Thailand. Yeah.
So you're doing all these like really,
really smart moves where you know,
you're,
you're looking at it very logically,
but you have confidence in
yourself but you're not,
you don't really not like a braggy guy.
You know,
you're getting everything
done with your work. You know,
you're getting everything done
with your results. It's uh,
it's interesting to see maybe cause you
want to see as many different kinds of
fighters as possible and you're
like a new kind of thing.
That's the most important
thing though, man. Like I, I don't,
I don't really tune in too much UFC and
like what's going on because of that
reason. Right. I don't care about
what people have to say in this.
I don't watch fighting to hear
what people have to say, you know,
like I didn't fight. Like it's not
about talking, it's about fighting.
And the only thing that I can prove and
have to prove is what I can do with my
skills. That's it. You know?
So like if they put me,
they put me against any type
of other fighter. Like if,
let's go back to the roots
of mixed martial arts,
let's go back to the roots of UFC.
Like when guys weren't even the same
size and they were just matching up
different martial arts, like
be down for that. I mean,
I'd consider it and if the, if it,
if it had to happen now, like yeah,
I definitely think about it and I'd
probably lean more towards doing it and
saying, no. Do you have
guys trash talk you
like you're pretty easy going guy. Easy
going. It's, it's nothing to my face.
It's always subtle. If, if I ever
hear about anybody saying something,
it's just through word of mouth and
I'm just like, yeah, we'll, we'll,
you never had like a Conor McGregor
type incident where always only in the
beginning with Paul Craig,
but I think it was just,
it was just like his thing. We've
like, we smashed that beef, you know?
That's good. Yeah. But what do you think
about trash talking in this day and age?
Because in, in many ways, look,
Connor is an amazing fighter
and his fighting skills,
what's made him such an
international superstar,
but he'll also talk some mad shit.
And that helped him too because he
was so good at it. It was funny.
He would say funny mean and salting
shit. It was fucking great. 100%. Yeah.
But I think what people forget, Joe
is I like, that's always been Connor.
Even when you go and, and,
and, and look at the, the,
the interviews from before he was a,
in the UFC and he was just like,
I'm going to make a bunch of money.
I'm going to be all this.
And so if like he created
that for himself and yeah,
he made a bunch of money from talking
trash because he always had a plan that
that's was, that's what
he was going to do. Yeah.
And so I think people try to hop on it
just to sell tickets or gain money and
sometimes it works.
It gets people wanting to watch and it
gets your name up and stuff like that.
But that's not the time.
But name I want to make for myself,
like I don't like people
talking trash to me.
So I'm not really gonna talk trash to
anybody unless there's something that's
really personal. But if I don't
know you and I don't care about you,
then I don't really consider it.
If like why would I talk trash?
I don't even care about you.
It's a waste of energy.
It's a waste of like I got so much
other stuff to care about her.
Yeah. It was a very healthy look, man.
I mean, so the way you saying that,
he said healthy,
like I like,
I like to maintain a healthy heart and
mind as much as possible to its damn man.
Like mental health is a real thing
like this, you know what I mean?
And especially like, especially
just having certain obligations and,
and just using social media and having
people reach out and they say like, oh,
ignore this, ignore
that. But it's like, man,
it's like I'm s it's hard to just
ignore certain things, you know,
like you still see things and so just
that and condition of the world and just
everything,
man,
being in multiple different countries
and here in this news and that news and
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Like for a person who like,
who wants to care about the world,
they're just genuinely cares,
like a lot can go on in my
mind. So I'm just like, ah,
I don't even want that in my heart,
man.
I'm just going to do my best to
kind of keep my own peace and uh,
come fight time. I let it loose, dude.
I liked the way you live it, man.
You got a great approach, man. That's
it. Appreciate happiness is important.
It is, man. It's a great message too,
man. And the tab would come from you. God,
I love those kinds of stories.
Where guys life was fall fucked
up and you figured it out man.
And you put it together,
man.
Tell me like nothing feels
better than just like being
fucking happy. Yeah, right?
Like when you're just, when you're okay
with your life and you're okay with your,
your, your, your, your heart and your
integrity. When you just feel like,
you know what, I have not, I haven't
done anything wrong. I'm, I'm okay.
I like life is happening the
way it is and I have not,
I don't have to think about did I fuck
this person over? Do I do this? Like no,
everything is okay. Yeah. So why
welcome anything else? Like no man,
clear mind, clear heart.
It's a rare thing.
It's rare feat to achieve balance
and balance is hard to maintain.
So it's like, it takes a little bit
of fighting. It takes meditation,
it takes anger,
it takes like Yin and Yang is the most
beautiful thing ever been like that is
life, that is life. It
really is the opposite.
The balance of opposites is constant.
The constant flow.
Like that's why I love just reading
like the Tao Te Ching and like just like
Kundalini Yoga, like all the like cool,
like spiritual stuff. I'm like, yeah man,
this is it. Like it just helps me to just
kind of reach for this like this piece,
this light. That's just, that's awesome.
Do you see the contradiction and reaching
for that piece and light while you're
smashing people? Yes. And that's
not, that's life. That's life man.
That's life. You know, like like a
battery. Right. In order for it to,
to give its power, like it's got
to have the negative and positive,
like energy's flowing
through it and it's like,
I feel like a lot of the times
people are too focused on one side,
like too much negative or
too much positive and you
needed a good amount of both
in order for that. Like that, that
energy to spark. So well said.
You're a wise man. I appreciate
you, man, and thanks for
coming on the show. And, um,
I can't wait to, uh, do commentary
for warranty fights again, man.
Can't wait to have you there.
It's really fun animation.
We had a good fucking time and that was
great. Thank you. Thank you. Smacked
it was great,
man.