Ladies and gentlemen,
man,
the Internet is a fucking crazy plays.
I need some positive uh,
positive stuff cause I fucked up today,
this morning,
got up this morning to my usual stuff,
checked my email,
handled some business.
Uh,
it was sitting there drinking a little
Kombucha and I read my message board
and uh,
I read this plan parenthood thread.
I'm just tweeting and um,
I read about Dee,
I don't know if you guys
know what's going on.
The uh,
planned parenthood was they were accused
of selling fetuses and actually not
just selling fetuses but making deals to
deliver more intact fetuses and talking
about um,
the body parts as a,
as line items.
And I was like,
well,
come on,
that can't be real.
So a,
call me,
Pete is the gentleman who put it up
on the website on the message board.
If you're having a problem,
join that message board.
By the way.
We switched hosts and there was
just a giant fuck up along the way.
And along the way,
there was some fun around
13,000 spam accounts signed up.
They were just fake,
like a bunch of numbers,
like six,
seven,
eight nine 10,
six seven eight nine 10 11,
six,
seven eight nine 10 11,
12 like that kind of shit
like a bunch of them.
So we have to figure out a
way to filter that stuff out.
But we'll,
we'll let people in soon anyway,
the video,
uh,
if you want to search for the video,
the video on youtube,
if you really want to watch it,
it's intact.
Fetuses in quotes,
just a matter of line items
for planned parenthood.
So I watch it and the video's disturbing.
First of all,
it's disturbing the way this woman is
talking about fetuses and you know,
it's,
it's Kinda creepy the way
she's talking about the,
uh,
there's buyers that want
these specimens and their,
I guess their for medical
tasks or for scientific tests,
it's hard to,
it's hard to sit through the whole thing
and then they get deep into video and
that's where it gets really fucking
disturbing because the people that are
buying ask if they can see some of the
product or some of the samples I think is
the word they used.
So the woman says,
well from the abortion say they're all
just in like a big pile and they say,
well,
it's okay.
We just,
you know,
we would like to go see him.
So they go to this pile and um,
they start picking things out with
tweezers including fully intact arms with
hands,
like a little baby arm that's maybe,
you know,
an inch and a half long,
two inches long with fingers and um,
you know,
they're talking about it
just like you would talk about
like how you grow tomatoes.
Like,
well,
if you get tomatoes that
are like six weeks old,
they look like that.
If you get them to their
12 weeks old to get more,
more parts,
dude,
it's fucking really disturbing because
they're pulling these things out with
tweezers.
Oh,
this is a lung.
was that,
can he,
can he see the Thalamus?
Well,
it's hard to tell him this big pile.
It's a pile of parts man.
And it,
it,
first of all,
if you've ever had an abortion and
you know someone's had an abortion,
we've had a girlfriend or you personally,
um,
you don't think about what
exactly is going on there.
But when you look at
this pile of these parts,
you're forced to recognize exactly what
it is and then you forced to wonder
what's going on through the minds of
these people that are just talking about
them and referring to them in quotes.
Just a matter of line items.
And this is fucking pile of baby parts
that they sucked out of a woman's body or
a bunch of women's bodies.
It's disturbing.
I,
uh,
I remember seeing this video because they,
it was made for a recent bill or
something like that in Congress that,
that,
uh,
the antiabortion people
put as a shock video.
I scare video and I thought
it was fully debunked.
Uh,
I didn't know that that
was actual real thing.
I was at Philly debunked.
Um,
I guess the video makes it show it was
supposed to be one of those like Gotcha
videos,
uh,
where it's,
it's,
it's mixing lies with like real stuff
that they actually do in the video.
And,
uh,
I thought for sure it was debunked,
but maybe I was wrong.
I didn't really look into it too much,
but I don't remember.
It was debunked.
Um,
and you can figure out a way to pull up
a link that says us debunk what planned
parenthood hoax really proves right
wing extremis have no qualms about
destroying people's lives.
And when does this come out?
Uh,
this came out July 16th.
Um Hm.
This is that salon.com though,
by the way,
which is an insanely left wing side.
Yeah.
Um,
so let's just Google it just to see.
Planned parenthood video.
White House says planned
parenthood videos are fake.
Well,
what's fake?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean,
it's not the real people.
Um,
okay.
New Planned parenthood video,
baby parts buyer jokes about shipping
severed heads two hours ago from the
weekly standard.
This is a new video,
the latest undercover planned parenthood
videos and interview with Kate Dyer,
CEO of an organization called stem
express that buys a boarded baby parts for
planned parenthood and
sells them to researchers.
There are no graphic images in this video,
but DIYers,
comments about shipping
the severed intact.
Uh,
I don't know what that word is.
Cow
calve.
Cal-Vet for calvarium.
Calvarial hmm.
Calvarium calvarium or
skull of an aborted baby.
Uh,
our bone chilling stem express,
they say,
uh,
I know we get requests for neural tissue.
Uh,
it's the hardest thing
in the world to ship.
The buyer says,
uh,
you do it as a whole.
Calvarial I guess that's the
whole head and stem expresses.
Yeah,
that's it.
Yeah.
That's the easiest way.
And I mean,
we've actually had good
success with that in the past.
Buyer says,
yeah,
make sure the eyes are closed.
And then stem express loud,
laughter,
tell the lab it's coming so
they don't open the box and go,
Oh God,
laughter.
So yeah.
Whereas so many of the academic
labs cannot fly like that.
They're just not capable.
Buyer says,
why is that?
I don't understand that stem express as,
it's almost like they don't want
to know where it comes from.
I can see that where
they're like in quotes,
we need limbs but no hands
and feet need to be attached.
We want to take it all off,
like in quotes,
make it so that we don't know what it is.
Okay.
This is,
um,
I don't know what his debunked and what's
not be bunked about that because it
seems like in the conversation,
I mean,
look,
when they're digging through
that bag of baby parts,
which was the most disturbing part of it.
Um,
look,
if people are going to get abortions,
I personally do not have a problem with
them taking the aborted fetal tissue and
using it for scientific experiments.
Because the aborted fetal
tissue already exists.
They're already having abortions
and if abortions are legal,
shouldn't there be something done with
that aborted fetal tissue that may be
beneficial to humanity?
Shouldn't there be a way
that they can experiment?
I mean it's not like they're asking people
to get abortions that would normally
have kept the baby and loved them
and brought them to adulthood.
They're there,
they're going to have the abortions.
So if they are going
to have the abortions,
is it such a bad thing to use that fetal
tissue for scientific experimentation?
That's not the,
the disturbing part about it disturbing
part about is the visual aspect of
seeing the
yeah,
the body position.
You shouldn't see that
is what pretty much sad.
But you know what,
what this article on the Huffington post
is saying is that what they did is they
took shocking video of,
you know,
borsch things,
which is going to be disgusting anyways.
And they're saying that planned
parenthood's making all this money off of
selling all the parts to,
you know,
in,
in what planned parenthood
is saying is no,
we just donate it to the,
to,
to science and,
and,
and people that want to use
it for medical research.
So that's not what was going on
video.
And the video,
the woman was talking about the amount
of money that they would get doing it and
it was thousands of dollars a week.
And that's why they see this.
They're saying that's a hoax.
And they're saying that the,
what you're watching
wasn't what the audio was.
And uh,
wait a minute,
that doesn't make any sense
cause you see the woman's say it,
that group behind the videos is facing
at least two lawsuits because it's fake.
Is it an huff post?
Huff Post.
Let's see here is on CNN.
And what does CNN saying?
They're saying it's a hoax too.
Yeah.
There's a company created
to go against the left wing.
I oversee a group called acorn.
And,
uh,
throughout this article,
it also says
the Acorn is the same
company that they were,
uh,
they were accused of,
they were trying,
people were trying to get funds
for creating prostitutes or for a,
for pimping member.
Remember that whole
thing where there was a,
a bunch of people that
are trying to get funds.
The first part here,
it says there's a fake company set up
called biomax procurement services and
that was the hoax.
And then according to this is the
hoaxers website was a 30 month long
investigative journalism study by the
center of Medical Progress documenting how
planned parenthood it sells
body parts for board at babies.
Right.
Um,
that's not true.
That's not true.
They don't sell them.
It's flat out untrue.
So,
well what was the woman in the
thing she was talking about body,
right
radio.
They were baiting them into
conversations about others,
about sales selling stuff.
It says that it really don't do that.
They were just trying to
get them to say it kind of
did get him to say it.
So what is the deal?
She was talking about the bottom line
about how much money they could make and
how much money she could add to the,
so was she like a rogue
lady for planned parenthood?
That's what they're saying.
And they're also saying that like,
you know what I mean?
This bill that was passing was going
to cut off all funding to planned
parenthood.
So this was like a full on attack trying
to get rid of planned parenthood by
anti-abortionists.
Jeremy,
scroll back down.
We went back where you were again.
Um,
the details of the processes are enough
to trouble anyone nonmedical people
don't talk about the price of requesting,
removing or shipping Oregon's pieces
of flesh for the from place to place.
Most of us would freak out if we
listened to professionals and the local
hospital,
funeral home or medical examiners
office discuss details about how a dying
person's request to have their body parts
donated for transplants or scientific
research actually gets carried out.
It turns out that the cadavers livers,
okay.
They don't walk themselves over to the
local hospital or a medical school for
free.
I just don't understand the outrage was
that for a lot of folks was that they
were selling these a baby parts.
Right?
So that is or isn't true.
It's not true.
So why was that a woman
saying in the video?
Because it's a big hoax video.
That's why she has to give to Lawson.
But without,
without further explaining,
is it because the woman was
actually saying those things?
So what part is a hoax?
Because you were also sad that that
woman was kind of rogue because she was
saying,
she was talking about how much
money they could make from it.
I'm really confused.
Like what is the hook?
So I understand that the people that were,
um,
that were making the video weren't really
what they were sending you saying they
were right.
These people,
they set this up and they got
inside of planned parenthood.
The way they were going through the,
um,
the body parts,
the way they were picking
up the body parts and,
but that was all real.
I mean,
there's 100% real,
the way there's,
there's no way.
It wasn't unless they're rubber
baby parts and they had actors.
Is there a chance to,
the audio you were hearing wasn't what,
that's what they're
saying match up the video,
the people's faces.
You could see him saying it.
Me and Lizzie was just fucking brilliantly
done by terrorists that says that if
you plow through the transcripts,
you won't see what that,
I mean,
all this also could be talking about a
separate video from what you just saw
maybe.
But uh,
these fucking things are so,
so confusing.
So there's a new or newly released video
that just came out that's a literally
two hours ago,
um,
online and this is the stem express CEO.
I don't know man.
It's um,
it's fucking,
it's just,
it's really one of those things.
Abortion,
it becomes one of those left or right
issues where you're either a left wing
person,
you support abortion or
you're right wing person.
You'd think it's terrific.
I,
uh,
I support people's right to
do whatever they want to do.
I totally support people's
right to have abortions,
but at a certain point in time,
like when is an abortion
completely fucked up?
Like when you have a nine month old baby
inside you and decide to kill it before
it comes into your vagina.
It's why it's illegal.
Yeah.
But at a certain point in time that
baby's still viable outside the womb.
But you could still have an abortion.
Yeah.
What does it say?
And I mean they changed it so many times.
I think it,
is it like six week or no,
it's something.
It's something,
it's not too crazy.
Maybe it's six weeks.
It's like two or three months
or something like that.
I think it's the most,
they were talking about 22 week old.
They were talking,
they were talking about like when you can
like really pick out Oregon's and when
he could see them.
You know,
that's all.
That's fucking four,
eight,
12 I mean think about it,
when you start going into at
six months old that's like,
Whoa,
that's a,
that's a fucking baby.
I would really like to know
what this statistics is.
If what you know,
if you're going to get an abortion,
how long until you wait.
Because I,
I,
it seems like most people I know,
once they find out they're pregnant,
they're like,
next day I'm getting an abortion,
you know,
cause they had sex with you.
But
I wonder how many people are like,
you know,
like three months in like,
you know what,
I think I don't want this baby.
That's when it gets kinda
creepy in my opinion.
Yeah.
Well we all know people that
are completely irresponsible
and if you give them a
way to justify anything and so they don't
have to take responsibility for it and
just take,
take it out of me.
You know,
they don't want to think if they
don't see it in front of them,
they don't think of it as a baby.
The question really becomes,
should you be allowed to do that?
And it's not my call.
I don't know who's called is.
I don't know.
I mean some people think it's their call,
some people think that they should be
blown up abortion clinics and shooting
doctors and you know,
they decided that they're there
to protect the children and uh,
that gets pretty fucked up too.
And it also gets pretty hypocritical
because those are the same kind of people
that are supportive of war.
You know,
once your kid eats,
reaches 18 or if that
kids from another country,
fuck them.
Now this is weird,
but it was,
it was real weird looking
at the unescapable reality,
that video.
So whatever,
whatever's fake or real in the
conversations that they're having,
um,
there's no denying at
all those body parts.
And that's where it gets really crazy.
Well,
we all knew that existed.
I,
you know,
when,
when you get an abortion,
what it usually is like a,
like a car wash,
like,
uh,
you know,
vacuum,
it's like a,
it's a big tube and it
goes into like a humongous,
like little pot or a at tank or whatever.
So,
you know,
if you're going to look in that tank
and you're going to see you just not,
you're not supposed to see it,
you know?
Well,
yeah.
That's isn't that it's kind
of part of the problem,
right?
They're not supposed to see it.
Yeah.
I mean,
if you look at anything like that,
you're going to be like,
that's fucked up.
Yeah,
but it's,
that is the fuck
dup one,
right?
Because babies are helpless
and once they're alive,
we want to take care of them.
And here you've got these people with
tweezers picking up arms with little
fingers attached to it.
It's like,
Whoa,
whatever is in that video that's fake.
You know?
That's not,
that's,
that's terrifying.
I don't know.
You know,
I don't know what's a live,
I'll Google debunked and I'm sure
there's a a lot that tells you,
but it's just left wing sites are saying
it's debunked or right wing sites are
continuing to promote it.
It gets really weird.
Ooh,
what a bummer.
What a,
what a bad way to start
off the puck right now.
Yeah,
that's what I saw.
That's how I started on my morning.
That and the Cecil,
the lion,
his cousin who killed a fucking safari
guide and the same in the same place
where Cecil the lion got killed.
This fucking guy was leading
walking photographic safari tours.
So the safari guide for the
walking photographic safari
tour got taken out by a
lion.
The lion was like,
what are you doing outside the GP
dumped fuck and just just jacked him.
It's hilarious that people are that
stupid that they think they think they can
walk around where lions are walking
around in this enormous enormous park in
Zimbabwe where lions are protected.
Have you ever been to one of those like
safari tours where like the animals come
right up and like the lines and the
monkeys just jump on your car or anything
like that?
Um,
I've been to one of those wild animal
parks in New Jersey to do that.
It was a,
it was real weird.
It just,
it just feels goofy.
Like you're in your car and there's
monkeys jumping on your car and they'll
break your windshield wipers.
They do all kinds of
fucked up shit to car.
I don't even know if that
place is still open anymore,
but it's just,
it's odd.
They would let you drive
around in your car and a,
you'd be on this tour
and that means better,
I guess than the zoo.
But it's gotta be fucked
up for the monkeys because
it's like the same thing is
looking at people through glass,
except you're looking at people through
glass that moves on rubber wheels and
you're just looking at these people
that are free and you're stuck in this
enclosure and they're
driving into your house.
You know,
they're on a road,
but it said it was weird.
It's,
it's like there's something
fucked up about zoos.
Just something really
All of them,
you know,
less fucked up for some animals.
Like my joke about giraffes that
giraffe seem to be pretty happy.
The zoo,
like babies can feed them.
It's like,
it's true man.
My three year old,
when she was,
well when she was three rather,
we brought her to the zoo and she was
feeding giraffes with her hand and there
was no worry at all.
Everybody's laughing
and having a good time.
No giraffe has ever fucked up a
kid at the zoo for feeding it.
It'd be really interesting to see
if animals could talk to me like,
no dude,
you don't understand.
I get to hang out here
to see people feed me.
I don't have to do shit here.
Like it might be the Cecil
the lion killer costume.
Is it coming out or it has come out.
Uh,
which is interesting that
they would actually do that.
It's actually a decapitated
lion with a dentist,
uh,
outfit with blood all
over the dentist outfit.
And the guy that owns the company said
that they've had so many requests for it.
So that,
I guess that's a thing that's this
hallway Halloween Cecil the lion cost of
course that had to come out.
Yeah.
You knew that was coming out.
I mean,
who?
Who didn't see that coming?
There it is Cecil.
The lion splattered all over.
The guy's still in hiding.
Huh?
Nobody's seen that dude.
I think I heard just the other day
he opened up his business to know,
have you looked at her page?
That's not good.
I heard a,
I heard he was going to reopen
up his business in September.
That's Kinda fucked up.
But Yelp,
because they're not even
reviewing his business.
They didn't go and yet their teeth,
teeth
cleaned or io.
I hope I haven't looked lately,
but I hope Yelp stepped in because I mean,
yeah,
it got where it was just
deadlines and his like,
like photos.
Whereas dentist office was his deadlines
and photos upload photos of sued,
stuff like that.
This,
this is my lion after I
brought it to the dentist.
Wow.
So TMZ did a poll with
almost 16,000 votes,
if that was funny or
offensive about the Cecil.
The lion costume in 66%
said that's offensive.
You know why?
Because there's 66% of
people so fucking stupid.
They post on CNN.
TMZ that those people are apes.
Those are people too dumb for Youtube.
Like youtube is like,
you're too stupid for our comments.
You got to go over,
you've got to go post over there.
What do you think?
Finally throwing one from my
opinion was thinking the fountain
because he's one of the beautiful animal.
Jimmy Kimmel cried.
Jimmy Kimmel crying,
I'm going to cry to Jimmy Kimmel
gave me the green light to grow.
It's pretty sad.
Well,
it's fucked up.
It's fucked up that the only way to
save lions is to make them valuable for
hunters.
That's ultimately,
that's the most fucked up thing about it.
You know,
that these people,
the idea that this is like,
there's two types of,
of hunting for conservation
that kind of makes sense to me.
And the like when you have to kill certain
animals because they're killing other
animals.
Like if you have too many lions and
you have to control the population,
but that's not really the case.
Like that kind of hunting for
conservation makes sense to me.
Or if there's like a lot of people
don't realize that that Rhino,
that that guy paid a
shitload of money to shoot.
They were going to kill that rhino anyway.
They had to kill that rhino cause
that rhino was killing other,
the rhinos.
And when they do that,
they,
they have to uh,
this is a like a non-viable mail.
It's not breeding anymore.
And so it was attacking other males and
killing them and even tact female and
killed it.
They think so that's,
that's an animal they have to kill.
So if,
if you get a guy who's willing to
pay you a shitload of money to cook,
kill that Rhino that you were already
going to kill and then that money goes to
conservation.
That makes sense.
So those are the two
cases we're hunting for.
Conservation makes sense to me.
Other than that,
hunting for food is the only
thing that makes sense to me.
I don't get the idea of hunting like an
animal just because you want to like add
it to your collection.
I think that's kind of fucked
up unless it's the only thing.
The only time it makes sense
is that it has to be killed.
They don't have to kill those lines.
There's not enough of lions
that they have to kill them.
It's not like there's an
overwhelming number of lions,
like they have to take them out because
they were eating each other like bears
and Alberta I think got a real
problem with bears in Alberta.
They have too many of them,
so that's why they let
you kill two of them.
They're like,
please come up here and
kill some fucking bears.
They have a real problem with La,
with a wolves up there in a BC.
They don't even have a limit.
You can kill as many wolves as you one PC.
They want you to kill him because
they're fucking everywhere.
They kill people's cows.
And those are the times we're hunting
for conservation makes sense to me.
But this lion thing,
these,
these are rich dudes that want to go
over there and they want to fill their
trophy rooms up and that's,
that's a real natural reaction
that people have that that's gross.
So just to like,
it's just so everyone knows I'm not on
the side of killing lions or anything,
giraffes,
anything,
unless it's for food.
They say the thing about lines is like,
they kill that Rhino.
Everybody ate that Rhino.
The villagers came and they fucking,
they fed hundreds of people with that.
Rhino.
Rhino is apparently tastes good
like rhinos apparently or like,
like beef almost.
And that all these people
were excited to cut off,
uh,
pieces of that rhino and have protein.
Nobody's lining up to eat a lion.
You know,
that's stuff.
Apparently though
mountain lion tastes good.
Mountain lion supposedly tastes just
like pork and it's apparently something
that people have been eating since they,
uh,
since the pioneers came to America,
I never got it.
It's supposedly good with
like a blueberry sauce.
They make like Loin,
like want mountain line loin.
I would try it.
I would definitely shoot
a fucking mountain line.
Those cons,
eight,
my dog and I don't like him.
I don't trust him.
They're just running around in our woods
and there was no shortage of me either.
Especially in California.
California is so goofy.
They don't have a mountain lion season
in California because we don't have a
department of fishing game in California.
We have a department of fish and wildlife.
It has a totally different like
nomenclature attached to it.
And because of that,
like it's run by like wildlife lovers
more than it's run by like hunting
advisers.
So like in every other state,
they look at the game numbers,
they look at the mountain lions,
they look at like and they
try to manage it accordingly.
And they also trying to manage it because
you get a lot of money from hunting
tags and California,
they,
they're less concerned with that.
And because of that they lose out on
a lot of money on hunting tags cause
they'll have,
they'll have less hunters because
they literally have less deer.
And the reason why they have less direct
cause they have more mountain mines.
It's,
it's a real controversial thing with h
with the hunting in California as opposed
to with every other state.
It's interesting.
It's all interesting stuff.
It's like what,
what people decide and not decide
that you can eat because there's all,
or what you can kill.
Because in these places where
they have these hunting laws,
you can just drive down
the street like California,
drive down any street and you're just
going to pass by Jack in the box and
burger king and chicken
places and they're filled.
Filled.
Yeah.
California.
And finally has wolves.
Yay.
Great Wolf pack of wolves.
Fantastic wait fucking disaster.
We put him there or did they just kind of,
when we put them in Idaho,
we put them in a lot of other states
and they're making their way down to
California now.
And what's the purpose is having
wolves to take to kill these people are
assholes.
They forget.
Uh,
there was a story that I
tweeted the other day about um,
famous,
uh,
strong men throughout history,
famous athletes throughout history.
And one of them was a guy who,
uh,
tried to,
split these two trees and he got stuck
in between the two trees and he got eaten
by wolves.
This is like in the,
you know,
the BC days,
but the,
I mean,
we've talked about this
numerous times on the podcast.
How many people throughout
history have been eaten by wolves?
That was a huge issue until people
started killing the fuck out of wolves.
And that's why we look at wolves now.
Like there are dogs.
We'd look at them like their pets.
They were never pets before.
They were always these
terrifying animals that,
that,
that killed human beings.
That's why they were
always a part of folklore.
That's why they were always a part of
stories like the Little Red Riding Hood
story or Goldie locks.
I mean there's always a,
the three pigs,
there was always stories of the big bad
wolf because wolves were something that
everybody was really scared of.
The wolves in Paris,
story from the 14 hundreds wolves killed,
I think it was something
like 40 people in Paris,
France in the 14 hundreds before they,
they fucking rallied together and
killed these goddamn things in.
During World War One,
the Russians and the Germans
literally stopped shooting each other.
They had a cease fire so they could kill
wolves because there was so many people
getting killed by wolves.
These soldiers would be on patrol
and they would never find them.
They're like,
what the fuck?
And they'd go and they'd find like a
foot that was still stuck in a boat and
their bodies would be
eat and wolves were just,
they were getting these super packs of
wolves of a hundred wolves together and
they would just kill people.
That's always been the case.
Just,
we eradicated them from our lives and
we'd no longer have a threat of moles,
but now they,
they implanted them,
they took them from Canada where
they have a real problem with them.
Where I do,
like I said in BC,
you can kill as many wolves as you want.
You can go to BC right now and
you can kill 50 wolves today.
If you could find 50 wolves,
you can kill them all
and they want you to,
cause they're hard to kill.
They're hard to find.
They're smart shit.
They worked together in packs and
they decimate moose populations.
Uh,
they decimate elk,
deer,
cows,
whatever the fuck.
They get a hold,
they'll eat your dog,
they'll eat everything they get
ahold of and that's what they do.
They run around,
they eat things.
So some,
I'm sure goofy liberal conservationists
decided to take these wolves and bring
them from northern Canada and these big
ass fucking gray wolves and bring them
down to a America.
Here's a picture that
Jamie just pulled out,
wolf attack,
scroll down so I can read that again.
Sorry.
Wolf attack leads to state of
emergency and Siberia's and Russia.
Siberia region is two years ago,
there was 400 wolves in a
super pac running around.
She says,
fuck the governor of
Russia's largest reasons.
Declared a state of emergency
after a surge of wolf attacks.
Fuck walls,
man.
People are just so goofy.
We have this beautiful
thing that we've created.
We've created an amazing thing and cities,
you know,
you go to the grocery store,
you get your food,
you walked down the street,
you hold hands with your kids.
No one's looking over
their shoulder for bears.
And because of that,
we have this real detachment from the
rest of the natural world that is outside
of our cities.
And we live our whole lives and these
cities and our perspective of animals is
completely shaped by these cities.
But these animals out there
don't give a fuck about you.
They don't give a fuck about your city.
They exist to eat and kill things.
They don't have language.
They don't have culture.
They live.
They don't care about you.
And all our ideas about them
are all from the lion king.
And some fucking goofy
ass cartoons and movies,
the anthropomorphize
versions of these animals.
It's really ridiculous.
And that's where all the Cecil,
the lion king shit comes from.
Cecil the lion king.
That's where all this
Cecil outrage comes from.
Meanwhile,
Justin Wren,
who was on the podcast yesterday told
us that 5,000 children under the age of
five die every day in
Africa from bad water.
Every day,
5,000 human babies die
because they don't have water.
And we're worried about
Elian that by the way killed.
Who knows how many other lions babies
because that's what they do when you see a
male lion and he is successful and
he runs a pride Garr run fucking tee.
That line has been killing baby male
lines cause that's what they do when the
babies are born and it's not theirs,
they just fucking slaughter them.
They slaughter them when they go into a
new kingdom and they take over and they
fucked some females and she's got males,
a little male babies,
they fucking slaughter him.
They chased him down the Killam.
I put a video up of it on the,
on Twitter.
People went crazy.
They went nuts.
Call me an asshole for
putting up a video of nature.
It's nature.
That is,
this is what happens.
So these people that are happy now,
we finally have wolves in California.
It's amazing.
One day it'd be walking with you,
a little cocker Spaniel and a wolf's gonna
come along and eat you and the cocker
spaniel.
It's been a hundred years almost that
since we've had wolves in California.
So I think that's what
they're more amazed at.
Yeah,
these people are so fucking stupid.
Why don't they bring back dinosaurs?
We need more dinosaurs we can to
bring back titanosaurs to Arizona.
There was a,
it was an amazing place when dinosaurs
roamed these to fly phase to fly.
We're going to have cared.
Terra doctorals launch our
first pterodactyl governor.
Yay.
They're gonna open up the cage.
It's going to swoop right back.
Kill the governor.
They released,
somebody released a funny video where
they showed that photo of Steven Spielberg
in front of the dinosaur and they
went to people on the street and go,
what do you think about that?
Almost everybody was just like,
I can't believe he did that.
He should be held accountable,
I guess in this fake trust.
Sarah top.
Yeah.
I guess Nestle a water just got caught
from stealing a bunch of natural water
and so a lot of people are,
uh,
protesting Nestle for stealing,
um,
California water while
we're in this huge drought.
Yeah,
I guess that's real.
Yeah.
Nestle pays only $524 to extract 27
million gallons of California drinking
water.
Come on.
She's like,
for companies get exempt from that.
A water ban on their blog
and they can sell it.
Yeah.
The bottled water and alcohol and all
sort of kind of goofy deals have these
assholes made with politicians that they
could steal water during a drought and
then sell it to us.
Yeah,
that's insane.
For $524,
they stole 27 million gallons of water
from 12 springs and Strawberry Canyon for
the brand.
Isn't that ridiculous?
But yet we can't wash a car,
take a phone over a five minute shower,
corporate America,
folks,
Corporate America.
You know,
corporations are beautiful
and a lot of ways,
I mean,
that's the root why we
have these microphones.
It's why we have these laptops.
It's why we have cell phones.
It's all corporations that created them.
But corporations,
they're all about infinite growth.
They constantly want to make more money.
Every year they're supposed
to make more money.
If a corporation makes you know,
x amount of money one year and then the
same x amount of money the next year,
they're a failure.
Which is hilarious.
That's ridiculous.
Like if they made,
like if apple apple makes
like whatever they make,
let's say,
let's just make a number.
Apple made $4 billion this year,
right?
If they make $4 billion next year,
they failed.
You're supposed to make 4
billion plus the new money.
It's incredible,
man.
It says here,
the most popular size bottle of arrowhead
is one liter and it retails for 89
cents putting the potential profit
for Nestle in the tens of billions.
So they're just making billions of dollars
on water that they've taken from ice
while we're going through a drought.
It only costs 89 cents for
a one liter bottle of water.
Why do I feel like it costs more?
Because the vending machines,
vending machines.
So he's like,
oh yeah.
Fitting machines are a super over price.
The whole thing is gross.
It's gross,
it's gross across the board.
And it's also gross that like there's,
um,
there's a lot of crops
that use this water and um,
there's a lot of waste
involved apparently.
And there have been
bills that were passed,
like Arnold Schwarzenegger
when he was governor,
said that they had come
up with a solution,
um,
at least a partial solution.
And he was bringing it up to one of the
other politicians and the politicians
saying,
even though this is an effective solution,
I could never bring it before my people,
I can never endorse it because my people
are the agricultural people and those
people that keep me in office.
So I'm going to just tell you right now,
well,
we're just gonna create a bunch of
red tape and it'll never get passed.
And even though it's
logical and it makes sense,
I'll never support it.
And he was like,
what the fuck?
Like this is,
this is what's wrong with
politics and this is what's wrong.
When you're dealing with people that
are not really the representation,
they're not really
representatives of people.
They're representatives of
whoever got him in office.
They,
they can pretend to be the of the people.
Sort of like late night preachers,
pretend to be the servants of God.
Really,
they're just making money.
They're making money and they're,
you know,
supposed to give 10% yeah,
well late night preachers,
you,
you don't even,
they don't even want 10%
they want everything.
You got heavy here with a tough,
one of the funniest things that they have
con people into doing is they figured
out a way to tell people like,
I know you don't have any money.
I know,
I know times it's tough,
but what you have to understand is
you have to have faith in the Lord.
Give everything you can.
The Lord will give you that back 10
fold like they tell you if you're broke.
So they're going after people who are
desperate and broke and they had all
these,
these people that would give these,
um,
these speeches there would talk about
what happened to them and they were
saying,
well,
you know,
I was broke and I didn't have
any money and times are tough.
And I was wondering how it was going to
take my bills and how I was going to pay
for food,
but I had this $100 and I was
going to use towards my rent.
But I said,
you know what,
I'm giving this $100 to God.
Everybody starts cheering and clapping.
And then from that,
oh Lord,
I got a new job and I got a new
car and everything happened.
And,
and,
and people are clapping and cheering and
music starts playing and they build it
up and they're just like,
making you come.
They're like,
oh they're like,
it's like this stimulation thing that
they're doing and they're actively
targeting people so stupid that they
really can't do anything about it.
Like these people,
that's like the right people to rip off
cause these people are broke and the
reality is most people
who are severely broke,
they're going to stay broke.
The vast majority,
whatever it is,
60 70 80% pick a number,
they're going to stay broke.
And so that's the ones that they go after.
So it's nobody cares,
nobody cares about them.
Like you get your rip certain people off,
people get really frustrated and
angry and you rip other people off.
Do you think in the future that's going,
that's going to be not
as big of a problem?
Do you think religions
shrinking or growing?
I think religion is
probably overall shrinking,
but stupid people are
always going to exist.
And so if you call it religion or if
you call it a cult or you call it,
I mean there's a,
there's a lot of organizations that don't
necessarily have some sort of a deity
at the top of their,
their structure.
But there's still the same thing.
It's one person who is,
or one group of people,
whether it's Scientology or anything else,
one group of people that is offering you
a solution for how to live your life.
And they have all these guidelines that
they have set up and they want you to
contribute and they want your money,
they want your money and they want
your time and they want you to donate.
Like,
did you see going clear?
Have you seen that?
How fucking scary was that?
I think that any kind call like that is,
or,
uh,
like I just saw a celebrity wife
swap and I know this sounds weird,
but Corey Feldman and Tommy Davidson
where the two people that switched,
uh,
and they really showed you an inside
look of how Corey Feldman treats his,
uh,
Corey angels is what he calls him.
He's trying to do kind of like a cross
between Hugh Hefner and Michael Jackson
or something like that.
He pretty much has
brainwashed these girls,
uh,
to,
to fall anything he says.
And it includes like a contract
that they have to sign.
Oh,
well,
you know that Corey was
an actor his whole life,
right.
You know,
is probably a bullshit artist and it's
most likely that this is a hustle.
Hustle may be,
but I know a girl,
let me say this right,
I know a girl that knows that girl and
that girl used to be one of his angels
and uh,
she left because it was too call like,
and the things that you were,
you had to do once a week,
they would have an orgy and then
that they would just do drugs,
have an orgy,
have people over.
And then the days after that
orgy you would work out to yoga.
I eat healthy and uh,
it's uh,
she,
she said to the her friend how it was
just like brainwashed girls looking for
their chance in Hollywood
and he would be like,
oh no,
you join this and you follow my plan.
And anyways,
the episode goes really into that and it,
it's,
it's watching them talk and watching how
he reacts to the wife swap part of it.
It's very interesting.
It's a,
it almost seems to me that like whatever
had happened to in his past maybe with
Michael Jackson are his childhood,
uh,
is really effecting him as
an adult because he's very,
like,
he's not making any sense.
Uh,
he's,
he's just like not a
ton of drugs first of all.
Right.
And you know,
I know a guy who was in like a
swap situation before and with,
with a UN no need to name celebrity was
the same kind of thing where this guy
like let his wife fuck other people
and then we're all together and uh,
he,
you know,
he came out of it and one of the things
that he said to me when he came out of
it was like,
uh,
you know,
he told me the story.
He was like,
listen man,
they're all fucked up.
Anybody that's involved in that
kind of situation is fucked up.
Like they're all crazy.
Like that's part of what it is.
But if you're in Hollywood
and you're in like that,
like want to be showbiz circle,
just plenty of fucked up people,
you could find plenty of people.
And if you can come up with
some sort of a name for it,
Cory's angels or whatever
the hell he calls it,
Eh,
you could do it.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean l Ron Hubbard was a
fucking moron and he was a moron.
And uh,
his,
uh,
books were terrible.
They were,
they were terrible.
And if you like,
listen to him talk,
he was not a charming guy.
He was not articulate.
He wasn't brilliant.
He wasn't this guy that had this point,
like even like David Koresh,
although he's a dip shit,
he played stupid songs or that the fucking
idiot in Australia that claims he's
Jesus,
they have a certain amount of
confidence and smoothness to them.
L Ron Hubbard didn't have any of that.
And meanwhile,
Scientology became a
gigantic organization.
I think for a lot of people,
the structure,
any sort of structure is comforting
and they're looking for something.
So like,
you know,
get back to the original point,
is religion going away?
There's going to have to be something
big that happens to human beings for
religion to go away.
And I wonder if that big thing,
what would have to,
it would have to be,
people would have to be able to clearly
see what you know and what you don't
know.
It would have to be a fundamental change
in how we communicate because like when
someone tells you,
I know that if you give that $100 to
know load will pay you back 10 fold.
Have you say that to someone who's stupid?
Like okay,
he knows he knows a little pay me back.
I got to give that money and the Lord
was going to pay me back 10 fold.
You know,
you really believe it.
But if you could see that,
oh he doesn't really know that.
If there was like a light bulb that
went over a person's head when they were
telling the truth or you could look in
their eyes and you could see the numbers,
like there's excellent,
you know,
like a Turkey tester you ever,
gobble,
gobble.
You ever see those,
uh,
what's your gates?
Yeah,
those things that put the lights out,
use those anymore.
Yeah.
You probably like leak fucking chemicals.
Probably not supposed to have plastic
inside a Turkey that you're cooking,
but like something along those lines,
like a temperature gauge or a number or
something where you could see whether or
not someone's being honest,
where they really know what they're
saying or whether or not they're
bullshitting.
Yeah.
Well,
what's interesting about this,
Corey Feldman,
they stuck on that sheet.
If you watch it,
you'll be no,
I mean I went frantic on it.
Kind of go.
I'm not going to watch and
we watch a little clip.
I do.
Is Him introducing you,
his angels kicked off of Youtube for your
fucking Corey Feldman week session or
would we
probably,
yeah.
Well we can watch it over there.
Right?
Can we watch over there
and not really watch it?
We can watch it,
but we can't.
Can we play volume?
Maybe.
All right.
We'll see what happens.
Jamie's kept good editing skills.
All right.
Play that bitch over
here and freaked me out.
Go ahead.
In our relationships.
So these are the girls is not,
it is down here.
I was like,
oh,
that girl's hot.
How's it getting that?
Um,
but uh,
it's the one right here.
Meet Corey Feldman and his angels,
the former child actor scroll down,
lives in eccentric and avant
garde lifestyle with his angels.
What avant garde,
what is avant garde mean?
Oh,
look at him.
I'm Corey Feldman.
You probably know me from lost boys
getting e's stand by me and only
started acting and singing simultaneously.
I've been
in singer and musician
for several decades now.
I am a bit eccentric a bit Ivan Guard,
but if I was just like everybody else,
I wouldn't be on your TV sets.
Ooh.
I have a lot of women with their careers
and Hollywood and then I would realize
they went off to be successful.
And what did I get out of it?
Not much.
That's why I developed my company.
Cory's angels.
Cory's angels is a management production
and development business comprised of
beautiful,
talented,
we girls sign a contract with
us so when they do succeed,
I can get rewards as well for
the work that I put it to that
when the girls become angels,
they move into my house.
I see why you're obsessed.
You frankly,
drag van trust model and
I'm one of course angels.
I am Caitlin and I am an aspiring actress,
professional model and
Cory's angel and training.
I'm Courtney.
I'm a Dj and I'm Cory's manger.
Oh,
I,
Oh hell out.
Also,
I'm his girlfriend.
Cory has changed my life in so many ways.
He uses in his own connections
to help me be successful.
He's sexy and gorgeous and I love him.
Is this the polyamorous as far as
what happens behind closed doors?
It stays behind closed doors.
Exactly.
We have a very kind of strict regimens.
Goal number one,
we will put them on the Angel Diet.
That means no meat of any kind.
I'm a fruitarian,
which means that I only eat fruit.
Number two,
exercise like,
go ahead you guys.
Hot.
Number three,
we don't allow men on the property
unless they're inviting guests.
That's how you do it.
This lifestyle is not for the
close minded or faint of heart.
I strive every day to do God's will.
Yay.
So he makes these girls
wear these slutty outfits.
They're not.
They have to wear like
these broad and lingerie's.
They're not allowed to work close.
Hold up.
This is on ABC?
Yeah,
he's on the ABC's going Desperado.
Huh?
Well I tell you desperate as fuck
through written network TV is desperate.
Yeah.
And I was really sad is
that Tommy Davidson was the
guy that they swapped with
and his,
he has like a nice family kids and
so they brought the angel over,
uh,
to his house and the angel's like getting
like Bachelor parties and naked people
in his house went in front
of it's kids and okay.
Okay.
You know that they arrange that.
The producers arranged that.
He seemed pretty pissed off.
He just left the house.
What the fuck course.
And of course he did.
Oh yeah.
I'm sure there's a sea salt.
This is all 100% fake.
Hundred percent arranged.
This is all planned out.
Cory has a fucking one piece of hair waxed
that hangs strategically front of his
face.
Yeah.
I mean this is a scam.
What this is,
is Cory's shot at getting back on TV and
what he's doing is getting those girls
with him and it's working.
It's getting them exposure.
They're getting on TV.
So his plan is to be this guy who's the,
the,
the ringleader.
I'm Cory.
These are Cory's angels.
This is the hustle we're
going to get on ABC.
And he's getting it for them.
But whether or not this is all real,
he's been doing the angel thing for a
long time course cause it says this is
hustle.
This is how he's getting,
it's like a pyramid scam forum.
Sort of.
I mean this is his intertainment shtick.
This is how he's getting
some form of attention.
He,
uh,
when these girls leave the angels,
he has contracts that hit the,
he gets a percentage of
everything they make from that on.
Good.
Good luck.
You're going to get 50 bucks from
the chick who works at Guitar.
Now
what is he gonna make?
I mean if they do get big,
they'll have him killed.
Do you know if one of
those girls gets huge?
She gets it,
becomes the next Rihanna
or whoever the fuck she is.
Who are you still have that car killed?
Please watch it though.
It's on Hulu.
It's,
it just takes smoke a joint,
cut the breaks of his VW bug and
push him off a fucking cliff.
He's announce hall.
Do you have that video of him at,
at the baseball game?
He took his band.
You're obsessed.
This,
this is crazy.
He took,
he took his band and he opened up or he
played at a minor league baseball game
and uh,
he just watch it.
It's pretty ridiculous.
You are fucking absurd.
So chip,
here's this band.
By the way,
none of these instruments I,
somebody told me none of these
instruments are actually,
they're not actually playing.
These instruments are not what you think.
They should be real about that.
Well,
they're authentic with their art.
Okay.
He's still doing the
Michael Jackson thing.
That's why he has his hair
like that state college spikes.
What does that mean?
Uh,
yeah,
I think a minor league baseball.
Okay.
People don't know what to do.
Look up.
There's only like 20 people in the
audience and they're looking at this like
it's a do that one white guy
bouncing around even stopped.
He bounced for a little and people like,
what are you doing?
Oh yeah,
you're right.
What am I doing?
Look at this guy with his camera.
I'm more wrong.
My Kid,
the guy on stage bottom right.
Just a little laughing his ass
off at how ridiculous a shit was.
Looking at him with his
fucking shiny pants.
That guy is so bizarre.
I look at the girls,
but listen man,
if you're that guy and you,
you,
you have to be the guy that like lets
these girls fuck other guys because
otherwise they're going to,
but they're going to get bored with you.
You wait 15 pounds and
you're a fucking freak.
He doesn't like guys into his.
Of course he does,
Dude.
He also holds and they
might not go into his house,
but they have orgies.
They don't just have origins with him.
Okay.
Other dudes are given those girls,
Dick Guaranteed caucus
that
Jesus,
that guy's like,
what the fuck the girl is like,
get,
get the hat,
get that.
Toss it back to me in a second.
Oh my God.
What is this song?
It's this.
He's trying to be Michael Jackson.
Well.
He's like a combination
of Michael Jackson,
Charlie,
Charlie Sheen,
Eddie vetter.
He's really weirdly Pale too.
Oh here you guys saw my daddy freelancing.
It's breaking it down.
He can't make eye contact
with people because they're,
they're all like looking
at him like he's a freak.
So like he's doing all this crazy
dancing and they're not reacting.
It's very strange and
he doesn't look at them.
He's sort of like looking
like at like their knee area.
You know what I mean?
He did the Michael Jackson
thing with the dancer too.
Is that again,
I would steal that fucking hat.
I would steal that fucking man.
It's on the ground.
Why isn't anybody going for pussies?
Someone go,
you had a chance.
We'll get tangled up in some
chords and the a lot of rescue him.
He's tangled.
He's fucking tangled.
Look out,
look out a little stages.
There's cords everywhere cause you're
like a hot air balloon holding those
courts up wise their cars because of
course they go straight up into the sky.
Wait,
we didn't just stay in one place.
Here's the plan that he got set up
on this whole event that set up.
Yeah.
That's someone fucked him.
That's why he wants that so bad.
How could someone set him up?
He's,
he's dancing.
They're singing.
There's no one there.
It was after baseball game.
It was unprofessional and,
Oh Yada,
Yada.
Oh my God.
He's,
he lost his Special Olympics game gate
gig because of this video.
What?
He was supposed to play the spa,
a special Olympics come gig.
And he lost it after this video.
So no,
and he's upset about it.
The Special Olympics.
Yeah.
Imagine if he got booed
by retarded people,
but is his shit,
I shouldn't say retarded
because they don't have,
they have down's syndrome.
Trans started there.
There's something wrong with them.
Retarded is not a real word.
That's why I resent the fact that you're
not supposed to use retarded for people
that are idiots.
And then I went and used it for
people that have legitimate issues.
That's,
uh,
he's,
he might be regarded.
There's something wrong.
There's something definitely wrong,
but it's also like there's that thing
that happens when you become like a Gary
Coleman or like someone who's a,
a personal,
you're a punchline and you're
kind of on the outside like that.
When they get real freaky,
they get like they get desperado and it
all becomes one attempt after the next
to try to get attention.
You know,
you see it a lot from
reality stars that like they,
they're there 15 minutes and then they
start scrambling to try to like do new
stents and new,
different things.
Do you remember kid was
under the real world?
His name is
puck.
Yeah.
Dead.
No,
I saw them on a sunset like uh,
maybe a year ago.
I saw him on Sunday.
How does a guy like that feed himself?
Uh,
how does that work?
You didn't look like he wasn't,
but what does a guy like that
do for a Gig for a while?
I bet he made money.
I mean this,
he was around 20 years ago though,
but you probably made money as a peer
on appearances for like 10 years just
being puck.
We still know his name,
pulled it out of the back of my ass.
But the reason why I know it is because
he was that guy that was like always
doing exaggerated things and always being
ridiculous to try and get attention.
But there's a lot of those fucking people,
man.
I mean that's,
that's,
that's like what the reality
show world sort of creates,
reduces,
it looks like puck was
in prisons now an ex con,
he's now living as a makeup artist
who sounds like he hates women.
He says he was with Oj
in prison for two years.
He was with Oj.
Wow.
He was in for stalking.
Oh my God.
Oh Jesus Christ.
He was in fucking jail for stalking.
Yeah.
Wow.
Hmm.
Okay.
Poor bastard.
But you know what I mean?
That's my point is that these
people that become like a punchline,
they get to that.
And also the other thing is
being a guy like Corey Feldman,
I don't know.
I'm sure he's a fine fellow.
Never met him.
Sure.
He's a fine fellow.
I don't know.
It doesn't seem like a mean person.
It's not a hateful person.
This is where I think it's fucked.
That guy became famous when he was a
little kid and I think when you become
famous in your little kid,
your odds of developing as an adult,
like a guy that we can
hang out with and talk to.
Just a normal balanced person,
they're almost fucking none.
I've only met a couple of people that
I know were famous when they were young
that I can hang out with and talk to her.
Like Ricky Schroder,
he's one of them.
Rick,
he's pretty goddamn normal for someone
who has grown up like in the public eye,
but he has been kind of out of the
public eye for a long time and he's got a
family.
He's very close to his family.
He's got a lot of interests.
He makes documentaries,
he hunts,
he like Ricky's a different sort of cat.
So he's like one of the few that like
was famous when he was young that I could
hang out with.
No problem.
Yeah,
it wouldn't.
When you went to ask her if that maybe
with like famous when young and still
trying to be famous the whole time
cause you just want to get out and they,
they make it or they get out for a
long time and they can come back.
That's a good point.
That's a very good point.
Like Jodie foster was
famous when she was young.
She was in taxi driver and she's famous
now and she seems pretty fucking fun.
It seems fun.
What do you got there?
Brian Moore.
Corey Feldman.
Your fucking coy Feldman.
Uh,
two years ago Corey Feldman told
cops he was molested and his abusers,
but they did nothing because they were
too focused on the Michael Jackson
investigation,
which seems suspect right
there that he telling him,
meaning they were abused by
someone other than Michael Johnson,
which he said that he writes,
the relationship with Jackson was the
healthiest in his life and that he never
abused in which,
you know,
whatever.
But he said he was molested and he told
the cops who molested him and they did
nothing.
Well,
why would he say that?
And not just say who molested.
Exactly.
And then he spiraled into drug abuse.
Having regular coke off challenges
with friends and doing heroin.
You ever been in a coke off at coke off?
No.
Do you think you could win?
Know how?
What's your tolerance like?
Eh,
I'm not into like I know people that can
just sit there and do coke all day long
and just whatever.
I'll have like one line and be like,
okay I'm good.
I've got to calm down
now I've got to come.
You know,
cause he's drink so much coffee.
Yeah,
exactly.
Go there.
Already elevated.
Right now a Trenta has
gotta be unhealthy for you.
Two shots in there.
Two shots.
You know what's worse is
getting a Trenta of cold brew,
which is 10 times more
powerful than a regular coffee.
What's not,
not more,
but it is more powerful that
Starbucks says it's 10 times.
Yeah,
we should look at that.
What is the new cold brew?
It was really 10 times more powerful than
regular coffee that literally would be
like that.
Have you ever seen that
caffeine powder that they sell?
Yeah.
Kids have taken like tablespoons of
caffeine powder and died like it does.
It has absolutely killed people.
And I would think that if cold brew was
really 10 times stronger than a regular
coffee because we have
those La nitrile cold brews.
I had a cold brew today,
just Caveman Coffee.
This shit right here.
This stuff is God damn delicious.
Cold brew concentrate.
You take this,
he put a third of this in a bar in a
glass and then the two thirds water is
delicious and it's,
it's awesome.
It's strong shit,
but it's not 10 times stronger.
Um,
so a 16 ounce Starbuck bucks,
cold brew coffee,
16 ounce,
which is,
I guess they're small,
right?
It's 200 milligrams.
I don't think that's the small,
I think that's the
Grande's 16 200 milligrams.
I think that's standard
standard cold brew.
That's a 16 ounces.
I think 200 is around what it
normally is a what's called Starbucks.
What makes you say it's 10 times stronger?
That's what they told me at Starbucks.
Oh,
that's just some asshole behind
the counter at Starbucks.
Uh,
trying to sell you a script.
Coffee.
I'm stronger.
It was brewed on an island where
they make dinosaurs read my script.
Uh,
a 16 ounce iced coffee has,
see where it said it's not 10 times.
I mean,
if it's slightly more
powerful I'd be surprised.
But you know,
Starbucks is a pretty strong anyway.
Starbucks is way stronger
than most coffee.
They put more coffee in the,
uh,
more Grimes and the thing when they,
when they brew it up.
But the shit that we
serve here,
this is pretty strong.
Jamie makes it pretty.
God Damn.
Um,
thick ice coffee is,
did you see a Floyd Mayweather,
his new car?
He has a new car.
Oh yeah.
Was it a I don't even a
Codec Koenigsegg Kona Sig.
Yeah.
I've seen those things.
Point 7 million it says,
but come on,
those things don't cost
six point $7 million.
Most things I was seen was 4.7.
This article right here says 6.7,
one of two.
Damn.
Yeah.
He drove it down to fat Burger on the
Strip two nights ago and such a crowd came
that he had to get a flatbed to take it
home because they didn't want to drive
it.
Why?
I said the article said he was too scared
to drive it home through the crowd,
through the crowd because he
didn't want to fuck it up.
That doesn't make any sense.
Yeah.
It's not 10 times.
It's 40 milligrams more,
but still it's more,
that's some guy
tell me that put me on
different dysentery.
I'll pretend that I'm a girl.
It's come on Rad band.
If 10 times more
posting all day on Tmz and then I
came over here to work at Starbucks.
I don't want you to have me on your show,
man.
I'm on red band.
No.
What's stupid is that you believe
that I worked at Starbucks.
It seems pretty high and I thought,
and that doesn't seem right.
I saw this today.
Did you see this today?
A kid fell and accidentally
punched through a one point
$5 million painting play
that play that cause this hilarious.
First of all,
how fucking stupid or day where you could
just have this thing right in front of
people.
Like watch this kid's slips.
Oh.
Holding his drink and punch through a
one point $5 million fucking painting.
And then this lady comes over.
All you
get out of here.
Who?
Yeah.
How was that?
Just hang up right there.
Why don't they have it in case in glass,
by the way.
I went to the La County Museum
of art inside of the day.
Thank you.
I'm just the one of the
worst pieces of shit.
Oh God.
It is like a fucking scene in a movie
where you mock pretentious modern art.
Yeah.
Dude,
I'm going to show you some pictures
and these are real fucking pictures.
See the painting that was just a white
painting that had nothing on it or the
room where there's nothing
in it except a chair.
Yes,
I did.
Even even better.
I saw the box.
Did you see the box?
Which uh,
they're,
they're trying to say is a work of
art is a fucking plexiglass box.
Yeah.
This is it.
It's roped off.
Can you say that?
Can you focus it on that?
Just because some people could see how
fucking stupid this is and there's some
sort of pretentious explanation
for why this box is significant.
All it is is a fucking plexi glass box.
Like if you had it in your,
it might make a cool coffee table I guess.
Like,
oh,
that's a cool coffee table.
Where'd you get it?
It's a priceless piece
of art from the Lockbox,
from La County Museum of art.
It,
that place is dog shit.
It is one of the worst fucking
museums I've ever been to in my life.
Right.
I've gone on rants about this in
the past because I love art museums.
Had Columbus Art Museum in Columbus.
Ohio is a great museum.
I even,
the Huntington Library,
which is here in Pasadena,
I believe is one of the best
art museums I've ever been to.
This one though.
I mean literally it was a joke.
I was so pissed off after going to have
how many rooms you would just walk into
a room and they're just be like
a shoe and you're just like,
wait,
that's it
with my kids because
I thought it'd be fun.
Take the kids to the art museum.
My kids love art.
Like they could see some
cool paintings and shit.
And I knew we were fucked when we first
got there cause we walked into this room
and it looks like there's
these curvy walls like,
and I felt like,
well you go inside the curvy walls
is probably some cool paintings.
No,
the curvy walls where the fucking art.
And I went,
no,
we're fucked.
It's one of these places.
And there was all these like super
pretentious people that were like,
please don't touch that.
Please don't touch that.
They're everywhere you go.
They're like,
don't touch,
don't touch.
And one guy,
I had my five year old on my shoulders,
she could,
she likes climbing on top of me.
She climbs on me all the time.
So she's sitting on my
shoulder and he's like,
sir,
can you please take your
daughter off your shoulder?
It's a safety risk.
I'm like,
it's a safety risk for who?
For her.
I'm like,
I'm not going to drop.
Are you out of your fucking minds?
A safety risk?
I highly recommend taking them
to the Huntington Library.
It's a cool place where they have gardens.
They have like,
I don't know how many gardens,
like 10 different gardens.
Yeah,
it's cool.
It's garden.
It's like a different like,
oh,
I'm in Japan now.
It's like they also have one of
the best art collections ever,
including like the blue boy and a bunch
of really famous paintings where you're
like,
oh,
that's interesting.
That's the official,
their original Abraham Lincoln
painting or whatever it is.
You know,
the,
uh,
LACMA.
Is it also,
what does that a rock
that they have there?
That's one of their things.
It's just a big rock.
Fucking hit.
Somebody,
God dammit.
They had not,
I paid and I didn't have to pay
because I'm a resident of La County.
You get in for free.
But I said,
you know what?
I want to contribute,
I want to contribute to,
so I paid and then I just,
then they had fucking jazz,
which is my other least favorite thing.
They had that and jazz together.
It's like super pretentious meets Uber
pretentious and they collide in a fucking
shit storm of hipsters.
Oh my God.
It was so gross.
Then on top of it,
like they have all these art
books for sale and we're like,
well maybe they have some cool art books
and this fucking Shit head with his
rolled cuffed jeans.
I like,
please be careful.
That's a delicate book.
I go,
no,
it's not a delicate book.
It's a book.
It's just a book.
You fuck.
It's all it is is a book.
It's made at a paper like regular paper,
like a regular book you clown.
That was one of the biggest
disappointments in my life
because I wasn't looking
forward to it,
so it wasn't being rough with the book.
I was going to touch the buck.
My seven year old was,
but she was just gently leafing
through the pages of the book.
She wasn't doing anything rough
assholes and county funded assholes.
That's the gross thing is that
tax dollars go to support this.
They have one exhibit that's all junk.
It's called junk.
That's like part of the name of
the exhibit and you go there,
it's like bottle caps that are
glued to like a cork board.
Like you fucks you motherfuckers.
You,
you put this on a frame and hung
it on the wall and you actually,
you're charging people
to see this dog shit.
I mean just total dog shit.
And what a waste of valuable
space in Los Angeles.
I mean there's rooms like 10 times bigger
than my house where it's just a light
bulb.
This should just let
homeless people move in.
They really should.
That should be the new museum is
the homeless people shit collection.
Just slip them shit all over the ground.
You splay spray plastic on it to
seal it and keep it in place forever.
Like the homeless people Turd pile.
That would be like more interesting
than anything they had there.
If you like,
let homeless people,
Shit,
you can come in and shit,
but you'd have to shit in this one
spot and you go under the ropes.
There's,
that's it.
That's the fucking,
that's that fucking thing man.
God Damn it.
That makes me angry.
This wall,
this curvy wall,
which is Kinda cool.
You know,
if it was like in your house,
I be like,
oh,
you have cool walls.
But to say that that's
a piece of sculpture.
The fuck it is.
Fuck you.
How about that other one?
The upper right hand corner.
The like the sticks.
So the sticks they have like,
they have like a half
of a fucking side of,
uh,
of a barn.
Ooh,
look at us.
We're crazy.
Look at the one below it.
That's like a half of a house.
Oh look.
It's like this is what a house
would look like if it was here.
You fucking assholes.
I'm so angry.
I was angry though.
You know why I was angry?
Because I was going to take my,
I was trying to figure
out which way to go.
Should we go to the Museum of art or
should we go to the Museum of natural
history so we see dinosaurs and cool shit
from the past or should we see art and
we went with art.
Huge mistake.
Don't go again.
Massive area.
And not only that,
this area is near one of the most
important natural areas in Los Angeles,
which is labrea tar pits.
See if you find the junk collection,
because if you want to fucking
scoop your eyes out with spoons,
it's fucking junk collection.
Oh God.
God Damn,
it makes me angry.
It was so gross.
So gross and stupid.
But like this is the,
see that one over there.
Scroll down there.
The one with the feathers and the
black right to the readier cursor.
This is the tar and feather.
This is the tar and feather piece.
This represents tar and feathers.
No it doesn't.
It's just feathers that you glued to a
board and you're making people look at
it.
You don't think,
you don't think people know what
the fuck tar and feathers was like.
What do you,
what are you trying to say when you're
trying to say whether your shitty piece
of art is just like a kids' science fair?
You know what I mean?
Like when they're eight,
nine and a half per
preconstruction board thing,
like Yoko Ono is somehow
responsible for this museum.
Well Yoko Ono had an exhibit that I want
to see once in Boston and one of the
exhibits was a block of
wood with nails in it.
And next to that was a,
a box of nails and a hammer.
And they asked Yoko
Ono and they said like,
well what is this about?
And she said,
I want people to contribute.
They be enthusiastic about the odd.
So they contribute.
So she encouraged people to pick up a
nail that's it and hammer the fucking nail
into that block of wood.
She,
and I'm like,
if you want people to be enthusiastic,
take the nails and put
them in your forehead.
Just put them right in your
forehead and let people lack those.
You'll have a line around the block.
People sign up months in advance.
Look at her art,
would it,
what does that say?
Incredible.
What?
See what Yoko Ono's incredible.
What video they,
they better be joking to better be joking.
Come on.
Reaffirms that.
She's the queen of everything.
Is that really what it says?
Oh my God.
Yoko Ono's incredible new video.
Reaffirm she's the queen of everything.
No,
she's a queen of tricking John
Lennon and to being with her.
Oh my God.
Yoko Ono.
Plastic Ono band.
And she's like dancing and screaming
and you want to hear it because it's
amazing.
Yeah.
What's up dude from quest?
Love is there.
Why did you do a quest?
I'm a bad dancer with no regrets.
Fuck.
And we got interrupted by a pop
up for huff post newsletter.
No,
don't want you to newsletter.
no,
no.
Now,
now,
now.
So see that Ted Cruz guy with them.
Um,
I know someone who's having Ted Cruz
come over their house for a fundraiser
because they're a big
supporter of Israel and uh,
we're invited to go.
I'm trying to figure out if I should go.
Some people are saying,
I should go just for the material,
but I'm like,
no,
I'm just going to get angry.
I don't want to get angry.
That mean,
have you ever heard that guy talk?
He's take,
why don't you,
that's a good,
good question.
Why don't you Google Ted Cruz is a
dummy and then find whatever videos they
have.
He's like Sarah Palin.
If he was a guy with a head injury,
if Sarah Palin was a guy
and he got hit in the head,
he's not really running for president.
I agree with that.
Let's listen to talk.
He's just so fucking stupid.
Son Wasn't born in America,
so I don't know how he's
going to be a president.
He's born in Canadian land.
Okay.
And they would never have them
listen to him talk.
It's just subject to coddle and
appease our enemies and so putting,
you better believe Putin sees and Ben
Gazi for Americans are murdered and
nothing happens.
There's no retribution.
You better believe that
Putin sees that in Syria.
Obama draws a red light
and ignores the red line.
Well,
first of all,
stop right there.
Sounds like a gay man to me.
Is that a gay man?
That does not sound,
I mean,
not,
not to stereotype too late,
but there's a certain,
there's a reason why we have
this stereotypical gay voice.
There's a reason.
Why is that reason Brian's
getting fucked in the ass so much.
That makes it voice go high.
Oh,
no,
no.
Because that's what they talk like.
Okay.
Listen,
if I talked to you like this,
what am I,
what do I sound like Brian?
Who do I sound like Brian
[inaudible] large black man,
right?
Large black man.
A confident large black
man is threatening.
Why we recognize that
these exist in nature.
Right?
Okay.
Here's one.
What does that it's a bird.
Herodeck okay.
No.
PTERODACTYL
wow.
But you know what I'm saying?
Like there's sounds that
things make and you go,
oh,
I know what that is.
I my fucking Gaydar says that's a gay man.
Sure.
Listen to him talk one more time please.
Nothing to,
first of all,
I love gay people.
It's nothing wrong with gay people
and not all gay people talk like this.
We've had gay people in the park,
like Josh Zaps.
You would never know.
Looking at him or hearing
him talk that he's gay.
Obviously he's gay.
Talks about being gay
unless it's a smokescreen.
This man says he's not gay.
Ted.
We will repeal every
single word of Obamacare.
It was big.
Old people are clapping,
you know one of the old
people are clapping.
Yep.
Fi's politic parties is
their top priorities.
Preserving their own hide and if enough
congressional Democrats realize they
either stand with Obama care and lose
or they listened to the American people
and have a chance at staying in office.
That's the one scenario.
We could do it in 2015 if not,
we'll do it in 27
okay.
Cut Right there.
Dad is a guy who's barely
keeping it together.
He can't wait till that interview is over.
If she could run out of there and throw
a dress on and put some makeup on and
some women's shoes and just rip his
underwear a par and just take it from
behind.
There's not a doubt in my mind that that
guy can't wait until that interview is
over for him to be himself.
He's barely holding it back like a dam,
like a,
a bellboy,
creaky wooden dam holding
back the river of his gayness,
a powerful glacial river of gayness.
He,
uh,
am I right or am I right?
I a fucking challenge anybody to argue
with me that that's not an a feminine
man.
Strongly a feminine man.
Which again,
there's nothing wrong with that.
I don't know that guy,
but he seemed kind of guy.
I would like a gay president.
I would love a gay president.
We could use it.
We can use a gay president.
We've had a black one.
I think gay be gay before woman.
Lesbian.
Strong gay.
Ma'Am.
I'm ma'am.
Lesbian one shore.
As long as she doesn't hate man one.
This is not one that had a
rough experience with men.
I met her,
Dick's to women,
man,
I don't want that.
They don't want anybody with prejudices.
You know,
you're not responsible for all
the men that had been Dick's,
that woman.
What lesbians do you know that you
think could be a fine leader other than
Hillary Clinton?
She gay
or asexual?
She is married,
I don't know.
Good call.
So it's Ted Cruz.
Melissa Athletic.
That's a good call.
I'll say Melissa,
but Melissa Etheridge thanks.
And uh,
love her to death.
But she also thinks that
if she's on a plane,
everyone in the plane doesn't have to
worry because she will not be in a plane
that crashes because she
creates her own reality.
That that's true.
You think that's true?
Yeah.
Hm.
It's hair stimulation.
There's no evidence to the contrary.
It's like when we had Burt on and Bert
was talking about how he doesn't believe
that you die.
He goes,
prove he die.
I don't think you do die.
Prove you die.
I was like,
well,
it got a good point.
Can't really prove it right.
I mean,
you know that people have died in your
life and you know the things do dive.
You've ever seen a person
die or seen a thing?
Die.
Things die.
But do you die or not?
Who knows?
Who knows what?
This is even real.
If you're listening to my voice,
you have no idea if you die.
You really don't.
You as far as you know,
I am a figment of your imagination.
You have created this entire reality.
Everything from streetlights
to fucking clouds.
Everything is all a part of
your absolutely spectacular
and vivid imagination.
Every experience that you have,
every sensory experience that you've
taken into your entire life may in fact be
a part of your,
your brain trying to make
sense of your imagination.
And then there's Ted Cruz.
It's just dreaming about Dicks.
I believe it.
I think we are all program.
I still believe it.
Well you believe in simulation theory,
right?
I believe that we are all
a program in the future.
And you know,
I was thinking of how's your program so
weird cause I'm stoned somewhere in 2000
years from now.
But uh,
I was thinking how weird it is that we,
we'd never,
no one is born in remembers anything.
You know,
the first couple of years,
usually at least one year,
you know,
like you're kind of just born and
then you're slowly diluted into being,
hey,
I'm alive.
Person,
you know,
and it's like this whole gray
area where you just kind of,
yeah,
at the beginning that
you're just kind of like,
I guess I
uh,
well there's a guy who
has a theory about that,
which is pretty fascinating.
I forget the gentleman's name,
but what he said was that you are not
really thinking like thinking as we know
it does not exist until you learn language
and that until then all you're doing
is like having sensations
and reactions to them.
But you don't have reference,
you know when your mom was there
because your mom gives you love.
You remember that she gave you love and
so he looked forward to you cry to get
her and that she's in there and you're
like the love is coming but you don't
have an internal dialogue.
You don't know that.
Like,
oh here comes my mom.
Give up the tip,
bitch,
come on,
I'm going to suck on some tea.
Get me some milk.
That's why it's funny when you have a
meme with like a kid thinking cause you
know the kids don't really
think like that or kids words.
They,
the idea is that once
we develop a language,
then we can put things into context and
then we have words for all these things
like chair,
floor,
door light,
and we have this thing in our head like,
man,
someone shut that fucking door.
I'm tired of seeing that
light come through and then
you have that in your head.
If they would just shut that door than
the fucking light wouldn't come through.
God,
I gotta get up in the morning and you
have this internal dialogue and once that
internal dialogue comes on,
you know,
talking about anything else that you
have a point of reference for or a word
for,
then you're really thinking,
so what a kid is doing is
like experiencing a bunch
of things but not thinking
about it.
They're not like recalling
like they see it again.
There'll be scared.
Like the dog barked.
Ah,
the dog freaked out and you see the dog,
oh the sound's coming,
but do you have this?
Oh this fucking dog is going
to start barking again.
Somebody shot him up.
That freaks me out.
They don't have that internal dialogue.
So that's why they
don't remember anything.
That's why from the time where
you're like a baby and your newborn,
which you really start remembering
is once you hit like five,
six,
seven,
once you have language in words,
once you have words that you can recall
and once you have things that you can
bring up again,
like my daughter will bring up stuff
that happened to her when she was like
three or four,
you know,
she's like,
remember that time we
saw that thing and all?
Oh yeah,
that was pretty cool,
right?
Like yeah,
that was cool.
I can,
she's five and she'll talk about
something that happened a year ago,
but,
but it's because a year
ago she had language,
you know,
she could talk a year ago,
but like she doesn't bring up some
shit that happened when she was one.
She doesn't remember it.
So late term abortions til
about two or three I think.
One,
some kids taught,
well,
my daughter,
the first daughter was
talking really good at one.
It's weird like some of them
to start speaking really young.
Some of them,
they speak later and it's,
it's a,
it's an interesting thing.
Like when,
when is someone officially thinking,
I think they think that,
I think it was like,
the idea is that 48 days after conception,
the soul enters the body was like
the eastern mysticism view or some,
some ancient view of like when,
when,
uh,
of a fetus viable,
when it becomes a person that 48 days,
up until then it was just a bundle
of soul or a bundle of cells.
It takes 48 days to install
the operating system.
Huh?
No,
something's happening.
You know,
you're,
you're accumulating so many different,
you know,
your,
your brain is growing,
your cumulating senses.
You're accumulating,
your ability to perceive,
your eyes are growing,
they're developing,
your sensations are
growing and developing.
It's really weird,
man.
I had a dream about a girl that
haven't thought about in a long time.
I wake up and all I did for
the rest of the day is like,
oh,
what's she doing now?
Why I should talk to her?
And then I texted her and I'm thinking,
how interesting is that something that I
had no control of while I was dreaming?
What's making me do
stuff when now is awake?
And I was thinking how interesting that
you know the whole shutting off when you
go to bed and your,
your dad when you know
when you're sleeping,
you're just,
you don't know what's going on.
But having that road affect your awake,
rural,
don't you say world world?
Why?
What?
What is it?
Why do you insist on do it?
No,
it's not.
No it's not.
No.
Jamie says world too.
Think retarded that Brian does.
It's an Ohio thing.
He's like,
I know where the gas leak occurred.
I might but say say when
thousands and thousands.
Everybody says 1050 h on the,
and you have to say it that way.
Thousands.
It is weird though to answer
a question that when you,
you dream,
you can dream about somebody and then
when you're awake you can think about that
person.
Like I literally like
woke up and was like,
man,
I need to find out
what's this girl's like.
It was almost not,
I was like being told to do something
almost and it was just because of interest
for me,
but it was something I had no control if
I didn't want to think of this girl and
you know,
but I was just,
that's just like an example of
something that's happened recently.
But what other things that you dream
about and you don't even realize you had a
dream about,
but during the day you're like,
you know,
I might buy some new
shoes and you're like,
wait,
but you jumped about
shoes the night before.
You might not even remember,
but you you dreamt about or shoes,
just like shoes.
She doesn't have to be
connected with your dream.
What's a terrible reverence?
You know what I'm saying?
Like,
like what you're saying
about the girl that is weird,
that people,
they get,
they get contained in your memories and
sometimes it gets contained incorrectly.
Like why is it about like exes like you?
Like generally,
a lot of times people,
like especially if you had a
good time with that person,
you only remember the good times.
And then he get with them again,
like you haven't seen him in forever.
And he started talking to him and he goes,
oh,
I forgot you're fucking negative.
Tell negative.
And there's still like bitching about
everything and complaining and always
looking at the downside of things.
That's uh,
that's something that for whatever reason,
a absence makes the heart grow fonder.
You know,
we,
we eliminate those poor memories and
only want to think about the good stuff
except when there's police involved.
I just remember that you have,
you have been in scenarios that have been
quite a bit more extreme than myself.
You ever heard of the men
Mandela effect men dollar Andela?
Like Nelson Mandela?
No.
What does that,
it's a theory that,
uh,
it's Mandela,
by the way,
Nelson Mandela.
Mandela.
When a large group,
a large group of people have a
vivid memory that's all the same,
but it's false.
Like there's a large group of people
that had a memory of Nelson Mandela dying
in prison,
but he obviously didn't
die like the barons teens.
That's exactly where
I was going with that.
Like it's come back around.
I know it's been talked about before,
but it's come back around recently
and now they're saying that we live in
parallel roads and stuff.
What it is just the Shel Silverstein.
I mean,
I explained that last time,
you know,
we,
Shel Silverstein came out the same time
as Bernstein and everyone thought or
Berenstain it and everyone just put the
two together thinking it was the same
Steen and we just,
it's just a memory.
It's especially for a word that's,
that,
that's an odd word.
Berenstain is odd.
But Baron Steen is pretty common.
Yeah.
There's deep reddit posts about it now.
And there's a top theory is that
someone's gone back in time and change.
Exactly.
Shel Silverstein,
dude,
people waste so much time.
Some fucking dude was tweeting
me yesterday about the flat.
I looked up,
oh my God,
this guy is,
this is,
I don't normally do this,
but uh,
I couldn't help it in this.
This guy tweets me.
I was weird at first,
but Eric Dubay has some
compelling arguments supporting
flat earth that can't be
explained.
So I tweet back in all caps.
No he doesn't.
And then he tweets me.
Have you extensively
looked into his research?
First of all,
if you're a fucking guy that's making
youtube videos about the earth being flat,
that Shit isn't research.
It's just not,
it's not real.
You're not a scientist.
You're not wearing a lab coat.
You don't work for a major university
just because you get some fucking jack off
alone in your room,
obsessing about nonsense.
That's not research that said,
so have you extensively
looked into his research?
There's definitely some fuckery going
on with most of the ISS footage.
So,
which I quote,
I wrote back in all caps.
Uh,
no he doesn't.
I know it isn't,
or no,
there isn't.
No,
there isn't a fuckery.
And then I just,
I stepped back and just
watch the comments.
The comments are amazing.
There are so fucking amazing people
actually arguing for the flat earth people
arguing against the flap.
You know who one of them is?
My Buddy Max.
Happily.
Did you see it or did you guess?
I follow him on Facebook.
I couldn't believe it.
I saw my friend Justin,
uh,
texted me about it.
He goes,
dude,
I shit you not max is arguing
that the earth is flat.
I called Max's nuts.
He's so nuts.
Earth picture thing too.
There was pictures like that same thing.
Got,
he was talking about the other day
about where all the pictures from Earth.
Oh God,
it hurts.
It hurts.
Did they not know that snipers actually
have to take into account the curvature
of the earth when they're shooting people?
Because the ball,
the bullets will drop.
Like there's a curvature of the
earth like you have to theirs.
That's a part of the calculation when
you're trying to shoot somebody fuckers
like,
God dammit,
there's this shit to think about.
And then there's that man.
Yeah,
man.
Well,
people love to fucking get
worked up about nonsense.
You know,
like I,
I posted about a fucking Cecil the lion
I posted today about the fucking lion
that killed the guy on the photographic
safari thing.
So I put this on Facebook,
I go align killed a safari guide in
the same park where Cecil was killed.
The Safari guy had a name
and was loved by the locals.
The line was not in all caps
authorized to kill that person.
I hope to all other lines do
the right thing and protest.
I'm just fucking around.
And then I step back and watch the God
damn fights that are going on in the
comments section where people,
first of all our thinking,
I'm an asshole because I,
I'm serious,
Joe,
you're smarter than that.
You should know.
First of all,
it reached 1.8 million people in the
two hours we've been doing this podcast.
How the fuck that happened?
But uh,
Joe,
you're smart.
We talked in person before.
Lions are designed to kill,
they have line breaks.
We shut the fuck up.
Stupid.
You're trying to sell sound smart.
You think?
I really think that that
line should have killed them.
I am glad.
Let me tell you this right now.
If there's a guy that's on a fucking
photographic safari and align takes him
out,
I'm glad you know why?
Because I've been on the four or
five at four in the afternoon.
We could use less people.
We could use less people,
and anybody that's willing to go
on a fucking photographic safari,
you're an asshole.
If you want to go on a photos,
photographic safari in the
place where lions live,
you ridiculous.
You've watched too many movies
and for the sake of mankind,
you probably should get taken
out so everybody else could see.
Oh,
okay.
They're just lions.
These aren't lines that are in a movie.
These aren't lines from a book.
These aren't lines from a cartoon.
There are giant cats,
big fucking cats.
I got a little cat at home
and I take little things.
I crumple up a piece of paypal
and I throw them across the floor.
She chases him,
dives on them and puts them in
her mouth and she's a fluff ball.
She's a cat.
These are 600 pound cats that
regularly kill shit all day.
They kill things.
They're hardwired to kill
anything that's limping,
anything that's weak and
it's in front of them,
including some stupid fuck
with a camera walking.
You should be in an iron man suit and
should be armed to the Dick that you
should be.
If you're going to walk
around where lions are,
it should be,
you should be like mocking them.
You should be in one of those,
not the regular iron suit,
but the big one where
the dude's inside of it.
The big fucking gray one that they had.
Yeah,
the whole killer iron man's suit.
That's what you should be in.
Did you see fantastic for?
Of course.
I'm not seeing anything
when they have kids.
Yeah,
they redo it and I was
like a young black kid.
That's the flame.
Stop with your diversity and okay,
I saw the fucking comic book.
You know blade was black.
The flame was not black.
You're making them black.
I know what you're doing.
Okay,
stop.
It's like Annie Black,
Annie,
Annie.
It's just make a new one,
man.
I'm not against black superheroes.
Make a new one.
But when you say the Superman's black,
I'm like,
come on,
come on.
He's not black.
Are Not doing that,
are they?
They are now.
Someone was going to,
yes,
he should be.
Do you remember when they
were saying that Santa Claus,
they were doing a black Santa Claus and
Megan Kelly got really mad on Fox TV.
Do you ever see that?
Oh,
I remember that.
People are so mad at
her because she's like,
she made it.
She was like,
there was a video,
you know on Fox TV where she would
say Santa clause is not black.
Okay,
let's just get it over with.
Santa clause is not black.
No,
Santa Claus is not real.
You flog.
Okay.
That's the correct thing.
You should have said.
Not that he's not black.
That's hilarious.
Saint Nick,
but first of all,
she's right.
It's not a lot of black people in Siberia,
you know?
But you know who is black?
Jesus.
It makes more sense.
Yeah.
He was black.
It fucking skin of bronze
and hair of wool hit here.
What?
Like lamb's wool and the skin was black.
He was Sephardic.
He was a dark person for sure.
It did.
Definitely didn't look like that hippie.
Let's let it play it.
Let's listen to her
in,
they have a piece,
uh,
on.com in Santa clause should
not be a white man anymore.
And when I saw this headline,
I kind of laughed and I sound this isn't,
you're so ridiculous,
yet another person claiming it's
racist to have a white Santa,
you know?
And by the way,
for all your kids watching at home,
Santa just is white,
but this person has just arguing.
Then net,
maybe we should,
we should also have a black son.
She's lying to your kids what
he is and just so you know,
we're just debating this because
someone wrote about a kid's.
Okay,
why don't you get that?
She's got like,
she's giving safe where the kids,
just in case any kids are listening,
Santa Claus is white,
white kids.
Listen,
Santa Claus is white.
That's ridiculous.
Show me a picture.
How long ago was that?
Show me a picture of
this fucking Santa Claus.
He's white
two years ago.
Two years ago.
Wow.
She's hot though.
She does.
Everyone want to save the kids.
Kids are Kinda smart or at least
they think they are way smarter.
It is important to save the
kids when it comes to say,
Jamie,
you don't know cause you don't have kids.
I'm like,
precious little babies need to be lied to.
They need to be lied to about Santa.
You can.
Kelly's going to lie to them.
Right.
I know this kid,
he,
he gets bullied all the time and he was,
and I actually got to see the bully bully
on the playground a couple of months
ago.
Yeah.
And uh,
he was,
and I was telling him like,
you know,
you should get him back and I,
and he goes,
Hi am I am?
And uh,
we made a plan where we Photoshop,
we found a photo of the his bullae and
we photo shopped him kissing another kid
that's another bully.
And then when we printed out a bunch of
them and then put them all around the
playground,
right.
But it's so cool nowadays with like,
like these kids like he was like,
when I was 11 I never thought about doing
crazy things like that to get back to
boy I just hid it or something like that.
But nowadays kids are so
advanced that even when,
when when dealing with bullies,
they're using technology.
I love it to be careful though.
The kid doesn't find out who did
it and beat the shit out of him.
Problem.
Yeah man.
Fucking why is it a natural instinct
for people to do that to little kids?
It's a natural instinct,
right?
Like this is like for those big
kids to pick on little kids,
it seems like almost
like a natural instinct.
It's a fucked up instinct
because like if you're bullied,
like bullying for me led me
into martial arts and it,
it helped me ultimately like that fear
of people kicking my ass led me to go and
train and do martial arts.
But for some people they don't do
anything about it and they have like a
particularly evil bull.
I got my bullying was very gentle,
nothing bad happened and
nobody put me in the hospital.
Nobody stole things from
me or terrorized me.
I just was scared to certain kids and
certain kids fuck with me and I avoided
them.
Like I'd see them in the hallway
and a gold the other way.
I'd try to find another way to get to
the bus in order to go away all the way
around and look around the corner,
make sure that certain kid that was,
that I was scared of wasn't there,
but it was fairly mild
as far as bullying goes.
But we all know somebody who's
like beaten up by bullies.
That chick can change your life,
man.
It could devastate your confidence.
It could ruin your whole year.
It could lead to depression,
it could lead to a drug use like,
and I don't know what the fuck can be
done for that other than I've always
suggested that teaching kids martial
arts and school would be a great way to
avoid bullies because avoid bullying
because they would develop confidence and
they would develop discipline
and they would understand that.
That kind of shit is pathetic.
That running around and beating on kids
like this kid that you're talking about,
they actually not only do in
the 19 martial arts in school,
they actually did the opposite of
doing things like kickball or games,
uh,
where they're actually
kind of promoting bullying.
What's the one where you,
we all had the lineup on the ball,
dodge ball.
It's like great,
you're teaching dodge ball,
which is hurting other people,
but instead we could have
learned karate or whatever stuff.
Fucking avoid dodge ball like the plague
because I was in when I was 14 was the
only time I remember dodge ball.
Well,
but this is like before I started,
marshal was kind of just
starting karate and uh,
I was scared of everybody beat my ass.
You know,
there's,
I didn't,
it was new in this neighborhood,
just moved there.
It was my first year in this neighborhood
as a freshman in high school.
And then there's just fucking kids that
were lighting kids up with these balls,
man.
Just fucking whipping these balls at
kids and they'd get hit in the face and
everybody would laugh.
And I'm like,
this is crazy.
Dodge balls.
Fucking crazy.
And choosing partners.
Remember you had to choose.
We are the lineup.
I Want Jeff on my team.
I went and taught at my team and then
just having to go through being cherry
picked the last you remember that there's
so much fucked up shit that they go,
they do to you as a young kid that you
don't realize that it's teaching you like
is your place in life.
Yeah.
Like your first place,
your second place.
Sorry you came in last place.
Now we're going to throw a ball at you.
Come Gladwell.
He's got a book called out about um,
outliers about people that
perform really well and things.
And one of the things that he brought
up in this book was how important being
successful is being born and a
certain date at a certain time.
A certain time of the year.
Because if you're born at
a certain time in the year,
you missed the cutoff and you're older
than the other kids in your class.
And so like they were talking about like
hockey players and that something about
like there's like you know,
x amount of players,
a huge percentage of them were born later,
like a rule or something.
I think in Canada,
like if you're born on January 1st and
December 31st you're playing with this
group or that group and you could be the
oldest kid or you could be the youngest
kid actually if you're born on the 31st
all your friends of the day after you in
another league.
Yeah.
So if you're one of those kids that's
like nine months younger than the other
kids that are the,
you know,
they're all 12 right?
But one kid is like nine
months older or 10 months old.
That's fucking significant.
Really significant when
it comes to sports.
And his theory is,
and it's,
it's really correct that the advantage
that those kids have by being older leads
them to get better as well.
Like one of the things about Jujitsu,
this is a very important lesson for
anybody who knows Jujitsu because a lot of
people don't like this aspect of Jujitsu.
Some people have this meathead idea that
the way to get good at Jujitsu is to go
against the hardest guys.
Get your ass kicked.
And that's how you learn.
Actually.
That's the wrong way to learn.
The best way to get good at
Jujitsu is to strangled blue belts.
You go and you find people
that are just learning,
but they're not as good as you and
he choked the fuck out of them.
That's how you get really
good at your technique.
And people say,
well,
that's bullying.
Well,
it is important for the blue belt too.
At some point,
spar with black belts,
it is important because when the board,
purple belts are blump brown belts
because you need to know that there's a
higher level of proficiency,
there's a higher level of skill,
and then there's a shorter distance
in between points that these guys are
hitting.
They're there,
they're cutting the chase,
they're getting there,
they're capitalizing on very small
openings and they they clamp down and when
they capitalize on these small openings,
they,
they get submissions quicker.
So you have to know that there
are guys that are better.
That's important.
But to drill,
the most important thing is drilling.
And when you drill,
you drill with like someone of your
level and you just practice on each other
like you choked me and you know,
you'll do it like twice
and I'll choke you.
I'll do it twice.
And it's just practice.
And maybe you'll resist like 50% like
sometimes like when you're doing a drill,
and I'll pretend to be resisting
resisting a little bit.
So the strangle me and chuck,
because that simulates real life
simulates how it would be in,
in,
you're supposed to be
building your muscle memory.
But the real way to do it,
the after you do that to get it really
sharp is to practice on people with a
limited amount of proficiency
just to choke the shit out of him.
So that's like the way that you ultimately
get better is to practice on people
that aren't quite as good as you.
And then you eventually develop and the,
you get to a point where,
you know,
that seems kind of impractical,
but I don't remember what my point was.
I'm choking people,
sports going against different belts.
A kid teaching bullying.
Oh,
uh,
getting better.
So the,
the,
the idea by that is,
the real problem with that is if you're
in a school and say you're the only
white belts and everybody else is a
brown belt or a black belt and you're
training with them,
fuck man,
you might not ever get good.
Like you just might get
wrecked all the time.
And that's the idea with kids that are
in sports that are so much younger than
everyone else in their class.
Or if you're pretentious and they
bring your precocious and you,
they bring you in a class earlier,
he skipped a grade.
So you're in seventh grade now,
Billy.
Well,
you got to go to seventh grade football.
Good luck.
You little fuck.
You're going to get run over.
What am I to one of my best friends
growing up the whole time we were playing
sports,
uh,
his birthday's a week after mine,
but he's a whole year older than me.
And so he played sports
with us the whole time.
He's smaller than me and doesn't
look like he's bigger than all of us,
but he would beat the shit
out of every single person.
We would play every sport,
football,
basketball,
baseball,
track.
When we were,
when we got the high school,
for some reason he was better
than everyone in that too.
He was a ninth grader and he was starting
freshman running back on the Varsity
team and the newspaper getting a,
but he was a whole year
older than everyone and ah,
well that's what it is.
15 years ago.
No one was really,
yeah.
Well that's,
that's a big deal because your,
your body develops like
very rapidly at a young age.
And so these young kids that are older
than everyone else in their class,
they have this significant advantage and
that advantage according to Gladwell,
it accelerates them onto success as a
professional that because you have an
advantage,
you continue to get better and you
can exercise that advantage over other
people,
which sharpens your skills.
Just like,
you know,
the idea of taking,
getting really good because
you're strangling blue belts.
Not good for the blue belt,
but it's good for you.
You know,
cause you're already ahead of them so
you're going to get better and better and
better and better.
I always back in third grade when my
parents got divorced and I was a little
young and uh,
it didn't help me at all,
but she didn't try.
He didn't even try.
Like what sports,
did you ever play soccer?
Did you play soccer?
How much did you try on a one to 10?
Three.
I hated it.
I don't remember.
Yeah,
that's a difference.
Um,
I was born in August.
I don't know if that's a good,
I don't think that's a good
month for professional sports.
Like if you wanted to go on teams,
but I didn't do it.
I mean,
I only played baseball when I was
little until I found martial arts.
But if,
uh,
I wanted to be a professional athlete,
like a soccer player or a
hockey player or whatever,
probably not a good month.
I think the the good months or like
February or something like that,
February,
March and the season starts usually like,
well you're also like
wait late in the year.
You know though I don't,
I forget what they said,
what year it was,
what,
what Gladwell said,
what year was the or what the time
of year rather was the best to start.
Who is an interesting thing too.
He had a thing talking about what the
best year to be born was like in the 20th
century and it was like in the early
1930s cause it was right after the
depression was over.
And like right after World War One.
So like there was a lot of jobs to be had.
The economy was booming and then you were
at the front of the line for like this
big baby boom that came on
after that before World War Two.
So you would be in
positions of management,
you would have these advantages.
It's really interesting when you think
about like how lucky you can be or how
unlucky you can be in certain situations
and how that like we're talking about
bullying can sort of
flavor your whole life.
I can unlucky roll of the dice can
flavor your whole life and also he was
talking about people that were born and
that went through world war one and he
was like,
well even if you went through it by
the time you were out of the military,
by the time you're trying
to establish your life,
you already in your forties like you are.
You already like trying to start a
career at the time where most people are
already clearly established.
Really interesting when he really stopped
and think about like most of us don't
engineer our lives.
You sort of just make the
best with what you're,
you've got,
but there's a lot of consequences.
There's a lot of factors that play on
behind the scenes that we really don't
take into consideration.
When you consider,
when you really think about
like where you are in life,
I mean hard work and dedication and focus,
all those things are hugely important.
Um,
the,
the ability to stick with something,
the ability to put in the
work to get up disciplined,
but also there's a lot of shit that you
don't have anything to do with man that
absolutely factors in.
But then there's that bitch
as part of people that go,
well,
he was the only fucking,
you'd go up there because look,
he,
you know,
he's only playing football for the
fuck of Dodgers are the Dodgers.
He talks about Bill Gates and his
10,000 hours of mastery and whatnot.
But a lot of what he's talking
about here is that he got lucky,
whatnot because his
childhood home was really close
to the University of Washington,
get access to some computer programs
that other people might not have had the
opportunity to get ahold of.
True.
So he might not have been Bill
Gates without being in the spot.
He was at the time he was
true.
But he might've been something else too.
I mean it's also what he did.
Like Bill Gates used to work from like
two o'clock in the morning until four
o'clock in the morning until six
o'clock in the morning coding.
His mother would try to wake him
up and he was always exhausted.
She couldn't figure out why because
the dude was up all night coding,
just having to work while she would put
them to bed and even like pretend to
sleep.
Then he'd wake up,
he'd sleep for a couple of
hours and then get up and code.
And I think that the people that
become successful for the most part,
they become successful
because they figure out a way.
But would they have
figured out the same way?
Would they have figured it out in
another way or would they have been
discouraged because of poor circumstances?
You know how many people who became
successful guts like take me for example.
I'm not maybe with standup because standup
is like something you either just can
do or you can't do and you have to put
in the work and I don't see any easy
roads for stand up.
If you get good at stand up and your
headline and in killing you put in the
work.
There's just no other way around it.
But it's TV wise,
I got lucky as fuck.
I only auditioned for two TV
shows ever and I got both of them.
It's crazy.
Total dumb luck.
Got on MTV half hour comedy
hour because of stand up.
Then I got a development deal.
The development deal led me
out the Hollywood where I um,
they Disney Disney gave me a bunch
of money and I auditioned for a show.
Just got total dumb luck.
They were looking for some athletic
guy to be in this baseball show.
Got that.
Then audition for news radio.
Got that two shows,
both of them onto just total luck.
Unquestionably lucky as fuck.
And then even fear factor.
Lucky as fuck.
They wanted someone who
had already been on TV,
they wanted someone who
understood competition and
they wanted someone who was
like a comedian that could
like work on the fly.
Look,
here I am.
Dumb luck.
So those things I will
never a total dumb luck.
But also you got to fucking show up.
You got to do the audition,
you got to not choke.
Like there's non luck factors as well.
Like there's certainly luck
involved in everything that happens,
but there's a lot of other people that
were trying to offer that same show that
were probably just as qualified as me,
especially with the first show.
And they didn't get it
cause they probably choked.
Maybe my luck was that I had gone through
martial arts competition so I was less
likely to choke because
I had done scarier shit.
So I was used to
performing under pressure.
So maybe there was luck in that luck
in the fact that I had this background.
But that's not necessarily luck either
cause that was fucking hard to do.
So it's like this black and white
thing that people want to put into.
You know when you look at like this
guy succeeded because of hard work.
Well maybe,
maybe he succeeded because of hard work
and what time of the year he was born
and that he was older than
the other kids in his class
and he worked hard and he got there.
There's a lot of factors.
There's a lot of fucking
factors in everybody's success.
There's a new drone Bretta type at Sony,
uh,
just released and it can go,
up to,
uh,
it can carry up to 22 pounds of
cargo and it can go up to a hundred,
six miles an hour,
uh,
and fly up to two hours.
How many bullets does that?
But there's a really cool
video that I sent you,
a gym that,
uh,
it's showing it fly and it looks like a
mini airplanes unlike the drones that we
know of where it's,
they're usually like circular or,
or like a square or something like that.
This looks like a little mini jet.
Uh,
but,
uh,
I thought it was interesting
because it can carry up,
you know,
22 pounds is a lot to 40
or something to carry.
You know,
it's interesting like,
look at the way that thing just took off
and how come they can't make plans like
that?
They did.
They have plans like that.
But I mean,
for people like,
not just like for jets,
like for fighter jets,
like,
look at the whole front end of that thing.
Why can't they fill that up with fucking
passengers and have that big circle in
the center be that,
that a helicopter thing that
makes it just take off straight.
That's pretty dope.
There's another video below it that
shows a little bit more of it flying.
MMM.
But they're thinking about they're
selling this so it could be used for like,
you know,
like Amazon and stuff like that and
pizza deliveries and things like that.
How's it going to be a real problem,
man?
It's going to be a real problem
for amateur pilots for sure.
I mean,
if,
if they fill the skies,
if they become so many of those things,
I mean,
think about if these
things become as common as,
I mean it probably won't,
but a cell phones and they're just
flying around all over the place.
People were sending people things.
Hey Man,
can I borrow your baseball?
Sure.
I'll fly it over to you.
Program it NBC.
This was this,
uh,
this is an Ohio,
right?
This was a second one that just happened.
Arrests on drone plot to surprise supply.
Prison contraband.
Oh God.
This is a Maryland,
I believe.
Yeah,
Ohio just had one off where people
were smuggling in drugs and to like
courtyards and stuff like that.
Why they got caught because the wrong
people got the drugs and there was a
fight.
Wow.
Look,
guns,
guns and prison.
That's hilarious.
They were smuggling and
guns are those things.
POKEMON cards.
Well,
what are they going to do when people
start smuggling in three d printers and
they can just build whatever
the fuck they want in jail.
Like I said,
hey,
that is that.
It might be tobacco.
That was the most of what
they had on that other one.
Those little things are tobacco.
Could be packets.
That's what this is on top.
Who cares what it is?
Just the idea that they can
just fly it in and drop it off.
Did you hear about the Pokemon convention?
You was it yesterday.
I get the newsletter.
I'm part of the fan club.
Of course.
No.
There was two gunmen that came into
a Pokemon convention with 250 rounds
or something like that.
Body over 18 dies.
Yeah.
Look at it as Pokemon at.
I mean,
who attacks Pokemon people?
They're like the most adorable,
nicest people in the world.
But yet,
look at that.
You said [inaudible] do you
not like the word world?
I don't like world.
Is that how you say or world?
How do you say it?
I put the r before the,
Oh,
it rolls off the tongue
easier then go in world world.
World world or old world.
No,
no,
you don't say it like that.
How do you see the world?
How do you say it?
We're old now.
That's the right way.
That's why they say no.
You say Barolo.
How does he say at Jamie?
You say Debbie Rl.
Now that I can't even say
it's the best thing in the
world world.
Okay,
keep saying it like that.
We're good.
No,
that's what I say.
No you don't.
You say world world world.
No,
it doesn't even say world world.
This is a boron.
That's what you say World Rod.
The best thing in the world.
Rod Wound.
Doesn't matter.
All right.
We gotta get Outta here cause it's about,
we're,
we're at a two hours in and I got a
buggy a did we cover everything that's
important in the world of the Internet?
Pretty much.
Hmm.
Uh,
if you,
uh,
see these things and you,
you know,
is there anything fucked up?
Just tweeted at us and we'll,
we'll try.
We're trying to do these if we can,
if we have the time once a week.
But it's tough.
Thank you Brian.
Thank you.
Was a good time.
Yeah.
Plug dates.
What do got
tomorrow?
You guys secret show with Russell Peters.
Tiffany Haddish,
Tony Hinchcliffe deemed
Delray some secrets.
And then,
uh,
we'll,
Stephanie had us be creeping
into the microphone.
But Tiffany Haddish his show was done.
Queen Vein.
Yeah.
She doesn't do that anymore.
Why?
Because he's on television on NBC now.
And you can see your show Wednesday
also Gerard Carmichael show.
Yep.
And also I have a show in Ventura,
California Friday at the Hong Kong
and doing a full set their ethos.
Sweet.
All right.
A desk,
squad.
Dot.
TV for more details.
Red Ban on Twitter.
And,
uh,
that's it.
You fucking savages.
See you soon.
Bye Bye.
Big Chasm.