Four three,
two,
one.
Boom.
Matt,
you're the first guy to ever bring
homemade cold brew.
Yes,
sir.
To the studio.
I think we should enjoy some.
Okay,
let's absence.
Yeah,
it's uh,
it's,
it's pretty much kerosene.
So you want to sip it,
be careful.
I usually,
yeah,
I usually dilute it with a little bit of
water.
Wow.
Yeah.
I got this off out about this guy.
It's a company called [inaudible] where
it's a guy and he just wrote this,
all these beans from all over the world
and drops him off at this one bicycle
cafe and a Venice or something.
No,
no.
I live in Los Feliz.
Close.
Close second.
No.
Cheers Buddy.
Thanks for having me.
My pleasure.
I had a coffee expert on the podcast
before.
Just start it.
I mean,
I don't know anything about coughing
just out on a whim because of this Guy
Peter Juliano.
That's his name.
Juliano or Giuliani.
I'm avoiding,
uh,
the word Giuliani,
like specific Juliano Juliano.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But he's the,
like a legit coffee expert.
He's explained to us that all coffee
comes from Ethiopia.
Oh really?
Yeah.
All of it came out of there.
That's,
that's the root originated it.
Oh,
okay.
And then they started growing it and
Latin American countries and all over
the other place.
Yeah.
Colombian.
You know,
we're always as a kid,
Colombian coffee was the course saying
like Juan Valdez.
Yeah.
He's still at,
we,
I went to Columbia over the summer and
uh,
you still see pictures and drawings of
him everywhere cause they were like,
yeah,
because he brought kind of fame to
Columbia and differentiated it from out
the other South American countries.
Yeah.
Well this guy was,
it was really fun.
This is actually a very good cold.
Oh,
cool.
Very tasty.
Nice,
interesting.
It's a different flavor.
Yeah.
I mean it get cold brew coffee.
You take at least 70% of the bitterness
out and it makes it smoother and it just
no acidic and you don't get that.
That's the stomach sourness you get when
you drink a big pot of hot coffee.
I usually don't get that.
I'm okay with coffee,
but I do like the flavor of this.
This is really good.
Okay.
This is Ethiopian.
Yeah.
I just,
I'm no expert.
I just go,
what's the best one to make cold brew?
And they pointed a bag and I buy it and
that's all,
you know,
smart.
Just defer to experts.
That's kind of the key to life I think.
But he was Giuliani Juliano Juliano
sorry Peter.
He was explaining to us that um,
the reason why they all have these
different complex flavors and how they,
how they would take care of the beans
because Ethiopia is a very dry climate
where South America is very hot.
So they developed all these problems
with a coffee,
rust.
Have you ever heard of coffee rust?
Yeah.
They develop like weird molds and stuff.
That's why they had to figure out
different ways of processing and wet
processing is verse to just leaving them
out and drying them.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
Did he talk about the illegality of
coffee and it's kind of earlier stages
when it would go out into different
regions and cultures and religious
areas?
Well,
bordain actually was the first person to
tell me that they were outlawing coffee
shops and coffee houses back in the day.
See there's a clip somewhere online of
bordain explaining to us how coffee
shops were being outlawed because at the
time everyone basically was drunk all
day,
right.
Because people just,
they,
all they did was drink booze because you
know,
a lot of times if you had water sitting
around that water would probably have
some funky shit and it was still water
and you'd get sick drinking it.
But you could be,
you know,
if water or the alcohol in it,
you wouldn't get sick.
It's a preservative.
Monks would only drink beer and like
crazy.
It's not,
I can't imagine if you've ever had like
Belgian Ale.
It's like I have three,
I'm just like,
fuck.
Okay.
Jesus.
And you'd think those guys just pacing
themselves all day to stay somewhat
hydrated.
And I think they just got used to it,
but it must have been terrible for their
bodies.
I,
yeah,
that's what I was thinking.
It's like,
oh,
I was just thinking about like life
expectancy and how like,
ah,
now I feel like we're going to see
people living well into their hundreds
and stuff and like our generation and
younger.
Uh,
but back then you're just like,
you're 30.
Alright,
you should make a whale man,
because it's,
well,
it's just if anything went wrong you
were done.
Where it's like I have a lot of friends
that have had their appendix taken out
or they broke a leg hiking.
They managed to get okay.
You know what I mean?
Like the back end that was the wolves
ate you lays leave you so the wolves
don't come after the rest of us and just
take one for the team.
If your appendix,
when you were just possessed by demons
know,
know what the fuck happened.
Yeah.
You just struck dumb,
like just fall down and just rotted out
from the inside and no one knew why it
and the amount of,
the amount of,
I've heard this statistic that like
something like 80% of medieval land land
battles were fought drunk or something,
something,
some insane ratio.
They like,
of course it wouldn't have to be.
Yeah,
I would.
I would have to shotgun a bottle of Jack
to pick up like a battle ax and just run
into a crowd of guys and just start
swinging away.
Well,
the vikings were famous for waging war
while they were on mushrooms though
would eat siliciden mushrooms and just
fucking go banana may Emma Nita Mascara
too,
I think was the other mushroom that they
ate and they would just go fucking crazy
with axes while they were,
who knows what they were saying.
He would say that the legend of the
Berserker.
Yeah.
Where are we at the term Berzerk from?
You're obviously familiar and you're a,
you're a warrior,
a philosopher,
so you know that is,
but like,
yeah,
that's probably what you just go into a
trance and you're just killing
everything in sight and you're basically
like a,
an insect on cocaine.
It's just chopping everything down
around you.
Yeah.
You remember when we were talking about
that new Viking show that's on Netflix?
We missed it.
It wasn't the comedy one.
There's another one.
There's another one that's like a
serious viking show on Netflix that's
supposed to be like the show vikings,
but way better,
which I kinda liked the show vikings.
Yeah.
It was good.
You're good.
I thought.
It's funny though,
how,
uh,
you don't image the last kingdom that's
asking the last I heard.
That's amazing.
Where I'm so,
you know,
we,
we focus on one thing and where it's
like you'd look,
you're the vikings,
you're like,
where are the hats?
Where they wear the helmets with horns,
with all these braids everyone has,
I think he's a normal pizza.
They all,
they,
they should all be monsters,
but it's like vikings were all sizes,
right?
Well,
they were all big like this.
The problem is like,
there's not that many giant actors
unless you want to recruit football
players.
It's so true,
you know?
Yeah.
But if you go to Holland or something
like that and one of the things you walk
right,
you go,
God damn,
everyone's big.
That's a good point.
Yeah.
Uh,
in a,
in Norway,
Norwegian countries,
they're very tall.
The median height is like six feet,
which is insane.
Well,
Iceland has a disproportionate number of
strong men,
competition winners.
Those guys who were the strongest man in
the world,
you know,
let's do this.
Thrill barrels,
cars hop.
I love.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Those guys,
a lot of those guys come from Iceland.
Well the guy who plays the mountain,
he who took strong commander in the
world title,
he's from Iceland.
He for sure is he is fucking you.
Like if you saw that guy coming over a
hill on a horse with a sword,
like,
aw fuck,
it's over day.
Yeah,
this is the day we stop existing it.
We're done.
This is day my clan gets wiped out.
Or that thing where they to save to save
lives.
They'd be like,
our champion fights your champion.
And then that person wins and then that
guy comes out and you're like,
ah,
fuck.
I was so good back in the,
in the,
in the knife Jim that we train in.
But this guy,
well that was the saddest part about
game of thrones is the,
that uh,
the cocky bisexual Guy [inaudible] the
Red Viper.
He was ahead.
I dude,
I was broken up with my,
my now wife and just was just back from
a weekend on the road and was tongue
over and was just like,
oh,
watch game of thrones.
And I just tweeted like,
ag,
I'll watch the,
I still have it.
Don't tell him what happens,
you know,
blah,
blah.
Just to,
just to have some connection with the
outside world in my one bedroom
apartment.
And I watch people like,
don't watch it alone.
I was like,
well,
and I watch it and it just ruined me
because it's so fucked up.
He's screaming how you're raped his
sister and he's crushing head.
And I'm just like,
aw man.
The way he did it too,
he just grabbed his head and killed him.
Like you would kill a chipmunk or
something.
The worst death.
And I've probably seen on screen and
I've seen a lot of bad,
horrible screaming deaths,
you know,
like it was worse than like the guy and
saving private Ryan where he's like,
wait,
no,
no one.
The guys just stick a knife in there.
It is right here.
Oh God.
Brutal.
Yeah.
It's also looks horrible.
Well I think it's,
it's,
it's something you write in a fantasy
novel.
Like I don't know how someone could have
hands that strong.
He has hands up.
Yeah,
you're right.
What am I saying?
Just strongest man in the world.
If anyone has handset strong,
he's going through the eyeballs.
You can pop ahead for sure.
Eyeballs first to grip.
Yeah.
Tell you think you could do that to a
baby.
Oh,
I thought,
I mean you couldn't,
but you could physically,
right?
Yes.
You could.
Moral diamond took over my bay or meth.
You'll probably wait.
What did I say?
I was to a friend of mine and she was
telling me that her dad had been
hospitalized and while her dad was
hospitalized,
he was in like this,
uh,
like a care home for older people.
And I'm a guy who has schizophrenia,
will freaked out and tried to eat him.
Oh God.
While he was there.
Well,
yeah.
And then he said,
fuck this,
get me out of here.
And he wound up dying at home.
We want of dying at home rather than die
in the hospital because a guy tried to
eat him.
Imagine like your last couple days of
life or escaping a schizophrenia guy who
got out of his room and tried to eat it.
This is why I worked so hard all my life
and raised a family and now I'm here.
I mean,
that's already your worst fears to be
Sidai away from your loved ones just
around strangers to be back at the first
day of high school basically.
But you're old and everyone's old,
but then someone's trying to kill you
and eat you.
We don't,
we don't get rid of people like that
quick enough.
Like,
you know,
you get rid of bad dogs,
dogs bite people.
You put them dot.
Yeah.
I should.
I got to tell my mother that because she
works with this group called the
village,
which creates a network in any given
neighborhood where if you're young or
you're old,
you registered on Kourtney thing and
basically,
uh,
this person can live out their final
years in their home because they have a
network of neighbors who check on them
every couple of hours or call me,
here's my cell.
Like I have,
I'm having a chest pain.
Okay,
cool.
Let's just get you to the hospital.
Cause it's like,
I think people deserve to,
you know,
as long as you're not eating people that
killing them,
they can die in their homes.
Yeah.
That's a,
that's a concern that you really don't
ever want to address until it's too
late.
Yeah.
The,
the,
the concern of when and how do I go?
Yeah.
You know,
I mean you have to accept that you're
going to go and some people just have a
really hard time with that.
Sure.
And even deep into their old age when
they're just decrepit and they can't
make it any more,
they just can't handle the fact that
it's all going to end.
No,
no.
That's why you have to live your life to
the fullest and not bite your tongue and
just be yourself because I guess or just
chill the fuck out and wait for the end.
What do you do?
One of the two,
I don't know.
What is the life to the fullest,
right?
If it's all temporary.
Sure,
absolutely.
I mean there,
there is that point where it's just
like,
well,
is there any point to life?
I don't know.
I've gone back and forth with trussell
on this where I'm just like,
Duncan,
Duncan will fucking send you down a
rabbit hole with that man.
I don't know man.
Yeah,
the cosmic,
he'll make some sense out of it.
He will.
He is the cosmic trickster without a
doubt.
I were bordain speaking of Dane,
he was that he was saying,
they were like,
how would you like to go?
And he was just like,
I just want just one bullet in the back
of my skull and you'll see a comment.
Yeah.
But meanwhile he did it himself and did
it with a rope.
Yeah.
It's just,
I was friends with them.
I that would fuck me up.
Fuck me up.
I wasn't,
and I was a fan of his since the first
article came out in the New Yorker that
he wrote,
it fucks you up because you just go,
I wish she called me.
Yeah.
I wish.
Or I mean I would have to France,
no,
I wouldn't of,
oh,
does it suck it up.
Pussy.
Right.
Don't kill yourself in France.
Yeah.
But in back to America,
she would have checked in.
Yeah.
Cause I mean,
I know it's all about perspective.
There are times where we've all come
close to not necessarily putting a gun
in.
Our mouths were rope around her neck,
but where you just feel like there's no
point.
Yeah,
no,
but someone can just come in.
I say it like coming up in the,
in the crew that I came up with in
Chicago,
you know,
Canadian and Hannibal.
Uh,
and,
and people like,
we,
we never let each other get away with
shit where it's just like,
yeah,
you're saying that,
but fuck you.
Like you need those people in your life.
I'll never forget.
I went through a horrible breakup and I
went,
I was in my apartment for like a week,
only leaving to wait tables and
bartender.
And then I finally came to a show and
Kinane is like,
hey,
look who pushed aside all the clumps of
used Kleenex to be with us.
Welcome back you fucking pussy.
And I remember laughing so hard and it
all went away.
It all went away.
It just cause you take yourself so
seriously and it was never going to get
better.
And it's,
I mean,
I just think about despair as this demon
that latches onto your back and it's
your job to fuck it up,
get it off you.
You know what,
what's your thing?
Uh,
destroyed the fight.
The bitch in you conquer your inner
bitlocker year you're going to pitch is,
I usually,
when I'm referring your inner pitch,
I mean the inner bitch,
it doesn't want you to work out well.
That's,
that's,
that's the one I relate to the most
where it's at.
I feel that every time I'm in a class,
every time I'm in something like that,
it's just like something and you're just
like,
I just want to sandbag it.
Let me just sand.
But just this time,
well,
I mean everybody has that.
Yeah,
I still have it,
but I've got that motherfucker on
lockdown.
Good.
Now I own him.
He's in there though.
He's weak.
He never goes away.
Oh,
he's always trying to tell you you
don't,
you can take the day off.
Maybe your ankle sore,
maybe.
Maybe you're feeling a little sick,
a little run down.
You should,
you know,
take a take a you day.
The dog looks tired.
He doesn't even want to run.
You know,
it's not about you.
You should take care of that dog.
Dog does not want to run.
My Dad said something brilliant on the,
for my dad lately,
like he's always been like a guy in no
words.
You mentioned like hospice,
living and stuff.
My Dad used to do hospice and he,
he would just,
he was like,
do I have to talk?
And the guy's like,
no,
you can.
They just mostly want to someone to
listen.
He's like,
I can do that.
And two would sit by dying people and
just nod his head and stuff.
And uh,
but he never,
he never talk about it.
Where I'd be like,
Dad,
what are you doing today?
He's like,
I'm going to go hang out with bill.
Like Dad,
who the fuck is bill?
I was this guy,
he's dying.
Like,
Dad,
you got to tell me more than this.
So now we're kind of,
he's opening up more,
but long story long,
he was like,
you know,
when you're waking up in the middle of
the night and there's that voice in your
head that is telling you you,
you're,
you're useless and you're,
you know,
you haven't done enough with your life
and things like that.
He's like,
I don't know if there is a devil,
but if there is,
that's him.
And I was like,
fuck.
And it just blew my mind.
Right.
And it's like,
dad,
you're right.
That voice that tells you to give up
that voice that tells you like not to,
not and not to,
you know,
to hate yourself and you know,
don't think you're worthy.
Well then it's such a weird pattern.
Right.
Because it doesn't have any real
evolutionary benefit.
What is the benefit
of self loathing and,
and just sitting around feeling pity.
Yeah.
They're,
they're plenty people in situations that
are going to kick the shit out of you in
life anyway.
Why?
Why do it to yourself,
but yeah,
but there's something good about feeling
very disappointed in yourself because
then it makes you work harder and like
you recognize or at least try to realize
your potential better.
You get more done and you feel better
about yourself.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
There's definitely something there is,
you know,
especially if you're,
you're in competitive sports or
something like that where you just,
there's nothing you hate more than
losing get because otherwise you won't
work as hard.
Yeah.
But Jamie was talking about coby Brian,
but what a psycho he was when he was
planning.
And they always say that about Michael
Jordan.
And of course Mike Tyson was like that.
Coby said he learned it from Michael.
That's like what he passed on to stay on
coby.
Pass it on to Lebron.
Yeah,
they went on the Olympic team again.
I heard Lebron spends one point $5
million a year on recovery because
recovery just recovery.
Cryo therapy massage.
A million and a half every year.
Yeah.
What a fucking stud.
She's crying that guy so bad ass.
He's like maximizing,
everything was like a perfect example of
someone was Maxima Freak.
Genetics.
Powerful.
We'll intelligence.
But then on top of that,
maximizing everything,
built a school has a good sense of humor
about himself.
Decent actor.
You know,
he was so funny and um,
uh,
was it?
No,
it wasn't wrecked.
The Amy Schumer movie train wreck.
It was,
I was asked half.
Right.
Yeah.
Did you ever see that hbo show where
they're sitting around with them?
You may shop.
Yes.
Yeah.
He's fucking great in that.
And you get that insight.
It's like,
oh,
that's why you're so good.
You're hock and crazy.
Like he was talking about his son
playing and he's talking about his mom
and like he's just his,
his drive and you know,
he doesn't,
he doesn't let anything go.
It's fascinating to me.
People like that that are like extreme
winters are there.
There's such a rare person,
you know,
and it's,
and it's rare that you could probably
stand to be around them.
Yeah.
That's the thing.
Especially like your,
your kind of your,
your tech billionaires or something like
that.
It's like,
after a while you'd be like,
you know,
I'm going to go to the comedy store and,
and uh,
we're going to break each other's balls
for a while because this is weird man.
Right.
Like Steve Jobs,
like known by everyone as an extreme
cont yeah,
right.
He was just a con.
There's no way around it.
Yeah.
Brutal.
Do you remember that video?
There's a video.
It's a,
he's demonstrating an apple product and
he can't give this camera to work and
he's pressing all these buttons.
It doesn't work.
And he throws it at the engineer with
this like purse lips.
Uh Huh.
He's like,
here you fix it.
See if you can get it work.
He just wants you fucking Loeser.
I'm in front of a million pay pal and he
can't,
he can't lose his mind cause it's like
that Japanese ethic of the person who
loses temper first loses right.
No matter who's right or wrong.
I'm sure he loses his tempo privately.
Oh,
without a doubt.
It is.
Watch this.
Right?
It's like he can't get it to work.
My camera's not turn it on.
What's that?
I could slide it and let go.
Angry.
Not Turning on
please like this.
Yeah,
you fucking,
he's fucking Turkey.
He's this close to Rome.
The Roman emperor.
Throw him into boiling pit.
You gotta think Jeff Bezos is like that
too.
Right?
To be and just to be the richest man in
all of the world's not real.
He's not really the richest man in all
the world.
He's the richest man who has a publicly
declared income.
Ah,
there's a big difference between him and
really good guards.
Yeah.
The oligarchs,
probably a drug cartel.
100%.
Well,
not trashed hotels.
I don't think they have that kind of
money.
But I think for sure,
um,
Saudi Arabian princes and Middle Eastern
and income,
right.
They have trillions.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Right.
Yeah.
That's different.
People don't talk about that and those
guys don't talk about it either.
They just go,
they let Bill Gates take the rap.
Sure.
Meanwhile,
they own like whole countries.
It's almost like how,
uh,
people,
people that have people that I went to
college with are ways around that their
family,
they came from money,
they never showed it.
Oh,
of course.
They always wore bummy clothes,
you know,
but like someone who was acting like
they had money to have like a dunhill
lighter or something,
I'll roll acts or something fancy.
But like,
that's,
that's those countries basically like
the kid with the scuffed up a gym shoes
that you're like,
man,
I know Michael Milkens your dad,
dude,
I know he's your dad.
Right?
I was gonna play with this kid.
And I was like,
oh,
really?
Yeah.
I think he,
he was Kinda like,
it's gotta be unnerving for him.
He's a good guy.
I don't know how much contact you have
with his dad,
but it was just like,
uh,
your dad's the junk bond king right now.
He's your dad.
That junk bond,
your dad,
the whole reason why you're getting by
so smoothly and the walls are so greased
for you in this life as your dad was a
human scumbag.
Yeah.
Full,
full on with wealth.
There's always a displacement.
Someone's rich because other people are
poor on some level.
But that was the most direct
correlation.
Always the case like this.
How about this?
Like beyonce,
is beyonce rich because someone's poor
or is it beyonce?
Rich cause she talented and she worked
hard.
No,
listen,
don't get me wrong.
I don't think it's,
it's,
it's across the board like that,
but I just think in turn a lot of ways.
A lot of ways.
Yeah.
Not ever.
No Way.
Not every time.
Right.
But people love to say that.
Yeah,
of course.
You know,
like he,
sure,
okay.
The Jennifer Lawrence fuck a bunch of
people over or she just really good at
actually,
she's amazing.
Are you sure?
No disparity of wealth is because
someone's out there being evil or is she
just really good?
Right.
And the thing that gets me is that they
always dump on those people.
Uh,
the public figure.
So people explore,
especially biggest example or like,
like sports figures were like,
I mean,
sure,
you get that much for a fight.
It's like,
uh,
are,
do people want to watch you fight?
You get that much,
you should get fight.
[inaudible] knocked off for $1 million.
That's my favorite.
He didn't say that.
Oh,
I'd fuck you get punched by Mike Tyson
for $1 million.
Yeah.
First of all,
you'd have to get in by enough people
that want to pay to see you get,
not just,
you have to make it worth a million to
see you lose your life.
Quite frankly.
Richard Lewis had that joke about his
uncle.
I remember when I was a kid and I'm
watching the TV and like laughing till I
cry,
where he said,
oh yeah,
I think it was Tyson actually.
It was like,
Yo,
I'd fight him for a million.
He's like,
yeah,
like anyone would paid 300 bucks a seat
at Madison Square Garden to see an old
Jewish guy get punched once in the face
and cry.
I laugh because it was so specific,
like be crying.
He'd be drooling.
You wouldn't be able to lose half your
intelligence see straight anymore.
You're fucking skull would be broken.
They'd have to bolt it back together
again.
You'd have to have everyone.
I love hostage in like a warehouse to
let him punch me once.
Dude,
when he was here the other day and I was
just,
I met him before.
I met him once before,
took picture with them,
but every time you meet him you're like,
yeah,
okay,
okay.
This is really Mike Tyson.
He's really here and I'm shaking hands
with him.
He gives me a hug.
He's hugged like hugging a tree.
He's like,
wow,
oak tree.
It's just like funk.
Aha.
He's just this beast of a man.
Well,
I remember watching those first fights.
It was like watching you put a dog in a
ring with a wolf every time.
It was just like that.
He would just run right through
everybody to the point where you're
like,
oh,
he's not from here.
You know,
kind of like those,
those,
those comic books were aliens.
It's like they're on a planet that has
way more gravity or something.
Say just punched fish right through your
chest.
Yeah.
That was a superman,
superman.
But if that happened,
what's fucked up about that?
Like scientists must get crazy about
that because if that happened you'd be
like really sick.
Like the,
like when people go to space and they're
in space for six months,
like their body breaks down.
Yeah.
You lose like years from your life
really fucked up.
It's not good.
Commander Chris Hadfield on the podcast
Belk.
Cool.
And he said that when he came back he
literally couldn't stand,
his equilibrium was so fucked up cause
he had been in space for six months.
Then when he came back,
like it was a horribly throwing up.
He like,
he like,
he couldn't see straight.
Like when you'd stand,
the world was all wobbly and shit.
Like his equilibrium was completely
gone.
I mean,
I think,
you know,
superhero movies are kind of
fundamentally ridiculous and silly.
I love comics.
I grew up on them and stuff,
but they never,
they never take physics into account.
And really it's always like you hit with
a gamma ray,
you get powers.
It's like,
why would it choose to give you powers?
It would just melt you.
Like,
that's not how forces in the universe
work.
They don't,
you know,
generally speaking mystically,
no,
never gets enhanced in real life by like
nuclear radiation.
No,
I don't think that's ever,
ever happened.
I the boat,
the best theory would probably be like
Godzilla.
Like some monster was born of it that
came out of the ocean.
There was a time where vice went to
Chernobyl and uh,
this was back when vice was really vice,
when Shane Smith was going on all these
journey and shit.
That was what was nuts.
Yeah.
Before vices,
sort of vice,
I mean,
vice still does some great stuff,
but vices just as huge multimedia
corporation now and back then,
uh,
Shane went to Chernobyl and,
they were hunting like these radioactive
wolves.
Well,
Mike is radioactive wolves and Chernobyl
and like,
you know,
they're mutating.
There's fish in the water that are
enormous and they're fucking weird and
you can never eat them.
They're like the fifth fishing near the
plant in a simpsons like with three
eyes.
Right,
exactly.
Yeah.
But the,
but it's real.
Like they really do have these animals
that live in this highly radiated area
and they've managed to survive by just
guy mean that the level,
the levels that we,
that we have taken to get energy and
affected our environment.
We,
you ever dropped San Diego?
You know that ride when you drive down
and you look to the right hand side.
Oh look.
Nuclear power plant.
I could throw a rock and hit it from the
highway.
Like what in the fuck is that doing
there?
Yeah.
So close to the water.
Well I think it needs to be close to the
water for cooling.
Oh yeah.
That's how they cool the reactor core.
Okay.
I think,
notice I say that like I know what I'm
talking about.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
There's a,
there's a nuclear physicist right now.
Nope.
Well,
that was the Fukushima thing.
That's what's happening over there.
They still don't have that thing under
wraps.
Well and debt that volunteer army of of
Japanese people older than 70 that were
like,
I don't have long.
I'll go work there.
I'll go clean it up.
They're all going back in time.
They're all 39 you go there.
It's like a Stephen King movie.
Amazing.
I do twice a 30 years old.
They don't want to tell anybody.
Oh,
commission.
I didn't know that the way to San Diego.
Yeah,
probably broke everybody around.
It's dead.
Yeah.
Cause everyone was throwing rocks.
It's like Joe Washes.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but maybe they woke up and like 1980 and
they go,
hey guys,
maybe this isn't a good place for a
fucking nuclear power plants.
Steam generators failed in 2013 Jesus
steam generators.
There it goes.
There it is.
The fuck out of here with that.
It's over.
Meanwhile that's still there.
Like the core is still there.
They can't move it.
It's currently in preparation to be
decommissioned.
Jeez.
However long that takes g's ever that
even that means man,
go fishing around that fucking thing.
Good luck.
You'll catch a big fish though.
I know.
Weird.
They'll have human hands,
he'll talk to you.
Don't eat what?
But they talk with thoughts.
Right?
They just stare at you and to your mind
Fukishima they were doing something
where they dug this giant swimming pool
and all around this giant swimming pool
that they dug.
They put like ice cores,
they put like some sort of cooling
element so they could freeze all the
nuclear waste to it and insanely cold
temperature didn't work.
This is like a strategy that they were
developing,
but apparently it fell apart.
I don't know what the fuck to do.
It's just you just don't,
you can't do anything.
I mean like they gotta do something.
You got to keep trying to shoot it in a
space.
I Dunno.
Then the aliens are going to get mad at
us.
Yeah.
Well there already.
Do you know,
like I,
I had a friend who I used to live with
who was kind of new agey but also
conspiracy theory ish and he would,
he was convinced that our planet was the
Mo,
the off limits zone for the entire
universe where every other plan it was
much more advanced and they were just
like,
don't go down there.
All they do is fight and blow things up
and they're,
and they don't share with each other and
stuff.
It's just don't,
that's why no aliens come.
So all that,
when people do stuff like that,
I always feel like they're
anthropomorphizing like the idea that
their life would be anything like our
life is a bunch of characteristic.
Agree with you more?
Yeah.
I mean there's a bunch of care.
This is a bunch of things that have to
be in place for us to get to the point
where we're going to war with each other
that are people that are over there and
right.
There is no war in the ocean.
Ever noticed that?
No,
exactly.
Yeah,
it was an ocean wars.
They don't,
they don't have and there,
you know,
they just eat each other.
Yeah.
And there's normal,
there's parts of the ocean we can't
reach and there's,
who knows if there's a,
there's a,
there's a whole other civilization down
there,
you know.
That's why we like really bond with
mammals only because fish don't do a
goddamn thing for their kids yet.
Those dirty fuck cause they don't really
have them like it's a trick.
It's like nature's trick them into not
being attached by the kids.
They blast some eggs down on the bottom
of the floor and then the males come
along and just on the egg.
Sure I'm done here.
I'll get out of there and they jet,
that's it.
And I leave like millions of kids.
Yeah.
The only ones that take care of them.
And there's a few female fish that keep
the babies in their mouth.
You ever seen those?
Yeah.
And then they let him go like,
and when the babies are in trouble,
they hold them in their mouth and then
like everybody gone good and they opened
up and the babies get to swim around.
Yeah.
That's it.
Once test fit in mom's mouth,
you're fucking,
which there's a bumper sticker for you.
It's,
but things that live in the ocean that
we do love,
like dolphins,
take care of their young.
Yup.
Killer whales take care of the young.
Yeah.
Right.
It's really weird.
You don't take care of your young,
you can fuck yourself.
It's kind of a mammalian trait.
Yeah,
yeah,
but like you're saying,
you can't,
we always try to create a like on other
planets is how does this,
it does this smell like,
yeah.
Love that.
You've found that right away.
That is amazing.
One is on the outside.
Mom.
Jesus.
Yeah.
Last door.
That's crazy.
What kind of fish is that?
Doesn't say.
Wow.
That's amazing.
It's like it's smoking fish,
right?
Yeah.
Like it's a hookah.
I get soup.
Dawson blowing out Swedish too.
It looks like a group or something.
It looks like something in the Bass
family.
Yeah,
it's gorgeous fish.
You mentioned the thing with feet and
I'd watch the Blue Planet to the other
day and there is not a fish apparently
it's called like a toad of some kind,
but it hangs out on the bottom and it
has feet.
It's,
it looks like a fish that grew feet.
It walks around.
Yeah.
That's not a fish.
I don't believe so.
It's actually a some sort of toad I
think technically.
Whoa.
But yeah,
and they look like human feet almost
like how his toes and everything.
It's amazing.
One of the weirdest
things that I ever saw about the ocean
was there was a theory that was going
around a few years ago that I,
I don't know if this is legit or not,
go google,
that they think that it's entirely
possible that octopus Octopi may have
come from eggs that were frozen and
landed here from an asteroid.
There was speculation that there was
something about the way,
yeah.
The way that they pro,
you know,
the DNA and rna of,
of octopus are so different than every
other animal in the fossil record that
it's almost that there,
there was a consideration that they
might have actually been an alien
species because you know the term,
you know what Panspermia means.
Panspermia is a theory that is pretty
widely accepted in the scientific
community that some life is transferred
through asteroidal collisions.
So like that,
say if a,
a chunk of rock slams into our planet
and knocks a chunk of rock loose in that
chunk has dna on it and uh,
the amino acids and all the building
blocks for life,
that bacteria,
whatever it is,
things that,
some things,
you know,
little things can survive in space like
tardigrades little life forms can to
survive in space that they slam into a
planet eventually.
And then when they do that,
that life is transferred onto that new
planet science news.
Holy Shit.
The buses came to earth from space as
frozen eggs millions of years ago.
Okay.
But this is like the,
the express,
I was trying,
I read it a little bit.
Yeah.
But that's,
that's the most feasible version of
aliens coming here.
Yes.
We tend to think of it as it lands and
they're like a space man who looks like
George Clooney steps out,
but he has like [inaudible] or
something.
It's like,
hi,
I'm,
I'm here to share with our,
our planet all,
all tuna or whatever and he speaks
English and all this shit.
Like it's,
it's on a,
on a biological level that we almost
can't comprehend.
You could go back to that James please.
I'm really good.
It says that the extraordinary claims
made in a report entitled the case of
Cambrian Explosion,
terrestrial or cosmic,
which costed by a group of 33 scientists
and published in the Pr,
uh,
progress in biophysics and molecular
biology journal.
And the paper suggest that the
explanation for the sudden flourishing
of life during the Cambrian era,
often referred to as the Cambrian
explosion lies in the stars as a result
of earth being bombarded by clouds of
organic molecules.
Wow.
I think that's also the theory of how
water got on earth.
They came from thinking came from
comments cause when you see comments,
comments are all water and I think like
millions of years of us can hammered by
comments.
Huh?
Like you know when you see the trails of
comments,
that's literally ice D and debris coming
off of that comment.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
Literally the more you know,
the more you know,
been in a comment,
but they think that about mushrooms as
well.
They think that spores can survive in a
vacuum.
So if something like,
say if some spores were attached to a
rover and we shot off to move to
the moon or something like that and it
got there somehow or another,
if there was the right conditions for
that thing to grow,
that they could actually survive the
trip and then grow on the moon or on
Mars or anywhere where it be water and
sunlight and atmosphere,
like invasion of the body snatchers,
we'll spores or even weirder,
right?
Because spores create mushrooms and
mushrooms actually breathed oxygen and
you breathe out carbon dioxide.
They say they're,
they're closer to an animal than the art
of vegetables.
Yeah.
That's uh,
that's,
I've thought about that when I've,
when I've eaten magic mushrooms a lot.
Right.
It's like I basically just ate an
animal.
Well,
you also feel like it's taking like it's
alive inside of you communicating with
you.
Right.
Don't you feel like that?
Like it's not as simple as I'm getting
high.
No,
I smoke weed.
I feel like I'm getting high when I eat
mushrooms.
I feel like I'm entering into the
thought process of an alien creature.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
You,
you put on like a space suit on the
inside in a way and you're,
you're evolving a certain way if only
for like seven or eight hours or
something.
Yeah.
Do you ever micro dose now?
I have friends that do that and Ron
White's big into that.
Oh,
Izzy,
every day
you laugh.
Found my sale.
But good kind of medicine.
Oh my God.
Ron.
Ron White kills me,
man.
I could just pick their most random name
you could have,
but I'm just like,
that makes perfect sense.
He's beautiful.
He's,
he's a real comedian.
In that he's always a mess.
He's beautiful.
He's always hilarious.
Yes.
Relationships are always full chaos.
Chaos.
He's always drunk.
He's always a peach.
He's always the nicest,
nicest.
He's never had any attitude with any
comedian ever.
And always just,
he's,
he's like,
he's like America is wise.
Crack and drunk uncle.
Yeah,
but not racist.
No,
no,
he's beautiful.
Yeah.
I love that guy.
Me Too.
I,
it was almost like,
you know,
there are certain,
uh,
mystical gateways and,
and signs you see that are like,
oh,
hey,
things are going to be okay.
I saw the magic monkey in the tree.
I landed in Las Vegas with my wife and
she loves vegas and we went to the cab
line and just standing there as ron
white smoking a cigar as if the city put
him.
They're like,
he's waiting for them.
Albany,
which is their people,
which they should,
you know,
that they should just make a ron white
hologram as you drive into the city
where he's there all the time.
[inaudible].
He's there all the time during,
um,
the Rodeo,
if you're in there,
you're in town for the Rodeo.
Ron White's at the Mirage.
That's usually match.
My wife's birthday's in,
uh,
in early December and that's always on
the Rodeo is that clubs.
Awesome.
Do you ever do work?
The Mirage you ever go there?
Uh,
I've,
I opened for tosh there.
Yeah.
The Terry fator theater.
Yes.
That's a bad ass place.
That's like a perfect,
perfect size theater for comedy.
Yeah.
It's like a thousand seats.
Not too big,
but it's all like right in front of you.
Yep.
I used to work the place where they do
the uh,
um,
the car theater where they do the Cirque
de Solei.
Oh yeah.
But it's too cavernous.
Yeah.
Like you,
you actually cost me money to work at
the Mirage and I'd rather do that cause
then it's fun.
Yeah.
That would be one was just too big.
That's what people don't think about in
terms of,
I think like we only think about that.
Comedians and promoters like the,
the architecture of a good comedy room,
you know,
like judge.
Generally speaking,
comedy clubs,
lower ceiling like the or the or at the
comedy store.
Yeah.
Perfect.
Do you ever do comedy works in Denver?
Yeah.
Loved Chellus flawless flood.
They nailed it.
Yeah.
Boy.
Your comedy store?
Yes.
Flawless.
Acme in Minneapolis.
He's got a few pillars that are a little
annoying.
That's true.
It's a huge building,
but the ceiling height is just right.
Yeah.
Wide Ass pillars.
You're like,
what if I'm sitting right here?
I got to do this to watch the show.
I got to lean left.
You worry about who's behind it.
It's like doing comedy in the round.
I'm always like,
I feel like I have to keep spinning.
You know?
I've only done that a couple times and
it always feels weird.
I hate it.
I need people in front of me.
Yeah,
it's awkward.
Uh Huh.
Yeah.
This is a good theater in Phoenix
though.
The Hollywood theater,
they do that in the round.
Louie did one of his specials there.
One of his hps.
Oh right.
Yeah,
yeah,
I remember that one.
Yeah,
that was,
that's crazy.
Cause that's huge theater and around,
it's not that big.
Really think it's 2,900 okay.
I don't even think it's that big.
It might not even be 2,900 maybe 2,700
find out young.
Jamie,
maybe I'm wrong,
but I know Sebastian,
I think he did theater in the round in
Madison Square Garden.
God bless that 18 teen thousand Jesus,
four shows.
Boom.
So good.
Boom,
boom.
He's one of those guys that like back
when no one knew where he was,
who he was,
you know,
three years ago or so.
Like I would make a point to stick
around and watch him at the store cause
he's so fun.
He's a great guy too.
He's another guy like no one begrudges.
If you've a grudge,
Grat,
Sebastian has success,
you're probably a shithead.
Well and you probably don't like fun.
Yeah.
You know I have such a blast watching
him cause it's just,
it's like he's like a silly ballet
dancer.
Yeah.
Making up all these,
all these stories and his facial
expressions and how he,
uh,
his,
his physical comedy.
It's just par.
Exsalonce I love it.
Yeah.
And he's always annoyed.
Everything is annoying to him.
Like that's this whole thing.
Yeah.
It's everything around.
It just pisses him off.
Yeah.
If you ever achieved peace,
like peace of mind would be terrible.
Awful for is what would you do?
Yeah.
You know,
I used to legit think about that when I
was starting out,
when I was starting to do comedy,
like a,
I wanted to meditate and to try to do
these different things,
but I thought that's gotta be bad for
your act.
I should probably not.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I know.
I remember guys saying like,
Oh,
don't,
don't be healthy.
It's bad for your act.
You want to feel like shit.
Yeah.
The only time you feel good is when
you're drunk.
Right.
That's it.
You want it to be depressed or be angry
and lonely to smoke cigarettes
desperately need their attention on
stage.
Yep.
No worries.
The only place you live,
we're all fucked.
Who Cares?
Well,
some of my favorite acts were like
really depressed,
like Richard Jennings,
one of my all time favorite acts.
It was super depressed when I'm killing
himself,
you know,
and just like,
God dammit.
It was,
it was maddening when I,
when I heard the news,
because he's one of those cues,
one of those go tos that I could just,
you know,
I get fed up with comedians that aren't
fans anymore,
or a guy in Chicago who,
ah,
you ever have those people,
you,
you start out around and you're like,
you just look at them and you never stay
up and you're like,
I never want to be you man.
Never.
And he would be the back and just go,
we'd go,
HAH,
funny.
Like,
is it because you didn't laugh?
You made a noise like laughter.
But you see everything is a competition.
And I love,
I love watching good comics,
whoever they are.
And like Jenny,
Jenny was one of those guys were just
like,
this guy's an ace.
You're like Brian Regan.
Or it's like,
I'm never not going to laugh.
He's such a sweetheart too.
We've talked about this in the podcast
and I think what that came from was
there was a famine mentality that
existed in like the eighties and the
nineties because the only way you can
become successful is if you got on the
tonight show and there was only one slot
at night and there's only five nights a
week.
And then if they don't know,
always have comics on either.
And then the only other way you would
get successful is if you've got to sit
calm.
Right?
Or you got an HBO special,
which only famous people got,
right.
Yeah.
That was the,
that was the highest would be Seinfeld
or Kennison or someone big to get an hbo
special.
So for a regular small,
like you were I back then it was like,
what do you do?
How do you make it so everybody was dog
eat dog.
Yeah.
It was all,
and I think somewhere along the line,
the early to mid two thousands that
shifted and it shifted because of the
Internet.
That's true,
isn't it?
It is.
It is an internet.
I kind of thought of it as an organic
thing from,
you know,
because uh,
the comedy boom happened because disco
died and you could basically fill a,
a,
a huge room with just a spotlight and a
Mike and one dude,
you know,
uh,
and these guys still have that space and
they were just raking in hand over fist
because people just,
they didn't want to disco dance anymore
and it did,
it just died a horrible death.
There was too much a cliche.
Everyone,
cocaine and everyone did disco.
Like Kenny Rogers did a disco song.
It was just like everybody kissed a
disco song.
I know.
And so I thought it was because that
kind of faded out.
We kind of just came to our senses as
audience members and Comedians.
But you're right,
it is the Internet.
That's what changed it.
Well,
the Internet came along and comics
started promoting themselves and someone
who really deserves a lot of credit is
Dane Cook for sure.
Dane Cook was the first guy to really
become famous through the Internet.
And then everyone,
including me,
started paying attention going,
oh,
this is another way.
Even though there is the regular way of
television shows and movies and all that
stuff.
There's this way to in this way,
just made at the time he was the biggest
selling comedian of all time.
Yeah.
He spent like 20 grand on a website,
which to me at the time I was like,
who has that kind of money that's and
why buy a car?
But he was the smart
one and he also spent all day day
responding to people online and then,
you know,
built up this reputation for doing that
and then promoted the shit out of
himself through my space and all these
different ways that he promoted,
you know,
the shows instead and then became
gigantic.
Yeah.
And then everyone else around 2003 or
four that's when we all started to jump
in and comics had my space accounts and
comics had facebook pages and,
and I,
you know,
I had a website in the 90s I had a
website way back in the night,
but I basically just wrote blogs on it
and had a message board and fucked
around in the message board.
But what he did was use it as a business
vehicle.
Right.
Like in a way to actively promote
himself.
So then somewhere in the mid two
thousands comics started doing internet
things like little internet shows,
like crackle was a thing and they were
doing little online things and then
people were working with each other
more.
So instead of comics being like
competition,
there were,
there was camaraderie,
we were doing each other's stuff.
And then podcasting took it over the
top.
Yes.
Once that happened then everybody
realized,
Oh,
you could really help each other.
Yeah.
And you don't have to use,
I feel like in between there,
uh,
one thing you,
one thing you left out was the amount of
the rise of what you call the Internet
comedian,
which where they just kind of would make
blogs and they had people that would
edit them so that they would be funny.
Yeah.
Like you and I have come up over,
you know,
20 odd years doing standup where you
learn timing,
you learn how to read an audience to ebb
and the flow,
your brain waves and how to pick when to
say something.
And how,
you know,
because timing is everything with,
with uh,
an Internet video,
you can have an editor just go,
nope,
here,
here.
He should have said that faster.
And it,
it's this thing that kind of vaunted
these kids into,
you know,
youtube millionaires if they were lucky,
but sometimes they'd go on the road and
people were like something that's going
on and every single time they'd eat
plates of Shit.
Like you can't just do,
that's like learning karate in your
basement.
Practicing in the mirror.
Yeah.
And then going to fight in a tournament.
It's like those guys I saw that,
that,
that you put up online of those,
those,
those tutorials,
horrible tutorial,
fake martial or come at me,
it's like that guy entering the squared
circle with someone who knows what he's
doing.
Are they still doing that style of video
where the edit constantly and make those
youtube videos where it's constant edit,
edit,
where they cut out all the pauses.
Is that still a thing?
I mean it's her,
there's all sorts of styles on youtube.
Shit.
I could find you a hundred videos of
that.
Yeah,
yeah.
I remember when that was like the
primary way these people were doing
these blogs.
Everybody had,
it was like,
then you have blah,
blah.
Everything was edited and it would cut
to,
it's almost like watching,
watching family guy,
uh,
you know,
Peter would be like,
that's my time I was into disco and it
cuts to him and he's like,
jacking off on a disco for this cuts
back.
You know,
it was like that because you could just
do that.
We have to say it on stage.
We have to have a segway and blah,
blah,
blah.
We can't just hit a click and then you
cut to me beating off and then back to
me in the audience.
I've watched a couple people recently
tried to transfer that,
doing stuff in front of a microphone in
front of a video camera to going on
stage for the first time.
I've watched the Aha.
It's terrifying.
Uh,
and,
and it,
it kind of breaks the covenant of an
audience because anytime,
like I have a,
I have a,
an opener who's like,
they're like,
I'm actually fucking nervous and blah,
blah,
blah.
You know,
do you still get nervous?
And I'm like,
yeah,
of course.
Of course.
I'd be a sociopath if I didn't get
nervous almost every time.
But you know,
you just,
you fight through it and it's fine.
But I always tell him,
look man,
the audience is rooting for you.
Like they want you to do good.
You know,
that's the thing that people forget.
They think they think every time you're
on the road,
it's,
it's an away game.
Unless you're a hot girl.
Yeah.
That's who you are owed for standing up.
There's a hot girl,
hot girl with like showing some cleavage
with a skirt.
Good fucking luck.
Yeah,
because guys just don't take them
seriously.
That sucks to be like,
what?
You're funny too.
I'm phony than you and not gonna hold
on.
Yeah.
Fuck it.
Fuck you.
Maybe would look judge odor.
That's it.
Yeah.
That's a perfect male privilege.
Like,
that's not what I want from you.
I want sex.
Well there's,
that's a weird look to like a girl with
like long legs and a mini skirt and high
heels on stage telling jokes.
It is strange.
That doesn't work well.
You're,
you're overly attractive comedian.
Male or female has always been a little
weird to me.
Yes,
there are people that are undeniable and
I'm like,
all right,
cool.
You know,
but it's like part of me kind of little
too handsome.
Their fellow tooth there.
There was a guy who,
when kyle and I moved to La and we were
roommates,
there's a guy that had a show and he was
a comedian and an a physical trainer and
he sent,
he emailed both of us,
like,
we were like,
Hey,
can we get booked on your show?
And he emailed both of us just,
she must take an every email,
uh,
in his,
in his book and just sent it out.
A blast of he is,
if you need,
if you need to get fit.
And the picture was a picture of him
shirtless under a waterfall.
Like,
hey,
someone's coming at him.
And I was like,
fuck this guy.
And as I say,
fuck this guy kyle and all caps goes,
take me off your list and just sends it.
That's all he said.
Cause I was like,
oh waterfall this,
this.
Looking at waterfall,
I'm so in touch with nature.
Sometimes I go backpacking by myself.
My,
my,
my favorite are probably one of my top
five onion headlines was a,
the trucker guide is like why do those
homosexuals keeps sucking my cock?
And he read the article,
one of them,
the second paragraph was,
I'm just hanging out with a bro under a
waterfall.
We're enjoying the day.
All of a sudden he's sucking my cock.
Hey Bro,
under a waterfall that every time,
yeah,
men under waterfalls with their head
back.
Like especially if they have long hair
flowing through their locks and they
tighten up their abs so you can see the
abs real.
Okay.
Yeah.
And it's like,
did you take it?
Did you take it up?
I'm still,
I'm flexing my core as hard as I can.
Let me know when you're done.
It's super spiritual.
Gut comes out basically plant based,
super spiritual out here.
There wasn't near.
He is.
That guy has taken it in the mouth.
That's like a kid that's like a kid in
Thailand.
That's like a,
an elephant coming on.
What do you like the muscular white
dude.
See that as more like a handsome man
feeling good.
I'll get a girl,
but it doesn't bother me at all.
When a girl is doing it,
get that girl back.
I'll get her to go grow.
So strange.
Live your best life
under that waterfall.
It doesn't bother me at all.
I see a girl under a waterfall with her
hair back like that.
Not even a tinge of disgust.
I don't see,
I don't even mind the guy under the wall
like that guys.
Just having fun.
Yeah.
That guy's not like he's not going.
Wait.
What are you doing?
Look at me.
Come back.
He's not being honest.
Your spiritual man like the one below it
with his arms down right below there.
Jamie on the bottom.
Bottom row.
Yeah.
That guy looks he's having a good time.
That's a fun dude.
Fucking party.
Super High.
Why the world needs happy men.
That's the,
what kind of fucking article is that?
I mean,
who wrote that?
Some depressed dude,
right about to shoot himself.
He's got a gun sitting on,
on the desk right next to the laptops.
Like why the world needs happy man.
I'm trying to think of it right.
It's like,
yeah,
we'll come back guy.
That dude's a ride.
Yeah.
Fat.
That's,
Oh,
Bert wishes he was that his kidney
dangerous amount of berry.
Burt fucking loses all this weight.
Every year we do this weight loss thing.
Toby follow along.
You're crazy.
You see with the hot yoga and he fucking
gains it all back every year.
Yeah.
Every year I saw him at soul cycle with
this wise fuck.
Yeah.
And he just,
I mean that's unbelievable.
He keeps telling me,
cause he sent,
he sent out a mass text test the other
day that we have,
there's a group on my phone called the
sober October group.
It is one of the best text message
threads ever.
It's ruthless.
Yeah.
It's Sigora,
Ari,
me and Bert and uh,
and look at,
um,
some kids burned with Bert Kreischer
that burn is not calories.
That's what's not burning.
No.
Um,
but he sent out this message of the day,
like,
I miss the heart rate monitors.
It's really old drunk watching,
saving private Ryan.
So sensitive.
Fuck.
Am I doing man?
You guys,
you guys talking without me?
What are you doing?
Yeah,
he's still,
he's like this.
What's going on over here?
Hey guys,
I miss you guys.
I love Birdman.
He goes out,
he'll do a comedy club and then go out
and tell everyone where he's going to
drink and then he meets them at the bar.
Takes the shirt off in Ottawa.
It's like 150 degrees below zero.
He drinks with them all and then leaves.
He's like,
well,
I love you.
Then he gets in his tour bus.
I mean,
I don't,
I don't go to the second location,
you know,
I'll,
I'll hang out at the club a little bit,
take pictures of stuff.
The people and they have a beer,
but like people like,
hey,
you should go to our bar.
Nope.
Yeah,
I've done it in the past.
I used to in the past.
But after a while becomes untenable.
Yeah.
You can't,
is there,
you're playing like 5,000,
10,000 seaters now.
Yeah.
That's a lot of pictures.
You can't,
your I watch,
I watched Jo Koy hanging out with were
on like,
they're going to kill him.
Like they're going to pete,
they're going to tear his clothes off.
Like Elvis used to almost get shredded
by female nails.
You know,
like there's so many people trying to
get a selfie with him and he just played
a stadium and he's just outside.
Wow.
Just like dude,
just Joe,
just careful security.
Yeah.
He's got,
he's got some people with him for sure.
But tasers,
Jesus,
different,
uh,
different.
He has the,
there's like a lady Taser.
It's not as strong and there's like
dude,
Taser for the various kinds of fans.
Yeah.
You gotta be careful,
but God bless him.
I mean,
that's kind of how he got that big.
The thing about burt's fans though is at
burt's fans were all drunk too,
right?
So they're probably not even going to
know what to do or you don't remember if
they were going to kidnap him.
They give it up on the meet him yet the
next day they check their phone like no,
that's selfies all blurry and shit like,
yeah.
Well your hand was shaking from the dts
while you tried to take it.
So coming back to town real quick,
give me a self,
your mirror selfie.
Come on.
Tries to dress up my facebook.
My wife's not talking to me.
Burden a your jokes.
The only thing keeping me going and uh,
the heart's not too strong these days.
The doc doesn't say I have long,
so please don't come around right in
this article for vox about why the world
needs happy man.
Three bullets in the train by once every
six hours.
Russian roulette,
one bullet,
not mine boats.
Nah,
not Verne's.
Not Verne's roulette mind with three
bullets.
I was thinking that the other day about
marriage.
That marriage is essentially Russian
roulette with three bullets
because one's going to die first.
50% of marriages end in divorce.
Oh,
and then there's the Chris rock line.
That's just,
he goes,
that's just the people that had the
courage to get out.
Yeah.
He was like,
how many cowards is stay and suffer.
Yeah.
So true.
True Catholic.
Yeah,
and this is coming from a guy who's
happily married,
but that's when I,
when I see people who are about to get
married,
I go,
Oh,
good Lord.
Yeah.
Well,
you're married.
Yeah.
As I said,
this is coming from a guy was happily
married.
Yeah.
It works.
It's just that you're talking about
Chris Rock and like,
oh,
he's divorced.
He's divorced.
No,
I mean,
but me,
I see people get married.
I'm like,
Oh yeah.
I always assume.
I was telling people like,
yeah,
I'm married.
I'm happy.
I love it.
Don't do it.
Yeah,
don't do is too risky,
dude.
That's why I got to have you on advice
from a dipshit because Amanda will call
through and she'll get like marriage
advice.
We have a lot every single month that
people call in and say,
hey man,
should I,
you can't give people advice cause first
of all there is no fucking way I know
how you actually are together when
you're alone.
I don't know that,
but it's advice from a dipshit.
So basically I just go by myself and go,
just make sure you're doing this,
this,
this and this,
and then you're on your fucking own.
You know,
they're not quote me.
You should have doctor Laura on your
show ever be mean to my God.
Be Amazing.
I don't care.
She's so mean.
Yeah,
she's just brutal.
He the meanest advice.
Yeah,
that,
well,
I mean if I need to have more of those
tough love people on the show,
I always had these comics that,
you know who it Santina was the meanest
once because a guy fucking big,
big Leprechaun.
He,
I had someone come on called it and was
like,
you know how he gets,
we usually curb these,
but like we get a lot of like,
how do I make it or when's the right
time to move to la or New York?
Never or whatever.
But like,
yeah,
but it's the eighties it's like,
it's like,
I don't know man.
It's,
it's kind of up to you.
And this guy was like,
I've been doing it like 12 years or
something.
And Andrew was just like,
the message to be finished.
She goes,
I would give up,
man.
I would honestly give up because this
business will eat you alive.
And I don't,
and that is something,
I don't have the heart.
I'm a sensitive guy.
I don't have the heart to say that to
anyone to just say back it up and move
on.
You're,
it ain't for you.
You know?
But Andrea was saying that and it was
kind of like,
yeah,
we're,
I appreciated his honesty,
you know?
Well,
like I,
I just think that it requires an
obsession.
Yes.
I give,
you're not like fully obsessed.
You're probably not going to put the
thought process and the effort and do,
and you're not going to survive.
The bombings know the bombings like
their test your soul.
It's just nothing worse than feeling
that amount of hate.
Where,
where,
where I ever been in New York and a dead
silence and hearing a guy in the back,
it'd be like,
Oh,
you fucking kidding me.
Can we fucking go home now?
I mean,
Jesus Christ,
like audibly,
audibly,
and the
silence.
Oh my God.
I just,
and I hear that guy in my dreams.
It is bombing on stage once and this guy
goes,
you're fucking terrible.
And I was like,
he's right.
It was nothing I could say.
I didn't never respond like not,
and I can say,
dude,
I'm with you.
I can't even pull myself out of this.
Yeah.
I got nothing.
Yeah,
Dave,
I remember Patton Oswald being on stage
at the,
the first festival ever did was a
Chicago comedy festival.
And I found,
I found the booklet from it recently,
like cleaning out my house and,
uh,
2001 and it was doug,
Stan Hope,
uh,
swarts in,
Tosh Kyle.
Who else fucking,
uh,
built wire,
a bunch of random like awesome people,
but uh,
patents on stage and,
and Marin back when Marin's still drank.
I think that was the last time you drank
actually that weekend.
Marin wasn't drinking back then,
man wasn't drinking way back in the 80s.
No d start drinking again.
Yes.
Oh,
that was like during the relapse period.
I remember it because he talks about
leaving the hotel and a friend who was
at the hotel was like,
yeah,
man,
when you left your luggage was sweating.
Like said it to me cause he was so hung
over.
But patent was like,
you know,
doing him and Marin were just dropping
in and places and this chick was so mad,
she got bumped.
She's like,
you fucking suck.
And,
and in fact it's like,
I agree with you.
If she was mad at him because she got
bumped and,
and so she was saying he sucked.
Yeah,
she's just at him from the audience and
like she just said,
you get up hunting.
Yeah.
Well I mean I was kind of like,
this is a free form room.
I got bumped but I get to watch Patton.
So she's a comic heckling.
Ooh.
Oh,
I know she ever made it did show.
No Huh?
Yeah,
I mean and and but it was that thing.
They were just like,
if you say I could be killing had been
one guy would be like,
this guy fucking blows.
And I'm like,
I believe that Guy Dan and I would go
one.
Oh that's the worst is when you're
killing.
You see one person in the front row like
this.
Yeah.
Like an old lady was scowling.
What?
Yeah.
I had an old lady like that at the store
the other day.
Older lady.
Like she was like halfway into my act.
She still had this look on her face.
Like,
oh,
I don't know.
I hit it with this one bit and this one
bid,
she throws her head back and then she's
Howard.
I'm like,
I got her.
Wow.
I got nice.
She didn't want to give and that's a
good,
that's a fun soda to cry when she was
like all of a sudden white best feeling
gave in.
Maybe it was the booze,
the booze kicked in.
How many without booze?
Boy,
that would be a struggle.
That would suck.
I mean our whole job is entertaining
drinkers.
I wonder what it would be like if we had
liquor free comedy nights.
Have you played?
You have to have played like those we'd
rooms.
Yes.
Those are too crazy or insane.
We did the Toronto one,
the underground room.
There was no air for the candles on the
table.
The candles were running on a promissory
note.
There was no oxygen in the room.
It was all just weed smoke.
I was on stage midway through jokes and
having second thoughts about it.
Like every linear thought was a tree
branch that was growing where I'm like,
which one would follow?
Well,
not only that,
what did I already talk about?
Yes.
Yeah.
Am I at,
what?
Am I covered?
All right.
I have no fucking idea.
Do you guys know what I was doing?
It was doing it with Tripoli and Tripoli
was sober at the time,
but we walk in this room and the
secondhand smoke is a fucking real
thing.
That's what I mean.
I hadn't hit a joint.
You have to wait till after my set.
I don't like doing comedy high and I
felt I felt high on stage and it's that
thing where it's like,
well you just got to run with it.
You can't,
you can't fight the tide.
Don't swim upstream.
You're not getting any better.
You just got to keep going.
I did.
There's a show that a guy,
Andy Haynes had called midnight run
where you'd smoke right before he got on
stage and you just hit this big joint
and I was doing great and then I had
this huge setup and then my brain just
the bottom fell out,
everything fell out,
all ideas,
all thoughts,
my name and I just went,
it was like,
and then the girl turns to me,
I've got to go.
And I walked in the middle of a setup
and then it was a crushed any cause
people were laughing so hard because I
just pulled the rip cord.
I literally was like,
I had a parachute that came out my
backpack that pulled me out of the room.
Sometimes marijuana is your friend and
sometimes it will fuck up your whole
set.
But sometimes it'll go,
why?
Why is that?
And then people go,
yeah,
why is that?
And then you're off on this tangent,
but you probably would have never been
on.
And that tangent might be the best part
of that set.
Yeah.
I mean I think about people that were
like,
uh,
from very regimented backgrounds and
went into the military,
you know,
in the 60s and then hit their first
joint and went,
this is dumb.
Yeah.
I hate this.
Are they,
cause that's the thing about,
I found it about marijuana is it
introduced truths about myself that I
found hard to face.
Uh,
and they were maneuver my new truth.
They weren't anything big that I,
that I was afraid of or something.
You know that like,
I really want to kill someone or
something stupid.
But it was just little things that we'd
like bubble up.
And I think that's,
that's the craziest thing about that
plant to me.
Well,
the idea that it makes you paranoid,
right?
That's it.
It's the paranoia,
right?
Oh,
I don't like pot.
It makes me paranoid.
I really think it makes you hyper aware
of all sorts of things you've been
suppressing.
That's it.
Because when I'm feeling good,
when I'm happy,
like I've been a good person.
I've been nice to people,
I've done the things I'm supposed to do.
I can get high and I enjoy the shit out
of it.
But when I got loose ends,
I'm,
I got things that are fucking with me,
you know,
maybe like something that went wrong in
my life or whatever.
And then I smoked pot and then it just
gets weird.
Yeah.
And I tend to not,
I don't smoke anymore and get and think
about myself and get worried about me.
I think about the world and I think
about way too big of issues.
And I work,
I think about maybe we're all fucked and
you know everything.
And do you have children?
No.
Once you have children,
then you start thinking about the
future.
Yeah.
Like what is it going to be like for my
children's children or their children?
Like you're like,
what,
what kind of toxic world are we going to
be living in?
Yeah.
This progress that we're exhibiting
right now,
if it keeps going in the same direction,
I think we're living at a level in a
level of anxiety as a human race that
probably four or five years ago I would
have been like,
we can't handle that,
but we're somehow handling it,
you know?
Well,
we were adaptable.
Yeah.
I,
I've definitely learned that,
but it's the,
the,
the amount of times I,
I'm so happy for comedy.
I'm so thankful that I'm a comedian and
I'm around comedians.
They can kind of just,
she just let the air out of me anytime.
What did you do before you did comedy?
I was,
uh,
I,
when I was,
I was an actor as I was when I was a
kid.
And then I went to school for acting and
then I went to Chicago and I got an
Improv and stand up and that was it
where I was like,
I'll still do acting.
But like this is,
this is where my heart is with so much
more fun.
It's so much more you can do it.
And it's so honest and it's so in the
moment,
I,
I've said this a lot,
uh,
on here and there,
but there is,
you know,
when you're on stage and you're going
through a bit,
you've done 50 times and you just drop
it and go,
you know what,
fucking I had the worst diarrhea
together today or whatever.
You know,
like something that you just share it
and the crowd goes,
oh cause a defense attorney wrote this
book and one line,
and it was,
the truth just sounds different in
court.
It just sounds different.
And it's the same thing for a comedian
when a person just goes,
I don't think my wife loves me and
you'll get a laugh,
but it's like fuck,
he really believes that.
And now the crowds like,
Ooh,
yeah,
good.
Now,
this is the meat.
You know,
you,
you took the,
you took the cheetos off the table,
now you've put the roasts down now good.
Now we have something to chew on.
And that's the immediacy of that can't
really be matched Improv,
maybe life theater shore.
But standup comedy is the,
is the moment like Buddhism,
like steep sand,
the moment and in comedy if you're out,
if you stay out of the moment,
you're no longer in the pole position.
Your car's going to drive off the off
the off the road because the ultimate
bullshit detector is a crowd.
And they know far more than they know.
They know.
You know,
I've been reading these articles written
by these angry women about Louis C.
Case comeback and some of them have been
going to his shows and writing about the
show.
And one of them that I read today was
from this woman in Pittsburgh.
What?
I thought it was fascinating.
She said that he has a,
he doesn't allow people to bring cell
phones.
You know,
they have those yonder pouches.
We put you and the woman's her,
her rationalization of this was,
and she included me and Dave Chappelle
and this,
that we use those because we know that
words offend,
but we don't want the consequences,
which is not what it is at all.
No,
it's,
you don't want people sharing your,
if your material online because you're
developing it and you're touring with
it,
just like we and jokes are a surprise
musician doesn't want you recording
them,
just noodling around before they finish
this song.
Right.
But it musician's song,
the differences,
you can hear it over and over and over
again and it doesn't lose any of the
thing.
You want to deploy it more,
more to the point.
But if you have a bit about diapers,
right.
And there's just like a very specific
punchline about a diaper and then they
already know it.
They know that punchline and you're
working out how to get to that punchline
and how to set up the bit.
But someone leaked the audio already
like that.
Like Louise touring right now with that
leaked set.
Yeah.
Which is weird,
right?
Like what?
All that stuff about the Parkland kids.
And I don't know if he's still doing
those bits,
but he was doing some of those bits.
Yeah.
He has a bit about losing all the money
and about,
uh,
how he bought a gold watch.
Like those bits,
like this woman referenced those bits in
the article,
which means that she went to the show
and he's doing the material from the
leak,
which he kind of has to do because he's
only if you wrote an hour over the last
10 months,
right.
He's been hiatus.
What,
what does he do?
Like what you can't,
he's touring shows you're going to tour
with a whole new hour.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Yeah.
I mean,
yeah,
I feel like,
I feel like he's,
he's quite obviously a special case
because of his behavior,
but it's,
it's almost like,
I will say that aside,
you know,
like,
uh,
I have my problems with Louie and what
he's done and everything.
But overall,
I'm on the side of free speech.
And in terms of being comedians,
we can't allow you to come in and film
our shit or recorded no matter who it
is.
Because it's,
it's the,
the larger thing is like everyone,
one thing with comedy is everyone,
everyone,
everyone thinks they're an expert.
There's no other art form or someone's
like,
I know what the best shit is,
or I got a friend funnier than you.
Right.
But in all fairness,
if I go to see a movie,
I'm not a movie maker,
but if I go to see a movie and I think
it sucks,
I should be able to say,
oh,
that movie blue.
True.
But you're not allowed to go on set and
filming yourself while they're filming
while you're also not allowed to bootleg
it and then put it online.
You don't go to jail.
Yeah.
And it really will.
And people,
uh,
that,
that record our stuff like,
uh,
Stan hopeless was tweeting about that.
Like,
how is this legal right after a louis
thing.
Yeah.
And,
and uh,
you know,
Chappelle has that thing that like the
comedy works has where you come in with
your cell phone,
they put it in a locked pouch.
Yeah.
You get the Combo,
you get it when you leave.
I was doing that before I did my netflix
special bar was only doing it to really,
because I was tightening up my set and I
didn't want any of it getting leaked
right before the Netflix special.
But once I filmed it,
then I stopped doing it because it was
like,
it's too hard,
too complicated and it's just like the
Internet is going to be the internet.
It's just,
it did make the show better though.
You know,
where it did make it better.
Miami,
I'll realize in Miami,
people are there such chimps that they
just kept getting up and walking out and
to check their phone so they'd get up,
they'd go out to get their phone,
they come back and so they were all just
like popping up and down.
Everybody's just trying to fuck and do
coke in Miami.
Miami will always be more insane than
any given American city.
It's just on another level.
It's forever young forever.
It's forever 21 yeah.
It really is like that.
Like the name of that city.
It is a cocaine city.
I mean it's created by cocaine.
There's more banks per capita in Miami
who I know in anywhere else because it
will cocaine laundering.
Yeah.
And,
and you,
you go there and they're like,
uh,
oh,
you're gonna,
you're gonna go out tonight and you're
like,
I'm out.
And they're like,
no,
I mean it's 1:00 AM we're not going out
until five.
Yeah.
What are you five extra years old?
And you're like,
what the fuck?
Fuck,
I don't do that.
You guys are crazy.
I have a wife.
They're all high.
Yeah,
exactly.
Fucked up on coke and pills.
Yeah.
Running around rapid.
You mentioned Chappelle and we were
talking about bordain before and I will
not say what the joke is,
but that guy is such an alchemist.
Like he can just make gold out of lead
in terms of,
in terms of material.
He had a board,
Dane joke that made me double over
laughing about the suicide and wasn't
talking about bordain per se.
But about his own family member.
Uh,
I like,
I don't want to blow the joke,
but it was,
it was that thing where a apologies to
people who are listening to this.
I know you want me to say what it is,
but I,
you know,
he's probably gonna do,
doing a special show.
I didn't do that,
but it was,
it's testament to how with comedy
there's always,
there's always a,
a mission impossible.
There's always a topic,
like,
you cannot make fun of this.
And someone found a way and it wasn't
disrespectful and I was just like,
God dammit.
You know,
he'll just say these setups that you're
like,
Ooh,
where are you going with this one?
Jesus Christ.
The idea that you can't make fun of
something is crazy.
Like just you just,
you might do it wrong,
but someone can do it,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
it might,
might not be your style,
but someone can do it.
Like,
you know,
everybody's got,
there's so many weird styles.
One of the beautiful things about comedy
is the fact that styles are so personal.
Yes.
You know,
like David Tail might be able to do a
bit that,
you know,
Sebastian could not do.
It's just not in his wheelhouse.
David tell is prob probably the funniest
man on earth.
He's one of them for sure.
Dude just,
just kills me every time he's another
magician.
He just pulls shit out of the air and
he's so prolific.
Yeah.
He's just always writing,
always,
always tone tuning things.
He'll call you up and go,
hey,
you ever heard something like this
before?
Because it's like,
it just,
it'll come to oils,
wants to make sure.
Yeah,
yeah,
he did.
Comedy is so beautiful in that it's
really is an art form that you cannot
learn anywhere.
Like you have to learn it yourself.
Yeah.
It's not like you can learn how to play
the clarinet.
You go and take classes and practice
music.
I've ever created anything.
And you could play beautiful clarinet
music.
Yeah.
I mean you don't have to ever have
invented a single song and you could
just go out there and make a living
playing the clarinet.
Well and you don't learn to play a
clarinet in front of an audience.
You don't bring it to the clarinet open
like,
Oh fuck you.
You have to learn in front of people.
[inaudible] yeah,
you,
you're not going to get up there and
play flight of the Bumblebee right away.
Is there anything else we have to learn
in front of people like that?
I mean,
even basketball,
you practice in the gym.
There might be a couple of friends
hanging out.
Yeah,
there's,
yeah,
it is the only,
only our from,
I can think of that you get,
you can only get better in front of a
crowd.
It's fucking crazy.
It's really crazy.
And there's no classes.
All classes that you take are useless.
Really.
They're all taught by fools.
Yeah.
They're almost sorry folks teaching
comedy class.
I've had friends who have,
who have been,
uh,
John Roy,
right stuff online that I think is
really illuminating to teach you what
the business is really like and,
and,
and what the best comedy is from a
comedian's perspective.
But he's not,
he just puts them up there for free.
He's not sitting in a room,
someone can give you a coat,
like a good comic and coach you.
Yeah.
Can say,
hey man,
you know,
that bit if you just came at it this
way,
maybe that would be an easier way.
Like Neal Brennan is that genius that
way.
And I did that for,
um,
for a show where a guy who was,
he was more of like,
he's entertaining,
but he's his,
his delivery and stuff was kind of like
a Ted talk.
And he was doing like,
uh,
he's going to do a show.
You did a pilot where it was just him
kind of talking about the news and
stuff,
and basically I,
they brought me in to kind of just
loosen them up to make it,
you know,
like the best comedians.
It gets like the funniest person at a
party or a,
Ha,
you're,
you're as natural in front of your
friends after a couple of beers as you
are on stage.
Right.
You know,
so I just had to fuck,
and it was just,
it was like,
like an tightening muscles on this guy
where I'm just like,
nope,
nope.
You're,
you're,
you're leaning into the funding,
you're trying to,
you're getting loud and you think that's
fine.
No,
no.
Just say it was fun.
That was fun.
Just coaching someone.
It's hard for people to see how other
people are seeing them.
Yeah.
Is sometimes,
that's one of the reasons why people
like to avoid
recordings or films.
They don't want to watch themselves
cause you watch yourself and you like
Yuck cost the worst.
You Watch an edit of your special I
have,
cause you already know the jokes.
They're not funny to you.
They don't hit you.
I have a special coming out February 5th
called find it a lot.
Finally live in Portland.
And what's it coming out on?
Ah,
it's coming.
It's going to be like Gaffigan's like
everywhere.
So Amazon prime,
Google play and Itunes,
all that jazz.
And it seems to be the trend.
Yeah.
I mean people who are doing that,
I was just tired of waiting where I had,
I had netflix and comedy central.
They both have good relationships with
them but they're like,
our is full for this year.
We'll try for next year.
And I'm like,
man,
it's,
it's the first part of the year now you
can't,
I'm just going to do it and,
and,
and Hinchcliffe is going to do the same
thing.
Smart.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's an callen to count.
Just did the same thing.
It's like you get to a point where
you're like,
look,
I got to go.
I get it.
That you guys have.
Yeah.
Five Hannah Gadsby specials on the best
burner ready to rock and roll about to
wake people up.
But I gotta make my thing.
But to the point,
besides my obvious sneaking in a plug
there,
I like watching the cut of it with a,
with an editor.
I'm,
oh,
death,
death.
People are like,
what's your favorite joke on it?
None of them hate tomorrow.
He'd all those jokes,
but that's cause you're good.
Any banks who suck,
they love everything.
They do.
This late two minutes,
I'm going to shit on Bobby Lee real
quick.
Even though we've only loved bobby.
I love him,
but,
and it's not even shitting on him.
I admired him when we were on,
when we were on mad TV together.
Eric Price and I were both on there.
We got hired the last season and then
they canceled it.
Make of that what you will.
But uh,
uh,
when we worked with bobby when he didn't
have his dick and balls out eating a
salad,
he would watch playback and we'll just
watch himself and be like,
to the point where Keegan Michael Key,
me and Eric would just point,
pointed him and go like,
she,
me,
I'm me.
He would literally laugh at his own shit
and I admired that about him.
I'm just like,
I could never,
it's a mental delusion.
He's got something wrong with his brain.
He,
uh,
he needs to put on a special,
I've been telling him forever,
dude,
you are one of the best standup
comedians alive and you don't have a
special.
And he,
he still goes to clubs.
There's like,
can I just do 20 minutes?
No one was like,
fuck no.
What we're paying you.
You Doing Howard?
Yeah.
He asked if he could do 20 minutes to
over an hour,
but he's all,
he's just so down on himself.
He's like,
I don't think I got it.
Can I just do like 20 can you let this
guy do 45 really says that when he goes
to a club and last were there to see
last I checked.
Yeah.
Cause he's just so down on himself and
he just get up and just crush you.
So funny.
I talked to him about it.
I was like,
why aren't you doing something?
I,
I'm going to,
I'm like,
you're not going to know.
You've been telling me you're going to
for years.
I've known bobby leaf for 20 plus years.
He's never put out a comedy special.
That's insane.
Yeah.
Bobby Lee almost got me killed at a
strip club in San Diego.
First Time I met him.
I already believe it be continue.
We were in our twenties
and uh,
uh,
I met Bobby Lee down there at the La
Jolla comedy store and then we went out
after the show,
this is probably like 90 [inaudible],
late 90 [inaudible] somewhere.
And we went out afterwards,
went out to the Strip club and there was
this Mexican gentleman with a tattoo on
his face in the 90s,
which is rare.
And he had long,
straight black hair.
Wow.
And he had a look in his eyes like he's
killed people.
I'm a good,
I'm a,
I'm a good at sniffing out danger.
I'm like,
that's real danger.
And Bobby was hitting on,
his girl was trying to get a lap dance
from his girlfriend.
I mean,
in Bobby's defense,
it's at a strip club.
But this girl was apparently his
girlfriend at a strip club and Bob and
uh,
the guy stood up and he stood up and he
said something to bobby and bobby comes
out and he's like,
fuck that guy.
And I looked at the guy,
looked at Bobby,
I'm getting out of here right now.
And he's like,
either I go,
either come with me or you're going to
walk home.
I'm like,
fuck you.
I'm not getting killed for,
you know,
we all ran out into the car and I had a
Toyota super at the time and I got in my
car and bobby was like,
that guy ain't gonna do shit.
I'm like,
cat in the fucking car.
dude,
you don't understand danger.
You're going to get everyone killed.
It's guys like you,
Bobby Lee's one of those guys that has
no spidey sense.
None,
none,
zero.
You know I have very strong where it's
tangling,
where I'm like,
oh,
I'm about to get jumped.
I needed just abandoned my pride and run
down the streets.
It was a was a real one.
I was like,
oh,
this guy's like a gang banger like this.
He had tattooed tears.
He was legitimately scary looking.
Even if he was bluffing.
W what is it?
This is a video,
like what would happen in this big guy
right here.
He just,
he gets pissed off and he basically
knocked everyone out here in the bar and
like nothing.
Nobody can do anything about it.
Oh God.
You just start one guy.
One guy's like,
hey,
you need to stop this guy.
Alex,
that guy out.
He starts beating up a guy over here.
He's just beating people up for no
reason.
Yeah.
Someone must have pissed him off.
He was dancing at the beginning of the
video.
He's like,
he's not doing anything now.
Fight.
Just telegraphing every punch.
I'm not even a fighter,
but he's letting him punch him.
He's just because they're all drunk as
shit to,
they're bumping into him.
Oh Man.
Oh,
he's guiding nudge in the morning or
something like that.
He's a Dick.
Yeah,
that's,
that's what could have happened in that
situation.
You have to send this to me because that
looks like my friend Vince Averil,
who's a comedian from the Midwest.
He's got that same kind of balding,
same size.
He's like punching little kits.
Yeah.
Look,
a giant punching little kids.
One of my favorite videos of a bar is a
girl and a guy and the guy had gotten
this girl's face and she grabs his,
his collar and headbutts some
unconscious.
She grabs and goes,
wow.
Wow.
Drops.
It's fucking hilarious.
Like that bitch must've grown up in a
hard family.
This too.
Cause this guy is way bigger than her
and it was a dangerous thing to try and
she just grabs his collar and fuck it
slams her forehead right into his nose.
I think you can,
you can get away with that if you're a
lady.
You know what I mean?
Cause it's cause it's guy,
well not that it's excused but don't do
it.
But like you're giving bad advice.
I'm not saying do it.
I'm saying shit,
this is it.
Yeah,
watch this.
They get closer to us.
Look at this back home.
Kod,
go to sleep bitch.
Holy Shit.
I look at her just strolling away that
Carl's done that before and that guy's
like,
Sheila,
you killed again.
Yeah.
Whatever gets you help,
whatever.
Who's going to resume you don't.
You don't tell he's moving.
He's like,
we didn't give you a bionic limbs to let
you do this.
There's just going to play the head
plate stall and when she was six,
yeah,
saying like put your hands on your
chest.
That guy had to be like,
what are you going to really,
he didn't see it coming Tux.
You never let people touch know,
even if it's a girl girl grabbing like
very careful.
That's a red flag.
If someone does that you you feel
tension.
Yes.
Feel like they're about to do something.
If you're a dumb dude and you think
you're invulnerable and then wake up
with a shattered nose,
get headbutted into oblivion.
That was insane.
The real scary thing is falling out.
Did the,
the,
the thing about getting hit is that you
fall in your head bounces.
Aha.
That's the most dangerous thing.
Yeah.
I mean I'm so tall I would probably,
I would have permanent brain damage.
Right.
All the falling.
Yeah.
Cause you kind of just,
you're just a sack.
The sack of Jelly.
Maybe that's why bobby so cocky because
he's not falling very far.
That's it.
He's just woken up on the ground rules
like tucks and roles.
He's like,
I was talking to that guy and I must've
bumped my head on something cause I woke
up in the alleyway.
But I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Yeah.
Have you ever done his podcast?
No.
I gotta reach out.
He's a good dude.
I love,
I love hanging out with a hobby.
Really does do a comedy special this
year.
I really do.
Cause he's so funny.
I mean,
he,
he's a no brainer for Netflix.
Yeah,
no brainer.
Right.
Diversity.
How should we go?
Yeah.
And he's a nut.
He has great stories.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
He told me a story once about a,
he,
he's,
he's at mad TV.
They had a table read and uh,
he hadn't slept in a couple of days.
He'd just gotten back from Mexico.
He had a giant bowie knife,
like tucked into a shirt and it was
fucked up on pills and he was just
sweating.
He picked up for days and he's at the
table read.
And that was before he decided to clean
his act up.
I was lucky enough to come across like,
well,
after those days,
uh,
and we,
they wrote,
they wrote a script to fuck with him.
They gave him the wrong script with like
extra lines with a monologue that took
up like the whole page so that he would
have to remember it.
We,
no,
no.
He'd had to read it.
And everyone's like jen cheap.
They tell everybody like,
don't worry about that part where he
thinks he's a bird.
And so bobby's like,
I'm a burden.
It's supposed to.
And like the writer was coaching.
I'm just like,
do the wackiest bird boy.
And he's like,
God,
God's supposed to fly and I'm a burden
I,
and he looks up and we're crying,
laughing and you see someone screaming,
fuck you got any through the script
across the room.
And I remember just taking pictures of
yeah,
just to,
they just did it.
I like on his birthday or something to
Mesh that was like the best prank.
Wasn't mad tv like the longest running
sketch show ever outside of center line?
It was.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
Nobody watched it.
It 10 people watch that show.
It costs too much.
I think that what it was,
yeah,
because they do a lot of like,
um,
song parodies and things like that.
And,
and uh,
it,
it just,
I mean,
I wish it would've kept going.
It was one,
of course you were working on it,
but it was one of those things where it
was like,
you'd see here it was still on.
You're like,
Whoa,
that show's still on.
Oh yeah.
Cause I was on it with Brian Callen in
1994 Brian Cowen and Artie Lange like 94
95 95 that's crazy.
Long fucking time ago.
Yeah.
And then all those years later,
I'm like,
what?
It's still on dude.
When I got the call to audition or was
that still on the television?
This was 2008 that is shocking.
Crazy.
Yeah.
2009 it ended 1995 to 2009 that's
insane.
We shot the last,
they cancelled it,
I want to say January of 2009 and it
was,
they canceled it on my,
they told everyone in my day on my day
off.
Oh,
so it was original network.
He was on Fox.
And why does it say the CW to try to
bring it back.
Tried to bring it back.
Yeah.
With like what Adam Ray was on it and a
couple people,
I don't know.
But what is the CW,
is that a real,
oh look there I am set up like a drug
dealers money laundering operation.
The CW network.
What is that?
Is it like those,
damn,
I live south of Glendale and there's a,
there's a banquet hall every two blocks.
I'm like there is some laundering.
Come on.
That's got to be some Geek,
some easy laundering.
Right.
Banquet Hall.
But just trying to figure out a way to
get rid of money.
Yeah.
Cause you got to move it around.
Justify the race to say there isn't a a
wedding,
two weddings a day.
Couple of weddings.
Yeah,
sure.
Yeah.
Well,
well that you got to think that if
you're a person in this day and age that
you selling drugs and you're trying to
launder money,
you have to be super sophisticated about
it.
That's the hardest part.
If you are making millions of dollars
selling drugs,
how do you,
you know,
you have to own like laundromats or
something.
Like you can't be like a Pablo Escobar
moving the money from the bottom of the
top.
It'll rot like fruit.
Like there's so many rats in there.
I was at a,
uh,
oh,
this is the best way to describe this
up.
Giving anybody up.
I was at a luxury automobile place.
Ah,
and uh,
this one gentleman came in who is in the
rap game.
Sure.
And He,
they had a large bag of money.
They were looking at Lamborghini's.
I'm,
I wasn't looking at Lamborghinis when
you do,
she bought a Lamborghini.
No,
but they sell them at this place and uh,
this guy had a bet and they were
bringing out the,
the money counter,
uh,
money counting machine.
Like scarface.
Scarface.
Yeah.
Like this is how they were going to buy
a car.
That's fantastic.
I guess if you're in the rap game,
that's how they like to buy a car.
Sure.
Till like to just like throw a duffle
bag full of cash and buy a car and then
you're done.
You're done.
It's like,
no,
wait my wire to come through.
No,
here you go.
I,
uh,
my,
I used to work with a business manager
who used to work with high end sports as
high on the athletes and she's like,
oh,
like I was just like,
can you eat,
set this up or some transfer?
She's like,
listen,
you'll never make my job as hard as
trying to get a Lamborghini dealer to
open at midnight in Las Vegas where a
client wants to buy one.
So many wins.
Yeah,
there's something,
I want to buy a lambo right now.
Coked out of their fucking mind how to
get married.
I'm going to buy a loom bright purple.
Who is that picture is his future either
rappers to him older than a million
dollar future.
His future is very,
very popular.
There's future and it looks like he's
got some stray hundreds in that a ring
finger.
You're slipping through his fingers.
Do you think he has a fuck hole cut in
the,
in the money,
right?
He's fucking that really well,
his pants are down very low and see
notice.
Good,
good point.
Okay.
It might be a,
might have a fleshlight paled into that
stack of cash.
So he's got $1 million in cash.
How much you have that Mike Tyson back
in the height of his,
his of his is heavyweight rain.
He used to carry like something like
$20,000 on a middle time.
Just something insane.
That's normal,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Well it's for a rapper.
It 20 grand is,
that's not funny,
but I'm talking the eighties but I
remember reading that article as a kid,
it'd be like Christ and I,
I went through two thoughts.
Isn't he afraid of getting robbed?
Of course not.
Of course.
Not Going to rob Mike Tyson.
He's going to find you unless you kill
him.
He's gonna.
He's gonna find he's going to sit on you
and punch your head until it's jelly.
It says broke.
Yeah.
That was after 50 cent file for
bankruptcy.
Right,
because like women were coming after him
for child support.
So he said he was bankrupt,
but he also made hundreds of millions of
dollars off of vitamin water.
Yeah.
He made a killing with that vitamin
water deal.
Yeah.
He's got some weird bankruptcy thing.
It was,
it was child support.
Is that what got him in the end
because no,
I don't think it got him cause he was
avoiding it.
He never should have wrapped,
have a baby by me baby be a millionaire.
I'll write the check for the baby comes,
who the fuck cares.
So like he said that since,
I mean you're setting yourself up there.
I guess he cares.
Yeah.
Well the thing is after a while when you
don't have a hit record out in like a
decade,
right.
You're like hey this shit could dry up.
Yeah.
Like maybe I need to go bankrupt and
stop paying these ladies and he's,
it's a cash only business.
He probably has it all hidden.
I don't know what he did.
Like he bought the vitamin water thing
isn't cash only.
I don't know how,
I don't know how that guy is a dollar
spent.
So you're bankrupt.
That's really is I think,
I think your theory is probably sound of
him just being like,
ah.
I think it was literally because of
that.
Like someone was trying to hit him up
either for alimony or child support and
he was like,
I got an idea,
I'm just going to hire some financial
wizards.
Work there.
Sorcery.
Yeah.
Dig a hole buried in the ground.
It is weird that people give people
money.
Like,
like you break up and go,
okay,
well now you got to give them money.
Like I get it if you have a child to
sport.
Totally makes sense.
Right.
But like if you dated someone for a
couple of years and then you married him
and then why you're married,
you made $1 million that didn't make
anything and you're like,
Hey,
I want to have that money.
Like what?
Three strange,
not together anymore.
Yay.
Yeah.
But,
uh,
I want money.
I want money from you.
Are you going to do half of my set on
the road for now on?
No,
no,
no.
But I want you to support my lifestyle.
Oh,
I'm used to a certain lifestyle.
That's another thing that gets me,
that people used to a certain lifestyle.
That guy,
the guy who,
uh,
Joan Collins,
I dunno,
16th husband or something.
I remember he,
that was his thing in court.
Like your honor,
my client has grown accustomed to a
certain lifestyle and that was all over
the news and it was just like,
ah,
come on.
Custom.
Like you can't change,
you cannot change.
Right.
There's no way you could live a middle
class life anymore.
It's that those days are done.
Okay.
It's upward.
It's only upward will you probably can't
you,
you can't fly anything less than first
class now can you probably I've flow.
Yeah.
Fly southwest sometimes.
Good for you.
Yeah.
It's just a fucking plane.
Yeah,
it's good.
But I,
I know people that if they have to sit
and like,
I remember when,
when,
uh,
during the whatever recession or
something,
there's some video of,
of puff daddy getting on a plane and he
was like,
he's like,
your boy isn't flying private.
We've got to fix these problems,
man.
I've got to fly first class.
And you just like,
why would I give a shit?
You're boy isn't flying private.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
It was amazing.
Thank you.
Thank you for tweeting about this.
I was worried about the government
shutdown and yelling at yelling at it,
and this was like 10 years ago,
but like yelling at the,
at the,
whoever's filming them on Tmz and,
and I think about the person that's in
like group D for that plane where they
call you and it's just like you and like
a stray dog that gets left on the plane.
Was he saying he wasn't flying private
because the money wasn't flowing because
the economy was low?
Yeah,
that was his point.
Yeah.
And there's someone that's like,
ah,
I use my last check to get on this plane
to see about a job offer and Tulsa.
Oh Jesus.
He's one of those guys.
Like he had some fucking billboard on
sunset.
There was like,
can't stop.
Won't stop.
And it was like,
all right,
I thought you stopped.
I didn't know he didn't stop.
He keeps the line.
I thought I told you that we don't stop.
Can't stop,
won't stop.
It's like,
yeah,
we had told you that.
We don't stop.
We,
you told us to stop you.
I haven't seen you in awhile.
You didn't stop.
Yeah.
Well what's he been doing while he
wasn't around?
He didn't stop.
What does he do?
It was 2008 because the gas prices were
too high so he stopped flying private.
That's what it was.
Thank you.
Gas prices.
It wasn't okay [inaudible] got to fix
this problem for puff daddy or ptsd or
whatever.
Like if I was playing stadiums or
something like that in 2008 and I got on
a plane and yelled at it like a tmz
thing and someone just creased my brow
with a brick,
like just hit me in the face earned.
Completely earned.
You know,
I don't think violence is the answer.
That's true.
I'm,
I'm I speaking dramatically.
But you know,
it's almost like that guy.
You ever been in line waiting to plane
and someone just starts playing music
and you're like c'mon man.
Like those rolling speakers on like a DJ
or something.
This is the thing that guys do at the
gym.
They bring their own small speaker and
overpower the music that's playing over
the,
no,
like what the fuck is that?
That happened to Tony and I in Toronto.
We were like,
what the fuck is this?
This guy just playing this shitty music
like really loud,
like techno
brutal brings his own music and you got
to listen to him because you're right
next to the lat pull down machine.
Fuck you man.
Well earbuds just to get by some ear
buds.
People are weird.
They're weird with their lack of
appreciation for other people.
Yeah.
Well the people that like watch their
ipads or like a phone and they watch
something with the volume on and I've
twice,
I'm not a very confrontational person,
but I'm just like,
Hey,
can you put some ear buds in?
And they're like,
I don't have any like can turn the sound
off.
And they're like,
oh,
they gave me a look like,
like I said,
something like,
you know,
take your pants off.
It makes you feel more calm if you would
You know,
like I said,
somebody that insane,
but they like,
they just look at me like I got it.
People listen to your stupid shit.
It's,
it's just,
it's,
it's distracting.
It's grading.
Well,
it's weird as a,
you'll go to a restaurant and you'll see
two kids sitting opposite of each other
with ipads.
They basically bring a portable
television and they're both watching a
different thing.
Yeah.
And it's like this sound,
these conflicting sound of two child's
programs going back and forth and kids
are the opposite side of the table and
the loud,
I was at a restaurant the other day and
there was two children and two parents
and no one was talking to each other.
The Dad was looking at his phone,
the wife was looking at her phone to
kids.
We're looking at IPADS and no one was
communicating.
They just sit in there like everyone
looked depressed.
There were all fat.
They don't have game rooms anymore
though.
Like when I was growing up,
we would go to a restaurant,
get a dollar game room for an hour until
the food came.
Yeah.
Dollar for what?
An hour.
We'll put that water back,
the quarterback,
then you can play four games and an
hour.
I didn't lose share.
He was amazing.
Kaylin and asteroids,
you get free games.
A Donkey Kong,
you a pinball wizard.
Now we as the pinball is a little too
old for me.
Pull position.
You know.
Ever since you were a young boy,
you played the several ball.
Yeah,
it's coming back for sure.
There's like leagues and all sorts of,
it's like made a retro.
Pinball is hard.
I know a dude who goes,
yeah,
he plays in pin ball league.
That's so impressive.
He's got pinball machines at his
restaurant.
That's amazing shit out of him.
But did you have to be good at something
like that?
It's just,
it's fruitless.
It's fruitless,
but it's impressive.
You know?
It's like someone who's really good at
like,
um,
like lawn darts.
Yeah.
Dick.
Fuck Bro.
There was a guy,
there was a guy,
king of [inaudible].
King of long darts,
Bro.
Yeah.
Like,
Hey,
this is the world's strongest man.
That's great and all.
But I'm the king of lawn darts.
I fucking rule.
I've given my life to lawn dark brown
who used to be these big ass weaponized
lawn darts.
Oh,
you could kill someone with them.
Lawn darts used to be like a small
football when the throat dagger would
just come straight.
Yeah.
Those are like hatchet throwing or like
axe throwing places.
I've made like a little bit of a
resurgence,
but I've seen it.
They becoming popular now in all the
major cities.
You know why?
Cause girls in their underwear on
instagram with throwing hatchets yeah,
like Aubrey and his girlfriend when
throwing hatchets at targets and their
underwear and the man cave men need it.
Need a new way to be violent during
drinking.
You know,
like it's just throwing an ax or it's
also very retro.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's very biking.
Yes.
Sam does acts as always land the right
way.
That's what always Fripp freaks me out.
But like it would,
my handle would bounce off the wall and
it would just fly somewhere weird in a
movie.
The guy grabs the knife by the blade
like this and it always lands with the
blade in the body.
Imagine someone threw a knife at you and
the handle hit like this,
you're like,
oh bitch,
you just gave him a knife.
This knife,
and I'm going to hold off after your
death grip and slide in your rib cage.
As you mentioned this yesterday,
but did someone duals that were in a lot
of duals?
I heard a stat.
I didn't,
I never knew about it that Andrew
Jackson was in something like a hundred
tools,
but he only killed one person.
I thought he killed a lot of,
usually get shot in the arm or like,
you know,
like a musket ball would go your leg,
or the one where he killed the guy.
He actually,
it was a,
I forget the guy's name,
but he was known as being a really good
doula.
He killed a lots of p like 26 people or
something like that.
So he challenged this guy and he thought
the only way to win would be to let him
take the first shot.
So he let him take the first shot,
got hit in the chest,
was bleeding,
covered the hole,
and then shot the guy and he died.
Whoa.
You shot him in the head of the city,
fell immediately and then died like a
couple hours later I think.
I don't know if he was the president at
the time,
but the doctor said like,
I don't know how you stood and took that
shot and he said if he shot me in the
brain I wasn't going to stand and take
that shot to kill this guy.
I don't know if you said like
motherfucker or whatever,
but like Andrew Jackson was crazy guy.
He's a crazy dude.
Like where his,
where he is,
where the statue of him is and I'm in
Jackson Square in New Orleans.
There's that church,
this behind it and that,
this is why New Orleans is supposedly
the most haunted city is because they'd
had the most duals because once Andrew
Jackson contacted John Laffite and was
like,
I need an army.
And John the feet was basically a
gangster,
which is basically someone that can get
you anything.
Like that's what a connected guy does.
And so he got him freed slaves,
native Americans,
creoles cajuns and just,
you know,
angry men and they repelled the British.
But then they stayed and they just lived
in the bars and they were dual happy
because their egos were so big and I've
looked for these and I can't find him.
What they had was dueling cards where if
you had one it would say Joe Rogan have
your face,
you know probably that image and it
would say you know dueling card and
someone bumped into you and you were
like,
you just give them your card and be
see you in the morning and mother fucker
and that means we're,
we're shooting it out.
Whoa.
You would do over.
And
the guy I went in this go this ghost
tour and the guy taught me,
they told me this story and he said,
imagine the amount of guys who are hung
over.
I woke up like,
Oh fuck,
what did I do?
I've got a dual now.
And you'd go behind that cemetery.
That's where they'd have their dual.
And imagine laying there with a bullet
or a piece of round led and your liver
and calling like,
I'm dead over this shit.
I stepped on my foot.
They'd keep cards like,
dude,
no,
this is just like a picture of one.
They also said that lot,
a lot of times the uh,
the dual wouldn't actually happen.
Like they might not actually shoot.
It was more of a test of will of like,
yeah,
will you just go through with it?
Yeah,
it was all honor and they'd have to
bring a second guy to make to like
verify that the dual actually went down
and said one was a pussy or whatever.
You serious?
He's like the judge,
he's laying odds.
It's like,
he's like,
ah,
there's certain states were duals or
legal.
I think there's still legal in Arizona
or they used to be because there was a
cop who shot someone in a dual like
years back.
Really?
Yeah.
It was a,
it was a weird thing.
Like a cop was off duty and he shot
someone in a dual,
oh man.
I want to say this is more than 10 years
ago.
So maybe they changed the law,
but I remember reading that going,
what you can you do all that shit.
Same Texas,
but well yeah,
this only,
what's that fist fucking dude,
what is that?
Well,
kill combat.
How do you take 10 paces in Washington
state as mutual combat law?
I just,
cause I know I watched a video of this
dude who was a mma fighter.
He used to dress up like a superhero and
fuck people up in,
he would like stop people from
committing crimes and then fight them.
And then one video,
Carlos Photo photo or I think his name
was,
he was fighting someone in Seattle,
in front of cops.
Like some guy agreed to fight him and
then you see right away what a terrible
idea it is.
And he laid,
kicks the guy and the guy's got this
look on his face like,
oh my God,
you actually know how to fight.
He beats the shit out of Phoenix Jones.
Yeah,
that's what he's called himself.
Phoenix dressed.
But watch this video of it here.
You can see it on that one too.
This is exactly,
yeah,
yeah.
So the guys like,
fuck you all.
Fuck fucking kick your ass and this is
in front of the cops.
It's like,
fuck you.
And he's like,
you know,
you think you're going to get,
and he's wearing this superhero costume
on and he's like,
give me some,
he's telling the backup.
You guys walking towards
see you see him wearing that outfit?
Yes.
And you think,
oh,
I could kick this guy's ass for sure.
This guy's a clown fucking cosplay Dork.
But watch that.
Skip ahead.
He's like,
okay.
So the guy wouldn't stop badgering them.
And then finally in front of the cops,
they agreed to let these dudes duke it
out.
Holy Shit.
That's it right there.
Let it go there.
Watch this.
Oh,
that's when you know you made a mistake.
The first leg moving around.
Yeah.
And again,
you got to useless and he's turning to
kick too.
He jabbed him to the body.
Yeah.
You fucked up.
Wow.
God,
this guy's life.
That third leg done,
that third leg kicks a real problem.
Yeah.
Oh,
the fourth leg kick.
Yup.
Wow.
That guy is basically hopping around on
one leg now.
Now.
Now it's a beating.
That's it.
That's rap.
Yup.
That's right.
Mutual combat.
You're right.
Yeah.
It's a mutual that law and cops are
standing by watching this Guy Gabe
brained.
That's what's crazy is like it's very
irresponsible for the cops cause that's
not a good fighting surface.
Yeah,
we'll have a,
you have a padded area they set aside.
There's a,
there's a great line from a buck Koski
novel where these guys are all gathering
after like a night out or something and
his guys hung over and he's just like,
he's like,
Hey,
I heard you got in a fight and he's just
like,
Oh man,
that guy had to be a pro.
Beat me so bad.
I shit myself.
Like that always gets me because it's
that thing where it's like when you
fight someone who's whatever,
what,
okay.
It's a fight but like when you fight a
pro,
it's just done.
Well it's like playing basketball if you
don't know how to play basketball.
Yes.
What a terrible thing.
Y'all place one on one and you don't
even know how to dribble this guys
dunking on him.
Like Shit.
Like why did I agree to this?
Is there a state where it's legal to
dual but there's no firearm?
When,
what,
how long ago was it still legal?
The late 18 hundreds I believe so.
So maybe this guy did it.
He was a cop.
He,
he had a dual with a guy who was fucking
his wife.
Whoa.
Yeah,
that's what's up.
Yeah.
And he just killed the guy.
I Dunno.
I don't remember the story entirely.
And he definitely killed somebody.
Jesus,
when was he was a cop.
I remember the whole story being that it
was very controversial,
but,
but it was legal.
Maybe I'm remembering it all fucked up.
Hmm.
It might've been more than 10 years ago.
Five places where it's okay to shoot
someone states.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
It's like international waters.
You get to a duel and unlike a cruise
ship.
So how does that work?
Like if you're on one of them,
carnival cruises and some guy in salts,
your name and throws Jello at you.
The laws of the ship or whichever
country.
I know about the international waters,
but like a cruise ship would be out and
that's nuts.
You know what,
I'm worried about cruise ships that I
would be on the deck when some guy
throws his wife off off the side of the
boat and you got to do something like
that does happen.
Yeah.
Husband and wife went on a cruise.
The wife can went missing.
I don't know what happened.
I went to bed early.
I mean Trisha kept partying.
We,
yeah,
we had an argument but we are a deeply
in love.
And uh,
we had a couple of,
I know people saw us
screaming and a,
and a,
and I might have slapped her a couple
times,
but uh,
boy I love her and her disappearing and
what's fucked up.
I learned from a buddy of mine who was
on,
he was with did second city Tour Cup
touring company or Turco and they were
on a cruise ship and he was telling me
that they found out that like all the
foods you don't eat,
they grind it all up and just shoot it
out in the water.
It's that attracts game fish and the
game fish attract sharks.
So anytime there's a,
there's a cruise ship,
there's just sharks all the time.
Really?
Yeah.
So,
so if you went overboard,
yeah.
Debts not,
there's not a lot of hope.
Oh,
good Christ.
Yeah.
Did you see that video of that woman in
Hawaii swimming around with the largest
known great white shark?
No,
it's amazing.
It's a more than 20 foot long,
great white shark.
And it's not like,
guess where she's just swimming around
women with it.
Yeah.
In the water swimming with it.
She's got a,
an instagram page is filled with photos
of her and this shark fuck off.
Awahoo it's so big.
It's so big.
It doesn't even look real.
And she's just swimming alongside this
thing.
It's a female shark.
It's like 20,
20 feet long at least.
So she just saw it and to swim up.
I think she's like a,
an expert.
Oh,
okay.
See if you can find that.
I got stuck in another article about the
dual,
sorry to go back.
Sorry.
S uh,
Oregon has a law that they were trying
to get rid of two years ago.
I don't know.
I'm trying to find out where they
currently are.
This gun,
where is Dick is?
That's a stat,
that whole stressor,
but it's still that,
uh,
here Republicans and opposed to scrap
172 year old ban on duals for public
officials.
Ooh.
I think their tech to highlight how many
arcane logs are still upheld,
but that's where I'm from.
I never knew I could have been dueling.
All this public official.
Well,
no,
they're,
they're trying to scrap the band so
they're trying to reinstate bands to let
people know how stupid these old laws
are.
They're still on the books.
She's a state decided it would not be
very civil of two members of the
legislature.
Legislature disagreed and then shot each
other on the front steps of the
provisional combat.
It's a bad look.
It's a bad,
yeah.
It gotta be cool though to see like Ted
Cruz and Paul Ryan standing on back to
back.
They have to use the muskets.
One coq one shot.
That's it.
I like in the upper right hand corner
Amaga hat board refuses to apologize and
infuriating interview.
That kid looked drugged and coached,
like he was just,
we both,
yeah,
it probably put them on some PROZAC.
Get out there.
A little fellow.
Apparently that native American guy
though,
they did an interview with him and it
was a disaster because he said a bunch
of things that just absolutely weren't
true.
And they're questioning whether or not
he actually was in Vietnam.
He definitely didn't serve in Vietnam,
but he wasn't in combat.
Right.
But you know,
he had some,
some conflicting stories and none of
these people were prepared for this kind
of attention.
You know,
it's like I was offended as as hell by
those kids and I'm a fucking big old
bleeding heart lefty for sure.
And I hate those,
those fucking hats.
But like I,
I in the state at the same time,
every teenage boy is a fucking idiot.
Everyone,
you know,
and like it's,
but those boys were standing there doing
their school chance while these,
there's a long video and the video is
two hours long.
I haven't watched it,
but I've watched segments of it.
And in the segments of it,
you see those native American guys walk
up to those boys and chance with their
drums.
So they're all there for different
reasons.
Yeah.
So the boys were there for the march for
life,
which is a pro life march there from a
Catholic school and they were in their
stupid red hats and then the native
American guy was there is for for
different reasons.
Yeah,
there were a couple,
there was,
there was a,
it was a native American celebration.
That's their yearly and you think they
coordinate these things but it's just,
there's all these different,
so a sort of marches going on and that's
all that's our right as citizens.
But it's just that they were all in the
Lincoln memorial together.
Well not only that,
these boys did not have like a good
chaperon.
Like these boys were wild.
They yelled,
they said something like it's not rape.
If they enjoy it,
enjoy it.
Yeah.
One kid yelled at again,
by the way,
there's 40 kids want,
if you have one asshole kid doesn't mean
everybody should be beat up because one
of your stupid fucking classmates has
something really dumb because he thinks
he's funny.
And he was 15.
I sat in an in an assembly once where a
friend of mine was in like,
uh,
in Chicago to Freeman.
I was doing a play and they were doing
like a scene from the play on stage and
a woman would come on stage and they
would,
these kids,
these boys,
I'm behind him and they're saying the
worst shit I can imagine.
And it just like Jesus Christ.
And it was,
it's that,
it's that it's the race to the bottom
like boys or it's like,
who can say the worst thing I can write,
I can,
yeah.
Can Yell The n word.
You know,
it's staying where it shows your tits.
Yeah.
Or just trying to make a lot of,
because what's the worst thing?
Rape.
And so this kid is gonna yell something
about race and it's,
it's uh,
their children.
Yeah.
I do feel they need better supervision,
but here's the thing they do for sure.
But there shouldn't be judged publicly
on a global scale like this shop fair.
Yeah.
I mean I disagree with uh,
pretty much everything them and their
parents stand for and stuff,
but it's their right to demonstrate,
you know what I mean?
So not,
I mean they look,
they are too young to know what the fuck
they're even demonstrating about to
really have a good argument about it.
Like to bring kids to a pro life
demonstration,
have them chant and yelder schools songs
and,
and put on magna hats.
Like the whole thing is so fucked up.
It's really,
well we're,
I mean,
back to what I said about anxiety,
it's just we're at each other's fucking
throat.
I mean,
I have a bit of my act about how like,
um,
I,
I feel like the Internet was built for
us to tear each other apart because
we're just throwing darts and running
away.
And if you put us in a room together and
talk it out,
we,
I think we,
I think we would mano a mano.
You'd,
because people,
the people,
we all want the same thing.
Yeah.
Deep down inside we all want to take
care of our kids.
We all want to have fun.
We all want a bountiful life,
you know?
But I also say like,
I'm also like,
I love people,
but I fucking hate people.
Like it's like,
you know,
it's like if you go through a whole day
without speaking to another human being,
you ever had one of those days.
Fuck.
That was awesome.
Isolation.
That was delicious.
It's only if you have too much though,
right?
If you get,
get around people too much,
then those game days where you just,
you could just recharge and then you
appreciate people when you see him.
Yeah.
And like,
do you ever get that where you,
where you go to,
you're on the way,
the comedy store and you're like,
I want to fucking go.
Like,
I don't want to go up right now.
I'm like,
something's masked with me.
But it's like that with therapy,
comedy sometimes.
And the gym sometimes where it's like,
I don't want to fucking go,
but every time I'm glad I did.
You know what I mean?
I know what you're saying.
I could have a set where I'd eat shit
and I'll drive home laughing and I'm
just like,
well that didn't work.
The thing that bothers me most about
this is that they wanted the docs,
these kids and po address out there
favor of that ever.
It's just so foolish ever.
And they're treating them like they're
rational adults that are,
you know,
fucking 50 years old.
It really know what they're doing.
No,
and it's not going to solve anything.
It's new.
You're not going to convert these kids'
hearts and minds by ruining their lives.
I do understand the double standard we
have had with like black youth though,
where it's kind of like,
uh,
you know,
this kid gets strangled to death for
selling cigarettes.
We were like,
yeah,
he's a criminal.
He's like,
God dammit.
You know?
Whereas these kids honestly,
cause they're wider getting chance after
chance after chance,
but I don't think their last should be
ruined.
It's like,
I feel like we've,
we've,
we've talked enough about it.
These kids did what they did.
Let's move on.
Yeah.
Well then you know,
who knows what they're getting chance
after chance.
But during this situation like this is,
this is the consequences of social
media.
The fact that you could take a video of
someone doing something incredibly
stupid when they're 16 years old.
Yeah.
And what they did was not even that
stupid.
All he did to stand there and smirk and
people wanted him.
He was being a shithead.
But like I keep a yc,
if he's just standing there and someone
comes up to him beating a drum,
how are you supposed to react?
I feel like the,
how do you think you would react?
I feel like the kid walked up to the
native Americans didn't correct
incorrect.
The kid was standing there,
the native American walked up to him and
the drama.
Okay.
Walked,
got rid of the video with sound.
What happened?
What do you mean?
The guy was,
that kid wasn't in the video where the
native American gentlemen was standing
there playing his drum and there are
kids around him.
But that kid that the main kid wasn't
there,
he walked,
he ended up walking up to them.
Yeah.
Okay.
But with the video that I saw,
the kid was standing there and that guy
walked up to him.
Here's the thing,
and this is two hours.
There's the,
there's video of these people that's two
hours long,
and the video that I saw,
those kids were standing there chanting
and that guy walked to those kids and
was beating his drum.
If that one specific kid walked down,
but still that guy instigated it by
walking to them beating the drum.
Not only that,
that guy got in that kid's face and beat
drum inches away from his face,
but I thought this is also talking about
that kid.
I thought that kid walked up to the,
to the native American.
I'm not sure.
The native American guy walked up to the
whole group.
Okay.
I haven't seen all that.
All of that video I saw American guys
said that there were saying build that
wall,
build that wall.
But there's no evidence of that.
Okay.
The Guy,
the problem is the guy's a human in
native American guys in human,
right.
And he's probably not prepared at all
for this kind of scrutiny.
And no one is,
there's a lot there.
There was an interview that he did with
CNN that is just full of holes.
Okay.
And uh,
it doesn't match up to the video.
It doesn't match up to what happened and
his like theirs,
you can pull it,
pull it video.
I'll pull that article.
But you've tried to find that article,
the CNN article.
There was an article about the article
that I read.
Either way I,
yeah,
I'm just,
I'm just inundated at this point with
all of it.
I will say like,
you know,
I've,
I've said for years,
probably 15,
20 years now.
I'm so glad youtube did not exist when I
was in high school.
Oh my God.
Cause you're just interesting book
twitter,
the things you would say on twitter or
snapchat or any of those things.
Yeah.
And I mean,
I did not grow up like,
you know,
my parents generation being mildly
racist if you're white,
you know,
I grew up,
uh,
pretty woke as the kids say in Portland,
Oregon.
So in Chicago,
Chicago is pretty left wing will
chicago.
I was,
I wasn't there until I was born in
Chicago,
but I grew up in Portland.
Oh.
And then I was more,
yeah,
but it was also,
it's funny,
we had,
uh,
we had right wing a Nazi groups moving
in when I was in high school,
uh,
gangs from La and then from central
Oregon and further toward Idaho.
You had,
you had a,
this,
the skinny metzger who had like a little
little camp,
you could go on partying if you've seen
in American history x.
It was just like that drink free beer
and they'd play punk rock music.
And the thing that everyone misses when
they look at those groups,
be it a gang or a white supremacist
skinhead group or whatever.
It's,
it's,
it's a community for,
for people.
And that's where they look at it first
and then they,
they,
they foreign communities,
sadly over focusing hate.
But I just feel like,
okay,
it's back here.
Yeah.
I mean,
which kit?
So they're all,
they walked up to him being in there
banging the drums.
That's the kid there and he's standing
there.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah,
there's a kid now,
but like he did,
but he's just standing there.
The guy walked right up to him.
You're showing me in the video,
the guy walking up to the kid and this
is exactly what I said,
Jamie.
He walked right up to the kid.
My point here was this,
the video,
I mean are these kids all mocking the
traditional native American music and
rhythm,
but Jamie,
that native American guy just walked up
to that kid and got in his face.
It's as clear as day.
I was just bringing up this like there's
this angle here.
He's standing here.
There's a group of kids who are out on
the kids might managing this thing
doesn't make any sense.
It's just the worst for Philip to the
kids.
He
walked up to the kids.
Any walked up to that kid specifically
got in his face.
There was a certain amount of separation
between them.
He walked to the kid and got in his face
while he's beating the drum.
I okay,
play it again.
I'm bikes right now.
He's the guy,
he's walking,
he's walking and the kid standing there
and when the kid standing that he walks
up to the kid.
So when they're doing the Tomahawk Chop
Chop,
they think it's funny.
Like did they understand that people are
filming?
They don't.
So here he goes.
The whole thing is so strange.
So strange.
Because what are you supposed to do when
someone walks up to you beating a drum?
So there's the kid,
the kid standing there and the native
American guy now walks up to him
completely violating a space.
Now imagine if this is a man doing this
to a woman.
You'd say,
okay,
he's violating her space 100% this is
fucked up and aggressive.
And that's what this guy's doing.
He's singing in this kid's face.
It's a little kid.
And what is the kid supposed to do?
I don't know.
Should he walk away?
Shitty.
Say I'm sorry that someone in the past
stole your ancestors land.
What is he supposed to do?
Yeah,
I mean it's no,
I'm not saying yes,
do that.
You know,
I'm saying what is the,
like the question is what does your kid
do?
But I mean these,
it's just he's,
I get why this guy is approaching
because there's just a,
it's a river of people mocking him and
his culture.
I get it.
But why this one kid and why?
Why get right in this guy's face or
you're beating a drum inches from this
kid's face.
Yeah,
that is the question and what?
Look,
it's the fucking hat man.
That God damn polarizing,
stupid hate that had so much.
Look at these,
even closer to him,
he's put the drum off to the side so we
can get closer to this kid's face music.
Expecting the kid to walk away.
I don't know,
but the kid doesn't do anything but
silly is blinking because the,
the beating of the drum is so close to
his eyes.
It's weird.
Yeah.
Okay.
The whole thing is very weird.
So weird staring that kid down.
I mean,
why wouldn't you walk away just to
define why we don't know everyone else
walked away.
But what does he have to,
doesn't have to be standing there and
the guy decides to get in his face.
I think you would walk away.
Probably the killer that on me,
I would,
I would definitely move.
I think I would probably move to,
because I'd be scared if that guy got in
my face.
I've done,
I think that guy's going to hit me.
I would think something's gonna go
wrong.
I'm like,
this is good.
This is just too weird.
But it's not the kids.
He's 16 yeah.
I the grownups fall for getting an a 16
year old kid's face beating a drum.
Yeah.
I look at it and I,
it's that fucking hat man.
I mean,
what's also the,
he,
the native American man rightly felt
like he was being mocked.
Yeah.
And then his traditions and his,
his heritage is being mocked and these
little kids.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't think he had the right to walk
up on the kid like that,
but it's like where,
where is your breaking point?
Well,
wait a minute.
Dot.
I don't think he doesn't have the right,
but this is where confrontation from,
do you have the right to make
confrontation?
Yep.
Maybe,
perhaps may,
perhaps,
but that's not really the best way to
communicate.
You're singing a song,
a native American song,
and he doesn't know what the fuck you're
singing and you're doing it inches from
his face.
Yeah.
And everyone's feeling,
it's a really a sign of the Times that
people took clips of that and they made
it out.
Like this little kids that can't and
even raise a offline had on is if you
ever seen a more punchable face like,
man,
it's your,
you're calling for violence on a kid.
Is that what you're doing?
It's,
it's,
it's the same,
uh,
you know,
level of,
and again,
you know,
as kids,
like even when you were pulling that
clip up,
I could feel my stomach make a fist and
I'm like,
oh,
there's just,
I don't want to see this.
But you know,
uh,
like it,
it's like that dude that,
that his,
that,
that kid at the cub game who had the
game in his,
in his earphones and he caught the ball,
which the outfielder was definitely not
going to catch anyway.
And they blamed him for the cubs loss of
the series and they had to squirt that
kid out.
And I thought the kid reached forward
though.
He did.
But I,
if you look at the tape,
I don't think that the outfield or had
it now fit her was pointing like you
fucked up kid.
Like you ruined it.
And it was kind of this,
why understand when you're playing major
league ball,
one mistake could mean the end of your
career,
right?
Your family's I man,
when I saw,
I think that's different.
When I saw that,
I thought that kid fucked up the game
there.
It could be argued.
Yes.
You know what I'm talking about this a
little.
Yeah,
but that's like you're staying there
with blaming one tiny play on the entire
game and you can't do that.
The fact,
the fact that back to what your point of
punched the kid in the face,
that kid had to be escorted out of
Wrigley field because people were going
to kill him.
They were drunk people that we're going
to throw hit that kid in
traffic.
Can we see that video of the guy
catching the ball?
I think that kid actually did fuck up
that game.
I think the difference is that kid
reached into the playing field.
What he did was definitely wrong and
illegal and let's see and everything,
but yeah,
let's check it out.
Tail the tape.
Steve,
here's the ball.
It's going.
Wait a minute.
Let me say one more time back that up.
No,
no,
but just back it up.
Okay.
I mean,
I,
I think I take it back.
I had,
uh,
I think they one more time,
I think I remembered it wrong.
Oh yeah.
They stole it.
They stole it from him.
Fuck.
I'd seen it take it all back.
He had the ball.
I take it all back.
That kid fucked it up.
Yeah,
he literally did.
He took it.
He literally took it from him in the
playing field.
Yeah,
you little cunt.
Oh,
he's got spray on on people.
Probably through beers on them probably,
but,
but it's that thing of like threatening
a kid's life.
That's crazy.
But also it's like if you're a kid and
the ball's right there,
you're going to reach for it.
You're not going to be thinking this
guy's going to catch her,
not going to catch it.
It's like you have the chance to catch
the ball.
It's right there.
Yeah.
You're to catch it.
Did you see that clip
from a letterman like from like,
I don't know,
30 years ago or something and he just,
there was a,
it was like the lineup was this famous
person,
this famous person.
Then just Aramco,
like a name.
You're like,
who?
And he brought this guy out and it was
like a middle aged guy and a ball cap
and he's like,
let him,
he's like,
you know,
I just,
I think you're the greatest living
American.
And the guy's like,
oh,
well I,
and he's like,
roll the tape.
And they show just like that home run
and it's going,
it's going,
it's going and this guy has just has a
beer and he's not looking and that
you're here.
The announcer go,
oh my God.
And the ball hits the beer.
And the guy's like,
fuck.
He gets hit.
And he's like,
Oh shit,
buff.
And everyone's kind of laughing at him.
He was like a home run,
there goes my beer.
And then endings later,
same line,
same run,
same guy.
And the announcer goes,
you have got to be kidding.
And the ball just hits the same guy like
again,
like twice,
same game,
but it let them and had him on and it
was,
it was like,
you know,
minor league or something like that.
Like you'd never would,
it wouldn't be unlike the nightly news,
but it was just like,
what are the fucking Huh?
How many people have ever been hit in
the head by a line drive that would fuck
you up?
That would hurt.
Like you'd be solely never be the same
again.
No.
Because when I was a kid,
Tony Conigliaro in Boston during the,
the,
the Red Sox,
he was actually like,
I was very young at the time.
Might actually have happened before I
lived there.
But it was like the store that everybody
always told,
he got hit in the head with a pitch and
he was never the same again.
And it was one of the reasons why they
started wearing padding helmets.
Yeah.
There was a kid who got hit in the chest
and his heart stopped.
Oh yeah.
Cause that,
that doesn't happen that often,
but it just,
it just makes your heart just go whoop.
It just knocks it out.
Oh Jesus.
Fuck.
It's a rock covered with leather,
you know.
I mean,
you feel a hardball.
That fucking thing is dense.
Uh Huh.
Yeah.
I mean soccer was originally kicking a
head around,
but that's what an Aztec culture.
Um,
they wouldn't like,
it was after like a battle.
They just take ahead and kick it around.
And that was like where the game is,
how we're soccer came from what,
from what I've read.
Yeah.
I knew they had some weird mind game
where they,
they played football and Mayan.
That's I'm thinking.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah,
and I think that they decided,
they used to think that they played and
then the winner sacrificed the losing
team and now there was also some
speculation that it could have been the
opposite that the winning team was
sacrificed was just like,
but I'm going to be in the fucking
slowest game ever.
Oops.
All got by me.
You know,
you scored again,
but the idea was that you would play
with such courage knowing that you were
going to win and then you're going to
get killed,
but you still want it to when it's,
yeah,
the level of honor that it was had to be
like so high and they are like,
my,
my family will never want for anything
ever again,
so I'm just going to,
or the level of drugs.
Yeah.
You were taking to pull the belief.
It's like,
you know,
assassin comes from [inaudible],
you know where this guy would just,
yeah.
Is this guy in in a,
what we call the Middle East basically.
He was like,
how do you kill a King?
You got to get an assassin who doesn't
care if he dies and so high on hash,
he built a of a family garden of
delights where he had naked women just
hanging around like prostitutes and like
flowing waterfalls.
And he would just get a peasant and
smoke them up so much.
And he's like,
do you want to see heaven?
And you'd be like,
yeah.
And he'd take them in the room and be
like,
check it out.
And he's like,
I have the door to heaven and if you
kill the Saltin and the town's Square
tomorrow,
you're here.
And so a guy would just run up and stab
this guy to death and the guard would
murder him.
But that was how you get a guy,
you trick a person.
So it's kind of like a,
it's the same,
probably the same thing where that level
of drugs where you're like,
if I,
when they cut my head off but I go to
vall Holla or whatever their version of
having is,
well,
human sacrifices always such a strange
thing.
You idea of getting like a living life
to the gods.
This was a such a common thing.
Yeah.
Kill people.
It's common.
It's like going to the game.
Are you gonna go,
you're gonna go watch that guy.
Get his heart torn out.
Yeah,
I'm taking my kid,
get some popcorn.
Couple of bud lights.
It's
um,
I was reading,
that a book,
uh,
not primate.
What is it called?
Simeon's sapiens.
Sapiens,
sapiens.
And there there's um,
uh,
there's a story about certain cultures
that were,
would kill like the older people,
they would kill like,
uh,
oh.
And this guy who had killed a few of his
aunts and all the old women were
terrified of him cause he would sneak up
behind them when they got too old
because they were,
you know,
there are gaps in Aladdin people and he
would hit him with an ax and they are
talking to these people and I'm like,
Jesus Christ,
imagine you got to kill your aunt with
an ax.
Well,
it imagine getting to a certain,
like your birthday party and blow out
the candles.
And he was just spin around it.
Fuck off.
Get away from me.
Yeah.
One of the craziest stories that I ever
heard was during the temple,
I think you say it too,
to con the,
uh,
one of the large Aztec temples when they
completed the temple,
they sacrificed something like 80,000
people over the course of two days.
Yeah.
But pull,
pull that up.
Temple of to ICAN.
I think it's,
um,
outside of Mexico City.
And when the aztecs constructed this,
when it was finally completed,
they essentially sacrificed all the
slaves that were used to build.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
So they just covered this fucking
gigantic temple with blood of 80,000
people that they butchered on the spot.
Yeah.
Oh God.
Over today's days to kill everybody.
That's a lot.
That's a lot of butchering.
That's a lot of murder.
That's,
that's,
that's exhausting levels of,
it's so much to the,
I had told a friend this story and he
was like,
that's not true.
I'm like,
I'm telling you,
it's true.
Why would I lie?
He's one of those guys doing the math.
I had to,
we had to get to a place where their
service and Google it.
Yeah.
It's,
it's just daunting.
80,000 people and these are the very
people that built the thing,
which I mean that was the way,
that's what they do.
Oh,
we're done.
All right.
Kill Them.
Well that was one of the weirder things
about,
uh,
going to cheech an Eatsa was there was
this one platform that was just designed
for sacrifice.
Wow.
Would kill people on this platform.
And it's like,
it was set up like a bench.
Like there's legs and the head,
like someone was holding this bench and
place,
they would just chop a head off and it
rolled down the fucking stairs.
Probably like a little,
a little hedge slide kind of thing.
What do you think the fascination with
that is?
Like this,
this idea of killing someone to appease
the gods.
And it was it because everyone was
afraid to die.
So that when you could force someone to
do it in front of everyone,
just for someone to die in front of
everyone and sacrifice them,
they would just,
it would long as it was like there was
enough distance between you and them,
they'll would be this charge of
excitement and very machiavellian for
sure.
Uh,
it's,
you know,
power perceived as power achieved.
If you see anyone can die and fall in
line real fast.
And I think it's also the,
the incorrect unpredictability of life
itself.
So it's like,
hey look,
we're going to kill 80 people but we're
going to have no,
no storms for the next couple of months.
Like it's no one I know.
Yeah.
Fuck them.
Especially if you have some like elder
who like some Shaman who tells you that
this is the only way we're going to stop
the storms.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
People believe the fucking anything.
Did you get to template to have finally
found it?
It says somewhere between,
uh,
there's a recorded article in 2011 post
story today,
84,000 people,
but it says this is a disputed number.
It could be a down the 4,000,
maybe the numbers disputed.
However,
some say as few as 4,000 were
sacrificed.
And what was actually a re consecration
of the Templo Mayor Corp in 1487,
nevertheless,
scores were killed cheese.
Um hmm.
So the one thought is 1487 the aztecs
recorded that 84,000 people were
slaughtered in four days.
Self sacrifice was common in
individuals,
would pierce the owners,
tongues and genitals to nourish the
floors of the temples with their blood.
And surprisingly,
there is evidence that Mexico was
already suffering from a demographic
crisis before the Spanish arrived.
You,
the Spanish probably came in at the
perfect time.
This is how you said the Great Pyramid
of t note Che Che
[inaudible], [inaudible] La is that I
say it,
that seems a phonetic,
that seems like I've seen that
vertically.
Alon.
To know,
to know Chit Lawn,
to know Chit Lawn.
Does it tell you Jose,
me,
Whoa,
cool.
10.
No Mexican pronunciation of say no
to know chip blonde.
Yeah.
I think that's right on.
Come up with better names bro.
Yeah.
Anyway,
a lot of people,
Jesus also said those games that they
were playing were,
uh,
that people already take capitated.
They might've been rigged.
They weren't sure if they were rigged,
but they might've,
how'd Roosevelt and faked or games to,
oops,
I lost it.
Died people like better.
They're more fun.
Those guys.
Yeah.
These guys you want around,
you got to sell tickets.
I mean,
we kill those guys.
We blow,
you know,
we've got no one to stadium next week.
The whole game.
It is weird that all cultures agree
that,
um,
one of the best ways to appease the
masses to have these large sporting
events or people gather around to watch
this mock warfare take place.
Yeah.
Uh,
like how the,
the,
when when Shaka Zulu came in,
they were just fighting like mock wars
and they were just like,
with fake,
you know,
swords and spears and he just ran out
and started stabbing people and they're
like,
what are you doing?
And he's like,
I'm trying to win.
Yeah.
It doesn't work that way,
Bro.
Trying to fake it.
Yeah.
Like if,
if we escalated past like football and
football,
like something way more violent came
along,
but not quite war like duels.
Jesus.
I know.
It's like I'm,
I'm,
I'm glad we're not there as much as I
have my problems with like concussions
and football and stuff and it's just,
just,
yeah,
I guess that's a good,
like what,
what's,
what be the next thing you can kind of
get away with playing football if you
get out early enough.
Yeah.
But even they,
they're saying that even kids in high
school have cte.
Yeah.
It's brutal.
Do you see what they do in Russia where
they have those a five on five mma
fights?
They have gang fights.
They meet on football fields.
Yes.
Russians are always taking it through
the night so that when you put up in,
uh,
it's like somewhere in eastern Europe
and it's just one big like bald bull
looking guy.
Fight like five guys.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I think that's Russian to good Lord.
Yeah.
These couple of guys decided to try and
take on a giant.
Yeah,
that guy was a giant.
That guy was like a dude that like
breaks rocks and like fi fi fo fum.
I smell the blood of an Englishman.
Fi Fi fo fum.
That's the kids even learned that story
anymore.
The fee fi fo fum.
Once they write some new ones,
why are we telling these old ass
stories?
Yeah,
I love it.
You see that movie about the,
uh,
about the,
troll hunter where that guy like goes
out into like the,
the end of Scandinavia and he's hot.
He hunted trolls and there's actual
giant monster trolls.
Oh yeah.
Remember that movie?
That was a fun,
stupid move.
It was fun.
And I,
one thing I loved about it was it was
just like,
are any of you are Christian?
Tell me right now,
right now.
And they're like,
no.
And there's one guy would like secretly
was and the troll could smell his blood
cause I think I smell the blood of an
Englishman.
I was like,
wow,
that's such an awesome angle.
Oh Wow.
It's just like that's cause he's,
he's like,
he's like a scientist.
He's like,
I know what these guys are after.
They want to chew up Christian people.
See if you can find,
find that clip for the trailer for
trollhunter cause it's so stupid.
It's so,
it's a good movie to get high and watch.
Yeah.
Well I love stuff that's like,
there's a giant thing in the distance
like coming.
That's how I,
that's a big thing.
If I'm high where I'm just like,
what if King Kong just came from behind
that building right now?
Yeah.
He's a volume.
Sometimes you get to see unique film.
Imagine they really wore trolls.
Just
he's just eating goats crawling up on
something
gay.
A foreign film.
Yeah.
It's,
it's somewhere in skin and like
Norway all day.
Come on.
Know
Micro Flora.
Well that's a lot of people think it
says,
do you think Michael Moore gave up after
the first trial documentary?
Like real?
Yeah,
exactly.
They're doing like a Blair witch project
thing,
but with trolls.
Yeah.
We'd get,
give me a little distance in this.
I'm tired of seeing this buildup.
I want to see the fucking troll.
This showed the trailer out for sure.
They don't shift wreck.
I'm Christian.
I love that
you just mush that guy.
Oh,
so many trolls.
Wow,
that's rad.
I love that.
I love it.
Monsters.
I love monster.
If there was something that big,
we would've never gotten to where we
are.
We'd all be holed up in caves right now.
Yeah.
Well they'd probably be like,
uh,
the,
the tech millionaires are like the guys
who like control one of those,
like he's just sitting on his head and
he's like,
kill those people,
you know,
crush that house.
You know what you think it would be tech
millionaires?
It would do that.
Richard's pick person.
No,
it would not be a tech person.
You,
I think you to have a trial.
You'd be sitting on a troll.
Yeah.
Weird.
When an opinion of me Zuckerberg,
he would have a troll.
He would,
he would pay someone to like train a
troll or something like that.
You'd find like a troll trainer.
And then let me ask you this.
Are you worried at all about ai?
Yes.
All right.
Oh yeah.
In what way?
I just wonder when it's going to get out
of our control because it's,
the technology is escalating beyond our
comprehension comprehension,
but yet you drive a tesla.
Yeah.
I do.
Contributing to it a little bit.
A little bit.
Yeah.
I mean it's,
I look,
we all are.
I am,
I am a dip shit
and a lot of ways,
I mean,
I'm an idiot and a lot of ways and I'm
just like,
I know you can hack a tesla.
I know you can.
Uh,
yeah.
But they're awesome.
Yeah.
No,
I mean,
if you guys drive a car,
I love it there.
They're apparently not doing so well.
It was some article that a,
I read today where,
uh,
there were,
there were talking about the letter that
Elon Musk's sent to all the people that
work for him saying that you're,
you're going to have to work harder,
but our goal is to try to save the
world.
Yeah.
Like,
see,
nobody wants to hear that shit and they
work for a company.
I mean,
and,
and really that's not what you're going
for before.
Well,
I think his goal is ultimately to reduce
our attachment to fossil fuels,
which can help save our environment.
I'm definitely with that.
Uh,
you know,
uh,
cut way down on factory farming with
meat,
you know.
Uh,
yeah.
I'm,
I'm all in favor with all this,
all that stuff and making way more
things electric.
It's like,
why don't we have solar panels on
literally everything.
Especially in California.
Yeah.
I mean,
we have sun everywhere,
everywhere and we have an amazing source
of light,
but apparently,
you know,
there's a lot of money involved.
I know this sounds crazy because a lot
of money involved in staying with the
grid as it is.
It's a share.
They've got to keep those nuclear power
plants running.
We love him so much.
Driving to San Diego,
sightseeing.
Well,
the old ones,
they didn't even have a way to shut down
like old power plants when they would
make them.
Yeah.
They can't stop them.
They probably figured we'll figure it
out.
Eventually.
It's late.
Let's put it off one day yesterday.
We'll figure someone smarter than us
will come along.
They'll fix it.
Yeah.
You when you,
you really hear about natural disasters
and solar flares and asteroid impacts.
He just realized how fucking fragile
this weird system that we have of a
power grid and satellites to distribute
information and the Internet is actually
a bunch of wires on the ocean floor that
connect us to Europe.
Like what is wires that are 4,000 miles
long?
Really?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That it's,
it's,
it's kind of like the human body,
like it's remarkably resilient but it's
so fragile.
Super Fragile.
One infection and that's a wrap.
Yeah.
Uh Huh.
Get,
if someone's drunk enough they can fall
off a building,
had everything going down and land like
something made a nerf and get up and
sometimes,
right.
I've watched a video of a guy who was in
a high speed chase with the cops and he
had a corvette and he flipped a corvette
and literally they went flying out of it
like he was a doll.
I saw that head over heels.
Head over heels was fine.
Yeah.
Landed on his back on the desert floor.
What?
You got some volume playing in the
background,
Jamie.
I'm sad.
Get to hear that too.
Those things,
they just pop up every now and then.
Interference I've been hearing
sometimes,
and I can't tell if you guys are hearing
it.
Oh really?
I've,
I've heard a couple of times.
But then you ever heard of songs in your
fillings?
Some people have recorded that.
They
hear radio sounds in their feelings.
Uh,
they pick up wavelengths.
Yeah.
Like you're filling will somehow or
another catch some radio sound.
Play it in your Foa.
Maddening.
When you hear like Mexicans radio
station playing out of your mouth,
it'll fucking plier to your mouth the
middle of the night so he could sleep.
Ah,
that'd be fucking brutal.
Hmm.
Well listen dude,
um,
your special when it comes out will be
available in February,
February 5th ended avail be available
everywhere.
Yes.
You'll be able to get it on t t tell me
all the places Amazon,
Amazon,
itunes,
Google play.
Uh,
I think it's gonna be on steam.
Weirdly enough.
The video game platform,
uh,
it's going to be all over the place.
Uh,
you can stream it,
you can buy it.
It's gonna come out in vinyl eventually.
But I know,
yeah,
I'll just put a couple of like a,
probably about a thousand out in vinyl
if people want to really?
Yeah.
I mean I,
it's called final finally live in
Portland and all the whole title is like
fake tattoos,
like dummies.
Where'd you film it?
At?
The Paris.
A former porn theater downtown port.
Oh.
They had a porn theater and I was a kid.
There were always like,
you know,
uh,
sluts and butts and stuff like that on
the,
on the,
on the marquee.
And then it was a,
yeah,
I see.
So that'll be like,
that'll be the cover of the vinyl.
That helium in Portland is amazing.
I love that club.
I told them where to put it.
They were like,
where would you put a comedy club?
I was like southeast Portland,
close to the water.
So people who live on the west side can
come across the bridge really easy.
You'll have a lot more space that way.
And uh,
yeah,
they've,
they've kept it running strong and it's,
and it's awesome.
It's like a club place to perform,
man.
Yeah.
It's a great,
that's another one.
This design with the low ceiling,
you know,
it's,
it's well set up and you've got to come
on advice from a dip shit because you
would kill it.
Okay.
I can see some good at giving shitty
advice.
Yes.
All right.
Yeah,
man.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Well thank you brother.
Telstra,
how to get ahold of you.
It's just brawner on,
um,
instagram and twitter,
just Bra,U ,
N,
g,
e,
r,
and then a map,
wronger.com for all my shows.
That's to me.
Bye everybody.
Thanks Joe.
Thank you.
That was great.