Free. You can't hold that pussy over my
head because I don't eat it right now.
I'm good.
Now I see someone annoying.
I see someone and knowing that
I don't want to be around,
that's pretty good for debts.
Why?
Because you don't like weight
watchers has a model, right?
If you're not hungry enough for an
apple, you a fucking hungry. Right.
Which just makes all
the sense in the real,
you're not hungry enough for an apple.
You Ain't fucking hungry.
That's a weird model. Okay. They use
the word fucking in that motto. No,
I just dropped it in there for effect.
But it's funny like they should
have a model for, if you,
if you still want to go fucking crack
coal and get blow after you've walked off,
then go.
I don't think you'll find the energy
once you wipe off and cut your legs right
off. If you sit there for tech,
like if you come to me and go, God,
I need $300 I'm gonna go kill a
crack call and get some coke. Right.
What would a heavyweight
title fight look like if like,
like say if you watch a boxing match and
then halfway into the boxing match, uh,
there was like a three.
Like at the third round there's a break
and some hot chick comes in and blows a
dude and then after he shoots is not,
he's got to go out and
fight the next three rounds.
It would be interesting to watch,
you know like how many dudes
fought well after they ejaculate
and how many dudes just
completely fell apart.
Just turtle up cause that takes the
fucking Fiat. That's what, as you say,
women weaken legs,
women weekend,
legs rack while they s they say
that when you do it for seven days,
when you're abstained from ejaculation,
by seven days your testosterone can go up.
I think it's as high as
50% but it normalizes after
that and then there's like,
well this loser just doesn't get any
pussy. Let's just stop making loads.
And then your body stops making as
many loads. Like apparently your,
your body can consistently makes
loads as long as you're using them.
That's the idea behind it. They
keep popping. You keep fucking help.
Yeah.
Anyway, the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by,
I think we covered the fleshlight. Yeah,
yeah. I think some questions are awesome.
Fuck yeah, go fuck those. I'm on
it. It makers of Alpha, brain waves,
Alpha brain.
It's a nootropic vitamins for your noggin.
It's essentially a bunch of,
uh,
like select herbs and vitamins that
have been known to enhance cognitive
function. It's a very controversial
subject. I believe in it.
I've been taking these long before
we ever endorsed Alpha brain.
I took a bunch of stuff and, Oh, I've
been in contact with Mr Romanowski.
Bill Romanowski you through,
through Twitter.
He's the guy that invented
neuro one and he's a,
a famous football player and that's how
I got into nootropics is, is neuro one.
If you're a,
you know,
if you're at a store and you ever see
that it's an awesome blend that he put
together.
Alpha brain is that it's all very similar.
It's all designed to stimulate your
brain's production of neurotransmitters.
And it just, uh, it makes you,
it makes me feel like I can
put sentences together better.
I feel like a little bit smoother. You
know, it's nothing, it's not going to,
it's not like limitless. It's not going
to turn you into a, if you're a moron,
but,
uh,
it does work and there's 100% money
back guarantee for the first 30 pills.
You don't even have to return
the product to you just say,
this stuff didn't work and we
give you your money back. That's,
we're trying as hard as humanly possible
to not rip anybody off and sell really
high quality stuff that I believe in is
a shroom tech sport is the one that I
talk about that I take every
time I work out. It's the shit.
It gives you tremendous energy. It's all
vitamin B 12 and cordyceps mushrooms.
It's fucking,
it's one of my favorite things ever.
Like supplements for like a preworkout,
the shroom tech immune.
And then there's five HTP enhanced,
uh, with uh, El Tryptofan.
It's called new mood. All the stuff's
explain a on it.com and again,
everything is 100% money back
guarantee for the first order.
He don't even have to return the
product. Just say it sucks. And uh,
use the code name Rogan and save yourself
10%. All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
the official beginning now.
Well thanks to see two oh
coconut water for hooking us up.
Dude, I drank something to dish
water coconut water yesterday.
I found there's a big difference in
coconut waters. You know, we had, we,
we found this out with a c two o the
company, uh, those guys came to uh,
to visit us at [inaudible] when we're
at the Improv and they said the Thai
coconuts or what you want,
that's like a short tree.
It's only like a five foot
tree or something like that.
And it's not like what we think of
these giant palm trees with coconuts.
It's not like that. It's a shorter
tree and it's like a sweeter coconut.
But all those cans go fucking Savoie
anyway that they all go south.
They will go fucking solid sema seal too.
I got them at the house,
so come to blow that smoke
up somebody's else's ass.
That's why I finally tapped out
and I go to a little Mexican.
I'm violin and fucking right.
Yeah. They get $4 he give,
he gives me the whole fucking coconut.
Oh, right there for the next two to three.
If you do blow,
trim it around like a Margarita with COPD.
Stop with those Kansas Shit
because they all go fucking south.
This is a great deal called Dao in la.
It is a great place called pressed juicery
and they deliver them to your house
maybe to deliver fresh,
fresh.
It tastes so much better.
He gave up.
It tastes so much better
when it's like right,
fresh and raw like out of the fruit,
but I got a cans,
I got a case from the CEO to and
it's fucking all south sea to
the one before that
they were in the refrigerator, drank
it it, I'll put some sugar in it.
Coconut goes a little fucking sideways
sometimes you just put a little sugar in
there and you'd open up with
some ice cubes to shake it up.
Sometimes if it's warm up, bro. Trust me,
I was drinking coconut water
when you were in Columbus.
Slumped drinking out of a red cat cock
sock that I was going to Puerto Rico on
the fucking seven days when you
could buy the big fucking coconut.
There was no tie around. In 1970 there was
no Thai food. There was no ties around,
so knock it off with a tight dress.
Ties get here and fucking like 78 I have
to kickbox and I have to kick box on
one. That's when they fucking showed up.
When I got to this country was Chinese.
A couple fucking jabs and a couple of
fucking Koreans don't start that shit.
The tie came later. Later on, all dark and
shit. Creepy looking, whatever the fuck.
I don't fucking dark skin the,
I don't know what the fuck they are.
I don't know if they have Puerto Rico.
They fucking Chinese ties came along.
The whole porno industry got
tossed on its head. Fuck. Yeah.
Those types of skills for the
ties came around there. I want,
and not even ties,
but there's some sort of an Asian
invasion that happened because before that
there was like river.
It was very rarely you see Asian porn
stars now there's like a gang of them.
And I love it.
I love to see dirty Asia except those
really like dirtiest one's ever. Yeah.
Would you have that one on your podcast
and one of them, one of the podcasts,
was it the naughty show?
Oh,
she's Asti beautiful to
look at the one with her.
I can't watch those man.
She gets brutalized. Oh,
gagged and tied up and face
fucked and know, oh my God,
the thing he can't just do
something happens somewhere
along the line, you know,
and I'm doing the that uh, David
tell show today, Dave's old porn.
I'm doing that right
after I get out of here.
Will you sit down like mystery science
theater style and it's in front of an old
porno film and you like mock it and
make fun of it and pick it apart. Um,
but those old shot, they were completely
different. You watch like an old porn.
It was just people that got together and
then they had sex. You know? It was like,
it seems so innocent and complex.
Get down to basics.
You build a fucking horny
cock suck all your life.
When was the last time you watched?
What was the first time you watch porn?
I want you to explain the
people and how did you watch it?
First Time you discovered point,
break it down for me right now.
The first time I discovered video porn,
like a real point, like on cassette.
It was my dad
phs.
Yeah.
Well let me tell you how long I fucking
have this government where they used to
come to the house real to real.
Oh my God.
Go for rate 95 you ordered it.
I knew somebody had to stay home from
explain reel to reel to reel to reel was
you actually,
if you ordered $22 worth a point,
each point real was a dollar 99
cents and this was when porn was just
disgusting.
When it was just to the point where after
that either you became a freak or you
fucking said, I don't even want to
see that again. That's what happened.
So what happened was for $19
not even guys, I'm exaggerating,
but 1295 you got three movies and a
mini projector. Brian in the mail,
he projected projected in
the mail. I remember it. So
you had a fucking stay home.
When is right next to the ad for,
do you get some kick sand in your face?
Do you remember that ad when the
kickstand, you went home, you said Joe,
we did $3 and we sent you the whole muscle
building shut. You're not the weights,
but he
also sent you a trophy.
You know one of those trophies?
I had 92 of them instead of the door
push up, you know what I'm saying?
And I do a pushup.
I just kept ordering Joe Weeder.
So you had a fucking put the
reel. The reel, correct? Yeah.
Tape it to the thing like
you were the fucking,
you had to do everything in those days.
You had, you had a splicer
he had, it was crazy.
It would fuck it.
You had to pull a sheet on
wall and hope that nobody came home until
you got the sheet off the fucking wall
for me.
Like my buddy's brought it over.
We put the sheet in the attic
and we all got together.
We smoked like a joint
between seven of us.
And we were all excited to
see this point in Austin.
And it starts like ten nine eight and
they showed this chick taking a piece of
bread, putting the guy's cock.
And this was way before crap.
I don't know what the fuck they were
doing to make these chicks do this shit.
the 70s it wasn't heroin because he
was awake. She put a piece of bread,
the guy's Dick on the piece of bread,
put Miracle Whip.
I'll never forget that memory.
And it wasn't even one of the bread is
that square fucking redneck be like in
county jail and the bitch bullet.
And she bit into the guys,
me and my five little sixth grade
friends looked at each other.
And that was the end of the fucking,
I dunno if we came in,
our parents thought we would just modify.
We never watched another point again.
That was the end for me.
But when the film broke,
I remember you got to stop correct Ryan.
Yeah.
You had a stop work whacking
off and put the film back.
Yeah.
And it sucked because it wasn't like,
it was just like put
the two pieces together.
You had the first like trim and
cut like a perfect like kite.
Then you had to put it in the
splicer and get those in your,
you got a boner and you're sitting
there rubbing into the tall white.
It was horrible. Porn was
tough. We had to work for it.
That's why you had a work sheet when they
would have stag films that they would
show at bachelor parties,
bachelor parties.
They would show stag films,
like guys would get together and they
would show films of people fucking,
and they would call them stag films,
but it was just porn porn is nothing
different. That's what they called it.
They called them stag films and they
would, uh, they would show them at,
at stag parties. Wow.
Yeah. How gross of that.
Then I went to a theater
in Jersey like one day.
My friends like Sunday nights to do
this shit up in jersey, dirty movies.
And you sit in the theater and watch
it with other people that God was the
lowest point, but it's not even low cause
you don't know. You're 16, you fend your,
let's go have a few beers. It's not
gross to you go to the bathroom. Oh,
the pissing the urine.
And some guy just happens to
pop out of the stall number two.
And he just stands next to you. Like
he's looking for flowers. Oh God.
You fucking shake your deck.
He staring at your day and
then you go back to your seat.
You could tell your friends.
When I went to the bathroom,
there was some perverted that you go
back to the bathroom and I like that you
take it again.
Boom.
He bumps out of the stall number two
and he's sitting next to you. Look,
I mean it would be so fucking creepy.
The whole lifestyle that's,
there's a lot of dudes that had ended it.
What
is it about sexuality that's so creepy?
Is it because it's so repressed,
but what is it about like that
one desire and so it's, it's,
it's so like gross. It's, you know, it's,
it's so undesirable. The idea
sexuality, like the idea of a,
you sit in, in a, in a real
like that's a part of sexuality.
You sitting in a room like beaten off
to videos of people fucking like a bunch
of other people in the room too.
And they're all like,
like looking up all together. Like
what the fuck? Why is that so creepy?
I don't know. But it is, you know,
for everyone was in there eating,
fulfilling that desire. There's no
issue. There's nothing creepy about it.
It'd be in a room and a bunch of people,
everybody is eating a sandwich
and there's no problems. You know,
we're all filling that desire. No issue.
I'll go back through it. But he got it.
But a sexuality issue, you know, like
it's very private and very creepy. And me,
even though everybody does it,
it's kind of mysterious so of be like
to sit in some room full of a bunch of
people and everyone's just openly like
sort of admitting that we beat off and
I'll sit in there together. Oh No.
Beating off in front of somebody else.
They're all doing man.
That's what they're doing with those
when they go to those theaters.
Not like just watching the film and
critiquing it. Wow. Her ass is huge.
How does she get all those Dixon,
the movie theater. A lot of it.
That's how peewee Herman got arrested
member, which is hilarious man.
How the fuck do you get arrested for
beating off at one of those fuck theaters?
Like isn't that what they,
you're supposed to do?
Aren't you supposed to beat off there?
No,
I don't think you're supposed to be
it off. I think you have like private,
I mean private rooms I could whack off
rooms like in bookstores are different.
The whole thing's ridiculous. You
know what's going on, you know,
do what you were showing people
blowing people and you're,
you're getting upset because
I'm a beats off with the crowd.
Look at your product.
What was the name of that club
where people went and paid money?
So Cyrus retreat, Devil's retreat.
Something's retreat. Plato's retreat.
Plato's Plato's retreat.
And what was that?
He was a sex club in the 70s and early
eighties where you paid, you know,
1000 bucks the door and you went and then
you fucked 85,000 fucking people play
those retreat thinking. You know, the
thing that always got me about sex that,
you know,
I've been addicted to drugs,
so I understand the addiction is when I
would get off the bus on 48th street and
it's,
you know,
seven 45 to go to work selling cars and
I would come home and roll the joint.
I would smoke it right down 42nd street.
I would just sit there and
watch that guys like you and I,
but guys that had families,
guys with suits on and tie that before
they have to go on with their day.
They would have to go into a peep show
and you know who I would see a lot of and
I'm not hitting to talk to me about,
he'd see a lot of Hasidic Jews. Really.
A lot of seeds would fucking run
in there with that black honor,
that whack walk with the laugh factory
is today with the laugh factory was in
Manhattan. That was originally a
strip club on that whole corner.
That was strip club fucking world.
Not even a strip club.
Beat shows where people fucking in a
circle and all that stuff. But I'm in,
I would sit outside of, you know,
because you have to cross that street.
That would just sit there
and watch people and go.
What would make somebody jump
out of a tree that was that.
You could see them like I
used to leave the store.
They have to go get a half gram a club
card. There's nothing else on your mind.
But that coat,
I would see them walking off walking
outside eight avenue fucking walking left
and you could see their body language.
They weren't going to stop.
The [inaudible] got to a fuck show to
see some guy fucking big flat black chick
in the middle of a room and you know,
some chickens up to you with
a tent and you could suck it.
It has a family that lives in the suburbs,
you know,
from Jersey and cleans or
that's what always fucked me up.
Like that's their fucking freak.
That's their freak.
My freak was doing two bumps and walk
it off though. Four in the morning,
there's was going right off the bus at
six in the fucking morning to see two
people fucking okay.
I remember a first time
I ever bought porn, uh,
you had to go to an adult bookstore
if you wanted to buy videos,
cause like you could go to some,
some video stores like
blockbuster wouldn't carry them,
but some like mom and pop video
stores. And then, you know,
of course you'd have to go through
like saloon doors you didn't have to do
or you go through like beads.
But um,
I had one time I went to an
actual porn store to buy it.
And I remember thinking like really
clearly thinking and don't fucking look at
anybody. Just get through this. Go,
go find what you need and
get the fuck out of here.
We're not here for small talk. Like I'm
not one of these people. I just need some,
but I don't want to be like,
and then I started thinking about it like,
who are one of these people?
Like you think about people that
visit porn shop to go, you know,
I don't want to hang out
with any of those people.
People that go to visit porn shops,
but wait a minute,
but I visited a porn shop like,
whooo. Why? Why is it so creepy?
But I don't know. But the instinct like
automatically is that it is, you know,
taking care of your sexuality, especially
yourself, it seems like such a selfish,
creepy, or harass like thing to do.
You're sitting there watching videos,
no drama, no drama, no
drama. You're whacking,
or maybe some people are
disillusioned from the world.
Maybe they just want to tap out for a
while and going home and putting a wig on
and jerking off his fucking
what they're into. You know,
that's the beauty of what we do.
That everybody's into
something fucking different.
I understand somebody going to a,
to a porn store or every
day because I go to the weed store every
day. So what's the fucking difference?
Corals correlation thing.
To me,
the point thing to me is fascinating
because um, like porn girls,
like there's like a huge number of huge
percentage of them who have had a bad
things happen to them when they're kids.
You know,
a lot of traumatic like sexual
type shit and it's not all of them,
but it's a lot of them. And so you
get to look at and go, this is crazy.
Like this is a whole industry that was in
many ways because of abuse.
And then that industry is,
is something that feeds,
you know,
through these online videos while he's
over millions and billions at people.
But we're all supposed to like
feel bad about it. It's all,
it's a weird sort of
undercover creepy thing.
You know,
you couldn't go into business meetings
and talk about your favorite porn sites.
You know, you can't just go there
and like, what are you guys doing?
You still going to youporn you
fucking noobs you know, hey come on,
you got to check out, you know, x, Y,
z up your ass videos.com or you know,
all Asians or whatever the
fuck WWE website it is.
There's like 100,000 like
free porn websites online.
But you can't talk about him. Everybody
goes to work and they just kind of, yeah,
if you brought it up you
could get in trouble.
Like if you shared that information with
someone that you work with, you know,
if like go like, wait, what
sites do you go to? Oh, you know,
I'm mostly like a fashion and
babies sides and well, what's,
what sites do you go to?
Have you been, have you been, he fucked,
I think it's called [inaudible]. It's e.
F. U. C. K. T. What is it? It's,
it's just like fucked up porn videos.
You know,
it's kind of like old style project, but
that kind of field. But like, you know,
the first one is,
uh,
this girl who's 18 has a whole hand in
her vagina and getting fucked in the ass
at the same time. If you just look at
the front page and all the crazy videos.
But anyways,
that's my new favorite porn shit.
It's just the abuse porn is very strange.
And so what I was saying about watching
like porn from like the 70s and the 80s,
they just had sex.
That's all they did.
I mean they got together and then
they had sex like porn of today.
It's like there's some really nutty
things they're doing, man. You know,
this little bottle like choking
and gagging and you know,
it's fucking spitting on each other,
spitting in mouth and
stuff. When we were in Ohio, me
and Jodie is wearing in Ohio.
I was over at my friend Shane's house
cause he had a baby and she was showing me
like he got the playboy of the
month and year that he, uh,
was born like that the issue,
which was like in 1974 and there
was this person on there that uh,
the, the, the centerfold was
the most beautiful woman ever.
And I'm like obsessed with her now.
Her name is, uh, Maryland Lang. It's m,
a R. I, l. Y. N. Lang, Ellie. And Gee,
what are you doing? You Stalker?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Yeah. Right. But, but she,
it was before, you know, implants,
like it was so weird seeing,
seeing like playboy that that was always
used to be all natural women curves and
boobs and stuff become like all
bleach blonde, early eighties. Right.
Was it early eighties, late
seventies? I don't know. But Lazy.
When you look at the evolution of the tip,
if you really look at a playboy
from 1969, you'll go, wow,
even the fucking nipples more rounded.
They will
point the uh,
you know,
it's really weird when a woman looks like
we've had this discussion before about
the women of the 70 [inaudible],
you know,
that way would the crazy one that Steve
McQueen was married to Ali McGraw,
I shouldn't call it crazy.
It was not for the smack that down set,
but it's just you see those women and
you see the women down. It's, I dunno,
I dunno if there's a
difference. I Dunno. Maybe.
Well I think it's more exercise
today and plastic surgery for sure.
And plastic surgery.
And so it's weird where like
unnatural looking tits are normal.
Like it's really an animal behind you.
She busted the scene.
She really damn anything. Pamela Anderson
really, and everybody in this room says,
yeah, she's gross. But at one time you
did look at this bitch and say she's hot.
She's hot. It was fucking that
picture. No, she's not as fun.
It is weird that we're looking at,
those aren't really her tits with
those are water bags under the skin.
There's a big surgical incision.
They stuffed water bags under her skin
and it stretches it out to make like the
nipples extend further and make the whole
thing well unnaturally tight and you
know, and swollen. It's
really kind of fucking crazy.
But you could tell humans beings, you
could tell she's got good policy for sure,
but how we'll show wago post how weird
fake tits. They're weird as fuck man.
It's a crazy thing. I think that's
a fake nipple or button. No,
that's a button silly Billy that says
place to perfect. Oh, you shut your pie.
Yeah. She probably know when it
comes to Paul and I don't really,
when I worked in captain video,
I worked at a video store and Aspen,
Colorado for a while and they used
to have like pulling in those days,
those sections, they had 12
boxes, you know what I'm saying?
Like a video store had to be six releases.
One of those releases within Olin sisters
and I brought him home and get coked
out with my girlfriends have in Berlin
and Georgia led the Lynn Lynn [inaudible]
and then the other one was when
that girl was busted onto the scene,
the one that was 14 and they let her
find that she was 13 and like I seen her
movies. Which are you talking
about Tracy Lord? Yeah,
I think she was 14 she was 18 there's
one video that you can get I think where
she's 18 well she did one called Tracy
does Japan takes a fucking doctor,
puts up a fucking pussy. Come on. Mama
Fried. Yes. She was fucking crazy.
I don't think you're going to look it
up. I'll look it up. Tracy does Tokyo.
Why wouldn't you?
Don't forget shit like that.
You know I got to find out
about course she was the,
I don't think so because they were all
trying to live up to the led Zeppelin
thing, but Tracy does Seattle.
They shoved a shark up some chick's
pussy in Seattle during an orgy dog.
Why Little Baby Shark?
He has that ball was the real bill though.
Check one of the freaking list and less
freak motherfucker till a couple of
books. Oh Man, I got to see
this. But Tracy did Tokyo.
There's an intro.
You have to get it. You got to get the
original fucking cut, the whole thing.
But Tracy does. Tokyo was when she
went on and that was the last fall.
Anything about octopus upper girls.
It's not going to just say,
you know what I'm saying?
It's not going to tell you.
She'd get to this toilet and
she puts it up a wiggles.
And I remember sitting in
that room because I used to,
you know how in those days you always
had a movie on and the video store,
I was so crazy. I put a fucking boner and
when people were killing it with kids,
I turn it the fuck off. You know, I was
living in another fucking dimension then.
So I remember pulling an island,
go look at this guys.
And I thought it was disgusting. You
know, I wasn't that into that much.
All that crazy. And this dog. My
experience is it's Boogie nights.
This movies online,
the parts of it that aren't,
aren't sex or online. This is
a wild fucking movie. You know?
I ain't got to drop the bullshit.
No one.
Whenever I come in and drop fucked up
knowledge, I don't know nothing about.
They know that Tracy Tracy Lourdes was
like 16 and look at those pictures she's
doing just hardcore,
hard fucking core hard.
God,
I got an idea.
Let's buy the movie and I'll masturbate
in front of each other to it on the
podcast.
Isn't it crazy that you can say
that there's something wrong,
but what she did, there's
something wrong. It's crazy mean.
She obviously knew how to fuck.
She obviously looked like
she should be getting fucked.
Right. All of the above. All
the pieces were in place.
Would you think that the numbers
get fucked up? I mean, if you,
if she was just a fucking garage, Jamba
juice, you probably wouldn't think that.
I think, you know, she obviously
wears a lot of makeup and her video,
that was 30 years ago,
those head cuts,
if you saw her when she was,
you know,
with no makeup at 16 dressed like a
16 year old, you'd probably go, oh,
that's like a young kid. Yeah.
But it's like that little Ramsey.
It's a weird thing where it's like what?
What is the right year like?
And no one agrees.
Like some countries it's like 16 some
parts of the world is 13 some parts of
this country, I think it might
be like really young, you know,
like whatever the age of consent is.
I think most of them are leaning towards
at least 17 as a, as a parrot. And those,
when you had sex at your age,
how old were you when the first time in
a fucking pussy. See what are you ready?
Where you really fucking
ready? I'm talking to you
man to man when you're ready.
Yeah, I was okay. I mean I handled
it. It wasn't that big a deal.
But I think for kids,
you know,
for kids fucking around with
kids there's a different age.
You know like you can say the age of
consent is 18 and if the age of consent is
18 that's that,
you know,
that makes sense to me because I mean 17
year olds can still make out with each
other. You know like there should be like
an age buffer where like an 18 year old
boyfriend who's been with a girl since
they were 16 and 14 should still be
allowed to banger.
Like once he turns 19 like they'd been
boyfriend and girlfriend for three years.
You know what I'm saying?
Like why can't they bang anymore just
because he hit some magic number and she
hasn't hit it yet. That doesn't make any
sense to me. Then there is a lot of that.
It's a lot of banging at
14 it was a loud bang.
The 14 bang on a 15 [inaudible]
14 I stopped some titties.
You know where you ready
for a lot of hand job?
Well you fucking ready for it was that,
you know the girl I was doing all that
shit with. This was kind of a thought.
As I looked at her Facebook page,
she wasn't ready to see my Cuba.
I grow it fucking 14 and then then you'd
have to refer to yourself as a parent.
What age do I think my son or my
daughter is ready to fuck around?
The question is what age can a man fuck
your daughter? That's the real question.
That's the real question because it's not,
can a 16 year old boy fucking 16 year
old girl? Yeah, of course they can.
Can a 17 year old boy fucking
16 year old girl? I guess so.
Can an 18 year old boy fuck a 16 year
old girl. Yeah. If she's been sure,
can a 19 year old guy fuck a 16 year
old girl know can a 20 year old and then
you know what I'm saying? Or he gets,
it starts getting exponentially.
Who's the judge of that?
Somebody in Kentucky probably thinks
it's completely different like it's seven
40 yeah. There should be, you
know, some sort of a standard.
But I mean at a certain point in
time I go to just got to let it go.
What are you ready? Look at
your kids around you. You,
whenever I meet people that have kids,
I always ask the parents,
how old are the kids? What'd
they say to me? He's 14 I go to,
I look at that person.
I go,
look at that kid at that age I was
already doing a thousand things.
What a shame. Cause I wasn't
ready for that. What she, yeah,
but you had a wild life.
Doesn't matter. 14.
You should not be hanging out with
guys robbing a train, you know? Uh,
I would say the cycle of true. How you
should not be doing a lot of things at 14.
Yeah, I have the, I stop and think about
some shit that I did not have some apps,
a fucking loot. We have 15 I shouldn't
have found somebody on the floor dead.
I shouldn't have done a lot.
You know what I'm saying?
I handled a lot at that age. I look at
these kids and like, oh, that's 15 wow.
At that age I had already mug somebody
a role, the drunk, I'd done something,
you know what I'm saying? It's
something to look over and you go, fuck,
either I liked this or I don't,
you know,
a shock like trace blood
do they like or he does it.
I remember hanging out on the street
at night as like a 13 or 14 year old,
you know, I remember like we just
be out on the street on the summer.
We'd be playing in the street. It'd be
like midnight or something, you know,
and we just be out. No one does
that. No you can't do that.
No cop would pull you over copper to
pull over and go and have a curfew at 10
got to be in.
Where's your parents drive you home?
We would just say like,
Hey,
I'm going to spend the night
at my friend's house and
Mri frame and say, yeah,
we're gonna spend the night.
But we had a protest and they,
the parents don't want to fucking talk
to her like little babysitter for the
night. We get the fuck out on
the couch. You know you guys were
mosquito bites and your Dick, right?
Remember mosquitoes man. Yeah.
Do we don't get that in la?
People don't realize how fucking conti
mosquitoes can be when you go out into
the woods and they just swarm on your ass.
I got bit in the face
when I was in Ohio from right here.
Regionally. Yeah. Off don't work no more.
We talked about this shit off that shit.
They power through those mosquitoes.
They drink that shift from mouthwash.
He got ahold of some Monsanto corn.
They were fucking super pumped up,
dude. My Dad was telling me about that.
This bug that came from Japan
and that's then hit, uh,
I think Canada and then went to Michigan
and now it's coming down to Ohio and
it's going, what it's doing is, is
it's, well, it's not bad for us,
but it goes into these trees. I forget
the name of the tree that like, uh,
that it's attacking and it, it, uh,
drills, holes in it and lays eggs in it.
And then when all the babies come out,
they just pretty much
destroyed everything.
So it's killing this whole
breeding the tree bark beetle? No,
it's something something I've never heard
of in in and it's just destroying all
the, my dad has had these trees
for 30 years in his backyard.
He's humongous trees. They're
all dead. And he's like, dude,
they're all the trees in
the neighborhood are dead.
Like it's just attacking Ohio right now.
And it when it was in Michigan before,
how do they stop it? They can't.
They can to pretreat a tree.
Like you could have these
people come out to your tree,
a tree and put this shit in it and they
drill these holes in the tree and put it
like this chemical on the tree
that supposedly helps it, but it's,
it didn't work for my dad.
And like all that he had all his trees
treated and it's just destroying all
these trees. That's insane.
Yeah. That's fucked man.
Isn't it weird how like now,
because of all the cross pollination,
which ships and planes and the weekend
introduce shit to a place where it has no
natural predators and that the whole
system just gets completely fucked.
I was on the, um, the, not
a, not even the highway.
It was on like a regular streets
last night at about 10 o'clock.
And as I'm driving down the street,
I saw this fucking coyote standing in
the road staring at me and then he trots
over to the sidewalk and then I slowed
down and I look at him and he's staring
at me and he looks left and it looks like,
and then he runs,
it runs up into someone's driveway.
And I'm looking at that kind of
like that mother, if that's reality,
that's nature.
That's something that doesn't know traffic
lights doesn't give a fuck about your
laws, doesn't give a fuck about, you know,
the, Oh, that's your kid. Oh, I won't,
I won't fuck with your kid.
You know this,
it's a crazy little monster or an
around eating. Cat's eating rabbits,
killing things all around people's homes.
And that's, that's, that's reality.
That thing's going to be here long after
these buildings rot away and nuclear
waste makes people evacuate, you know,
everything west of Pasadena, you know,
I mean once that actually happens
with things like that actually happen,
there's a gang of code,
there's a gang of coyotes that live in
Burbank and I have this thing where I,
I feel weird with coyotes cause I don't
feel like they're going to attack me at
all even though they might sometime.
But I always rolled down the
window and fuck with coyotes.
Like I'll whistle and be
like, hey, you know, like,
like do you play with the coyotes
dogs? But you're going to see a picture
of a coyote with her mouth open. Yeah.
It's scary fucking nuts man. They look
like cartoon mouse like their mouths have.
So like take it, pull up a
picture of one coyote mouth open,
big teeth something Google
asshole. Um, but Ho asshole,
whatever you want to
put in the um, um, the,
the extra like extra teeth that they
have are really fucking anything.
Set this picture out.
Jesus. We can always
fucking teeth. Look at that.
Look in his fucking teeth.
That's so scary.
That's really fucked up when you think
about that young girl that got killed by
coyotes.
It's so rare that that happens,
but it can have a little kids
get bitten by them all the time,
but usually little kids
are near their parents.
So usually what happens is
like the dad comes over,
beats the fuck out of the
coyote and the coyote. Let's go.
Like it's happened a few
times, uh, in recent memory,
but fucking this chick was just walking
through the woods and a whole gang of
them circled her.
I just said we can take her and just
jacked her killed by coyotes. Ooo,
that's gruesome.
Yeah. The gang in my neighborhood
just hangs out around my fence.
Like I'll let my dog will come out and
go to the bathroom and you could just
hear like,
like it.
My dog started barking and then you just
see all these feet scattering around my
fence. Like, oh, these coyotes
are going to try to attack my,
my dog if they can do it.
Knowing the coyotes can
attack people like that.
I say we kill all of them
when people are like, no,
these are our friends. Do you know they
killed a mountain lion in Santa Monica?
Do you know about that? I heard
about that. Were you go on Joe Diaz
is coyote could eaten
like can you eat a coyote?
Cause what if we can make
it some kind of Coyote Berg?
I bet you could eat it if you had
to eat it, but it tastes like shit.
I've had it tastes like
hatred. A big coyote meat just
tastes like rotten hatred.
Yes.
Coyote brain.
That's like crazy
Auntie fucking animals.
Kylie's are so they killed this
mountain lions and Sandy and um, uh,
Santa Monica and like where everybody
is second Monica populated area.
And it wasn't a homeless person.
No. So fucking mountain lion.
It was a real mount line, not a cougar
and not a crazy old bitch. And um,
when,
when they killed it,
there was all these Facebook posts
and one of them was my favorite.
It was so awesome.
There's this woman and she said,
why are w w it's only because of our
ego that we think we are better than
animals. You know, animals have
a soul and she like, you know,
soul in all caps.
I would gladly take a bullet for an animal
or a dog or a cat or a bear or a deer
before I would for a person.
Exclamation point, exclamation point.
I mean, I was, I was looking at this, I'm
like, this is amazing. Like this is a,
this is a person that's actually saying
you shouldn't kill that monster that's
roaming through the neighborhood,
the 150 pound cat.
Now you shouldn't kill that unpredictable
beast. And if you wanted to do that,
I would gladly take that bullet.
I would sacrifice my
life for this monster.
You sacrifice your life for one of the
most horrific creations of nature of big
cat
mean thoughtless killing machine that
you can't even roll a basketball in front
of one of those things. They fucking dive
on and bite it. That's their instinct.
Yeah. But they could have also done
that as a weapon. Just like, Hey,
get away from me cat here to chase
this ball and all this technology.
They can pull one of those bullets and
put them to sleep and take them to the
zoo. I figured out what's going on and
kill fucking everything. Yeah, I do.
I do think that kill everything in the
stand up there is as a harmful animal,
whatever. But something made
that bed come down that bed.
I'm gonna fucking nobody. We don't
want to fuck with him. Right.
So we did a building somewhere.
They shouldn't be fucking building or
there's no food for the fucking bed.
It's most likely.
No,
and it's also the problem with bears and
people is that once they find out that
they can go to garbage cans and get food,
that's it.
They just threw the
garbage cans all the time.
Then they have to take them and put them
in zoos and shit. They become, yeah,
I understand.
You have to protect the community.
We can't have a bear or
a fucking mountain line.
Does anybody know what a mountain lion
will do to you? Him being and how fast.
But at the same time. Let's see if
we could fucking mummify him first.
Take him to a museum.
Figure out what made this fucking Mama.
She one of those guards
on them that we have.
You got something on your list
when we have darts and lasers,
laser lasers and dark running under
one o one backwards and he gets shot.
Darden. What the fuck?
You got these dark squawk.
You got dark officer's Darla laser room.
You talk about them.
You show them the Chuck Norris movie.
Now you're on the one on one and you
don't want a dark nobody. You follow me?
We're a little bit to Taser and people's
dangerous. We're a little bit too,
we're a little bit too quick to pull
the fucking trigger. I loved the,
I loved the fucking, you know, bearing
arms and everything, but it's a bear.
Anybody who knows hunting or whatever,
just sit still for two minutes
and get the fuck out of here.
Get the fuck out of there.
You,
you kicked the garbage can that more
skeletal us until we fucking corner.
You know, I, let me just fucking ask
them what they were everywhere they were.
You gotta be real careful.
I gotta be real careful with it,
but I seen it a lot now.
I used to see schools are raccoons schools
and I'm crossing the street from the
big ones,
the little tiny one at the end.
I know those motherfuckers are dangerous,
but you can't hit them with a car.
Let them be.
I wish I saved a picture. There's
a picture that I saw once, uh,
I don't remember if it was online
or in a book or a magazine.
I wish I saved this picture cause I
haven't been able to find it and all my
Google searches.
But it was a guy who was a photographer.
It was killed by a bear and he was
taking pictures of a female and her cubs.
And the last image on his camera before
he was killed by the bear is the bear
with its teeth glared charging them.
And it's a fucking horrific
picture. They found it. They found
it on the dude's camera, but it is,
I don't remember looking
at it and thinking back
on your business when they shot Jim
Jones and they camera man went down.
I remember the camera kept running as
they was shooting everybody as we got on a
plane from Guyana that was live footage,
the ad on television.
What the fuck were you doing in Guyana?
You should've been taking pictures
of San Francisco where you live.
That Jim Jones story. Remember that
shit? They shot him at the airport.
What was the dude's name? Who did, who
played him in the movie powers booth. Ooh.
Bad mother fucker for certain things.
Oh my God. He comes out and when,
when you need a heavy southern gentlemen
throwing heat and you always booths are
bad.
Motherfucker.
Look at the screen here. Is this the, for
some reason the image isn't showing up,
but it says the images captures at
bear seconds before it's mod two.
It's photonics falls.
Well, I think you're thinking
of a different picture though.
The, the, the one, the,
they're thinking of one where it's,
I'm a bear comes into a guy's tent.
I think that's a different image.
Okay.
What's up Joe Rogan Baby?
Nothing, man. What's going on?
See if we could find that you're very
excited about this series and one fake one
though. A fake one where they showed
the photo shop to go with you.
I was going to be, this is a great fucking
card rate card. It's going to be sick.
Just some great college coming up to
the next few fucking weeks to dos Santos
and Frank Mir scoby nuts. I was going
to ask you to remember this. Salvia gay,
that was the crazy MMA guy
that was always talking about,
not Salvia, but Stevia. Stevia. I
know that whole story. Yeah, I dunno.
Probably shouldn't talk about it.
Yeah, don't give him any attention.
Something's wrong with them. Maybe it was.
Break it down. I'm very excited for you.
Sorry, I can't go. Yeah,
we should it go be fun.
I want them.
I watch one with you guys.
We got to go to a strike force car next
time. It was a big strike force fight.
Did you see? Yeah. The last one. Did you
see Josh Barnett and Daniel Cormier? Ooh,
what a fight. Both guys broke their hands
in the first round to look very good.
It's a beast. He's a
fucking voice. Takes a,
launched Josh Barnett into the
air to Josh Barnett is a big boy.
He's a big Daniel Cormier. Hoisted him
up and Whoa, boom. Threw him for a ride,
control them on top, smashed him,
cut him up with elbows. He's a,
and he's only had like, I think that was
his fifth that, I mean, it's amazing.
Tenure Karma is a motherfucker
is out of the baby face assassin.
He's been around forever. He was a
old, one of the youngest UFC champs.
He won, I don't know how old he was when
he won the title, but I remember he beat,
he beat Randy couture.
And then there was some sort of a
dispute with the UFC eve, you know,
management and UFC didn't get along.
And he laughed.
And then he started fighting overseas
and he fought in pride and you know,
and then he came back and it became
part of the strike force tournament,
you know? But he's been around forever
and he's that guy he's fought. He's, yeah,
he's fought. Minotauro is fought
cro cop twice. You know, he's,
he's filed a lot of fucking dudes.
I just thought his experience
would really shine through.
But for call that mother Fucker, man,
well you know though, Josh Barnett, Bro,
his hand the first round
and so the core me Yang,
they both broke their hand the
first round. So, uh, you know,
who knows how a rematch with girl,
but call me a won that
fight with his wrestling.
He won that fight with his striking. I
mean, he's just a mother fucker dude.
And he's not been doing it that
long and he's, he's bad ass man.
I haven't been really praised.
The head kicked Josh Barnett twice.
That's what you know. And Josh
Ran, I couldn't take them down.
No one's to be able to take them
down in, in a UFC match. I mean,
he's such a high level wrestler.
It's going to take a fucking beast
to take that guy down, you know?
And so you got to stand with
him and he's really quick man.
And he's not a tall guy, but he's
like compact and explosive, you know.
And that all the years of wrestling,
that high level wrestling,
I think the mental toughness
that those guys gain from
high school. Yeah, he was
amateur wrestling's and there's
a different animals, man.
Those are different animals there.
Those guys are tough on a whole different
level. They're like, in my opinion,
that maybe the tea all like
in camp, you know, you tell,
you look at just the percentage that might
be the toughest group of human beings
on earth. Just the toughest mentally
toughest is amateur wrestlers.
It really might be. They're
fucking animals, man. Those
guys, some of this shit,
those guys go through it and they do a
dehydrated and malnourished and they're,
they're out there like fucking animals.
You know what's crazy though?
You went to the UFC in Jersey and
he has all these MMA fighters.
The audience say that,
but everybody kept looking at that
Penn state fucking wrestling team and
everybody kept looking at that coach
war people went up to shake that
motherfucker's hand. I heard more
people go small. It is, what's his name?
You think coach a Penn state. That's
the best wrestler in the world. Oh,
Cael Sanderson, who was at the
fight right in the row behind me.
And he's wrestling again. No.
Yeah. I think if I, I don't
know if it's the same guy,
we're thinking about that. What do they
say is the best wrestler in the world?
Yeah.
He's an amazing I fucking two years guy.
Even not something that you're like, oh,
I'm not going to mess with him. Very,
he was sitting behind this with the team
at everybody who walked by had a say,
oh my God, this channel Sanderson
Old Cael Sanderson. Oh my God.
Like everybody was fucking
like in awe of this guy.
And that was when we threw the guy out.
And then the guy that was with him said
to me, Joey Karate, we got your back.
That's when it all went down
because the guy was yelling,
but everybody was looking at that guy,
like he was a fucking killer that day.
And I mean, from fixed to Guido, everybody
was there standing there, you know?
So yeah. He's the coach at
Penn state. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's Cael Sanderson. Yeah,
he's a beast. It's crazy. His, um,
his, the, the, the people that, uh,
he was wrestling with
like teaching in college. They're the
ones who encouraged them to compete again,
he's still physically got it.
He just stopped competing.
I just think like that high a level,
like when you're at that
high a level in any sport,
whether it's wrestling or anything, you
know, boxing, when you get to that level,
it's so hard to maintain
that kind of pace.
It's so hard to just live your life like
that where you're constantly coming.
Painting,
when I was a kid,
I see the high school wrestling or the
way you were fucking voices just creeping
me out with a cause that you or him,
when I was a kid,
I see the most of the best fights ever.
I seen a high school decorated wrestler
fight this kid that was a scrappy
fighter or Billy Lou dog, two minutes and
he got his hooks in this motherfucker.
It was in front of the VFW.
You know how they always have
an American flag with a pole?
There's a little fence.
He picked him up and threw them over the
fucking fence dog. Oh No, the strike,
I didn't know. He just landed on
his head. He just took to it like,
what am I going to do? I'm not going to
get back up or fight this fucking month.
So just pick up. And that's when I
was like, restless, got something.
They got that core strength they'd
been working on since they were young.
And some of these guys with
the bent knee isn't shit.
They ain't got no time to fuck around man.
They'll take you the fuck down.
But it has made a difference in him.
It may that I've seen,
I don't know much about it. I, I, you
know, I watched a little bit of pride,
but in the UFC you've seen these
wrestlers that makes a big impact.
Judo guys and the wrestler,
that's the, that's the, those are
the two toughest to deal with.
But the thing about a, you know,
and both of them, you know,
especially when it comes to
international competition,
they both have to deal with some pretty
fucking stiff and crazy competition,
you know. But judo internationally,
especially as you know, really popular,
it's a really popular sport. And a lot
of different countries, but wrestling,
there's something about
wrestlers man, that, that,
that what they have to go through,
their mind becomes capable of pulling
shit off that other where other people
wouldn't push hard enough.
They would, they would just,
they would back off before the
wrestler does. You know, these guys,
red line in man, they know how to read
line their brain, their body, you know,
some of the most savage fighters of
all time. Dan Henderson, Randy Coture,
you know, go through the lineup.
All the, the Matt Hughes,
think about all the different guys
that started off Koscheck the,
all the different guys
who started off Hendrick.
Yeah. Rashad. Rashad, yeah, absolutely.
The lest of John Fitch was a
captain at Purdue. The list is a,
and it takes a while for the hands
to catch up with everything else.
But some guys picking right up, uh,
Griffin. What's the name of fabulous?
Phil was the one who just fought Rashad
before. Phil Davis. So Davis, I'm sorry.
Yeah, fabulous. Whatever they call him.
Mr. Wonderful. What's the one before fall?
It's just,
you know,
a lot of evil that he always said that
you better get ready for these wrestlers
and learn how to fight off your back
cause he's rest is gonna fucking take you
down. You know. So there's so
many guys that become successful.
If you started with the Japanese
cultural center in Hollywood,
no one is close to Eddie's. It's a
couple blocks from the old uh, legends.
The one on the Vermont and one that
just moved the culture of some of the,
it's like where the Japanese
go to practice judo in town
and it's real dirt cheap. It's
hardwood floors. It's all old school.
Some people go sign up one time and get
the fuck out of that cause it's very
traditional and they didn't
really do two classes a week,
but it's going on down there.
All these other things like high kido
on labrea with the swords and shit.
The gun I'm talking about down on a and
they'd been there since 1940 something.
Is there something that Keough
school in Hollywood? No,
they moved to Burbank and
then they moved again.
I drive by on Magnolia and I
seen everything is in Burbank.
Any style that you want is in Burbank
martial arts. I went to see that.
He's uh, I went to Burbank last night.
I had to go outside, swung by Eddie's,
I counted six fucking karate
schools, kickboxing. Uh, the kicker.
Oh who's the other guy though?
That we are all fabulous.
Benny Benny the jet has in school,
I mean Burbank catnap the martial arts
hall of fame. Then the Jetson Burbank now,
but in the Jetson Burbank man,
they got a new kid kickboxer school.
They got to Gracie virus.
Yeah. When I used to Mexico,
when I first moved here, man,
I used to go to his place in Van Hise.
He would have all these gang bangers that
they would give a free classes too and
let them work out. And you know, you'd
be like taking kickboxing classes,
but this is funny gang bangers
man. It was, there was,
there was some parts of it that were
kind of creepy and a lot of people were
complaining about it cause
there was like a few problems.
But I remember this one dude came in and
he had a tattoo on his back that look
like you drew it, you know,
and it said, whatever the,
it was like vodka or something like that,
fuck the rest.
And he had it tattooed on his back. Wow.
I mean, it was like look like you did,
or like anybody gave you a tattoo gun
for the first time and said, well,
just see what you could do.
And I was, I was thinking like,
this is not a guy you
want to punch in the face.
This is not a guy who has a lot to
lose. Like, you know, this is, uh,
this is Mike. I might want to just
keep my hands up and sticking mood.
Might want to just get in your car
and get the fuck. Yeah. Well there's,
there was a, he had, there was, you know,
Benny the jet and then he, I think he had,
um, uh, family members that would
also teach there too. I forgot.
I forgot the whole history of it,
so I don't want to talk about it.
But they had a lot of, uh, there were
a lot, a lot of gang bangers car there.
It was a big culture
shock thing coming from a,
coming from New York and then moving
here and then taking kickboxing with
gangbangers. All right, fuck that.
Remember that?
Remember that bug we were talking about
earlier that is counting on this trees.
It's cut an emerald ash borer and
look at that. It looks like a,
a cricket at a disco. I mean
it's, it's scary looking.
Looks High Tech looks like a robot
cricket. Yeah, it's like a Nissan Gtr bug
and nothing does.
That's the thing that just goes into
trees and fucking lays a bunch of eggs and
trees that destroys that.
The trees and then those things
hatch and become more of these.
It's like a fucking army of tree
killers. That's so funny. Fucking
nutty man. Yeah. It's so weird.
So what do we have to do?
Bring over like Komodo
dragons eight these fucking,
doesn't that look like alien technology
that that's take alien technology.
Got nothing to do it.
No.
You know what's going to happen?
We going to fucking, dude, come on.
This has been going on for years.
We started with termites.
What do you expect from here of the fuck?
I'm just saying this started years
ago with termites. They eat trees,
they eat the roots.
I know to you,
but it is new when it have
been invasive species waiting,
when we know we're bring them
weeded through cup with Miami. Wait,
that was coming in and those fucking
bags, right? I think we're just waiting.
Life's and fucking bugs and Palmetto
bugs or snakes with this couple of those
fucking shipments,
you know,
big nine foot fucking Cobra got in
from some fucking Columbia jungle.
You think this and that.
And they got Dick's and they look
for ears and they always fucking,
creeks is 2013 going to have a
new fucking creature every week.
And I'm about to smoke my
little vapor so I'll get the
master motherfucking cushions.
I was smoking the shit on
the plane or it's tremendous.
You know what's so funny?
He was smoking on the plane
next to an old lady and I did.
We talked about this yesterday and
w and I'm like, wow, that's crazy.
I guess you know,
I guess you can do,
probably is not against the law to
do those things. You know, vapor.
If it was like an electronic
cigarette I guess. But then,
then he did it in a car when we're
driving to Pittsburgh and he just starts
hitting it and all the windows are up and
immediately smelled weed. And I'm like,
if you did that on the plane, everybody
smelled that. It does smell like
we'd still a suction thing.
Right?
If you blow it can have a vacuum.
So when you blow it over your
shoulder to the window to the left.
But I was smoking on two
different flights. Nobody smells.
None about pot smoke man.
That when you're
smoking, it doesn't smell like
anything. It's the weirdest thing. No,
it's just like cigarettes.
Will you? Yeah, I bet it is.
Just like you don't smell the
smell smoke on your own body.
Well that's a weird thing that they say
about smells that all factory senses,
they only detect changes.
So like you can get used to a stinky town.
That's how people live.
If they live like someplace,
it has like a mail or something
like that, but yeah, yeah,
that that could do it or I'm a think
slaughterhouses. That's a real problem.
How poop? Cow Pie. Yeah.
If you pass like pastures and cows are
shitting all over the place and just
stinks horribly fucked up. They shit so
much. It's just shit everywhere. Oh yeah.
Drive by to shit.
You're smelling and shit.
Yeah.
I go to my mom's house.
I have to go buy like a good half mile
where the whole like air is just shit
smell.
It smells like a thousand poops.
It's nature telling
you that this is dirty.
You don't want to eat
anything anywhere near this.
That's like a big warning sign.
That's why shit smells terrible.
Right? Oh fucking though. What do you
want her? I don't think you should.
Well,
that thing on a plane and I'm going to
make you promise that you're not going to
do that from now on.
And he got caught with it at an airport.
He
did a bank, took it out, looked at
it. They couldn't even figure it out.
Those fucking geniuses.
So the Capo,
when they gave it right back to me and
I was puffing all the way to the gate.
Number three,
like a doctor,
what did you say it was when they
electric cigarette. Oh, didn't even ask.
How's that one for you? Didn't
even ask. They didn't even ask.
They just looked at it.
They want to know if it was like some
sort of a gene Simmons bomb from one of
those movies such whenever
the thing, a little while. But
Rutger Hauer gimme the bonus. Fuck
the bonus. They pulled the thing.
I might think just the fat
seen the movie's horrible,
but that seeing this fucking listen man.
How many movies did Gene Simmons do?
I don't know why.
I know he played that and I showed them
on an episode of Miami Vice One time.
That's it. I never seen him, but he's
probably done a bunch of fucking movies.
He was on an episode of Miami Vice.
Yeah,
he played like a drug dealer was shot
Miami Vice changed the fucking game.
Dude started wearing blazers and no socks.
They started wearing
loafers with no socks. Why?
Because that's what they wore in Miami.
Vice one to be like, you're in Miami.
Do start buying white cars.
Fuck.
Bought a white car before 1980 there's
was white cars. Get out of here.
What your stupid fucking white car.
How many white Corvettes or do you see?
This is like 10 of them ever made white
seems white whites only for like Honda
at courts or something and they saw that
white Testarossa. They went, oh shit.
Did you see will white wheels too? You
see will Smith is slap that dude. Yeah,
that's crazy. And then he lied. He's like
tried to kiss me in the mouth. I'm like,
Hey, we can all see the video. He
didn't try to kiss you in the mouth.
Kisses face a few times. He might've
been trying to kiss them, you know,
in the mouth. It might've been like some
polling or I didn't think about that.
I don't like that either.
Bad slap them. You know, he,
he barely touched me and he just
went like this and the guy's face and
everybody's saying that it was
like some assault. Oh my God.
And out of here it's
like always at publicity.
He's up at events with somebody
at the longest shot thing,
so at least said something to fucking Burt
Reynolds and Burt rose bushes. Listen,
he's 66 years old. He was just trying
to get publicity for the fucking movie,
you know what I'm saying?
Probably not even,
I suppose as ego guy came over
and said something was just like,
did you see the original one got goes?
No. Burt Reynolds smack them. Really,
really? Whoa. That online is that,
oh you got to see Max
guy run smack the fight.
The Burt Reynolds is one of those guys
where I look at him and I kind of feel
bad, you know? And I see like his face
all stretched out. Like when I was a kid,
I looked at Burt,
run onto my tech guys.
This shit like I remember like smokey
and the bandit, he's always smiling.
That's what I would always think.
Like this guy looks like he's always
having a great time to have a good sub to
marry Loni Anderson that fucked him.
I shot him down and left the with
pills and he was willing, but dog,
you watch them even to the longest shot
at the beginning of the longest yard.
He goes in, he beats the bitch.
Bitch, the bitch. Watch the movie.
He gets in the car and what fucking
songs does he get out when it turns it on
Saturday night? Special Leopard
skin. Watch it. So fuck.
He's got a Valora jacket on with fucking
patches of the she. They look like a
fucking, he looks like the
guy that played superfly.
That's what he looks like in that
movie. Smack. So he's laying in bed.
She's giving him a hard time. He
smacks her. He takes her fucking car.
Saturday night special
drives, it cuts off. Cops,
takes it to the ocean
and dumps into the ocean.
Then goes to the bar and they come get
them at the bar and they start fucking
around.
He beats the one cop up.
Then they take them to Burt Reynolds was
the shit. Here's us. Here's the video.
Burt Reynolds apparently got
little slap happy last night.
QBS producer at a movie
premiere and Chelsea,
and we're the only ones with the video
was Michael Palmer on here now with the a
blow by blow, Michael Maurice Reynolds
attending the premiere of his new film,
really a remake of his old pill and the
longest yard when neither in jest or an
anger,
depending on who you believe.
Reynold slap the CVS employee who was
asking the star about that movie and today
she'd be as new says it is looking into
the matter. You judge for yourself.
I don't know anything about it.
I liked the guy.
The audio is hard produces nobody knows
a smack like the dude who got smacked of
2020 by the wrestler.
It's a punk with that little backhand
backhanded gave the dude that wrestler
when he fucking smacked, what's
his name? Tom? Something like
that boy got up, but he
fucking smack them with a hand.
That was a smack Wilson make giving
this guy a fucking loved that.
Oh Will Smith did was go touch the
guy with his fingers on his face.
Anybody who calls what
will Smith did a slap.
He gently did this to the guy's face.
It was like,
so it was so non aggressive.
Yeah.
This guy's a fucking huge dude.
That's terrific. That all you got.
I asked you the standard questions.
Standard questions. I think at this bank
you're going to get bike. There you go.
What the Hell is wrong with you?
That's the open hand slap.
You think it's thinking
after the fucking real guys,
that dude cough
to cough as a guy not getting paid
enough to do his job well, you know,
it's also the way he said it was very
arrogant, like he was going to be safe.
I think it's fake know it's not,
you know,
saying it's fake de fucking Duh.
Everyone knows it's,
you know,
it's, it's, it's obviously planned out in
advance, but to say it's not a tough job.
You're crazy. Those guys are always
busted up. Those guys are always,
they get hooked on pain stuff.
What they did the exam wrestling on
2020 and they showed us all the tricks,
how they would take the razor blade
and cut you off. Yeah. Yeah, yeah,
make it bleed.
Bleed.
That was a great expert as a lot of
people didn't know about that shit.
Imagine they did that.
They used to cut their own hair and I
knew about it because one of the training
schools in New Jersey,
so when I was going to graduate school
and the teachers kept telling me,
if you're good guys, we'll take it to the
wrestling. I know chief Jay Strongbow,
whatever.
It's all fake and shit.
When I found that wrestling
was faking the fourth grade,
I was pissed for about 10 minutes.
I went to El [inaudible] the other day
and they had the Mexican wrestling on
those due to have some fucking dope moves,
man about the outfits.
The outfits are outstanding
dudes with like long Conan here.
No one looks like they've
ever even heard of steroids.
It's so weird because steroids are
legal in Mexico and these dudes are like
regular looking dude,
but they had some crazy moves.
I was like really impressed,
like jumping through the air,
wrapping their legs around the dude's neck
and flipping the dude through the air.
Like they did some nutty shit that
was like, wow, that is acrobatic.
If you can't appreciate that, I mean
obviously it is theater, but there's,
there's a physicality to it that you,
you know,
it's very disrespectful to call it fake.
It's not fake.
That little attitude he
did that. Oh, Sassy. Yeah.
He said it to a guy without any fear
of his own safety being protected.
He thought by a camera and reality
and media wasn't shut down.
The media wasn't what it was today.
The media wasn't shit.
They were just somebody who
was taken up your fucking,
it just didn't have to be
cut to you about it. If he,
if he can communicate with
the guy and asked him,
are there predetermined
outcomes, how, you know, I mean,
that's what he should have said.
You know,
instead of saying like the way he did it.
Yeah.
Well I'll steal the standard question. Is
it fake? It looks fake to me. You know,
like, wow, you're, you're, you're,
you're, you're pawing of a lion. Like,
look at the size of that guy, that guy.
You don't feel uncomfortable with that.
This guy's all sweaty and hyped up from
a fucking wrestling match where they
always get kneed in the head and fucking
kicked in the head accidentally and
punched in the head.
I think you see some of the shit they
do where they do feel like flying
sidekicks and hit each other in the head.
They hit each other in the fucking head,
man.
There's a lot of times they're actually
hitting each other. It's not PR.
Even if it's choreographed,
it's not precise as a fucking really
hard way to make a living. What's funny,
when I went to Miami,
April that week was also Wrestlemania,
so all these old timers in Miami,
so every radio show I went to do
that week had an old time rescue.
I was talking about it and it
was very interesting to see that,
believe it or not, these guys still
have followings. Oh, I believe it.
They still have followings.
They do all those things that they show
you in the wrestler where they people
come and t shirts and talking about 1981
I wonder where the Jimmy superfly snuck
is ice.
Do you remember the fucking,
the, the war. He used to live
in boulder in his heyday did it.
He was up in boulder. Shoot fucking
it by that. A juice slim jams.
This mother fucker.
I remember one time seeing him at the
Potter carwash he had at that time,
nobody had a seven BMW in the early
eighties I don't even think they made them
and he had them just because he had a
fit one and I'll never forget it was off
season or something and he
got out of that fucking car,
Joe and he had a vein that was a court,
I don't have to lie to know,
but they go look at fucking the
ultimate warrior giant dude and dogs,
but his veins, his biceps with some
of the biggest, most that was a bicep,
but he had a vein out of here that lifted
three quarters of an inch from his arm.
I seen it. I looked at it,
stared at it and like was like,
let me see how far his
vein in his bicep went up.
Three quarters of an inch
off the skin brown. Yeah.
There's a lot of people don't realize
how big those that do some and see if you
get ultimate warrior shaft. For
me, I saw a hog in the first time,
like when I was in Hollywood,
like it was right outside of, um,
before I've met him.
I met him at a UFC and I had the honor
of interviewing them once I get to talk.
That was fun because I got to like talk,
like get excited about pro wrestling
with them, you know, and they pump it up.
He's fucking great. His gray, that
guy's got a lot of pain now it's got,
I mean he's gone through. You ever see
like all the operations? Holy Shit.
That's the ultimate warrior. That's the
whole fan. And how tall is that dude?
He's like six, three or some shit. I'll
talk. Don't focus on this deck Brian.
That's how I was looking at his own shirt.
He's busting through his own shirt.
But you know as far as crazy though,
why does he have a heart finger?
I think it's just Europe.
Is this Richard Simmons
looking at his face? Crazy.
Isn't it crazy that they decided to like
paint your face up and the outfit with
the suspenders? Whatever the fuck they,
I look at his arms. This guy was pretty,
Yo came in the barbarian bros. I remember
seeing when I was a kid, those two guys,
they were in the Flamingo Kid.
I don't know what happened to those guys.
Face paint like war paint a strange thing.
The idea that you know you're gonna,
you're gonna draw your face up
to make yourself look meaner.
When you go to battle,
like that's going to matter is like the
ritual of rubbing shit on your face and
put your wore mask on
before you go into battle.
Like where the fuck did that ever come
from it? Does it make someone extra scary?
Or if they got black
stuff all over their face,
but he's talking to the
bottom of the street, we,
you're talking like that for
them to be an American Indians.
And I'm talking about,
you know,
different people that have put war paint
on with over the years the American
Indians symbolize, remember Braveheart,
he put like fucking Cheetos or something.
But like if you're in the green baret
you gotta go take paint your face green.
That's yeah, but it's still,
it must put you there. Yeah.
The ritual that it's time to fucking rock.
It's time to get go crazy.
It's got to get you.
That's how you probably get fired
up by putting the makeup on.
And when they do you guys
remember this date announcement.
So what do you want to do? I don't
know. What do you want to do?
And
for those that I didn't watch this,
but rather listen to this podcast,
that might be one the most retarded thing.
It's a big giant Roy it up.
Dude handed out slim Jim. Is he
still alive? Is that guy still alive?
That's deck at the rob
lit like a motherfucker.
He's still alive before they
figured out the test. Wow.
I wonder what it looks like now
in Slim Jim.
What a strange ad. What is it
supposed to be snapping to a slim Jim.
And why are you so angry, sir? What's
going on here? You're fucking going nutty.
Screaming and flexing.
I'm going to do a slim kid bites into it.
He flies out of your shoes like what
the fuck kind of physics are we dealing
with here? What is it? What kind of
who? Who Green lit that commercial?
I think they ultimate warrior
has a blog now. Oh he does? Yeah.
Well how fun would it be just to
start shooting steroids and that stop.
Just get crazy and go hulk
style. They go, you know what?
I'm going to start fucking eating
them and I'm not even doing cycles.
Well I think if you look at
those guys who have done that,
like it is possible stay alive.
Like look at the guys who were like
big time professional bodybuilders.
They're still like, they're still
out there. They're, you know,
they get off the shit and they, their
body shrinks down to like normal size.
I want to know what Tom Platz,
his legs looked like tonight.
That's when you got to find, that's what
we got a fund. That's a good question.
I want to know what Tom Platz
looks like to that. I want to know.
We all look no look like, listen
bro. The first time you've seen,
what was the movie pumping iron was the
shit. You can say whatever the fuck.
I don't know.
The Franco Columbo,
a little fucking Italian with
that back from here to here,
laying brick and block all his life.
He was like, I'd get a big blog.
I the fuck out your face,
your whole family tree,
late fucking 12 inch block built
everything and fucking hit.
When you look at you, you're a
little flock. He was, he was yoked.
He was a strong dude. Isn't
it funny that you, you,
you said Tom Platz and we both know
that that guy was associated with having
giant legs. It's like he's sitting on
Hummus. I remember his incredible though.
There's no other guy that has like that.
Like there is synonymous with
just one body parts, legs.
His legs were giant. You know,
Campbell had big legs, but uh,
uh, Tom Platz had just ripped, I'm
sorry. There were giant to shred.
You find that picture.
They were so big legs just to show flats.
T Z. He was like 10 80. If you can't
cause that's what he was a king.
His upper body was big. I mean, he
was a shooting, nothing like his legs.
His legs were shooting in their legs.
Look at that.
Look at his jaw. Look on his
fucking jaw, his jaw, his shoes.
He's got muscle and it's, that guy would
crack a fucking Ari penis. Look at him.
Look at his leg.
Look at that.
This is 1982 looking at
his cheeks back up again.
Oh my God. Look at his, his, his
legs are the freakiest thing.
Now look how much they stand out from
the rest of his body. That's insane.
It's like somebody opened up his legs
and stuck a whole basketball in there.
He's got a basketball in each leg.
Look at the fucking size of those things.
They're crazy. That is the craziest
Shit I've ever seen in my life. Ever.
Ever seen 80 he has a waste
for each thigh. That's insane.
Look at the veins going to the fucking
leg. What the fuck are they shooting?
And he has no balls whatsoever. If
you look fucking legs, when you look,
when they get to like this size,
there's so juice to the gills.
Their balls or shot town.
They just tapped show.
Look at the size of him.
My God, he was enormous.
I got find it. It looks
like today. Christ. Hi God.
Look at the fucking sign.
Oh my God.
That's like from another animal.
It's like he took some meat off of
a horse and put it on to his body,
but he used to like try to
sell leg workouts. You're like,
no one wants to have legs like Tom.
That's number one.
Number two was not no fucking running up
hills. Got You. That shit. Not only that,
it's also a genetic issue. He must have
crazy genetics. That's what it looks like.
That one of those milestones. What
is balls live on here? Issue dogs.
See if we could find that picture.
I look at Robbie Robertson and
then the black guy. Oh my God,
this is fucking Robertson.
Oh my God. Jesus Christ.
God, look at this. There's a photo.
We're looking at a photo of his back,
Ladies and gentlemen,
and it doesn't even look possible.
It doesn't only possible.
It looks like if you were going
to do like a cartoon on what, uh,
you know a bodybuilder would look
like. You know, like if you were,
if you were drawing it for south park
or something, I can't even be real.
Isn't it crazy though that that's what
happens when you do shit like try to have
competitions where you see who has the
best body and the biggest muscles like
standards sorta change. And then
just like fake tits, like the,
the standard becomes the unnatural,
unachievable without drugs. Look.
But what's crazy about this,
Joe,
is I thought that weightlifting and
steroids and recovery and everything has
excelled so much in 30 years.
That had to be 1982 when
Tom Platz took that picture.
That's 30 fucking years ago.
Oh look at that picture.
He looks great. He's got
no, he's got no pants
on and he's flexing his legs.
That's cartoon land is cartoon.
So cartoonish. It's crazy. He looks
like a crazy, he has extra muscles
in his legs. It's, I mean, and
he became famous for it too,
so that became like the
thing he concentrated on.
If you keep hearing that sucking in
the background, that's Joey Diaz.
He's using some, some device. He's
Jewish. He went right into the microphone.
Eureka vapor like a motherfucker.
Joe Rogan.
That's uh, that's amazing that Tom Platz
guy. That's amazing. That's shocking.
It's amazing what a person can do. You
can, the way you could change your body,
just sticking some stuff in there and
do a fuck load of squads. Yeah, brother.
What are you doing? Joey did, is he
tweeting? That's been text messages.
I have my wife
Brian.
Do you think
we'd ever be uh, willing to, uh,
get on a bodybuilding program and
do roids for like a TV show now,
but I'm supposed to Saturday I go
to Richard Simmons and his class,
his class doing it just because I think
it will be funny. Oh, it'd be amazing.
Where are you going to do is climbing?
It's in Santa Monica. It's called. Yeah,
I do. I want to, I have
to do the UFC though.
Saturday is the UFC. It's like, it's
like sweating to the then how often?
How often is he there?
I think he does it like every week.
Richard Simmons,
do you fucking work out
with Richard Simmons and all
these really old ladies and
gay guys and we're gonna make it happen.
Let's work out with Richard Simmons
Saturday. I mean look, either way it's,
you'd be amazed.
It's a good workout if you tried to do
sweating to the oldies and he actually
kept that. It's like a nice
little workout, you know?
I think if I get really baked, it's going
to be the best thing I've ever to cost.
I think it's like 60 bucks. That's
worth it. I left the y today.
They would do and a, what's the country
line? Country? My mind aerobics,
bunch of fucking big rednecks and
they're fucking doing aerobics.
Well like country line dance and mixed
with aerobics. It's like fucking zoom.
So line dancing, line dancing
mixed with the Roche aerobics.
It's amazing what people do for
jump up and down. I tell you what I,
I'm really digging that Mike Dolce book,
Bro. I'm really, I love the, I never,
I always said to myself,
why do people go to the
widely on a fucking treadmill
where you can walk around
in north Hollywood park and get
some vitamin D and really sweat.
Then I read his book,
like I told you on the plant.
The diet stuff is hard for me cause
I don't like a lot of vegetables.
But the fucking workouts, you know,
the beginner treadmill workout,
it's sensational. I can't do
the full speed yet, but I'm
doing it. You know, it's,
I'm doing it.
He's coming on the podcast soon please.
He's saying it's going to be on the
weekends and you know what I'm saying?
He's fucking great. He really is.
That book has really helped me.
A lot of them understanding I can't
do a lot of shit cause of my knee,
but he's got great basic exercises and
I, you know, when I was really skinny,
that's how I got size,
doing little strength
things.
So I know where he's coming from.
I mean in this book he talks about how
he went up and a bunch of weight that he
lost it just to prove his
point, that strength. So I
understand what he's saying.
So I really enjoy the one book. I have
the one I'm going to get the other one.
I couldn't find that you ought to all
three of them at the tee shirt and it's
not a bad deal. I just couldn't
find that particular thing.
So I ordered it on Amazon
but I think he's actually doing
the podcast next week. Yeah.
Do at least he's, we'll have questions
for him. His Shit because uh,
his book is really helping
me a lot of things.
We had a lot of podcasts next
week, Dude. We got dolce,
we got Bassnectar I got
to get back with that too.
And we got bobcat Goldthwait
and we've got Shane Smith. Dude,
we're becoming on your television show.
Hopefully we don't run out of shit
tight that I'd tell you what man,
I went to Adam Carolla's place
yesterday and for first of all,
we need more employees
cause he has 10 right.
And second of all, I got mad podcast
studio envy, his fucking set up.
It's so sweet. Adam Corolla is
a savage. He built his own shit.
He built his own broadcast man,
man, he's a man's man. He's a,
he's a fucking construction
worker fella. He's out there. He,
he wired everything. So it all goes under
the floor and it comes out through the,
the legs of the table. The wires go
through the legs of the table like that.
So there's no wires exposed
and the whole thing is set up.
It's really fucking sweet.
It's really sweet.
It's got cameras like high def cameras
facing everybody and they're all
controlled and remote control. It's kind
of like a little broadcast booth. I mean,
it's amazing what he's done.
Like you over there and he'd
get mad podcast studio envy,
took it to the next level. He's making
it happen. We got to follow that.
Did you have a nice time though, Jim and
I show he was great. He's a great guy.
But you guys talking
about the girl else bros.
It's very funny to his little sidekick.
She's kidding. She's hilarious. Um,
what do we talk about? Everything.
You know, talking about punching.
Yeah. Talked about, uh, they like,
it was all these like, uh, you know,
like the hottest chicks in the world.
Like they had some thing where they like,
you know,
they were debating whether or not women
belong in the hot chicks for me and him,
a very different tastes. Like he was
talking about Olivia Munn, you know,
Olivia Maan it's hot as fuck, right?
That's about as hot as you can get. Okay.
But he was like, yeah, Gosh,
I have been to her house.
She's not really smelly feet.
He's out. They sound grounds. And
he was talking about, you know,
some girls will walk into a room and just,
you know,
everything's just stops and you
just want to talk to them. Right.
That Olivia one's not like that.
Like, all right, really that's crazy.
Talk live in my mom is all my top five.
And then she came out of nowhere.
You know,
like I liked her on with like
Kevin Prayer on that show,
whatever attack attacking the show.
But I never,
but then I fell in love with her and
then she left the fucking sho. Now Sho,
he added that shut off Mike.
Let me tell you something.
Break time. Fuck Cleveland.
I just want to say it before
I forget. In Pittsburgh. I really
did. Yeah, me too because I
fucking Columbus man. There was
some crazy motherfuckers there is.
He rocked Jason. Justin though. Got
It. Made us the fucking edibles.
I still got some fucking candy
left at the house. You know,
fucking Cleveland was crazy.
We were outside that garage shop
as a cool fucking spot, man.
That's a cool fucking spot. If you
don't want to perform at the Improv.
I got nothing against the Improv,
but that garage shop is a cool spot.
Cool part of town.
You know Pittsburgh,
it was an honor to go to
fucking Pittsburgh, but man,
has the economy destroyed
those little cities, man.
The bar we were at is only open when
there's a Pittsburgh pirate game or a
football game and it's across the street
from the stadium. It's called Mullins.
They were fucking great.
The Barbecue Sandwich was great and the
guy who was telling me that it's just
people don't go to that side of
town number like people, you know,
this is not a seven
night a weekend history.
No more people going out and in Pittsburgh
they go out to watch the games that
get fucked up and they
go there and you know,
I've been going to Pittsburgh for 30
years. It's amazing that you look,
go to these cities and you see these
people and you say to yourself,
what's next for these people?
I mean this is the real core.
It's so funny how I was losing,
I was hating doing comedy
in that way and it,
and it transpired for me to like I was
starting to hate to do comedy and it was
because I was doing too much comedy in
l h o l I wasn't doing comedy for real
people. I was forgetting
what I was doing comedy for.
When you're in La a long
time like I was and we are,
we don't travel like normal headliners.
They go out every week when I'm in La,
you thinking about shit that you think
in La and you think there's going to be
somebody in the audience or who's here
with you or what you're saying when
you're on the road and you're talking
to people in the Midwest or taxes that
fucking real,
you got to bring it a different way.
I can't bring it like la way I got and
that's what I like about going on the
road again.
I really enjoy it like people like,
do you really like going to the Midwest?
No, I went there. I fucking love it.
I love going to Iowa.
I love going all those spots
like that once or twice a year.
Just to remind you that it's
not all the big city man.
We met some cool fucking beat hazing.
We've seen some great properties,
great trees spread out,
low traffic.
We've got too much weed and
had too much weed, you know,
and it's hard to see these cities and
they got nothing and these are the people
that are really voting is showing.
We don't really know the country's issues.
We see a thousand fucking cars and
20 weeks stores and shit and all the
restaurants around here a fucking open.
You know when we went to
Pittsburgh dog on a Saturday night,
all of those businesses were Felice.
That's the truth.
Those are the people
that are really voting.
Those are the people that
are really paying attention
to what the fucking police
was.
Rough man.
We will leave maximum tour years ago
and I remember driving around the city
going while there's not a lot of hope and
this, it isn't. Not a lot going on here,
but the people are bad motherfucker fuck.
They just got so much that it's got a
lot of good people. Yeah, no, no, no.
Ohio's always man.
When I used to work for the sports
betting service day where the biggest
collection of gamblers really like,
and my Mac and my mind,
I'm like all of the sharpest guys in New
York and Vegas, they wiped their ass.
That whole, that whole Youngstown
with a hall of fame is all that shit.
That's big. Bookmaking Bay. You know,
you got to remember one thing, you guys,
the worst economy gets to more book Bacon.
Prostitution gets bigger and keep talking.
Drug sales go amazing.
You know?
That's why the mob and organized
crime will never go away.
They make more money when
the economy's bad. You know,
when we had a prohibition
and the Great Depression,
those monsters are making money,
selling booze.
People want to forget about their
fucking problems. It really is.
The worst economy is the more money
people have to take a gamble with it.
It's really weird to say there's more
gambling because people are desperate,
so people like, fuck it, I'm
gamble more. I will drink more.
The only fucking things that do not
get affected by the economy is crime.
Think about it. What? Gambling
is not gonna affect it.
Vegas is still booming every
week we hear how, oh my God,
we went to Vegas and there was nobody
there. They keep building on it.
Then they get money from somewhere.
Somebody is putting that Betson and it
ain't me and you, but somebody is losing.
Yeah. They're just banking on the fact
that it's going to bounce back that night.
Then they stopped a lot of the
building. Now. I stopped a lot of it.
I mean everything.
They just nutty for awhile.
They just opened a casino in Vegas when
we were there or I mean and Cleveland
while we were there that weekend and
that's like another way for them to try to
bounce back isn't how they,
Eva Longoria opened up like a spot.
A restaurant.
Didn't she open up like a
nightclub or some shit? Oh,
restaurant. It's still there.
Old Is it don't drive by them.
A basal.
Is that what is Hollywood boulevard?
No, no, no, no, no. This is in Vegas. Oh
yeah. She had like a club or something
like, listen bro, I never figured out.
Somebody come with you. Joe Rogan
and Glen, I'm an open up a club.
When you're a Vegas, come hang
out. We'll give you a kickback.
It's part of your club. You give
whatever percent they want. Right.
What's that called?
When you lend money and
there's no guarantee you
he'd give a certain amount of
the club. I mean, how much
do you make from that?
You got late teen fucking partners.
That's why I told you,
I told you specifically and I
know you don't like this shit,
but you really got to watch the pimp
of Joe Davis. It's been out again.
I'm fucking HBO.
The sports thing they did for an hour.
That motherfucker had it so bad,
New York that he finally said fuck it.
We got to buy a bar. Like they
had a buy a bar, like they go,
they got sick and tired of going
out after games and spent the money.
Watch this documentary. It is brilliant.
I watched the guy the other day,
I got a quote, John have a bar in New
York, bought a bar in midtown Manhattan.
His fucking slogan was I liked my woman
blonde and I like my fucking scotch
black.
That was his shit dog.
You gotta Watch this thing and he's
this little town and he just went to New
York, Bro. I mean he got married
at like 42 because he had like,
his knee was bad as shit because
slave dateline, he had to,
well he would have never got married.
Like this guy was a fucking dicks liner.
He was slinging so much dick
that he had to buy a bar,
like to keep all his bitches in line and
then that they took the bar from him.
You got to watch the whole thing.
We'll, we'll, we'll get called.
He had acid and cvs.
What? The bar special,
but it's on HBO. He speaks on HBS
but on HBO for a couple of months.
And what's it called?
It's just called David naming and you're
going to love it because you remember
it's not about football,
it's about what this motherfucker,
how crazy he was and how
he was just a good old boy.
But he owned New York Bro. He just
owned it. He just had it by the balls.
But then the fucking, they fucked
him. They said he had a close the bar.
They made them close to bar because it's
because they said he had too many weird
people hanging out in there
too. Any weird people?
It's a bar. It's a bar, right? Nobody
had too many fucking weird people.
So watch this special. He really don't
like people that live above bars.
One of nutty way to live that as people
that live in front of it above like food,
like fast food.
Like you know that grease smells going
to go right on Chinese restaurant
upstairs and there's something
dangerous about it though. You live on,
you live on top of the bar
when you're a fucking hockey.
That's the reason why you will live
in Jersey. You see on the New York,
UCL was bars at two dwellings over it.
Nobody decent lives over a bar.
They live over a bar because
they know that two minutes away,
no matter what happens,
I've only known a few people
that lived in midtown. You know,
like when I was struggling,
I only know a few people that were,
I got over their apartment and
get to see like how they lived.
But like living in cities like
New York, when you get like, like,
like studio apartments. That's
a weird life man. It's weird.
You enter into a door,
it opened the door and you got like
little space and it's like a tiny little
sink and there's like a little hot plate.
You know a lot of people, they're there,
they're living almost like in closets.
It's almost,
it's like a big closet,
a big closet already.
Steven's just got his first fridgerator
and it's not even a full size
refrigerator. It's one of those small
little frigerators and he's had one for,
he didn't have one for like almost a
year. Oh my god Bro. I'm advice that date.
This girl Julie Novak and she was a
Kansas girl that I met him in Colorado and
follow holding the restaurants. Why
did comedy yet and she was, you know,
you meet people like I'm moving
to New York, I'm gung Ho.
She went to New York with her body.
It was a childhood dream.
She had to go to new year.
Archie's can Kansas.
They went to New York and
they moved to 15th Street,
up the block from Manhattan on the 15th
like in Ninth Avenue that they were
paying 1800 a month.
This is 1994 it was just what you said,
you opened the door. It was a
combination. One Room, 1800 a month,
1,801 room TV with a
fireplace that didn't work.
It was one room and then you open the
door and there was a little kitchen and
the bathroom was there. So when I had
a fucker, the roommate was in the,
she had a roommate. Oh,
because they couldn't afford,
oh 1800 she had a roommate,
so she would have to sleep in the fucking
living room and I would have fucked
her in the kitchen on the
floor. Oh my God. And we
couldn't fit your feet. You Go,
oh my God. Horrible. Horrible.
1800 a month just to fulfill her
dream to live in fucking New York.
Are you fucking crazy? But that was
good training. Why is that dream?
So people love that shit. I just want
to go to New York and then they get,
then they get mugged. When you look
up to a beautiful day, look down,
your bags are gone. Your
fucking Mama. What is it about,
I guess there's something about being
able to tell people that you live in
Manhattan, New York or whatever. Listen,
I told her a thousand times,
you gonna live in New York City.
If you don't live in like John Lennon
and the Dakota, go fuck your mother.
You didn't say go fuck yourself.
Yeah,
I'm going to struggle and drive down
and cat gentleman and lived at the
motherfucking Dakota and he walked around
and good, he got for shot, whatever,
but he walked good. Don't know. What
I'm saying is, you know he got shot.
He didn't have a body guard
and he was just a regular guy.
He would walk through central park every
day and get freshly squeezed orange
juice and didn't give a fuck of it.
Cost $12 or not because he's John Lennon.
So a, the Dakota is like a
really nice place. It is.
Where else are you going to live?
Is that the nicest place that's topples?
Everything that's installed over anything?
Well I live at the plaza bitch.
I live with them motherfucking Dakota
and my name is Tom Petty. What is like,
what is that like? What
it is like? They're like,
what is like a real like go look it up.
The Cota or what's your
average property on the Dakota?
Cause I think you have to buy the condo
and they gotta be three, $4 million,
which is really a fucking apartment.
Which is right. I mean I can't,
I know he had two of them in there.
You know,
people will live with the Dakota
just like authors will get bank.
That's the type of people,
everything around it. The
code is expensive. You know,
if you live in the Dakotas cause you
fucking wow, I want a beautiful belt.
Oh it's beautiful dog. It's the shit.
That's the only way to fucking do it.
If you're going to do it,
it's incredible.
I'm going to live in Bronx or Brooklyn
or queens and drive in or take the a
train. Fuck you. I'm standing right there
under the code. Right. Central Park.
Isn't that weird? If you think
about it, what that building is,
it's like a safe for rich people, rich
people. It's like inside that safe,
you cracked that safe open.
There's a bunch of rich people in there.
I mean that's what it is.
And it's right there on the street where
all the poor people can drive by and
look at all the rich like inside there.
Well all they have to do is say, well,
you know what though,
you know society is functional and
there are police officers so it doesn't,
it's not feasible that we go in and
just take all the stuff out of there.
So we'll just leave it alone.
But they know where the stuff is.
The stuff is all in that
room, that big box, that's a,
that's a big mouse trap of rich
people. And so that is, it's a bank.
There's like little little pockets in
that bank and inside that you can get
money and there's jewelry and it's
expensive stuff all throughout that place
while you can't get in there now.
But if the shit hits the fan, yeah,
can get in there,
that'd be
easier. That's one of the first things
they're going to get into. You think so?
Fuck yeah. Fuck yeah. When the shit hits
the fan, why would you charge to Dakota?
You know the only thing that fuck you up,
his body guards.
You know how many dudes are rocking body
guards? Probably a lot in that place.
So there you got a bunch of armed killers
that are laying in wait things out of
the roof and all that shit.
But how long before they quit too and
get the fuck out of there after a couple
of weeks. This places abandoned.
What does it cost to live day Joe?
Just what's a property? The
color. Just shout real estate.
Just a mother. If it's even for a
sale. I wonder if he even, yeah,
they gotta be for sale.
What are you talking about?
Did you see that some guy in
New York is selling as part?
It could be code Elliot and month,
a million a year.
What did you see that in a million a
year for a parking spot? Parking spot.
People think about it. They're
like, well, it's there.
It's close by.
I don't have to pay for fucking tickets.
That's hilarious. Apartments for
sale at the Dakota, New York City,
Manhattan Condos, one of the most famous
residents, buildings and all of New York.
It's the Dakota. It was a bold
building when it was first developed,
built so far north of the
pulse of the city. At the time,
citizens snickered and nicknamed it,
the Dakota,
a reference to the states
of north and South Dakota,
which were very far away from
New York City. Isn't that funny?
They nicknamed it the Dakota because they
thought it was too far away. Meanwhile,
this crazy city has built up so much
now it's actually in the heart of
everything.
Isn't that weird?
It's weird that New York shitty must've
been like way smaller back then.
I guess obviously it has to have been.
Yeah, I mean it's a crazy place, man. I,
every time I go there,
I fantasize about living there for
like short periods of time to heal,
but you know, I never, I don't
think I can do it. I'd freak out.
I'd have panic attacks.
It's too much. Too much.
You can't have like realize that that is,
you're getting interaction.
You're g you're, you're definitely
getting something off of those people.
You know?
I don't know what it is,
but I know there's a difference between
the way I feel when I'm standing on a
mountain and I,
I look out and I see fields and I see
like clouds and I see birds flying
overhead.
There's a different feeling than when
I'm on the four oh five when I'm in the
four or five.
There's a hive of humanity and there's
some residual effect that you get from
all these people. This is a
different feeling that you
get when you're in a city.
You're all there. There's an awareness
of, of humans are elective stress. Yeah.
There's something, it's like some, it's
pheromonal, whatever the fuck it is. It's,
it's in the air, man. It's, it's not,
it's not as simple and as innocuous
as if you're not touching me,
you're not affecting me.
I think it's,
we're affected by our
environment some strange way.
So that's why I don't think I've got
to do in New York City when I was at my
mom's house this weekend. And she lives
in the middle of nowhere, like just farms,
like across the street from her is a
strawberry field and it's just in the
middle of nowhere.
And at night when I was sitting in my
car waiting to go inside her house,
I was just like,
it was so quiet and so like the stars and,
and it was just, it was like, this is,
I would not have any stress
if I got to come home to this.
It's crazy. Now you're, you're, you're
door. You hear cars driving
by your street. You know,
you might hear your neighbor wizards,
wizards are in the neighborhood.
You realize,
uh,
you know how much unnecessary
shit you have to deal with.
How much unnecessary stuff is
inside your head. You know what,
what it's all about.
You know, it's all about
life is supposed to be about enjoyment,
right? So to be about having a good time,
it's not supposed to be about dealing
with all this extra curriculum nonsense.
And we shouldn't have to have so many
fucking people around us like we shouldn't
be living here. This is silly. Like
why? Why would this 20 million people?
What you find? It's really weird
when you talk to somebody like,
uh,
somebody who lives in New York and I'm so,
I'm trying to figure out a comic who
lives in New York that they just fucking
love it. They clip the badge and living
somewhere else. Some people fit into that.
A lot of people love it. You know? For
me, I don't mind. I fucking lives there.
He loves it. Who? Who's that Gaffigan?
He's got kids too and knew it was there.
You know, some people, they
find a good place there.
You know what I saw fucking crazy picture
of Anderson Cooper Anderson Cooper
lives in a firehouse.
Does it really? Yeah,
because it's busters converted firehouse.
I did. Yeah. Awesome. Is that, yeah,
it was a stupid fucking thread on my
board where people were talking about
Anderson Cooper being gay or who gives
a fuck. I mean, he's gay. Who Cares?
I see you want to fuck.
I'm always trying to fuck you.
You, can you, can you imagine
bringing a girl home and like,
like I'll be right down and like coming
down like on the, uh, Firepool where,
you know,
with a bottle of champagne,
I guess you can,
you can see the actual place
that'd be the ultimate podcast studio.
Fucking making it out of a fire station
or something in the summer along those
lines.
Yeah.
You know, what would be the, the ultimate
would be that, uh, that missile silo,
that drug dealer had vice documentary,
I remember that.
He buys a four point $3
million in New York home.
Anderson Cooper Barney firehouse,
the 8,240 square foot home.
Wow.
That's a huge place in Manhattan at 84
west third street between Sullivan and
Thompson's,
which he purchased in September.
Both the original spiral
staircase brass fireplace.
So beautiful. It's pretty dope
fire stations. Pretty sweet. Well,
the crazy thing is, oh yeah, you,
you say what's crazy is it still says
fire patrol on it and it's his house now.
Yeah. I mean that's kind
of dangerous, isn't it?
Like people coming up to the place and be
like, help me, I need to drop off this.
I wonder how many babies he
gets dropped off. Oh God.
What if Anderson Cooper comes
out of his house every morning?
There's like two babies and he's like,
damn it again.
Four point $3 million.
This is why it's amazing it because
somebody is getting fucked by the fuck.
Pay 4.3 for fucking fire truck house.
See if they left the fucking fire engine
dance that's a pussy magnet or this
whole mango or whatever it is that
you're an asshole magnet. It's,
I think it's Kim been converted. I mean,
I think inside it's pretty dope. Um,
it's um, it's more than 8,000 square
feet and that's a big fucking house.
Some New York City. Fuck yeah. In
New York City, that's an enormous,
but there's all these cool photos
of it. It's pretty dope, man.
You gotta be creative.
This is creative as it gets an
old fucking Fiat guaranteed.
I love to know if they left the poles
inside so he could fly down the fucking
pole. I know. I would.
That's part of the deal and I'd have
the Batman thing to shoot right back up.
You got it.
You got to fly down there.
You got to fly down the pole of the ball
and when people just got a garage man.
How about having a garage in New
York City? Who the fuck has a mirage?
He bought a house with a garage and I
see I would live in New York City if I
could live like that.
There was only one way to live in New
York guys and that's what a lot of fucking
gators because it cost a lot of
fucking genius to live in New York.
If you're super rich,
you could pull off live gives a fuck.
I take a cab everywhere,
freshly squeezed and Bagels are 20 bucks.
Who gives a full,
a lot of guys just have drivers,
so super rich dudes that
have like a pen houses there.
They just have like a driver. You know
what does it place? That's his house.
Whose house?
Oh my God.
That's I think the people
that lived before or when it
was on sale. I'm guessing.
Oh my God,
that is fucking killer man.
What a killer house. Yeah, you
could put jacuzzis you can.
I've been to, I've been the one
incredible house in uh, in New York.
It was a friend of mine's dad had a,
a penthouse place.
I don't remember what homeboy did, but he
was very wealthy and we went to the, uh,
the top of this building and that's where
the apartment was in the fucking view
was insane.
It was insane.
He was just in the middle of
all these giant buildings.
They were all lit up and he had
this enormous glass opening.
Like his, his, his window.
He was on a corner,
he had a corner Penn House and
it was just, it was staggering.
Like you would look out there and you
just go, wow. Like you kind of get it.
It's like they get to live like
in a science fiction movie,
like every day they look out their window
and they're on the 90th floor or some
fucking building or whatever
the hell it is. You know,
I don't know what he even went to.
Highest building is there now,
but I mean if you,
if you're on the 50th 60th floor and
you're looking out and seeing all of
Manhattan and you're like in the
heat of it and it's kind of crazy.
Science Fiction Mad.
There's,
if you were like really into that like
man I could see but I think the baddest
house I have seen was a Maroon Creek,
maroon bells and Aspen,
Colorado.
We were building a house I was working
on for the electrician and the guy next
door we became friendly with him and
he was showing us, this guy was like,
can we produce it?
Don't ask me who the fuck it was.
It built the house from scratch.
But yeah,
I could tell that he was kind of off the
chain, like not a junkie and nothing.
He had manmade hot springs in his yard.
Like you would walk away under this under
the moonlight and he had them like 40
yards from his house.
He got like four different ones.
It was just amazing the view.
He had a Colorado looking down from one
of the top clips up in Maroon bells.
I mean it was fucking,
it would take your breath away.
It would really go like you would fucking,
That's really weird to see that
user where the user work a lot.
To me a huge, you know, some
people don't, don't, don't care.
I'd rather just be in a nice
neighborhood or whatever I need.
I like looking out the window and seeing
shit when I look out the window and see
shit. It's inspiring. I that was like
one of the best parts of Colorado.
One of the best parts of being a look
out the window and just see the mountains
and the trees and the, you know, if you
could look over the ocean and you see the,
Oh that's like the best view where
you got a little bit of mountain,
a little bit of ocean,
you can just stand there.
It's like you're looking at the greatest
natural art ever created like me and
one of nature's most beautiful and
wondrous accomplishments is the beauty of
nature itself. Looking at mountains,
looking at the water, looking at,
especially at from afar,
looking at all of it together.
Like when you're flying into Hawaii and
you can't even believe how beautiful it
is. Like look at this
fucking place, look at it.
He'd like it charges you up just
with its own natural beauty.
But even Malibu has natural fo
Uli, Malibu, staggering beauty.
You know? Uh, Columbus. I
seen some shit. The trees,
the way they were cut. You ever look
at Columbus or a Malibu real estate?
Have you ever looked? No.
Jesus Christ. You just know.
You go online and like look Google like
Malibu real estate and see some of the
houses for like $60 million short.
But then they have,
where is all this money coming from?
Who are all these people?
How many rich people are there?
Like Jesus Christ.
Here's some people buying
up $60 million houses.
I know we talked about this a
long time ago on that podcast,
but I don't know if we
had video back then,
but like remember Mike Tyson's abandoned
mansion Suttington Ohio and like people
in Ohio would just break into
it because he abandoned it.
And so in there it was like,
it was still furnished and it was like
he just left it and it was really creepy.
Like, cause the water, the inside pool
had not been treated for a long time and,
and like look at this bathroom,
this is like a crazy shower. Wow.
And uh,
they had cages for those ages where the
animals in the back and then they had it
like his own basketball court,
teen Tyson and then number that was like
don king got them into all that team
Tyson Shit. And look how nice it is
outside in Ohio. Can you imagine that?
That would all be your,
it's pretty,
he just walked away from that.
Yeah, he just walked away from, Oh,
I'm sure he walked away.
Five of them like that.
I heard his house in Jersey was
fucking awesome. It probably, I dunno,
but like the website that that's from,
it's called Elicit Ohio is
one of my favorite websites.
It's just abandoned ship
in, in Ohio. Like look,
this old music school where it's just a
bunch of keyboards lined up and there's
no kind of a Ben Shit in Ohio. Oh yeah.
This is just a guy that fascinated,
you know,
he,
he's fascinated with it and he talks
about like the old penitentiary. Uh,
here's the old amusement parks and
stuff and air force air force town.
It's called Elicit Ohio.
I said Ohio. I L L. I C.
I t, ohio.com. Here's an air
force town, which is a frog.
And uh,
well what does that have broken
rollercoaster it. What are we doing?
We're just watching things.
The conversation is actually a it to us,
like scrolling through it together,
but Mike Tyson,
his old house.
I wonder if you would be creeped out
if you bought it and you knew that like
Mike Tyson and just gorilla fuck
chicks in every room. The house. No,
it probably has a lot of positive
energy in it. You think so? Oh yeah.
Except for the Brad Pitt Energy.
Oh yeah, that's Taurus. Hilarious.
That's Joey Diaz is crumbling in the
background. Ladies and gentlemen,
what does that set up?
Pop Popcorn Mike Tyson have walked
away from I probably a bunch.
Right for seven.
I mean how much did he make?
He must've made like half a billion
dollars or something crazy. Right?
Cause they said, everybody says that Guy
Rob Don King. Yeah. Who knows? Who knows?
Who knows where it all went.
It's isn't it crazy though when you see
that story like repeated over and over
again throughout history.
I know guys,
when I got shit load of money and then
it all goes away and then they got none.
I mean it happens so often.
Well,
didn't end the way he was living so crazy.
He was given away.
Bentley's remember that he got an accident
with his Bentley and it gave it to
the cops and the cops got in trouble.
Like you can't like just accept a Bentley
from Mike Tyson while you're on the
job. He had no idea what they just
told to. He had 80 billion and go,
why can't he fucking just accept the
battling that's fucked up for the cops?
Cause the cop could have sold that Bentley
and not worked for like five years,
like quit. And I just got to live
off this battling money bitch.
And they sell that Bentley for quarter
million bucks that there was a lot of
money. Aren't they? Especially the
convertibles. She was so crazy.
You just crashed them
and giving them away.
He's going to do a one man
show now in Vegas. Yeah, I
heard he's already doing it.
I heard it's amazing. I he's already
doing it. I heard it's amazing.
It's amazing bro.
That guy has good tell a story like
I don't even get them into boxing and
fungus. What a great idea. He's a savage.
That guy's a fucking sad. But Joey is,
we need to get you a one man show and
he could just, you could just, uh,
would you be willing to do that?
I could do everything.
You just want to do a one man show night
in Vegas. I got plans already though.
Don't worry about it.
But he's the type of motherfucker that
you could just let him go for hours just
about the trainer yet.
And then he has six chapters
that you could go 12 hours on.
What's the original guy that adopted that
model? Then he went with Teddy Alice,
and then his days with
don king that his days with that
fucking skank from saved by the bell.
Then his two years in fucking prison.
Then when he came out to the
guys that killed brothers,
what's with the bow ties
and shit? Remember they were
guarding him for a while.
Then two years ago he smacking
somebody in a fucking movie.
You understanding the different extremes,
not the match. He lost a little girl,
not to mention these fucking Mike Tyson
and people look at him sometimes and you
may judge them, but that
guys, Jimmy is fucking deep,
deep, deep. And when you watch that,
we both watched that Tyson
biography together. Then we,
and he said some shit in the beginning
of that made you fucking think about my,
I remember watching a hotel room somewhere
and you said two or three things that
you're like, you know what the fuck you
look at that guy. He's as intelligent,
as deep as can be. He'll figure you the
fuck out. He was beaten fucking people up.
I just watched him against Irish Pat
Murphy or something, but he's a killer.
He was a good guy, was a killer
when he was at his best. I mean we,
we talk about him all the time because
when anyone is at his best, it was like a,
it was a force of nature
who said he just had an,
whenever someone who can can summon up
intensity than other people just can't
match.
It's always fascinating to watch a guy
who just raises it to the next level and
that's clearly what he did. He came
along and just took it to another place.
Like everybody was like,
Whoa,
we never seen intensity like these eight
chapters right in front of our eyes.
How many boxes do you know that went to
prison in the middle of their career or
football players and now
they're making movies.
Is this got him going to prison under
like some pretty shady circumstances?
He went in there for fucking rape.
Yeah.
I'd go with a girl who had it all ready
and had falsely accused someone of rape.
She was only like 19 years old and she
had already before him falsely accuse
somebody and they still didn't
get them off and their, their,
their defense was so crazy. It was
like, what do you expect him to do?
Look at who he is.
She should have known.
She should have known that if
she's going to be alone with him,
he was going to fuck her. Like
that was the defense, which is,
you can't say that that guy,
that guy is getting thrown
away more money thrown away.
He scrolled away more money than a small
country has that back account. Oh yeah.
He's showed us through more money than
10 people live through in a fucking
lifetime.
You know how interesting that guy
would be to get them stoned by mistake.
Like just to give him a hit a fucking so,
oh Gee Kush and let that motherfucker go.
Just let him go.
Just tell him just about three of his
boxing fights and what led up to it. Yeah.
What happened in Japan against
Buster Douglas, you know, so I,
I wish him all the luck in the world
cause that's a true motherfucker right
there. We watch that guy
come, go, come, go again.
His daughter had died two years ago.
Not many people can bounce that
back from that Bro. You know?
And he's really trying, you know,
I used to see him at the YMC,
but for all the fucked up shit I used to
see him try because they had them in a
rehab up there.
He was always pulling over the ass and
teaching a kid how to throw a punch.
Right. You know what I'm saying, Dawg?
And that's what it's all about it.
He would always stop and walk past the
boxing thing and if he sees somebody,
he'd go and he'd go like, let me
help you. He would hold the bag fee.
Well fucking champion all the bag
for you one time. He can still
talk to, he doesn't have problems
forming sentences or anything.
He doesn't have like,
you know, speech issues.
So if you're got to do a one man show,
that's the last thing you need. You know,
that's a satisfying about boxers,
man. As you'll watch a great one.
And then you watch him in an interview
later in his career and you hear him
slurring his words and
you're like, man, he paid,
he paid a big price for that life,
that wildlife or has paid a big price.
You know? And now we're sitting here
watching it. But some people, man,
that must be maddening to know that,
you know,
your career has forced you to in your
later years not being able to communicate.
Right.
But do they know it? They know
that they can't communicate, right?
Well they just want what's in their mind?
What's their head? Well, I think this
drums and there is a spectrum rather.
I think there's a broad range of, of,
of brain damage. But I think a lot of
them don't know what the fuck is going on.
Like that was the thing about the HPO a
football special and they were talking
about concussions.
Uh,
they showed a lot of these guys later
in their life and they didn't know what
was going on. These poor guys were
like delirious. They just literally,
their wives just guide them
all around their wives.
It was like they had an a child, you know,
they had a child had to take care of,
you know, so there's, there's
a broad range of trauma
related to that, bro, with football. I
don't blame it all on the fucking, uh,
the head shrub.
I blame it on your body getting hit
by a truck for fucking 10 years.
You're getting hit by a
truck seven months of a year.
That's reality. You know, how
much abuse can your spine take?
How much abuse can you Oregon's
take? It depends. Fucking shops.
You have the shot that I would give
you if you're standing like this,
getting the ball.
You know when a guy waiting and he gets
it and I come from the all the writing,
I give you the kidney. So I don't
blame it all on the fucking head shots.
It's gotta be a motherfucker to put
your head down and hit somebody.
Even when it does it your spine,
something's gotta be Bro. That controls,
you know all the electrodes that
controls all this shit in your fucking,
your body. A little spine. You
know, I've told you many times,
the last two years before I stopped
doing blow at the end of the night and my
fucking spine,
but the top of my fucking neck with her,
it would give me little voltage like,
so I knew it was starting to fuck shit
up and you can't talk. I can't imagine.
But I want to know if they know what
they're going through that I want to know.
If you sit them down and go,
how do you feel?
And if they would say to you at times,
I want to express myself and I can't.
Yeah, I'm sure they can't. I'm sure
that's exactly what they were telling you.
That's gotta be a terrible fucking
feeling man. Like he's gonna be terrible.
I see something like Vinny Corto
who I know he's been punched in the
head lady fucking times. You know,
I could talk to Vinny for hours.
I talked to him last week for like 45
minutes and he'll go from sentence to
sentence and it's amazing how he remembers
certain things and I'm very impressed
by it. But at the same time when
I hang up the phone with them,
I'm sure there's another thousand
things that he's forgotten, right?
For the 20 that he's remembered,
he's really forgotten a thousand so I
might think he's sharp and that that's all
he remembers is a handful of
that stuff yet compromised.
You know there's a certain amount of
compromise you just, you're going to get,
if you were involved in kickboxing
or contact sports or football,
any anytime where you're getting head
collisions over and over again you're
going to get,
you got to pay a price.
It's like how much is the
price you're gonna pay?
Is it just going to be like
a weird little achy thing?
Like you know like you might get like a
hurt wrist is going to be like that and
your brain's like,
I that's kind of annoying.
But not that big a deal
is going to be that.
Or is it going to be something really
serious when your mouth doesn't work right
or you can't formulate certain words where
you struggle to try to put together a
sentence and you forget what you were
talking about right in the middle of the
sentence and you're not even,
hi, nice. It's really weird how
I know from two ways I know from riding
a motorcycle who and falling off of
banging my head a few times.
I know from getting hit in the head a
few times and I also know like how you
feel the next day you get hit in the
fucking head, whatever used to it,
then you feel terrible is what you,
you feel.
You do feel a darkness and just call. It
feels dark. It feels like there's no sun.
That side.
You know when you get clocked in the
head for a couple of days and you see
things, that's a good way of
putting it. It's fucking crazy.
I know when I got clocked in the head,
it scared the shit out on me. You know?
I survived. I lived to
tell the story. But you,
you know that it's not right for you.
You said you'd know all that.
What I'm doing is that fucking healthy
because this isn't normal for me to feel
this way. You know? It's not what the
concussions, it's not only the, the, the,
the words and your memory,
it's also your mood.
It controls your fucking moods.
I could control whether or not you ice
yourself or you fucking don't know how
you live. You know? That's all the shit.
That's enough. Every brain, you know,
I don't know what they are,
but you know, different,
like somebody was saying that the front
of the brain controls your wrangler and
that the Buddhist belief for years,
if you meditate through meditation,
you could get through that part.
I'm just giving an example,
but I think that affects
a fucking lot of things.
Your mood and your depression or
your and to the fucking has to men.
And that's why when they talk about
football plate, they bro, when, when uh,
who kicks hard, the UFC cro, cop waving,
when cro cop kicks you
in the fucking liver,
you're not going to feel that for a
couple of weeks. And should I have,
I got to do something to your insides
because you kicking me over here.
It's got a borrow from something.
You don't have those fucking kicks.
Got To do something. That is a thing that
people don't think about. I was like,
the damage to your organs,
Jesus Christ fuck packs from whether
football or kickboxing or whatever.
Now you've got to think about
that because you can't see it.
So you just assume
everything's okay in there,
but you know like someone's Shin slamming
in the rib cage and fucking rattling
all your shit full blast
into your rib cage. Really?
Jesus Christ. You know how much,
how many of those can you take?
What's going on inside there?
You know,
they was showing up is everything on the
other fell. When we were in Pittsburgh,
I was watching and I have to do TV was
I'm trying to write whatever and that was
showing a Earl Campbell and that would
show the best 10 power backs of Walnut.
And they showed Earl Campbell playing
against some team and he had a plague of
something Solomon and they said,
look at the shot,
but it gives him what had by mistake,
he hit him with a,
the in the solar plexus pick about
it right here by mistake like he was,
he went to tackle them and I
tripped over play his foot.
So the momentum and him coming
around the D was right. That band,
oh my God. But you just seen it. It
was like hidden Carbonell Campbell.
And you'll come and as,
as he's coming around band,
it was just, it was perfect.
The fucking written this
year and this motherfucker,
you just seeing his arms go like this bro.
Like everything.
Space Cake. Don't give him
more. When are you doing?
He can't take all this. No one
can take all this. Just know.
He just seen a whole bag of popcorn la.
Incredible.
Because it's what amateurs shift that
your shit when you call me crying now,
an hour from now, Joe Rogan, you should
see I want to talk to you Dana dear on.
We did this podcast every day and she ate
a whole bag of that popcorn and by the
end of it she was so
calm she couldn't even,
I had to call her cause I
was so worried about her.
Like we stayed here for a bit
until she came down. But wow. Yeah.
You've got to get someone some
coffee or something, right? Yeah,
he'd do what he do. You just got to
ride it out. Yeah. There's nothing else.
Let's go ride it out. It's like a
Piss test for you. Fucking amateurs.
Don't be playing with those edibles.
Dangerous. That of bolts are danger,
my friend that is not regular weed folks.
That's not regular week.
You gotta you gotta understand that it
was going to affect you a lot differently
when you eat it. I was just
hungry. That's the only reason
I'm going to be talking to two fucking
space to that 40 minutes. Fuck that.
Fuck that dog.
I haven't even a level a couple of days
is Columbus and he just ate a whole bag
of popcorn and one of those you're
going to be crying and one hour, dude,
remember those cookies?
I gave us a in Columbus,
Ohio and you ate them right
before you went on stage.
Did you start feeling it while you're on?
I think I remember you saying something
about it. I felt a little bit on.
So you know whenever you eat another
boy and you go on stage, you go to yoga,
you go to Jujitsu or whatever
the edible sits in you.
But once that adrenaline
mixes with the edible,
you've got a different type
of fucking savage in that.
How about our friend that gave us those
cookies in Chicago and you had a mild
heart attack from
what happened was,
this was a couple of years ago,
we did the one Chicago Club.
Well, that's very a white.
My 40th birthday he came
up to and it was crazy.
This guy gave me these fucking
cookies that were a rapper.
He brought them and I ate two of them.
They're life changing cookies. Oh my God.
The next day, the next day
I had like an off beat my
fucking heart. Like my, uh, my,
I had like a heart murmur,
you know,
three days later I went to the doctor and
they're like, yeah, you had something.
What the Fuck Julie? Oh my God, you
gotta file artist. I'm telling you, dude,
they were not regular cookies.
I don't know them later.
I don't know what to after he put
those weren't regular cookies.
There's a point, there's a point
where I could tell what they were.
These cookies I was eating for a while.
I'm not going to say from what place.
I'm not a year later that
the dude was putting volumes,
these cookies with doing something to me
that these cookies with doing something
to me that nothing else was doing.
I been around the block
so I could feel it.
I know the difference
between eating like a cookie.
And so he knew that he was
going to get people hooked.
He was saying these are the
strongest fucking things guarantee.
And then when they got a call one
day, that whole, I got a call with me,
went to the fucking hospital. What in
the ass hole? The guy was like, Bro,
you don't have THC.
I know you can't be this asleep.
Like this whole wow, that's, yeah.
Well that's the thing about
having marijuana all shady
and semi illegal the way
it is. You know, there's a lot
of fucking disreputable folks.
You're going to get involved in
this just to make money. You know?
Think about like pots. Good
man. Yeah. Pot's good. But he,
when people are selling it,
you're gonna get people that
are just trying to make money.
They're not like pot advocates per se.
Some of them are just in
the business to make money.
Business people stick
around for that long, right,
because you've got to put too much
wheat to kill the radio to, well,
the whole thing is it's gotta
be a one shot operation,
so it's gotta be a store
that buys three pounds.
They trim it and whatever they have
leftover, they make the edibles with.
If you go with to buy wheat to make
other bulls, you're going to lose money.
It's not going to work for you.
Make it from the trimmings are the fucking
seeds and all the fucking stems and
that's how you do it.
That's how you do it.
That's to do it to be profitable because
it's once doesn't have the same impact.
What do you mean? Yeah, yeah,
it's all the same strength.
It's all the same strengths.
The stems have the same amount of Tsh,
but all the leaves and all that Shit.
You put it with the butter and you still
get the butter with the same high THC
ratio really sustain from the leaves.
They trim it with the leaves.
That's all made from leaves dog, you
know when they tell you, oh yeah,
it's way through.
They'd take a beautiful bugs grow
and then they take the leaves.
They trim it when you buy. Okay. Let
me give you an example. That grind,
you have that grind that
you have has two pieces.
It has a piece for the weed and other
little weed. It has a piece for Kush.
What does it call it Kiki? Kiki. Okay.
See how much Keith you got in there.
There's a lot. Is there a lot. Okay.
This is what you do when
you go to a weed store.
Now before they give you that weed, they
beat the kief off the week. They do.
That's how they sell kief you bring,
we'd evolved from a weed store
now there's no keef on it. Yeah.
That you could get 25 grand for
that shit dirty at grand. Yeah.
The place next door.
It's one of those schools that teaches
you how to grow weed and like you can
have like like up to seven plants or
something like that and they and that you
use there. There are lighting
and just go, you know,
a couple of days a week or whatever to
check on your plants. It's like kind of,
it's kind of cool,
but they just bought a,
an extraction machine and so now they
can extract the wheat into like the weed
juice where you can just
this guy show up. This guy.
I love it. Yeah. I love y'all
Brandon.
Next door he showed me he has a syringe
and it's just a syringe of like liquid
and you just so I can just drop it.
No,
I not fucking boring an intravenous.
How long before someone takes
that intervene? No, no, no.
It's a syringe just to drop like a
little drop on a, on, on your nugs. Oh,
I understand what you're saying,
but I think how long before someone
takes that and shoves it into a vein? Oh,
totally. Them. One year. You will,
the spoken reef will be obsolete one year.
Would you be
smoking reefer smoking?
It's like 2012 Joey Refa will be obsolete
between these things because this is
the first one that's prediction.
This is the fucking first one.
The next one's going to be. Right. Okay.
The next one's going to be in your
fucking iPad. You know what I'm saying?
You just have to look through general,
but we just have to assume it. Gentleman,
if they're extracting
fucking weed juice from weed,
how long was it going to beat? So some
motherfucker opens up a store and says,
Joe Rogan,
I'm going to put the shit you drink in
the morning or the blue mix and I don't
take, we'd use with that,
which is all natural.
They're going to find out that we juice
mixed with the shook up without you the
shit where you drink in the morning, the
shot, it's going to be like that. Well,
you know that they say that when
you juice weed or when you eat it,
you eat it like raw. It doesn't get you
high, but it's really good for your body.
Yes, super. Really super helped
start getting ready in a year.
This is going to be obsolete.
She asks people still in to smoke pot,
but you're not going to have to,
you can just go to meet Joey.
Did you bring the dripper?
It's going to be like a dean.
It's going to be an advisor team
thing and you could control it.
Look what's going on with soda.
Now you can make [inaudible] at
home that's just gone. This shit.
Yeah, very good. You know like
when you go to a grocery store
store and it has like the off brand that's
like 89 cents and it tastes like coke
but like flat or, or are just
not as good. That's what it is.
And it makes no sense.
Like his Po is soda and Popcorn really
that expensive where we have to make it
at home.
I think the idea is you're supposed to
be conserving somehow because you know
you're recycling it using your own
glasses and it tastes like shit though.
What's the,
what's the other thing they have the
thing that you put in club soda or water?
Uh,
I don't know.
You remember you come buy it.
It's like why them was something
you put your bottle. Yeah. Yeah,
at the gyms. Now anybody, I tell you
what I know about you motherfuckers.
Joe Rogan, I know you remember this.
Remember when we were kids, how south.
So he used to come if it came like
this sounds like a tank where you were
professional, alcoholic, that's
what you had at your house.
Remember New York Seltzer whenever
it happened to that. Ah, yeah.
Yes and no, but it's got to
be at like Jewish Delis only.
Like they don't have it,
but a lot of, but it's so weird.
I remember when I was a kid,
I go to [inaudible] house and we get
great koolaid and put self surrender from
that gun. It was the best thing
I ever tasted in my fucking life.
Do you play with bubbles in that
motherfucker? Tremendous. What's up?
You guys know that this is one of the,
one of the craziest fucking stories ever.
I think we've talked about this
on the podcast. I'm not sure.
But that the cocaine, you know cocaine
used to be in Coca Cola. Yeah. Yeah.
And but the people in New Jersey take
it out now. Yeah, we talked about,
did we talk about it on the show?
Yeah. That's how nice he is at that.
There's like billions of dollars in
cocaine being made by a company that its
tracks it from the the leaves.
They used to make coca cola or cocaine
or ruts and never, like I said to you,
it's the whole business.
Once you tap into the whole thing and
you learn how to control like all right,
the cartel in the 80s Pablo Escobar,
all those guys that when
they were processing code,
that's what they were doing.
They weren't selling it.
They were getting it and selling a kilo
for 6,000 and what you did with it was
what? What was your business? Okay.
That was how it started. Then they said,
wait a second,
we're going to become partners and get
some of that from New York where we're
taking it from. So instead of
selling the key for eight from them,
we're going to get 16 we're going
to get 20% of their profits. Okay.
Then they said, Ooh,
that's some good money too,
but they were paying
people to transport it.
So I would come to Joe Rogan ink and go,
Joe Rogan every week,
Tuesday you're going to
transport 2000 kilos.
At 5,000 of Kalo. Okay, that's
it. We're going to do that to you,
and then they did that.
Then Carlos laid dead,
got out of prison and went to the
cartel and says, what we're going to do?
I'll be a new fucking partner.
50% you're going to process it.
You're going to do this. I'm the one
that's going to take it up to the state,
sell it, set the pricing, control the
routes. He got the island off the coast,
whatever, and he got the island there,
so now they, they ran it from a to z.
You're following me.
They control different a to z.
They just weren't coke dealers.
No more.
The same thing's going
to happen with this weed.
The same thing is happening that
these guys are getting a pound.
They turn and half of that to Keith.
They turned the other half into
edible and they, the other half,
they sell at 20th fucking grant.
There's no loss in wheat.
When they take the stems off.
Now.
They'll just throw that into mixing
the edible weed they found floating off
please. But it's Mexican weed, so he only
cares about that. I didn't hear about it.
Yeah. Yeah. There's some
kind of like, oh my God,
2000 times or something like that.
Right.
Fucking magic dumped from
like a probably I guess
could be right.
They might've been running out of
gas. They had to toss it over, but
what would the best me right here.
Why is it even on the ocean? So
where was it coming from? 180 bails.
Oh my God.
8,000 pounds of weed.
Holy fucking shit.
180 bales of we'd found
floating in the ocean.
And what do they do about that? Did
they have to burn it now? Can't take it.
They put it somewhere. Then when they do
a big cookout, well, what's the navy have?
Medical Marijuana. Why
doesn't the government sell
it? We could use that money.
Well, first off, they found the bales.
How much water got into those bales?
Sell it cheap.
Let me tell you something.
I smoked fucking weed that's been dry
from bells in the early eighties really
fucking horrible. It tastes like salt
water. Oh really? Fucking horrible.
Blow the seeds that weeds got season.
We don't want them to do,
but that we could use that for edibles.
But the thing with that weed is
they'll take it off. How many bales?
Hundred and 80 by the time they burn those
bands, that government gets the burn.
No beat. 92 bells left. Really think I
was fairly well covered. Tell please.
So what about the,
the salt water and all that shit?
Some poor soul or fucking some porcelain
like North Dakota where you can't get
good. Need more fucking brother that likes
to smoke blunts and make videos at his
house. What's the hardest spot
in the country to get weed?
Where's the hardest part?
Front of the Capitol in front of the
camera right in front of the cow might be
the easiest. I know you ain't gonna
get no weed at the fucking White House.
I think you'd get weed everywhere. I
think now in this country it's wide open.
Could you go on the streets like the
old days? I think if you had to yet.
Hey Dude,
pull up Penn Jillette's rant on Obama
and we'd Penn Jillette fucking nailed it.
The,
you know,
Penn Jillette has a podcast
now on Sundays and uh,
Adam Carolla's a network and a,
it's called Penn Sunday school.
And he went on this rant about how
fucked up it is that that marijuana is
illegal and that people
are in jail for it.
And one out of six people in jail
are in jail for marijuana. And he,
he went on his fucking brilliant
rant, man. And it's, it really is.
It's a shame. Like what, what,
what's going on right now,
arresting people for marijuana with all
the information we have about how we,
you know, we know it's not dangerous.
We know the laws are ridiculous.
It's a real shame when you see
people getting arrested for,
and he makes this intense point about it.
Business.
We know this president has said
his own book dreams from my father,
1995 before entering politics,
he admitted that he had used marijuana
and maybe a little blow, maybe,
maybe a little blow, which
as you know is crazy talk.
Maybe a little blow is what someone
who uses marijuana every weekend says,
man, I used cocaine once. It was
crazy, but he used every or two ago.
Maybe a little blow.
That's true.
That's such an odd casual way to say,
ah yeah,
maybe a little now he is not
left us to state's rights.
As you know,
a medical marijuana as our good friend
Joe Rogan will point out to you any time
medical marijuana you can
get in California and the
feds are coming in to try to
stop this. They're showcasing
piece of states' rights.
Don't mean Jack Shit to
the Obama administration on
anything except a sub gay
marriage. What troubles me
about this is, and there's,
it is not hypocrisy
because as everybody knows,
hypocrisy doesn't bother me very earthy
and so Obama and yet you feel this is,
I think it's beyond hypocrisy. I think
it's something to do with class. You know,
in a lot of people have
accused Obama of class warfare,
but in the wrong direction.
I believe this is Obama chortling with
Jimmy Fallon about lower class people.
Do we believe,
even for a second,
anybody believe that if Obama had been
busted for marijuana under the laws that
he condones would his life have been
better if Obama had been caught with the
marijuana that he says he uses and maybe
a little blow blow cocaine blow felony
conviction. This casual attitude
towards drugs, a casual attitude door,
drugs that makes him really cool on the,
on Jimmy Fallon makes him
the hip president. I'm the
cool president. I'm happy.
Happiest happened as president. I say
weed, I say blow. It's all a big deal.
Hahaha.
Huge laugh from the college students.
And if he had been busted under his laws,
he would have done hard fucking time.
And if he had done time in prison time
in federal prison time for his weed and a
little blow,
he would not be president of the United
States of America and he would not have
gone to his fancy ass college.
He would not have sold books that sold
millions and millions of copies and made
millions and millions of dollars.
He would not have a beautiful,
smart wife.
He would not have a great job.
He would have been in fucking prison.
And it's not a God damn joke.
People who smoke marijuana
must be set free.
It is insane to lock people up.
Now,
people bust me all the time
for carrying on about how,
I've never had a sip of alcohol,
never had a puff of marijuana,
never done any drugs in my life. They say,
why do you always bring that up? Well,
maybe in this case it's
okay to bring it up. Okay.
I've never had a puff of marijuana.
I've never had maybe a little blow.
I've never even had a glass of wine.
All right?
None of that shit.
But the people who do any of this
stuff do not deserve to be in prison.
Throw some numbers at me. Good. No,
750,000 people in jail for
a victimless crimes. Uh,
uh, uh, a great number of which
are marijuana. One in six,
one in jail are there for about one
in six people. A victimless crime.
Now when it's ignored,
people in prison,
one in six people in prison.
What?
Brilliant rent's six people in prison,
hinge and listening.
I those love the rent and
if you want to listen to it,
pendula at Sunday schools is fucking
amazing. I want to meet him so bad.
We didn't figure this out 10 years
ago, but come on. That's a great,
that's a great Rancho de wasting my time
with the shift came to the talk to you
while I'm talking to you right now.
Welcome me about what? It's a business.
What the fuck do you want?
Nobody knows prison is a
business and that's what it is.
It's a fucking business
guides. It's important when
a guy like pendulum, I said,
boy, guy do for you break the fucking
law. You go to jail, you sell weed.
I guess the law in 10 bales, you get
caught. You go to jail. I went to jail.
I'm responsible. I learn how to fucking,
that's it. What are you going to do?
There's a law. You cannot fucking
do it. You're going to go to jail.
Jail and prison are a fucking business.
They're a business.
That's why you get a ticket driving with
the phone. How much they tell you this,
how much they tell you this,
I don't know.
$25 until you go down to La County and
it's $225 because you've got to pay the
court costs. The prison fee,
the judges vacation. It's a,
it's a fucking business guys. They're
gonna raise the taxes now, uh,
for fucking parking tickets. It's a
business. What the fuck you want me to do?
This is the oldest conversation.
The book,
they should have legalized this
after they shot Kennedy. They didn't.
We fucking fortunate that we live in
California and we don't have to abide by
this. When was the last time you would've
stolen? They kicked the door down.
Joe Rogan. How about you my
friend? So all this shit,
you guys talked about them kicking the
doors. The feds, I have never seen it.
I go get weed every day.
Stop scaring these fucking white kids and
getting them talking. This is nonsense.
This is nonsense talk and that they should
kinda with Jim when I never drink it.
So what? So who gives a fuck?
It applies for everything going.
There's a lot of people who are in jail.
They get out every day on a DNA
or whatever. You break the law.
You sell five pounds a week, you
got to go to jail. It's a business.
You didn't do nothing wrong, but it's
a business. They have guidelines.
If you get caught with
dirty 28 grams a blow,
you have to do a certain
amount of fucking time.
You get caught with a quarter rounds.
So we have to do a certain amount of time.
You got caught with it. Why are you
crying to me for you got caught with,
I was a criminal for 30 years. You
ever, somebody gets caught with blow.
We either blow. No, you follow me. There's
a way to do it and as a way not pile.
Fuck.
Are you going to get caught with fucking
weed and not think you're going to go
to jail if you live in fucking Ohio and
in fucking Kentucky or wherever you're
gonna go to jail. I kind of see your
point, but I also see his, cause it's a,
it's an important mind. It's
brilliant though. It's important.
It's not together with Fallon
and the presence hip or what?
I don't give a fuck dog. You don't
care. I'm smoking. Look, look.
This is what I think about
your whole drug thing.
Looks like the same thing I've rubbed
my balls with for the last 32 years with
the sativas and the bullshit.
Just get high dog.
You'd be playing too much drama to the
gift that God gave us. A getting high.
You got too much drama.
I can't.
I've got to put a Dang at the
end of the joint to be cool.
And even while you're smoking electronic
cigarettes, he's fucking electric.
What? I'm smoking it. Think
about that. I'm smoking. Oh,
that's all that matters at the end
of the week. That's all that matters.
Fucking people want to be
intelligent all the time.
We can't wait to share the stage tonight.
Not fucking stupid rare form.
And three out of four people in there
for rape and murder. What do you,
what are you telling me?
Who gives a fuck?
Who gives a fuck and to show people
that you give a fuck. Who gives a fuck?
I don't give a fuck.
I don't want people locked
up in jail for weed.
You know what my favorite thing Joe,
they came in here. Jack boot thugs.
Marilyn fucking high your way for your
little pencil comedian for 20 years.
I drink from time to time.
Did ever get behind the car when I'm
drunk and got a Dui. That's a choice.
You make these all the choices you
make bro. So what are we getting at?
I know it's illegal.
I know it should be illegal and I know
that John Lennon is going to make a
comeback, but for today,
but for today, 2000 tonight,
but for today, if you get caught
smoking and fucking in New York,
you're going to jail. I don't care what
you said, bro. I love hearing your talk.
Fuck, I'm going to put up with this
nonsense pendulum but will give them,
I was going off yesterday, I was saying
how Joey Diaz will get mad about ketchup
because there'll be one thing it would
just fucking Heinz Ketchup or ranch. Oh,
I fucking hate rant. I don't know
how the fuck people delete that shit.
I don't know how people could eat rat.
I like when I go to a
place and I say you all,
you have wings and they
say it comes with ranch.
I get up and leave even
if I don't get the wings.
Because if you're going
to serve wings ranch,
I don't want to do business with you but
I don't want to do business with you.
I'm very easy. I'm very fucking easy.
So if you fuck up pork fried rice,
what are we got to talk about? Wings
must be done with blue cheese. Yeah,
like the wave they invented in Buffalo,
New York and we got to do something.
Who would original?
You're going to show up with that rant.
As small as like somebody
is at [inaudible] ranch is
starting to replace ketchup.
Yeah,
that's good.
If you're a fucking hillbilly and you
want to taste the ass in your mouth all
fucking day.
I hate that fucking rich shit.
Don't put it close to me and I'll put it
around me and see the blue cheese with
wings and go fuck your mother. That's
the next year. All right, please
give me a fucking rat. Would fuck
a wing. I can see blue cheeses. We
go fuck this shit.
Fucking gotta gimme branch with my wigs.
That's how you mother
fuckers. I'm stoked. Fucking
cheeses.
Wigs.
Fuck your mother fucking Shit.
I lead my people around the a ranch,
like don't order it. I shit around me.
Do me that favor.
All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
fucking podcast is over.
I got to go and um, do a,
David tells a, uh, Dave's
old porn show today.
So we've got a show tonight at the
ice house. It's not quite sold out,
but it's really close. There's only like
two tickets for jade from that week.
And it was like sweet. 10 left, two
chickens come on. But it's a ice house.
comedy.com is a website. You can buy
tickets online. It the lineup tonight.
Spectacular. It is mad flavor.
Aka Joey motherfucking Diaz,
Brian Bread Band,
Aka Reichle.
If you're looking to give them something
with a social security number and tat
Doug Benson is going to
be all up in this bitch,
Ari Shaffir just texted me and said
he's gonna make it down. Yes, Paula,
he'll, he'll squeeze in. And Don,
my rarest coming down this fucking show
is going to be people chain off the
chain. There's no, there's no, no way
to be too many people. It's perfect.
It's beautiful.
It's half ready.
We're going to ride on a pitch right
into the beach. That's done. That's done.
You shouldn't even invite it. We're going
to have a great fucking show tonight.
Whoever comes down,
we're going to have a great child and
we will also be broadcasting a podcast
simultaneously. We'll start before
the podcast. We say it starts at nine.
It really doesn't start until like
nine 39 ish in case we get crazy. Uh,
and if you're bored and you're in front,
just leave it on and you'll find
out what time it starts. So, um,
that is called the Ice House chronicles
and you could watch it live on Ustream
at the same channel, the, uh,
the Joe Rogan channel on Ustream.
But if you want to download the podcast,
you have to get it from either
iTunes or death squad. Dot.
TV and death squad.
Dot TV is all of Brian's
podcasts that he produces.
He's got a gang of them online and they're
eventually going to be broken up into
separate feeds now, right?
Is that how you doing?
Yeah, some of the main shows
of are already on a separate
feeds on Itunes, but, uh,
we have, uh, you know, Doug
Benson has been stopping by a lot.
He's been on the last two
triple x squads and you know,
we have MF said we had the,
the vice or the guy that's behind
call of duty on the last one did.
We should be all on,
on
death squad network.
We should all figure out a way to get
ourselves all together on a website or
something. Let's do something where we're
all in this thing. You know what I mean?
I mean, we love for three years. We have
to figure how to do this. I know we,
we really all should be together. We'll
do, we'll, we'll figure out how to,
how to organize it just
to, just to, you know,
like we need at least have
a page on our website.
Like these are all the people that we
associate with these squad honorary death
squad.
You know,
we have like official death squad,
honorary desk squad, closest associates.
Familiars right. We have to two, we label
these things. Well, I'm trying to do that.
That's why right now I'm going to, I'm
going to make like a link page thing on,
you know, like what you were talking about
with the grading and stuff like that.
I just need help with wordpress.
Yep. Beautiful. We'll, we'll, we'll,
we'll hire somebody. We need to
hire some. Yes. If you're a cook,
if you're a super master at
wordpress, like a, you're just a bad,
if you got some wicked websites,
get ahold of red van. Yeah.
Get Red Ban at red band at Gmail,
red manage email, Holler, wait, wait,
wait for the wave of crazy because
here it comes. All cabs, serious,
serious people. They have a portfolio and
everything. Don't be mean. Don't be mean.
Why was tomorrow
these guys tonight, I'll be at
the Irvine Improv tomorrow night,
eight o'clock show nine four nine
eight five four five four, five, five,
four eight o'clock I want to thank
the people, Columbus, Cleveland,
and Pittsburgh is a bat to the ball.
I'll see you motherfuckers in Buffalo,
New York, man. Listen, New
York was fucking amazing.
Play this for you because you haven't,
you haven't even seen this.
This is you going on stage in New York.
I save this.
I played this for don my rare last night
and we both just sat and listened to it
in my car with our mouths dropped
because this is you going on stage.
This isn't cold play. This is
Joey Diaz. Listen to this. Ready?
You got standing those idle or shows?
No people.
That's New York. No, you getting on.
So he hasn't even introduced you.
You're walking on stage right now
and they're going fucking bananas.
He tried to calm him down
and that's me going, wow, that's fucking
amazing. I love you motherfuckers.
You coming out, we'll get
better and better. And uh,
I told you the dream by the end
of the year would taking over.
This mother fucker wants him for
New Year's woods out December 12.
We'll be ready for the Martians.
What was showing up?
Whoever's showing you fucking we got,
yeah,
we're thinking about starting compounds.
We're gonna make our own
tax deductible religion go.
I've got to put the documentary out of it
sounded like hotcakes if you donate it,
if you bought it, I give my heart
to you. Thank you very much.
How did they find any of your stuff?
This was on pay, the documentary,
but we'll put it on iTunes next week.
So once it's highlight tunes,
I blow it up on Twitter and Facebook is,
you're a CD still number one on nine 11,
it went down.
They went down that day.
Went down from one to like 92 went
not like Brendan Schaub and Brazil.
You follow me down on and
what is it called again?
It's either you or the motherfucking
priests, but you know what?
I'm not a fucking priests. Just are
the priest, right? You want to find it?
I'm sorry, a priest. You're
going to bring it back up, Julie.
We're going to bring it back up to
that document going much as it is.
I've got my balls from,
it's five bucks payloads.
I appreciate everything you guys.
Where I got my boss from was the
documentary and that's on payload payload,
p a y l o a d z.com.
Powerful. I love you motherfuckers and
if they want to follow you on Twitter,
it's mad flavor. Flave come to Facebook
to whatever we got subscribers.
At least you get the Heli Shit
I'm talking about. I love you Jo.
I love the red band. You know what man?
I lost the link I was talking about.
That's mine. I went away. I
didn't go on there for so long.
It just told me they threw me out
of the fucking thing. You know,
we would be back tonight,
back tonight for the icehouse
chronicles and tomorrow with a wild man,
Bert Kreischer. Oh Shit. Oh Shit. Oh
Shit. We love you. We love you guys.
Thank you.
Okay.
Is it okay? I forgot to
thank our sponsors. Ladies
and gentlemen. First of all,
I'd like to thank unsolicited sponsors.
Defense soap is a soap company
in that I use for grappling.
It's Kinda like tea tree oil and all these
like probiotics and it keeps you from
getting like mad herpes and nasty shit.
Like that's the thing that happens.
You get scratched up when you do Jujitsu.
You can get like ringworm and
people don't know about that stuff.
You can even get staph infection
and people get really sick from it.
It's very dangerous. And the way to
keep your skin healthy is two fold. One,
probiotics take acidophilus,
very important, um,
Kombucha teas and other good probiotic.
But anything probiotic, that's,
that's like very important.
But acid office has a really strong
one that keeps ringworm dead.
And then to use natural soap that doesn't
fuck with the natural ph balance of
your skin.
You don't want to use antibacterial scope.
So because that stuff actually
kills the good bacteria as well.
Then what defense?
So business has like tea tree oil in
it and all sorts of different like
eucalyptus,
all sorts of different night natural oils
that are good for keeping the healthy
flora of your skin safe,
uh, from nasty cooties.
So That's defense soap.com
that's unsolicited.
That shit's for free and see two oh
coconut water and other unsolicited one
cause the shit.
Those guys are the shit.
And I have to c two O for as Gatorade.
I used to be a big
Gatorade guy that you know,
like after a night of drinking or just
whenever when I'm dehydrated and Joey
said it went sour, but I get to see this,
I will take all his CTO and drink it.
Uh, thanks to the fleshlight
for sponsoring us.
Go to Joe rogan.net and click on the link
for the flashlight and are in the code
name Rogan and save yourself 15% off
the number one sex toys for men. And uh,
thanks to onnit.com that's o
n n it makers of Alpha brain,
which I took before the show, which
is why I'm so motherfucking eloquent.
A shroom tech sport, shroom tech,
immune, five HTP, enhanced new mood.
Go check all that shit out@onit.com
o n n. I. T use the code name,
Rogan and save 10% off any and all
orders from now until you stop ordering.
We are done. Hold on. One more shoutout.
Walk cats a sucks.com go to the
webpage check, checking that sack.
Order a tee shirt with them. BMB Dot 20
a 20% off the tee shirt that my sponsors.
I love them. Beautiful Ball sex check
and go check out Julie's podcast. Yeah.
Beauty and the beast.
And go check out fucking dove organic
and get yourself your little fucking
Eureka, Boone's Sherlock block.
Boom by death squad shirt
that's got that TV. Yeah,
that's quite all right.
We love you guys. Bye.
Okay.