Panion podcasts. If you'd never
heard one of these podcasts before.
Don't expect us to even pay
attention to the fights.
Sometimes we do it. Sometimes
we felt like, oh great,
Joe's going to do commentary.
No, Brendan's not doing commentary
accounts. I do commentary.
We'll do commentary because I
know nothing about the fight.
He'll pretend that he is giving strategy
advice. That wouldn't really work.
Exactly. But uh, what we do is we watch
the fights and a, you can sync it up.
Um, right now it's the
first fight. Who is this?
This is Hein.
And we'll try saying this name.
Nick Heine Verses Luke has
said Jif ski to juice ski.
There he is. There is,
Luke has said juicy.
Who's my favorite fighter
who ends in a ski there?
This is the first fight on the main card.
Who's that guy there?
The guy on the left. Yeah. Fabulous
Viking character with tattoos.
Dms a great look.
He's not tall to thumb.
Two thumbs go.
People like me running out there is Lucas.
And uh,
so like I said,
we,
we will might talk about this
fights or it might be diarrhea talk.
Maybe you never know. Drugs and podcasts
that you knew shirt. Yeah. Yeah.
Nice fighter. And the kid
killing it. Thank. Thank you.
To Brenton shop, our design,
our chief designer fighter and the
kid.com I go like this. He asked me,
I might pin it and I go, I don't
know, maybe. And he goes, Oh,
I'm not asking your opinion, just showing
them to you. I don't hear back from him.
I'm like, I have an
opinion. I said, I said,
you have the fashion sense of Anne Frank.
Literally I was dead to
Holocaust reference. That was,
I was very surprised because she
can't see what she's wearing.
Very similar to you. Well
No, no, no. Now you're,
you're confusing and frank with Helen
Keller. That's right. Fortunately
why did you have
oh wow.
Shit and frank would be great if you
were aware in Cabo. In an attic, right.
And exactly.
And that's it. Yeah. Had, I knew Joey
and I should have just kept my mouth shut.
But the problem is,
and frank though it would work within
then frank because she probably wore just
one like dowdy dress cause she had to
live in an attic. Right. Or a year.
Damn behind is ripped. Now he's a big
kid. Kids in good shape. Yes, he has.
He was in his corner. Oh yeah, he's
a tiger Muay Thai guy. He was also,
he was also a pro uh, policemen.
Tiger Muay Thai apparently is,
it's just a fucking bang and
gym over in Cat Thailand.
They just have an amazing camp there.
There's a couple camps down now.
Aka has a big kid. I'm like switch down
there, right? Yep. Yeah. No I don't,
I'll wonder why Mike Swick decided to move
his camp to Thailand. Oh Shit. Totally.
No, this is what a
subscribers that's going on.
You get to see a nice surprise once you
lock us in since you're the last one in,
so no one knows who you go. No one
comes in here and looking for, yeah.
I think for SWIC as I'm sure decision,
right. Like he was going to open a gym.
And why Thailand?
I mean he has a family.
I don't know why the fuck you
decided to go to Thailand.
I forgot he had a family.
I thought it was like wiling out on the
girls and no jams. That sounds good.
Can I hear amazing things about, that's
what I hear. Amazing. And when I,
when I shot a little movie called hangover
to all the stunt guys and most of the
just tough guys around.
We're all professional or
aspiring professional Moy
Thai guys who spoke I think
a little bit about training and Paquette.
Yeah, that area. Um, like I said,
he's got that too,
those two gyms and it's supposed to be
like a really cool tourist area too.
It's really beautiful. It's
spelled p h, e t which would be,
fuck it Tony mother
sounds like a great plan.
Lightened bitches on fire last
night at the comedy store.
Then shows up for the fight companion.
Funny like he's in love with Yolanda
Jerk Riddick I'd say Jerky Dick.
I took the beat for that
for the bonds.
No fans. When you put it on the back end
to have a boss right now. By the way,
that's great feeling.
Oh boy. Don't say, but if you say Jerky
Dick in front of Tony, he might get upset.
I get a little offended over this.
I wish we could.
I wish we could respect
Johana. I do. She has the baby.
You should know how to say her fucking
name before you tell people to respect
her and Jay Check Yohanna
Yohanna and their last name.
Yen J. Check, check, check,
check, check that she,
the way she has it. There's like a
little bit of an ou in there as well.
You and jet check. I just call
her JJ it friends. Call her JJ.
Have you ever forgotten you'll do
that college age? I made that up. Oh,
you should get better. Like talking about
Jj, the champ JJ, but he's gs marketing.
She has,
it's not even tough to say George Saint
Pierre and everybody was saying GSP,
it's too long when you have you
ever, uh, when you call it a fight.
Do you ever guys guys, seriously guys.
Okay, first fights about the star.
If you're gonna sync this up, I'll let
you know. Right when they touched gloves.
Now they touched gloves.
Yeah. So the clock right now,
the moment they showed the clock,
we'll let you guys know so you could
sync it up. We call this Sara Lee.
The Michael is feeling the guy
out for 40 ushering, four 47,
four 46, four 45. Okay, so there you go.
Now you sinked up because the Internet
runs about 10 seconds at least behind
depending on where you are. The Ustream
feed will run about 10 seconds behind.
Great Tan on that dude.
Can you tell he trains and Thailand.
Lucas is going after it.
Yeah, you can't help it.
He's got a kind of skin it smolders.
Isn't it interesting that like Tan like
that is actually good for your body and
your endurance and the way your,
um, your, your body makes muscle.
It's anabolic,
you know,
vitamin D and your production of vitamin
D at aids and the antibiotics process.
That's why a lot of fighters get tans.
I do. Steve Maxwell told me that. Yeah,
but you were just sexy bitch.
I would get 10 cause I'm vain.
I get 10 cause I'm very vain.
And you don't mind wrinkles.
No may know on the face. He liked
that fucking leathered old look. Well,
I do dye my beard. My sister looked
at me the other day and she goes, Ooh,
your face looks like
it needs lots of water.
This is just me. She's hilarious. But
mean she's very smart. Yes she is.
Yes. You guys are get
along very well. We did.
We got along great at your daughter's
party. Yes. Clung to your sister.
My sister has one of those.
She's pretty amazing.
She's very smart because smart.
Not sentimental either. Good. Yeah,
she doesn't. I said you get hormonal when
you uh, have your period Cheetos. No,
and that annoys me. I remember when
she was younger I was like, whoa.
It's not a very, it doesn't have a lot
of girl energy to get along with patty.
Great.
Very well.
Call everybody pussies. Yup. Geez, that's
too intense, man. That's too intense.
Kathleen is not like when girls talk like
them, man. Those guys of scary. Yeah.
My sister is not sentimental
hoods seats like, whoa, whoa.
She's not romantic stuff.
Easy bit. Some are down bitch.
Someone's going to make you swallow your
teeth. Cat. My sister, my sister used to,
my sister used to have
an eye for weakness,
like if she saw a guy with a w what she
called a week Chin or if somebody was
sleeping with their mouth open, God help
you. She'd be like sleeping on a plane.
We'd be on our plan. Should go look
at that guy with his mouth open.
What a weak link. I was like,
come on man. He's just sleeping.
His jaws hanging open.
She's like, that's annoying.
That's your dad's barbarian jeans?
Yes. She's all my, I call her I,
the joke is I look at our go daddy.
Oh, I mean Kathleen, they look alike.
That's not good. No, she's got, she's
got bigger bones. She was the Husky one.
I was the frail. You wish you
had your sisters genes, dude,
I would get cold really
easily. I had no, I had,
I was so skinny and my sister was like,
what are you cold for you baby?
She has a full set of hair on her too.
She does. Chicks don't usually go ball.
She's not suffering from male pattern
baldness. What we're talking about.
I'm like, she's a fucking war.
Like I said, I hear on her,
she also has a little Dick.
It's got a tiny,
tiny cock ball.
That was a nice styles,
a nice transition there behind
recognizing that that knee is coming.
Kind of telegraph that knee now ride
the back but give up the position.
Most small, small arms is short
arms and legs. She's very muscular.
He sits a rare look these days.
Gosh,
get your hands off in the lighter and
lighter weight classes guys are becoming
less and less muscular.
Really? Yeah. Yeah.
Well cause we got Caligiuri
and CBRE on the car tonight.
Two guys that were real thick for
their way class. It's just super rare.
Wait til this drug testing kicks in
and it was only like gumby and shit.
You're not joking to Kermit the
frog. Not Joking. It is. It's very,
very weird. What? What's going on here?
Because the UFC is deciding
to do it on their own.
They're deciding to clean
up the sport on their own,
but it's an inherently dirty sports,
but they're not part of it. Right.
And they're handed off so, and you'll
see, they can't tell him who to test.
They're just saying, hi, you
guys do it strictly as fuck.
We're just going to stay out of it.
They're telling they're telling the
commissioner to do that. No, no,
not a commission.
I bringing in water that bringing the
people that busted Balka the strictest
drug testing in the world. They're
going to have it year round. Right.
They're going to do it randomly
all year round. The five,
five random tests a year.
They show up at your house,
three o'clock in the morning, Brian,
get up. God Damn you ain't no. Yeah.
The problem with that and awakened
me. A Wiccan security son. Yeah.
Hashtag rich they're getting,
they're getting guys that are um,
you know,
looking in the middle of your sleep cycle,
you're fucking up their whole day.
If you could fuck up a couple
of days of training problem,
they could take a shot and maybe they
wouldn't have taken if you'd done that,
you know, I mean, they might be slower in
the gym because of that. That's really,
you're going to get a piss.
I'm gonna Piss on your face.
You wake me up at three in the morning.
There should be,
but they don't want to make
it so that you could cycle it.
You know you can get apparently
Alex Rodriguez, by the way,
this scientific analysis is brought to
you by Joey Diaz told me about this.
Don't take it with a grain of salt. Yeah,
dog. They got these fucking gummy bears.
Alex Rodriguez was taken gummy bears.
He would take him and they would test.
By the time he knew exactly when to take
these fucking things so that when they
were going to test them, it
would be out of, it's just, no,
he's right fucking gummy bear.
He's right that he would do it and turn
the game by the end of the game is if
they test them as another system.
How's that possible? I have no idea.
I wish I had the fucking scientist.
But is that still possible?
Cause someone to get those
to veto lunch yesterday.
Was that the weirdest
transition of bodies? Vito?
Between Luke Rockhold and
veto fighting Weidman.
It's like what the fuck happened
or or over him that time. No,
but over him still looks like a stud. Like
Overeem is smaller than it used to be,
but he's still looks like a stud when
old tour, it looks deflated. I agree.
He looks like he looks like someone stole
his meat over him when he fought Brock
Lesnar I was like, holy fuck, you need
to beat bright ass. Shut that shit.
Oh hell yeah.
It's called guys guys.
Obstructional you beat Brock's ass and
then just walk on over to the fucking, uh,
Orleans casino and when the Mr
Olympia like you could do both.
He was fucking Jack. I watched
it. I was like, Oh fuck.
I need to find a different career or a
different doctor. Holly, different doctor.
What can I ask you guys? Uh,
I watched the Kimbo slice, uh,
frank champ. I mean then shamrock,
shamrock fight and him, Ken,
him and Ken had him
completely stretched out.
When I got to tell you right now
that fight look fake as fuck.
That's what I was going
to take that literally,
that's what I thought was a couple of
things I don't like about that fight.
I don't like that clinch,
that long clinch that they had
where they were mouth to ear,
they would amount to each other's
ears for Nolan was really striking.
Like if he's turning your wrestler,
I'm popping those elbows
and fucking take me down.
How about the fact that would have
stretched out when Ken did take him down?
He never hit him once. How about that?
He never hit him. He had him down.
He had them flattened out.
He had his back and he's not crashing
them. He's not blasting with punches.
He's got him flattened out and he's not
hitting him. That doesn't make any sense.
He's also, he also had a full, he
had a full head to toe. I know,
but he's also 51 that's true,
and a fighter 51 yeah,
that's true. You'd, you'd a hundred
percent correct and I was like,
I watched everyone, right? I watch
all the [inaudible]. I watch all UFC,
I'll let you everything. So the bell tour
when, when the interest is, I was like,
this is so dope. The, it was kind
of like the pride and all that.
Then I was on board. You have the, I was
on, you had, he had big brown on board,
but then when Ken shamrock walked
out, I was like, what the fuck?
How about the girl who was singing?
What was that about? I don't know. See,
I'm down with that though.
I'm down with lights.
His love for Brian to thing for me,
when I walked,
he is a man. He's really tall and
brow. No a singer, not like that.
He's got great hair and a part inspired
by the great Gatsby that would crush so
hard.
I'm working with big brown,
his big brown,
big brown.
You could totally get an opponent's head.
By the way,
when he's laughing at your insurance,
he's going to punch this guy in
his big fat and take him down.
Be careful of his game.
I don't want a west side story
and surveys.
Just two is second to none.
He's really handsome. That
doesn't, he can turn on a nun.
Don't ever play with me.
You didn't even try.
But shamrock came out.
I think his whole family was
behind him. He had a white girl with the
daughter and the kids behind it. Yeah.
He had a girl that was with them,
mostly his granddaughter or something
that had his daughter maybe that had a kid
on board until that,
until that it was very WWF.
The entrances to me, it looked
the whole thing, the entrance.
So suspect because he was
shaking everybody's hand.
It didn't look like he was about
to go to a fight and it was about,
he was about to go put
on a performance nervous.
And if you watched Kimbo fight when he
was in the UFC when he was fighting like
mitre own or Houston Alexander,
that motherfucker's taking it serious
now when he fought Ken Shamrock,
he's talking to him in the ring
before the entrance. No, no, no.
The baddest motherfuckers on the
nurse really don't talk like that,
but they might have told them that this
is the way to generate interest in this
fight to hype it up all
the fake bad blood like,
and then the other thing that got me
was the way Kimbo stopped share mark.
That was real as fuck. I mean
he definitely was crap. I agree.
So maybe they made an agreement and Kimbo
said I'm to punch this mother fucker
anyway. Yeah, he was like, it's
fine. Glasses dude. Um, but,
but he did have him completely stretched
out with what looked like a full rear
naked choke. Am I wrong about that? Sort
of, but he never went behind the head.
Like he choked him,
but he had it like on top of the head
and sort of sort of weird and Kimbo was
able to just keep grabbing up because
it's hard to choke out with one arm.
And this year, I mean you gotta you
gotta be real mother fucker. Yeah.
To be a monster.
But timber just kept grabbing the one arm,
which is the right move
to do. But I saw, oh man,
it was disturbing to me how easy
Kimbo Shuck Ken off his back.
Like there's a lot of shit that I
didn't like about it, that it was dealt.
And you see their next card,
they're doing a doublet they're doing,
and if I call on it, Diamond May.
I love it. Yeah. I'm on board.
[inaudible] daily on that.
I don't know if he's fighting daily,
but they're both fighting on the car.
I thought he was fighting daily.
If he's funny. Daily daily's
and fucking trust. Super
trouble. He's in trouble. Yes.
Joe Shillings.
A tall motherfucker who can crack
and he's been in there with the best
kickboxers in the world and daily date.
Yeah.
Dailies really good kickboxing for MMA.
But then again,
dailies got that fucking
ridiculous nuclear left left. Yeah.
But if he don't think Joe Schilling seemed
better striking. Yes. He knocked out,
man. Come on. Yeah, he knocked
out, man. Oh Man. I have
kicked him and I can't imagine
if I told him. Yeah, yeah.
Watching those, those kickboxing fights
where it's just kickboxing with huff his,
so he was so devastating for a while
that he used to be a Schilling.
Schilling knocked out fucking Simon Marcus
with one punch after they've gone to
four rounds. Four rounds. Yeah. And that
was the first guy to ever beat Marcus.
Marcus was undefeated like 39 and then
went to a drawl. Right. And then they,
they had to go to the next. Right.
And the reason why I went to withdraw,
Simon had dropped him. Simon had dropped
Joe showing, but then Joe Schilling,
you'd come back and won
some, like it was, you know,
the way they do to Gloria was the old
k one way where if they go three rounds
and then if it's a draw, they go to
the fourth and final round tiebreaker.
That's a mother fucker.
That'll fuck your mind. Well,
how about the fact that he had to
fight two more times after that night?
Same night. Yes. He had a fight. Fucking
Wayne Barrett, who's a bad motherfucker.
He had a fight him after that. And then
he had a fight. Art 11 in the fucking,
this is all just striking right up.
Oh, kickbox gets paid for stuff.
That was a pretty, pretty good
pay day, I'm sure. How old he was.
Just talking about how sorry was like
for days you had hit asleep in an easy
chair. Every time he'd get up he'd
be like, oh, his arms wouldn't bend.
Everything was fucked up.
Just like getting hit and balking and
three fights in one day. That's what that,
that's way, that's crazy.
He fucked 10 rounds,
10 rounds against three
different opponents. I did
four sets the other night.
I thought that was hard.
Can I be honest with you?
It's like you're looking a little more
vascular and I appreciate it. Weights.
I got the kid lifting that squad Straw.
You started
when we were in Canada.
The kids saw us with our shirts off and
decided to start lifting. That's right.
Brian switched shirts to rep you?
Yeah.
Oh, nice. So all three of
you played a part in it. Nice
man. He started working out.
Yeah, I had to. Yeah. He saw the kid
with his fucking shorter. I saw that.
It made me like really sad. Rogan's pretty
jacked. Rogan's very thick. It's a lot.
They like,
I
didn't, I was like, I
need shoulder surgery.
I have a torn labrum. I hope.
I don't know. So man. Yeah,
it clicks and it makes them more,
you know,
the problem has been bugging me for a
year and for a year I've just been pushing
through it. Because you're an extremist.
Moderate. I always stop Joe. Definitely.
No, I called Brian the other night.
I'm like, where are you man? He's like,
emergency room, Bro. I got a
sore throat right now. I'm like,
I'm not making this up. He's like, I'm
in the emergency room. And it could,
it could, you know, you see a white spot
that can be canceled. I'm like, Yep,
that's spastic catch shit. Same thing.
Or is it, no, no, no. I had, I had a,
on my dingleberry I W it was a
white spot and I was like, Oh,
same one spot or a new one that
I was the same one. But I go,
that's cancer and a guy looks at my thing
and he goes, and he goes, this is, I was,
I was so convinced. And he
goes, Huh? I already, he goes,
I guess that that's wild.
I go, what is, he goes, you didn't,
it's probably, where were you?
I said it was in Costa Rica. Oh, I
used to work in a clinic down there.
He probably has something from there
by just a self limiting virus. Oh,
by the way, gone the next day. I think
it was food on my tonsil on my thing.
It's embarrassing,
man.
He was probably ate a chocolate donut
with like powdered sugar on or some shit.
A hypochondriac. Powdered sugar. Gotten
a little thing. Meanwhile I pokes.
I fucking hate them.
Jesus Christ.
While your sister has spots all over
her fucking tongue, it doesn't do shit.
A bitch doesn't give a fuck.
She eats grass at me.
Who's up some grass clean mouth.
It's got green mouth syndrome,
foamy green bubbles on the corner of
her mouth. You chewing that cut again.
Shut the fuck up. Pussy. Looks
like you have your mouth open.
You don't have four stomachs.
Stop Chewing.
Cutting's a special type of dude
to be with a girl like that. Yeah.
I'm not one of those guys tried it.
I am not that guy. I've tried it too.
I like women who are women.
Me Too,
like women who want to argue with you
and they get fucking gangster with you.
That's not interesting to me.
That's like when I, when I tried,
I had a little affair with growing the
national Canadian water polo team who was
so hot, but she went back, was
thicker than mine and her hands,
her knuckles when we'd hold
hands. I was like, well,
your hands are a little just a smidge
bigger than mine and I have a big problem
with that. See, that's what I
love about my girlfriend Yolanda,
is that she doesn't start
any drama or talk shit,
but she, she knows her role.
She's mentioned she'll finish it,
uses it all up given chicks concussions.
She's exhausted by the time
she gets to you. She's very,
she's very beaten pitches. I want to
see you guys today. If you guys fucked,
you wouldn't have much say in it.
Don't need you lick pussy now.
I think boozy, you'll come out of your
fucking tired. Come on down. She wouldn't
go to sleep. I know why they call him the
Golden Pony. It's he's, he's surprising.
He has a surprising dick. That's
good. Is Dickie. So Bryce skinny,
skinny but like me, but he's
surprising. It's more of the ivory pony.
I give it to her. Good guys. I'm serious.
She didn't know your hair up in corn rows.
Just
I'd give it to
her.
Good guys
come.
I wouldn't fucking give it to her man.
That's how you know a guy's mouth.
He started laying the proper,
I was setting up for my cornrows line
too. Good man. You know how I do it guys?
Like looking for everybody
to confirm my guys. You know
guys, I would, I would
fuck her. Good fellas.
The time I was telling her she needed,
we haven't talked about this fight once.
Yeah. This guy sergeant is actually
getting the better of him right now. He's,
he's uh oh there it is man.
Highness slick. He, he's very aware
of what's going on. Like when,
when the other guy is throwing
shots and kicks, he's,
he's aware of like where
the angles are coming from,
is capitalized a couple of times on that.
He's cardios good.
He hasn't stopped moving man.
He's not tired. He's tire.
Roger Works is a good fucking trainer man.
He's apparently going to
fight again on the UFC. No,
he's fighting on one FC last week. His
last flight, right. Soccer fucked up.
He fought one 72 and Roger's not,
not even that big for one 55. Going
to catch an angles. Look at that dude.
You remember Roger Roger when he was in
the UFC and he's like the poster boy.
He's the first one that everyone thinks
Rhonda was the first one on the cover of
sports illustrated. Actually Roger worked
up. I'm great. This is my man over here.
It's walking toward him to straight
toward him and, and then we met he,
because I think he beat, uh, I forget who
he beat in that one. Eat a lot of guys,
but he was front kicking the guy and
who was the front cover of sports
illustrated. But then he got to
like big headed and he was like,
I want to get paid, whatever. So is
not just that you want to get paid.
He started complaining
about shit publicly,
started complaining about the media duties
and not getting paid for media duties.
And it was like, what? That
motherfucker disappeared. He made it.
He said to do what? That's
cool. Check this out.
Shelf Ia for a nice young two years
and here's the worst matchup possible.
Here's gray Maynard. See Ya. I'm
gonna fucking went to Thailand.
Last time I saw him fighting, he was
in a street fight in Texas. Yeah,
that was amazing though.
The dude hit a girl.
The dude hit a girl in the
parking lot. What? Yeah,
and Roger worked a pig ass
dude and Roger worked a k.
Oh this dude in front of a football
player. Big football player. Wow.
He sucker punches this girl.
Oh, I don't know what happened,
but this guy stepped up and sucker
punches. Girl got his face and he goes,
I'll knock you out too,
motherfucker.
Roger takes his shirt off and
just tees off on this guy.
It's like Goddamn action movie.
The camera pans to the guy,
pants to Roger moving towards the guy.
Next thing you know,
there's like a scramble
people in front of him.
The Dude's laid out and Roger soccer
kicking him in the ass, dude. Wow.
Did he get in trouble for it? No, he got
love from the whole world. Fantastic.
Could you get trouble for
that guy's a con, right? He's
a good dude, man. Good Dude.
He's a great guy. Really good guy. He just
had the wrong people in his ear. He's,
oh, he's on. He came and he
was in Denver for a while.
I remember training with us and he was
always just the fucking just bra man. His
boy one. Yeah. Well he's, he's taken a
lot of punishment in his career, man.
He tried being an APP. Yeah.
Well that was the thing.
He was dating that Laura prepon.
Yeah. From that 70
[inaudible] show. Yeah. And a,
I think she probably got in his head and
she was like the first celebrity I saw.
I thought Rogers. So Cause Marty,
how's it go? Shit. Dan Hardee.
Jesus Christ. No Guy's, he
looks like Tom Hardy though.
Cause Tom is also playing a character
like this. So there's Roger.
Look at handsome bastard. I'm look at
him. Yeah, he's a fucking ladies' man.
I've ever seen one kit to stud. They tried
doing the whole acting thing in fine.
They get you man.
They get you.
Dan Hardee gave that dude
the Mike can't do that.
That's frowned upon Dan hard.
He's going to be slapped when he goes.
What is this speech?
This guys can't do this.
It's about to start a revolution
of some kinds of shit. I'm on.
It sounds like Hitler. Mine comp. Yeah.
He's the only thing with his hand.
This is intense. This some
fight this on bypass shit. Hey,
there's some fipass shit man grabbed up.
Take that mic Dan Hardee who gets taller
than I thought 1,000 just give him that
mic. What's stretch? I mean that's
a big no, no, right Joe do that.
You can then very rare
occasions I hi guys on a trust.
You know, mentally like really hard
to share a mic with anyone ever.
You know when it's your role when
you're in control, but it's a difference
[inaudible] because when I'm doing
interviews like you never, I very, I'm,
I have no personality when I'm
doing interviews, my personality,
my or my interviews are all about trying
to get the most out of the fighter.
I just tried to ask him question and
give them the opportunity to express
themselves. But you very, I've, I don't
interject very much. Most of what I do,
I'll give them a little enthusiasm,
tell them how exciting it
was and how awesome ones,
but my goal is 100% while I'm doing
interviews is to try to get that guy to
express himself. That's why when I, when
I've tried to give people advice about,
you know, I've had a lot of guys
ask me like, what do you do?
How do I give interviews?
That's my scariest part a lot.
A lot of these guys are real nervous
about interviews because it's live.
You don't know exactly what to say and
you kind of ad libbing it in the moment.
I'm like, the most important thing
is it's not you, it's not about you.
It's all about trying to get the most
out of that guy. This is his moment.
What he was thinking, how it feels
to be a champion. All that does.
Is it surprising? Um,
give us your thoughts.
I want to know how a guy feels afters
cause sometimes a guy will say,
you know what man, from the second round
my hand was broken and uh, you know,
I tried to eat and you don't know, right?
Like you have to, you have to ask. Like,
how do you feel like, what happened? What
was it like? Was anything surprising?
You can't give him the mic. Don't
give me the mic. I like, Yo God,
Tfa tek.com blog gets everyone.
Was your, were you, um, I'm
surprised at the, uh, Cain Velasquez?
Uh, no I wasn't. I wasn't,
I wasn't surprised when I thought about
it afterwards. While it was happening,
I was like, whoa, this is crazy.
But you can't just go up to 7,500 feet
above sea level and expect to keep your
cardio. Especially when you haven't
fought in two fucking years. Man,
you just haven't fought. I see.
I think that's a good point.
You can't do that.
However you don't become a multi time
world champ and not know that that's an
issue. And I think his issues are way
beyond that. I think he realized that,
I think they could have fought in
fucking la at sea level and he would have
looked like that. Really? Yeah. I think,
I think [inaudible] a bad example.
You don't get to his level without
assuming that. I think it's a cop out.
I gotta be honest. Wow,
that's interesting. So what
do you think is going on,
do you think for you were doing,
just got that much better do
you think came to slipping?
I think for doom got that much better.
And I think Kane has had damn near
two years off and he's taken a lot of
punishment, man and good points. And
with these injuries. It's not like,
you know how it goes,
man,
when you have something to drink can
still work on stuff and continue to get
better.
Two years off of with surgeries and Rehab,
two years in MMA, the UFC, the game's
changing fast as fuck man. Like even now,
I haven't fought since December.
If I fought at then this next
December with a year off,
the games changed little over two years
and then you're fighting a motherfucker
and for doom who's been activists fucking
getting better and better and then,
and he's tall and he's got long reach.
Don't want to take them down. Enjoy that.
So what are you going to do now? And he
got strangled. I mean, that's what it was,
which is actually better
for him. You know, he was
getting fucked up on his feet.
He was about to get knocked out.
He's about for doing.
He was wobbling all over the place.
I would imagine if you were getting ready
for her doom in your Cain Valasquez,
your coach says, never
shoot a sack. Double leg.
Only a single know his coach was to
Javier Vasquez for versatile or Javier
Mendez rather who, first of all,
it was a fantastic coach. Yes,
it doesn't have a background is grappling.
Black belt in Jujitsu was not some
worldclass grabbed her. Right.
I don't think he's ever rolled
with a guy like for over doing.
Have you never rolled the guy who has a
fucking nasty guard look for doom guys,
you don't know. You can't take that guy
down, right? You can, but there has to be.
You have to bring in a guy like boosh
shusher to get you ready for, for doom.
Shoot a single.
I got them because they're going to
different stuff to get ahold of your neck
like you shouldn't see you like
on a high level guide Jitsu guy.
He's going to get a hold of your neck,
but you can pass and still taking the
matter to shit is in the first round. Yes.
Well he loves his head on the outside.
Knows that problem has
to be on the incident.
Your head has to be pinned to the chassis.
You should a double on a guy like Carl,
like Fabricio,
but for [inaudible] guard is so fucking
good unless you bring in a Vinnie
Magallanes or someone who's
got like a commensurate guard.
Good luck being able to defend
against him because he's got hit.
That double leg was desperation.
You can see him exhausted.
Have you ever seen change Cain?
Cain shoot such a shitty double and he
was just exhausted and then first of all
it's his technique was shit, right?
You see him over his, he leans,
he he liked leans over and over.
Dunamis is fucking promo.
Turn his volume of Jamie.
Best Promo ever. This is,
this is amazing fucking Promo.
I'm so fucking pumped things. Me and
Eddie got a crown on this fella, Hon.
Do you guys better grant?
Who'd you buy? Really? Ooh,
I'm rooting for Connor though.
I love that guy.
He walks even. It's so cool.
It's just a cocky fuck.
Like I love it.
This is such a great commercial
commercial, by the way. Cost $1 million.
Look at those eyes.
What a great fucking commercial.
God Damn.
July 11 hurry up and get here.
Please say what was it cheap
is using that Jay z song?
They're probably got some 900
grand than a hundred Ghana.
I'll do that shit for $20 right now.
Yeah.
Could have sang the song for that
Promo. That would have been, oh,
I hope that's right. Machida and
Romero, are you around for that?
You in town? I'm in San Francisco
at the punchline. Is that what? No,
that's not next weekend. Callan. June
27th June 27th this is June 27 yeah,
you and next weekend is the 27th around.
I'll be in you're there to,
to doing business. What are you doing?
Business. What kind of business?
The podcast sponsors business sponsor
stuff. Meeting with sue sponsor,
rearrange that. They would stand
up. You want to see my work?
I'm all,
I could go up and do yourself.
Do you have to set, oh, now the
year, now that you mention writing,
how much new stuff? Now let me ask you
this about your special, which by the way,
it was fucking so much fun to be at. The
only time I've ever opened up for a guy.
This is the only time I've ever warmed
up a crowd. Incredible. Like, I dunno,
15 fucking years I haven't gone
to on a show and 15 years. Yeah.
It was weird. Yeah. It's
weird to just go up like that.
Like you do it all the time,
Tony. You know, you're like,
there's a talent to getting the
crowd going. Like getting into it.
It was fun. Yeah, you did a great job,
but that room is fucking
amazing for a special.
When I was backstage watching on the
Monitor, I was like, this is perfect.
It's the perfect room. I loved
it. I loved the, I love the state.
I love the feel on the floor. I feel so
grounded. Did they ask you to do, do,
do you have more than one camera? Like
how many cameras? Six camera. Six cameras.
Yeah. See, I was thinking like the one
camera that they have when you work there,
you know how you worked there. They
make a film of every show. Right.
And the one camera that they have when
you work there as well. Perfect. Yeah.
It's like that one. I've been
watching specials lately and one,
one of the things that I've
been coming to this conclusion,
it's like you need one view of the show,
like head on the way you
can kind of watch a show.
Do you think 20 cameras over kill Cowen?
Six cameras.
Well he had a guy with him that does hair,
who had a holster,
was dead serious for sure.
Relax. I'm just giving them a,
I was just giving them my credit. You
know, he's a good guy and whatever,
giving them credit for all those people
were in the way during the way of
thinking. There's relaxation. If
it wasn't for Brendan tonight,
you probably wouldn't have been loose.
Yeah,
cause we were back there busting
those guys balls. It's right.
Like what you had on a Bentley belt.
Little too much.
He had a Bentley belt of red
Kango backwards of course,
and a holster. Any little cal writing
eyes was like, don't fuck this up.
See you went, how long he grabbed
you by the ears. What did I do?
Like 20 1520 minutes? About
28, 20, 28. But it was great.
They loved it. Hell yeah. Was
very appropriate and it was great.
The thing we talked about, Kevin was
so ready to just smart move to have uh,
such as, you know, a way over
qualified opener for a special,
I mean it's hilarious.
Joe Rogan opening for me.
I had Joey Diaz do mine at the Ice House.
That's says do it man.
That's how you do it was bloody murders
through. The thing was is I got,
I go Joey, I can only have
you do 15. Cause if you do,
if you do 21 minutes or longer,
there's no way they're going to be
able to listen to me for an hour.
And you have to be careful with that.
Like you don't want that fucking like
earned amount. Kevin Hart opened for you,
Joe. I got three guys opened for me before
when I was filling in special fuck too
much. Yeah, it was too much at some times
when I show we Dunkin. Oh No. Was it Joey?
Ari, Joey, Ari. I think it
was Joey. Ari and a red band.
Did a set. Yeah, it was
ridiculous. Two people. One person.
I didn't go on stage to the
hour and the show plus too much.
I'll defer your special. Yeah.
Wow. And it lands with you.
It's like you know when you are worried
because you're sweating so much.
He wouldn't shut up the second shot.
I turned the heat off.
Don't worry about it. Just do it.
Show look. You're in a club. Yeah.
No one gives you a club. You wouldn't
care. Right. If you were just,
it was a set on the weekend,
it wouldn't even cross your mind
if it would cross your mind,
it'd be something wrong.
I was just thinking about not being
able to use the second take because the
sweat was different on my shirt and by
the way, don't wear a shirt like that.
Don't wear a light blue shirt. As soon as
I walked in on the, God damn it. I know.
I always knew to wear a black shirt or
best was in between shows. They're like,
Brian, we have to fix the hair on the back
of your head. I'm like, no, you don't.
You don't have to fix his hair.
He's like,
he's the back of his neck like the back
of his neck just winding up. I'm like,
no one is going to watch
this fucking special and go.
I thought it was funny until
I saw an errant hair is here.
Just sweating just isn't funny.
Yeah. Back of his neck is just,
the hairs is uncanny. So wet. I
just didn't like it. I'm gonna call,
I'm gonna call it wet to get,
get a look at this Guy Steve Kennedy.
Cause that's where every UFC fighters
body's going to look like after drug
testing becomes 100% implemented.
We're all going to look like steam shop.
I looked like Roy Nelson.
Damn Bro.
What do you want me to do?
Yo Dude fighter and the
kid.com shut the fuck up.
His marijuana considered a no,
you're good.
It's only the week of the fight. Yes. Oh
really? Yeah. Only the week of the fight.
So you can get caught smoking weed and
they're not going to touch you for weed
unless it's the weekend. Wow.
This is the question I have.
So you know how they say they're going
to test you five times throughout the
year.
So if I fight 3:00 AM I getting tested
eight or does that count as part as the
five? That's a good question.
That's a very good question.
I think they said five randoms throughout
the year, so it does it not count,
you know? I mean he's bummed me out.
One of the things bums me out is it,
this is going to cost a fuck
load of money to go after,
you know all these different guys for
using performance enhancing drugs.
The fighters that money I, that's
what I'm going to say. Sorry.
Yeah, it needs to be said,
man. It needs to be said.
Can you imagine if they started
drug testing and standup comedy?
What would happen?
They would make sure that you were on.
We'd then make sure you do it.
You get suspended.
If you weren't using cocaine and
marijuana matching your suspension,
Bro Plain you, they suspended you if you
smoke pot because it made you too funny.
It's definitely a performance
enhancing drug when it comes to comedy.
I write all my best shit on weed. By
the way, I got these new vape pens,
Goddamn to the pump. Dignity. Really? Who
makes a big fan of vape pens these days?
I don't know. Make some, I don't
read them. Start Smoking that shit.
You just open them up. Open them up.
Why don't you make your own fuck.
Other people don't want to get in that
business. That business is sneaky.
Like you gotta be real careful because
it's federally illegal and when you make
a shit ton of money and we're going to
come after you take it all away and if
you're like me and you like to talk a lot
of shit, some things he'd get up. Yeah,
I'm kidding.
People can get upset and they can find
the fact that get an example of you and
all that. Yeah. It's one thing if you'd
like to smoke a little weed personally,
that makes me feel,
but if you're selling it and making it,
then you don't need to. Yeah. You
don't need to get in that business.
It's also like a level of wealth that
I'm not sure you really want to get to.
I'm not sure you want to get to a level
of wealth where everyone knows your
worth $1 billion and you have to
drive around with fucking garbage.
Like whenever I look at
Lorenzo Fertitta and he has,
he's fucking former seals around them all
the time with earpieces Noz fuck cause
you gotta worry about
going to kidnap them.
I can take an eye answer
and being a sex slave,
the dudes that fucking guard
Lorenzo Fertitta or legit as fuck.
Yeah, you look in their eyes
and like these are dudes.
It will kill you with a pencil. 100%.
You, you know there's one, you're,
there's a service as a service. Whether
if you're going to do like a, I dunno,
something like climb mount Everest or do
some crazy fucking kayak trip or go to
Brazil.
You can,
you pay a monthly fee and they will pick
you up and rescue wherever you're at in
the world.
There's only a certain light,
they won't go to Syria and they
won't go to like Afghanistan.
But other than that,
anywhere in the world you're covered.
It's only like $175 a month
or some shit. Yeah. Good.
It's got to be way more than that. No, no,
no, it's not. It's only more than that.
If you're doing some like crazy shit
and you tell them ahead of time,
but so membership, so what do you have to
do it where Fr. RFID chip. No, check it.
You have to have one of those satellite
phones like those big ass satellite
phone, which a small price to pay a
pretty small. Now we used one one.
We're in Montana hunting. There's,
they're shrinking. What are we doing?
Another hunting trip. Let's schedule
it. What do you want to kill?
What do you want to let me
shoot some shit? Yeah. You
want to get in? Yeah. Okay.
You know we should get killed
my hands. We should. Oh Jesus.
He should all go to to hone ranch
and go shoot some pigs. All right,
because it's an hour and a half. That's
great. I don't eat swine, but I'm down.
No, I'm just kidding. I'll eat. I'll
eat some days. Well, they don't.
It's hard to get bacon because bacon
really comes from an animal that's been
overfed and fattened up. The
pigs eat. Oh, that guy's lit.
I'm not trying to eat a skinny plan. He's,
he's got his, he's not coming after him.
Yeah, he doesn't. His head goes up when
he gets thrown him. His Chin goes up,
but the pigs that you're going to get her,
you're going to be way leaner.
But the hams are fantastic. These pigs
in such good shape. I don't like that.
Wild as fuck. Now. All right.
Now this guy, red rash shorts.
He's going to knock this guy
out. Black. It's black as fuck.
I don't want to be no lag.
Pig may see a white.
Every now and then you see like a
white spotted one or around one,
but most of them are black. So you know
what the demonstrating you and me is.
I won't make them my pet. Bring
it home. I have pets are ready.
Thank you very much. You do have a
shitload of pets. I've got a few pets.
I got chickens, I got cats and
I'll shoot some shit or oral all.
I'll be like the dog he has won't need
one of those dogs. Those point 'em out.
I remember when I was doing Kirsty alleys,
TV show,
I went to her house and she had to
blind lemurs. She had a Shitload,
a Chinchillas who thousand dogs,
cats,
and she had a huge desert hair
in the middle of her lit bedroom.
It was fensten and it
couldn't use its back legs,
so it had to drag itself until you
show how rich you are to people.
How much random ass PECI.
That's me carrying a bear
out of the woods on my back.
That shot with a bow and
arrow. Damn, that is all man.
So mixed on that in Alberta.
I sat there that night.
Brittany, defendant has a
bond. You need to frame this.
Let me say that. That's
a 250 seat. I was there.
I'd be in the back and here's
Brennan tears. Just crying.
Terrified 100 yards through the woods,
over dead falls with that bear.
I'm as crazy. No one's got your shoulder.
Oh am I totally didn't get hurt.
How much did that thing way to 50 my
shoulder was hurt from more from is about
that bears your size motherfucker. For
real though, my shoulder was hurting.
Benching phase. I think benching is
really what I did. It just flat bench.
Very young shoulders.
Is that right?
Inclined bench man or dumped just a well
Subotica got the rear naked and one arm
trapped. Wow. Oh this is
over because it's a crank.
He's turning away from the choke,
which is,
you know as long as you could
really pin your neck down.
It's a real crank right now though. That
shit. He's pretty map. He's fine now.
He's more wrapped up now. He's more
wrapped up. Good position on that page.
I love that body triangle, man.
That body triangle is so good.
See I did not in MMA because how are you
get, what are you going to transition?
A blue belt can defend the rear naked
choke with those giant gloves on so we
feel body triangle can't transition
anytime. You can really SAP a guys will.
I agree. You can control your breathing,
especially if you go belly down. Yeah.
If you could turn that guy and get them
belly down with that body triangle. God,
that's so nasty.
He gets it like Ken shamrock and now
Peter [inaudible] bad mother fucker Dean
list or in his corner that day and you
know that motherfucker can't choke wrong.
Dean lister had been looking for
his neck for the past six years.
It's just find it. It's just
head, shoulders. He's his thing,
man. I met him at the metaphors. I
couldn't believe how thick he was.
Shy Has Josh Barnett tapped him?
How about Josh Barnett tapped
him to talk to your boy. He,
Ron Dude Barnett Barnett,
other the best catch wrestler of all time.
All time.
Really so impressive that it was better.
He tapped dean lister and any tap here,
dean. He tapped d. First of all,
people say Dean listers never been
tapped out in training and he's 16 years,
never been tapped out in training.
He's never been tapped out and cognition.
Fucking ed, he got tapped with like
of headaches, the neck crank, crank.
He got him in that judo headlock.
Fuck. It's silent Trojan motherfucker.
See his next fight. Who was he
fighting? Roy Nelson. Japan son. Ooh,
I like it. I'm not going to fight that
or UFC like it. What'd you just say?
Not Ufc or US close. Once you
grab some bench, take a break.
What are you talking about? To
understand what the sport, I mean,
fuck the UFC guys. I don't
know. Look at Dean lister.
I can't believe you've never been
tapped in practice even. That's cool.
Josh Martin. I said, oh, that's cool.
Check this out. That was a slick move.
You see the way he set that,
that a rear naked up we, he,
he made them defend one arm to sy.
Set them up for the second one.
He turned away from the one
arm into the second arm.
So Baba knows what the
fuck he's doing with that.
He like it almost like he fed them the
one arm so that he would turn away from
it and then slip the second one under
the chin. I'm not mad at that shirt.
Very nice. Here's a little tip. See, I
saw giggle. I don't take heat for this,
but bear with me here. When
Daniel Cormier, I saw him,
he's The new light heavyweight champion,
right?
And UFC selling his shirts and
then as soon as July 1st kicks in,
Reebok's going to design the
shirts. If I'm Daniel Cormier, oh,
I'm Conor McGregor or Ronda Rousey,
one of these mega stars,
why won't you have your own website and
create your own shirts and sell the fuck
out of them,
reap all your own benefits and that you're
speaking like a businessman. You're,
you're a smart dude and you have the
ambition to do that kind of stuff.
But a lot of guys don't. They just
hire someone to do it. You're right,
you're right. How about
you? Why don't you do it?
Maybe that's a good side business for you.
I don't know.
I mean I would get my own shit.
Fucking savage.
You got a little too much going on selling
about 8,000 t shirts and 20 minutes.
I always text you right away like Joe,
check it out.
They'll put up these shirts for
sale and self souses in minutes.
And I'm like thinking about the numbers,
I was just plus expenses. Holy Shit.
That's real legit money and
nothing gets me more excited. Oh,
it's when they sell. I'm literally
jumping around sweating. Well,
when I was at Brian's,
I'm taping.
The fucking audience was
filled with your tee shirts.
Everything was fighter and the kid.
I think you'd be surprised.
There's so many different shirts. Crazy
audience is amazing. It's really cool.
He shot like fourth one's drop in our
show. Dope. I love what you're wearing.
An American flag type shit.
Red, white and blue tank.
And then we've got the master Kim shirt,
but in red, white and blue. It's so dope.
I'm like, awesome. Yeah. Anyways.
Ooh. He handed it to her. I cooking.
I'll tell him you did y'all.
I need some fucking priming Joe Rogan
shirts. I'm always rocking my winter.
I kind of, I gotta be honest. I feel
like a tool rocked in my own shit.
I know what you mean. That's what I'm
saying. You never seen me wear my shirts,
nor do I even talk about them.
That's a real problem.
I have a Goddamn tee shirt company and
I never had to advertise it like three
times. But you do well with it. It makes
great money. When I was talking to you,
it goes all the time. I didn't
even, I didn't even know
he sold shirts. I was like,
what you gotta do bro? You got to
do this. You're like, motherfucker,
I've been selling shirts
forever. I'm like, Oh really?
Regina has a pretty boxer.
She wished she can't box.
He's got teeth. Fuck
yeah, guys, your boxes.
Fat did badly care. I love athletes. Oh,
I sure would show her a good time.
Right guys I share with you guys.
What's her? She pulls her pussy
lips apart and brushes her teeth.
She gets a fucking one of those
little waterpiks down there.
Ah Man. I'll tell you what the struggle
is real with girl. What is her name?
Regina is, it is so real. I love
girls, man. It's a fucking curse.
Well, they're better than dudes when
it comes to having sex with them.
You got to do what you got to do. They
don't. There's a reason opposites attract.
Right. They don't look like you see it
at what point? I just attracted to one.
You know what I'm saying?
Fucking curse. You feel me? Yeah.
That's problem to being attracted
to one. It's very difficult. Yeah.
I love all different kinds of women.
There's also,
then there's also the problem
of just getting along. You know,
everybody has a fucking
different sensibility, man.
Men and women see thinks so goddamn
differently. Different goals,
truly different needs, different think
different things that pissed them off.
You know what hurts my feelings is
girls that I've dated before, we've,
we dated for years, even lived together
and now just cause whatever. We're not,
you know, still intimate in
relationship. We're not friends anymore,
but you just get us thinking
about the time you've not wasted,
but you spent all those years together. To
me, I'm like, no, let's still be friends,
but they can't do it, man. Some of them
can't be. But you can eat the arms. Yeah,
because he used to send it in there and
shoot loads inside their body and they
loved it around you in the man I love
you and they feel your back wall of the
path.
They feel that crease where the spine
is and the the muscles wrap around the
valley cause muscle valley
shop does that thing where he lies on
his back and he puts the weight bar here
and he does those fuck exercises
load that puts them up on Instagram.
400 pounds.
One more set. One more.
One more Rep. Meanwhile,
Rampage's trainer I follow
Rampage's his trainer on Instagram.
It's a woman with an ass created by God.
What's the name please?
Juliet something or another? I
don't know her name. Oh good.
Well I mean I guess she's only
doing squats for houses. Retarded,
retarded and she does 400
pounds at that exercise.
That same exercises you overdose of it.
Videos of it. Undeniable. The face though,
she's pretty, she's not ugly at all.
She's pretty, but it, you don't even care.
I'm going to slip on the heard them.
Dean thinks she's married and she
has children that had been there.
Her ass is ridiculous. It's ridiculous.
But she does that same thing.
She has like a yoga mat that she uh,
has rolled up next to the bench so she
could pull it up here and she puts her
elbows on the bench cause
she can't get under it.
Like she's not as strong as you to get
under it. But once she gets under it,
it's on, let me find it. I'll find it for
you. Yeah, that's fine. That the shell.
Yeah. I get dead serious. I'm like,
I should be on Instagram and you'll see
a girl's ass and I'll be like, God damn,
I don't care where I'm at. You
just, it's like so frustrating.
It's like seeing a dope ass car.
Exactly.
And then I'll go to their fucking webpage
or I'll go to their Instagram page and
you find out that they have 7
million followers can all it is,
is pictures of their ass girls get way
more followers on Instagram than they do
is look up there. Yeah. That's
her find the one when she's doing,
find the one when she's doing
that. A, that's a strong gal.
That critter got to shit or honor. Oh
yeah, sure. You gotta wait, check Jamie.
Find the one where she's in
there doing the, the fucking, oh,
that's rampages.
Well,
she's got a page. What does
it said, Juliet? What? Yeah,
but I'm telling you that she has a page.
So what is it?
What does that say that they had
at Juliet Lynn 82. All right.
I'll find it. Hold on the
sheet. She's not that. Don't,
this is going to be interesting.
There's nothing better than a nice ass.
Hudson was this cat is this
Seaver and Jerry are ready.
That's the cove Maine. How the
fuck is that happening? Are Ready.
This is a short night.
It's a great deal of,
Ooh.
How about that Forman Bella
tour tournament coming up
in September. I know, right?
What is that? It's uh, who
is it? It's a saw king,
Mo and filled day manual.
Newton King Mo. Phil Davis.
And he's the last guy or the fourth guy?
Yeah, he's a baldheaded. One night. Well,
one night, right? Yeah. They're
all fighting one night. Yeah.
Four man tournament in one night.
God Damn you Scott Coker.
You Genius Bella Tours
trying some experiments. Huh?
I'm not mad at to mix it up cause you
gotta do some cause you're not going to
give with the UFC count
for towel tell you this,
the front patio or the
comedy store last night,
everybody was waiting for that shamrock.
Everyone loves Kimbo man.
And it garnered attention and you know,
I don't see the UFC up on that TV
as much at like, I mean that often,
but you know that gets, that gets a
different crowd watching for sure.
You know what I mean? I agree. I
think they're doing it. Smart man.
I've never even really seen Bella
tour in the past like year until,
uh, until last night and I was really
surprised about those WWF engines.
It's fun though, Huh? Yeah. They're not
quite doing it right? I don't think so.
We'll see you Mickey.
It is and I don't think they see what
works about the WWF sentences that they're
not doing. Like it's cool the production
value but a little too much. Right.
It's Corny as fuck.
Have the guys walking in and fight.
It's not sense the entertainment.
It's not though don't it is. I think
the UFC came to the right conclusion.
They taught about it and they said,
you know what? We can get more seats.
We could sit more people in here
without this. They're really great.
Seats are important to get rid of this
ramp and plus we're spending all this
money on pyrotechnics and shit for what
and then they decide to be awesome.
I don't think it's awesome, man.
I don't, I think the UFC is more,
it's looked more as a legit sway,
more towards more of a spectacle
but it sure, okay, what do you do?
You can go talent for talent. Do you
see this is what you do. You Poach.
What bell torn needs to do is do some
of that Goddamn Viacom money and take
advantage of this, this
route. Reebok thing,
this Reebok thing that has a lot of
fighters that are going to lose a shitload
of money. Here she is. Look
at this. Come on, son. Wow.
Fuck did I say wow girls, no joke. There's
a bunch of videos of her doing that.
She, she's letting you
know, man. She's t man. Oh,
I would do serious things to her.
No,
you would fuck the shit out of [inaudible]
and she would open up a window and
shoot it and trash guy with her pussy.
She would pull her dick off,
pull your dick off with her vagina and
this guy opened up the window sticker
pussy. Tanium she'd kill a
bird with it. She's in. Shit.
I'm going to start doing now is what does
access. I've got to start doing that.
What's the benefit of that exercise?
Work your ass, hips and glutes.
It gets you ready to fuck fat shall
be good for your sprawl, right? Yeah.
Great for your sprawl. Good. Good for
hip mobility or look at that booty.
Look at that booty. Yeah.
It's a ridiculous booty. No,
no, no. Go down. Scroll down.
Look at that. Why did Jesus Christ?
That's good, but it's black.
It's hard to see because of the blackness.
Scroll down a little.
There's one little further,
little further. She gets it.
She gets up tickle biddies to that.
That is a fucking validify booty and
I'm not mad at that. Good for her.
Congratulations on your wonderful body.
Congrats. Yeah. Oh, she
trains hard. Well, she's,
rampage is a strength and conditioning
trainer. I guess. Rampage has a gym. Yeah,
he does. Right. And a Orange County? Yeah.
What does it's called like Rampage's
fitness or something like rampage for him.
Good for him.
I'm glad he's invested his money.
He's still dealing with that litigation
bullshit, right? With belter? Yup.
What is that about?
Bella tours signed him and then
they violated their contracts.
So the judge released him.
They put an injunction. Judge,
Judge List lifted the injunction.
He fought for the UFC.
Everybody loved him. Fought
Fabio Maldonado. Great fight.
And then they got a new injunction and
so there's a new legal issue going on at
the table. What? They had to
release his contract. Revelatory.
That thing was Beastie. Yeah.
He's making a lot of money.
Are you allowed to hang a banner if,
if, if you're under the Reebok deal,
can you hang a banner? He
came to that sober. Wow.
Not only that you have to wear Reebok
closed the entire week of fight cannon.
He yells, show up and fight when
Reebok pumps. Oh my God. Wow.
Um, you know what man, forcing
me to get her Bible. Ted,
it's an open Barb wire run
your bicep fucking tramp stamp.
I'd rather just get a Reebok trance.
Then we're rebounding nineties tattoos.
The um,
the thing about it is that it's opening
up the door for belter in a big way.
If they can show that they can come up
with a lot of money for you in a contract
and let you get your own sponsors
like the way it used to be,
they'll change the fucking game because
all you need is a few of those guys jump
over. Davis was the first
man. Yeah. But Phil, he was a,
from all due respect, Phil was a
free agent. With all due respect.
Phil was not really a threat for
the title. It's just not, you know,
you watch the Anthony Rumble
Johnson beat him up. It's,
it's hard and Jon Jones is going
to see Ryan Bader beat him.
It's like, I don't know. I mean he could
beat Machida and he beat Gustafsson.
He did. He did. But he beat Gustafsson
very early in his career. My submission.
It's true. And that when a guy
named Sheila with beat Glover tech,
he said he'd be wrangled him a cheeto
did and clover clover trained for that
Shit and Connecticut and his backyard.
I'm just saying literally beats it.
I know he did. He but he beat
some top top guys. Don't look.
Phil Davis is a tough guy,
but no one thinks of him.
The way they think about rumble over.
They think about Daniel that
like he might be, you know,
is a real shot at the title.
So him going over to bell tours,
not the biggest loss you're saying
we need like, exactly. Exactly.
Word Aldo went over to Bella tour.
How about this?
I'll go and Borow of Henan Borow how bout
if Hanan Barao Beats Tj Dillashaw and
then goes over to belt or,
I mean that's craziness.
If they get a few guys
like that and by the way,
they have fucking that
fucking pretracheal pit bull.
Did you see that fight last night and
came back, came back and CalEd them.
That was a wild ass fucking advice. Now
I saw some good spots with a belt tour.
Violence.
See like any powerhouse
sponsors. I'm surprised that
everyone's not jumping the train yet.
They need more numbers, you know.
And the last thing, he's good. Yeah,
I'm sure it was.
They need to bail on that fucking name.
Bella tours a stupid name. Yeah, I'm not
a fan of it. What does ballot tour mean?
It's like like warrior and Latin or
using a dead language about that tour.
I don't know.
Let's find out cause I'm talking shit.
I don't really know what the
actual name for sure. Switch it up.
There'll be a little more professional.
It should be spike MMA. I just like,
just like, you know, showtime has
showtime boxing. Hbo Is Hbo Boxing,
MMA. Viacom fighting. What?
Make it more professional, man.
It. What is the name? Good.
That's an interesting senior way. What I
was right. Brandon, what do we do here?
Okay. It's warrior in
Latin. Dennis Seaver,
but it's hard for to Seaver
to fucking get motivated.
After Connor Mcgregor stole his soul.
You see that fight in Boston?
He looks so slow. You need
to see walks so slow. Crazy.
Mcgregor walked him down and beat the fuck
out of him. I know you can't pick Joe,
but uh, Tony, Brian, honey. See Connor,
I chose a hick kind of go there.
I,
he doesn't know. There's no
idea. I mean, if I had to really,
if I had to really put you on the other
line, if I had to put money on it,
I would put,
I would put money on,
on Connor because I feel like there's so
much momentum and he has so much belief
and I feel in some ways maybe he's
inside Josias had, can I, can I do,
can I help you out here? So you
think he has more belief than Josie?
It guy was at Lawson did nine years. 10
pound best in the world. 10 year, 10 now.
Yeah. Yeah. A little bit
more belief than Josie.
Elder look at Aldo has
massive belief in himself,
so don't question not better camp.
All those beaten.
Everybody they put in front of them.
Here's the best leg kicks maybe in
the world and now he's motive MMA.
His leg kicks us.
So God damn fast and nasty professional
level soccer player and he has that
ridiculous fucking hip snap because of
that. Some of the best takedown defense.
Spectacular.
The only thing about Aldo is he's had a
lot of fights and he's had a lot of wars
in the gym.
A lot of like tough rounds in fighting.
You know that last Chad Mendez fight was
probably the toughest fight he's ever
had inside the octagon. True
Mendez cracked him man to
man his punishment. Yeah.
Men has hit him. Some bombs and
men has can hit fucking hard man.
You see that Ricardo Lamas fight.
You see the hardest hit her
in that division by farm
and he cautioned and Josie
Aldo took that and still what he says he
did twice and I'll go drop them in that
first round sort of illegal cause.
Kind of like after the above is tough.
The crack a little loud.
She had caught Connor's taller and I
feel like his hands are probably better.
Well, he's never fought anybody
remotely as good as all doses,
not even close level of competition.
Now that's true.
If I'm putting money on it in Vegas,
yeah, I'm going to Jose Aldo all day,
but personally for the UFC,
since I'm team UFC,
I want Connor to win.
If Connor wins,
he's the biggest star of the
UFC is the habit of Aldo wins.
It shows everybody what a fucking monster
they'd been sleeping on it. Yeah. Right.
But then what do you do with Khan
announced a gimmick. We built,
he rebuilds depends on how he loses.
Here's my thing.
I think it's brilliant that they have
Connor fighting Aldo right away like this,
because the reality is we have
not seen Conor fight a wrestler.
If you see Conor in there with a Frankie
Edgar Connor in the air with the Chad,
tough favor. Never. No,
ma'am. Wrestlers can be a bit,
you never know what they could do to him.
You never know if they could
take him down at smother him.
Look at the way Frankie Edgar stole cubs.
Watson's fucking Amil just stole it.
Asher body. They don't want
that cause that Clay Guido,
Anthony Pettis,
remember that you don't want that.
And that's what [inaudible]
did to him to this. Exactly.
But does on with better stand
up. Yes. So, but the thing is,
it's going to be rough for Connor. As
long as he makes it a fight, we're good.
If he goes in and gets fucking
dismantled, then it's like, oh my God,
this shit talking. It's embarrassing.
He's so big and so strong.
I don't think he's going to get
dismantled, but I think it's a fight, man.
It's a fucking hell of a fight.
I think Connor has gotten
a little too confident.
I think he's wearing sunglasses indoors
and shit now his thing or the show
wrestling fan,
but most of those guys come in and
sunglasses when after they have the belt,
he's wearing the sunglasses indoors
before the belt. You gotta wait,
you gotta pay your dues.
He's almost back to sunglasses.
That's why mentality and it's going
to ruin this whole fight podcast.
I'll do you bring this up. We'll shoot
it. How agiri on top with Dennis.
He re look at this,
but it's not pro wrestling.
It's high school wrestling
that I'm talking about here
because I think I'll does
going to do to macgregor.
What core me did the Johnson all
not a wrestler on that level though.
Does that Jujitsu guys a big difference
between wrestling and he's going to try
to knock them out. You're bat
shit. You're bat shit crazy though.
If you think it gets into grappling match
at is not going to get taken down or
out Jujitsu. I believe that all those
Jujitsu is so fucking underrated.
Is that goodwill class,
that world class he beat Cabrina.
Oh,
shut the fuck up. Police guys.
He's guys, I'm sorry. He's beaten.
Worldclass black belts. Let's just say
that in straight Jujitsu concentration.
Jujitsu. He's, he's elite. I
mean when you watch a movie,
you watch his Mike Brown fight. When
you fought Mike Brown for the WEC title,
he takes his back like a ghost gets those
hooks in and just [inaudible] you're
going know when you're a kid. Second
on your mom's titty. He was an ag.
That's how long he's been doing.
Shit. Big Difference. Accurate.
But he's been doing it a while.
My man, well he's explosion his,
his speed with those who kicks and
punches men older than me of the others.
63 years old. No, you are a motherfucker.
Look at Seavers busted up cow. Caligiuri
yeah, that's a great photo. You Dennis.
He runs a guy where I was talking,
I was doing this interview
with Crooklyn Stephie from,
cause she's with bloody elbows. I would
you do like regular interviews with her.
She's my friend.
Um,
but we were talking about
Ken shamrock and Kimbo
they were,
they were on this pro ped rat and they
got cut off because both of them were
basically like, who gives a fuck?
Why don't you steroids you steroids.
I'm thinking, why can't guys
like make an agreement? Like if,
say like,
you know,
if you got like Vitor Belfort and whoever
and they made an agreement to be able
to use whatever the fuck they wanted.
And you know, you're both saying like,
can canon chemos proof example
41 and 51 super suspect if,
and they fought in Missouri,
so did Bobby Lashley and Bobby,
then Bobby Lashley always fights and
these strange places with fucking soup
propped up athletic
commissions. Yeah, I mean,
I just think that there's not nothing
wrong with making an agreement like that.
Well, you know what's weird to me
is like, you look at other sports,
like in baseball, if you get tested,
if he testifies for steroids,
your show fuck no hall of fame, you get
booed ever. We go look at Barry Bonds,
Alex Rodriguez, right? And
then sending all these records,
if you get caught in the, in
the UFC, you're kind of fucked.
You look at a guy like Rothko who
got caught or Alistair Overeem,
then they fight. Everyone kind of forgets.
It's whatever. You get cotton football,
it's not a big deal. It's weird to me,
man. It's weird how we baseball's America.
It's weird though. America's
not change. Damn it.
And you don't need to understand in your
mouth once a year looking all fucking
Eurasian.
Oh look at all brown brown.
I just think society needs to
be consistent. It shouldn't
matter. Right? Like if,
cause baseball's a weird one man,
because it's like who gives a fuck? No,
you're batting the ball.
Bat speed.
You can keep playing and all up
into your thirties and no shit.
I want to see home runs.
I want them jacked on steroids to the
gills and crush and balls. Yeah, exactly.
Like Sammy Sosa.
Mcgwire how dope was that?
That was the only time that people
were excited. Yeah. Felt deflated.
There's this weird old as well. How
about Sammy Sosa turn into a white guy?
What the fuck happened?
Michael Jackson's super crazy.
I think in the collegiate to skin or
something. It's like a gray color.
It's weird. It's dead. Yeah. He
looks like it was like a corpse.
It's just so weird how
the society bring up Sam.
He says that when he first went into the
league and when and when he was two 40
it's the difference is ridiculous.
Oh Martin. When we get my was wire,
he was giant. He had the fucking
Paul boomer arms, thighs,
forums where show Jen my thighs
with a hand at the end of it.
That's what I want. Like Tony, you love
fucking bullshit wrestling pro lesson.
You love that fake wrestling.
Now think if the drug test it was like,
do you have seen they're all skinny?
Is it as cool now you watch pro wrestling
cause are these characters they they
look like superheroes. We'll see. I'm
takeaway drug tests and see second,
here's a bad example,
Doug cm punk is one of the
biggest wrestlers in the
world and he's 100% clean.
He's the exception.
But,
but there's a went through at UFC
is going through back in that hall
Cogan thing in the late mid,
mid, early nineties. It was huge.
And so they had to eliminate it. They
had to, they have to do it themselves.
They have like a super strict parole
say burrow. I'm serious. Super strict.
And tell me, but Tiesta and the rock
are clean. No, watch your words sir.
Come on. The Rock. The rocks on steroids.
This is Tony.
You weigh six pounds and you're talking
about a guy who is an immense super app
is probably about two 60 is Brock Lesnar
on steroids. Of course they're all,
they've all done something.
They've all done. Brock Lesnar,
first of all has superior genetics.
There'll be the phrase
structure that that guy has.
You can go back to when Brock
Lesnar was in high school,
he was a fucking monster.
He benched two 25 49 times.
Yes. 49 we can see is Columbine is
calm down. My numbers are stupid.
Combined numbers are through the roof.
His vertical is insane.
Polite Brock Lesnar's combine numbers.
Jamie,
all that said he got shitted on when
we get to the NFL, they made fun of it,
wasn't ready for it and
he was playing football.
He's been doing wrestling fruits.
Brock Lesnar's the super freak,
but back to bullshit wrestling.
You don't think these guys cause pink
color schedules to their schedule is
fucking insane.
Night.
You're not eating protein shakes and
staying on that schedule. My mandate,
the Piss on your sport or
your entertainment. I mean,
well those guys are constantly not
getting enough sleep and it's a brutal,
brutal schedule. You talked to Tony
who's in that business. It's brutal, man.
And after, a lot of times they
have to pay for themselves.
You have to own rent cars
and then bill the company.
It's a brutal circus of shit.
Totally.
You think triple h is
a fucking called clean.
You don't get a neck like I an east.
I don't know what triple h is doing.
I that's, that's an interesting
one. I mean, he's a fucking monster.
He shaped weird. What about Battista?
Dude, look, Patista is the word.
I don't even acknowledge that Battista
was ever even in pro. He's so,
he's so terrible. What are you
talking about? He was great.
And Guardians of the galaxy.
Phenomenal. Oh, Europe mess. No.
How dare you now the guardians of the
galaxy disappointing to watch him talking.
Shit. That movie was great.
Spotlight. You're out of your mind.
What's a good movie? Mad Max was great
but didn't see it. I heard it was awesome.
We're going to fucking love it. You know
what? Too much action. You know it's dope.
Dude did I didn't see until this weekend
when I was flying back from Mexico.
John Wick, the Keanu Reeves movie,
the action will be replaced.
They kill his dog and he goes and
kills everybody. Really? Oh Hon.
They kill his dog. So he goes, no, no,
no. I'm not doing it. Justice. Revenge.
They kill cells. Combine numbers. It's a
fucking phenomenal movie they're doing.
John Wick to look at is 44
seven 40 by the way, 283 pounds.
Four seven 40 35 inch vertical jump,
long jump,
10 feet standing,
jump,
10 feet bench press to 25 to 30 reps.
Jesus fucking Christ,
a running back,
living in the body of a defensive end.
It's ridiculous. He's an ease of free.
I gotta be honest, especially when he
did do that as a number of years ago.
Now that's not that freakish.
Yeah, really, really.
But you got to think about
if some fucking freaks.
Now this isn't something
he was training for. No,
this isn't the guy that was moving towards
towards being a pro fungicide to do
it. Brock Lesnar's is the biggest freak
the UFC has ever seen, ever, ever.
Hands down if Brock are
dicks off right now,
if Brock Lesnar had the right coach,
like if he went to a mat,
not saying there's anything wrong
with his coaches, this is what I'm,
what I'm saying is if he had the
right coach the right amount of time,
like if you went to a Matt Hume
or a Foracia hobby and they,
they engineered his career
from the beginning to the
time he's being introduced
to the UFC to the time he's
introduced to high level competition.
He could have been an all
time. Yes. Paul's heavyweight,
the capabilities he fought a former
heavyweight champion and his second
professional fight,
he fought Frank Mir and his second
professional fight had no idea as a defend
against the leg lock. He got leg locked
mass. My favorite fighter of all time.
Great fight.
Frank Mir is a bad motherfucker,
but then in his third fight after that
he fights heath herring beats the shit
out of heath.
Herring.
Then he fights Randy fucking coture
stops Randy coture and his fourth
professional fucking fights.
Yeah.
But Randy couture was like
stuck in a wheelchair.
Does or octagon and fucking Brock
Lesnar still. It doesn't matter.
He's still for the foreign
professional fight.
Insanely impressive what he's done in
his career, man. Shane in his prime. Yes.
He James in his prime.
He got fucked out.
There's Shane rocked and after Shane had
a shit where they could have stopped it,
let's be easily,
could've stopped it easily.
Good thing they did it because he
came back and one that's came back and
strangle them. Look, Brock Lesnar,
I mean he had no business
fighting Allister after he
came back from that surgery.
He had no business fighting Kane.
He just was not on that level.
But if he learned to get on that
level, it's all those guys. He beats,
although he has more talent than all
those guys, all those guys. And, uh,
but he doesn't like to get hit dude ass
pat Barry when he was in his training
camp and pap it, you know, they brought
Pat Barry and before he fought someone,
I forget in Pat,
moved out there and was in Minnesota
and he said he'd only train like three,
two or three times a week and they were
sparring and Pat, you know, pat goes hard.
I was a train part of mine for years.
Peck is really hard. He's a beast man.
He's a beast. Stand up,
terrible ground. Anyways,
so he fucking hits Brock and I
guess Brock freaks the fuck out.
And his coaches were like, what the
fuck are you doing? And path like,
what do you mean? Like don't fucking
hit Brock in the faith. That was like,
what the fuck am I doing here then?
And they're like, you just Paul Man,
just feel it out. What? Yeah, I'm
pals. Like this is some bullshit.
They weren't hitting him,
but that's [inaudible] great
story. Well that's weird.
Him Training with Brock.
I had heard conflicting stories.
I had heard that that's not true.
Hmm.
So I'm going to have to do a fight night
without you guys. I'm very sad. No Way.
Next weekend. No Man. Saturday
night fucking bullshit.
And my boy Leo does fighting to Cindy.
You don't have to be there with him.
You come with me. He does. He needs.
Why? What's it for without me?
He gets lost and I think
he does well with our dog.
Maybe this bet. No, no, no.
That's not true. Where's
Brian? I'm depressed. His head.
Hags hello my boy. Leo's fighting. I
was just with him last week. Tiny man.
He looks great. Does he?
Looks Great. Does he great.
What was going on with him entering into
that Rockhold fight. This is a second.
Whoa. That's a tight guillotine. He had
the right knee was more important
than even the choke fine. 100%. Yeah.
Getting that right knee up and over.
It was more important.
Position over submission. This
are right. That's fucking great.
Kenny. As a position over
submission. First of all, defense.
I am always safe. Leo said in
that Rockhold fight, he had,
um,
in exchange got hit in the back of the
head and he was out of sorts then sort of,
he said it was in illegal shot.
I completely disagree.
I watched the elbow land
Atlanta to the side of the head.
It was a ruthless was fucking
elbow that Rockhold hit him with,
but Rockhold had already had his back,
was already beaten them up.
Rockhold had them on the ground and
Machita didn't look good physically.
He looked different physically.
He looks soft. I agree.
A hundred percent rock called
he's gonna fight widened, right.
Rockhold is going to fight Weidman and
that's a fucking motherfucker of a file.
Real quick. Best fight in
middleweight history. Naval
battling could be maybe him,
uh, Anderson versus Weidman might be
the only other fighter that's old school
Anderson, but Anderson, the first
by Anderson is prime Anderson.
The first fight versus Weidman. We
didn't know that it was over and I know,
but we found out really quick. Well,
we only found out because he fucked up.
If Anderson didn't fuck up Anderson
escape from the knee. Need Bar,
right escape from the leg lock attempt
by Weidmann and was beating Weidman
standing up before he's clowning around
and trying to goad Weidman into an
exchange so he could,
you know,
he could counter attacks and I'm standing
up because he's making such a joke of
kicking the shit. Punched him in the
face. He was not punching in the face. No,
it was not. Well, he
barely hit him in the face.
He didn't like kids
through a lot of leg kicks.
And it was the first thing that John
Danaher said to me when I went into the
corner, John Donner, her said, uh, I said,
congratulations after Wyman. Beat him.
Donna is such a fucking wizard.
The first thing that it was mine,
I don't like how many times he was
getting hit with those leg kicks.
He was the first thing out of his mouth.
It's like the guy just won the
middleweight championship of the world.
Knocked out. Anderson Silva
was a great coach. Exactly. Um,
I just think you have two fighters in
there. Very, very prime, right? Like,
yeah. Rockhold had to slip up where
he got his fucking, I kicked out by,
by Vito juiced up Vitorin Brazil. Right.
Other than that, he's a mother fucker.
You have Weidman is prime.
You have Rockland is prime.
It's rare. We see this man.
Yeah.
To me it's the best vitamin weight history
if not one of the best fights in UFC
history. I would agree. I would agree
with that. I think, I think Brock,
Shane's better. I think that's a
bigger fight. But other than that,
I think what's meager five because it's
the heavyweights settles most important
title Troy,
but,
and those are also two true heavyweights
who brought some shit to the octagon.
Right? Like canes to a tough sell man
because he doesn't look in posing.
Right. He doesn't really talk. He just
wants to wrestle and fucking chill. Right?
I don't think so.
I think you've Cain was more active and
he hadn't been injured and you just run
it through the division like he was
when he was in his prime before.
Like this two year layoff.
If you look at the cane that beat up
junior dos Santos and the second and third
fights,
if you'll get the cane that stormed
through Ben Rothwell that's old school,
but that cane if he had
was like more active,
he'd be like Canelo Alvarez.
He be fucking huge.
It's just tough to sell him when he's
on the shelf for two months or two years
rather than me.
But think about when Brock Brock fucking
Lesnar the WWE crowd and then he had
the UFC crowds sold and he's being
bitches up former champs frank.
When you heat up in the air and you
could tour, you know what I'm saying?
It's insane. When he beat up mirror and
stop destroyed, his face smashed his face.
He's the biggest star of the UFC has
ever had. And then you have Shane Carwyn.
Remember Shane just got
done beating the brakes off.
Mayor knocked out Gonzaga
and all knockouts. Mgm Grand,
biggest heavyweight, 12 time
in UFC. That's the biggest
fight in UFC history. Yeah,
no, I just think Rockhold and
Weidman is a dope, dope fight man.
What was also the biggest paper view card
ever is also, it was UFC 100 of course.
So it was a big event and you know,
it was a lot of shyness and a UFC 100 oh,
that's right. I'm
thinking of mirror. Yeah.
You're thinking of Mayor Brock and Shane
was UFC one 16 at Mgm Grand One 16 one
16 because I fought rusher on that.
There's your boy pat. Yeah, there it is.
We've got to have him tell us the story
of training with Brock Lesnar MMA record
three and two of that stuff.
Um, yeah. Interesting. Yeah.
Brock does crazy stuff in the WWF that
seems in human that other wrestlers have
never been able to do.
Skylar asked me, sir,
don't bring in Dodo events. Keep
bringing it up. Is The guy there?
He has 69 he's 70 that's
natural. Totally natural. No one,
no one has ever looked like that at 69
if you'd quit bullshit and get on TRT,
that could be you.
That thinks 21 years older than me.
22 years old out of them.
It's insane. Richie Shit,
which is shit muscular tits.
Great market and love it and crazy.
Ooh, look at this. Is Dick's
probably hard all day long.
He destroys on Mcgregor.
Conor McGregor.
I comb that.
I come from the show.
I said on, I spoke, I spoke my
country's name and my native tongue.
I said, ed, I'll tell you what.
That's what I can't wait to hear those
Irish and Brazilian chance going back and
forth can be outside.
She can't
wait to hear is the sound of head kicks
from the crowd as fucking giant Broccoli.
I wanted to shoot my myself like a
lightning bolt through his chest.
Let's you sounded Scottish while he's
looking back is actually from Scott,
but you're ruining the new tattoo.
The tiger on his stomach fucked up when
I set of apps like that and you cover it
with that bullshit and it's such good
work. It looks like a three d image.
Look at him. Although Scarface, Scarface,
bad, he's a bad motherfucker. People
got to educate themselves on all though,
man. I mean he's no joke and
mother Fucker, he's no joke.
Any, any of motivation. Not
that he doesn't. Anyways,
but now he's talking all this shit.
Like I said, I'm a Connor fan though.
How can you not be man?
What he's done for the story's crazy.
Did you see how all those brought in the
jungle fight guy? Be a [inaudible] know.
How do you say the Bald Guy Bill? How
would he know? No. Pull up a video.
Josie Aldo brings in Jonah's bill hotard
hene hole does not know how to say
that.
Say the dude's name,
but the point is the dude who we
brought in can emulate Connor perfectly.
He's built like Connor and he's a
beat. He does. He move like tunnel.
That's the different, he's good dude.
He's good. Yeah, you got to see this guy.
First of all, pull up, pull
up a highlight reel, pull out,
pull up a highlight reel for
Jonah's jungle fight champ. Jonah's,
B. I. L. H. A. R. I. N. H. O. O.
I've seen this dude fight before.
He's a bad motherfucker.
He fights one 45 and he fights
the same style that Connor does.
A fuck isn't any in the UFC. He will
be eventually. He's a beast. I mean,
he's got a, he's got a contract with
jungle fight. He's was champ. You know,
it's a big Brazilian organization's
trouble for Connor though.
If he found someone to mimic that style.
Well that's the issue with Connor.
Watch this cat. This cat's good dude. Look
at Bill Marino. This is him because his,
they call them speed,
but watch how this guy moves around.
He moves around exactly the
Connor and he fights southpaw.
Watch how this mother fucker fights. Look
at this. He looks just like, oh, he's,
she's wicked. He's wicked
dude. He's wicked tail.
He's got nasty kicks.
He's a real good striker and
he's got a vicious look at that.
Look at that fucking switch. Kick to the
head, Dude. He's built just like Connor.
You exactly. He moves like Connor
to look at this motherfucker. Ooh,
he's good. His kicks are
better than Connor's. How
about that? He hurts dudes too,
man. He's good. Damn Bill.
If Reno's no joke man,
strictly please stand up, huh?
No, he's, he's an MMA champ.
He's nasty dude. Look at him. He's no
joke. Okay, so this is the guy moves.
Exactly. This is the guy that Connor's
bringing it and a lot of local cobra.
Look at the,
I know is better than Connor.
A lot of people think that he
could beat Conor in an MMA fight.
Fucking looks good,
man.
Man. Look at this fucking movement.
He's no joke. That's straight left.
Does he have any losses?
Ah, I don't know man.
I know what his record is cause I mean
obviously it's a highlight. So yeah,
he's a bad motherfucker, but well, you
know, look, he's, he moves just like him.
He looks exactly like him. There couldn't
be a better trainer, but he's nasty.
I wonder how he's lost.
He's even wearing his hair like
Connor and preparation for this fight.
Damn all in. Yeah. Watch this. Okay,
now pull up a video of a Aldo training
with them. Watch this. He also,
he painted his face all the way.
Look how he's doing his hair.
He's got his fucking hair up like Connor
lowly shit son. And he's just like,
exactly. He's doing all the shit
that Connor does. He brought,
he brought him in to mimic Connor.
Dude on put my entire life savings.
See how he's doing now.
Yes, this is a game changer.
It's kid fish die. Fuck man.
He's just like, exactly.
And he's, you know, he's got that
style of movement in the first place.
All the three 60 wheel kicks and
roundhouse kicks and all that shit too.
That's trouble. It's interesting. It's
very interesting. Very interesting.
What is that guy's name again? Bill
[inaudible]. Bill arena. I'll see promise.
He's from Brazil.
Sage A. I. N. H. O. M.
Have a new boyfriend. Guys Know Joe.
He's no joke. I like [inaudible].
He said better kicker than Conor.
Better than he must like it. See,
Connor's kicks her almost disdainful.
If you watch the way
Conor throws his kicks,
he throws his kicks a lot the
way like exactly like bitch,
I'll just throw these kicks out there.
So He's six and no,
he hasn't lost every wind's been by Tko.
He's got one decision. Dan, once
a mission, we're in naked choke.
He's a bad motherfucker. Holy Fuck Man.
Where does he fight? What fights you?
The junk of five champion.
He's No,
25 five 11 five 11 one 45 and Connor
Connor's not five 11 five not five 11 see
is I'm five 11 Connor's not close
to five 11 you. Dot. You're known.
When we find out that you're wrong,
it's going to be ugly.
Take a look at the Instagram picture with
us. How much time you, you go Instagram.
He's slouching. I stood next to him
and I know, you know I look at body.
You have boots on. I'm obsessed with it,
right? You're right. Thank you. He's five.
Nine. Everybody be quiet. Is He? Yes. Yes.
Everybody. Give it up. Give it up. Kevin.
Come on, man. I'm trying to be death.
Oh, sorry. Sorry. Jesus man. Connors.
Five eight says it says
they're five eight. Well,
I'm five eight and honestly I
think he's an inch taller than me.
I think that's not correct.
It's tough. It's tough, man.
That's insane.
I don't know.
I'm more surprised that he
brought in that guy or calendar.
I feel of Reno Bill of Reno is
a fucking real game changer.
That's a game changer.
Yeah.
Big Game Changer because he's going
to learn how to deal with that style.
And Bill arena was explaining to him
all the different setups that he does.
Because bill,
you fights exactly like Connor fights.
He sets up kicks and punches in a very,
very similar way. And that's huge man.
Because when you fight someone
like Connor there, there's very few
fighters, there's Connor, Leo Machida,
Ronda Rousey, Stephan struve.
Cause he's fucking nine foot tall.
There's certain guys we get one shot at.
You can't duplicate it. Right, right.
So now you find a guide just like Connor
or maybe you're going to see that dude,
that's a fucking game change.
Exactly. Exactly. Damn.
And I'm putting a lot of money on Giardia.
I'm rooting for Connor though.
My heart wants Connor, but my brains, I
don't be, I love Josie. I love Connor too.
I have no,
I have no dog in this fight.
I really do mean I just want a great
fight. I went to live up to the height,
Dana said he thinks would be the
biggest paper view ever. It could be.
It's not going to be bearing
UFC 100 so let's get real.
It could be either one of these days
are bigger stars than Brock. Oh.
But internationally,
they certainly are.
Conor McGregor is the biggest star in
combat sports history to come out of
Ireland. Wow. Well, really?
There's a lot man co Madeline
traditional bra on boxer edition.
Yeah, but they've Wayne
McCullough, your boy.
Wayne McCullough comes
from Wayne McCullough.
There's Dev a lot of great boxes
that have come from Ireland.
Look at this daily superstars back
for over 1 million paperclips,
so not the biggest average says on track
for 1 million. I misquoted Dana. Oh,
fucking rip. My Connor thinks it's going
to be the biggest ever, not Dana. Okay.
My bad. Connor or Dana, this takes
over a million. Look at that site.
It does over a million, so sure
it does over a million. 100% yeah,
I think it does a million watch. I think
internationally in Europe especially,
I think we really have no idea how big he
is. What is the date? It said July 11th
find the kid won't be at the UFC expo.
It's all the shit going on.
What is that about?
How come you guys won't be in the UFC?
Actually we can't talk shit about
Reebok and show up at the X.
Is that what's going on?
I'm just saying I'm,
I'm assuming that it has
a little bit to go on it,
but do they see the shit going
on? Shit going on. Listen,
if we ever want to do it,
well we could do is next time there's a
UFC where you guys want to do something.
We could just get a studio
somewhere like it, uh,
at a casino and do a live event and
have a podcast with a three of us.
We just go onstage live. So we'll do
the way in and then after the way,
and we'll do like a 6:00 PM
podcast somewhere and the only few,
and I do an 8:00 PM show
somewhere at 9:00 PM show. Dude,
really?
And Tony Hinchcliffe,
Tom [inaudible] and I will be at the car
theater at MGM where they do Cirque de
Solei. That's a great show laying
in the show. I just remembered.
You're reminding me I have to act
to figure out, maybe I should email.
It's someone who like knows more,
but they told us last time at that car
theater cause it's a Cirque de Solei
theater that we can do like crazy stuff.
What do you mean come in like on a
zip line or they're not coming in.
I was too much to your fucking
trying to be a tour for comedy now.
It's like, no, you can't do that.
You can just go out there and
you do get sick. A zip line.
But it has a nice suit on like
the Golden Pony and saying,
do I get to do something like
that instead of your own show?
Show some sensor and you don't.
You want to come in from
the bottom like brides a hi
Todd. Cigarette guy died at that
Cirque de Solei theater. Dying. Dying.
Dying is a combination.
Wrestling.
Think about who's the guy who fell
fucking Brett. The hitman Hart's brother.
Do you want to be Brett? The hitman
Hart's brother? Here's girl Jessica Benet.
I gotta take a leak before this gets
going. She looks calm, man. For sure.
Don't duck lip it though to lock the gun.
She's sexy, Bro. Yeah. Don't hate on sexy.
I'm not hating on see yourself.
Don't hate it.
I just said the winner of this gets a
nose job. Frenos job. Dammit. Brendan,
what's wrong with that? But let me
tell you something about Yohanna.
Me and Tony got a couple beaks ourselves.
Yeah.
Wait a Salem throw me under the bus.
This big bomb, Bro.
We're part of the beat.
Clam guys might know this is
probably smaller than well,
my nose is right there with you guys.
Huh?
Johann has a is the only one that
doesn't have the weird knows.
[inaudible] knows I'm waiting
for it to get messed up.
[inaudible] no, right. I'm with
you on Johana and on. I like,
I like these.
Both these girls are attractive to me.
I don't care what anybody says.
You're such a pussy. Yeah.
You still worried about people
lashing out on dude, we,
my air BNB did said they're unable
to accommodate my request. Hey,
let's do this offline. Kellan sorry,
but for 100% don't text her in the shot.
Hurts me.
I mean, she's got a wrestler.
That's her only chance.
Did you see it just jumped to the yard?
Do you follow you on, on Instagram? Oh,
I don't.
Oh my God.
You should look up this thing of her
striking the other day we watched it.
Oh my God. Fucking animal. An animal.
The one where she's hitting
the Mitts and then sprawl.
What up? What up? Pop Up. Pop Up.
[inaudible] she's a fucking monster.
She's the best women's
striker to ever grace the UFC.
Is She gonna win this fight
then in your mind? Oh,
you're talking about the the fucking
minus 700 favorite? Yes, Brian.
I'd think so. Well just
get a penny. I mean,
it's gonna be a tough go for her
because she fucked a Carlos Esparza.
Fucking Joanna did and
just dismantled Esparza.
So Penn eight her only chit chance,
not striking.
She's going to have to get
him to the ground. Yeah.
It's not wrestlings Jujitsu and
all of you on his fights ago,
because I've been to quite a few of them.
Just luckily, you know, matched up
with the gigs that I do with Joe.
And she just happens to be on
the card and two fights ago, uh,
she went all Jujitsu against the Jujitsu
girl and rolled with our man and her
specialty is striking and
sh she just g out Jujitsu,
the Jujitsu Carlos Spo Spars,
Esparza tried taking her announce
something like 16 times as successful like
once or twice.
If that,
and a spark I would assume is a better
wrestler in Penn a so she has her hands
full. I, if I'm predicting this,
I think Jay Jay knocks her out
in the third round. All right,
take [inaudible] not knockout.
Tko is in third.
I don't like seeing a girl
who's this good at striking.
Just beat up some other girl on
the fake Cyborg. Gina Carano.
You ever seen it looked like bully
beat down. I was like, oh my God.
And Carano was a sexy
beast. Beautiful. Oof, oof. Sign me
the fuck up. She's in the audience.
I'm too loud asked for it,
but I'll make a go at it your way.
You're just not her style. Doesn't
matter bro. She was dating superman.
Who's superman? Oh, that guy.
Can Superman fight though? No,
it's just a sexy bitch, you know?
That was not good enough. You can't.
If you can't fight, you can't fuck
that girl the term maybe, but I don't.
I just don't see anything
she needs to fight around.
She's a Weidman or some
fucking Luke Rockhold,
Brendan Schaub type character
side it. That was a pro
football player, right? Yeah.
Calculus quarter.
She's too hot and she's a Badass fighter.
Like she's not going to be able to deal
with some guy who can't fight and just
look squishy. Walk around. I would
have. How much do you worry about?
She's not a little girl. I say.
Well, when I saw her, she was she.
Yes. She's easily bought
at one 45 yeah, she's,
she's won 60 when I saw
that she's hot. No, guys,
you think the girls need to be skinny?
You're crazy. I don't lose my band.
And number nine I agree guys. Dude,
she's just all woman's Janet chronic to
me is the sexiest female fighter ever.
You want to make some gladiator babies?
That's your fucking girl.
100% no doubt. I mean for
real man. When she fought,
Cyborg Cyborg was at her juicy juice.
That hurt my feelings.
That was a hurt feelings. I feel like
guys should have jumped in there,
defended her well. It would be a guy
fighting. I feel like Roger worked does,
should have jumped in then and
defended a girl. That's fucked up, man.
That was fucked.
Such a fucking beat down Dave.
They almost are responsible for the
lack of drug testing they did for her.
They just didn't give a fuck.
What was that like, man?
I think Cyborg might be choosing a
nice house and her eyes are intense.
Look in her eyes, look at
her, say turning. I think I
agree. She take that back.
Only her and Rhonda are the
only two that I've been in.
Atlanta has a good nose flattened.
You know what JJ though
looks better without makeup.
I think it's when she puts makeup on.
Where's that?
God Damn Polo top is
where it gets trouble.
She's such a, in her country, in
Poland, Polo tops, herb that's hot.
It's like bold knapsack people and the
renaissance days and were like back then,
that was good to be Rubin. Ask.
It was sexy. Catch you who pray,
protect it from disease. Nobody had
any food trailer like yoga pants in La.
That's right. First Polish UFC champion,
first female European UFC champion.
She is, this is what it should say
under her title. Bad ass bitch.
Six time world Moitai
champion it 100% legit.
You watch her Moitai it's so crisp.
First of all,
her fucking jab is a laser beam and it's
so fast and so technical and she has
confidence. She's cool. She's so
gangster. What's she doing here?
That video of her lighting up the
pads. Jesus Christ. That's impressive.
I haven't seen it. You haven't
seen it. Jamie, pull that video up.
The video of her from the UFC Instagram
page just to get a feel for the fucking
hand speed.
This chick possess for the UFC.
They need her to be a
dominant to make this
uh,
was it strawweight to make the strawweight
division [inaudible] siding and heard
it just dominate bitches like Rhonda is.
Cause if you have the
belt constantly switching,
it's hard for people to jump on board. You
know what I'm saying? I agree. I agree.
I think people will
catch on like her fists.
I like Ron does armbar you know like
she sort of has this fun thing to watch.
It's all of our striking.
It's not just our Fiserv elbows are nasty.
Boils up bitches and clinch. No,
look at that. Look up at that screen.
Watch this calendar is your worst
nightmares. Damn fucking dude.
And I'd watch your spa. Light it up. Light
it up. Light it up. Sprite. Light it up.
Light it up. Light it up.
Light it up. Light it up. Let
it up. Sprawl. Come on Tony.
It might be too much my man.
It's too much.
Rather look at the confidence she is
Jesus' right hand speed is the same world.
I need a girl like that to defend me.
If I ever make fun of somebody too bad
and they get in my face, it was like,
it's speed. Camera, speed it or no it
isn't. Look at the guy was totally normal.
Sick. Look at the guy's movement.
That doesn't like speed it up at all.
We know that's not speeding. She's 115
pounds of fury boxing tonight too, man.
Watch.
Watch me.
Watch me hit mets to know you're
going to throw your hands in the air.
They don't think you're going
to hit things with your hands.
You don't find that box. I am way
McCulloch makes me wear headgear, right?
God dammit. He hates when I
do. He hates it. He hates it.
No, I hate that. You think
you're fighting? Hey Bro.
That's what he hates. You don't.
You guys have video on me. Nice. He
knew and Wayne, where do they get,
I've seen you sit down during the
middle of the round from exhaustion.
That's true.
I am 48 I just don't care enough.
Last time I hit and while I do my job,
shut up. Last time I hit myths, I puked.
Did you? It's so hard. It's, it's
exhausting. Two or three times a week.
You know what a year.
You know what it is.
I'll help both you out get in shape and
brought what's wrong with you. February,
I'm in shape.
How dare you got to sit between rounds.
I don't have to sit anymore between Raz
now I know that's not what I energy.
You know every time you sit I
get a text from someone's a gin.
Brian's the only guy I got.
Tony hasn't seen me in a long time.
You got multiple eyes on you.
Brian's the only guy who,
you've got people watching me. I texted
him once. They let me know how he does.
Brian,
is it true that in between rounds when
you sit down and a guy comes and fixes
your hair down with a, with a
towel and has a Bentley belt,
is it true that when you're sparring a,
you get afraid that you're sweating
too much? He comes over and good.
There's motivational things with my hair.
Does it upset you that your wetter
in round two then in round one?
Sometimes I look good when I'm wet.
She's confident.
She's so cool.
She's a bad ass.
I would eat her ass.
Whoa. You get nose deep.
Probably have to just,
she's going to make my son elbows to save.
She's nervous. You can eat that ass or
you're not eating dinner that night.
It's got to be nerve wracking.
Ooh.
Oh.
Kiss, kiss, lick. Yes. Nose to nose.
Noser nose beak to be big.
To be beat to beat dog.
I'm explain something to you.
All you fucking guys right now.
You've got to get your jab in her face
and you've got to just follow up with a
fucking serious kick.
Okay.
Predictions that third
round Tko by upper cut.
Yolana round to Roger Worth of jumps in.
There we go.
This is the fight we're watching.
This is the first of all these phones.
Does anybody know who won the couch area?
Joe Idea.
Jerry won by decision changed your
bring those shorts up. We'll pinay.
I liked the way she's
moving to light on the feet.
Throwing up a Nice Crisp Jab to
Tko round one. No, come on. I would
jump to guard. Look at that. Jab,
Jab. Ooh fucker. Don't kid yourself guys.
Penn has been training hard to
that jab that you want to has.
It's like one of my favorite
jab in all of MMA. I agree.
She mixes it up to the body to look at.
Oh,
she goes below scan in the pocket though.
Left took is standing
right there and yeah,
but do you understand what's standing
in the pocket means you have to exchange
like these aren't exchanges. She's
getting tickling. [inaudible]
guys, can I tell you something?
Penn is the real deal. Well,
penny has very good
takedowns I'll tell you that.
You saw that on the ultimate fighter.
She's really good at hip tosses.
Good luck taking fucking JJ does. She's
going to take your mom's taking her back.
Nah, Brian, you realize
this isn't a takedown. Well,
he's, she's got a headlock,
a headlock. Rhonda loves his
fucking position. Big, juicy,
huge. Fucking 10. Look at this. She
escapes. Ron has a judoka. Ne Is fucking,
she's taken some shots, man. Coming
up and keeping her eyes open.
I'll tell you what, I don't like Jay
Jay's long board shorts. I mean, either
your shoulders was around her shoulders,
keeping her protecting
her chin up. Ooh, comes,
she's throwing chocolate Liddell
style. She went down, right?
Don't let that fucking Roy Nelson right
hand hit exactly on a oh great timing by
penny. Oh at this take down
right back up. Right back up.
I'm not gonna line up. I'm not gonna lie
to you guys. I come for penny. Really?
How come? I don't know man, because she's
such an underdog. I agree. Wow. Brendon,
I'm with you.
I am really liking you.
Want us to take down
these UFC needs JJ to win,
but it's fitting that her name's penny
cause Yolanda is going to beat her like a
wet noodle soup that did that by
the way. That's good. Sit down.
Look at this balance. Look at
this. Take down the fat. Hates it.
When I do jokes,
discipline is displayed.
When I see them come and mill
it down the fucking train track,
but not everybody sees him. I didn't
see him. The fucking flashing lights.
Meaning it's a macaroni
joke coming your way.
Oh my God. Don't let him. Don't let him
suppress you. You keep with the jokes.
Need is a body sweat pants to do.
He's going to tire her out.
You guys, I told you this.
Oh nasty elbow in the clinch.
Nasty old going to hold on
for like leg taken a saver.
I see a fucking foot going or if it's
a five round fight. Kids. Yes sir.
Oh ooh. Don't do it. Left
Hook. [inaudible] can take
it. I'll tell you that man.
She can.
She's taken some good shots.
I mean there are 115 post
Jessica training with Penn h.
She trained under the
timing. She trains. Uh,
she changed that Bouchez Jim Fujitsu.
I know she goes there all the time.
She was at rain for a long time and
then she also trains at a Ruca Bisbing
spots.
I'm excited about.
Here's your champ. Stand up. Come on.
Yeah, she's going to catch
her any second. Do you hope
I know how to Saturday you can
be if she gets submitted. Tony.
It's an it's impossible. She
doesn't get her up. Jessica hurt.
She got hurt. She got hurt.
Yeah, she's her dad. Oh elbow.
She's talking her head in goods.
Look how,
how those hit good fucking hips by you.
Ana. Can't operate right back on the head.
Yeah, no, right. That was a
little slightly illegal minute
to go. You get a warning,
but pinay she's got to go to your button.
Recovered. There you go. Just sit there.
Chill. Fuck. You're like, let her take
the lights. Cool. Chill and recover.
If she needs those legs. Well,
she needs her fucking cobwebs,
but those are world legs. Grow legs
are all soft. They can't take not Jay.
Jay's, hers. A schmuck in bats will
sinewy look at this little snaps
that it's so weird. Snaps. See
she's recovering. This is smart man.
It is smart. Super Smart. Yeah.
She's definitely not to the
body's exact same thing you do.
Letting her cobwebs clear up a little
bit here and she's looking at is bots
guten standing him up. All right. That's
a good way to get back up to your feet.
Clean to hell. Yeah, that's
good. They back up. They
didn't want to but school. Yup.
Hit Jessica. Pinay man. She's
game as fuck. Don't kid yourself.
Come on Jessica.
And you know what all this
was that dance. It was. It was a hundred
percent legit. You still lost the rich,
but she's showing that she's game is fuck,
but she's still in there.
Come on Jessica, don't worry.
And by the way, you know,
you got to think that this is fucking
wearing on. We've making her fight.
That kind of grueling grappling, extreme
exchanges is going to wear on you ana.
Yup. And she's going
to slow down. Yup. Mm.
Oh Jessica would have right
hand look at us. Very nice.
Look at that. Great timing. Great timing
on that shot. She's the real deal man,
which she's forcing her to wrestle and
once she forces at a wrestle it you want
Ooh, nice nasty elbow on the claim. That's
the one that popped in as she is right.
Get inside man. That was a nice writing
on the outside. She has Minjan it man.
She's mean. Well you know how hard life
is in Poland. The field look like that.
Yup. And if you're a fighter and
skinny little winery chick, oh,
hard life man. Hard. Right?
The boys or the boys aren't knocking
at the door to take you on dates and
[inaudible] is when they got one of the
funniest guys on the planet after when
they stick it in there. Not Nice. She's
funny too. She's got a good sense of you.
She always makes cracks, jokes and a show
and she'll fall in love. That's right.
Well Tony, should we set this up
the way open for you in Poland?
Tanya, let's see if Jessica
[inaudible] does anyone different?
Damn judging is sitting on a shelf.
She's strong like these one punches one
and one two and you just can't do that.
What y'all want.
She's just so ready to be there.
Right when that second
punch gets pulled back.
Well especially if you're
looking for a take down,
you've got to throw them all in one shot.
Then you shoot.
Especially if she doesn't anticipate
a third or fourth punch comment,
like no change of angles. No opera
cuts. Yup. So she's looking for the one.
If she throws the one,
the two's coming behind it and that's
about it and she knows she's going to be
right there pulling back and then
countering instantly when that punch pulls
back, Jj is too high level to
get caught with that bullshit.
He'll look at this and that
riding desktop on. There you go.
Just hold the gap though. This
with the clench here, man.
Yo want to gets pinay but she's got
to be careful of that head the way she
leaves at head dead.
Pinay when you watch the ultimate fighter,
she took a lot of girls down from that
headlock position and look at this.
This g the judo toss. Oh,
acquisition hide kicks out of Jj.
Yannis fucking let's go girl.
Well she doesn't do it because she
worries about people taking her down,
but standing right there man.
Fuck yeah. Is She's tough dude.
Honor Toes. Good. Really Good Tom.
Oh
Hey my feet straight. Laugh. Oh,
check. Jab to the body's now too.
Oh look at this combination is reaching.
The exact combination is nasty.
This fights close to being over
gentlemen. Yeah, it's getting rough.
It's getting rough. Penny's. She's
taken a beating cancer. Come on penny.
Last or third round. Yeah. I
love the movement of your honor.
The way she slides away from things and
then comes right back in and attacks.
There's those head kicks.
She's loosen it up now. Yeah.
Why can't mount like got down?
Oh Nice.
Oh she damn
her nose.
Your nose is wide open.
It's like of this common
nation. Goddamn. That hand
speed is ridiculous. Holy
Shit. Oh, look at that.
In the clinch, she lands in elbow
right to that same spot on the nose.
The smarter penny.
Fuck yeah.
She needs to bleed inside.
If you want his ear just getting those
inner ear and she can take serious
punishment, man. She, that's too without
the fuck else are going to be broken.
Elbow and noses splatter.
Oh ooh. Jj is comfortable. Hands down.
Is this just a low,
that nose. Look at this.
Look at her face. Pennock jumped
head kicked. Just barely missed.
Henoch get under hooked up to half guard.
You want to set it up the left high kick.
Just when? When she goes south. Paul,
look, it's coming covered combo. Mi, Mi,
Mi three. No nother elbow saw
in the clinch. I tell you what,
I've never seen a female fighter fucked
another girl up with this much damage.
Ever. Look at her face, man.
This is insane. She looks
like a monster movie. Yeah,
she has a giant Gash
on her nose real quick.
Tony are still into this or I'm, I
love this. Look, look at my girl.
She's covered in her opponents blood
like a fucking warrior and you're still
attracted. More attractive.
I like winners. Job Tony.
That's all the gay and Tony coming
to the surface itself in the form of
a real woman. You, you fucking,
you chauvinists. He's appearing.
He's imagining her with a
strap on right now. Tony,
what about Caitlyn Jenner or
left eye is closed. Her right?
Eye's all fucked up too, man. Oh Jesus.
Look at this Combo. Hey, real quick.
Tough is Jessica. Remember Jay Jay's
115 pounds fucking girls up like this.
You don't see damage like this at the, in
the female that kick to the body. Jesus.
Dan, just Jessica Payne is a bad,
bad, bad motherfucker. Yeah, she is.
It's fitting that her name's penny cause
it looks like she is tomato sauce all
over your face
up on the hill.
But I said the better one for a second.
So hard to fight somebody
this good looking up blood.
I mean is a tomato sauce.
Come on. So wait till the third round.
So big browns predictions, right? No, no.
He has this pass. What are you doing?
Got a new favorite female fighter. Yeah,
she's a beast bro. And he's tough and
I'm just kidding. Jay. Jay's my faith.
Second seconds nation.
My grantee Kale baby man.
Dude, this is so impressive.
And look at this. Panay is still working
for the tape. She's super flexible,
son. Wow. This thing's
TK on the third baby.
I want to say followers fans.
So it's like I'm a fucking
so fucking impressed with
my God. I love, look at her.
Fuck you gash on her nose.
Stop that. Oh my God,
look at the cutter knows I've never seen
a cut on and I was like that before.
I'm going to be here now
because it's a female.
Will they stop it early and
then if it was a male for it.
It depends on a lot of experience with
this email fighting. We're in Germany,
right? Oh my God. That's a huge
gash. And you do it. Most man. Well,
they put adrenaline on it and
they could try to close it up.
They close it up with Vaseline.
Ouch. Ouch. Ouch. Oh fuck that. It's,
I think it was an elbow
that lit her up elbow.
That was him right there.
Immediately. The blood SLOs. Jj.
He's my favorite fighter now. Hey Tony.
I'm on board. I don't want to fuck her,
but she's my favorite. She's my
favorite fight and fucking in man.
This bitch is bad. Hey, real quick. I
never watched her fine. I gotta be honest.
I don't watch a lot of
girl fight Ronda fight.
Somebody in that way class with this kind
of striking would be very interesting
on that side,
but not really
in fucking tosser 20 feet.
There's some nose dad.
Her nose was just totally smashed. What
a bad ass. You've got to give it up, man.
Oh, Jessica Bernays. No
joke. Jasmine Benet. No,
you don't get to this level without
fucking being tough. Come on, man.
This is different. This is more than
tough. This is transcended the well,
this is fucking no easy.
Easy to know for sure.
Take it. Come on Jessica.
Wow. Come on girl, Baby. So Crystal,
Jessica [inaudible] toughness, man. So
impressed. Ouch. Keep your hands up.
Please keep hands. I've never seen a
little hundred 15 pound female fighter.
Fucked a girl up like this
in my entire life. So good.
It's Cyborg doesn't do this to girls.
She fucking sledge.
Sledgehammers the hands out,
but she doesn't have this
kind of technique. No. Ouch.
Keep your hands up please.
I've never seen a little hundred 15 pound
female fighter fucked the girl up like
this in my entire life. So good Cyborg
doesn't do this to girls. She had that.
She had fucking sledge
hammers the hands out,
but she doesn't have this
kind of technique. No. Wow.
Look at the wealth above and below her.
I don't let her get Jesus
Christ next for Jay Jay. No,
it's want to sign up for it took a day
to day and her had a really close fight.
She wanted to split decisions.
Yeah. You're talking about
the 2.0 Jay Jay. Yeah.
Well she's a different
Jj. No, she's got it.
She's got the another elbow for sure.
Finish this round some right though. Jj,
what are you talking about? What?
It froze. Oh, we'll reboot it,
man. Reboot. It just rebooted.
Rebooted bull shit.
God.
Can they hear the recording?
It's still live. Right? Recording
Jessica [inaudible] contact.
She's amazing. She's, she's tired.
I'm looking at when she
keeps moving, man. Fuck Dude.
She is definitely tough as fuck.
She's so tough.
She just doesn't have
an answer to this now.
Who does look at the
swelling all over face?
Not that I still moving her head still.
Pinay is definitely game. God is,
she had her hands up. Tam. Hands up. God,
I'm stressed out. Low left. Took
why he's stressed out. I like to see
girls get fucked. Oh really? I don't,
I don't hate them exactly.
To Brendon. I don't either.
I Hate Austin. I'm exhausted.
I cringed. I don't feel, I feel
sick aunt and my hands feel numb.
Jj is a fucking nightmare machine. She
hasn't been touched. It's just no good.
She's no joke. That's for sure,
man. Her technique is so beautiful.
I want to see her go to the body.
I like how she switches up
to southpaw orthodox. Either.
That Jab is ridiculous. God Damn. Ouch.
Oh,
Jessica pinay with the clinch.
You want to get a little careless there.
Jessica trying to drag her to the ground,
could drag him to the ground.
Look at this
part to get her down and knock her nose
off of her to get her down on the knee.
Oh, it's squirting out of that girl's
face. Is that a hell of a fight?
Fuck yeah, it is, man.
I think it's interesting that the UFC as
male centric as it has been for so long
is a leader in feminist,
like a feminist activity,
like a leader in women's
fighting and it's, and it's
as exciting as men's, right?
Well, there's no women's boxing
of any prominence right now.
You don't know of any women's champions.
Nobody talks about in the other leaks.
There's just not, well, there's
Invicta, right? They're all female.
But to this boxing,
I mean there's only,
there's only a lion fight that has
women's Moyie Thai fights, time bomb.
She's that shoot.
I just watched the other day I was sewing
president to tweet it out. I was like,
God damn, tiff, time bumped that beast.
She's a beast. Get a girl like that.
The traffic to son. Get a girl
to learn how to sprawl. Right.
Enjoy that. Well, young JJ on
your hands that he's there you go.
Well she's at that same
level if not higher. Yeah,
she's a Maltese and measuring shot and
Tiffany could go do some modeling she
wanted to to, you know what I'm say
up. That's when you get a superstar.
Now that JJ can be a superstar.
Hobos man, those elbows in tight. Jj,
go ahead and finish her for me,
girl. Hey Brendan. When is that way?
What does the doctor do?
Their stuff it, they uh,
how much they can put things
in them in it, but like up it.
But then in the back they set, they set
your notes. I've had my nose set twice.
I said, Ooh, your Adrenaline Jab.
That's Tareq and right
hand. Now I'll call it,
nailed it and fight. It was crazy.
She's a beast. She is a fucking beast.
Slugger. Airy. Look at that blood on
that. No one wants a piece of that son.
Who's next?
Who's next? Yeah. What did she look to
the car, Tony, you get fucked up tonight.
I love it. To fucking
Badass. She's so cool. God,
she's a police man. Mad Respect for
Jessica. Danny's a fan favorite.
Now you cannot be a fantasy show. Tough.
Oh look at her fucking nose, dude.
Look at her nose. Oh my God. Oh my God.
That knows.
Now when you get a gash like that,
that opens up easier the next time.
Right? Scar tissue. Yeah, on the nose.
It's not too bad.
It's on the ice where you're in trouble.
They're going to repair it. They'll do
a great job. Did you see? Um, uh, Dave,
who the fuck showed? Uh, oh, um, uh,
Raquel Pennington brew cal paint and
had a big gash on her forehead and then
show me pictures of it before and
after like the job that they did like
repairing it. They did an amazing
job. Like you can't even see the scar.
I don't know how the fuck they did it.
I mean they have like really good plastic
surgeons these days. Scar tissues.
A mother Fucker, man. Yeah
it did. And people scar
differently. Like black people,
they tend to get more keloid scars there
for some reason. Their scars like they,
they have like thicker wealth type
co scars. A stickup higher. Mm.
Depends on the person. It depends
on it's side of, it's genetic.
I had a nose job after I fought cro cop
and he shattered my nose with an elbow
Chan. I was worried. I was like, God, am I
me fucked from now? And the doctor's like,
no, your nose probably won't
ever break again. Because what?
The way they structure it, they, they're
so advanced now it's stronger. Wow.
Stronger after you break it. How do they
do? What are they doing? I'm not sure.
Because he threw an APP. What? Like
shattered my nose into pieces, right?
We put like a mesh net and it
almost, oh, face isn't touched.
Look at her fucking face.
Look at Jessica's face. Kind
of feel bad dude. How about,
what's she gonna look like in
the six hours? That's awful man.
Look at this fucking monster.
Not touched. Not touched.
Does she's a bad ass. Get somebody
that far ahead of you and striking.
What are you gonna do?
I mean she's so try and take them
down cause she's far ahead of her and
grappling. But now it's just pay off.
Yeah. Not just far ahead and striking,
but takedown defense as well.
Unbelievable.
Take out these ads or take down
defense is nasty. Finable balance.
Dan Hardee rocking the
fucking converse all stars.
She's totally about the take. It's
Mike from him. If he could, if he left,
the other ones have its current
crank this up so we can hear this
and again and again and again
from me.
These five we'll do the one.
Not really. It's more of a beat. Well,
it's a kind of war like when
the UFC has a world like this.
It's sort of like when the United
States invades Afghanistan. Yeah.
It's kind of a war I guess,
where we're just like, we got
God. Come on. Give me a shout out.
Could you imagine my number one fan,
Tony Hinchcliffe Golden Pony,
golden pony on the topic.
I had an idea to success and victory.
I think she said it. It's our belt. This
get to the face kid. Ooh,
that's no fun. Oh yeah.
Jay Jay's my favorite fun.
Her angles are amazing.
Dammit.
Mark are
God damn. She's good. I
agree with you. A big brown.
This is so important for this division
to have a dominant champ like that to
really make everybody excited about it.
It seems to think if there was no
Rhonda at one 35 what do we do?
What are you doing? What's going to
change nonstop? Yeah. There's nothing.
There's no, that's a problem with Rhonda
at that weight class. That was it.
Less Cyborg and get down to one 35 who
do you anticipate to see? Even a channel.
Rhonda is a different story because
she's such a dominant champion.
She's just destroying it now. It's
like, all right, this isn't cool.
Like she's like,
she's moved past that 0.41 15 we need it.
But around has already gone past that
point where we have to have some sort of
competition. Cause like I bet
when she fights in Brazil,
I bet the numbers aren't great concern.
She's destroying bitches.
You get the Mike Tyson effect where
you're too good. Where it's like hold up.
I'm not going to spend $70 a c or
merge some girl in 15 seconds. Right.
Cause the comp tickets then,
not that she's not fighting good fighters,
but people assume that they're not
good and Ron has just been spoonfed,
which is not true.
Oh look at that fucking elbow.
Do you think batchko HIA has a chance
at she not. She has nothing. Oh really?
Batch and your talk shit about
Rhonda is deck commit suicide.
You fucked up so good.
Yeah.
Well she said she doesn't
commit suicide after the fight.
She didn't apparently said she didn't
know that her dad's suicide. You know,
believe, believer, no, I don't
believe her. She may not.
I think she got too much heat and
then she was like, oh that's gross.
But you give Rhonda reason to break your
motherfucking arm cause her dad what?
Dude? She's in trouble and, but the UFC
is doing everything they can to black.
All right.
This one's going to be close.
We're centered to Brazil to fight in
the home country of batch. Now come on.
Wow. It's too much man. But
it's not Rhonda his fault,
but the public views it as,
oh they're just tossing anyone to Rhonda.
But that's what's the best
available. It's not. Rhonda is fall.
There's your girl Toni, look at her.
Keeping my eye on these coaches are hers.
I got a little touchy.
Your fucking hands up high girl.
She's so good. Does she have a nickname?
No, they need to make one for you.
Refer to as j j j j is a good name for
him and I like change market that man.
Yeah, no, I liked Jay Jay, I think.
I think you nailed it. The other one,
the jerk or a Dick?
I don't think we should use that.
I just didn't know what to say.
I took some heat
press with her, man. He too fucking
technique is so spectacular.
Scary little thing. She's so good, dude.
I've never seen a female
fighter just destroy,
grow and break her down and do that
damage better than Cyborg. Way Better.
Way Better.
Way More.
Way more skillful and not just
overwhelmingly physically dominant.
It's all technique because yes,
girls with submissions,
but she's not like cutting
and breaking them down.
Destroying this girl cologic a Dahlia
and her had a very close fight. This,
this is the next one in line
because Claude, you could Dahlia,
they went to a fucking split decision.
They went to war. Man. A good day.
It took her down like a day is now. Joe,
Tim's good day is pretty. And by the way,
I thought day you'll won the fight. Wow. I
fucked. Could tell you one. The decision,
I thought it was very close. She's gonna
fuck with Dell. You're wanting to resign.
Yeah. 12 and one and that
one is to Yolana. Wow.
The one and the one was a very
fucking close fight to JJ.
Now they fight,
I want to say a year and a half ago.
You're dealing with a confident
JJ, right? Yeah. It was before her,
her title fight with,
um, it was to set up the,
the title fight with Esparza.
She,
Michelle Waterson in their division
now though. She's, she's not,
she's in the UFC now. Oh really?
The broader signed with UFC. Yeah.
She's fighting similarly.
She looks heavily Musk muscled.
I wonder if some of that is help get
diarrhea. Yeah, she might test positive.
Well Michelle Waterson they'll beat,
uh,
submitted Jessica Penne a shallow water
sense of peace. Yeah. She has a beast.
She's very Jackson's.
Yeah.
You won't talk about someone
who for sure stopped doing that.
You want to talk about someone
who's super marketable,
Michelle Waterson cause she's
really pretty too. It's true. Well,
they need that man and they need to make
sure that she's ready because she won't
be pretty after Chavon answers. Right.
Girl tend to unpretty if on you,
she goes, look at her. Who's next?
Who's next? Next. Next. Next. Geez.
She's only 27 two men. She has
what they need now. When, when she,
what did she study?
Just strict more time cause it looks
like boxing six time world champion.
She's definitely got great hands. Well
Shit. Holland Dutch came white tie is,
you know,
more ties boxing as well.
Like there's a lot of Moitai Thai
fighters like yachts and climbs up fucking
Badass boxer. I mean Moitai is not
mean that they don't have good hands.
Especially today in this day and age
before guys like Ramon Decker came over to
Holland. A lot of those guys didn't
concentrate in their hands as much.
But once the European guys
and once some of the uh,
American guys started going over to
Holland or to Thailand and fighting you,
you started to see a lot more
hand techniques from the ties,
the or the motherfucker because people
are really good with the elbows man.
Somebody like her star,
like what she does or look at Cro cop,
Conor Mcgregor, 2008 Oh, crank that up.
Oh well he handles, it's all over
his face in 2000 looking sharp.
He really stepped his game up.
You got a big head, Huh? All right.
Yes, it does. Noggin. I'm the future.
That's when he was like 16 damn man.
He was about to retire two years ago.
Yeah, about to retire. He had a friend,
apparently his friend had got so battered
up in a fight that they told him never
fight him. Fight again.
Yeah. It was really worried,
like thinking about his life
going, fuck, what am I doing?
It was out of the gym is coach called him.
Doc offered him a fight.
He didn't answer the phone.
He told a story on a podcast.
He didn't answer the phone over and over
again. Finally it was like, Oh fuck it.
I'll pick it up. How crazy.
The Anderson Silva, same thing,
basically was going to walk away and
know. Kara was like, no man, this,
let's just see what happens.
Keep going.
They get signed by the UFC
and does fuck Chris Liebing.
He was retired and no guarantee.
That's why he owes his career
that he says that he goes,
I owe everything to Nogueira
because big nog was like, no man.
Just keep going for a little bit.
Let's see what happens.
And he talked him into it.
What does and do now?
I mean he's in this weird predicament
too with the drug testing where they uh,
apparently they found like he had to two
samples and one of them tested positive
and the other one from a different
lab did not test positive.
So this is dispute as to
which one was correct.
That's the thing that bothers
me is he just denies it.
Like he should just come on back.
Listen, my leg was fucked up.
I used some stuff to get my leg better.
He said that I don't think he did.
He's well, from what I've hear he's
denied any bit of it. Really. Yeah.
Cause he went on the ultimate
fighter and he was like,
I've never taken steroids is bullshit.
It's all a scam. I thought he said Anders,
I thought they said Anderson admitted to
taking something to heal his leg but it
was out of competition.
And then once he,
because he tested positive more than once,
you know, tested positive before the,
before the fight in camp. And then he
tested positive again after the fight.
But said negative after
the first positive.
I'm always fascinated with those,
those moments in your life where
one person says one thing to you,
when it changes the course of your life,
what do you mean? You know what I mean?
Like when somebody goes, okay, don't,
don't quit. Keep going. Maybe one more.
And you think of those times that were
seminal in your mind and your life will
be that one person,
one teacher,
one guy who says one productive
thing or one negative thing. Well,
I stopped competing.
I stopped fighting and I focus 100% on
comedy because this one kid at an open
mic night said to me that I was
really good when I first started,
but I've drifted off. Oh, I was like,
fuck, he's right. I really was right.
I didn't even get upset. I was like,
he's right. It was like six months in.
It stung. It's fucking,
it's so important though.
It's so important to hear that Joe
sit with it. I'll tell him, Brian, um,
the talk we had right about not fighting
anymore and how I need to move on,
but we were talking, I was
talking to Nate, more carts,
head coach and um,
I sent him what Nate tweeted out,
how he made all the excuses and
they tweeted back and he, yeah, he,
he wasn't feeling it. He was
sick. I'm like, no, no, no,
no, no. I get that. I get that.
It's time to move on man.
You have got to tell him it's your
guys' duties to move on and then hit me.
I'm like,
this is why fucking Joe was so honest
with me because if you kind of skimp
around it and you, and
you leave the, you know,
like you kind of leave an open
door worried about their feelings.
I can come with a million excuses
why it can be world champ.
You know what I'm saying?
But you have the fuck it's going to hurt.
Like a mother fucking might ruin your
career, but you just fucking hit him.
Right straight man. He got to be dead
honest because even his coach is like, no,
he can figure this out. I'm like,
no, no, no motherfucker, it's over.
You have got to tell them it's
time to move on. Like yeah,
but he might do this for what?
So the UFC gives them these young lines
and they make a name off of them for
white man. He has heat. There's just,
there's things we're seeing
where it's not good. Yeah.
There's a certain point in time where
your time's past you and you've got to
understand when the time is.
And the only way to understand when
their time is is you have to be objective
with yourself.
You have to be honest with yourself and
you need someone to tell you you can't
be objective and honest with stuff.
Cause you don't get to an elite
level fighting being objective.
You don't because you know,
do I still believe I can be
a champion? Yeah, I do. No,
you know, no matter what, especially now,
like what if our Lawsky beats for doom.
And then you look at our
Lawsky and your fight,
which was you could have easily won
that fight. I definitely beat them.
But you know, look at that and you go,
well how can be champ? Yeah, yeah. Which,
which is great. But to me it's
like, um, when, when I never,
it never hit me till till I was talking
to Nate and I was like, oh my God,
this is what Joe did with me.
Like you,
you have to be so fucking honest and
you can't tiptoe around their feelings
because they're not going to get it.
It's really weird.
Like sometimes you'll see like I
was the first time I appreciate it,
but that literally last week was the
first time I ever was like, oh my God,
I get it.
Cause fighters,
you don't get to that level
without this crazy confidence man.
And people tell you stuff
and sometimes not good.
You have to block that
out and just keep going.
What's also different than anything else?
Like if you were a musician,
no one would ever talk to you like that.
But the difference
between being a musician,
making bad songs and being a fighter
and getting punched in the face is that
you're going to suffer for the rest of
your life with any unnecessary damage
that you take.
And the more you can stop that,
the more you can have a
great rest of your life.
You know what a friend told
me that though when I was,
we were arguing about Nate. I'm like,
Bro, I'll fucking talk to them. Right?
Cause me and Nate are very close and I
was like, I'll talk to him. But he goes,
all right.
He goes to different stream.
Joe Talking to you and you talking
to Nate is you have other options.
I don't have to ever fight
again. I'm fucking fine, man.
My life's actually better now. I'm
not fighting so much way better. Nay.
What's Nate going to do? It's true
or any father not on the article.
I'm just saying I started fighters.
I don't know coach. Yeah, it's hard.
It's hard when most guys
don't prepare for your kids.
They also don't have that kind
of personality that you have.
That translates really easily into
podcasting and fucking around and being in
fucking around whether you're doing,
you guys are having fun and getting
paid fucking around around. Yeah, yeah.
You're fucking around and cracking jokes
and you know that's, it's entertaining.
And he's not that guy. He was done there
attain, but the guy was talking to him.
I can say his name, but
he just goes, he goes,
that's easy for you to say because you
can walk away and you're gonna make more
money not fighting. So you're like,
yeah, see everything's great and dandy.
These other fighters, they don't
have that man to fall back to there.
There's no 401k. There's no retirement
plan. Right. Nate has four kids,
a wife of mortgage bills. Fighting's
his number one source of income.
You see him and then at least he's not
getting like stunned with every shot that
lands like gray Maynard,
gray, Maine or bugs me. You
know, I really liked that guy.
He's a great man.
He's a good dude and a great fighter.
And it came that close to winning the
world title and now you see him and he
gets lit up when you see like his
body just starts short circuit.
Heartbreaking man. It's hard.
What if Reebok did this to
help fighters out? What,
this is a little off this and what if
Reebok said all right to help fighters out
because you only get paid when you fight,
right?
So guys are hustling trying
to figure things out.
What if an awfully Reebok has the money
and obviously the UFC has the money
because they're drug testing every
fucking fighter a million times,
which is expensive.
What if Reebok did a monthly payment
system where you're not forced to take
fights where you're not getting
injured and showing up for fights?
What if he did a monthly plan? It's
not, they don't have enough money.
There's not enough money invested in this.
You think about the $70 million
that Reebok put in over six years,
which is nothing. Yeah, it's not much,
but you got 600 fighters or something.
I'm an OFAC 70 million
to rebus nothing but to,
to give people enough money to live
comfortably. I didn't say comfortably,
I'm just saying it helps out because
the fighters are losing tons a month.
He's right. Yeah. So you make that up
and they're not, you're not, you know,
risking fighting, injured stuff
like that. Brain trauma they get,
they're getting monthly. So that
makes sense. Maybe. But you know,
the real problem is securing a future
outside of fighting and what a guy like
you, you have more potential outside of
fighting now than anybody and more than
you've ever had before.
And as your podcast,
your podcast is fucking giant right
now and it's growing at this crazy rate
where you guys are millions and
millions of downloads every month.
It's going to keep going and going
and going and going and going.
And it's just getting stratospheric.
They don't have that.
They don't, and you have like all this
thing, you have something to work for,
like you see,
you see like progress and excitement.
It's like you're making a
smooth transition. These
guys, they don't have that.
And when they don't have that, there's
literally nothing. Talk to your boy Shane.
You know what his car wouldn't doing.
He's working as an engineer that has
just not the same as being the fucking
heavyweight champ of the UFC has not the
same of the glory when he smashed Frank
Mir, you know when he smashed
Frank Mir and got ahold of him,
tied him up in that clinch.
It just ripping those fucking
uppercuts mean that is go
Lori.
Just Gloria on the highest
level excitement on the
highest level and when that
ends and also you're getting a paycheck
and the government gets a big piece of
that paycheck. I paychecks. Not
much anyway. No. Yeah, like I, I,
it's depressing to talk about, it was
just true for fighters. Most, you know,
to my references, all dogs don't go to
heaven fighting. It's not like the movies,
man. This ain't no mark Wahlberg movie
where the credits roll and he's walked off
then sunset with a bag full of money
and it's usually not like that man.
You know? And we all know guys
that when we talk to them,
we see that diminishing things.
We see their eyes not focusing right.
We see their gate.
One of the things that bothered me about
watching Nate fight was how closest
stance was.
There's something that happens when,
when fighters get hit
a lot with their legs,
they start moving their stance closer
and closer together and it's just like
they don't have that wide like,
you know, see how, you know,
Connor fights and he's getting this
wide stance. I fled up sneezing. When,
when guys get hit a lot,
they start moving their legs closer and
closer together and it's almost like
they, their balances fuck their
motor skills are affected. You know,
it's one of the things that I talked
to a guy Medsker is working with this
company in Dallas that um,
uh,
rehabilitates people from traumatic
brain injuries and it's one of the things
that they talked about is the gate.
Like you could see the differences in the
way people stand and the way they move
and the way they, they move inside
the ring. This is, there's a,
Ben and I were talking
about whether or not,
and it's a very tricky thing to pull off,
whether there should be
some kind of an expert body,
a governing body of experts who can
look at somebody in their fight and say,
you just can't fight anymore. You lose
your life. Okay, but you say that,
but how do you,
how do you stop our Lawsky from
fighting [inaudible] because there were
[inaudible] was on the way out. I'll
ask. He gets starched by Fader, right?
Starch flatline.
He gets a starched by a surgeon
or surrogate Keratan off,
kicked starches up for us.
You can get us the big foot,
beat the fuck out of them by rumble,
rumble, smashes him in the first round,
breaks his jaw and you're looking at him,
you're like, this guy has got to stop.
Now he comes back to the UFC,
wins a couple of fights,
knocks out Travis Brown and he's
next in line for a fact. We say,
I would say the answer to
that is that's a hard case.
And to understand that this
exception, hard cases don't
make good laws. And, and I,
and I hear you. It's an
outlier. It's an outlier.
And I think if you'd have to weigh the
overall sort of benefit to to con to
that. So, so I do think that,
I do think that most of those, those
come back decisions could be avoided.
Where you'd have,
you'd make most of the dishes will be
very good if you had a group of people who
really know their shit and they took in
all the factors. Most people would go,
that person 36 years old,
whatever it was,
37 38 he's been starched
whatever many times.
He's not the same as I'm moving the
same. Right. He's got to stop. Okay.
How's he supposed to make
more and more important?
How do you tell him to stop when you
tell people it's okay to sky. Dot.
We tell people it's okay to base jump.
It's a wingsuit and jump off a cliff.
But is it also worth it? Like if
I'm a professional fucking swimmer,
that's like me having this great career
and be like, this is fucking crazy, man.
I got wet. Yeah, you jumped in
water. You can get wet, you fight,
you get punched in the face
and head trauma, same shit.
So we know what we're signing up for.
Not the same shit though.
And the reason it's not the same shit
as that head trauma and the d and the
damage that these guys are taking,
they're going to pay for for the rest
of their life. And it's life shortening.
I don't think you could say the same thing
about things like swimming and things.
So you don't think we know that that's
like, and I hate him more. And soldiers,
a soldier sign up for the Marines,
get going out on a fucking tour getting
shot me like what the fuck this is
bullshit man.
And addressing the fact that you don't
get to be a fighter and a great fighter.
Uh,
like a lot of the guys without being
objective is probably not your friend in
the ring when you're a young man
that's in all sports though. Football,
Joe Montana, which if it was up
to him, he'd still be slinging.
Football's a 49 or is that 60 years old
for every athlete's going to keep going
till? Well, the NFL and NBA is, it's very
simple, right? Nope, there's a young guy,
we're not paying anymore.
It really bums me out that they'd go
after a guy like Roger Clemens for using
growth hormone to throw a ball
faster. Cause like why? Like he's,
yeah, he's using some stuff, but by
the way, that stuff's not illegal.
It's not like he's using math.
Okay. He's using stuff that's legal.
You can buy it that your body produces
anyway. Your body produces in any way.
Scientists developed it.
It makes your body work better.
And all he's doing is prolonging
his career, throwing a baseball.
He's investing in itself.
No one's getting hurt from Roger
Clemens taking growth hormone and still
throwing. Every guy that he's
pitching to is on the same shit.
So what's the point?
And he's not hurting these guys.
It's not like he's kickboxing
and because of this, he's alive.
He's showing up with hyper human hormone
levels that allow him to absorb punches
like tic tacs and just see guys down raw
Vandelay in his prime with that kind of
shit.
It comes back down to the old idea of
competition sport on a fair playing field.
That's where that's,
that would be the argument that the
commission would make and baseball, right?
They'd say, well, you know you,
you, you're, you have an advantage.
Then over the doesn't have an advantage
because he's still just a picture and
it's not like he's throwing some ball
190 miles an hour when no one's ever seen
that before. Throwing, he's throwing
pitches at a normal speed. I mean,
he's not doing anything unusual. I mean,
you know what I'm saying? I do. It's,
I mean I think baseball is
one of the worst arguments.
I agree when it comes to steroids and
the amount of crap that Barry Bonds Tuck,
like just being booed and bro, look bro,
he just broke the three
thousands home run. It's insane.
He just passed like Hank Aaron,
Babe Ruth.
I was she and that is his piano cover it.
There's a little ticker at the bottom,
but not a lot. The Yankees, he
spoke at all of these bonuses.
There's Matthews are saying,
nope,
we can't mark this because you're known
as a steroid user. Yeah. He's like,
what the fuck to my contract? You want
me $6 million if I hit this milestone,
that's never been done. How many new
Yankees are saying, nope, we can't do it.
We can't market you. Hold on a
second. You voided the contract.
I'd been testified for steroids.
Is that true? 100% true. So he,
did he void his contract and be
legally, is it void the I, I, I'm not,
I don't know the contract,
but they're not paying him and he's
not putting up a fight either. Wow.
Look at Barry Bonds,
Marty golden gloves and Barry Bonds,
one nine sat a shitload and that steroids
are not can help you necessarily field
balls to that level and that skill,
well that's not true.
It's going to help you run faster.
You're going to get to the ball quicker.
But I'm saying like you said, to your
point, a great deal of baseball is skill.
And I would say steroids for baseball
allow you to play longer so we'll know.
It definitely allows you to hit
a ball harder. I understand.
And be your bad speed. Faster. Bat weighs
less too, but you also play longer.
You can also just play into your late
thirties where you probably couldn't
because your bat speed slows down.
Now do you think,
and this comes with
bullying and all this shit,
do you think with society become a little
bit sissy sissified now it's like head
traumas, a baker deal. Cause head
traumas always been there and it's about,
we know more about it though.
We know more about it,
but at the same time it's like,
oh, we should stop this football.
They shouldn't play with helmets. Well,
when I signed up for football, I'm like,
all right, I'm clashing. My
helmet, he gets that dude.
It's probably not safe. Yeah,
but, but I do it. You thought it
was about your bowel was wrong.
Now as we learned more and more about
not only what it does but the longterm
effects are harder to,
it's harder to condone it when you know
that the people that are doing it right
now are going to pay a very steep price
or could paste. It's harder for society,
I think, to deal with that. A lot
of athletes, they're variable.
I think if you asked most of
the athletes like came in,
your brain's going to get fucked up.
It's going to take 10 years off your life.
He's still going to do it. Most of them
say yes. Well, because the hearing, yes,
they have no other options.
I think that those stories existed before
of the guy who got a concussion and
the coach put them back in there and
then he got paralyzed moments later,
but they never get broadcast
because it wasn't the Internet.
So those stories were trapped in
Toledo, Ohio and some, you know,
some parents would tell their
friends and it would be a tragedy,
but it would never make it
across the globe right now.
Those stories become huge
international stories.
You also see your childhood heroes
talking about how they don't remember it.
And Tony Dorsette did that interview and
talked about how he just forgets where
he is,
what he's doing.
Dicta Mike Ditka Hall of fame
coach Hall of fame player was like,
if I knew the repercussions is going
to have on my players and myself,
I would never play football. I would
never coach any of it. And they go,
would you let your sons or your
grandkids play football? He goes, nope,
that's not right. That's Mike
motherfucking Mr Football Dick.
That's so cranes and the trail and talked
about the fact that his son wants to
play football. And he said, well,
that's not going to happen until
you can basically you're in what,
sophomore or junior in high school until
your head start to develop and maybe
college. Well then you're not
playing right. It's stupid.
But that's what makes it that material.
And it played what for
seven years it was like,
I don't want my son playing football
right now. Isn't that amazing?
Like he's fighting and MMA in
the UFC and he's like, Dad,
that's not as dangerous.
That football things.
What you really should be worried
about. I disagree really. I mean,
I played in both. Yeah. I think my
breath bad. Right? Yeah. Neither one.
Neither one's good for your
health. What's, what's worse
do you think? Both will.
Okay, so let's, let's just say for
example, so what, this, uh, 2016,
it'd be my eighth year in the UFC, right?
Eight years in the NFL. I'm set for life.
I get a stipend every month. Every
time at playing on 401k. I'm good man.
I don't have to go fucking
figure something else out
to do. I can live off that.
I'll be all right. I'd full benefits.
UFC, I take some head trauma,
which I'm going to get if I'm in
for eight years and I retired, uh,
January 2nd after eight years.
There's no stipend, there's no 401k.
I have no options. I better figure some
shit out. These thing that fell. I,
I'm still gonna get head trauma,
but at least I at least I'm going to
get compensated for it down the road.
And it's not [inaudible] fault
because u of c right now,
you know we're getting there,
but we're in leather helmets.
If his NFL NFL said it's
been around a long time,
it's a smooth operating machine.
There's a player's union. So I get that.
But if I had to pick least least,
if I'm with severe head trauma,
at least I don't have to when I retire,
at least take something back.
What does that make sense?
Yeah.
What do you think what but what the
from the actual doing of the sport,
and I know it probably
depends on the position,
but the say a free safety
or someone does that,
does a free safety take more head trauma
than somebody who is an active fighter
in the UFC? I don't think so. No.
I don't think she uses because they the
protection of the helmet on and then if
you're talking,
if you're a heavyweight,
you swine with other 260 plus pound
professional athletes and when you're
sparring,
especially now we have more,
we have more knowledge and guys aren't
sparring and much taking as much,
you know, hits. But I had a day,
I mean you get hit with a
jab from the UFC heavyweight,
it's gonna fuck your brain up man. And
you're going to get hit. It's what?
It's what you signed up for him? Yeah.
There's really no way around it. No.
It's part, it's part of the game. Talking
to Tony Jeffries, I mean when he was,
he was like calculating in the
how many fights, how many head,
how many hits he took to the head.
He didn't the average 55,000.
He said if he got hit, uh, six times
around in the head, which is low,
if you got to hit six times.
And he asked how many rounds he did an
amateur fights and pro fights came out to
white light.
You five thousand fifty five thousand
hits to the head and then I did,
I kind of did it on my calculator and he
was right. I was like, God damn. Well,
think about George Saint Pierre.
We know he got hit 800 plus
times inside the Oxford.
Crazy by world class fighters.
How many gloves on? Yeah.
How many times did you get hit in the
head of the gym? You know how many,
how many different rounds did he spar?
And he goes,
hard man has to those hard. He does, Huh?
And against the very best in the world.
Once they come out,
if they come up with a way
to regenerate brain cells,
they come up with a way to fix.
Like if they come up with some sort
of stem cell injection when they can
regenerate your tissue, oh then
we're good and we're good. Fuck yeah.
Until that had the best sport in the
world. Yeah. Then it's like, man,
why worry about it? Yeah. You know,
maybe they give you some shit.
It makes you way smarter
than everybody else.
Once you get brain damage like that movie.
What's that movie trying to
reverse engineer the brain.
That's the brain project
in both China and,
and they say they're not
even close to the brain.
So complicated that every everything else,
they're good brain.
They can't figure it difficult. It's
a 10 year project and then nuts. Yeah,
they just,
I think they're coming really close to
reverse engineering the red blood cell of
a dog, which means that then they'll
be able to do it with a human,
which really means they'll be able
to replicate it with a tiny machine.
Well,
that's what Kurzweil was saying.
Kurzweil was saying they're going to
come up with artificial blood cells that
are so efficient.
You'll be able to take one deep breath
and go to the bottom of a pool for an
hour. Yup. Yup. How about that?
How about that and sprint,
you'll be able to sprint on a breath.
I can just run two sports
will never be the same.
It won't be an ever be the
same. It'd be fun, man.
Thousand Years from now till strength
won't be, it won't be good. No,
it's going to be so different. It'll be,
it'll be the technology in your body.
What can you afford? You know, it's cool.
It will not cool as people are
going to be like, you know what?
I want my kid to play like Lebron
James and looked like Brad Pitt. Well,
but that raises that race is not good
playing level. Like you want people
to be different man raises what?
Like then if say you could do that,
say you can engineer and like
the perfect person, right?
Then it would then it would be,
it would raise really weird questions
about what a human being is because so
much of what we define a human being,
you know,
based on what their will and their
ability to figure out how to make someone
smart or make someone have
a good personality makes
someone have a funny sense
of humor. The sense of
humor, especially unique.
You can't really engineer
that with a computer.
How you put it all together and you may
even have a guy look like Brad Pitt all
you want. If somebody like you comes
along and goofs on him and he falls apart.
Thank Gosh, that's huge. Like look at you.
You're not genetically engineered Aria,
what would you have done without that?
Probably Starve. You know, they'll
get you your fucking science process.
You're going to walk away with a girl.
That's what we were talking about that
like with an athlete where were like,
there is in the human element,
there's the unmeasurable,
there's something called Sante
humor personality, things like,
so we were talking about
athletes like you can,
you can mention the best athlete I can
run the fastest, jumped the highest,
you know,
all that stuff.
Yet somehow they don't win games the way
somebody who does all that stuff in an
average way it does or not as well.
So Wayne Gretzky didn't have the fastest
slap shot and even close with in the
fastest skater.
Somehow he could put it all together.
And the question becomes how much of a
factor is that measure in when you talk
about how good an athlete,
somebody who does Larry Bird,
Larry Bird was never a great athlete,
but his fucking accuracy.
And those three pointers,
his competitive edge had edge demeanor
and confidence and disability.
Getting into the other player's head.
The biggest trash talker. Yeah. I mean,
you know, you're looking at a guy
that's like a pasty white dude.
It didn't look anything like Brian
James. So awesome. So dope that,
but that is that,
that weird human x factor that thank God
exists because technology may be moving
forward, but it, Tony, you're a
football fan when you watch it.
Do you care that there's brain
trauma going on? Oh, of course. Yeah.
It's fucking crazy. But you still watch
it every Sunday. Yeah. And fighting you.
What? Like you just what do you, so you
realize [inaudible] got brain damage.
Correct. Don't give a fuck. I got to,
I got a couple of bad concussions
back in high school. Wrestling days.
Got Stuck in a head, scissors and
a guy slammed my head, you know,
he pops back and I was out. I woke
up with Puke all over me on the mat.
That helmet that you were wearing, that
cryo helmet, those guys contacted me.
You liked that? I liked the, I like
what they're doing for, you know,
just cool me is a, a really cool
non profit organization, um,
that basically tries to get the word out
there that when you have head trauma,
uh, he was a veteran. Uh, I think Daniel
Damn, Daniel Ortega, Daniel or teas, uh,
I'm sorry, I can't, Daniel wins.
I was, I think his name is,
and he runs it and he was at, he
wasn't skinny, he was Mexican.
He was asking me this or take solid
solid Daniel Gonzalez. The last was,
sorry Daniel for not getting your new ido.
But Daniel was in the,
in the military and I
believe he's a medic.
And one of the things that they found is
that when you have head trauma and you
cool somebody immediately you cool their
head right away. It can, it can be very,
very beneficial to stopping
longterm, um, uh, trauma.
And this guy who, the Cryo
Hammad Guy Douglas, uh, he,
his brother's a boxer. He was a boxer
and his brother actually has a gym.
And so he created this basically this
cryo Hammad where you just put in the
freezer and you just put it on your
head after contact and he sent it to you
because you're worried about head trauma.
He told me though,
because he listens to the podcast,
he goes, stop boxing. He goes,
what are you doing? He goes, stop boxing
and don't box. There's no reason to,
and if you insist on it,
fucking cool your head.
But you're getting your bell
rung when your box. No, no.
I mean he'll catch me,
but it's not. I'm fine.
Then you go home and you put on
the cryo helmet. No, I don't do it.
I just got it.
I will now will.
The guy was smart sent to you and Joel
Road Elementary. He's a great guy.
It's very smart fighter.
But I'm doing it because I think
I just call me as a nonprofit.
I use barn with Wayne Macola.
Yeah.
And Wayne McCullough was just like
popping you going with when Mikala
[inaudible] Mikala moves around with me.
I try to his horse with other guys though.
I seen him as part of the you guys.
I'm like, what are you doing? But they're
not. What does it look like when, Gosh,
you haven't seen me in a long time. Well,
no, I was going to help you up. Brian.
Brian's foot works better and all of his
foot works better than all these guys.
I mean, he's not leaking
this fucking guy. Yeah, look,
so when you take off your cryo helmet,
is there a guy with a blow dryer and
a holster there to fix her hair? Yes.
Is, but Brian is getting hit
in the head when he's sparring.
Not Hard. Still hits to the head.
He's still trauma to the head. I know.
I like doing it though. I
liked box. I don't get it.
Why don't you just do Jujitsu?
That's why I fucking to start doing.
Why don't you do it? I'm going to, well,
why don't you, I'm trying to
box. I have time. I'll do it.
I played tennis. But you
were a good grappler when you
were a good grappler. Yeah,
I know. I missed the show. I remember
when we first started training,
when I first brought you in to Carlson
Gracie's, you will go hard, man.
You'd go after those.
You're going to roll this Saturday with
Tarik and Jake shields. I can't wait.
How will I do against Jake? Be you going
to get mauled? Come on dude. Oh Man.
You seen the way I hark and Jake shields.
Gene do great Brian.
She's just saying thank you and last
time you were old. It doesn't matter bro,
because what happens is I square up.
What are you going to do? Take me down.
Hold on a second. You guys can, uh, in
San Francisco. Is that what's going on?
You're going to train up there?
Fuck. Are you doing up there?
What are you guys done to get to the
punchline and then he's coming over and
we're going to have two
meetings with sponsors,
one for personal and one for the podcast,
and then we're going to have fun like row
with Jake Shields. I can't wait. Yeah,
that'd be fun for about three seconds.
I mean, I have no business piece.
It's squashed.
No pain with Jake first week of May
cause he's getting ready to fight.
So all he's working on his leg locks.
He's a fucking monster. Jake's a beast.
He's a very good man.
Very much the way to 20 really?
No one seven.
Exactly.
Once I got to understand like jobs
inside, my weight's on my feet. He's,
he's made out of lead
cut down to reign him.
If you cut down to one 40 I'll wrestle.
You wrestle off 40 I couldn't suck that
kind of weight cut loose 30 pounds.
I think you could do it, dude. I have
to do it. I think you'd do it, man.
I'd have thought. Yeah. What are
you scared? One 45 can I suck?
I have to do a cooking show yesterday
talking about my diet and how strict it
two oh five is based.
Just me bullshit him the whole
time they're going to hear this.
I don't give a fuck. They're like, so like
right now. Where are you at? I'm like,
like right now. No now. But like, yeah. Do
you have a scale here? I'm like, I don't,
so I wear like this tight black shirt.
I looked like fucking John Claude van
Damme like black shirt, but giants.
He is so enormous.
We were,
he hadn't eaten and we would done a
podcast and he's like, I'm starving.
I'm starving. And I can see the
friends. He'd look in his eyes.
He's got a food issue and horrible food
we'd go to to take away my favorite
places. He orders, he orders, he
orders a sandwich. That's the cooking.
Show me bullshit my way through this diet.
Where's this at? Where? That's my house.
Nice. Yeah. And so what does this
show? What does this cooking show? Ah,
just basically the beak ground. Slim
down because I, I know ray was there. No,
I said watch out. Like I wish Rachel
Ray was this. Yeah. Hell yeah.
She loves people and looked like a burly.
You look like a burly cook.
There you are. Early Cook. If you're
a cooking dude, do you know the car
model post that would go your way
with your shirt off? You know what
though? Like Shit, and I was so hungry.
We went to Juliana's takeaway so much and
he goes like this. He finally, he goes,
he looks at me, he looks at me
after we ate, and he goes and I go,
what's up with this? I'm getting
another piece of pizza, and I go, well,
kind of things. I am Brian. I'm
going to do it, and I, all right,
there's nothing goes great. You're not
going to jump off the 50 foot cliff.
He goes, I'm doing it. And he goes,
I'd like another piece please like a
little dot two cookies and you're talking
to a girl and I see her looking
at Mego. Brian, I'm debt. Yes,
I got your cookies and pizza, man. I'll
tell you what you've never seen before.
Who you want to see something nuts.
You need to see Ari Shaffir eat at
Fogo de Chao. I eat a lot of food too,
but I can't fuck with Ari when he has an
all you can eat buffet at Fogo de Chao
fogo they have the chip. They flip
it over. I don't know how he does it.
He got EOD. It's all of us.
It's because of his Jewishness.
He sees the opportunity to fulfill upon.
It's good.
It's like a berry just cause
it's all you can eat. It's,
I don't know how he does it,
but do you eat because you're,
I mean your lean dude and I see your post
at night where it's like Moose fucking
meat so you're not eating a lot of
carbs that doesn't put your weight on.
Well I don't eat much carbs.
It's like if I limit my pasta to like
only a couple portions a week and I live
at home, I'm bread. Yeah, I
don't, I don't believe in it.
I think pasta is mostly just dough
and gee, it's a fucking golf.
It's like when you eat it, it's
just doughy. Julie, massive fucking,
it's just so like coming.
And Lou did you just have great genetics?
Well I have really good genetics for sure,
but I definitely eat a lot of good food.
I get a lot of vegetables.
Like what was your breakfast? I haven't
eaten yet. Do you have any at all?
I hit this bar. Do you do that on
purpose? Like intermittent fast day,
late at night,
late at night.
And had five eggs and I had some
steak and I want to go sleep.
I can't eat protein at night. I
literally, I'm asleep if I did that.
If I eat eggs and steak or beef,
I would wake up two hours later in a
DNA hot sweat and I have to throw the
covers off and I would be up awake for
another three hours. I can't do it.
Guess what? I can sleep on carbs. Big Bowl
carbs. No problem. Why? Why is that? What?
It depends on your metabolic type
apparently from what I've read like,
and I'll give you a questionnaire.
Would you,
can you eat carbs at night and you sleep
well right through the night if you eat
protein, if I eat any
protein, I'm fucked. See I,
if I eat carbs like I
feel like weighed down.
Like if I eat a bowl of pasta,
I love Spaghetti man, like
Spaghetti and meatballs.
I'm in heaven. I love it. How about,
how about right after it's over,
it's just went after. It's over.
I'm just like, oh, I just hate glue.
You know what the,
you know what the problem I'm having
sticking to a strict diet is when you have
a goal, like when you know you have
a motherfucker look Andrea loss,
you're going to fight a cro cop.
It's easy to be strict as fuck right now
because you're afraid basically I have
a goal. You have a goal in mind. Like
right now, you know there's, there's no,
like I said, I'm only taking a
fight if it's a super fight. I told,
I told them that
so, but there's nothing set right. Right.
Right now it's like tonight I'm going
out to this dinner. It's like all right,
well usually I'd go out and I'd eat super
strict but in my head like when I get
the minion I'm like for what? Why would
I eat superstar? Just enjoy food man. I,
and then I'm worried about getting fat
and cause I have body dysmorphia. Yeah,
the best boss. Like girls, look at your
body. What about when we saw Mika Kelly,
how embarrassed was that? And I like sat,
I'm just kidding me. Kelly is, it is,
it is a, an actress and I think
she was on the hills or something.
She dated Derek Jeter. I, she got the
same place. She's, you hide your function.
She's looking, they're looking at him that
the three girls, I'm looking at Brent,
I'm going to turn Brennan and
Brennan goes like this, Brendan,
because we're eating how we're just
down the way. And he goes, um, I,
I'll take a box please.
I'm going to take this to go.
And I got hot and he puts it in
a box and I said, I was like,
that's weird and I'm eating away.
As soon as they leave, he goes,
I'll be honest with you. I didn't
want her to think I was a fat ass.
And he opens it up to stretch out
even remotely. Fallon, I don't know.
You know what I was telling,
Brian isn't telling me. He goes,
why are you like that?
Cause I'm not like,
like I don't look like Alistair Overeem
and when I was in high school or
girlfriends said something
to me before, like, oh, huge
competition. She's like, God,
be nicer.
If you had a little flatter stomach and
since then like my high school stupid by
the right time to get over
that, huh? Well, I don't
get bullied.
So time to get over that.
Get over that right now. It was
only 20 years ago. It was some time.
Some time. Man. Let's see here.
Would Vinny shoreman said the
hypnotist that I had in the podcast,
he was talking about this guy who was six
years old who was standing on a top of
a hill and he was looking down. He
was like, well, why don't you go down?
He goes down and those guys
are down there. They used
to bully me in high school.
He's 60 and the guys who used to
bully him in high school, we don't.
He was waiting for them to leave
before he went down. That said, whoa.
Like he was looking,
don't happen to me.
I got bullied for a full year
and it turned me into a fucking,
if somebody tried to blow me, I'll show
up at your fucking house and kill you.
That's what happens. I get so angry. I'm
not buying that. When he talks about,
I hate when you fucking
bullying bullying me right now.
You've talked to too many guys that
let you say shit like that and then it
becomes like vernacular comes like
a part of the way [inaudible].
I know when I first met you,
all those people used to hang around with.
Those are all toxic and they've ruined
the way you're allowed to communicate
with people because they said stupid shit.
And then you said if somebody who was
looks for any bro, look at how am I,
what do you have to say to me?
Well what's the scary movie with the law?
We have to hold on just
a scary movie with them.
And it was the most annoying thing
to me. What? He goes, fuck this guy.
I can wish a demon would grab me, man.
You know what I would do? And I'm like,
I get mad. Why are you talking to
me? He's like, not that you get mad.
It's so you hang around with people for
a long time you hung around with people
that allowed you to talk like that.
No, without mocking [inaudible] Bros,
Bros pros.
Let's not fuck some.
You bully me Bro. I don't give
a shit about your USC bullshit.
I will fucking come right at you.
I could pin it on the ground right now
and put me into the trial. You could try.
You could try and guess what?
She gets the Nice,
that's why I would fucking come right
to your house. You'd be dead Joe.
Yup. He needs friends like us cause he
gets it around saying guys who don't know,
I'm putting it away to muck
around with all lot of idiots.
There's a lot of people that he hangs
around with full of shit that they're,
they're, they're dumb. I feel sick.
I feel sick. You do. You hang out with
a lot of people that are such bullshit.
Artists know and you don't. You
know, you know who I'm talking about.
You have friends that are bullshit
artists and you don't even realize that.
You know.
You know why I know you do and you've
had them from the moment I met you and
they lie each other. I met Brian and 94
he's surrounded by idiots. I was like,
what's going on here? With
these fucking people. Come on.
They try to drag you away.
Slowly and surely guys,
I pushed those people off cliffs. Slowly
but surely I separating him from most,
they're like, hey, your friend
doesn't like me. I was like, well,
just a little hard to,
he's hard.
He can push a marrying one of them at
a certain point in time. I was like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Everybody was, everybody else was like,
it's good luck. Good luck brother. No,
it's going to work out. It's gonna work.
I'm like, what the fuck are you
talking about you out of your mind?
You out of your mind. It's just me and
patty were the only one that was telling.
I remember Gotti here. You're not
married. You did save me dude.
All meet people or I'll meet some people
with celebrities or not and for some
reason I was like, God, real
good. Fucking hate this purse.
That's the way I think of things like
job they would thing is that Joe will
actually like kind of let it be known
or at least just be kind of right away.
Just ignore them really hard and
I never do that. Well you can't.
You can't ruin my life.
Those people are that they, it's
almost like this. People have energy.
He's afraid it's going to stick to them.
They do stick to you.
They become a part of your life and then
you have to deal with their bullshit.
You have to do,
you have to like pretend that what
they're saying is not retarded.
And when you do that,
you compromise the way you think
and behave and communicate with you.
Nip It in the butt right away. Even
on your show, you nip it on. But,
but even like before we
can do a show in here,
this guy had this bullshit
machine and you're like, Bro,
this is fucking terrible.
That armbar thing.
Bone in my body.
I tried to help people's feelings since
meeting you. I'm getting better at it.
You can't do that because it's not bad
for them. I'm not saying you're a loser,
you're a bad person. I'm
saying this, this, the idea,
one plus one doesn't equal six. You know
it's funny, but saying it equals six.
I'm like, this is crazy. This is not,
there are two people I've known in
my life who had really bad breath.
One was a girl, the guy the worst route,
and nobody wants to tell the same guy,
the same guy. We know that's
another guy. You have three,
but I can't live your whole life and
have bad breath. No one says a word.
Want to sit there.
And I kept saying,
how do I tell this person?
And I never could because I felt
like I wasn't quite close enough.
But it was always, and so they've
been walking around with bad breath.
We have a mutual friend and I've
left it up to count. I go, bro,
tell him his breath smells
like pure shit broke.
It would ricochet off the car
window. And I'm like, who farted?
Who's bars in my car? Was his breath
like an open call Brian? I'm like, Bro,
please tell him no.
So we just chilled for a nice three
hour car ride in this pure shit.
Eat Shit. I just saw him the other day
too. The problem is, I don't know how,
what do you like? Oh yeah, bad breath. And
what do you say to them? Go to a doctor.
What's a doctor's wife would tell him?
I know your nose is broken.
Maybe she had a head injury. I think when
you have head injuries you're fucking,
your nose gets a year. No,
it doesn't work. Oh good.
Maybe Marcus Davis lost his sense of
smell for a long time. My friend. Yeah,
my Goddamn head trauma pho.
That's one of the things
that Rhonda Patrick talked
about when we had her on the
podcast.
She was talking about what the,
the mechanism that goes off
in your brain to protect you.
Like when you start getting really
serious head trauma, they just,
certain switches started just shutting
off. She's a circuit breakers.
Sense of smell is a big one. Taste
right. And some guys have taste, taste,
taste and smell and losing your
taste and smell. When you smell,
a lot of times you lose your taste
as well. Yeah, yeah. I connected.
Yeah. I mean you're fine. You're fine.
Right now it's the w, you know the,
the guys who just continued to get that
fucking head trauma over and over and
over and over and over and over and over
and over and over and over and over.
No trouble. And then the gate and I like
the knee than what we're talking about.
Dude. I'm honestly, I'm
going to get spot man.
Like I was telling Brian this the other
day, like before companions like, dude,
I can't before fight
companions before the podcast.
Sometimes I can't sleep at night.
I'm so excited to do it. When, when,
when our shirts we get released,
it's the same to me is that when I fight
I'm that excite for them to fucking
drop. And so that's awesome.
It's awesome man. Thank you.
So long as you're doing
something you really enjoy,
that is really the key to life purpose,
but you want to wake up with a
perfect cause. He shows that we're,
we've been doing lately,
you're working on new material and
just like trying to get it together.
Like it's exciting before while
you're doing it. And Caitlin,
it's exciting when it, and afterwards
you listening to the recordings,
trying to figure out how to tweak
the joke and add this to it.
As long as you're doing something,
building something. Yeah. It's,
it's building something.
Yeah.
So I think one of the big problems that
we were talking about like fighters have
is at once the career's over, there's
no more progress. There's nothing.
Where do you place your energy?
Yeah. What's happening? Where's your,
where's your excitement?
You know,
you mean there's only so
many gyms you can open. Yeah.
And that's not gonna
fulfill that fucking the,
the constant pulse you always used.
Didn't really know what I'm saying.
I don't know what you do, man. The answer.
Believe me, I'd fucking kill everybody.
And that's why a lot of guys
like the one I'm going to drugs.
They want to go into something
to try to forget it, man. Yeah.
Recharge that excitement.
Yeah. Get that juice. Need it.
Get your shit together,
bitches.
We're going to wrap this up nice and
tight with a big fat bow fighter and the
kid.com Tony motherfucking in the house.
Uh, Tony, you got some dates
coming up besides the ones with me?
Uh, yeah. I'm going to be in Toronto
at just for laughs at the, at the,
at the end of summer whenever Toronto
just for laughs. It's a Google that shit.
That's an a summer, right?
Yeah, it doesn't, it. Uh, Tony
hinchcliffe.com. Yeah, Tony.
But ours is actually t f a t
k.com. Oh, it's not firing the kid.
Now do you have that? We have the
fire and the kids shop.com. Okay.
Let's t f t t t t J.
Dot.
Fat Fighter and the kid.com.
The first letter of each of those things.
Just come see me in San Francisco.
Brian [inaudible] with a y on Twitter.
Brendan Schaub in the mother fucker.
Oh,
Aka big brown Joe Rogan. Dot
Net tours, tour dates. Uh,
they've got a bunch of shit coming up.
Uh, but it'd be with Tony July 10th.
We're going to be at the cop theater with
Thompson Euro. A lot of shit coming up.
A lot of shit. All right. A lot
of podcasts. Next week until then,
much love big kiss.
Bye Bye.