Okay.
Well,
good experience Joe Rogan podcast by
night all day.
We are now live.
Jeff Ross is the first time we've ever
done a live podcast from the comedy
store.
And it's with you buddy.
I feel like we're in Hitler's bunker,
which was,
I think Hillary was Boehner's.
It probably not as well lit.
Definitely didn't have the sound
dampening.
That's how you know it's a real podcast
studio.
They have this shit.
The sound dampening sound dampening
stuff.
Do you see it?
It's cool though.
It's in the color.
The color of the comedy store.
Again,
the old old comedy store sign in the
background and uh,
we figured fuck it.
We're here all the time.
Usually I'm just here hanging around
after.
Why not do a podcast?
Have some fun.
I love it.
Hi everybody.
Happy Thursday.
So this is how many about you fucking
show tell you're,
you're a roast battle is on comedy
central.
It's crazy,
man.
It's amazing.
Started out in the belly room.
You know,
you came in great.
It's one of the reasons why I came back
to the store.
When I came to see that show in the
belly room.
I was like,
wow.
It was the day before Ari film this
special.
And uh,
I hadn't been to the store in seven
years and I remember I came here for you
at the Improv that night.
Yeah,
I'd seen you a couple,
a tip and Finney at the Improv Aranow I
kept talking about it.
That's where I was doing sets.
I kind of made it a personal mission to
bring you back to the comedy store.
Oh,
sweetie.
And roast battle was the bait.
Well,
he roast battle definitely helped to
also because it was so electric.
I was like,
man,
there's something going on in this
place.
I love doing the show so much.
And the comics love doing it.
It's the only competition show where
comics who aren't even on the show come
to watch other comics.
Yeah,
it's insane.
It's one of the rare shows were comics
come to watch.
Other comics were shooting in the old
house of blues across the street.
They're knocking it down and a couple of
weeks of building condos forever.
Very historic building.
It's kind of crazy.
So our producer Joel and had the idea to
go in there,
pull the stage,
I'll clean it up.
There was like all kinds of stuff living
in there.
And we built our roast battle arena
inside the old house of Blues for four
nights.
I can't believe this is happening.
That's crazy.
It's like,
you know the early days of wrestling or
fighting or something.
I can't believe it.
Turn it into condos.
That stuff's hard to realize that that's
what we're going to have across the
street.
But maybe it will be good in some way.
Well I bet a lot of comics who are just
going to get a fucking apartment there.
If you can afford it,
that'd be amazing.
Stumble out of bar across the street
about that.
Why not live there?
I mean,
come on man.
It'd be the greatest.
And if you have a reluctant girl,
you know,
you're uh,
trying to meet a young lady and you're
like,
come on back to my place.
Wow.
I mean,
I'm getting kinda tired.
Listen baby,
it's just across the street.
Yeah,
come on over.
I mean we don't,
we have,
I mean you are kind of funny and I just
want you to know I'm not that kind of
girl.
Well because we'll play,
we'll play ping pong in my a rec room.
Paint.
Ping Pong is a good one to play.
Everyone thinks he know how to play
foosball,
right?
I'm not,
I don't know.
Do they?
Yeah.
A lot of drunk people think they know
how to play the whole foods thing.
Nobody knows how to play ping pong like
a few people do,
but those are,
they're assholes.
I have two Chinese cousins and they're
very good at China and ping pong go
together for some reason.
Is that video,
has anyone seen that video of Bruce Lee
hitting done chucks?
Is that a real,
real damn.
Why did you think it was real?
It looks so fucking fake.
I could eat glass.
Imagine if he was a world champion Ping
Pong player plus this martial arts
master and even take it.
In fact it is ping pong was that good?
That was more like he was hitting the
ball without,
what's he doing it with nunchucks?
Yeah.
Yeah,
sure.
I can't,
I don't even know why I answered that.
I should have told you.
Yes
Bro.
Boosie was a master.
Never wanted to know what I shouldn't
have asked
night or Eddie Griffin was telling a
Bruce Lee story and Eddie griff was just
drunk as fuck and he was making up some
Bruce Lee store.
He's like,
it was 39 people in the room when he
died.
All of them attack Bruce Lee,
18 of them died before
God.
I'm like,
wow.
I was like,
what?
he had like an allergic reaction to a
drug or something.
They're like a blood clot or something.
I don't know.
Something you think some people think
that Chinese triad had?
I'm whacked.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Cause you know his son Brandon died on
the set of a movie where they had a fake
gun,
like a gun with a blank and they shot at
him and there was something inside the
gun and it wound up killing him.
Yeah.
What a way to go.
Was it a stunt man who shot him or
another way?
I think it was another actor and they
from then on,
they now they made a new rule after
that.
I think this might be bullshit,
but I think the new rule was what I had
heard was that you can't point a gun at
someone when you shoot them.
Like instead of shooting you with a
blank,
if you and I were in a movie and I was
going to shoot you the blank,
I'd have to do that.
Or it looks like from over there that
I'm shooting at you,
but I'm really shooting to the left of
it.
Fascinating.
Wow.
I guess I never realized that syteline
is weird.
Yeah.
You remember his brother,
the chro or the sun rather than the
movie the crow.
It was cool and they did after they had
a finish it without them or something.
Yeah.
They had to like hire some guy to
pretend to be him.
I think it's 2017 we're almost done with
January.
It not one major celebrity has died in
any way.
Yeah.
Crazy.
How amazing.
How many dropped off right before the
end though.
Carrie Fisher was a bummer.
That was crazy.
Who else died?
Prince.
Prince George.
Michael.
David Bowie.
Prince is a bad one,
man.
He died from fucking pain pills.
It would go to,
we lost fish a year ago.
Really?
Beginning of
last year.
Oh Shit.
Tough one.
I don't have about 75 years old.
He was at least that old.
What was it about Barney is sag number
was three.
Barney Miller,
right?
Was that a those onto a plate shot?
Barney Miller and then he had fish.
She was on his own show.
He was in the godfather movies.
That true.
He had to spin off though,
right?
If fish.
Yeah.
That was this.
That was also,
that shows only on one season.
But everyone remembers it
for one season.
Never heard of it.
You didn't remember.
Fish lasted one season and everyone
remembers it.
This.
Now that you know,
you know you've been on tv a bunch of
times and you know you've had your own
show and now you've got rose paddle on.
Do you think there's so many shows on
now with so many networks and so many
channels and then the streaming shit
like Netflix and Hulu and you know CSO
and a million and it's almost like
there's too much content.
I think it's just for some reason more
narrowed.
You know you get your exact audience.
That's true.
Strange.
You know like Doug Benson had something
for pot smokers and someone else has
something for home improvement and then
there's a 30 a channel just for cooking
shows and it's kind of like that I guess
a otherwise it's hard to understand.
Well it's,
it's hard to get people to know about
your show just from TV.
Right?
You need like some sort of a web
presence and some sort of a social media
presence and something else.
It's like regular shows.
Like if you just put it on after a
successful show,
nobody knows what the fuck it is.
They just change the channel to
something they do know.
Right.
Interesting.
There's almost too many things going on
now,
Jeff.
That's what's hard about it.
It's launching any TV show and roared
doing our show is a tournament like as
an event.
So by the time you even know it's on,
it's over.
Yeah,
but it's so good.
It's so good.
It can't lose.
That's,
that's a show.
When when they said that they were going
to turn that into a television show,
my,
that campus,
it can't miss.
And I,
you know,
especially if you could figure out a way
to do them all in the belly room.
I really feel like the belly room is
something special.
It really is.
The magic is something.
It's so intimate.
It's so,
and when you see someone get fucking
crushed in the belly room,
like I've heard some goddamn titanic
lines up there.
What did Kim Kong did say about this
girl?
She said,
oh,
she said she's not union but her tits or
sad.
It really is a joke.
Writers showcase.
It is.
Well you want it to last next weekend.
I don't know when you were posting were
alive.
So it's,
yeah,
we're live now.
We're live now.
Hi,
I forgot.
So when is it a 26 27 28 and 29 January,
four nights in a row and it has it
already.
It's a bracketed tournament.
We're started taping tomorrow and then
the finale is live on the 29th that's
awesome.
Live on TV.
It's fun right now because right around
we're in the comedy store right now.
All the New York comics are staying
across the street,
so they're all coming over to check out
the comedy store and now we're shooting
across the street,
the old house of Blues.
So like this whole little neighborhood
is going to be roast battle neighborhood
for a week or so.
You hear the piano?
It's kind of great.
We're downstairs below the original
rooms
underground.
That's what we're going to call it
underground at the comedy store.
Right.
Perfect.
Because we're underground.
That's what we'll call it.
You got it.
Love that.
Live underground from the comedy store.
Fuck yeah.
Cause you can hear,
he can hear comics killing up there and
you can hear the piano music.
It's fucking oss.
Got a real feel to it bro.
Dude,
you shaved your eyebrows.
I ran into you in New York five months
ago and you had shaved your eyebrows.
How do I look now?
They're kind of not fit back yet.
I'm a strange looking guy.
Rogan.
I mean,
how long has it taken for eyebrows to
grow back?
It could be a lifetime.
That's fucking nuts.
That's so weird.
Like I,
I thought eyebrows would be like a
beard.
Like you don't really have hair on my
body.
You don't feel like your body here.
Like my sister's never shaved her legs.
Look,
Greg Fitzsimmons everybody come on in
Greg.
Fuck yeah,
get in here buddy.
We saved you a spot.
Isn't this cool?
Hi Greg.
Good.
You are for here.
This one's fine.
Okay,
beautiful.
Welcome to Hitler's bunker.
I know.
Can we geva no.
How would you say,
how was your set?
You know,
it was one of those crowds where if you
did new shit that you were excited
about,
they were with you and as soon as you
did a bit that had any dust on it,
they just fucking flatlined.
So do you think
that was you or they felt they felt it
and you
always,
definitely me.
It was me because I felt like when you
have new stuff,
you get so excited about doing it that
you come alive and you're,
you're not reciting it.
You're really saying it.
And then when the transition into shit
that you've been doing for too long,
you lose that freshness and they sensed
this as difference between the,
the material.
There's a moment when you're doing an
old bit where you're,
you have so much shame and you try it.
He tried to like reignite it,
power it up and it doesn't work.
Oh,
why am I still doing this?
Fucking shitty.
Yay.
It's like when you see a guy yelling at
his son and a parking lot and he doesn't
even believe it.
He's just doing it because he thinks
that's how it filed.
They suppose that,
yeah.
You know what's even worse is when you
see someone yelling at their kid and
then you look over and you make eye
contact with them and they realize they
shouldn't be yelling at their kid and
lost their cool.
Plus.
I can imagine you are looking at a guy
who was yelling at his kid.
There's probably a little bit of a
medicine left on your face.
I try not to be,
I try to be kind.
Yeah.
I don't want to be menacing to parents
or audiences for them.
I don't know.
I don't yell at my kids,
man.
I might raise my voice occasionally if
we're doing something really fucked up,
like they're being mean to each other.
But,
uh,
I remember people yelling at me,
man like that the cortisol rhythm
reaction,
you know,
that happens in a kid's brain and all
those stress hormones that get released,
it's like there's plenty of fucking bad
shit going on in the world.
They don't need their parents yelling at
him too well,
especially when you put it in
perspective,
like your parent at any given time is
possibly three or four times bigger than
you.
Oh yeah.
And then when they yell at you on top of
that,
that's really,
that's fucking intimidating.
Well,
like a couple of pussies.
Right.
And we have kids become a pussy.
You definitely do.
In a certain way you become a pussy.
Yeah.
You definitely,
the good thing about that,
me not yelling is my fucking six year
old is not even remotely scared of me.
Not even a little shit.
She mocks me like openly.
Like I go,
hey listen,
you can't do that.
Shoot.
Yeah.
She sticks her tongue out at me and
she's not even like a little nervous
around me.
Like maybe I should be a little harder.
Just leave some videotapes a you doing
Jiu Jitsu on somebody just in a loop.
White teacher.
I teach my kids,
you know,
they take martial arts and my six year
old is actually a higher rank than my a
eight year old.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I think that gives them the confidence
to talk smack at you now.
No,
it hits me.
I can block it.
No,
I don't think that's it.
I just think they know I'm not going to
do anything.
They,
they beat the shit out of me though.
They're allowed to hit me like a cause.
There are a lot of practice techniques
on me.
I laugh at them full blast leg kicks.
So especially my eight year old,
she could fucking hit hard man.
She'll like step into a leg kick and
cry.
Like you know,
she lets me know she's going to do it,
but I let her do it so she could feel
what it's like to hit a real person.
Like as hard as you want.
Yeah.
You're her meat puppet.
It's interesting.
You know Jeff Ross,
a black belt in taekwondo.
I did know that.
Yeah.
What year did you begin to digress?
I was not even 11 host who's a junior
black belt.
Easy Buddy.
Hey,
that's nice though.
It says it's great if you find a major
lack,
but I had a teach adults in order to get
my black belt,
he really to teach adults.
Really?
That was part of the test.
You learn a lot when you teach.
That's true.
Your son's a black belt,
right?
Yeah.
Junior black belt,
junior black belt,
and he did it for like eight years.
A lot of different schools that I've
looked at that age was pretty great.
What's tough is once they get the black
belt,
there's not new forms to learn.
It's just perfecting what you've already
learned and a lot does a big dropoff
because kids are so,
and they're so used to getting a new
belt and learning new,
what do they call it?
Katas.
Yeah,
depending on it's either,
yeah,
it's a,
depending on what,
what style Art Katas is actually a
Japanese word and it depends on what
martial art,
like in Taekwondo,
I think they called it wasn't boom says,
yeah.
Says,
and it's different for other styles of
Korean martial arts.
I have a different name for it too,
but um,
yeah.
Well you can go to higher degrees
though.
You can get like a second degree.
Third,
it takes a while.
Yeah.
It takes a different mentality to go to
that level.
Yeah.
That is a thing,
man.
Once people achieve black belt,
they feel like they're done.
You know,
they're,
the mountain has been climbed.
No.
That's one thing that you'd done.
Well I guess he kind of have that at all
martial arts,
but TACO window,
you're doing a lot of,
uh,
like light contact sparring,
you know,
and because of that,
I think,
uh,
it's not as engaging as like Jiu Jitsu
because Ju Jitsu is kind of like full
blast because you're not hitting each
other.
You just like doing chokes and arm bars
and stuff like that.
And as long as someone has control,
like,
you know,
and they don't hurt you.
Like,
you know,
when someone is in a bad position,
you don't like if you know you have
someone's arm and there it's totally
locked out.
Even if they're not tapping,
you're not going to break it.
You know what to do.
You know,
like when it's breaking and when it's
not.
So
I usually just wait till somebody gets
interaction.
Then we call it a day.
Do you finish them off?
Oh yeah.
Fuck yeah man.
I was just saying any joke last night on
your shell and just kind of came up,
but somebody goes,
ah,
I see this guy goes,
I'd have sex with you.
And I go,
I go,
oh,
that's nice.
He goes,
he goes,
but I'd be the top.
I go,
of course you'd be the top.
Because the only way,
and he was fucking me is I'm flat on my
face and you just tackled me and it's
probably a threeway.
That's the only way I'm getting fucked
as these two guys and I'm the bottom.
There's something there could be.
What's the closest he ever came to fool
around with a guy,
Jeff,
right now.
Not Close.
Not Close at all.
This conversation you ever got high and
like,
uh,
not
what happened.
He just cut himself off.
He's like,
God can't,
you can't.
You know what he's thinking now.
This is part of the problem with being
the roastmaster.
You think someone's going to use this
one to me in a roast?
Yeah.
It could be a real shot.
Soft under belly.
Do you think you'll ever wound up
battling on Rose Battle?
Definitely road.
I think you already preparing.
No,
I just think about how it would work.
You know,
I look at like who I would be fun to
battle.
You know,
I'm obviously a big,
easy target for a guy who works the door
here.
He's going to destroy me,
you know,
like it's like of course how the mighty
will fall,
but I still think it would be fun
anyway.
What does it feel like knowing that you
roasted the president of the United
States?
You rose to trump is it is totally and
totally a weird feeling.
And I saw him a couple of weeks ago.
I saw him down in Florida and exchanged
pleasantries and I'll let you your kid
and you were just talking about that on
stage.
I saw him,
uh,
in Palm Beach and uh,
his golf course and his golf course
having lunch
already stand your life,
Jeff.
Ross is life is like nobody else.
I follow him on fucking instagram and
like every night he's in a different
city with a different set of cool
people.
Well,
when you're a man,
you don't have children,
right?
Not Married.
You can do whatever the fuck do you want
Jesus.
What a life.
Yeah,
you really do have a good life in that
regard.
You're free as a bird.
It is cool.
How the fuck have you managed to not get
tied down?
I'm ready to get tied down.
I already,
I wish I'd say they say that I wish I
was meeting.
Who could?
Who could do that are around us.
That's not true.
I would like to settle down.
Really?
Yeah.
I haven't met the right person.
Hmm.
Well,
how come you haven't met the right
person?
You're in a new city every night.
You fuck constantly travel maybe.
Yeah.
Maybe I'm looking in the wrong way.
Do you think he came close a couple
times?
Do you think you'll have a little jeff
someday?
I really hope so.
I really how old?
He knew 51 that's all over.
Why?
Because your was bad.
I really think so.
If it tastes good,
it's probably better.
It's probably like middle freak me out.
Don't freak me out.
You already told me that the Bruce Lee
video wasn't where he thought.
The Bruce Lee video.
Bruce Lee playing ping pong with
nunchucks.
He thought that was rude.
How are you serious?
They're round known checks are brown and
blue.
Fuck his back.
Good time.
It you'd have to time.
I like the ping pong.
It's not like a paddle.
This is like a rigid thing where you can
kind of hit it.
You hit the time to swing it a thing.
I thought it was a bad ass.
Well,
he was definitely a bad ass.
No doubt about it.
Huh?
He was the original mixed martial
artist.
Yeah.
You think might come as bad.
It's probably not good.
You probably have to get a nephew or
somebody to kick in some of Greg's com.
Greg still got a couple of good swimmers
in this terrible news.
At a certain age when men have children,
there is a high risk of autism is
somebody was mocking trump,
I think it was Rosie O'donnell was
mocking trump's kid.
Donald did.
Yeah.
Which I thought was like,
wow,
I know that.
He said some fucked up shit about her.
Uh,
going after his kid like that.
It's like that's how it shows you how
much he hurt her.
Yeah.
She wrote a poem about how depressed she
was when he became president.
When he won.
No,
it wasn't.
He hadn't even one yet.
He made fun of her in a debate and one
of the debates he was talking like
someone said he talked bad about women.
He's like,
well Rosie O'donnell,
what?
Everybody agrees with me.
Yeah.
And he like,
he got a laugh and apparently she was
just,
she called this kid autistic later.
It was after that,
like after that.
I think she was just like crushed.
Yeah,
she was talking about how sad she was
and I like she couldn't go outside and
have been seen as kid.
Does he look autistic?
Suck a fucking kid know he's a tall,
good looking kid.
He's got a launch kit.
He gave him Rhode Island for Christmas.
The comedy store.
Well the kids 10 and he's 70 yeah.
Yeah.
I mean so he 60 when he
shot one in Jesus.
Because the thing is now you just think
about how much your cell phone is in
your pocket,
how many waves are going through your
Siem and all the time you don't put it
in your pocket.
You do.
Why does everybody think that radiation
is bad?
I remember when we were kids.
Yeah,
Comic Book Guys got Radiation.
Those are the heroes,
but then became heroes.
Don't sit too close to the TV they used
to tell you.
Yeah,
they were worried about that.
But I think that was for your eyes.
Right,
but like,
like radiation in comic books,
it always does.
Good Shit.
Yeah.
You know,
people get the right.
People go radiation when they're ill.
It's a healing thing now.
Not really.
They do to kill the tumor,
but it kills you to,
it just kills the tumor more that it
kills you.
It kills the tumor first and it brings
you to the door of death and then you
pull back and start drinking wheat grass
juice and getting your life together.
That's right.
I just started some probiotics online
today.
Oh yeah.
You should eat the um,
actual live probiotics.
Oh really?
Yeah.
She Yogurt Kiefer's.
Yeah,
all that stuff.
I'm a big proponent of probiotics.
I eat a lot of it,
man.
It's huge.
Like what,
what is that Kim Cheat?
Well,
probiotics is,
anytime you're taking in like healthy
bacteria,
like a,
whether it's in the form of yogurt,
Acidophilus,
a Sauerkraut is actually a healthy,
especially raw sauerkraut.
Actually a very good probiotic.
Huh?
Really good for you.
It was a lot of like natural food
stores,
like whole foods type places that have
probiotic sauerkrauts really good for
you because it's fermented and anytime
you fermenting something,
what's happening is like this bacteria
is,
uh,
you know,
living on the food.
So like,
like when you're eating Kimchi,
there's bacteria living on the food,
but it's healthy bacteria.
Okay.
Cause I fart so bad and it's been,
it's been years,
I think it caught grd.
And when I was down in Florida really?
And it just rings or creek,
no tap water in Florida,
man,
you're not supposed to drink it.
It's the worst tap water in America.
But because it's a sandbar,
there's no fucking fresh water down
there.
Yeah.
But it's an all tap water treated with
chlorine.
Yeah.
But there's only so much they can do
with that shit down there.
Look at those people.
And so I started farting and it just,
I took,
I went on all kinds of antibiotics and I
got rid of like a bulk of it.
But the farts have remained.
And so somebody told me to probe
probiotics can clear it up if you ever
heard that when people get poop,
um,
transfusions now,
yeah.
They'll take poop from a healthy
personal,
yes.
Yes.
It's a real fast to ass.
Well,
they don't make you go,
but I think they go in and fish it out
and they shoot it up in you.
Well,
they literally will shoot somebody
else's poop up your up your asshole into
your body.
Yeah.
And some people even swallow poop
tablets.
Wow.
Yeah.
Did never heard that.
They do.
To,
um,
to people that have like really
unhealthy gut biomes.
And one of the,
with a lot of people is antibiotics.
When you take antibiotics,
it doesn't just kill the bad stuff.
It kills good stuff too.
Oh,
they just had the first woman who
couldn't be cured by antibiotics that
you read about that?
No.
Yeah,
she had some kind of a,
I don't know what it was.
It was some kind of a,
a bacteria commercial.
You know,
I,
I wish I knew more about the story,
but um,
I dunno.
Maybe we can look it up on the Internet,
but it was the first time that they
tried every type of antibiotic and it
didn't work and they said that this
could mark the beginning of untreatable
viruses.
So bacteria virus,
I guess bacteria.
Bacteria is right.
You don't treat viruses with
antibiotics?
I don't think so.
You tune antiviral medications a
different thing,
right?
We've but bacteria like as far as,
um,
like the stuff that you get like from
staph infections and stuff like that has
gotten stronger and stronger over the
years.
Yeah.
Especially in hospitals,
man.
There's a lot of people that catch
Murcia from hospitals and they fucking
wind up dying.
Yeah.
Hell yeah.
Big issue.
Guys are really depressing me.
I'm sorry.
Come on man.
Do you have a,
do you have a light?
Yeah,
I do.
so,
so we are in the final hours before the
inauguration.
The inauguration.
It's a crazy time.
I didn't think that I would be this.
I really thought after the election I
would wrap my head around it and I would
be like,
okay,
this is normal.
Trump is going to be president.
Like I would have some sense of like,
okay,
I don't feel any more,
um,
uh,
ready for this.
Then I was denied after the election.
No,
it's weird.
It's 100% weird.
I was watching this video that someone
was playing,
um,
on their instagram page where they were
there while trump was walking into this
room and DC and surrounded by secret
service agents and all these sycophants
and all these weird people around them.
And this guy's yelling out.
Thank you Mr. Trump.
Thank you.
You are a god send sir.
You're a god.
Andrew Santiago.
Ladies and gentlemen,
come on in.
Have a seat fellow.
You're coming in right at the time.
Jeff Ross is handing you a joint.
Oh,
thank you,
Jodi.
Thank you.
Please gentlemen.
Andrew Sandino,
a live netflix special on the way trump
supporter,
by the way.
You voted five times.
Huge trump supporter.
I voted as many times as I could.
I kept doing it.
He had a fake id,
pretended to be Mexican.
I did actually.
Yeah.
Became Andrew.
Andrew.
Andrew sent,
Dino said [inaudible].
So I switched it up.
Teen sent Dino.
Yeah.
Santiago big,
big trump supporter fits you are to,
well,
I'll just say right now ladies,
get your abortions before noon tomorrow.
Don't you think trump's had a lot of
girls get abortions?
I think he's going to back off.
Are you shitting me?
He's got a frequent fetus card.
Oh yeah.
He's,
he's,
he's driven a few ladies off it to the
clinic.
Of course.
Absolutely.
That's his thing.
Well,
they were saying that about Gw Bush is
that there was a pretty well documented
case when he was in college.
Pretty good at Texas or something.
Yeah.
Uh,
that he,
that he went to college,
he went to,
he went,
he went to Yale.
Didn't he know Wharton School of
business?
No.
That's trump
talking about gw.
We didn't want to go to you.
Yeah.
Yeah,
because he was in his colon bones.
Right.
Cheat all the bushes.
That's one of those grandfathered in
things though,
right?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Your whole family.
Barbara Bush double suicide to get out
of going to the,
all right.
What do they do it hospital.
Really?
Yeah.
They're both time right now on.
Why don't we just start taking our
money?
Can you charge?
He maybe we should stop taking a better
car.
We won't have to go to the inauguration.
I want to go skydiving.
I is Martha Washington and my Bedroom
Jab.
Put that down,
see him for years.
And then I saw him recently and he was
in a wheelchair on some,
some interview in some video and it made
you realize like,
wow,
it's been a while.
Think that Carter is still alive and a w
is still alive.
He holds Carter Bush.
He's old.
He was old president 76 was he?
Yeah,
he was already old.
he was an interesting guy,
man.
You know,
Carter didn't really get a fair shake.
Who's a go to the presidential library?
Carter's in Atlanta is awesome.
You should check it out.
Well,
I heard some speeches that he gave
before when he was running for president
back when hunters Thompson recorded less
speech that he gave at one of those
Washington's it out.
No,
I'm good.
I'm good too.
Oh Jesus.
It was a,
it was in that movie.
Fear and loathing,
not fear in loading the other one,
um,
Gonzo the life and works of Dr. Hunter s
Thompson,
the documentary on him.
Really interesting man.
Like Carter was,
you know,
he was pretty intense and moral guy like
very,
very powerfully.
So
he was a good Christian.
He was the good kind of Christian.
Well because I think people can use
Christianity as a way of feeling better
then.
Yeah.
Or you can be or it can be a life of
service and he was very much,
life is service but there's like two,
there's like the,
the the way that like my dad goes to
church still just cause he just likes
the people that are there more so than
anything else.
He's like I just want to go see fucking
people that I've known for 40 years.
He's like,
I don't really listen to ever.
I mean like my dad is a tourist had just
fallen asleep and park every single
time.
He just there to like see some friends
before and after.
It's a fucking,
it's a club.
But do you love?
I mean,
cause here's,
I'm,
I go back and forth on religion because
it's so easy to take like the,
uh,
you know,
the agnostic route and say that all
religion is evil and all that,
but it's like so much good has happened
because of organized religion.
I'm,
you look at what the Jews have done in
this country with the just fucking
hospitals alone.
And then you got Christians that had
gone to Central America,
you know,
nuns that of fucking save villages and
know for sure.
Yeah.
There's tons of good stuff.
I think it's,
I think the cheap fucking route is to
say that religion sucks just because
that's a blunt,
easy blanket to go fuck religion.
It's just caused every war.
It's the worst thing.
It's like,
yeah,
there's a lot of fucking negatives to
it.
Yeah.
You know,
that blamed it on every war.
But war is something that's caused by
people and people would have found a
reason to go to war.
They go to war because they're apes,
they go to war because apes fight
against apes.
It's like they're always dominating for
that Alpha position.
If they're blaming it on religion,
it's just a convenient reason to go fuck
somebody up.
They would have done it if they had
diamonds or they'd do it for oil.
Yeah.
That's the thing in Ireland,
they try to pretend that the,
it's a war between the Protestants and
the Catholics.
No,
it's the fucking Brits trying to
colonize and destroy a population of
people.
Yeah,
that's it.
And people get tribal.
They did.
You know,
people will fight.
The fucking raiders will fight the
eagles.
You know the fans.
We'll meet in the parking lot and have a
fucking gang.
That's just what people do for a shirt
color.
They just want the people do mean didn't
they?
They beat some guy almost to death in
dodger stadium.
They put him in a coma.
Horrible.
San Francisco Fan.
Some guy with his kid,
right?
Yeah.
Kids.
His kids with him.
And he was dead.
Two dudes just,
I think the kid was autistic,
was he was going to say help himself.
His
instincts took over.
He was autistic.
Yeah.
It's just crazy how tribal people are
and that's one of the things that you're
seeing with the selection too,
whether you're a trump supporter or a
hillary supporter or a Bernie supporter,
whatever.
If you just can step back from it for a
second and look at it objectively,
what you're seeing is these people that
are like blindly loyal to one side or
the other and then you just see giant
clumps of them that move in that
direction and very few people who look
at it and have like a balanced
perspective that's outside of like an
ideology.
Very.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Like very few people are going,
well,
we got this guy who won a popularity
contest and he's the first actually
popular person who wants popularity
contest and everybody else who's been
one of its popularity contest.
It's just spinning this one select
group.
So in that sense it's a good thing
because it's going to be a disruptive
thing and this system is not good.
It's not good to have the same fucking
families run the country over and over
again and have the same bureaucracy,
that same red tape,
all the shit that people have had to
deal with when it comes to politics.
Like it's not a perfect system and it's
not getting improved.
One of the reasons it doesn't get
improved just cause the people that run
the system have a,
uh,
they have,
like a concerted,
it was,
there's a great benefit for them to keep
the system in place.
There's plenty of job,
there's plenty of people doing it.
There's plenty of red tape.
There's of confused as plenty
of debate in influence and,
and it goes back and forth from side to
side and all that keeps it relevant and
it keeps people from stopping and
saying,
why are there these two groups?
One is right and one is left,
one's conservative ones liberal.
When most of us are a combination of all
those things.
Well not only that,
it's a,
it's,
you know,
it's all projections by the big business
to say there's even a right and a left.
They,
they've got both there pulling the
strings on both sides.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I was saying that,
that,
that I remember like coming around the
store and listen to people at the
beginning of the campaign in trump's
campaign,
you know,
like vehemently hated him so much and,
and that kind of like extremism was the
same for like Bernie support.
Like the Bernie chaos.
Like the Bernie thing was crazy.
I mean it was like the same kind of
crazy Catholic like fuck anybody but
Bernie and the trump supporters are the
same way.
I was like,
fuck anybody but Donald Trump,
it was like extremes on both sides.
And it's the same thing.
At some point you're,
you're on a level plane,
right?
Zero is the same as a hundred.
You know what I mean?
Like if I said,
if I said to a friend of mine,
how gay are you on a percentage scale?
Zero to a hundred and if a guy says,
if a guy says,
uh,
a hundred,
okay,
he's gay.
And then if a guy says,
second guy says,
Oh yeah,
I'm,
you know,
48 I'd be like,
okay,
I get that.
Yeah,
that's tendencies.
Yeah.
Yeah,
Jeff,
me.
But then if a guy says zero,
I'm zero.
Fuck that.
It's the same as the hundred guys.
Extremism is the same.
It's just a different,
it's just a different angle.
But there's not enough people that are
40% gay.
There's a lot of people in the middle of
it all.
Yeah.
And a lot of people try to say we are
and um,
I actually really am in defendant and
it's like I wish,
but then you talk to them a little bit
and they're there on one side of the,
it's very difficult because there's no
truth anymore.
There's no paper.
There's no one day used to be like if
you watched,
you know,
CBS,
NBC,
ABC News,
there was a journalistic integrity that
they subscribe to and both sides said,
these are the facts.
Right.
There's no news outlet any longer that
both sides look at.
No.
That's a really important point.
I mean,
it's very like very clear.
It's cut and dry.
How did that happen?
I don't know.
I want.
I'm curious to know when and how,
like what at what time period of
politics at that become the notion of
the shift of like an obvious,
this is precisely who were,
who were four and it's clear.
I was watching CNN and Fox News back and
forth like after the debate and it was
so fascinating,
man.
It was like,
who is telling the truth?
Like what?
What has happening here?
Because these,
he's two totally different stories and
they're,
they're so,
they're so clear on one side or the
other.
Like Fox News,
excuse me.
It was so clear on trump's side and CNN
was so clear on Hillary's side.
It was so odd places in one day
on Fox News.
They just switched places overnight.
Yeah.
Well it's crazy.
Be One of your network and
the reality.
Well,
what a news do you follow Jeff?
Follow it all.
I don't follow any news.
I watch and read a lot of news.
I always have like a aggregator on your
phone that pulls from different news
sources,
tend to
search up topics.
I'm curious what Chris Christie is up to
this week or Al Franken or just get
someone on my mind.
Sometimes I go to politico and usually
there's a great angle that you hadn't
thought of.
Politico and guardian are good for
different angles.
The Guardian's good.
Yeah.
Cause they're,
you know,
they're outside the,
well originally I guess there's a lot of
their writers are Americans now.
Right.
Did you see the Guardian initially was
UK.
Yeah.
You want some water?
No,
I'm good too.
I don't know what's going on that we'd
strong.
Did you see that guardian article,
um,
by um,
Glenn Greenwald about this,
the unseats unsubstantiated attacks on
trump.
It was really into now,
but like fake news.
Yeah.
And he was talking about what,
um,
you know,
Eisenhower had warned about complex.
Yeah.
I was like,
wow,
this is a crazy bold article.
And they predicted at trump like figure
rising up.
Well,
it's not just that,
like he's talking about how the deep
state is attacking trump.
Like that's,
that's what he's bringing up.
That the deep state is attacking him and
going after him.
Yeah.
And they're like the CIA and the
intelligence agencies,
like they're making some sort of a
concerted effort to,
to single him out and go after him and
destroy his person,
destroy his,
uh,
excuse me,
destroy his,
um,
you know,
public persona and that that's where all
the,
the urine,
you could end up now when you get into
politics,
all this stuff,
but,
but it's the,
yeah.
Doesn't give a fuck about politics.
They care about the FBI and if anybody
crosses them the way trump already has,
they're going to set a barium.
Yeah.
I mean,
think about that.
When,
has there ever been a time where an
unsubstantiated story about a guy who's
the president elect about peeing on
beds?
They talked about that like so openly.
Yeah,
it's been,
it's been so open.
That is last press conference.
He shut down the rumor by saying he's a
Germaphobe.
That's how massive of a story that is.
That during one of the most important
press conferences,
he addressed that fucking thing and it
didn't stop there.
Then he went on to talk about,
well,
you know,
everybody knows this camera is in the
room.
I mean,
you know,
what am I stupid?
What am I,
am morally was the weight of I stupid.
Unbelievable.
Yeah.
And then you watched how he,
I don't think I've ever seen,
I mean,
this might be me being ignorant,
but I don't know if I've ever seen a
president in a press conference or
president elect shut down a source like
he did.
CNN was like,
I won't talk to you.
I absolutely like,
I don't know if I've ever seen a
president single one out.
And then they probably slyly ignore
certain journalists that they don't want
to fucking talk to.
But I've never seen one to be like,
I don't talk to see it.
I don't talk to that new source.
Fuck you.
Well,
I think that there is a protocol for who
you go to first.
Like for years,
the first question always went to that
one old woman from the Associated Press.
From the,
yeah,
she was always the first question.
And then,
um,
and then after that,
I think it was,
there was a certain pecking order to it.
And,
and trump just basically said,
you know,
I'm going to,
I'm going to choose what news and
questions you guys here from now on is
not that the press corps is no longer
traveling with him.
It's the first time a president has not
had the press corps with him at all
times.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Cause and as well,
and his reasoning was he was like,
what are you gonna Watch me eat food?
That's that.
That's what he thought that they were
at.
They,
he's like,
no,
they,
they're interested in what's going on.
They,
they're interested in what this,
this conversation you might be having
with someone have some sense of
importance.
But he was like,
I don't want you watching me do simple
shit,
but that's just part of their fucking
Gig.
Yeah.
That's what they've always done.
And,
and then I think about that like how
much simple shit,
if they seen where it's so annoying,
it's not,
they've got to be like,
fuck,
this is so boring.
Especially when they get on Air Force
One and they're going to fucking Russia
for 10 hours to sit around.
And so they can do like a,
uh,
like a 32nd photo op and yell questions
at him and then another 10 hour flight
home and imagine like some,
one of the guys in the group is just
like,
I think I'm going to go talk to him.
The other guy was like,
don't,
he'll go in his room,
dude.
Like why?
I think we're cool now man.
We've had some moments,
you know,
I feel like we don't,
don't be that guy.
And then the rest of the nine hour plane
flight is fucking miserable.
He was praising Kanye West for
supporting him.
I remember watching it on TV.
Is this real life?
Yeah,
it was a trip.
Is this real lightweight?
I read the greatest.
I wish I know the source just because I
don't want to fucking say somebody
else's shit.
But there was just a meme floating
around in the Internet that said,
I bet you they,
years ago when Obama gained presidency,
there were so many fucking extremist
going.
I bet you the first people that are,
he's going to talk to our rappers and
Steve Harvey
and then you see fucking zoo trough just
drags in rappers.
And I loved it.
I thought it was,
I was like,
that's so fucking true.
How many white extremists were like,
fuck this.
Fuck.
He's going to talk to rappers in the
White House and it's trump that's doing
it.
Yeah,
it's great.
Yeah.
It's so funny.
What is he talking to?
Like who else is he like publicly?
Well,
yeah,
Don King.
Yeah.
He loves Don King,
but they've had a relationship in the
past,
so like they've,
they go back.
So this is almost like he gets to invite
his actual friends to remember when
Obama in trouble or getting
ambassadorships.
It's going to be crazy.
No,
not,
not Christie,
Christie.
Nothing.
I don't need,
I don't mean his political friends.
I mean his friends,
his life,
France and his book buddies that he
knows,
you know,
it was this man with a little bottle
attached,
that really
radical professor who was one of the
weathermen.
Is that what it was?
Is that what they call themselves.
And they were like doing acid and having
orgies and shit and robbing banks or
something.
And he was like a part of that and some
way.
And he was a professor that Obama knew
in college and it was always this big
controversy that he knew this radical
terrorist.
Right.
Obama is like some fucking sleeper guy.
No,
but he did have to distance himself from
the guy because he,
the guy did have some very,
um,
pro,
uh,
succession,
what do you call it,
the blacks to think you should return to
Africa and which you pay for it.
He was one of those guys.
Secessionist sucks.
Yeah.
I guess succession,
succession.
Succession is a session.
A session session session.
Yeah.
Just to see it.
So we know he had to back off from that
guy,
but it,
but it's,
uh,
what about the guy who,
have you guys seen his brother?
Do you know about his brother on the
playground?
Groundwater.
Obama's brother.
Do you know this account?
Have you heard about this?
There was like a guy who's saying he's
his brother and psych.
I,
he's like,
I don't support him.
I support trump.
You,
you haven't,
you haven't seen it pretending to be as
brief as you saw this.
Yeah.
This is his half brothers,
half brothers
fake news.
I probably is.
Who knows.
I'm not talking about fake news.
He was talking about it too.
I think that was fake.
But trump's,
but trump was fucking job.
Trump is talking to this dude like
thanks for the support.
Thanks for not supporting your half
brother.
Talk about fake news.
How about trump ran around for three
years saying that fucking Obama wasn't
born in this country.
Crazy.
I mean that was the beginning of
news.
Let me see his ID.
Let me see his birth certificate and
then how would the irony,
now trump won't show his fucking taxes.
He won't.
And because he's his excuses even after
the audits over,
what do people need to see now?
Like that's,
that's the reasoning is like what do you
want to see if the,
if the,
if I get audited and I'd fucking deal
with the government through the audit,
what do you need to know other than
we're taking care of it.
I think people want to know how much
money he has borrowed from China and
Russia.
Yeah,
because that could really affect is a,
you know,
policy.
Absolutely.
I thought that that was like one of the
things that you had to divulge your
income.
You do.
It wasn't a deal with Howard.
That's why Howard didn't eventually like
really run for governor after a certain
point because they wanted him to divulge
his taxes.
That's how they found out who hasn't
paid his taxes.
He doesn't pay taxes because of his
major loss a long time ago.
Oh,
that was that weird thing.
Atlantic city law,
he had to make some disclosure,
but he does it.
It's,
it's a general summary of his income.
It would also say Mary has money and
certain types of ways,
but it's not as income taxes where you
know what he spent on phone calls and
security and everything and it's just
invest rico,
he would also tell you how much he's
donated to charity,
which he doesn't want.
People
didn't know.
I mean,
he created his own
charitable,
uh,
what do you call it?
Charity.
Yes.
Charitable charitable funds.
Charitable,
charitable,
a charity and a,
and apparently he hasn't given any money
to it.
And like two or three years,
it's just been money he solicited from
people on the outside to give to his
charity that then he disperses so crazy.
But that's the whole thing is like,
then do we know that that's real too?
Like that's the other,
I don't know.
Right.
Hmm.
I,
I'm,
I would like to think that's gotta be
true,
but then I'm like,
I don't know.
Because they can,
they can solicit the records of his
charity,
the nonprofit.
Right,
right,
right.
But they can't do it for his personal
and private
game president for 20 years.
He's gonna.
He's going to change it.
He's going to step aside.
Let us buddy take over like Putin did in
Russia.
Eventually one of his kids or something.
This is,
hello.
Came over.
Get on board.
Game over.
I think so,
yeah.
Chris rock was seeing them on stage or
over,
you know,
a bit wrapped around that.
It was very funny and I was top of the
thing.
I was like,
we're all laughing,
but if something like that did happen,
if it wasn't trump,
it was somebody like that.
Maybe it's the next guy to figure out
how to do it like that.
We,
we've,
we essentially exposed the personality
contest.
You expose the flaw in it.
You're not looking for the best leader.
You looking for the person who's got the
best personality for the job.
The person who's got the best story.
Why you fucking one?
Scott Adams,
the guy wrote Dilbert.
He's a really,
really smart guy and he predicted trump
winning a long time ago and the reason
why predicted,
he said he's the most persuasive guy
I've ever seen.
So He's incredibly persuasive.
He just understands the art of
persuasion extremely well and he's like,
just if you looked at it like
mathematically,
I like this guy is a really good chance
and he predicted he was going to be
president and people gave him so much
shit and he doesn't even vote.
He's like a really interesting guy.
Very,
very smart guy.
And he wasn't saying that trump is going
to be president because he's this big
trump supporter and he was,
it wasn't that he just,
he was looking at it like pragmatically.
He's like,
this guy has incredible abilities of
persuasion.
Well,
he's broken every single rule,
every conventional wisdom about running
for president,
he broke and one,
so now it's like,
like you said,
Jeff,
who fucking knows?
Who knows?
There's no,
there's nothing normal anymore.
Do you think he gets two terms easy and
then after that he's just going to line
up people?
There's no more term or terms no more.
She said No.
Then it's just,
there's no more voting.
I really think so.
I feel like it's gonna get interesting.
I don't,
I feel like he locks up his own military
is going to start.
He's already marginalized the press.
He's told he's got,
he told his followers that the press is
lying,
arresting him.
You're not impeaching stand in the White
House for like two nights a week.
He's not even moving the fucking,
yeah,
he's not going to,
he's going
to stay in these satellite White House
in New York City.
He wants a satellite in Manhattan.
Should have seen the way way operates.
There's no way he's going to the White
House and having all that around them.
You know what's so funny?
I think for a little while for them to
make it look good,
but I am fucking freaking out right now.
Pitch people in New York or Paul Shit.
But then you get out the trafficker and
again,
he might like it there and stay.
I could see him all,
you know,
it was so bad.
He likes it when he can rub elbows with
famous people.
That's what's so funny about this
inauguration weekend for him is that he
couldn't get any celebrities and that's
all he really cares about.
That was the most important thing.
And then he got that one young,
they offered it to that one young
singer,
the chick,
and she said,
um,
I'll,
I'll do it if I can sing.
Um,
oh,
what is that fucking song?
Uh,
it's about,
it's about slavery in American,
about black people swinging from the
trees.
Uh,
sweet home,
Alabama.
Yes.
That's the one.
That's it.
But she basically was like,
I'll,
I'll do it if you let me sing this song.
And of course they were like,
no,
absolutely not.
But she was just like,
I'll come do it.
Does every artist in the world was like,
I'm not singing there?
Absolutely not.
No chance,
no chance,
no chance.
She was strange.
Is that,
have you ever heard anything like that
where there's no artists that you know
about that want to go to that is one
country guy and he's fucking nuts.
Who's the country guy?
Um,
was a country guy.
His name was sang every singing.
Is it Hank William Julius tonight?
Oh,
Leo Greenwood or whatever.
Now,
no bigger than this guy's huge.
Um,
Toby Keith,
and he's mad.
He's mad.
He,
I think it was tonight,
actually colby teeth.
So be Keith Lee Greenwood and three
doors down with the main doors down.
They're there.
Every band.
You've never heard that one song.
One big superman.
What does it Roseanne Barr.
Kryptonite bar singing the national
anthem issue.
Really?
Yeah,
but they're done.
they're done.
That's a good song.
That's the one.
If I go crazy,
man,
we used to call me superman.
Right?
Is that it?
I don't know.
Is that a good song?
Yeah,
it is a good song.
But they going to sing that for him.
Is that going to be,
you know they have bruce springsteen
cover band booked and they'd fucking
canceled.
Yeah,
I had a bruce springsteen cover bands.
Sorry.
Done.
We're born to run.
Well they were going to do it and then
they got so much shit from their fans
and then they say we're stepping down at
a respect to the boss.
The boss.
Did he issue a swimming pool with this?
Did the boss say anything about it?
I don't think he has two kids from
Delhi.
I was wondering if he like publicly made
a statement about the fucking,
the cover band playing.
You don't know.
I think bruce has fans were very vocal
with these guys.
They did it.
They never work.
You probably
got an email about some fucking gig is
like the,
I turned it down.
I bet you could find it is a good play.
You got to get publicity move.
Yeah,
it is.
I bet you could find a comic that would
do it in a heartbeat.
I heard him once say there's a bunch of
you.
I'm sure there's get a bunch of these
demons.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
I love it.
I heard Marlee Matlin is going to say,
I heard that.
I'm like,
what is the,
or they got David Bowie,
they're going to get holograms.
Celebrities against their wills
graduate.
He would do,
he did a prince hologram.
I know this.
I know for the inaugural parade secret
services on high alert in case Donald
tries to attack somebody.
Why didn't Kanya play?
It is at the,
uh,
is it another inauguration?
He said he's not American enough or
something.
I'll find the quote real quick.
Or even the people that are doing it are
not necessarily saying they support
trump.
They're saying that their patriotism.
Yeah.
Any of the money.
Toby,
Keith's supporting trump.
He is.
He came up on stage with a Red Dixie Cup
and cheered him.
Did he did a big cheer.
I swear to God
what?
Jesus Christ is not traditionally
American enough is sort of the quote
they said.
Who said that?
Trump's team that that was asked and
Operation Committee.
Okay.
That Kanya is not American enough so
they,
that's so ridiculous.
What does that even mean?
Not American enough kid rock.
I'm surprised kid rock didn't do it.
I was kid rock.
Not on the card.
I don't know what kind of show you think
this is.
Anyone they can get.
I don't know what it is.
You guys see this Ted nugent grabbing
his dick at the,
at the trump rally.
Oh,
he was there.
Have you not seen this video?
Who's grabbing his dick?
This was at a,
this was,
no,
this was up up in Michigan.
Look at.
This is a great video of Ted nugent.
If you have never seen this
to the player,
get in the asset column.
Finance,
real Michigan,
greatest state in the nation.
They should.
We must not let me get it out.
He's dressed like a fisherman.
Illinois in New York and New Jersey and
Maryland and Massachusetts.
Blue right here.
Just grabbed his deck and he said I got
him to lose state right here,
baby.
Hello Ted nugent baby.
He's very happy.
You're a big noodle fan.
Love to cat.
Scratch fever.
Yeah,
but dude and strangle hold great fucking
song.
I got your blue state right here.
It's amazing.
It's somewhat funny or die.
He did,
uh,
did uh,
did a thing where they kept zooming in
on him,
grabbing his penis to accentuate like
the physical hold
of his pain.
He physically grabs it.
It looks like he's holding onto a
lighter and then the fucking cubs
punching in,
hot it to show up
doing it.
When did,
uh,
when did he do that?
When did that take place?
Was in,
this was at a rally and I think it's
Michigan.
Do you have it up there and recently?
Let's see.
I just got it sent.
It happened there along the campaign
trail
was a while ago.
Yeah,
it was a while ago.
I was doing a crazy thing.
The victory tour,
like how do you win the election then go
to the state she wanted we wouldn't you
go to the states that you lost and see
what they have to say.
This is a different going after snl cast
members.
That was kind of weird every week,
not just one.
Alec Baldwin's one thing you would ever
go after.
I'll let you go then and the cast isn't
funny.
I was like,
Oh Geez,
23 year old first job.
Now the president saying that only on
his twitter that I'm not funny.
I think the beauty of it,
it's just a few months of the finest.
It doesn't have to go to the CAF.
Look.
An snl is benefiting from that.
I think it's fantastic.
It's great for talking to [inaudible].
No,
that's funny.
They got me.
He should like make like he was just
being tough.
Yeah.
Well,
the thing about this country is we love
it when we hate somebody and then we
liked him again.
Yeah.
You know,
so all he has to do is that all he has
to do is put out some positive tweets
and be conciliatory and then watched the
country just sweeping them up in there.
I look at what happened at Bush after
nine 11 yeah,
that's true.
He had the lowest favorable favorability
rating of any president in history and
after nine 11 he shot up to like 80%
that's right.
I remember that.
Somebody,
they said,
they said trump has the lowest
incoming president elect a approval
rating in the history.
How do they,
how do they compile that?
That's a very good question.
I've always wondered.
I was like,
how do they compete?
Oh,
who are they asking exactly?
I don't know.
I don't know who's taking polls.
People would take polls.
That's what they're doing.
What?
Well,
that's like the funniest people that
projected the election to go to a
hillary.
Well,
what's interesting is they trust him
anymore.
They will know,
but they were right.
If,
if it was a popular vote,
like they actually were,
right?
Yeah,
it was real.
It's really funny,
like it's,
it just shows how crazy electoral
college system is,
but he said,
no,
it should be a popular vote.
He goes,
that's a different race though.
Like he like conceded that it's better
to have it be the popular vote.
He goes,
exactly.
He says that's not the game he goes to
the game is the electoral college vote
and that's,
that's the game we played and we won by
a landslide.
Right.
He's right.
He played it like a game.
They played it like this thing that
they've been doing over and over and
over again.
They fucked up in that they,
they rigged it for so long that they,
their popularity contest got taken over
by someone who's actually popular,
like an actual famous person and knows
how to become like,
he knows how to become more popular.
Do you know what I mean?
Like he understands the,
some people know the formula of how to
do that.
He knows how to fucking do it and he's
rich as fuck and he doesn't have to do
what they want him to do.
Right.
It's different.
She can finance his own campaign.
He gets there,
he gets pressed by talking mad shit and
getting people to talk about him like
she knows how to do it.
See,
here's the thing that I'm confused about
is what's the overall vision?
Like what is trump ism like if you think
about democratic,
what's trump craddick it's a good
question.
Small government.
Well,
I mean I think it's,
I think the tea,
I mean his truths are to to make sure
taxes are low for people that are
earning a lot so he can,
those people can stabilize that market
that they're already in.
You know what I mean?
That people don't have to sacrifice at
the top.
I think he's pretty clear about that and
he's little.
He lowered,
he wants to lower the fuck out of
business tax.
He wants that to go see the low.
So He's saying zero government let these
people fucking govern themselves.
Let small businesses,
that's his whole campaign is to keep
money up top where it is the fucking
let,
let pockets that are pretty fixed day
thick.
I mean I don't,
I think he's pretty transparent about
that.
That seems to be a thing that he's
pretty obvious about.
I think he wants the rich stay rich and
he's not afraid of saying it and for
some reason people that are poor,
like I like it.
Yeah.
I like what he's going for.
It's,
that's,
it's crazy.
Yeah.
It's going to be very,
very interesting.
I'm really curious to see how this plays
a Hubbell.
Oh,
it's going to be interesting.
There's no doubt about that.
I mean,
it's like any other time when I'm not
happy about what's going on politically.
I just put my head in the sand for a
while and I go,
I'll just check in and a few months,
but I cannot stop reading on my phone in
the papers.
Like this is like we're living through a
part of history that's probably more
turbulent than any other historic,
any other presidential transition.
Do you think this is for Johnson and
Kennedy?
This is like a big metaphorical
question,
but because of the,
like Obama lived through the age of like
the bursting of the Internet space and
the,
and its involvement in politics,
you know of like twitter and instagram
and all this shit.
Shit,
this was bigger.
This is even bigger than that.
It gives midlife breakdown right now.
This is it bottoming out halfway.
This is the halfway point.
We got another two I think.
I think,
I think trump is president for 20 years
or three days or it's like something
terrible.
But do you think,
but do you think,
worry about something terrible?
Sorry to interrupt you because,
because I think he had a real control
over his message in America.
You know,
he has friends who own the tabloids,
remember Asanas.
I remember flying with them.
Nevermind.
But it's like,
no fuck you go back.
You can't see mind.
My best friend's own tabloids.
Wow.
You know,
and,
and those are his boys.
It's like the [inaudible] family.
They had all the bad stories locked up.
But now when it starts happening in
Russia and stuff,
he doesn't have quite the old on it.
People can really get to and
then,
you know,
he's not young.
Yeah.
I worry about something bad happened.
It may not end well for him.
You know,
it's really a tricky one.
The mother part of me says get fine
because you're going to be around for
the rest of my life.
The Glenn Greenwald thing is an
interesting angle though cause Glenn
Greenwald is a really respected
journalist.
He's the guy who exposed wiki leaks.
He's a guy who a lot of people go to and
he's not without his criticisms.
I mean a lot of people criticize.
I'm like,
uh,
he's had this ongoing feud is Sam
Harris.
Um,
but if you,
you look at like what he's,
what he's talking about here,
if there's any shred of truth to it that
you're seeing like this old institution
attack this new coming incoming guy and
do it in a foolish way that actually
kind of strengthens this,
this disbelief that people have in the
news.
Like if they make up some crazy story
and you hear CNN talking about it and
all these other people talking about it
and substantiated reports that involved
lewd activities and golden showers,
like who the fuck is doing this?
Like who's doing this?
Like what are you trying to do?
Because by doing this,
especially when it looks obvious and
dumb like that did it makes his case
look stronger.
It's almost like something that he would
do to attack himself.
Like that's like how nero burned Rome,
you know?
Like do you,
you might do something like that.
Attack yourself so that you'll look
vulnerable.
Do you think he did?
No,
no,
no.
I don't know what he's a great ad is a
counterpoint.
I've been living in New York City during
his entire reign of popularity.
He's a great counter puncher,
so if something happens,
even if you perceive it as bad for him,
he knows how to work that.
That's what he talked about with Kanye
west and I talking about Kanye do that
every time a really a friend would say,
oh boy,
this is going to really going to sink
when I go watch.
I go nuts.
You can't run a country like that.
You can,
you can win an office but you can't.
Who knows?
He knows what he's going to do.
I'm just super,
he doesn't probably,
he probably knows but we don't know
deal,
you know,
if you're,
if you're right about saying that he's
never going to leave,
then obviously that's going to become a
problem.
But if you're not right about it and he
does manage to show some flaws in the
system and expose them,
then it could be be great.
Sure.
Maybe,
maybe no one else is going to do it
other than Bernie.
If Bernie won and obviously they were
conspiring to t Bernie out,
but if Bernie won,
we could have seen some really weird
changes in the system and and overall
like a,
he's a,
he was a,
he would be a mood shifter.
Like Bernie would be a guy that is like,
that's kind of what a lot of people
looking for.
Someone who is not money oriented.
Someone who is like for the people,
someone who lives a fairly simple life
for a guy like that
pope when the pope got in you were like,
oh he cares about the,
it was like the pope.
They became friends,
the whole thing.
Yeah.
Like the pope got rid of that throne.
He went with a more casual dress.
Yeah.
It's in a lot of ways like what Bernie
would have represented I think is
someone who's
not of the same cloth as we're used to.
We want someone who was like concerned
about equality across the up above.
Yeah.
And like broke.
Yes.
Sorry.
Now let's say you're right.
No,
just and this and then so fed of the guy
should are there,
the woman who should or could have,
you know,
they're fighting of the wrong game all
the time.
You know,
Hillary,
it was probably a great smart person
and,
but you know,
you drift into distractions and she's
trying to,
well this is also the,
something weird happens like the why and
wiring goes haywire and the guy who's
the most popular at something completely
different gets in there on a freak of
nature.
I mean this country has gone through in
50 years,
you cannot set amusing.
Definitely amusing.
There's a little part of glee in your
heart where it goes,
what the supreme court was.
It's like seeing the whole thing fell as
comedians.
It's,
you know,
I live long and we all have everything
kind of talk about for the next four
years.
It made everyone's life a lot more
interesting all of a sudden.
But don't you think that there's a
certain amount of intimidation about
criticizing him?
Yeah.
Like there's,
there's some real intimidation that
comes from,
he's a legitimate powerful man.
Do you want to be on his enemies?
No.
It'd be horrible.
And everybody said it feels like that.
And with great power comes great
responsibility.
And that's one of the things that people
were really terrified of with a guy like
that because he's got so much power and
so much influence.
He didn't used to,
he was a joke in a weird way to a lot of
people,
but I always knew that he could actually
do things like when you see him in New
York,
you go,
all of a sudden you're like,
Holy Shit,
there's a tower.
There was not there.
He's,
people think he's willy nilly like
shooting from the hip.
He's patient built buildings.
That's different.
I was,
when I grew up in New York,
he was,
you know,
w when he was a celebrity in New York
and not the country.
He was just a slum Lord.
That's,
that's sad.
We talked about it and my family,
you know,
they was just a guy who was a guy who
had suits against him.
He owned,
he owned projects when,
and it was pretty well known back then
that he was a slum Lord.
Yeah,
twitter is a hobby for him.
I think building is his occupation and
it's a really hard thing to do.
I remember the,
the,
the skating rink popping up and he was
always talking about taking over a
squashed of land in New York when you
were lucky to get a little apartment
somewhere.
This guy who's going to buy like the
whole,
where the trains where there's some ways
you have to be like you,
you are to all of that.
You couldn't help.
But even if he didn't and his politics
didn't emerge until much later,
you could just kind of kept the cool and
it was just like a playboy and you know,
a personality and you know,
it was like a kick to see him around.
He always loved a good joke,
you know,
he was generous so I get it a lot
easier.
A lot of them not surprised some of the
smartest,
most successful people I know in New
York supported them.
Do you think though that at the level of
responsibility that you have when you
become the president and the amount of
power that you have,
do you think that anybody can really
manage that correctly?
Well,
let's fix it.
What's your take on this position?
And this,
one of the things is it's exposing this,
this is exposing how ridiculous the
position is that you could get someone
who's just this one popular person.
It gets into place and run this entire
thing.
Like what one person running anything.
It's crazy.
Well are we overstating the president?
Really runs,
look what he's doing.
No,
but I'm saying once you're in office,
do you think president has as much
power?
People were going to find out,
we're going to find out what kind of
power he has.
Cause look who look what he's doing.
What could we be talking about with the
press corps?
Look where you're talking about with get
power.
You security.
That's,
yeah,
he's accumulating leverage and power.
And,
and by putting people around him
operate without his family,
he's always going to have his family
around.
It's like you don't just suddenly Tello
indycar driver tomorrow you're driving a
nascar like he's been doing it a certain
way.
Yeah.
But his,
uh,
his son and his daughter or his series
two sons,
they can't advise them on policy because
they're running is a companies.
They have to,
they have to never have a conversation
with him again about the businesses or
politics.
Come on like,
come on.
That sounds so ridiculous.
There's no fucking,
I mean there's just no fucking way,
but even if they still,
even if that's how it is,
it's still as family,
but you know what year did they won't
want to talk to him about it.
He got it.
He's going to be the richest guy in
history.
It's going to be,
they say that poop mythical figure here
about some oligarch.
They've got arrested.
It said that gluten's the really strong
history.
No,
dude,
he's a pause.
I mean he will become,
you're going to bet against it and
become larger than life.
This will make him larger than life.
It'll just be,
it'll be like a fucking,
it'll,
we'll be able,
Beth,
if there is a huge scandal,
it's not going away.
He's got a million kids and family.
I don't know round for me,
if you think about what's going on in
the last year,
I guess Kendall make some stronger.
He fucking,
Billy Bush got fucking trampled on the
fucking on the bus thing.
I think it just made him stronger.
Do you think if this whole story about
the Russian prostitutes pissing on him
got corroborated,
do you think it would hurt him?
I read so I read,
someone said that they thought he'd
fucking started that shit.
I was like,
that's a fucking interesting angle.
What if he was like,
yeah,
that's what Joe was saying.
Like,
like why not hire you?
Yeah,
hi.
Well yeah,
I don't think that's the case,
but I do think that turned out stuff
around pretty good tax or foolish
because they are,
so you've already proven that he's
Kevlar.
Like do you get the degree?
He got past,
grab the pussy videos,
what did it,
but then,
but then conversely,
then what?
Then you can't do anything then.
So what,
what's the legitimate thing that you can
come out about him?
If you present facts,
they get kind of pushed away.
If you present these crazy news stories,
it just fuels the fire.
So what,
what do you do then to,
good question.
What does the,
what does the opposition do?
Because anything they come up with is
either fake news to him or it's
something crazy that makes people go
off.
Dude.
How funny was that?
They pissed on that fucking bed than
Obama.
I mean,
it just becomes a,
then it becomes like a social bit.
The worst thing that could take place is
that people decide while he's in power
that he can't be empower people decide
that there can't be a president anymore.
We've decided as a nation that we're
going to abolish this and we're going to
start a whole new system of government.
That is where it should,
could get really crazy.
I would get crazy.
That's what Susan Surandon wants.
Does she want that?
Yeah.
She remember when he was running for
president,
he said,
she goes,
maybe trump should win because maybe
it's time we do have a revolution in the
streets.
Maybe we need to change it.
It's like,
yeah,
that's easy to say where you're on the
fifth fin of five story Brownstone with
guards.
You know,
not fucking living in the projects there
and ready to leave
for rich person to say that a poor
person has nothing to lose him would
call for revolution.
But when a rich person does it,
I think she's got some,
or did you think they become it for her
first?
Probably.
Yeah.
When I talked to trump,
somebody said,
how'd you do that?
He's like,
he's like Hitler.
I go,
if he's Hitler,
you'll be glad I'm friends with them
because otherwise I can give it up.
Your fucking moves is in home address.
Well,
it's,
it's bizarre too because he's actually
like publicly supportive Putin,
you know,
and he talks about Putin being a smart
businessman.
So He's talks with whoever he's been
friends with,
talent,
money be taken away from it.
A surprise.
He'll figure all that out.
But he can't pretend that these aren't
as pals.
And if you meet somebody famous once or
twice and they're nice to you,
that's all he's plus.
He's his stuff's deep.
You know,
he would go over there,
he would bring tv shows,
they're all that stuff is where a
client,
he's,
we're another,
uh,
um,
piece of commerce in his portfolio of
how he does business.
So he picks up the phone and he knows
some guy in Japan,
of course he's going to mention his
properties and that's how he gets going.
What does that works
really well?
That's what it,
that's a better system.
Yeah.
Putin used government and a private
ownership to amass fortunes,
but he didn't get his friends fortunes.
But it's kind of,
it's almost going to take something like
this to make people realize that this is
a ridiculous system.
I mean,
otherwise we would never figure it out.
We just still look for a better and
better version of the impossible.
Maybe we're all looking at it wrong.
It's such,
should we've tested it?
Anybody can become president.
Well,
maybe it is a good system because it's
got,
yeah,
it's got that and it's got all the
checks and balances in place.
You know,
I mean,
maybe it is a good system because of all
the bureaucracy,
something beyond on what's right and
wrong.
And I've heard that argument.
Dynasty is not the right thing.
So it's time for,
you know,
civilization had a great run.
What else you got?
Well,
what's crazy is as dark as it can plug
in.
How much is he?
Here's the thing,
because there are wars going on,
right?
There's wars going on right now and we
will always say,
welcome waitress down here.
The fucking,
the board is going on.
No drank,
but there's wars going on right now,
but they're just not going on right
here.
I like,
are we just naive or we naive to not
understand the danger?
I think it's my,
it might be coming.
Yeah.
And you're like,
oh yeah,
it is.
Yeah.
What,
what would,
what would stop?
What would stop it at this point,
dude,
I don't think I,
I don't think any war with Russia is on
a lot of barriers.
No,
no,
no.
France or Germany,
Why would we go to war with Germany or
France or anyone thinks is possible
leaking.
Well also date what you define cyber
warfare is is is what it's all about.
I mean,
if we had natural boundaries before,
but now you see that they can hack into
the FBI and the CIA and fucking,
you know,
it was a no one unknown now and this,
to presume anything.
It's true.
Yeah.
Okay.
Here's,
here's a scenario.
What would it be so crazy ideal way
outside of a dictator.
What would be the ideal way to run a
nation?
Like whoa,
what would be better than having this
one alpha that we keep putting in place?
Which seems pretty ridiculous at this
point.
It seems like we might have fucked up
and got a super alpha in there.
Well,
I don't think that the framers of the
constitution didn't see the presidency
as being such a big deal.
He was like,
he was kind of a lead administrator,
but he wasn't supposed to be a be all
end all the power in this country.
And I think we probably want to ratchet
that position down.
Guy that they didn't give it to them.
This is not even that cool of a thing.
It's a weekend.
Right.
You don't want to be just a baby
photo out drawing,
sketch jobs,
kind of photo ops.
They head back.
No,
I was kind of a pragmatist about it.
I wasn't a supporter of anybody except
uh,
um,
I'm pretty much,
I was against trump winning,
so anybody but trump type of thing.
Right.
Yeah.
So I'd love to say like,
my wife has a big Bernie supporter.
I would like to say I was,
but I think I was just,
I was betting on the best horse,
but I thought was the best because
actually you didn't even make the bet,
but you were hope you had a horse in
mind.
Yeah.
And it didn't win.
That's what it was like.
Well,
but you lose it.
Yeah.
I mean,
I can't sit here and say for all the bad
things I say about trump,
I can't sit here and tell you that I was
passionate about hillary or that I even
like her,
you know?
I just saw it as the lesser two evils.
Yeah.
You saw her as business as usual,
not business way worse.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it,
it seemed like it was just another thing
to sell like a woman president.
Huge.
Great.
Has this,
has the relationships that exist that we
already know.
So you're like,
okay.
It was almost like,
yeah,
but the next,
the assistant coach has been there for a
while.
Just,
yeah.
Do that.
Like that's what it felt like in my
brain that was going to happen.
But I gotta say I was shooting at night
that people were watching it and of
course we're here in Los Angeles,
like fucking not one of those crew
members isn't hardcore left and watch
people watching it on their phones and
like their reactions were like complete
confusion.
It was crazy to watch from this
perspective and I wonder what it was
like watching from like Michigan.
Do you know what I mean?
And I did a live podcast.
Oh yeah.
That was crazy.
Yeah.
We did a live podcast with a bur and
stan hope and burt crow a shot on
youtube after it.
That's right.
I saw that.
Hey Os and it's just so strong
gambling crazy.
Well cause first of all their fucking
facet joints around the whole time.
And I was looking,
I thought this is a celebration party.
Yeah,
why not?
Yeah.
They realize that was going to go into
the most confusing moment of my life and
I just failed like it was going to
trump.
I just like all of a sudden I looked up
at Joe's fucking laughing and Stan hope
is carrying on.
I'm like this nothing funny anymore
sober.
And I just went and I sat in my car in
front of my house for like two hours.
Oh yeah.
Jesus Christ to your bum me out.
I don't listen.
We were having fun.
How you where you guys were having fun?
We were just,
it was just bird killing.
Yeah.
For like four hours.
He was,
he was on fire that night.
Fire,
fire.
And then when we became legal and bird
took a hit.
Yeah,
he doesn't smoke pot.
He went right in there.
It was the whole fucking room.
Somebody came out with Bert Kreischer I
think came from the back and he
announced that pot was now legal in
California and three out of four people
in the audience immediately lit up and
there was a cloud of smoke that just
took over the rails from the actual
moment.
Fuck Troy Conrad's took this photo of
the moment.
Wow.
Burt's running around.
There's always people in the front row
where I'll go crazy right here.
Everyone's going crazy.
That's the very moment when we found out
that pot was legal in California.
We're doing a live podcast from the main
room.
Jeff Ross just walked back yet,
but yeah,
the cut.
The other crazy thing is that doug,
Stan hopes girlfriend at the time or
still,
but when she was in a coma at that time,
she's not anymore.
Thankfully.
She [inaudible].
We're going to wait to hear what's next
Gen.
Doug's a fucking trouper man.
Not,
not many people would have power through
right there,
dog.
He's not it.
He's dug stan hope is a special human.
I've known that guy for a long time,
man.
He's fun.
He's the real deal.
I mean,
he actually did move to Bisbee,
Arizona and essentially start like a
whole community of Weirdos that live
down there and hang out and work with
them and do podcasts with them and you
know,
he,
and he's kind of using the podcast is
like an open mic.
That's how he rant and that's how he's
coming up with material.
His whole setup is very interesting,
man.
It's like,
yeah,
he's,
he's the real deal.
He told you about it or listen to it.
I've I've,
yeah.
Listen to it a bunch of times as podcast
is awesome,
but he owns like,
he's like a real estate mogul and his
fucking town.
Yeah,
he owns a bunch of houses,
but houses go up for sale.
He buys them.
They're all like four grand that he owns
a ton of time.
He's telling me about it.
He's fucking bind the town.
He's going to be the trump of Bisbee,
Arizona.
Doug Sandals.
God,
I own this town.
He's going to be like the bad guy and
roadhouse.
Remember the bad guy.
I own this town.
That's what,
that's what Stan hope's going to do it.
I'll have to dress like him.
I'm telling him,
I'm thinking about moving there.
Sometimes I think about moving there.
I'm like,
why not?
What's fucking join them?
Let's sees seven miles away from Mexico.
If shit gets weird,
you go left,
you go right,
pick your poison.
What do you want to deal with?
Drug cartels are rednecks.
What do you want to know where you want
to go?
Yeah,
he's got a weird spot man.
They see people like when you're,
when you're near the border like that,
you see families coming over.
Like I've talked to dudes who've been
hunting in Arizona and there's areas
that they avoid because uh,
too many people are um,
coming over the border and they're their
walk,
you know,
and the,
the leaving put things on their shoes,
like big chunks of carpet.
Um,
and they,
uh,
timed down to your,
to their shoes so that they don't make
any footprints.
The hunters,
no Mexican Mexicans coming over from the
border.
I deal where things on their feet so
that they don't leave obvious tracks.
It's really,
he's like,
it's crazy.
I know guys that have seen them down
there and run into him.
It's like a super common thing.
So like there is a trickle of people
that are pretty comfortable cause it'd
be like,
it would be like running across the
border on a carpeted area,
high class.
They did it for comfort.
It just so happened to cover a lot of
those folks died.
A lot of those folks could go over and
they get dehydrated and you don't have
enough water and they,
they get stuck in the desert and you
know if they tried to come over like in
July and August,
like you could get fucked in era in
southern Arizona.
Yeah.
If somebody doesn't pick you up,
you know there's supposed to be someone
to come pick you up.
I mean they have like this whole system
I guess set up how that,
how they get people over here.
It's Kinda crazy man.
It's Kinda crazy that we have like this
boundary in the dirt that we decide if
you're born over there,
you're fucked.
You stay over there,
born over here.
You're on our team when it's all just
there.
Just Pete,
if he pulled back from it.
And you look at this connection between
Mexico and the United States,
it's like it's a landmass.
It's one landmass.
Like Mexico is physically connected to
us.
It's a part of us.
If we were uh,
being,
that would be like being at war with our
foot or not letting our foot come in the
shower,
no,
you can't wash.
I'm going to wash the whole body.
Like this is a,
this is a part of the entire,
this thing,
you know,
like to break it off into these
imaginary lines in the sand is no
different than us telling Seattle they
have to go fuck themselves,
you know,
and no one from Seattle can come over.
It's just,
it's the same thing.
they don't,
you know,
the obviously aren't under our
constitution,
our laws or any of that stuff,
but they're connected to us.
There are literally a part of us,
they're right there,
but it's like what you said before about
tribalism.
It's just so deep,
you know,
it's random and yet it's deep.
Like a sports team.
It's like any guy can get traded any
given year,
but you're still gonna cheer for that
fucking color uniform.
Even though like a fight,
like the mets in [inaudible] 86,
after they won the world series,
they fucking traded everybody off and
they weren't the mets anymore,
but people were still like,
you know,
wearing the jerseys and cheering.
Now here's the question.
How do you,
how do you stop something like that?
Well,
the hope was globalism.
Would,
you know that with all of us having
access to the Internet,
in our pockets with the same as people
from India,
that they would be this,
you know,
uh,
the people had this amazing image of all
the walls falling down and,
but that's not,
hat doesn't seem to be happening.
Do you think?
No,
because I mean,
you're getting,
we're getting more connected,
but,
but culture means a lot to people and
they're going to keep it and that's,
that's,
that identifies them with who they are.
So they're never going to get rid of
that and just become super otherwise,
uh,
you know,
the westernization of the world would
just be with them all being us.
I mean,
what would that,
what's the end to answer?
It's like everyone should be the same,
but most places you go around the world
that are Westernized,
quote unquote,
that are globalized.
It's uh,
it looks like us.
Hmm.
Yeah.
But I mean,
we know for a fact that apple goes to
China and pays people pennies and they
have nets are on the buildings where
these people live and work.
They have dormitories and they cover
them with nets.
We know about Foxconn.
We know,
we know that story,
so we know.
And we still bodies fucking phones.
I didn't even think twice again twice.
I'm like,
those fucking jumpers make a hell of a
phone.
Wait,
wait.
Plus breast,
a little a $1 an hour hearts or whatever
the fuck they get paid.
And we accept that and we accept that
not just in China,
but all throughout South America.
There's a bunch of different factories
that employ people that pay them pennies
compared to what they would have to pay
the same person in America.
So he's saying that we care,
we care less about them because they're
not Americans.
Exactly.
Yeah.
We literally allow people to give them
slave wages.
Well,
we would consider slave wage.
Just like if someone took a guy you and
made you work for 14,000 on that,
you know the Blah Blah Blah factory that
makes you know,
fucking jeans or sneakers or wherever
the fuck they make.
If they made you work for that amount,
you would think you were in jail.
He was like,
oh my God,
I have to live off of this.
These people control me,
they own me.
They,
they have paralyzed me with poverty.
Like there's no way I'll ever be able to
escape this.
And the only argument against it is a
while.
It's the quality of their life is much
better than it was before the factory
got there.
You know,
before the factory,
not there,
nobody made any money at all because
they were eating coconuts,
mangoes,
and they were catching fish,
but they didn't need any money.
I you made them work.
There's a lot of these places where
you're setting up shop,
like they'd been there for thousands and
thousands of years.
It didn't need the factory.
You know,
it's maybe the factory is nice to them.
Maybe it is good.
Maybe it does.
Maybe they do become dependent upon it
over time.
But people have existed everywhere,
all over the planet without factories
for a long fucking time.
You don't need that factory there.
There's a lot of other solutions.
It's not an either or proposition.
Like either the factories there are,
they never get their shit together.
Like,
no,
that's not the case.
Like if they could,
they could develop their own culture and
society just like the United States did.
But if you just make them in prison to
these factories where they get paid
slave wages in these foreign third world
countries that we don't care about as
much as we care about Detroit or we care
about Chicago or were care about places
that are just like that place connected
to us.
Yeah,
well I'm a Cami or something,
right?
Jesus.
It's God Damn Kami talk real realist.
It's gross.
The whole thing of not letting those
people over here is gross.
It's you're going to have ended
eventually like when you get to keep it
like that for a million years,
a million years now we're going to have
states and you can't cross.
You can't immigrate from Mexico.
So million years from now,
we're still going to have deep poverty
in Mexico and we're terrified of the
drug war and leaking over our soil.
Is that what's going to go on a million
years from now?
No,
we're going to fucking,
we're going to be one united planet once
super organism that they can read each
other's mind.
Federation,
a corporation.
This is a corporation.
This is a hiccup along gigantic trail
that leads from us throwing shit at each
other from a tree to us being able to
transcend literal space and time,
become a part of some artificially
created dimension that they establish
that's,
that's a hundred years from now or 200
years from now.
This is like a,
this whole thing we're going through
right now is a blip in time.
And it's also a challenge to how much
technology,
uh,
really connects us.
So it like this guy's going to present a
lot of challenges as to like how much
technology can unite human beings.
Well,
the problem is,
and you and I were talking earlier
about,
uh,
what's the law called again?
Moore's law,
Moore's law that every two years this
speed of computers and the memory of
computers doubles and at that's held
true since the guy came up with the law,
which was in like 1960.
That's the neighborhood,
right?
Jamie Moore's law.
And,
uh,
and the problem with it is I'm reading
this book right now about it and the
problem with it is that we can't keep up
culturally,
emotionally,
legally with how fast information is,
is a traveling and how,
like you said,
it's become,
everybody has access to the same
information,
but it's also just,
you know,
the ramifications of,
corporations being able to get into your
information.
Like we don't have laws in place that
can really tackle that because it's
happening so fast.
You look at Airbnb,
we didn't have laws in place for people
renting out their places,
all paying taxes on using your own car
to drive people as a taxi.
We're like a one step behind progress
and we're going to stay that way because
it's happening so fast.
You know,
I saw a taxi today,
I don't want,
wow,
this is going to be like one of those
payphones.
Yeah.
I'm looking at this car,
this guy's drawn.
I'm like,
this is going to be a payphone.
Duke,
we're just gonna have prejudices and
they're going to use people who are
going to take uber.
It's better,
you know,
happening in big cities is uber sort of
replacing the cabs,
making it tough for cabs and probably
buses and the private limo.
Certainly now it's starting to cut into
cars.
People are not needing a car in major
cities in La and it's cuts out all that
drinking and driving shit.
I watched somebody slam into a fucking
barrier last night.
Yeah,
yeah.
I was driving home last night and there
was this guy driving home from the ice
house cause this guy to the left to me
and he was speeding and he was a flying
by me man and he was losing control of
his car a little bit,
just a little bit like it was just like,
you know,
he was just wiggling a little,
it was wet.
The,
the roads were wet and uh,
this guy was just driving way too fast.
He's probably hydroplaning and a,
I said this guy is just not keeping it
together good.
He might be trunk or whatever.
Swipe,
pull over two lanes.
I give them some space and a minute
after I do that bang hits the fucking
side.
The cement barrier spins out.
Correct.
Spins again,
fucked his car up.
No Shit.
Why you come to a stand still in the
middle of the highway came to a stop in
the left lane.
Yeah,
to turn in the right direction.
Fortunately his car was fucked up for
sure.
He might not have been able to drive,
but he was at least looking that way.
Cause sometimes it's wind up sideways
and when you wind up sideways on the
highway,
you're fucked because not everybody's
going to see you and it doesn't look
like rear tail light.
So you're not getting the same kind of
reflection that you get.
If you saw taillights you put,
the guy was stopped in front of you,
you saw those taillights,
you,
you would know,
oh there's a car there.
Like sometimes when people are not
totally paying attention and you,
here's a car that's sideways parked on
the road,
like dude,
who I watched that happen once.
I was in um,
New York and I was coming home from a
Gig with my friend John and uh,
we were driving and there was a car that
was stopped dead in the left lane and
uh,
it had hazard lights on but the hazard
lights were dying.
There was like super damn,
there was no battery juice and I saw it
and I changed lanes quick but not that
far away from it.
Like I'm,
I barely missed it.
I missed it by like,
I dunno,
50 yards or something like that,
close enough where it was like,
Holy Shit.
And then I look in my rear view and this
guy plows into it at full speed and I
see the cars in my rear view as I'm
driving.
I see them spinning in the rear view
mirror and I'm realized like,
people are probably dying.
I'm,
I'm looking at dead people because they
hit that thing going 70 miles an hour,
just slammed into it and everything's
spinning stuff.
Visions of,
of a plain car crash.
It's so scary.
Oh yeah.
I had a guy,
bad car,
car,
car accident.
I've been banged around and spin around
mostly when I was um,
you know,
old tires as a teenager but not like a
fucking wreck wreck.
I got in a couple of smaller,
not too bad.
Rex is a comedian,
you know,
trying to drive.
Yeah.
Drive like a new drive home in the snow
and shit.
Cause I didn't want to pay for a hotel.
Dumb stuff.
You know,
I was running late at night and I saw
that car,
there was a really bad car accident a
couple of months,
two months ago on fountain where a girl
was fucking shit faced.
And people always fly home on fountain
cause there's,
you know,
it's,
it's fast.
There's no lights and a girl must have
clipped a curb and then she headed to
the other side,
like the fucking other side of the road.
I mean and missed parked cars,
which was insane and smashed into way
one of those concrete walls on the
corner.
You know what I mean?
On the apartments have those concrete
fucking huge,
well,
I mean it and it looked like a fucking
bulldozer ran into it on 50 you know
what I mean?
It was like a million pieces.
I mean there was shit like two blocks
up.
Who was unfucking rail.
Yeah.
When you see someone really hit
something with a car,
you realize how crazy car travel is and
how those autonomous cars are like the
future.
You're not going to be able to argue
against it.
Yeah.
Right.
Because it takes,
I mean,
we've all been,
I've fallen asleep at the wheel on the
highway at night ice to drive from
Boston back to New York.
Saturday night I would do two shows.
Then I get my car wherever the fuck I
was and I would drive to New York that
night and I can remember windows open
singing as loud as I could it just
because I would close my eyes and I
would fucking wake up on the shoulder
was craig.
I think about how many times I could
have died,
you know?
And I remember when I was a teenager,
there was this 69 cougar that I was
going to buy from this kid named Billy
Arduino and it was a muscle car and he
had it fucking jacked up.
It was a motor head and I was going to
buy this.
Where did you get from Terry town now?
The order windows.
And so this other kid bought it and
driving down nine
right in front of the hospital.
It's a two lane road but it goes like 50
miles an hour.
And a,
I see the car and it's driving in front
of me and has a light rain and uh,
and I see him,
I don't know what the fuck happened but
he started going back and forth fish
tail and the fish tail.
I think he was gunning it cause he saw
me and he was trying to be a bad ass.
Yeah.
When in the opposite lane hit this
mother and kid no fucking head on.
And to this day I can remember the smell
of burnt rubber and loyal.
Like it happened like right in front of
me.
And,
uh,
the woman was hospitalized sometimes.
Somehow that kid was okay and this fat
fuck just got right out of the car and
then nothing happens.
Yeah,
yeah.
Like chipped a tooth.
Yeah.
When you,
uh,
you see people drive and really fucked
up man,
there was a,
I pass by this,
uh,
one of those power boxes,
whatever it is,
you know,
those things that are on the corner and
it had all these um,
wreaths on it.
Uh,
and uh,
all this,
uh,
in memory of this person.
And then I looked up the store and it
was two kids.
They were racing down the road and some
lady pulled out and they clipped the
lady and spun her car around but didn't
hurt her and went straight into a pole
and just died.
My best friend's handicapped from doing
the exact same thing at school,
Buddy.
He was just going to say years with
them.
Yeah.
Wow.
Derek is oh,
fucking scary.
You know,
and the building of the three guys in
the car walked away being competitive
like that on this,
on regular streets and racing with
people.
So fucking dangerous.
So dangerous.
Just like you see those painted bikes
that are chained to polls that represent
bikers that died.
I mean there's a,
Oh,
is that what that is?
Well,
La doesn't really have a lot of it in
Chicago.
It's big.
Where I'm from,
it's a big thing of like commuter bikes,
passenger bikes and messengers.
They get hit all the fucking time and
then when they die they spray painted
white and then they change it to the
pole at the intersection and my mom was
saying it was like she's fucking,
one year.
It was almost like every other block she
was driving down to a psych.
There was another bike.
It's another bike because people are
fucking drunk as shit.
A fuck clip.
Some guy that's driving and riding his
bike home from work or some shit.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's a commitment to go,
I'm going to ride a motorcycle.
You got to really buy into it because
your odds of dying just go up
exponentially from driving a car.
Odds of dying more.
I'm a bicycle or
motorcycle.
Sorry Dude.
You're right.
I'm Debbie Downer.
I'm trying to,
we're looking at,
Joe's got the reigns and he's taken us
down and we're going to,
I did not meet any correct frying your
fucking pog cause I be correct in me.
Thank you.
Let me to cry now.
You're alive.
You're right.
Who needs a couple of days?
I'm not the first card.
The cry in the basement of the comedy
store.
Oh definitely not.
Definitely not.
You're probably the first.
It didn't really do anything horrible
though.
I came down here
and it brought me down.
He had this like a back room over there,
which just like storage,
she in it.
And you know what I found,
I found pauly shore is original script
of in the army now with his acting notes
to himself.
No.
Like one of them was like be the weezer
weasel,
the weasel feed,
the weezer
be that band.
They got some be raised there,
but like the whole script he had marked
up the fellows acting nuts.
Did you I would've taken a fucking try.
Want to take it with you?
Yeah.
Well there you go.
This place is,
you know,
one of the most,
uh,
if you believe in ghosts,
one of the most notoriously haunted
places in all of California,
maybe in the country because it used to
be Ciro's nightclubs.
I still Yakov smirnoff here together.
Ah,
a lot of killings happen here,
right?
There's the mob killed tonight.
Roast battles,
taping them all three.
Is it,
um,
is it all sold out?
I don't know.
Roscata tickets.com maybe the finale
might not be.
That's next week.
Now when you,
when you do these things,
do you open up tickets to the public?
They're free tickets.
Oh Wow.
Roast battle tickets.com is how to sign
up.
Oh,
that's awesome.
All invited.
And then,
um,
it'll eric,
January 26,
27,
28,
29.
It's a bracket tournament.
16 comics.
A lot of people from right here in La,
comedy store people.
A couple of people who work here like
answering phones,
j light,
Frank Castillo,
frank's hooper,
a lot of la comics from here in the
comedy store.
Taj Mary's doing it.
How he is doing it.
Wow.
Who is he going against?
He's just like a curse on.
He's fucking funny man.
It's going to be,
prayer is one of the most
underappreciated guys working today.
He's a fucking funny guy.
He's funny as shit.
So Lawrence holds the belt,
right?
Yeah.
And does he have,
does he get,
did he get challenged?
I think he's going to challenge whoever
wins this tournament.
There's so many funny up and coming
comedians and that is one of the best
places for them to expose or to get
exposed.
Some of them already barely comedians
and roast battle and it helps them
figure that out.
Yeah,
they're just starting out your voice
through this roast jokes and some of
them are like,
we did well.
They did jokes that they,
right.
I'm fucking blown away every time I sit
in and judge it.
I'm like,
how long?
I'll say to them afterwards,
how long did you write those jokes for?
There'll be like three months.
Like they literally right from month one
Rose Battle,
two of the roasters told me they have
the bracket up on their wall and they're
writing ahead in they advance or from
when they advance.
Well,
you guys have always said it's a joke
writer showcase.
Yeah.
It's such an important thing in comedy
right now.
Thank you.
It is,
dude.
You need to have that world exist for
people in a world right now where pc and
people on their toes and who knows what
to say what all the time and that's such
a fucking deal.
Now I'm so happy that that is still
being represented in the comedy world
because it fucking lightens everything.
It makes everything,
all the voices shut the fuck up and
enjoy two people making fun of each
other.
Yeah.
It's like the gates,
like the most clean thing that we need
in an entertainment and especially for
comedy because dude,
right now I feel like you're on tippy
toes sometimes when you do shows in
places and you're like,
what do I,
what can the,
what are these people going to get a no,
you're going to get offended by and,
and that fucking there's,
well,
what's so weird is that when we were
coming up,
you know,
like I know Joe and I were really in a
bill hex and like I didn't necessarily
agree with everything about his
politics.
Certainly with kinison.
I didn't believe in any of his politics,
but I fucking loved him.
And now as a comedian,
the crowd has an expectation that they
have to agree with you.
Yes.
And that they'll actually yell out if
they disagree.
It's like that's not an option.
The last name guys like not funny.
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
You're going to have that.
And they feel like they have the right
now because they're so used to
commenting on things.
Yeah.
So used to comedy on things like social
media,
you control pencil,
what it is,
Rosa battery comments.
We don't troll on the Internet.
We troll to each other's faces.
Yeah.
Well no,
that's a different animal look.
Roast battles.
So beautiful because it's a pure
competition.
It's like,
you know,
Mike is so doom and then oh shit.
And then here we go counter.
Like it's like you're playing a game,
you know,
and sometimes the ball goes out of
bounds and sometimes it doesn't work.
At times he hit that,
you know,
sometimes you fucking smash it right in
their face.
I mean it really is
less people.
Amazing.
And I wouldn't say it's you're more apt
to go to when if you go harder.
Right.
I mean is that too many people that lose
by going too far?
Is there?
No,
no,
never.
The best ones I've ever seen are people
that just,
oh,
people are nervous as long as it's
funny.
But what's really weird is when someone
goes super mean and it's not funny.
Yeah.
Yeah Dave.
And that's beautiful to see.
I love that shit sort of entertaining.
Yeah,
of course.
Yeah.
Sorta,
cause you know they don't win,
but it's good fun entertainment folks.
Squirmy,
thank God the audience knows that
failure and comedy is still a thing
that's not just like everything's not
just a special prefabricated a late
nights set.
I think a lot of people,
because they only see comedy in that
way,
they see specials on Netflix,
they see blade nights sets,
things that are tight in our formula
that had been practiced.
Then when they come see live comedy,
I know an inch of any sort of faltering
and they're like,
what?
Well let me ask you this.
The pro e.
S.
N.
T?
No,
you're,
I'm about to release her netflix.
Showtime on showtime.
Oh,
show on showtime.
So when that comes out,
do you abandon your material now?
I mean I,
I've already started to to implement a
bunch of new stuff and do and do both
right now,
right before it even comes out.
Just cause I'm trying to get in the
habit.
But yeah,
I mean I think so.
I mean that's a personal thing.
I don't,
I don't think there's a right or wrong
way to do it,
but I think I'm trying to,
uh,
get rid of that stuff and try all new
stuff.
I'm going to stop doing your shit.
Probably.
You do it so much better.
That's the problem.
That's high.
I sit and watch you do me after.
No.
Yeah.
I'm trying to abandon.
I think I,
but I don't,
I'm not trying to do a special every
year type of thing.
I don't think that's,
for me.
I know that that's like the new thing,
but I don't,
I think even louise backed off of that.
I mean,
I know a lot of people have that
aspiration of like,
I'll do one every fucking year and I'm
always like,
what?
What,
what for though?
We'll wait to see what kind of year you
have.
Yeah.
I mean,
I am years,
right?
Like a motherfucker and I have years
where I'm like,
I'll look like,
I'll look at a set list on my computer
that says like,
you know,
January,
2016 and I looked at it recently,
I'm like,
wow,
this is not that different than what I'm
doing now.
You're like,
I see a bunch of stuff I tried.
It didn't work right.
And then I have years where,
yeah,
I will come up with close to an hour.
It's going to be the year where every
comedy,
the trump,
that's the one thing.
Every comic,
we'll have three specials.
I want everyone to have three.
Everyone's going to get three.
Dude,
you can do trump a little.
Just a little bit.
Do you mean give me a little song.
I heard it.
I like Joe Rogan.
Joe's good.
He's,
you know what is a fighter?
That's what I like.
Fighters.
He's a fighter.
I like fighters.
It's not bad.
It's good.
Except you gotta get the are out of
their other New York.
Yep.
Yeah.
You're close enough fight and you're
like,
almost you from Chicago.
Oh,
shake you down.
You could do this.
Like,
I can't do as a voice.
I can't make that sound like I can
imitate certain people's voices,
but I have a very limited range.
Yeah.
You know,
like the people that I could do,
I could do good,
but I can't do him.
He's self as someone was saying how
hard,
uh,
like trump has almost so quote unquote
simple that like,
that's why anybody that comes down on
snl and there's people can just,
it was a lot of people that can do the
impression,
but they were saying how hard hillary
was,
which I get,
I didn't really think about it,
but I was like,
oh yeah,
that is such a,
she's such a fucking hard voice to
imitate.
Do you know what I mean?
Like it's such a chump.
Trump is,
that's another reason it's so
cartoonishly perfect that you're like
anybody who can do the voice.
A voice like [inaudible] like that is
going to get Bernie.
It was easy as hell.
Oh my God.
He's just an old jail.
It just was Larry David.
Yeah.
Brian was the same fucking medical
revolution.
And then we're going out for soup.
Okay.
So everybody pays for her own food.
He's like Jackie Mason a little bit.
Hey,
hey listen kid.
He said to the pope,
I said,
I met the pope.
listen kid,
what a great job with the Catholics.
Did you see him today?
He was doing that.
He did something he today or yesterday,
Bernie Sanders,
where as grilling,
the guy that was at the Senate
confirmation hearings trying to make
some sense of all of this.
They don't know how to put the thing
in the sky.
That's kind of a climate change denier.
Yes,
so you're telling me that you're
responsible for the climate.
You don't even know if it's [inaudible].
You're fucking you,
you.
It's actually the climate change denier.
He's a skeptic to the science.
You think it's true.
You deny it.
You the night.
What's the truth?
Let's get soap.
That's a good some soup.
You still owe me $2 for that split split
peas.
He's got a tab at canter's.
He said,
listen,
I don't know my Qantas Tab.
I was the lockers for no baby.
I would love to have an only child as
well.
He is.
He's,
he seems like a genuinely nice guy.
Who Does?
Who's that?
Bernie Sanders seems like a g.
Yeah,
he does.
He does.
He to me does.
He seemed like a bowling ball but,
but,
but don't we know that anybody who has
kind of the audacity and fucking self
indulgence to want to be president is
also behind the true fucking crazy.
You're fucking crazy person.
I'm sure he's a nice person.
I was there for the right reasons.
I beg to differ Bernie 22 years in the
Senate or the mayor of my town of a
more,
isn't it possible that someone could not
want to be president until they realize
that the country is back is up against
the wall and that's when he finally ran
is that it is possible for you to
realize that there was no hope on the
horizon for the status quo or this is
new thing,
this trump thing and he's like,
maybe I'll go.
Do you think,
do you think had had had the DNC not
fucking strategically shoved Hillary
Clinton in front of him?
If he had fucking one do youth,
do you think he could be trump?
That's a,
that's an,
you know,
it's just an open speculation.
Who knows how it would've played out?
I'm sorry.
I'm a fucking curious to see that.
I would love not something I'm prepared
to discuss at this time,
but will you,
what do you think you would have one
Bernie,
or what do you think you would have
fucking beat trump?
I think I would have give him a run for
his money.
I think our water,
one of the two states
lucky states.
You think you would have,
I think I went to one in a meeting,
Michigan.
You had it down and cut the head.
I would have been very competitive with
the trump campaign.
Oh Wow.
What about outside of right?
Definitely.
You should do your trump impression now
and you guys should do,
listen,
I'm sorry,
Mr President.
I can't accept your presidency.
I'm stepping out of government.
I'm taking a job at Goldman Sachs.
I need to make some money.
You're welcome.
That's what I would say.
I think done for you boarding
you've ever done for me,
so you're welcome.
You want to make college free?
You got to make college free.
I'm going to charge four times for
college.
Four times more debt with Detroit.
Don't beg me.
Don't any tax returns.
I'm not going to show you my tax bills
to your Baba.
I don't think so.
My stylist does what he does very well.
She does very well.
I have a trans stylist,
by the way.
I have a transcendence.
You want to talk about Trans Culture?
I Have Trans Dialis.
Okay.
Don't tell me I don't like the Lgbtq.
I'm very low budget.
I'm working on,
I care more about the important things
in life.
He looked like you should have at the
dollar store.
It's pathetic.
I try to control that.
They were harder to digest to your
forum.
Trump steaks are delicious.
Don't listen to that.
They're better than Omaha steaks.
We have premium cows.
I powers are beautiful.
They're shipped over from Russia,
from from California.
But appreciate your racist comments that
you've made in the past.
I'm not racist.
Sound ratio.
Um,
ratio with disabilities.
Uh,
what,
what?
I can mock a retard anymore.
What's the news coming to today?
I can't do that.
I can't sit up there and Joko by risks
like we used to when we were seven,
screw you.
Burn.
I'm going to mark a charred once in a
while.
Get used to in America.
That's legitimately what that was.
The Gym.
What would come out of his fucking
brain,
that's for sure.
And you know what that would be fed live
to America and argument between those
two at fucking,
his fans would love it even more.
Like he's right.
He should mock fucking read.
Fine Fun.
That's what my buddy said to his mom.
He was like,
she was a die hard trump supporter and
he said justify seriously to me justify
how he could mock a handicapped person.
She just tell me,
tell me the,
what's the fucking spin on that?
He said it was,
it wasn't because he was hint,
just watch it once.
Volume off.
Watch it once.
No one in the world.
If someone who speaks no English and as
it doesn't understand,
our culture would go well.
They're probably making fun of it.
Looks like they're making fun.
I'll make him a of character of
somebody.
It's just,
it was this kid,
he was a comedian.
He does that about everybody that he
thinks is flustered.
There's like a whole series really
thinks.
He goes,
Ooh,
he does that with when no one knows what
they're doing.
Oh,
and he's trying to figure this out.
Literally that's his thing that he does
when I'm not defending him,
but the real fact is he always does.
I right.
They showed a video of the loop it but,
but specifically he did like this arm
thing like that.
Yeah.
More specific,
more extra sassy like risks banging
against each other.
Can you have a move?
He does this in some of them open handy
and then this was kind of like,
I mean it was just like what you would
when you were a punk kid in third grade
or fourth grade was we're doing to each
other mocking shit.
It was like so obvious that that's what
the boys,
this comic,
and I know you guys probably
won't even remember him,
but he was in la comic,
one of those guys.
It was just always around and you never
really saw him go on stage much.
Earl Skakel and he,
uh,
he had this,
he had these giant front teeth and like
a receded upper lip so that his teeth
just like jutted out.
And I'm talking to him and I don't know
what the fuck was going through my mind,
but subconsciously I like,
you hurled my slip up above my teeth.
And then he just looked at me and he
goes,
oh,
that's really funny.
That's really,
and I realize like in a second that I
was doing it right and I was so fucking
embarrassed.
I didn't know what to say.
That's kind of like when someone's like,
yeah,
when someone's twitching,
you just naturally just do it with them
for some think it's a monkey response.
Monkey see,
monkey do.
It's like subcon's yawns and you start
yawning,
right?
Holy Shit.
Or when someone has a fucking thing on
their face,
you,
you just kind of even feel it on your
face.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah,
there,
but you start to like feel it on your
own face and then you've got to go,
dude,
if fucking,
what are you doing,
Jeff?
Ross?
Somebody knocked.
There was no one that shit.
I got to go.
Anyway.
Jeff,
this has been a blast.
I came in an hour before these you,
uh,
you are the first ever on a live
podcast.
Great.
From the comedy store.
Big Day.
I want to arrest.
Yeah,
you had a lot of shit going on.
It shows it tomorrow's when you tape,
right?
So one more time for everybody.
He Roast Battle January (262) 072-0820
nine on comedy central.
That'd be great.
John Mayer,
Sarah Silverman.
Um,
Jason Sudeikis,
snoop dogg jostled,
beautiful,
beautiful.
All live on comedy central.
You're in the,
uh,
in the,
sizzle reel.
It Open.
I'm so proud.
Nice.
It's really fun.
Andrew Santina,
you're showtime special.
What's it called?
It's called home field advantage.
I did it in Chicago,
uh,
at the theater.
Yeah.
Oh,
beautiful.
And He's already said that when you're
talking about the accent,
I forgot.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I did it in the theater that I used to
go watch bands in when I was in high
school.
It was such a fucking surreal thing.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Let's talk a mile.
What does it out?
June.
It'll be out in June.
Beautiful.
Yeah.
Greg Fitzsimmons,
uh,
fits dog radio,
podcast tour dates coming up to coma.
Whoa.
Austin,
Tampa.
Um,
I've been coming to phoenix.
Go to [inaudible] dot com [inaudible]
says,
shows what's
live poker game look alive.
We'll post the podcast.
Yeah,
that'd be perfect for the,
I don't know how to play it.
Awesome.
Well that camera,
you stick it in the middle of the table
and you can see everybody playing.
That's great.
This and fucking Ken.
An air conditioner.
Yeah.
We could do some shit to this room.
This room is pretty bad ass.
It's cool that they have it.
Also open it up.
Little bit of a
nice and cool down here.
Yeah.
It's not bad.
Yeah,
it's a good spot.
It's cool.
You can,
if you have this door open and that door
open,
you can,
I didn't hear the show background.
Well you can definitely hear the,
we,
we can still hear the piano.
We're going to get back to get a TV down
here.
We can see what's going on on stage.
Would you get a monitor and watch
everybody?
That would be fun.
That would be so fun.
Yeah,
we can easily do that.
Like mystery science,
theater,
uh,
comics that we know.
Yeah.
That's not like rocket science.
Jeff.
Thanks buddy.
Thank you.
Always a pleasure my friend,
although I can't combine them.
I gave you a dainty womanly handshake
there who was like,
hey
man,
shake.
Thank you sir.
And Greg were,
where can people get Ahold of your shit?
fitstar.com baby [inaudible] dog.com.
And the Greg Fitz radio was your
twitter.
That's it folks.
You,
you have been witness to the very first
ever and it went into the 20th.
So it's an inauguration.
Podcasts.
Oh,
it is?
Yeah,
because it's the 20th.
Um,
and uh,
that's it.
You Fox,
first time ever.
Comedy store.
Live podcast.
We'll do it again.
It was fun.
Awesome.
Hmm.