The joe rogan experience.
Right.
And then you can't trust if you're are
80 80 year old billionaire,
you can't trust a girl who's willing to
fuck you with tapes,
exact test.
So then it's like a lot of like,
it's like three people fucking up.
You know what I thought was the most
bizarre about all of it?
Um,
apparently I was correct and that what
she is as far as the most recent story
is that she was supposed to record his
saying his conversations because he
would say things and then forgot he sat
him.
Right.
So He's,
he's got,
he's dementia 81 years old,
these old as fuck.
So he would say crazy things and then
she would record them and you know,
and let him know like what he said.
Right.
Well in this case,
somehow or another,
it got leaked how it got leaked to
speculation,
but he knew he was being recorded.
Right.
That is true.
So you can't,
it's against the law,
the record,
anyone like what if they don't say
anything and it's just bathroom noises
and stuff.
It's against the law still.
Even if they don't talk in it.
Absolutely.
In California,
they don't know about it.
It's against the law.
You're not allowed to record.
The essence can be like if you just put
a tape recorder down behind the toilet,
they don't say a word.
They just,
you know,
and then they leave.
That's still against a law even though
they don't say it.
It said they're just their spirit being
in the room.
The noises of them,
um,
being recorded are actual physical
presence being marked by the sound of
their feet.
I think that's probably illegal.
Really?
Yeah.
That's why they used to tape crank and
criminal.
So I said he guilty as fuck.
He's like,
if you take a tape and put it in behind
the toilets in Bourbon,
whatever,
and the girl might happen to be a
stripper,
whatever,
whatever.
That combination is never gonna happen.
But if it did,
it's just they know that you were
recording her pooping.
It's interesting because I guess so the
recording like no,
no,
Brian,
that's an interesting fucking spaces.
Interesting.
When we talk about that you clam up when
you're like,
oh,
you can't require people pooping.
The real issue with putting all of your
eggs in one basket and that basket being
athletics and especially athletics,
especially combat athletics,
the idea that you're going to have some
sort of a long and successful fruitful
career by throwing your bones and
another person trying to separate
themselves from their consciousness.
That's quite ridiculous because just the
very act of doing it in preparing for
that very active to the amount of damage
that your body and your brain even
endures is.
But we have this idea in our heads that
you know,
a guy has to be an undefeated champion
and you know,
my son's going to be a champion someday.
Like,
man,
if you're really lucky,
your son won't be a champion.
If you're really lucky,
your son will learn the valuable lessons
of martial arts as far as like character
development and the as far as your
ability to overcome what seemed to be
unsurmountable obstacle,
but to become a champion,
you have to be a crazy person.
Yeah.
You have to be crazy person who's
obsessed with nothing but that and that
will take over your life.
Yeah.
And I feel like having worked Avi
obviously with people like that,
you know,
shadowed them and recognizing that
mindset.
Um,
uh,
I,
you know,
and I find too,
like there's just some point at which
like there's some gifts that are just
bestowed by genetics or something and it
didn't matter how hard you work,
you're not going to quite get to that.
Maybe that level that separates the real
and you won't know that until you hit
it.
You know what I mean?
You're not going to know that wall until
you run into it.
And I feel like for some people,
like I was talking to one guy,
just a guy at the gym and,
and uh,
he said something more or less like the
best that he,
he ever felt in a fight was when he was
up against someone he knew was better
than him.
And he knew he was going to lose.
And if they fought a hundred times,
he'd lose a hundred times.
But he packed guy,
he made that guy see something about
himself.
He got that close to him that the other
guys sorta recognize.
I'm a frail.
I made out of the same crumbling stuff
that he's made out of.
And so,
you know,
sort of pierce that teflon armor that,
that I think some fighters carry around
with themselves and he's like,
that's,
that's all I could do.
That for me is the victory.
I still lost.
But I made that guide,
discover something about himself that he
hadn't discovered up until that point
because he'd never been tested to the
point that I got to.
I was not able to test them.
And I thought that's another part about
just being,
recognizing what you're able to do,
you know,
and it may not be beating them,
but it's you,
you find some other measure of success
you
eat.
First of all,
you being a veteran and you,
you being unabashed in your love for
soldiers and your respect for your,
your,
your fellow military members.
When you got on top of that cage and
after,
you know,
they were all cheering and you were
yelling out to all those people that you
loved them.
I mean this is all off camera man.
We had cut to commercial and you're on
top of the cage and you're just yelling
and all those people let them know that
you love them.
That's some intense intense shit.
Yeah.
Overwhelming emotional near shutdown.
I'm walking out to the cage and I see
this dude,
he flies for the one 60th,
which is like the special forces wing of
aviation.
The last time I saw that dude was us
handing him my shot buddy.
You know,
I'm like,
it's a big thing in special forces
community.
We're real tight.
You know,
like I'm handing him my brother that has
bullet holes in him and,
and um,
and I'm like,
I don't want to let him go.
And he's like,
Hey,
I got this.
This is what I do.
You go do what you're supposed to do and
get back to work.
That was the last time I saw this dude
was handing him my buddy on a medivac.
Then I'm walking out of the cage.
I was like,
Holy Shit,
there is that dude from the one 60th
that I handed my shot buddy to.
Totally overwhelming.
I have to go in there and fight and then
uh,
you know,
Nice Fifth Special Forces group is co
located there.
So I saw a bunch of dudes from like the
Green Baret regiment.
Yeah.
It was entirely
too much emotion.
I just want to be like curl up and cry.
Yeah.
It's a completely different kind of,
there's you on top of the cage up there
in that,
that photo.
That's just an intense,
intense picture.
That picture should be framed and on
your wall somewhere because that is one
of the greatest pictures of every scene.
And you could cut me out and just have
the dude.
No,
no,
no.
You need to be in there for reference.
Yeah,
I mean,
but that's your attitude.
What you just said,
cut me out and leave the dude's that
there really is your attitude.
You,
you really don't want that.
you were saying while you were up there
that my job is,
is in here is easy.
What you guys do,
you guys are my heroes.
Yup.
You know,
memory.
Yeah.
I remember everything.
It's disturbing.
Scary.
Don't get a fight with Joe Rogan
verbally.
Okay.