The Joe Rogan experience podcast by
night,
Tony Hinchcliffe hiding right now in the
basement from Cris Cyborg.
This just in.
Ha Ha.
President trump has not responded to any
of Tony's calls.
He's ignored all of his tweets.
Tony does not know what to do.
Brian Red Band is not helping.
I'm trying to find the sound effect for
breaking news.
No,
we don't need to ask sidebar inside.
Giant icons on your phone.
Do you switch the size of your icons?
Canada?
I have regular exercise.
That's what are those sounds?
Oh,
that's why I was confused.
I was like,
well,
I thought there was a.
like you had some hack to your phone.
I also hadn't wanted that.
That's how stupid people are.
I see.
Like,
like a different size icon of go.
Oh,
I hear.
I just bought a hacked.
A firestick off Ebay or Amazon one.
Yeah.
It's one of those things where you put
it in your.
You have everything like movies that are
in the movie theaters.
You have every single TV show,
paper views.
Yeah.
You get and yeah,
all everything you get.
Well,
you know what?
Those little,
those little Amazon things or the little
google one,
those little google sticks,
you stick them in a Usb port on your
computer or on your tv and you can
stream something from your computer
right to that and it plays on the TV.
How in the fuck does that work?
Because like your apple TV.
I have apple TV.
It's like a,
like a big Mac,
big Mac size,
but this is like a usb stick.
It's got a little processor.
The same like in the cell phone in it.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
I don't know how any of that stuff
works.
I can barely get the TV I have to work.
It's because I was watching some fight
to the Dan espn three and I don't know
if you knew this,
but espn three is not really a station.
It's a,
it's a website.
Yeah.
There's espn one,
espn two.
Those are both on tv,
but espn three is like a website,
so they had glory fights on espn three.
We've got an issue here.
Jamie's in here.
There must be an issue.
Um,
espn three.
I had to watch the fights on espn three
because they were on UFC fight pass had
glory on up until this one fight and
then from that one fight on,
it was all on espn three,
so I had it on my laptop and then I
said,
well,
oh,
I don't have a fucking apple laptop
anymore.
Now I can't shoot it directly to the
apple TV,
and then I found out all you need is one
of those little drives.
You stick that soccer in your TV.
Are you sure?
I could,
yeah.
That's how that one.
It works.
A little USB drive and then you could do
it right from your phone to your TV.
I just bought an antenna the other day
just to see like what local channels I
can get.
Holy Shit,
you're a signal 100 and well I got a
hundred and 12 channels.
They're all Mexican and have all the
white people.
It's just distress signals like the
first episode of fear of the water
walking dead.
They're like,
I think I hear something
weird.
Gunshot.
There's one channel that just plays like
Johnny Carson in like old shows from the
eighties.
Oh,
good call.
And then there's just like,
yeah,
there's Russian Mexican,
Korean,
but it is weird just watching
like all these free channels that they.
Well that was one of the things with
radio,
one of the things that happened with
radio is in La in particular,
they would close down,
like when they closed down that FM talk
station,
there's an FM talk station and they
closed it down and then a Mexican
station popped up.
I think what was another talk show?
Pretty much every FM station in La is a
very Mexicans.
There's a lot of Mexican,
like morning radio shows.
They all sound the same.
There's always some big Mexican guy in
some like little tiny guy.
It's always like to sit in the woods.
You sound Japanese.
That's terrible.
Yeah,
that's a terrible.
That was an Asian accent.
Definitely not a worst racist Super
Mexican radio station.
Worst Mexican of all time,
but when I would pass by these bus
stops,
like all over La,
you'd see these billboards that were for
these stations that you never gonna to
listen to.
You know,
like this one neighborhood that my ex
gardener,
I had an ex gardener.
He used to fight chickens who was a.
It was a funny dude,
man.
He came over here a couple times from
Mexico.
He snuck over here,
worked over in America and it's not back
and then snow pack again.
Wow.
What do you mean?
He fought chicken.
He used to have chicken fights.
He was really not really in terms of.
He would go,
he would go,
but the other people would actually
fight the chickens and it was like this
thing where all the men in this
community would go and they all had
these roosters.
I mean this,
we went to this guy's place and went to
check out his backyard and he had,
I don't know,
a hundred rooster cages and I'm not
bullshitting.
They were fucking stacked on top of each
other and then they had an arena.
You'd go into the arena.
It was like a little barn and then it's
like a little sunken in area that they
had dug out and put like a little fence
around and that's where they would check
the chickens in and so they'd have to
guys and they would handle the chickens
and they put spurs on the chickens.
So it's not just the chickens fight each
other,
but they put little razor blades on
their feet.
Wow.
Yeah.
And then they bet on who wins the fight
and then when they,
when like when you know that either one,
both chickens are fucked.
Like they're essentially dead.
Like maybe if you're lucky your chicken
doesn't get totally.
Are there chicken commentators,
someone like and here we crow,
something like that.
You know what I mean?
Fuck.
And here we can't help yourself grow.
You can't help yourself.
You're terrible bird fighting.
Yeah.
But it's apparently a huge thing in the
Mexican community,
but it's interesting is like you
remember when Michael Vick gotten that
big,
horrible situation when they found out
that he was killing dogs and he had dog
fights and you know,
this terrible thing.
He was executing dogs.
That shit is happening all throughout
the south every day.
It's a huge part of their culture by
animal fights,
like dog fights,
but much more so chicken fights in
chicken fights is a weird one where you
can kind of okay with it.
You know,
like people do.
People have a hierarchy of animals that
they give a shit whether or not they're
having a bad life and chickens are super
low on that scale.
Weird that the black people have dog
fights and the Mexicans have chicken
fights.
You would think the black people would
have chicken sites because then they
could just have dinner afterwards.
You know what I mean?
Their favorite.
Well,
the Mexicans eat chickens too.
Dude.
I don't know if say racist bitch,
but the mind makes a Ginsey to dogs or
Mexicans eat Sushi.
Sushi served on a Samurai or my,
my ex girlfriend who used to live like
in like the ghetto part of Los Angeles
and it was always so weird at like six
in the morning.
How many are you hurt?
Like it was like a lot like crazy.
They just get used to it.
Yeah,
it becomes like norm for the community,
right,
for someone to have a fucking rooster
and we were tripping our balls off in
Joshua tree one night and it was like
three or 4:00
AM.
The Sun was not out at all and there was
one rooster that in the middle of the
night was like,
we were always at their big group of
Comedians and us and we started fucking
dying riffing about this like,
you know how out of control this
chicken's life is where you know,
he's such an idiot that he's boxing in
the middle of the night.
All the other chickens are like,
there,
you can look who's blowing his load
early over here.
We're all on mushrooms is dying in this
premature ejaculating basically chicken
that was below lined and it was just
like,
didn't want anybody to know.
So maybe it's clocks off.
He took a nap earlier in the day.
Who just jumped the gun?
Yeah,
he'd be the guy who jumps the gun and
felt way to refresh or mainly he felt
that you guys were on mushrooms and he's
like,
he got there.
This is.
These people are crazy,
or we're on mushrooms and like,
this'll be hilarious.
Oh,
they'll love this.
Watch this.
Three in the morning bomb.
Yeah.
Maybe your very presence or maybe you
guys are loud and you woke him up.
Probably.
We were laughing a lot.
That's probably what it is.
It's fun.
Public are pissed.
It's probably a dog barking.
Right?
It's probably like a bunch of reasons
why a chicken does that.
Not just because they wake up,
but also maybe you could fuck you shut
up trying to sleep over here.
It's not bad enough.
I sleep with my feet on a stick.
Do they?
Yeah.
They purchased so they sleep.
They climb up.
We have these areas in my chicken coop
where they climb up and they put their
feet down and we have other areas where
they could go into a little chicken
house and they could like go inside and
there's like a little roof on the
chicken house.
They fucking never use it.
They don't use that.
They don't want to sit down.
They want to like have their feet on
something.
You'd like to grab on something and hang
on to.
Weird,
so because they're used to purchasing
like in the wild,
they're their body's designed.
We think it as our to with my hands,
I'd be so fucking tired,
but their hands are so different.
Like their feet are designed for that.
Like it doesn't make them tired.
That's an evolutionary advantage.
They can live in trees.
How many chickens do you have?
Twenty three.
Wow.
I didn't know you had that many.
Have a gang of chickens.
Fresh eggs everyday.
How many eggs is 23 a day?
Depends on the time of year.
Like this time of year they're starting
to,
they're,
they're making a lot of eggs because
it's cold out and it's been raining.
And when,
when there's less sunlight,
they make more eggs to dethrone a lot of
eggs or do you just.
No,
no.
Give them away.
But I eat a lot of them.
You know,
if there's um,
if there's 23 of them,
they might make 10 eggs a day and I
probably five of those.
Maybe six.
That's great.
Yeah.
I eat a lot of eggs.
Everybody eats eggs.
We eat eggs and eggs are not bad for
you.
That's a fucking long standing myth that
someone concocted in the 19 fifties and
there was a New York Times article about
it if you're really interested,
is terrible.
But um,
the sugar companies for not that much
money for what's like in American
dollars today,
like $50,000,
they paid off a bunch of scientists to a
fake these reports and write reports
saying that saturated fat was causing
people to have heart disease and get
overweight.
And when it was really sugar.
What about cholesterol?
It's not bad for you.
Not only cholesterol,
not bad for you.
It depends on what kind of cholesterol.
There's certain types of cholesterol
that people have genetic propensities
for the not good,
but there's ldl cholesterol and then
there's actually like different sizes of
different ldl cholesterol.
Cholesterol is,
and some of it's actually good for you
and some of it's not good for you.
And there's hdl cholesterol,
but dietary cholesterol,
like eating dietary cholesterol doesn't
move.
It doesn't move.
The blood lipids doesn't change.
That's not what changes your
cholesterol.
It's like sedentary lifestyle and
Saturate and sugar and processed foods.
Those things elevate cholesterol more
than eating things with cholesterol.
It's very strange.
And then saturated fat.
We all grew up thinking saturated fat
was bad.
That's why you have margarine,
right?
Margarine is fucking illegal.
Now,
do you know that?
You know,
trans fats are illegal now.
Do you know trans fats in the next three
years?
They have to remove them from food.
They have three more years to take them
out of food.
They gave him like a grace period of
three years.
So these companies can shift their
manufacturing.
What's that?
Has Trans fats that we all ships a lot
of like Doritos and shit.
I don't have to read those,
but Fritos,
say some shit with trans fats in it.
Yeah,
so those are going to start tasting
different soon.
Probably don't taste as good.
Well then it might taste better.
Honestly.
The thing is that people thought that
like margarine was good for you,
Marjorie,
and is fucking terrible for you.
Yeah.
Unsaturated fat is bad for you.
Saturated fat is good for you.
That's how fucking stupid we are.
Our whole lives,
we grew up with shitty information and a
lot of it is because scientists were
paid off by the sugar company because
the whole New York Times article about
it stunning.
You read it and you go,
oh my God,
this is like responsible for who knows
how many millions of people making poor
dietary choices and perhaps ruining the
quality of their life,
ruining the amount of energy they have,
ruining the amount of inspiration they
would have because their body was
fucking with them,
causing all sorts of premature death and
diseases and it's not an exaggeration.
This is like a subject that is been like
knowing at me for years now.
It's a crazy,
crazy subject.
Yeah.
I've sort of been talking about lately a
graze upon it in my standup about how
like,
uh,
you know,
fats,
something that you need and carbs,
which is what makes you fat is something
that you don't need,
but we call fat people fat and that's
insulting.
That's why I don't call fat people fat.
I call them carbs.
Carbs aren't even necessarily bad for
you.
It's sugar.
Sugar's what's bad for you and the issue
isn't carbs because carbs with fiber,
like some carbs like Zucchini bread,
it's not bad for you and it's just
amazing though,
like the marketing of it though,
you're right,
because it's like you're taught that
sugary sweet and sugar is good and give
your kids candy on Halloween and sugar,
sugar,
and then fat.
We call fat people fat.
That's the part.
That's weird.
What's weird is
if you see those photos that you saw a
long time ago from like the 19 twenties
in the 19 thirties,
you don't see anyone fat.
You see these people walking around and
everyone looks lender.
I mean it's super rare when you see like
a Jackie gleason,
Karen Sweden to whenever we're in
Sweden.
Yeah.
Even the pregnant women were skinny.
It's because America has let these
assholes put all kinds of fucked up shit
that tastes great,
but it's hugely bad for you and they've
put it all throughout our food and they
did it when we were growing up.
I mean,
come on,
man.
We all eat lucky charms.
We all like cocoa puffs and fucking.
I used to love captain crunch.
That shit is straight sugar.
I would eat a whole bowl of that like a
giant bowl.
You know they sell just
the berries now as a serial.
Oh God.
Yeah.
That's insane.
They're not even going to pretend fuck
all that crunchy shit.
Just marshmallows and trans fats.
Cakes,
pies and cookies.
Especially with frosting.
Oh,
too bad.
Those like hostess,
Apple Pies,
those awesome hostess pies.
Microwave Popcorn,
microwave popcorn as trans fats.
Frozen Pizza,
fried fast foods cream filled
candy,
crackers.
Breakfast sandwiches,
cheese,
breakfast sandwiches.
Breakfast.
Yeah.
What about like big macs?
Cleveland Clinic Max.
I mean,
what about like the griddles because
just because you said that.
Okay.
Want one on the way home,
but I had one two days ago,
so that typically contain at least one
gram of trans fats.
Take a close look at the ingredients and
you're likely to find partially
hydrogenated oils in the top five.
See,
we used to think that that was good.
Partially hydrogenated oil,
just partial,
partially hydrogenated corn oil.
Amazing.
We used to think that that was good.
People would prefer that you would think
you making the healthy choice
by choosing that motherfucker's it says
if refrigerated or frozen dough produces
a texture.
That seems too good to be true.
It probably is.
God dammit.
Yeah.
You gotta make it fresh and that's
probably what's in like Vegan ice cream
and shit to make it all mushy.
Yeah,
whatever they did to make vegan stuff.
Good.
They did it because towards the end
there,
I'm telling you the Vegan stuff was
pretty good when I was doing it,
like the tastes of it was amazing.
There's a lot of really good vegan chefs
out there that know what the fuck
they're doing.
Yeah.
You know there's a place called follow
your heart.
It's like this cool little place in the
valley that you can go and get these.
I'm Vegan pancakes.
They're like Vegan,
buckwheat,
pancakes.
God damn good.
They just have no idea.
There's no eggs in there or milk.
There's a place at the one on one and
the Bar Ham,
same thing.
Vegan pancakes that are banana
blueberries and you can taste every
fucking real blueberry.
It's just one of those things.
Yeah,
they make some pretty decent like Vegan
Sandwich,
meat type products,
you know,
but the thing about that is that kind of
processed totally.
I mean there's a lot of preservatives in
that stuff.
It's just to get something that's Vegan
doesn't mean it's necessarily good for
you because Oreos are Vegan too.
And I'm telling you it's very true
because,
you know,
I was a Vegan for five years and then my
diet fucking completely changed.
I mean just steak every day for lunch at
some point,
whether it's in a sandwich and a bowl of
fa.
Well,
whatever it is,
you know what I mean?
That's how you say it.
What was the reason why you decided to
make a shift?
Um,
a lot of it was just like I was just is
more gone to than I am now.
I just couldn't keep up.
My schedule got busy and I just,
it wasn't that good at it.
And it's impossible to do on the road.
It's impossible.
And I did it.
I was eating fucking the bare minimums,
like French fries and you end up out
there and you got nothing.
Even if you go French fries,
so a lot of times that's boiled and
before.
Yeah,
no.
I know beef fat.
Yeah.
It's like an,
it was just a nightmare,
but I mean it was also,
you know,
at the time I had a really,
cool smart girlfriend who was Vegan.
It was cooking amazing stuff,
fucking Vegan enchiladas once a week
that were just mind blowing and all this
stuff.
So it was sort of easy for me and at the
time,
you know,
I was just looking for anything to help.
And what was the day that you did it?
Why did you do it?
I know you had a lot of influence.
We were going to.
A lot of great steakhouses wasn't long
after I started working with you and I'm
just watching you eat a steak and then
you know,
you're,
and I wasn't getting.
My energy levels have completely
changed.
I go to the gym every day now pretty
much,
you know,
six,
five,
six days a week and knock something out
and it's.
I just wasn't like that before,
but isn't it funny?
But if I brought this up to you while
you were a Vegan,
you would just be raving about how much
energy you have and how healthy you are.
Like that's one thing that people always
do,
no matter what they're doing.
I mean I'm guilty of it myself.
When you're doing something,
you want to promote whatever that thing
is because you want other people to do
it.
So you start ranting and raving about
how great it is.
And it was for a because.
And I thought that it was that,
but it also probably had a lot to do
with the timing of everything was where
you started making money for the first
time in comedy around that very same
time when I started dating that Vegan
girl,
that was the beginning of the five years
of that like it was when I started
getting to do the road a lot with like
Jeff Ross back then.
And I started writing on the roast back
then and I had a little bit of money and
things were going good.
So I think that that played a lot into
my like energy and just feeling good
overall was,
you know,
being able to survive
was the first place.
Did you go to Fogo de Chao or something?
Is that what you did?
You guys all went.
So you were there,
you saw us?
Oh yeah.
I think I bought your.
Me.
I was happy.
It was like a holiday for me because it
was awful.
Having like your friend and especially
being on the road and you just wanted to
go to an awesome restaurant and then I
don't know about these options that we
have here.
I was never that way.
No,
no.
I was never that way.
He would always make a thing about it
before I die.
Are you able to eat here?
Like they never had a problem,
but it's all good.
The point is is that that first day,
even after Fogo de Chao,
remember,
I was like a fucking pit bull after
that.
Like that night you called me up
screaming.
That night I was,
I made a beat.
Now I'm a different person.
It felt like,
what the fuck happened to Tony?
It was,
I've never done like real steroids,
but I'd imagine that exact.
I felt like a fucking animal.
Did you still have.
You haven't had elk yet?
Now?
I've never.
Oh my God.
In the.
When we set up,
I'm getting a new grill.
I'm getting a new yoga grill and I'm
putting my old one at the studio.
I want to set up at the studio because
you know,
I have freezers back there.
I'm going to grill some steaks.
Great.
At the studio.
You got to eat it.
I mean you're,
you're gonna feel you're gonna.
Feel another bump above where you're at
now.
Like I used to watch Ted nugent and I'm
just like,
where's this crazy fucker?
Get all his energy because he's crazy as
shit.
Right?
And he's yelling and screaming and then
he's like,
he's like 70 something years old.
And I'm like,
how does,
how does you have so much God damn
energy?
And then I saw him.
He had this interview once where he's
cooking the steak,
this deer steak.
This is years ago.
It was probably one of the things that
is before I ever hunted,
one of the things that popped into my
head,
the idea of hunting and he was cutting
up this piece of meat and showing like
how red and dark it wasn't talking about
how many nutrients that there was in it
and how much more nutritious and healthy
it is than store bought meat that has
hormones in it and antibiotics and all
this jazz and I remember thinking
motherfuckers probably right and then
the first time I deer meat from an
animal that I shot and I was sitting
there eating and I was like,
God damn it.
I feel it.
You can.
It's like a extra charge to it.
Why do you think that is?
Do you still really healthy animals?
If you.
If you eat a deer,
you're eating a wild sprinter.
I mean it's a wild sprinting machine
that's trying to get away from eating
machines,
eating machines at what?
Literally want to tear it apart.
Like that's it's life.
It's like,
what was that noise?
If you see a deer and the wild and just
constantly like was gone over here,
let's go.
They bounce every now and then they
scare each other and then they have to
fucking chill and come back.
Is there a restaurant at least in Los
Angeles that serves dear,
like even that place in Calabasas,
like what?
You can get some places that serve it,
but here's what's ironic.
Most of the stuff that they serve comes
from New Zealand.
Most of the venison that you buy comes
from New Zealand and New Zealand.
New Zealand's a treatment because New
Zealand is this gorgeous island.
I want to visit New Zealand just to look
around because also because it's where
they filmed the hobbit and she's like,
you look at those scenes,
those landscapes.
When they.
When you watched the Hobbit,
you go,
my God,
where is this?
But it's real in New Zealand.
My friend remy is a hunting guide.
Remy Warren.
He's been on the podcast before and he
goes to New Zealand once a year and
guides people over New Zealand.
He sent me some pictures of like what it
looks like there.
I just,
I don't even want to go there to hunt.
I'm not.
I want to go there just as a vacation,
just to see what it's like because it's
supposed to be just stunning to look at
waterfalls and everything is green and
lush,
but here's what's fucked up about it.
Didn't have any animals on it.
He's people from England came over to
New Zealand and put all these animals.
They're so.
There was very little local wildlife and
the local wildlife they had was so
fucked up.
They wind up killing off a bunch of
them.
They used to have an eagle there.
It's called the.
It's called the Haas Eagle that had a 14
foot wingspan and they think it hunted
people.
They think it's one of the reasons why
they exterminated that thing.
Wow.
Yes.
Oh my God.
What in the fuck?
How cool is that?
Double check my math.
I'm pretty sure it's 14 feet long,
but it's way bigger than the biggest
eagle we have today.
Way Bigger.
It was the biggest eagle ever and there
was a lot of speculation that preyed on
humans,
but New Zealand has no predators,
so New Zealand has like all these elk
and deer and everything and a lot of
them are like fenced in and then they
slaughter them and send them back to
America.
They send it all over the world costs
eagle h a s a h,
a s eagle.
It's an extinct eagle from New Zealand.
I think it only lived on New Zealand as
far as we know,
two to three meters.
That's about three meters.
That's nine feet.
I'm full of Shit.
God Damn it.
I thought it was 14 feet.
I think.
Go find something else because I swear
to God,
something said that it was bigger than
that.
You know what?
We did this on the podcast before we
went over this on the podcast,
there was an episode where I said,
Oh,
I thought it was bigger than that,
and then we found out other places did
say it was bigger than that.
Now I remember.
Okay,
so you see if you could find one that
core operates my shitbag memory.
What should we do with this thing?
Dude,
I'm all vape pens these days.
You don't want to smoke it.
Whoa.
So if you don't have predators,
like they don't have bears or wolves
have nothing.
They have nothing.
So these God damn things are everywhere
and they,
they,
they slaughter them.
They get so bad that sometimes they have
to shoot him out of helicopters,
don't overpopulate areas.
So they fly over these areas and gunned
down these stags with helicopters and
leave them to rot.
What a panda bears eat like you can live
to.
That's weird.
Yeah.
They're vegetarians,
right?
Yeah.
Pretty much.
They do a lot of rape in though panda
bears apparently the rape the fuck out
of each other and not pandas.
I'm thinking of cool.
Those qualities of the Eucalyptus.
We are too.
It's funny because we thought that.
But um,
so anyway,
New Zealand is.
I'm so wild game meat that you get.
If you go to a restaurant and you have
like elk,
you by elk today,
most likely you're getting it from New
Zealand.
What was that one meat that you gave me?
One time it was cooked.
It was the best meal I've ever had in my
life.
That was wild boar for.
Yeah,
there was smoke ball.
Oh my God.
That was.
I remember thinking there's nothing I've
ever tasted.
That was that good?
Yeah.
Well it tastes different than anything.
I cooked it for my kids the other day
and my wife was saying what while we're
eating it.
Charlotte,
sorry to hear that.
She was like,
this does not taste like any other kind
of meat because you're eating a wild
animal that's struggling and surviving
the acorns and shit.
It was like dark pig times too.
It was like pig,
like dark meat,
Latin restaurants because you gotta you
gotTa Kill Them.
You got to go out.
You'd have to go out and hunt them and
kill them.
There should be like.
But there's weird laws about that.
There's weird laws in this country about
wild game and it's good.
There's are good laws because the reason
why they establish these losses because
in the 18 hundreds we had almost no
animals left because of market hunting.
When market hunting is,
is after the civil war,
and actually even before that,
no,
they didn't have refrigerators man.
And so if you wanted meat,
you had to get it pretty fresh.
It had to be killed like within the last
couple of days.
And so what they would do is they would
go to these,
um,
uh,
soldiers who had come back from the war
and really didn't have anything to do
and these guys would get hired by these
meat companies and they would just go
out and shoot buffalo and elk and deer.
And at a certain point in time they had
almost eradicated all of the wild game
animals in this country that,
you know,
today,
like wild deer.
There was almost no deer left.
And the early 18 hundreds and the early
19 hundreds,
the turn of the century,
you would be super lucky if you saw a
deer.
If you went deer hunting,
it'd be super lucky if you saw a deer
and they wouldn't be a big deer.
Everybody just,
everybody just went buck wild on him.
It was common in preparing themselves.
There should be a subscription box
service that lets you order hunting
meat.
No,
no,
you this,
you don't.
You're getting me wrong.
I just explained that you can't sell it
because of that market hunting wiped out
all those animals because they sold
them,
so they made laws,
established laws that say you cannot
sell wild game,
so if you go to public land and there's
a good percentage of the hunting that's
done in the United States,
at least is done on public land,
and what that means is Freddy Roosevelt
a or a theater.
Roosevelt in his wisdom,
realize that we have all this incredible
land in the United States.
Who's Freddy's brother?
Freddy Roosevelt.
You're thinking?
Yeah,
but I said Freddy Roosevelt Franklin,
but I was thinking of Teddy.
Yeah.
The Theater Roosevelt.
But was it Franklin Roosevelt who
established for two different
Roosevelt's?
No.
Teddy and theory is the same,
right?
No,
teddy,
but Freddie Franklin,
Franklin,
Franklin Delano Roosevelt,
a different person.
When was he president?
Theodore Roosevelt Guy who set it all
up.
Anyway,
Theodore Roosevelt set up conservation
for like,
I'm good dude tonight.
Ten 33 to 45.
Which one is that?
Franklin Franklin.
Oh,
so Teddy Roosevelt,
the original.
That's why they called the teddy bear me
establish things like,
um,
like um,
yellowstone,
like when you go to yellowstone,
that's all because of those guys,
like in the people in his era,
they looked at all this amazing land and
they realized like,
we can't let this go away.
Like this is really important.
Like we gotta keep this public.
We got to keep this.
We got to figure out a way where
everyone can go and enjoy this and not
have someone just put a fence around it
and make it impossible for people to
traverse.
So they set up all these public lands in
this country that are.
It's really rare.
You don't have these giant chunks of
land that no one can buy or sell in this
country.
We do.
It's really,
really rare in other countries.
What are some of the other animals that
tastes good that we don't ever get to
eat for El boar and elk are prime.
Harriet Belk is probably the best meat
you'll ever have in your life.
It it tastes so much better than beef.
It's just,
it's just a pure meat.
It's pure and you're eating an animal
that eating when it's supposed to eat
too.
It's a healthy animal that's in the
prime of its life,
so you can really only get it if you
hunted you only or if you have a friend
that's a hunter.
The only way.
Weird.
Yeah.
It's weird.
It's weird because that's what we should
be eating.
I mean it's so unamerican to not be able
to buy something.
No,
you can't because we would wipe it out.
Right?
It's smart.
We would wipe it out.
But what if you have farm raised wild
anymore?
Then not only that,
when they do that and they have done
that,
they do raise wild ones and they put
them in these pens and they put fences
around them.
The problem is we're not supposed to be
eating all of the same spot and when
they do,
they develop diseases.
They don't have immune systems for them,
so they develop something called chronic
wasting disease.
So it was a giant issue in a lot of
parts of the midwest where they took
these animals,
and this is just speculation,
they don't exactly know what caused his
chronic wasting disease,
but it didn't exist before.
These farm systems where they would grow
these deer in these pens and so these
put these high fence operations up,
these giant chain link fences.
The deer can't get out,
they're all stuck in there and they
would feed them and when you feed these
deer,
they'd be eating each other's saliva and
they would develop all these diseases
they never developed before because
there were grass eaters.
They're supposed to be out there eating
wild vegetation.
That's what is supposed to be eating
sage and grasses and all the different
things that you see.
Like you know when you see a,
a buffalo roaming in a field,
that's what they're supposed to be
eating,
man.
But we've in our wisdom,
have realized,
oh,
we can get these fuckers fatter if we
just stick them in this thing and make
me eat corn.
And so that's what fucked up our food in
this country.
It's what?
It's the same thing that fucked up the
production of processed foods with all
the sugar.
It's the same goddamn wisdom.
I don't think we're far away though for
having like cloning food,
being able to like,
hey,
we can make food nowadays.
They can do it.
You can do it.
Yeah.
Do you think though it's not far away
that where you could actually buy a
certain thing.
You go to the grocery story.
This is fake food,
but you can buy like bore and all the
game.
It probably won't taste the same for the
same reason why a cow doesn't taste the
same.
If it eats grass,
like if you give a cow grass,
it becomes this different animal.
If you give a cow corn,
it becomes this fatty,
lighter colored animal is a lot of
people think is more delicious.
A lot of people like that better that
like corn fed better include Anthony
Bourdain.
He likes the corn fed beef.
You know,
it really does.
It does.
I really like a fatty steak,
but he's also a chef.
You know,
he knows how to cook it perfectly and
under manipulate that fat and you know,
marble it perfectly or the cookie
perfectly rather the marbling and all
that sort of hang out with him,
Huh?
Yeah.
A couple times.
One hunting with him.
Does he love his life as much as I think
he should.
Here's the restaurant in the world
according to him.
You know,
we.
What?
Did you guys have the world's best job
in the world off with each other?
No.
No,
like youtube.
Well,
wouldn't you like to have the only
people that I know that really,
really like seems like you guys should.
I mean,
I know you do.
I don't know him,
but I have always hoped like,
man,
I hope he fucking knows what he's doing
is everybody's dream job.
Oh,
for sure.
He knows and I know too.
Yeah.
I definitely know that I have dream
jobs,
but my dream is different than his dream
job.
We just both have dream job.
But you guys found your own dream jobs
is what I'm saying?
Oh,
for sure.
Yeah.
Like his dream job.
Absolutely.
One hundred percent is doing what he
does,
he fucking loves it man.
And you know,
he's also like super into Jujitsu now,
which is really weird.
So everywhere he goes,
he's born in Jujitsu than I ever was.
He trains every day,
every fucking day.
Every day.
Was that his lady?
But they got divorced but he's still
like.
But there were super good friends.
They just lived separate,
like he's on the road all the time,
but they have a kid together and they're
really close and they raised the kid
together and it's like,
it's not a bad situation at all.
He's a great guy.
He's a very,
very,
very smart guy and very real guy.
You know,
it was very [inaudible] me,
he need just found something in Jujitsu
and just pursued it and he's getting a
reward out of it and he chases it down.
He's like,
he goes to these places,
man,
he's just sucking this world up.
You know,
he's in Jamaica or China or anywhere
he's going,
he's just stuck in these places up.
He's just pulling them in and writing
about them and talking about them and
experiencing them.
And you get that from the show fucking
powerful show,
man.
It really fucking is because he's
somehow able to really tap into that
culture as fast as possible.
Again,
with whoever those are that are doing,
like,
you know,
there's a whole thing that has to go
into that.
It's not like Anthony's calling places
in Cuba,
you know what I mean?
So whoever's producing that and doing
that research and he makes every little
bite look unbelievable
what is called zero point zero.
And they're the same company that
produces mediator,
same show or same production company
that produces those two amazing show.
So they didn't know what the fuck
they're doing.
They make great stuff.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
It's um,
and again,
for him,
that's his dream job.
Me,
I'd be like,
yeah,
let me the fuck home.
I don't like traveling that much.
I mean,
I traveled pawlenty and I'm,
I'm home for a lot lately.
I'm home more now than ever before.
And I like it a lot better and I'm not
working less.
I'm working just as much on getting a
lot of shit done.
But all that air travel and all that
stuff that.
That is bullshit.
You're working smarter.
Yeah.
But I just realized like there's a way
to do this.
And another thing that helped fucking
tremendously,
it's coming back to the store because
I'm working on shit all the time.
I did four sets here the other night on
last Thursday I did four sets and I'm
like,
I can do four sets on a Thursday night
at the same goddamn club.
Don't need to go anywhere.
Like I do eventually.
I mean I do like to do the road.
I do like to,
but even the road,
like what I'm doing the road,
I'm doing less theaters than ever
because I'm like,
uh,
I have more fun at clubs.
Like it's,
I like 300 people.
That's what I like.
You get more work done by doing more
sets.
Exactly.
You get more work done by doing more
sets,
but also the experience you're not going
to get as much money with the experience
is a different experience,
a better experience.
It's more standup and you're connected
to those people.
Whereas those theaters,
a lot of it is really fun,
you know,
like New Year's was a fucking blast.
Right.
But a lot of it is a show,
right?
Big Ass show,
big lighting,
change.
People there,
you know,
a lot of it you're paying for that pop
that happens when the lighting change
happens and the show's about to start.
You know what I mean?
Well,
you just paying for all that energy
because you don't get that.
You get always a cheesy thing usually at
a comedy club coming up next week at the
chuggle hood.
You know what I mean?
Almost every decent parking validation
available.
They always have weird announcements.
Is there a chuckle hut by the way?
It must be.
I don't think so because that's the fun
of everyone's jokes.
What did they say?
Everybody says uncle fuckers chuckle.
Hut,
right?
That's what everybody says.
Oh No.
I've just always chuckle.
Head is like what I picture like the
worst comedy club that sound like,
oh yeah man.
Those things are so important though
that without those clubs.
Look,
I've had this conversation with club
owners before to like give my thanks
because I think there's a lot,
there's a combative relationship that
happens between a lot of comics and club
owners,
you know,
they're trying to fuck us and because
everybody has a story,
right?
Everybody has a story where a club owner
fucked you over or something happened.
Everybody has a story and so in the
beginning it's hard to get booked,
so developed a sort of contentious
relationship with them in the first
place because they don't want to use you
because you're not really that good.
Then things start going for you and then
you start selling tickets and then you
think they're not giving you enough
because you sell too many tickets.
Then eventually you realized somewhere
along the line.
I think hopefully eventually I did at
least that the fucking need those people
like without them,
there's no art form.
Like we need a place to practice.
This isn't like music.
This isn't like writing.
Like we have to go in front of those
fucking people and we're not going to do
it ourselves.
You know?
We're just the.
Especially the funny ones,
you think Louis Ck is gonna open up a
comedy club comedy club and Bill Burr
Bill Berg and open up a fucking laugh
factory.
No.
Are you going to open up a comedy club?
No,
no,
no.
No.
One is.
So you need those fucking people.
Yeah.
It's crazy because like,
you know,
without.
And it's also amazing how each club has
their own different vibe and totally
different DNA.
There's no,
I mean other than the Improv's,
which you know are the Improv.
Yeah.
I figured out a way to make them all
feel the same.
I think that's it and I don't like that.
I mean I enjoy my time in the southern
California Improv's when I performed
there,
but like,
here's a thing.
No,
it's not bad.
It's not a bad feeling.
Like if you go to do the Tempe Improv,
even though it feels like all the Improv
is a fucking great clubs.
Yeah.
Same thing with all of them.
They figured out how to do it right
because you go to every place.
It's almost all the same experience.
It's a good experience and then it just,
they leave it up to the stand up so they
have everything down in between,
but it feels very different than say if
you go to Zane,
he's in Nashville.
Exactly.
That's a club that's been in that form
for 30 years or something like that.
It's an amazing spot.
This ancient headshots in the world on
the wall where half the people are dead,
you know,
love that.
That's a different vibe.
Right?
Or the Ice House.
That's a totally different vibe.
That's a non corporate vibe.
That's like a holy shit.
Look at this gym,
you know?
I love that place.
St e's in Chicago,
Portland,
helium,
Denver,
comedy works.
All those places.
Helium and Philly.
Yeah.
That's great.
All those clubs are like these.
Almost like a mom and pop organization,
if you had to look at it that way
because they're.
They're a small business.
It's a small business that caters to
live comedy.
Without it,
we're fucked.
Look what happened in Houston.
The last stop in river oaks closed down
in Houston and so did the scene.
I mean,
I know there's some guys out there and I
don't want them to feel bad that I'm
shitting on it.
I'm not shitting on Houston and there's
a lot of great comics came out of there,
you know,
a lot of our friends came out of there,
Maddie Kirsch.
Um,
but what happened was they had this
powerful fucking scene.
It was like everybody thought about,
you thought about La,
thought about New York,
you thought about Boston and San
Francisco and you thought about fucking
Houston.
Houston was a real scene man.
They had kinison and Hicks and it was
like they had a whole thing going on.
And when we came along I came along and
I started working there in the late
nineties and it was still echoing.
It was like they,
the Hicks was dead.
Tennyson was dead,
but there was like this bar,
just the last reverberations of the
echoes of that crew,
Jimmy Pineapple and all these guys that
came through with him and,
uh,
the outlaws of comedy that they used to
call themselves.
And they were like looking for the next
ones.
Was there in Austin scene back then?
Yes,
there was,
there was always a scene and very smart
seen.
Austin has always been thought of as
like a,
a smart place,
you know,
like because of the universities there
and it's like a real liberal town,
a smart towns.
The velveeta room came along and when
they were.
When did they start out?
I tell you what though.
Houston has got a new up and coming
that,
that new club that opened up the secret
group.
When did they open up?
Just this year.
We.
Excellent.
Yeah,
it was amazing.
They did an entire festival in like it's
this multi room to like super warehouse
and they have an outdoor parking lot and
they put a huge outdoor tent so we were
doing like kill Tony in one room while
Joey and sold out big ass warehouse,
like a fucking rave version of kill Tony
and outside in this big open field under
a huge tent.
Joey Diaz just fucking,
I mean this place has so many rooms and
I do believe it or lots of comics that
got together and bought it.
They have a club too.
It's called the secret group and that's
perfect with a bomb ass,
huge green room in the middle,
like off,
you know,
but everybody's going to do there.
There's different shows,
different room.
That sort of proves my point that you
need a club because the Houston scene,
they opened up an Improv there,
but you know with Improv's the same
thing we were talking about,
it's a corporate environment.
It's a totally different thing.
You're not going to have a bunch of
people hanging around.
They probably don't have an open mic
night.
If they do,
it's probably not that big of a deal.
It's hard to get work.
Like one of the things about the really
good places is you can actually start
out there and then work,
you know,
like a comedy works like Wendy as a
whole system.
You started out there as a open miker.
You develop your act and they let you mc
on shows.
They teach how to bring people up to
teach you how to middle than you learn
how to headline and then all of a sudden
you're on the road.
You can actually become a comic and you
can get paid there.
She has like local headliners that,
that started out in her club that'll
come down there and do a week and sell
tickets like people know who they are.
People in the town.
She's a beast.
Yeah man.
You need a club and need a club.
You need cloud are,
you know,
looking at this place the greatest of
all time.
We've got to paint this room black
because we're going to do more of.
These are going to paint these room
black and I'm going to put blue leds
behind the comedy store.
Like,
like,
uh,
Mexicans low rider.
Yeah.
They have those things up.
I tell you what,
uh,
you know,
Hugh,
I think it's Phillips Hue.
Uh,
you can get a lot of light bulbs and
then control it with apps and change all
the different colors.
They have the New Light Light Stir
protuse,
uh,
which are so bright,
but it can change any color you want.
And just sit there and go like,
I went purple behind the comedy store
right now.
Interesting.
It's great.
Check it out.
I think it should be blue though.
For what?
To make an act.
You want leave it blue.
I'm just thinking about a foot and if
you have a black wall,
but the red behind it.
That's right,
because that's the light.
Yeah,
and we put the light on what?
We're going to end the podcast.
It's like the red light,
like,
oh my God,
the light is on time.
As I wrap it up,
we found it.
That's it.
That's what we're gonna do.
Okay,
so that's fine.
We'll put a red led light behind it.
We're going to paint this whole room
black and we got to get rid of the
interrogation lighting.
This is the first 48.
This is that room where people fuck up.
Don't talk even when they're guilty.
Keep your mouth shut.
Why do I walk in and put a cigarette out
on my forehead right now?
Whenever I watched those videos,
tell the damn truth.
I always watched those videos.
I hope those guys lie.
I hope they do a good job.
Am I?
Come on.
You can get out of this is really good
at it.
Do you know,
I mean I did.
I tell you this,
that I've been watching those videos
lately,
real interrogation videos.
It's interesting as fuck to me because
either they break or they don't break
and
yeah,
very rare.
They don't break,
but when they don't break you have to be
really worried,
but it's.
Those are fucking sociopath.
That's exactly
clean.
The interesting thing is when they don't
break your even more amazed like,
Oh,
you evil motherfucker,
just able to stay so calm.
You've got to look some of these up.
My favorite is when they admit to a
little bit of a lie and then they have
to correct their store and then you see
him like four hours later and they just
beat these dudes down.
They keep talking to them hour after
hour after hour,
which should be,
by the way,
totally illegal because you leave me in
a room for fucking six hours.
If I think that I'm going to get to a
bed and six hours,
I'll start confessing to shit.
Like that's when people do like,
yeah,
okay,
I fucking stabbed him.
Can I go to sleep now?
Explain.
Uh,
yesterday got stuck on the tarmac in San
Francisco.
Was It delta?
Yeah,
it was.
It had nothing to do with delta.
It was a,
there was a ground stoppage for the
first time in a very long time at lax,
which means any flights that are about
to leave from anywhere automatically
delayed until further notice because
they were the cause of whether they were
at full ground stoppage and about the
interrogation thing.
I'm on the tarmac.
They,
the delay was four hours and I was
literally fighting back tears.
I was breaking as a human.
Yeah.
You were crying about the rain.
You were upstairs crying about the rain
during killed Tony.
We had a massive drought.
People are dying.
There's no waterfield babies die.
Nobody's dying from this drought.
You know how many people died just
yesterday for hurricanes.
Tornadoes to or.
Yeah,
maybe.
Tornadoes,
tornadoes,
hurricanes.
One of those.
Yeah.
Atlanta.
Atlanta got hurricanes.
They know it's coming.
If you get fucked up by hurricane,
either you're really poor or you're
really stupid.
Right?
But if you get fucked up by a tornado,
you just got shit.
They said that 18 people died in Atlanta
or whatever that was,
but I looked it up in like 12 of them or
10 or 16 something.
There was a very high number of the
people were all at one trailer park.
That basically just got like squished.
I thought that was crazy.
It was like whatever I'm in.
I am just trying to guess here,
but out of the 18 people that died in
Atlanta,
12 of them is my final answer on the
guests all from the same trailer park
and I was thinking like,
what the fuck had to happen to this
trailer park?
I didn't really get to figure it out.
They didn't have much detail.
There's been some towns
I think I want to say Jasper,
Missouri,
maybe that's one of those towns that was
literally wiped off the map by
tornadoes.
Tornadoes came in like a gigantic eraser
and you talking about like hundreds of
yards wide and just destroyed
everything.
Just clean the entire top off.
Killed everyone that was there and just
through the building through.
There was nothing left.
Annihilated the whole town.
There's a before and after.
Photo might not be Jasper.
I forget what the name of this town.
Oklahoma,
Kansas City.
It sounds about right.
It's all in that same area.
There's definitely in misery though.
Why am I saying Jasper,
Missouri?
I don't know.
I'm going to be right.
Jasper,
wherever the fuck it was that this
happened.
Whatever this town was.
Um,
I had no idea.
I thought they would come down and just
fuck up a few houses.
I never knew.
They occasionally killed the whole town.
Twister was on at the hotel the other
day.
Remember that movie?
It does not hold up.
It was pretty entertaining.
The very high.
I'll tell you this,
there was one part which I noticed in
which I'm like,
go fuck yourself.
There was a,
there was a member of the part where
Helen Hunt gets out when all the balls
drop out of the machine.
She's like,
no,
go ahead.
I'm going to put the balls back in like
an f five tornado right next to the
student.
Embarrassing.
There are parts in old movies that just
wreck it.
All.
That one scene is so unbelievable now.
For some reason that it ruins the whole
entire movie.
Yeah.
No,
it wasn't Jasper.
Yeah,
it was.
Uh,
Yeah,
it was an f category five hurricane.
Those,
that fives or the ones catastrophic
damage.
Yeah.
I was so obsessed with a and afraid.
I was definitely afraid of tornadoes
when I was a kid.
There was a whole period for a few years
where it's Joplin,
Joplin,
Missouri.
That's where I fucked up.
But look,
that's the town.
Whoa.
Not Jasper.
Joplin.
If you look at it is nothing.
It is annihilated.
It's fucking crazy.
And that was an f five that was like as
high as it gets.
Right?
Is that as high as it gets?
Two point $2,000,000,000
in damage.
Holy Shit.
Two point $2,000,000,000
in damage.
That is insane.
GC,
that house for sale in Los Angeles is
like the most expensive house in ever
worried was the one in Bel Air.
That's like $500 dollars.
And it comes with a helicopter and a
car.
A classic car collection.
I don't know if it does.
I promise it.
Really?
Yeah.
No,
Jamie.
Jamie could tell you.
It comes with a helicopter,
a real house though.
Look at this house because it's got all
the things that are a house,
but it's not made for people to live in.
It's like a party place.
So it's for someone who doesn't want
to live here for the one weekend.
I mean,
how many bathrooms does it have as many
six bathrooms and wanting to do the
town.
Some bitches like God.
Isn't it weird that a car survive but
not the whole town credit for those that
either can't see the image of Joplin.
It looks like the inside of old.
A pencil sharpeners.
I mean it's just insane.
This house comes with a $30 million
dollar car collection to $30,000,000
car collection.
A bargain.
So then what's that?
Number four.
It doesn't make any sense.
They're saying like how much for a week
and it also comes with seven full time
staffers to help tend the two mass own
them.
I own this stuff.
I can fuck yes or no.
I can fuck this stuff.
Good stuff.
I can fuck.
Yeah,
there's definitely you to have some
hookers.
What's the airbnb on this place for the
night?
I left too much for you.
Comes with all the pussy you want.
Tony spent the rest of his money on one
night,
one night.
The AIRBNB,
airbnb.
Because there's dudes out there that are
balling so hard.
We don't know about it.
You know,
there's some royal family members that
are worth trillions of dollars.
Did you know that when you hear about
like the richest man in the world,
you are,
wow,
what's it like to have $90,
million?
That's not the richest band in the
world.
It's not the richest man in the world is
a guy that you don't even know those oil
dudes like those dudes in,
in Saudi Arabia and the Middle East
that,
you know,
oligarchs,
he's,
they have monarchies.
They have these fucking gigantic piles
of wealth that you can't even wrap your
brain around.
Trillions,
trillions,
thousands of billions
really have you.
You know this?
Oh this,
yes.
Thousands of billions.
Do you know,
started the salt.
No.
Dubai Sultan of Brunei rather.
No soul,
no Bernai.
Um,
he would bring in gals and pay them like
$50,000
a month,
just come on down and they would go for
a few months,
make quarter million bucks,
then fly home and you'd get all this
jewelry and diamonds and shit.
And one little hook ruined the whole
Party.
But she was the quarter with a laptop
straightened stories about it.
She wanted to write a book about her
experience.
So this dude,
this is what he would do.
He had a disco in his house and one of
his many houses and uh,
he would have it filled with all these
girls are making who knows how much
money,
just tens of thousands of dollars and he
would come out and he's fucking gold
underwear and just in slippers.
And you slide across the room.
Like he was in that scene with Tom
Cruise.
What's that movie?
Risky business play slides in slide in
like that as gold underwear.
And just go eeny meeny,
miny,
moe,
and just pick one out and just fuck the
out of own.
And then the next day do the same thing.
And He'd do whatever he wants.
And that chick wrote the story on it,
one of them did and there was like,
so what
I'm going back on this is that had
known.
That's really him.
Pack Reagan.
Meanie miny.
Mo.
That guy's totally covered in gold.
Look aT him.
That guy's worth more money than you can
I.
Can I be one of these girls?
I'm like,
go away for 50,000.
I'm doing a gig in dubai guys for a
whole month.
You just want to be the court jester.
Go over there and crack some jokes,
man.
That's fucking crazy.
You think he wears a condom?
No,
no condom.
Shut up.
You want to do that?
Yeah,
exactly.
He's just shooting loads of these gals.
But
then again,
he's opening himseLf up for possible
does.
I wonder if they.
I bet he gets them tested.
It puts them in catapults and shoots him
in the air.
What does that giant throne looking at
his throne?
Oh my god.
That's insane.
Look at them.
Sit there and he's covered with this
thing that looks like something that
belongs inside the pyramids.
It looks like a sunglass hut in
glendale.
So everything is gold.
Do do you understand that?
That's real gold,
like everything is gold plated,
everything.
Real gold plated everything.
Everywhere you look,
gold,
gold
goal,
second set cookies,
cake,
cake.
For your birthday,
dude.
That's all from oil money.
Yeah.
They have a different kind of money,
man.
It's a different level of money.
See,
we have this idea that like bill gates
and warren buffet.
Shit,
the fuck outta here.
Those guys are broke.
They're broken.
Comparison to this dude.
You know donald trump's worth
$4,000,000,000.
That fucking guy is laughing.
if you gave him only $4,000,000,000,
he would start crying if he found out
all he has left is $4,000,000,000.
If you go what?
What would fall to his knees?
How has god cursed me with only
$4,000,000,000?
His plane has that us a vIrtual floor so
you can see what you're flying over.
Of course it does.
Hashtag wow.
Hashtag balling out of control like our
ideas of catastrophic wealth.
We,
we,
we are so sheltered from the true
catastrophic wealth because if we were
really exposed to it and we really
understood it and then we understood
where it came from,
we'd understand what the fuck is going
on in the world and how bizarre the
system of government we have that
supports this and allows this kind of
shit to happen.
Let me ask you a question.
Please do.
You're hanging out one day,
all of a sudden your phone rings,
right?
You're sItting there cutting up some elk
and some jalapenos and you're slicing up
some avocado.
late night your phone rings and all of a
sudden you hear,
hello,
joe does me the salt and I heard the
talk about the podcast and I will fight
you over to a Saudi Arabia.
I'll send the plane.
How many hours do you have?
Really?
Because I heard you have 150 ferrari's.
Ferrari's is.
Yeah,
I might.
He might get mad at me for saying only
150 probably might be a thousand
ferrari's.
Like for real.
He's got one of the most ridiculous car
collections the world's ever known.
How would you go visit him if he sent
the plane for you?
Reported over 300 ferrari's.
300 for come out too.
Drive my ferrari.
We'll do a podcast,
steven outside
too,
but I got a podcast with bill barr.
I can't.
Okay.
Well how many?
300 followers.
She's got over $5,000
cars and three a reported over 300
ferrari's.
He probably bought 300 new ones.
Jay leno just killed himself.
If you listened to jay leno's place is a
fucking riot.
Yeah,
right.
You've never been like if you get a
chance someday and you know like one day
you get to be on jay leno's garage.
If you get a sick car,
get accustomed car,
something like that.
Take it just to go there or next time I
go,
come with me.
You'll free.
It's right in your neighborhood,
man.
Burbank airport.
It's the craziest thing I've ever seen
in my life.
He has 11 buildings,
warehouses filled with cars.
Like I thought it was like a warehouse.
I thought like jay leno's got this cool
collection,
so warehouse filled with cars and no,
it's 11 warehouses and he can just jump
in one and start it and your job where
everyone works,
they have mechanics,
mechanics everywhere.
They take care of everythinG.
The whole thing.
Every.
Every car is functional anD he drives
them all the time,
including like these 19.
Oh,
three tractors.
He put these things.
They have metal wheels.
They didn't have tires,
so he had rubber put on the outside of
the metal so you could drive them on the
street and got them registered.
They're death traps.
There's no way you can stop.
There's no way you can take a corner.
I mean is the most ridiculous thing
you've ever seen the.
Well,
but he drives it.
He tries it all his cars around burbank
all the time.
You always seem like in a firetruck or
like a lollipop.
It's got to be crazy for him.
Seeing seinfeld doing comedians in cars,
getting coffee and he's like,
I really missed an opportunity on that
one.
You he's doing this.
Like what?
He's doing better.
His was,
I want to say it's better,
but his show is really about the car,
whereas seinfeld is like,
the car is just like a set where the
comic,
you know ricky gervais' can pretend that
he's laughing hysterically.
This,
it's a prop,
You know what I mean?
Whereas with jay leno,
like I brought my corvette on,
jay leno show a dude,
that guy fucking loves cars.
I mean he's going over every little inch
of the car.
we're talking about this,
we're talking about that.
You see this glint in his eyes.
He's talking about suspensions and tires
and wheels and you know,
what kind of power steering you're
running and will.
What are you doing for the interior with
the bolsters and the seats of these
stock.
These are.
These are custom where he's coming from.
He does that with every car man.
He fucking loves cars.
So for him it's not even about being
funny.
He doesn't give a shit of a whole show.
Goes by way.
It doesn't crack a single joke.
He'll just talk about I now I've seen
him host the tonight show,
sort of a bitch.
You son of a bitch that was more of a
letter man Guy.
He's way better doing this than anything
he's ever done.
That's great.
And he and I had a conversation about
it,
you know,
and he,
he was like really honest about it.
He talks about it on my podcast too.
He's like,
you know,
I used to have these people on and I
didn't give a fuck about what they were
doing.
I didn't know the band,
you know,
he's like,
fuck,
I'm 57 years old and I know this band,
this band.
He's like,
I didn't care,
but it does the job.
The job was to be friendly,
have this people out.
He goes,
now he goes on talking about what I
love.
These are these cars.
He loves cars,
man.
You bring that guy a car and you know,
it's especially like a hot rod or
something like that.
He just gets to spark in his iron man.
He just walks around them.
He just has a d almost as much as he has
a love for comedy.
I don't know if they're the same level,
but it's like right above my love cars
more.
He really did.
He might love cars more.
Do you think he should dye his hair
black?
Fuck dude.
He's wearing jeans.
ShirTs.
he's worth $100,000,000
for like a hook as fuck.
He's got like 11 cars that are worth
more than a million dollars.
Man.
They're all over the place and it is
fucking garages.
It's crazy.
It's got these old lamborghinis and
shit.
These old ferrari's.
You looked at him like what?
He's got a car with a jet engine.
Wow.
And is it true?
Like what about the day here is that he
doesn't,
doesn't spend his tonight show many
accolades.
It's all from standup doing corporate
gigs.
Oh my god.
It's all corporate gigs.
You got to think a guy like that guy on
the coast,
the tonight show,
if you do a corporate gig,
you can make a ton of money.
Like I don't think people understand.
He's probably making hundreds of
thousands of dollars a gig.
They're flying them out there on a
private jet.
He does the gig that comes back and does
the tonight show,
so he would leave the tonight,
show,
the tonight show tapes during the
daytime.
He'd be done.
He'd fly somewhere on his private jet,
do some ridiculous corporate gig,
make hundreds of thousands of dollars
in,
fly right back,
and then do it again and do it again and
do it again,
and he's making millions of dollars a
month doing that.
Burbank airport balling shade leno's
man.
When I had him on my podcast,
he swore he was telling crazy stories
about when he worked with the mafia and
mafia.
People were threatening guys.
Life.
These monsters.
Yeah.
Was hilarious.
Hanging out with the salton and I don't
think so.
He never never put the slippers on the
golden underwear.
I want to figure out how to make friends
with this guy.
I want to ride around in a gold car.
Yeah.
You don't want to be friends with
somebody that's that powerful because if
you fuck up or you do something wrong,
then you have somebody that powerful.
It gets your enemy.
I,
there's this guy named ikea or whatever
his name is.
Jay owns this,
whatever this thing,
and I got scared.
You might want to say as the name before
any other description talked about it on
joe rogan before.
Remember we used to do a with him.
Remember that really rich guy that had
that.
Oh he mentioned it,
but it was scary because after a while
you're like,
you don't want somebody that's wants to,
is going to troll you for life.
That is that powerful and rich and
that's what it felt like with this guy.
Like,
oh,
if I get on his side where I become like
a,
a baba booey or some kind of howard
stern guy and he could just like fuck
with me for the rest of my life.
Kind of like what they're doing upstairs
at the dingdong share right now with
perry there.
They're saying that don's dead right now
and they're fucking is dead though.
Sure.
What barriers you fuck the whole thing.
He doesn't know internet.
Seeing the live stream right now.
Well listen dude,
you wouldn't be that guy.
You're not that fucked up.
But you know what I mean though,
I don't necessarily know what you mean,
but I do know what you mean.
I just don't think you're describing it
in the best way.
But yeah,
I don't make an enemy out of a crazy
rich dude.
Like powerful.
Yeah.
They're almost scary to even know.
Got it.
I wonder what else is sultans do for fun
though?
You kNow what I mean?
I'd love to know what that is like.
I get like,
I mean,
I'm just saying if he fucks on that
level of eeny meeny,
miny moe,
than what else is he doing for fun on
that level that we can't imagine because
that's how he fucked.
So how does he eat?
You know what I mean?
Like imagine what he must walk into.
Well,
you know,
if his palace,
if everything really is gold like that,
his,
his meals must be fucking spective.
Must be wild.
And
couple chairs.
I bet.
I bet he's got boar and elk just stacked
to the ceiling.
I wonder what they eat.
Oh yeah.
Who knows?
Lobsters.
Anything they want,
you know,
I get it.
I bet it's one of those things where he
probably has food shipped damn everyday,
so he gets to choose what he wants and
it's always fresh and they just get rid
of what he does.
Neat.
I bet it'S one of those deals because I
bet when when you have that kind of
money,
you would probably want to have like a
full menu where you could pick from
whatever you want.
Even if it was just You eating alone.
He's probably one of those guys so they
have to fly in fish and lobster and
it's probably a vegan.
It's probably like vegan.
I don't know.
He just seems like you'd be vegan.
Why would you think that a guy who fucks
all those girls and lives in a gold pals
vegan?
Because you think you'd be like,
oh,
the library because he can afford it.
Most people can't afford healthy
lifestyle.
Healthy lifestyle.
Yeah.
It's expensive to be vegan.
They keep this guy pretty low key
though.
Huh?
Um,
well he keeps himself low keY,
particularly now after that whole thing
with that girl writing that article or
the book or whatever the fuck she was
trying to write after tom,
don,
they have a three day,
I don't know if you were to call it a
festival or something,
but they allow,
it says 30,000
locals and visitors arrive each day to
banquet at the royal family's palace.
Wow.
Fees for the locals I suppose after
ramadan.
So
he's muslim.
So he probably eats things that are.
Hello.
So he,
he probably eats a lot of meeting
whenever the fuck he wants.
They have restrictions.
So I don't think he's allowed to eat
pork.
So he's probably not eating bore.
See they,
they came up with all that stuff though.
Back when people are getting diseases,
man,
you know,
pigs,
they eat whatever the fuck they want,
lead,
eat everything including each other.
So they probably came up with that stuff
like those religious rules about pork in
particular.
That's almost definitely related to
disease and illness.
You know,
it doesn't make sense.
Jews and muslims all have that in their,
in their religion that you're not
supposed to be eating pork.
What do you think about this?
Like trump taking the ta or the us
government to Israel?
Have you heard about that?
But uh,
um,
you know,
when other con,
when you have like bases in other
countries,
he's going to put a base in Israel.
So I would just say.
And that's something that presidents
have been scared to do for a long time
and he's at palestine's like pissed.
Is that true?
Jamie just said at the end of the,
at the end of the feast,
everyone gets a cake,
but he also inserted a clause into the
constitution that proclaims quote,
he can do no wrong and either as
personal or any official capacity
that's in this constitution gave them a
cake man.
What the fuck do you want?
He can do no wrong.
So you can do whatever he wants.
So he has a clause in their constitution
that he could do whatever he wants.
What does it say?
Coming to our constitution,
trump's plan to move the us embassy to
jerusalem?
Truthfully,
I can't even talk to you.
Ruzzio.
Welcome to read.
Are you drunk?
Got drunk.
You brian now struggling with the words
jersey tourism?
Yeah,
I mean that's just,
it's a weird word though.
Jerusalem.
The um.
I can't even say it.
They used to have some crazy ass words.
Mesopotamia.
Yeah.
Jerusalem is a jerusalem.
That's where I stop and think about
that.
Like,
how about czechoslovakia?
Why do you have to use so many noises in
Poland?
Polish areas.
But why?
Why?
Um,
welcome to the wealth and the wet.
Whoa.
Whoa,
whoa.
Slow down.
Why did you name your,
your place that this is your spot.
The noise I make for my spot.
I mean think of what they think.
We don't know what lithium Lithuania
means,
but thing of what they hear when we go
the,
the United States of America though,
like they're probably like listening.
Well they need to talk to me and I'll
just go.
Marika marika way from America,
from czechoslovakia and your name sounds
funny.
How come your name so long?
How come y'all decided to put all those
fucking sounds in your name?
Greedy ass sound user sucking up,
all of a sudden attributed it to your
patch of dirt.
Huh?
How big is this?
Czechoslovakia?
That's it.
That little tiny ass thing with that big
old fucking name as the problem and a
lot of them are real little.
How big struggles avaya.
Is that a big spot?
Maybe that's what it means.
Maybe they're trying to overcompensate
for hockey.
A big spot.
Am I talking shit now?
It's little.
It seems like it would be little.
Yeah.
Gimme a the dumbest name of a country
that you know.
Algeria.
Why?
Because it's just.
They didn't know that name before they
came up with that name didn't exist
because is stan.
Oh,
right.
Antartica.
that's kind of a goofy one.
But it sounds pretty because it's not a
lot of z's in it,
you know,
throwing a lot of zs.
You know it's supposed to be from
kazakHstan.
They get super mad at him,
you know,
they sued them.
That whole fucking good.
They are so pissed.
I bet that guy has to hide those
Kazakhstan people are so fucking pissed
because the character he's time.
Could you imagine if there's was one guy
who was doing this character of your
tiny little country and it is a fucking
huge smash comedy hit this complete
recharge is representing your country
and just fucking up everything.
You know.
Remember when he did that movie and I
asked him where to go to the bathroom
and he took a shit in a bag.
They handed the lady the bag trying to
get.
I go there,
I do it this.
and she's like,
well,
what's that?
This is my shit.
Boy.
Do you see as new one that I heard it
was a scene in it that's really worth
the whole movie.
Which one is his new one?
Uh,
the one where he's like a tennis player
or something like that.
Like a problem with those is those are
comedies.
They're not like little what I like and
the stuff that's illegal now,
right?
Yeah.
so the stuff that he used to do it,
he kept getting sued for.
That's the best shit jackass was on the
other night on the front porch after the
roast battle and just watching jackass.
I missed that.
That there's something to that.
So funny that just seeing people getting
fucked up,
it's one of the
funniest thing.
So it's just undeniaBly funny.
It's unbelievable.
Well,
yeah,
it's instinctual.
It's like in your,
in your system.
Like there's,
I remember I'll never forget this one
where they,
they,
they uh,
had this big hand on a spring that would
give guys high fives and it would come
out of nowhere just fucking nail you and
send you fly it across the room and had
bags of flour on it.
So like when it hit the flat face and
blow you up with flour and it was
fucking huge.
Like it would knock people over.
Yeah.
They're all amazing.
I love jack ass so fucking much.
And I stumbled across jackass two point
five recently,
which is basically all the footage that
they didn't get a chance to use or that
was too edgy or came out to extreme for
their show wild boys because it turns
out that they had to like have it ready
for mtv.
It was just different than that shit.
They were really pulling at this level.
So anything in which the network heads
were like,
we can't air that on mtv two or whatever
the fuck wild boys was on.
They just turned it into this super
movie of shit that was literally too
fucking good for mtv and the show wild
boys at the time.
So what's it called and why?
It's a jackass.
Two point five.
And so these guys and remember the dorm
wild boys,
which is more like,
you know,
like they're out in the safaris and the
desert.
It's like with cheetah and everything.
Yeah,
they were playing.
Keep away with hyenas,
with a ham and some of them fucking
scary.
That is no,
I mean I hyenas will cure you.
There's huge 200 pound wild dogs that
crush bones with their teeth and they're
playing.
Keep away with them wild I anus with a
ham.
They're standing right in front of them
with no fence,
no protection.
Those guys are fucking hilarious.
The other thIng about jack as two point
five is they're the ones that were also
like you could tell a couple of them
were just so disgusting that they could
input it on mtv.
Like my favorite fucking one and it just
like I was dying of laughter.
I've been,
I have is howling like,
like an animal all of a sudden,
you know,
and there's sort of like explaining
like,
you know,
we didn't know what we,
we met this one guy who was the world's
longest fingernails.
We dIdn't know what we were going to do
with them.
And another cool thing about two point
five is it's sorta like more documentary
style because they're like laughing
about all this footage from India.
He has these crazy crew,
super duper long fingernails and they're
like,
we didn't end up knowing what to do with
this guy.
So you know,
steve,
I had this one idea and then that was
it.
And all of a sudden it cuts to this
indian guy,
you know,
you've seen them.
Like they,
they just giant long fingernails,
like five feet long or whatever the
fuck.
And all of a sudden you just see an
indian guy's face and it slowly starts
to pan out.
You see as naIls.
And he has a bottle of miller lite and
he just goes,
hello,
I am blah blah blah blah.
This is miller time.
And you see them just start to pour the
beer on the back of his hand that's just
hanging there and back of his hand that
has the fingernails and all the beer
starts rolling down his fingernails and
the,
as the camera pans out,
you just start to hear like,
you just start to hear that noise.
And as it pans out,
you see steve was laying on his back,
on the ground underneath them and all
that.
Miller beer.
He's rolling down the fingernails.
Water slide.
I was screaming.
I was screaming by myself in my
apartment watching this dying of
laughter.
There it is.
Jamie's got it this time.
But you.
But you hear steve.
Okay.
Gagging before the camera.
You've been so fucking funny.
He's gagging and throwing up so much he
throws up.
Oh,
it's about to get great.
Right?
These indian.
So oh my god.
Oh my god.
look at the pile of vomit in front of
them.
It's cute.
That's the worst.
Steevo is crazy.
So interesting.
Seeing him sober now.
He's a fun guy.
I really liked that guy a lot.
He knew who was not sober.
Andy dick the other day told you in
hell.
It was the most uncomfortable thing.
They let andy and if he was drinking and
I don't know.
You know what man?
I knew that was gonna happen,
but he stole david's beer.
He heckled them the times.
Still three beers stole my last call,
last call and I got to tread noise given
impact and aggressive.
Listen man.
That's Why I didn't have mine again.
I just telling you like,
this is not gonna.
It's not gonna last.
It's not temp.
It's just temporary.
The sobriety thing.
Working on sobriety.
He's a slingshot and he pulled that
slingshot back and then he's eventually
got to let it go and I don't know why.
I don't know.
I don't understand sobriety.
I don't understand people that go off
the rails like he does where they get
that fucked up and that crazy,
but he's got it.
Whatever that is.
You worked with them all the way back.
Fuck him.
And I worked with him for five years and
was always that way.
Always that way.
Party machine.
okay.
A lot of it is,
I really honestly believe this.
And maybe andy would probably agree with
me.
I think some shit happened to him when
he was a child,
you know,
and I think um,
he,
he battles that,
you know,
and I think he has like a real issue
man.
And he,
he,
he's talked about it before.
I'm not revealing anything that he
hasn't said already,
but he doesn't remember like a lot of
his childhood or a lot of it.
It's blocked it out and he's got a
substance problem he just had,
he has it more than anybody I've ever
met in terms of like he gets it and then
that switch goes off and he's gone.
He's off to the races and he's a sweet
guy and he's a fucking talented guy.
He's a really funny guy.
Like andy and I,
we did scenes together.
Well we had to do three,
four and five takes because I couldn't
stop laughing.
I was holding it in as much as I can.
He's a really funny guy.
It's shit faced to end as a negative and
annoying as he was the other night.
He was still sort of killing it through
this glaze of just annoyance.
I mean,
of course,
of course.
It was like he was just the scottie
pippin is chappelle's Jordan because he
was literally heckling chappelle while
he's on status.
That's fucked up,
david again,
you know,
they should have kicked him out.
Yeah,
they totally shut of you can't do that.
you can't do that.
And then he tried to fuck our friend.
The first five times I met andy,
he was completely shit faced and
obsessed with trying to fuck me and that
was,
I'm like,
okay,
nice to meet you again.
And,
and that was that.
And then the last few times he was sober
and fucking awesome.
Really great guy.
And then I saw them for the first time
since that the other night.
And he's sitting in a chair right in
back bar area,
like where the employees are.
He's the only one just sitting there in
a chair and I'm like,
oh,
I wonder what happened to annie as I'm
walking up all in one motion is I get
closer.
I see that at the same time he's licking
somebodies arm that he's with just
licking their arm up and down and I'm
like,
oh no,
he's not sober anymore.
Like his variation of sobriety and not
sober.
I've never seen him like getting drunk
or having a drink.
I've only seen him on her.
Absolutely.
At a thousand miles an hour.
Shit faced and aggressively sexual
continuously or very nice dude.
Yeah,
it's so weird.
I think he's a nice dude.
These are nice too.
I think he really is a good guy.
I think andy's a very good guy.
He's just a very good guy that does not
get along with substances and he needs
them for whatever reason.
He,
they,
he was drawn to them,
you know,
and I don't,
I don't know what you do to cure someone
of that.
I don't.
And I think,
you know,
I wouldn't even if I knew what to cure
one person,
I don't think I,
I think everybody has their own
individual answer for that.
And I think for some people they just
don't want to ever get completely free
or they do and then they don't,
you know,
they get bored or they can't take it
anymore or whatever the fuck it is.
But,
but isn't it weird that when somebody
does start drinking,
like it's never just like a little bit.
It's never like,
oh,
you know,
I started drinking.
I shouldn't be drinking.
I have a little.
But it's just like opposite.
Yeah.
It's um,
it's a genetic thing too,
man.
There's something about that alcohol.
They either got that thing or you don't
know.
Like if they,
like I'm sitting here,
I've only had waters nine and I'm
looking at your,
your drinking.
You know,
I've had drinks but I'm not like going
to fucking drink and drink.
But some people they look at that
goddamn drink and they just,
they just feel it.
You smell,
you smell it.
Smell that whiskey in there.
And you just go,
fuck,
fuck.
He just starts pulling at you and then
you want it and then you just say,
fuck it.
Let's just.
One shot,
just one shot,
boom.
And they throw it down.
Yeah.
Wow.
Off to the races.
Tate says that's him.
Yeah,
that's,
I mean,
you could tell anyone that stopped
drinking.
I started drinking red bull or starbucks
all day.
I'm like,
the strongest coffee I just had in uh,
in san francisco.
I had a starbucks.
Has this new nitro,
a coffee.
It's like having them pull up,
pour you a pint.
It is.
It's amazing to.
Companies are making that announce
nitrogenated coffee.
It's amazing.
And they had half of a grand day and I
was like,
oh my god,
I feel like I'm on drugs.
Like we have those cave man once.
Caveman coffee,
they're small.
They're tiny and they have 270
milligrams caffeine.
Is that?
Yeah.
SO a lot way more than a venti starbucks
drinks five,
six of those at a time because he
doesn't drink fucking 200 years.
Fifty pounds,
you know?
So it's Got more room to distribute over
his body.
Yeah.
He geTs fucking wired on those goddamn
things.
Get super excited about.
I love caffeine.
So much of all the things you can be
addicted to that one is the most
productive and the least destructive.
It doesn't,
doesn't,
doesn't fuck you up to the point where
you make shit decisions or get in car
accidents or anything.
I think I've done so much caffeine.
I don't feeL like I feel it.
Like I like I'll have coffee,
don't as much.
It seems something youtube with
caffeine.
Well that's why people who use it for
performance enhancing purposes,
they like to not use caffeine during the
day normally and then take caffeine
before they work out.
Like say if they have wrestling match or
something like that.
A lot of guyS will do that.
They'll have no caffeine in their diet
and then right before they go and fight
or something like that,
they'll take a caffeine pill and then
they get the full effects of it because
of the fact that you're not like.
Like how often we smoked pot,
if we got anybody that doesn't smoke pot
down here with us and we were hitting
the same way that we're hitting,
they would freak out.
We've seen it.
You've seen it all.
We've seen it before.
I mean how many times we've gotten
somebody high like,
do you get high?
And they'll like,
well I'll try it.
What the hell?
Like,
okay.
They take a big hit and they take a
second hit and like your god
for buddy.
I thought he was dying for a second
after smoking kelly weed for the first
time.
He started shaking and like he literally
sort of like just,
he looked like he was getting
electrocuted for.
We've done that to people so many times.
You know,
like you want end come on in,
but it's just way too strong for that.
For us it's nothing.
We do it all the time.
So it's normal and your body builds up
this tolerance,
but if you don't have that tolerance,
you get hit with it.
And that's what I'm.
Terence mckenna used to say that's the
best way to smoke weed.
He just say the best way to do it is to
don't do it at all for a long time and
then do as much as you can stand.
Yeah.
Like then it becomes,
well very,
very psychedelic and he would hit.
his thought was that we abused marijuana
and he was guilty of it himself.
He said it's one of the things we were
talking about.
He's like,
listen,
before you listen to this,
like I am a confessed cannabis addict.
He goes,
I small cannabis every day,
all day.
I smoke it at night,
but honestly I think the way to do it is
to take a long time off and then smoke
your fucking brains out.
Just take like weeks off.
Just get,
bring you,
bring your body completely back to
baseline.
And then just two days
often it feels like if I smoke it,
it's back to baseline.
Like that fast.
I don't want two days off.
How often you guys go on stage without
it?
I tried it most of the term.
Do you struggle talking when you go
onstage?
I,
uh,
yeah.
I,
uh,
I stutter or I lose my train of thought,
like if I'm going to like,
oh,
I didn't go to the app that bit now.
Then I'll like,
forget it.
I'm like,
wait,
what?
I,
I say just thinking it's memory for most
of me.
I think like,
especially with like pizza,
we'd,
I find that if I don't smoke weed,
I actually remember everything I did
that night.
But I do smoke
pete,
we'd,
I don't remember anything I did that
night and I used to always think it was
alcohol based,
but I,
I've been trying and experimenting the
Same way.
I remember everything.
I,
I smoke a lot of weeds,
weeds,
and it just blocks my memory.
Men in black kush.
The memory eraser.
Yeah.
Well it definitely has a different
effect on everybody,
man.
There's no doubt about that because
you'll,
you'll hear some people talk about pot
and you're like,
what are you experiencing?
I almost want to be in your body.
I roasted snoop dogg a few weeks ago,
maybe like a little over a montH ago and
hanging out with him.
It was.
I've hunG out with them a few times,
but this time it was after I roasted a
man.
I had hung out with them the day before
because we were talking about the roast
and I was helping him with his thing at
the end and everything,
you know what I mean?
So we were smoking then and then after
the roast and I lit his eye,
lit snoop up at this.
I made fun of everyone.
It waS really crazy,
like one of the most fun things I've
ever done on stage.
Anyway.
Afterwards we were kicking it like hard
fucking core,
right?
Because I had just like honored,
honored the shit out of them basically
in front of all of his friends and this
big cool theater in la.
So you know,
we were hanging out all this stuff and
it ever since then he inspired me to
smoke more weed.
Not by saying anything,
but just sort of like watching them
operate anD just realizing like wow,
this guy just stays laughing anD
creative all the time because it never
shuts off for them.
Every time I've ever been around him,
he's always just riff in and always the
funny by far,
the funniest comedian I've ever met or
worked with by far.
You ever hang out with snoop?
No.
Never meT him.
You would fucking love him.
You guys would click.
You guys were crossing the streams would
be unbelievable because he's,
he gets it,
man.
He's cool as fuck him.
And Martha Stewart is the best
combination in the room.
Don't they have on your show?
Yeah.
Together.
Cooking show together.
What is it best combo?
Um,
they just have a killer cooking show
together.
And is it on tv?
Yeah.
That's one of the regular.
A regular show.
And you know who you know,
who does it?
Oh,
chris mcguire.
No shit.
Yeah.
Really one of the roast jokes that I
didn't snoop was he,
that he has a cooking show with martha
and when asked what it's like to work
with a 75 year old lady,
martha said not that bad.
Ah,
it's amazing though,
like I've seen the clip of like I just
put it up on youtube a couple of days
ago and uh,
already tweeted about it and,
but ever since watching it have actually
having the clip and getting,
when it cuts back every time it cuts
back to snoop laughing.
I still like my brain is like I can't
fuck.
I still can't believe that it happened
like that,
that snoop laughing.
Right,
right.
That you actually did rose.
It's so fucking weird.
Wow.
But anyway,
I've doubled my pot intake since this
snoop thing and I was already,
you know,
a very regular daily,
pretty much,
you know,
once I get the bulk of work done in the
afternoon,
if it's,
whether I'm writing or just,
you know,
whatever I have to do or book or
whatever responsibilities I have,
it's on,
you know,
until I'm a fan.
Yeah.
And then I woRk out a few hours later
and then I do it again.
I just keep smoking throughout the
night.
Okay,
good for you.
It works.
I approve this message.
It works for me.
Yeah.
Why not man?
As long as it works.
And if you decide at one point that it
doesn't work anymore and you want to
switch it up,
I mean sometimes that happens too in
your life.
You get tired of a certain pattern.
Yeah.
You know,
it might be a different kind of workout
you're doing or whatever it is,
but just changing things a little bit,
changing certain aspects of your life.
Just a little bit,
just a little bit of a turn,
a little deviation,
something new,
little something different.
It can be huge,
huge for your brain,
you know,
start thinking of things different.
I madE,
I emptied my house out recently,
just decided to pack everything up.
I got a storage unit and I put
everything in the storage unit.
It's weird though.
We were talking at kill tony,
about how people lived in their cars.
I didn't know that there's a whole thing
of homeless people that have storage
units and they used the storage unit to
bathe in and they just hang out there
all day then.
Thank god there's a shadow warehouse
storage june.
No,
no,
no.
They'll just come there with like wet
naps and like we,
like they were showing me my unit when I
got it,
me and jan and she goes,
oh we can't go down this hallway.
And I'm like,
why?
She goes,
just hold your nose.
We can't go down this hallway.
And I and I look ahead and there was a
woman naked like washing herself and
poop rags everywhere.
Just rags on the ground with poop on it
everywhere.
And it smelled like poop.
And she said that she just lives there
during the day.
That's like how she shits on the ground.
They let her,
she can't throw her out.
There's nothing they can do.
You can't like get her for like some
sort of a health code sitting on the
ground.
That's what I said.
And she goes,
you would think you would think it's
very weird and touchy and it's funny how
much people like try to protect people.
Like if she had a house you could arrest
her for that.
Like if she had a house and she just
wants to shit in public.
I like to go to my storage unit and take
shits on the floor.
People would say,
you fucking dirty bitch like you to go
to jail,
but because she doesn't have a house and
she goes there and shits on the floor
like,
oh,
we can't do anything.
It.
It's also the location.
There's this California culture where
that we nurture people,
but like if that was in Texas and some
storage unit owner walked by,
you better pick up and put your.
When you put your pooper exit way,
you get it up and you get out of here.
Right now I just got to say that is so
much better than your japanese mexican
accent.
You have a two days to pack up and get
up to the storage unit,
back up and get down to theater.
This is Texas.
Nothing's like san francisco.
San francisco is the worst when it comes
to that.
There's fucking aggressive homeless
people everywhere.
Somebody took all.
Somebody took
a huge shit human shit right in front of
the punchline comedy club.
It was.
I didn't know it did because I filmed
it.
I periscoped two videos of it and in I
can just save any photos.
I can see right now.
Video is on photos and video.
I got video of me so it's hard to see in
the video,
but it was,
but it made me puke.
Okay.
A little towel next to it.
Yeah,
man.
I've never seen more homeless people
just wandering around anywhere in any
one location that I have in san
francisco.
It seems like they're just super
tolerant up there.
It's one of the things that make san
francisco awesome is that open
mindedness and tolerance,
but
we were there.
It also leaves an opening for that.
We were there on saturday when they were
doing the marches up there.
Oh,
it was a good times.
It was powerful.
Drained the.
Well,
the kill tony show was amazing,
but the to standup shows I had after
that you could tell and I.
By the second show I was asking like how
many you went to the march earlier and
it was just like.
I mean,
wow.
Raised.
Have you ever even heard,
have an elected leader that's been
protested this hard right after they got
an office before they've done anything?
Now
the funny thing is there was a bunch of
women out there obviously that voted for
trump or didn't vote at all.
That's what the,
a lot of the numbers would say because
they said that most women voted for
trump.
Right?
Isn't that a style?
No.
Okay.
Most of the women that voted voted for
trump,
correct?
Well,
no,
no.
I thought I heard.
No,
no,
no more women voted For trump than voted
for hillary.
But not most of the women voted for
trump.
So if like there's a hundred and three
women,
53 of them voted for trump,
50 of them voted for hillary.
Really fat kind of a deal.
but when you're talking about the
numbers that they had,
like an la whitney coming sent me this
picture and uh,
I looked at,
I wonder what in the fuck,
where is that?
She goes,
that's in downtown la.
I'm like,
that is insane.
That's insane.
I go,
how many people are there?
She goes,
they expected 80,000
and they got 900,000
is the biggest one.
Even bigger than dc.
Yeah.
She said they,
they don't even really.
They don't really know how many,
but she says they think somewhere around
I think 970,000
people close to a million credible.
Crazy.
And it was interesting how many older
ladies and older women didn't like.
I flew back and the woman next to me was
an old lady that sprayed her hair blue
and she's like,
well you got up to protest.
I think this all came from the grab the
pussy stuff.
Like if he didn't have the grab them by
the pussy stuff.
This wouldn't exist.
Right.
It's because of one clip that they dug
up from the early nineties in between a
commercial break with him on inside
edition with some guy talking about who
knows the context that was happening
before that before
and his,
his,
his whole.
If You him talk
his whole persona like shona.
Yeah.
And he's Talking about your son is the
mexican word for it.
you may know him.
He's from jerusalem.
It's very,
very good
guy.
Jockey like he is buying is very
negative for women.
Yeah.
He's a good old boys' club guy.
it's awful too for me to.
I don't.
Why is it awful for you?
I just don't like it.
I just don't like hearing him talk,
man.
He's just such a to me.
Like I don't like them.
Who kid though?
No,
I voted for weed,
but I didn't vote for trump or didn't
vote for president.
you got to that and you just left it out
now because I didn't like either.
I wouldn't have had a,
you know,
old man mickey.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Did you vote for Gary Johnson?
Did my podcast.
I voted for him.
He seems like a throwaway.
I'd really rather not vote and that
brian,
it's never a throwaway.
If everybody voted for Gary Johnson,
he would won.
Yeah,
but that wasn't gonna happen.
Well why not?
Because it's never a throwaway.
It's like you have to vote your mind.
Otherwise voting is pointless regardless
of whether or not you think you're
throwing your vote away.
Like,
there's so many people that were saying
that the reason why,
you know,
my,
my state was going to go to hillary
clinton already.
So I already knew that,
right?
Most people predicted that if I stepped
in as a complete objective observer,
I had never had anything to do with the
system up until that point.
And then I walked in and they were
telling me the projected victory was
already to hillary clinton before it
even started right in this state.
And they were right and they were right
in New York.
Right.
So if I vote for Gary Johnson,
stopped throwing shit away,
it's just voting my conscience and it's
not even really my conscience honestly,
because maybe gary's not the right guy
for the job either.
You know what I mean?
He didn't know what aleppo waS,
but,
you know,
but bernie sanders isn't enough anymore
and I'm not a big fan of hillary and uh,
um,
I don't think.
I'm not a big fan of trump.
I'm not a big fan of any.
I'm not a big fan of being president.
How about that?
I don't think anybody should be
president.
Yeah,
I think there's an article that I
tweeted recently that someone tweeted to
me and I retweeted it about having a
council of wise people like seven or
eight people
like star wars.
Was that jim,
this article on fortune.com
says that a 42 percent of women,
most of them white came out to support.
It came out to support trump.
Right.
But we weren't talking about that.
We.
We're talking about the marches against
trump.
I know,
but I mean that's done.
Tony's point is that 42 percent of women
voted for him so that,
that.
You know what I mean?
How many women then were there that
voted for trump?
ProBably none
because there's 20 million people in los
anGeles.
You have 20 million people in los
angeles and you got less than a million.
It's highly likely that,
that less than a million.
I think a lot of secret trump supporters
should are disguising themselves as
these people telling you they're out
there because they have to these.
It's a game to
some of these people.
I can feel it.
What you think the people that are
walking around in that rally actually
voted for trump and they're holding up
signs.
Fuck trump.
You really think that
I.
Yeah,
I think that some of them.
Yeah.
I think that their secret trump
supporters.
Yeah,
aBsolutely.
Marching with signs the whole deal for
their,
what they have to do for whatever their
jobs are or whoever their bosses.
Yeah,
Sure.
Marchelle join yet the march.
Yeah.
Yeah,
sure.
Definitely.
As long as you talk to tom about that
raise or whatever,
you know,
whatever the people do.
But it's crazy at that march.
There's like five year old girls,
you know,
they're there.
I mean these parents are mad about what
the possibility of what of their kids.
Hearing something that trump said and
there's like five year old girls walking
down the street going down,
catch my pussy.
Don't touch me.
Really true.
Do you really see five-year-old st?
Don't judge my.
The march was saying don't touch my
pussy and there's little kids that yOu
were saying that five-year-olds are
saying that probably not fight.
Like here's,
here's my question.
Do you Think that having these gigantic
marches all over the country like they
did,
don't you think that's probably a good
thing because a guy like trump,
the last thing he wants is all those
people hating him.
The last thing he wants is to realize
that there's never been a president ever
in the history of this country that has
gotten protested so widely and so hugely
right after getting into office.
Right.
That's got to freak him out and that has
to affect the way you make decisions.
IT has to.
Knowing that these people like,
oh,
you,
you know,
you just got in,
you haven't done anything.
All you did was when the election again
in,
it almost seems interesting to you
because what if that ends up turning him
into,
you know,
what if the.
I mean there's a chance with it.
He just turns on these people and starts
fulfilling the propheCy.
Right?
It's a weird thing,
but,
but then,
you know,
the republicans that support him that
are on the fence,
they wouldn't support him anymore.
He's a populist and a lot of ways since.
One of the more interesting things about
this,
like he's willing to change his mind on
things.
If the people are really vehemently
against his decisions,
I think it's going to be real weird.
Who knows who the fuck knows what's
going to happen,
but one of the things that I'm reading,
it's really fascinating is that they're
trying to keep him away from television
and criticism because he freaks out and
then they don't want him to overreact.
TheY don't want him to respond to
criticism of him because he keeps making
these fucking crazy tweets.
What's this?
His press secretary or somebody that
just put out a thing the other day that
was talking about the numbers.
How many people were at the at the thing
you know,
he's like a publicist though.
You know what I mean?
Like he's not even a press secretary.
This guy's a publicist.
They have a publicist because of how bad
trump is going to get into
trouble.
He's going to get into like,
that guy is going to be saving his ass a
lot in the future.
I feel my friend Jason Harrison,
he's the guy who owns this company.
That makes sense.
Cool.
You got 10 minutes.
Cotton mouth is that it is one of the.
Shut the fuck up with.
He's one of the best.
Uh,
he makes some of the best,
uh,
hunting gear in the world and he has his
picture on his instagram and this is
disputing what the press is saying when
they were talking about how little the
crowd was.
Look how big the crowd is there.
This is an actual photo that he took
with his actual phone and they were
saying that the,
uh,
the crowd didn't go out to the press
tent.
we'll fucking it clearly.
Does she?
That's a huge crowd.
It could also just be now.
What's that?
It could also just be the photo.
There could be like a brand.
Look at that photo.
That photo shows a gigantic crowd of
people that goes all the way back past
where they said the crowd didn't go.
I,
yeah.
I'm saying that there might be a big gap
in just how the photo is that you can't
see that there's a gap in the middle,
you know,
kind of like this.
The whole thing.
Yeah.
but look what I do.
But look at what you're looking at.
Yeah.
Not in that photo and that photo you are
looking at.
look at all those people all the way
back there.
They go all the way past the barricades
looking at me.
People There are like,
that's not the pictures they showed on
television.
Yeah.
So the.
And you can see these folks show Jason
Harrisonj a s o n a,
m h a I r s t o n.
So this is a photo that he took himself
and that's where it gets weird.
So like someone who was actually there
who went to the inauguration,
they could take a picture of this.
This is photoj
pbs put up.
This is a time lapse from the top of the
Washington monument from the top.
From day,
like the time of day started like
sunrise.
So everyone started leaving it.
Oh,
so they have all of it?
Yeah,
they have sky view of it.
Okay,
so his photo,
does it represent what this is saying?
There's gaps though.
See there's gaps in between.
The crowds was not filled in from that
angle.
It.
It represents a big crowd,
but when you look at it from the top,
you can see like the gaps in the.
But either way,
there's a lot of people there but it
wasn't.
I don't know if it was a million.
Yeah,
but either way it's a giant crowd,
but it's nowhere near as many that went
to see obama,
that that's been proven by the amount of
people that take public transportation.
Right.
So thIs is still not filled in yet and
it's still.
See I.
If you're,
if you're standing,
if there's a bunch of people missing in
the middle,
you're not going to be in the tail
because the people behind it's going to
fill in the gaps.
That does look pretty goddamn packed.
It does,
but maybe that's what you're saying.
Then because of that,
it really in your head,
it's hard to imagine what obama's
must've looked like because that does
look insane,
but he wasn't where we were when obama
was inaugurated.
He wasn't there taking pictures in the
same spot.
Then we would get a chance to really
check to really check it and understand
it,
but I mean that I would buy more than
this because of what you said about
perspective.
Yeah.
I mean there's still a fuck load of
people,
man.
They were making it seem like there
wasn't that many people.
That's a lot of god damn people.
It's just not as many as obama.
I would like to compare that to when
bush was inaugurated,
bush had more.
Bush had more.
Yeah,
it was raining and the trump
inauguration.
That's true.
And how many of those people were hair
spray in respect to Mr.
Trump.
I saw point someone made to that at the
time in 2009.
I guess when obama,
when the inauguration happened,
there are a lot more people out of work.
Oh shit.
and that now there's people that have
jobs and they had less.
There's a white house,
propaganda welfare baby statement.
help sincerely.
Obama tried to find out how many people
were there when bush was inaugurated and
how many people were there when clinton
was inaugurated and there's a good
thousand bushel.
What's that?
Two thousand one.
The first.
First one,
right?
Yeah,
it was 2000.
There was a good photoshop out there.
It shows overall shows,
reptiles.
It shows you their illness shape of a
skull.
Alex jones,
did you hear he was at down there and
somebody,
some trump supporter or something like
that and gotten a huge fight.
And then with alex?
No,
no.
Alex jones.
It was right next to it and had to call
the police.
Oh,
I saw someone was saying that Alex Jones
had liquor on his breath.
He says he doesn't drink $200.
Three hundred thousand or so for 2000.
One for bush,
400,000
in 2005.
And then one point $8 million for Iraq
in 2009 and 1 million in 2013.
In comparison,
bill clinton also had 800,093
and 250,097.
Damn two and only 250,097.
I mean the rain is going to deeply
affect that though,
because it's all local people,
right?
I mean,
who does that?
A lot of people.
Jason harrison fluent for that.
Margaret murphy,
she flew in for that shifts the march.
Yeah,
but she flew in,
you know,
a lot of those.
That's another thing that goes against
that.
A lot of those women that were marching,
they're marching in the rain.
You know,
the one that.
I mean,
that's why jeremiah watkins and his
character.
Daisy watkins.
Yeah.
I like daisy.
I like his character.
Yeah.
That was amazing.
They all had raincoats on during the
roast battle tonight or during the.
I'd rather kill tony tonight.
Represent those hillary supporters that
went out in the rain.
Is it a big deal because of this?
The question of the size or the question
over the lining of the size.
lying of the size of size,
but he doesn't.
He wants to say,
this guy wants to say this is the
largest crowd of any inauguration ever.
Clearly that's not true.
RIght?
That's fucked up.
That's clearly not true.
If it seems like a big ass crowd to me
looking at that photo,
but I've never looked at a photo of the
inauguration before,
so if you compare it to obama,
it's clearly still a big ass crop,
but it's definitely not the biggest
ever,
so
that's not good when the fucking white
house minister of propaganda sounds like
that guy from baghdad.
Remember at the beginning of the war
there was some guy that was doing the
baghdad population thing.
Remember that guy?
Who the fuck was that guy?
who is this more on outside of the door?
They're letting people downstairs just
walk downstairs so they should keep that
door shut.
It's such a bad.
Who was that guy?
Remember that guy joe baghdad or
something like that.
Remember that.
It was like.
It was a meme.
It was hilarious.
Was like when?
When the war started,
get the fuck outta here.
Jamie.
Kick these guys out of here.
God,
jesus christ it latin people.
Fuck with us.
Anyway.
Um,
there was a character that was,
um,
baghdad something.
God dammit.
What was his name?
I can't remember it.
Do you remember that?
And what was he saying?
He was the proper,
the minister of propaganda for Iraq
before we invaded.
And he was always saying like,
you know,
the iraqi troops or destroy any american
that bob.
No,
baghdad.
Bob,
bob and his ridiculous true predictions.
This guy.
Yes.
That's the guy.
Bob.
Yeah.
He was a,
he looks like a bra on it.
Looked like saddam hussein before saddam
hussein went into hiding.
Remember they went into hiding and they
found him in a whole.
Remember they pulled him out [inaudible]
and hung them on tv.
We watched them like everyone could see
him get hung.
Remember?
You saw it on tHe internet is an amazing
fucking crazy.
But this baghdad.
Bob.
That's it.
It is baghdad.
Bob.
Yeah.
Did you watch a that saddam series on
hbo?
No,
but what I'm sayinG is this baghdad bob
guy.
This is essentially what the trump guys
doing.
He's saying shit that everybody knows is
not true.
He's exaggerating in a way that
everybody knows is not true,
and this is just the beginning of the
administration.
His quote is,
my information was correct,
but my interpretations were not.
Remember that.
Who was saying that?
The fact that bob guys quote is,
oh,
but this way house guys should be fired.
Right?
That should be like a blatant firing,
right?
That start off a relationship with the
american people with a big,
fat,
juicy lie like that.
Fired.
What about his speeches to he?
Didn't he say he was?
There was a picture of him handwriting
his speeches and then he's blatantly
ripped off the bain speech and the
avatar speech too.
Speech close.
Did you see it?
The same thing to the people.
That's not a typical political speak.
Everybody that's a typical.
You're right back to you,
to the people.
People turn it into the bain thing.
I'm like,
I hope everybody's about it being
stolen,
like you know,
not plagiarize,
but it's the same thing.
The problem with it being the same
thing,
is this what bain said before he fucking
went to destroy the city,
but you shouldn't say that shared when
everybody knows.
That's what bain said.
That's true.
There's supposed to be a guy much
checkin for bain speak.
No,
but imagine if you were going to say
something
cool to have a president that said
something had been said
that you're ridiculous.
Give it back to you.
You're just that one.
Part of it is like a whole.
It was like a whole two or three
sentences,
not just that phrase.
There is no way that guy has enough time
to write his fucking speech.
You know what?
He took a picture and of course my
fucking.
You should add a quill shit.
I got down feather and an ink bottle.
Clearly trump likes to write his
speeches while watching batman.
Maybe he was just writing notes on the
speeches with a pen and so it wasn't a
lie.
Sort of,
kinda
cut through his next speech.
Dear white house press.
Why so serious?
Yeah,
we got a problem.
Um,
president trump.
Were you watching that man with heath
ledger last night?
Yes.
It's going to be real weird,
man.
It's going to be real weird.
If that's how it keeps up,
maybe there'll be an adjustment.
Who knows?
Can you imagine how cool it would be if
it was revealed that he did have a
breathing problem all of a sudden
and had to wear some fucking mask.
How awesome.
The avatar part is not,
not true.
That wasn't set in avatar.
Well,
we already discussed who snopes is.
Who's running the guy that married a
cowgirl.
I don't understand that.
I still think it's a.
It's pretty good.
It's pretty good snow girl.
Okay.
But you have to listen to you.
This one guy behind this thing
obviously,
well guy and his wife and they got
divorced and now he's a guy and a former
escort and they,
uh,
they still run it and they have a very
clear left wing bias.
It's a very.
They've been a part of like anti bush
rallies in the past and so I get it.
It's good to have something like that.
I'm not totally dismissing it,
but these are just people.
This isn't like objective academics who
have combed the land and looked for the
correct answer all the time.
There's stuff is widely criticized.
I don't always agree with the criticism,
but it's not like they're the end all be
all when it comes to truth is what's
real on the internet.
No,
no,
but it's definitely a really good for
like say like a hey,
they say these tacos are making it out
of horses and then they and they go,
here's an article,
here's an article.
Yet god,
thanks noax.
Some shit that was going on in a leading
up to the election that was pretty
criticized fund.
I criticisms of snopes.
See if you find anything that's any
good.
I found a great thing that a university
put together of how bias each thing is
and which direction.
Everything leans.
Like they went really deep into it and
they made a really cool graph.
Then that middle part is mainstream and
the higher up it is,
the more actual and factual everything
is in the lower it is,
the more.
It's just like fake news,
like crap jargOn and the farther left it
means that leans liberal,
like there's crazy stuff over there.
And then the far right leans,
conservative and it has everything
listed.
What's really fucked up is we don't
have.
Cnn is hot dog shit.
If you're wondering like the fakest
terrible news,
but it says that it's better than
reading the news.
And what was the source of this?
Oh,
it's a fox from what this was.
Um,
this was a study dOne by.
I can't remember the college says one
point 3 million views.
But um,
I like pbs or runners.
It's on edgar from the name of the
person that posted it is wild.
You katon man.
Why you see a t?
A n,
m,
a n,
but it has one point,
3 million views.
Some school,
I can't remember the exact school.
I found this off reddit and then just
snagged a screenshot,
a picture of it because I found it so
amazing and it shows you everything.
Like basically bbc and npr is right in
the middle.
Like it's like above tHe Washington post
above New York times above nbc.
And abc usa today and cnn way down at
the bottom and it says that the
economist,
the guardian,
the atlantic in the wall street journal
are basically the best minimal partisan
bias mainstream but still reputable.
well they say about the wall street
journals because it deals with the
financial markets and because you can't
have just a clear editorial bias that
leans one way or the other,
that's gonna affect business.
Like tHey're not going to tolerate that
shit.
They want to know what the fuck is
really going on.
Clean and clear without all your,
you know,
hippie logic thrown into it.
Yup.
What do you think about our t?
Is that with
rt Russia today?
No,
I'm mad.
It's owned by Russia at the end of the
day.
You know,
you realize that like they've got some
sort of an influence over them.
I don't know how much of an influence,
but I had lee camp on my podcast and I
was asking him whether or not I'm
putting uses fillers.
That dude fucking clamped up.
He didn't want to say a word fillers.
Fillers like on his face,
like his face is looking.
It looks like someone's doing something
to his face,
like botox or something.
Then he just clamped up.
Whereas I've had,
uh,
abby martin on the show before and she
used to work for Russia today and she
just decided not to do it anymore.
She's doing her own thing now and she
was doing it.
She was a reporting on the,
uh,
the situation,
Ukraine and they wanted a shipper to
Ukraine feel like,
yeah,
why don't you go check it out.
We're going to send her there and she's
going to go there on the ground.
She's like,
the fuck I am.
I'm not going to Russia or you create
out of your fucking mind.
And that's when she realized like,
oh,
I got to
get out of this business because he was
criticizing them Russia today.
It's,
uh,
it's interesting,
but it's probably a better news source
than what you're getting from the
America propaganda networks to this bad.
I watched post debate,
um,
I watched cnn and fox news and I went
back and forth for a couple of hours.
I decided this is going to be like my
project for the night.
I'm going to see What the left is saying
that I'm going to see what the right is
saying.
It was crazy.
It was like to alternate realities.
Two completely different worlds and it
was so biased on both sides.
There is so biased.
There's no one who's saying anything
that might make the other side look good
or it might soften someone's point of
view or get hillary clinton is a fief
and a liar and she's profiting and the
clinton foundation is a problem and she
needs to go to jail and anybody else
would be in jail and taxes and this and
that and fucking real estate scandals
and and then you go to the other side
and it's all sexual assault.
Donald trump's sexual assault,
choose of sexual assault.
A woman accuses him of sexual assault.
This video,
the grab the pussy video and like it was
all concentrating on that
and that's another crazy thing about
this study is that comparatively,
according to this huge crazy study that
they did fox news while being while
completely leaning right,
but still reputable,
cnn is not and can just not reputable at
all.
Wow.
Bottom of everything,
but they say better than not reading
news at all,
but
send me,
take a screenshot of that and send that
to me and send me to with the guy's name
on it.
I'm going to put it on my instagram and
give that guy interesting.
Nbc.
Nbc is in the middle with the Washington
post.
Well,
Brian Williams made sure of that.
In fact,
he went to battle for it.
Well,
msnbc.
Yeah.
Is the one that they're saying is the
fox news of the left basically,
but still sort of there,
but they're more,
much more according to this.
Much more reputable than cnn.
That's rachel maddow.
Yeah,
she gets.
She gets a little bit crazy to just a
big old lesbian running that show.
I love it.
I love the fact that you could have a
clear and obvious short haired lesbian
woman with a,
you know,
ivy league education being like your
mouthpiece.
Like she's the main dude over there.
It is.
And then you have that keith overman
guys gone bananas.
He's just insane.
Yeah.
And another thing.
Well he's like,
he just talks about like we've had a
coo.
We've been taken over by Russia.
Russia has taken over the United States.
It's been a bloodless group and he does,
uh,
that show,
the resistance,
you know,
he's going super hard left.
Yeah,
he's,
yeah,
it's some loopy stuff like watching him
for nine minutes the other day,
just random.
Seems like he's in like some sort of
like
one of those cable access studios and he
has to keep going,
like it doesn't go to commercial and
another thing.
well that's what he's always done.
He's always been a great ranter.
He was one of the original espn sports
center guys and he was a fucking beast
man.
They what happened?
Why did they take him off espn?
Because that's where everybody loved him
and then he went from there and started
doing political news.
So good.
It's almost like once you start doing
keith olbermann right,
you got in trouble.
What do you do?
Some shit that he shouldn't have said he
kept going against the like,
I think it was mostly mostly it's like
disney or the man because disney owns.
Yes,
but fucking man,
he got like him and dan patrick there.
I think they were both band from espn,
like facilities and not talk to anybody
for 10 years.
And dan patrick recently,
I got back in good graces a little bit
and they'll,
or maybe it was older men did and dan
patrick is still completely like,
you're not,
don't talk to dan.
Patrick is what they kind of have to
like.
It's like a big no,
no.
What did they get in trouble about?
I'll look it up second.
Wow.
But,
so then I didn't follow him and I
didn't,
I don't follow sports so I didn't know,
you know,
I didn't know that he was like this big
sports guy,
but I had heard people talk about it and
they really liked him and then I
remember he went over and started doing
political stuff and then there was a lot
of controversy and I feel like some of
the controversy was like if you start
out doing sports,
you got to stick with sports
motherfucker.
Like people don't like you starting out
with sports and then all of a sudden
you're talking about politics.
Like what?
What are you running a political shit,
what the fuck?
Baseball,
exactly.
What about Willie Mays?
Right?
Babe ruth?
Come on.
Keith baseball.
Yeah.
That's what everybody,
you know.
Right?
What happened as you get your respect
for that and we're supposed to like
listen to your opinion on ranting
political stuff.
Spend sports and politics go hand in
hand it two things.
I can't stand,
you know for the most part.
But you care about this trump thing I
did just because I have to hear about it
nonstop every single day.
Every single thing.
I like internet,
tv people and all are talking about
trump.
It's like a nightmare that won't stop.
Like I don't give a shit about politics
but I have to talk about trump and hear
about trump.
But you do give a shit about trump
though.
It's not just you hear about them.
You were just saying I give a shit.
Yeah,
I,
it's embarrassing,
but I'm like I wish I could just stop
hearing about it now.
Like it's nothing.
I think people are tired of people
complaining about it,
which is fascinating to me.
So what do you want them to do?
Like I'm just tired of people fucking
complaining about a god damn it.
So I get up,
he won,
so I get up.
He's our president.
Like,
okay,
do you really expect the people are just
going to stop complaining because that's
ridiculous.
People always complain.
People complain,
no matter who the fuck wins.
If hillary clinton had won right now,
people would be going crazy on fox news.
they would be screaming for her head.
we can only hope that someone,
someone has the courage to prosecute
this criminal for deleting those emails
and they would just go crazy
about it.
But the difference is republicans would
not have walked in the street unless she
had a grand by the deq video that they
pulled out of nowhere.
And even then people would think it was
funny.
Women would it be out there,
grab his deck,
grab his deck and let's throw this out
there.
Yeah.
Okay.
So first of all,
the whole trump thing.
Grab them by the pussy.
He's talking about if you have a ton of
money to to some guy being famous.
Very specifically,
is that what it was?
He's like,
you're a celebrity.
You can just grab them by the pussy.
Yeah,
they let you.
But he was saying they let you.
He was talking about like crazy
groupies.
But here's the thing.
People are like,
oh,
that's unfit to be president,
but what our last.
I mean,
our last great president got his dick
sucked in office in the,
in the oval office by an intern.
Then he lied about it to everybody,
including everyone.
I did not have sexual relationship.
Economy was bumping.
Gas prices were seventy two cents and
nobody gave a fuck,
but now all of a sudden it's like,
wait,
this guy is demonizing women.
It's like,
oh,
okay.
Well he just got caught and it's one of
the things that he said.
He's like,
I told clinton say,
well,
worse things.
Yeah.
Bill clinton,
the golf stuff.
bill clinton got his dick sucked while
being the president.
We're talking about a recording on
commercial break of what insight
edition?
Ninety two.
I mean,
the comparisons are insane,
but bill,
bill clinton's,
uh,
seen any one's got freakishly great
president.
There's a difference between hearing
someone say something and knowing they
did something to people.
There's a difference like knowing
someone did something,
it's like,
wow,
I don't see it.
I hear it.
I know.
So if the audio of bill clinton getting
his dick suck came out.
Oh yeah.
It was like,
you won't that into her and ron,
let me shoot on your dress.
Jamie,
what were you gonna say
was olbermann that was actually banned
from espn to main campus.
That's why when he came back he was
doing a show from New York in times
square for my canadian abc,
like sub studio.
He just had lots of running and starting
in 1997,
he went on a daily show when it was
still hosted by craig kilborn,
who was a former espn co-anchor with
them.
That was like his first problem.
He,
he,
uh,
he called espn main campus at
godforsaken place.
Got into an argument for saying that,
just lots of different things that
happened over like 10 year period.
And then he came back,
like I said,
he had a little stint with them.
He got in trouble again for sanction
against penn state supporters.
They suspended him for a little bit for
that.
Penn state support is after the sandusky
trial.
What was,
what was so upsetting about tiredly
also?
That stuff is kind of all been forgotten
now.
None of the,
the,
all of their punishments of just kinda
all disappeared.
They don't,
they're not punished anymore.
They're back in the top of the college
football rankings and everything for
penn state.
Yeah.
Really?
Coming down here again,
we've got to get one of the um,
comedy store.
People to block the door.
They found that they can get down
here where they just leave the door open
and then there's a stairway where people
could just fall.
Sure.
They're supposed to be a security guy up
there and that's supposed to let them
down there and she just shut the door.
Well,
people found out we're down here now.
That's the problem because I opened my
big mouth because we're telling him
about it.
He called it the underground.
At the comedy store.
Yeah.
But there's people that work here that
are supposed to be down here and they
haven't been doing it.
This,
this is the loosest like as like the
people that work here,
they're all comics for all fuck off's.
Everybody like half is everything.
It comes to like letting people in to
anything.
It's hilarious.
It's better.
What's half of the fun of this place?
We're going to have to have someone
watch the door from now on these fox to.
That was the producer guy already?
Oh no it wasn't.
He said it was him.
I saw another dude too.
All right.
Well yeah,
I told them to try to get someone to
watch.
Either way we should do these live
instead of like making it like this down
in here.
Maybe we should just move this shit to
the belly room.
I love live podcasting more than
anything.
Well the belly room is such a great spot
for it too.
And we've already done a bunch of killed
tony's up there.
I feel like maybe there's a problem with
people knowing that we're doing it down
here.
You know where they want to see what new
africa killed tony.
They're like,
where were you guys doing that show was
like,
you can't watch it.
So go home,
get a new lock or something for that
door up there.
Well,
they just need to have someone that
actually stays where they're supposed to
stay and not,
uh,
not let people down.
And also like,
that's crazy staircase.
There's all sorts of equipment down
here.
This is totally like behind the scenes.
there's all that equipment at the comedy
store owns.
It's all out there sitting out there.
You can't just be wandering around with
that bitch,
but people are weird,
man.
They just want to be behind the scenes.
They want to get to that back bar.
They want to go behind the bar that
people want.
I always want to go to that one place
where you not supposed to.
And that's what's crazy is like when I
got here,
I was mr.
Like I,
you had to invite me.
I've always treated this building with a
ridiculous amount of respect.
Like I never wanted any.
Fuck.
Now I'm talking about that.
It goes that it,
there's a statement that that is a thing
in which like,
and I've seen it,
those people that push themselves into
that back alley that are always trying
to smoke pot with everybody,
they're never the ones that end up a
fucking doing anything.
They're always the ones in which it's
like a found out about having to move
back home.
My mom sick so I got to go to
worst when someone like,
chimes in on a conversation and just all
of a sudden talking about themselves.
Yeah.
But yeah,
exactly.
Or you get a lot of that back there.
It's the worst and they're losers,
you know what I mean?
But my point is,
is like the people that,
you know,
go with where they're invited and with
people that they're friends with,
you know,
it's different.
There's just a different thing.
No,
it definitely is.
People want to race to the back,
to the,
to the green room in the back to smoke
because they think there's a shortcut
waiting for them there and is a not.
You still have to meet a shortcut to
make it as a comic.
Yeah.
But I guess,
but I,
but I think this analogy applies
probably for any job,
you know what I mean is it's like it's
not just about the hang,
it's about,
you've always had this combination of
the two.
You've always had this like disdain for
people who network.
Yeah.
Because I think there's a way to do it
and I think it happens organically and
naturally and in people that overdo it,
it's just gross.
The people that overdo it or almost
always not that funny.
Yeah.
And I do it a lot,
but I do it my own way,
you know what I mean?
Does that make sense?
Like I'm not a networker,
but I hang out and I do three podcasts a
week and fucking stand up all the time.
It's different.
There's one thing that's Like,
you're not consciously trying to
network.
You're working with your peers and your
friends.
Yeah.
That's.
There's,
there's that network.
I think there's a natural amount of
networking that happens.
Watch house of cards.
It's my favorite thing.
I'm the one that.
Do you watch it now?
Yes.
Tell me about.
A lot of people told me about this,
don't try to claim you told me about
this.
I'm sure a lot of people did because
it's like one of only four.
Let's go back to the show.
Yeah,
it's a fucking hilarious show.
When you realize like this is probably
how it really works and that networking,
like that kind of shit like that.
That kind of networking is what we're
scared of in comedy.
Like that's how the entire business
runs.
That's how the white house runs.
That's how politics runs.
That's why you're scared of it because
you're scared of that kind of shit
getting into here where it's all about
favors and bullshit,
right?
Yeah.
This place has a loophole for not having
that crap.
It used to be,
dude.
It used to be.
That's how you got gigs.
It used to be the.
There was a.
There was a big problem in hollywood for
a long time.
It was like that's how people got on
shows.
That's how they were writers.
Like there was a lot of fucking really
bad writers back in the day that we're
on sitcoms.
Like you would think,
hey man,
you get to be a writer on like a friend
or a seinfeld or something like that.
You've got to be a really funny person.
And
by the way,
that's totally still a thing in writer's
rooms.
Oh yeah.
Tell me about that.
I mean there's,
you know,
a guy or two that I've worked with,
in the small,
you know,
roast writer's world that I've worked in
that are literally,
you know,
they're pulling a huge favor man.
Like maybe the people feel bad for this
guy,
you know what I mean,
or whatever.
But you know,
he's lazy and doesn't do much and you
know,
sort of just gets to like phone and in
while everybody else is sort of like
writing the actual thing probably gets
nothing in.
You know what I mean?
It's a part of,
part of a.
I think it's a part of that entire crazy
world is there's always like a favor
always.
There's always that.
They have these teams.
A lot of times comedy teams are like
writer teams are one really funny guy
and the other guy who writes the funny
shit down,
totally got the funny guy,
wanders around the office,
scratches his beard and the other guy's
writing shit down.
Even if you watch six days to air,
like it's so fucking,
you know,
matt and trey,
period.
While those other people are,
you know,
writers,
but you barely tagging anything,
you can totally see the vision.
Just puking,
puking it out of his head,
laughing.
They're both laughing and adding to each
other's thing.
Then there's these other people that
know.
People are like,
they're just.
I mean that you need them to in that
environment I think.
I think you need like the occasional
dusting and sprinkling.
Totally,
but that's a different situation because
you've got a super genius.
Yeah.
That trey parker dudes a super genius
and so that's.
That's one thing,
but like those sitcoms,
when you're working on a sitcom,
that's when it becomes really,
really apparent and it's also one of the
weird things about comedy writers is
some comedy writers or standup comics,
but most of them are not so like were
they practicing all this comedy?
Like what are you do?
You don't perform it,
but you know what's funny?
You sure?
Are you sure?
It was funny because I write a lot of
things down that I think is going to be
funny and then not really funny like how
do you practice?
You don't you get taken by people like
me.
They get added to the writer's room and
you get fucking house and it makes these
people have to.
What do you mean you get taken?
I come in and all of a sudden I'm
writing the jokes that are making it to
the actual episode.
For example,
like let's got to be some funny people
you're working with to totally,
totally,
but they're.
Those people.
Normally by the way,
are standup comedians as well.
There's a few gurus,
but occasionally
people have ideas that are not.
They're not performers that had just,
they just write,
just are comedy writers and you just go,
what is going on with this?
Yeah.
Some people were continuously.
Some people are bs.
It's a very interesting business.
Yeah,
but there's a couple of people that get
by on.
I don't know how I.
It shocks me sometimes when I see a
certain couple people in another
writer's room making writer's guild
medicine
loan is a fascinating enterprise.
You know,
making things up,
sitting down in front of a computer and
making up scenarios,
making people,
making up stories,
making a plot,
making the twists in the plot and
characters and it's fucking crazy way to
make a living.
It
is weird.
It's like use your mind to formulate a
world,
you know,
it's continuously asking yourself
questions.
You're like writing a trivia game and
answering it at the same time.
Who's the character?
What would he do?
What is that?
What would it smell like?
What is this?
What would he say?
That's why comedy teams totally makes
sense,
but I've met the comedy guy from the
comedy team after they broke uP,
like the one that got tired of the guy
who's not funny and said,
what the fuck am I doing with this guy?
He got tired of just reading things to
the guy and the other guy.
I've met that guY too.
Those guys are brutal.
And you'll go,
oh,
you were a part of a team.
huh?
I met two guys like that or whatever.
That.
What?
That one those to attend?
No,
no,
not comedians.
I'm not talking about.
Stand up.
No,
no,
that's italian.
No,
I'm talking about writers.
Yeah,
there's a zone.
I've met a bunch of those guys.
Like when I,
I had a development deal long time ago
with this guy that uh,
he used to be a writer on friends and
this dude had like bowling shoes on and
he was part of a comedy team.
The team broke up and uh,
I met with a guy and I was like,
he's wearing bowling shoes,
like,
you know,
trying to be like wacky,
like why is he wearing bowling shoes?
Those aren't comfortable,
nobody wants to wear a bowling shoes,
like he was wearing bowling shoes
because like bowling shoes is like,
he's so wacky.
He wears bowling shoes around the office
and I was.
I was telling my manager so he's wearing
fucking bowling shoes.
I don't like it,
and he's like a serious go.
Yeah,
why is he wearing polling shows?
Like we had this conversation like,
why do you care?
I go,
I care.
Because it's like,
why would you do in that?
Because you want to be whack was you
have exploding tie like you gotta look,
check out my carnation plot squirts you
like,
what is this guy?
What does he think is actually funny?
He gave us a script and it was the worst
piece of shit I've ever read.
It was so bad.
It was stunning.
It was so bad that the network who
recommended him and theY gave him a
gigantic development deal after he left
this,
a sitcom might've left friends and went
to another one.
I forget what it was,
but they gave this cat a gigantic
network deal,
like a huge development deal.
And this was the first thing that he
delivered off this huge deal and
everybody was like,
oh no.
And that's when the concept of the
comedy team became apparent to me what
others.
Two of them are the funny one and left
this guy behind and he's like,
fuck this guy.
And they're like,
no,
no.
He's very funny too.
And most importantly,
you understand story structure.
I got an a.
he's not funny.
I go,
this is definitely not funny.
Well,
you know,
this is a first draft and you have to
like,
nope,
this is a terrible concept.
Like the concept was awful.
It was about a guy who time travels and
uh,
our,
he's immortal.
And he was,
yeah,
that's what it was.
He's a mortal and uh,
all he does is like get laid like what?
It's been around since ancient Egypt
usually like cursed in ancient Egypt so
he can never die.
And he just gets laid and the whole
night or they're like looking at each
other,
like,
what in the fuck?
I go,
yeah,
well the samei so good luck with all of
fucking abandoned ship.
It was hilarious.
There's things like that.
They get pitched every day,
there's some guy who comes into an
office and I've had some fucking
terrible ideas myself.
I've had some terrible ideas that I
thought were good.
Write them out like this is it,
and then you'll put it down for a couple
of weeks,
come back to it and you're like,
what the fuck was I thinking?
Like,
oh my god.
I mean,
what percentage of ideas that you start
out with that you bring to the stage
eventually wind up making it onto a
special or making it into your act
permanently?
Um,
is it even half?
Probably about.
Probably a little.
Probably about half.
Yeah,
I think so because I really don't try it
unless I really,
really think it's funny,
like in think that it fits with my tone
and everything.
Rub you have the possibility of working
those things out,
you know,
hammering them out on stage.
Like to really knock it out of the park
with a comedy script and not ever
practice.
Like that's one of the things that makes
south park so particularly special.
It's like they're not even practicing it
and turning it into like it's best form.
They're kind of coming at you with this
idea.
Like the initial idea.
I mean they,
they've honed it,
they've cut it down,
they've edited it,
they've gone over it,
they've made it funnier,
I'm sure,
but like they don't get to do it for six
months in front of various crowds and
watch it come to life.
You know,
if you think about guys like Stephen
King,
all the shit that guy's made up Just
sits around and makes things up.
Did you see his new show?
The 11 slash 29 about jfk assassination
and time travel?
No,
I've even heard of it.
Oh,
it's great.
It's on netflix or hulu?
Hulu,
hulu.
James franco's like the star.
Oh,
what's it called again?
11 slash 29 slash 11.
Twenty three 63 I think the day he got
shot.
Oh,
it's really good.
Shout.
Yeah,
it's,
it's fun.
It's uh,
it,
it does time travel.
Franco's great in it.
Do you want to stop and think about all
the fucking amazing entertainment
Stephen King has put out over the years?
That guy's insane.
Yeah,
I mean carry it salem's lot,
christine.
I mean you can go on and on and on and
on and on.
Pet cemetery maximum over at.
You guys made some sheer misery.
Oh,
and I'm helen bowser name kathy.
Kathy bates.
I was thinking of Helen Hunt because you
have,
you put her in my head earlier.
chicken up those twister balls.
Yeah man.
god damn that one guy is responsible for
so much iconic entertainment.
Silver bullet.
The kid in the wheelchair and the
werewolf.
It's already too,
like it's been remade right now.
It's coming out this year.
Who is,
who's remaking it?
Uh,
I mean he's part of it.
He's going to talk right into the mike
suk a bill's scars gotten.
I don't recognize anyone that's
skarsgard skarsgard as scars go.
Oh wow.
Look like that guy who's putting the
show together.
Is it a movie we had to make a movie?
But that's a book that's so long.
I've read that book.
It's a long book.
It.
Yeah.
that's why when they had it on
television then they have multiple,
a,
of the mini series.
Yeah.
And there was,
um,
that comic,
not a clue.
Tim.
Tim wasn't that the guy from rocky
horror picture show?
Curry curry.
He was the clown,
right?
Wasn't it?
Yep.
And do you know,
do you know tim curry is like in a
wheelchair now and could barely talk and
he's like a,
he's like a vegetable.
What happened?
I think he had a stroke.
He had a really bad stroke.
no one really talks about that either.
You don't really know that.
Like I saw him in an interview and I was
like,
what the fuck happened to tim curry?
Oh,
that's a palmer.
I didn't know that.
You know,
richard dawkins had a stroke to the
scientist.
The selfish mean you don't know that
guys.
He's a pretty famous atheist and
scientist and I'm author and he had a
stroke,
but he recovered and it didn't affect
his cognitive function,
but it did affect the way your hands
moved.
He can't play the piano.
And it also affected.
He can't,
he can't sing anymore.
I can't pull it off.
Like he's,
he's diminished,
but he still speaks,
which is really interesting.
The part of his brain that was affected
by the stroke,
it didn't fuck them up to the point
where he,
he can't sing anymore or he can't talk
anymore.
He talks Just as well as they always
did.
Makes really lucid points.
Still very smart.
It's nuts how it's probably like a
microscopic fraction of a difference,
like a stroke.
What it hits and what it doesn't hit.
You know what I mean?
Look,
could hit any portion of your brain,
but the portion that it hit on his brain
just affect motor skills apparently.
Fortunately for him.
But fuck man.
What a weird
feelIng to know that your bodies as kind
of like short circuiting that you blew a
fuse.
You know,
like I'd be a blue a circuit the other
day,
you know,
where you plug something in,
it doesn't work.
Like what the fuck?
Then you go out to the circuit court,
oh god,
this fucking flip out for the flip that
sucker over and then it starts working
again and you gotta think,
man,
that's kinda like your brain's almost
like a biological circuit board.
You know,
there's a bunch of electricity going
through there,
bunch of neurons firing all these cells
in there and every now and then one of
them goes,
that can happen to you.
It's tim conway still alive.
It's a good question.
His son was a really good radio show.
Hosts conway and steckler tim conway,
alive and kIcking.
I love that.
Yeah.
Conway and steckler.
They used to have a really good radio
show on fm talk station.
I think he's still doing some.
I heard him the other day on some tim
conway junior.
Never hear about them.
He would have a great podcast.
That guy,
maybe he does.
He does typed in his name and it pops up
the tim conway.
I think it's that show.
Tim conway junior on demand.
It says.
I think it's just called his name.
Well,
there you go.
Yeah,
I did it.
Show a gang of times way back in the
day.
Back when the talk radio was crazy.
They had a whole network.
good.
Oh,
radio station devoted to talk radio in
la.
It was crazy
and I remember listening to it like they
went all talk is when I was on news
radio,
I'd be driving to work.
I'm like,
this is great.
They just talk.
They would just have funny shit and
occasionally and have a whack host.
They let a few whack ones in there.
Oh,
well these lessons am radio fm fm talk.
Wow.
Yeah.
Hey,
Still actually is is uh,
he's on the,
on the air here.
M,
s kfi am 6:45,
six,
seven,
10 week days and I tAke that.
Does the morning show on a protest at
night?
Six to 10:00
PM.
Oh,
ten cents to take that.
Put it as a podcast.
Had a nighttime show back then to what
happened to that steckler guys
still around
apple dumpling gang dumpling.
I didn't even know about that.
You always bring that up.
I don't know what that reference.
What does that reference to?
Tim conway and don knotts movie your
daughters would love it?
Probably not.
It's yet one of my favorites.
Beetle juice.
That's,
that'd be a fun one.
they liked that a lot,
but you know what they thought it was
fucking hilarious.
Talladega nights.
There were
all a little inappropriate,
inappropriate moments.
A few inappropriate things.
They say,
but god damn,
that fucking show is funny.
That movie rather was funny.
Did you show him molana or whatever?
Yeah,
they love that.
THat was amazing.
Star wars.
Yeah,
they seen star wars.
It's funny.
I watched the old star wars.
You watched the old star wars.
Then you watch the new star wars and
like this special effects.
Some school project,
you know?
I mean it literally looks like something
that a million kids could do better on
the
net right now.
Wasn't a fan of the new one.
I fell asleep like 15 times during that.
I didn't see the newest new one.
I saw the one before.
The new one.
We're a hunt solo dies.
I didn't see the newest.
The one I liked.
I liked the newest new one.
I heard the newest doin.
It was one of the best ones.
yeah,
definitely.
No,
I think it was boring as fuck.
Brian needed sleep that day.
Yeah.
You probably saw was because it was in
three d,
three days,
and I know the three d was an after
thought 3d,
you know,
where they're like,
yeah,
let's make a three d,
you know,
it wasn't anything awesome.
And uh,
I think I'd rather not have seen it in
three d.
I think maybe that might've been it
because it was so boring that I just.
And there was no three d going on,
so it was just like,
my eyes are getting tired.
I just need to sleep.
I kept on falling asleep.
They just sound unhealthy.
No,
no,
I'm clint.
But I thought it.
I thought it was just me,
like I thought it was something like I
didn't have any sleep,
but then,
uh,
people I've read on twitter's a agree
and said the same exact shit.
So
it's probably people that follow you and
they'll like,
I'm sleepy too.
Ha.
No,
I would like to see what you thought.
Eventually acting was horrible.
Really horrible.
I literally
no nothing crazy person.
Okay.
You know what?
I'm excited foR john wick two.
Now with that,
I just saw a good movie last take.
I shouldn't say good.
It was really,
it was pretty good.
It wasn't great.
Uh,
that movie split,
which is getting a lot of news right now
because I'm a ding dong movie did
surprisingly well.
I guess it was,
keeps tricking me.
It wasn't a,
it wasn't one of those kind of like,
oh,
there's a big twist at the end.
Everyone is saying there's a twist at
the end.
It's not that big of a fucking surprise
or anything like that.
But the movie itself was pretty
interesting.
It's about people with did,
which is disassociative disassociative
identity disorder,
which is fucking weird.
I looked up some more stuff on it.
If it's real,
the way that this movie depicts it
fucking insane.
But
well,
people definitely have blown brains,
you know.
But that night shama lama dang dong guy,
he got me with that fucking elevator
movie.
I'm like,
oh,
watch.
This was in the elevator man.
I skipped a bunch of.
How might you motherfucker.
I think the marky mark one with the
trees.
It kills the trees.
Come to live and kill folks.
Yeah,
you got me with that one too.
He got me with the village,
you know the people that live in the
village,
they find out planes flying over the
head.
They walk out to the road.
It's walking distance.
They didn't even bring food.
Sixth sense was cool.
Signs was scary at points,
but really
stop and think of how fucking stupid
that village concept was.
They had this village,
they thought they were living in the 18
hundreds.
We're all bummed,
but meanwhile they're in modern America.
Okay,
and the way this is an experiment in the
way that protects his experiment.
Planes didn't fly over it.
Oh,
okay.
Well surely you must be no fucking way.
We're near people because.
Oh,
you right over there.
you can just walk.
You could just walk to the town and they
didn't find out about you all these
years.
Fuck you.
Yeah,
fireworks.
Fourth of july.
Come on.
Something as the fuck outta here,
bitch.
I don't think I saw the village now that
I think about it so stupid.
It was so stupid and I thought it was
about monsters to,
of the monsters were taking people what?
It's like people
you want your heart to Beat,
watch a movie called don't breathe,
unbelievable movie about a bunch of,
you know,
punk,
cool,
smart,
like thIeve kids that are coming up and
like on a good run of robberies and they
go and they will,
they see that this former Vietnam vet,
a one like a ton of money and a law suit
and someone close to him at the bank
said that he took it all out and cash
and has it in his house.
Like so they got this hot tip that this
guy has like a couple million in cash
and his house and he's some old old
Vietnam vet,
so let's do that.
Then they go to say anymore.
Yeah.
What the
fuck did I showed you the.
now that's it.
That's literally the setup to the
trailer for this on the podcast and I
mistakenly said it was the guy from the
Kevin Smith movement.
You called it out as the guy from
avatar.
Like the general.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Okay.
That's.
Now I remember it.
Yeah.
Don't breathe.
No one else is supposed to be really
good.
There's a zombie movie,
but I think was made in england.
I think it's called a girl with all the
gifts and it's about a kid that's a
zombie,
like there's a disease and these people
get it and it's not like some free.
It turns a frantic and this one girl,
I think they're using according to the
trailer,
they're using her as a,
um,
like a to make a vaccine.
But these,
these Fucking pandemic disease movies
where people go crazy and start killing
each other.
They seem a little scarier now that
trump's in office.
Right?
Serious about that.
Trump getting a mask thing.
Like how great that would be.
You were using your precedent,
dude,
you should've been here the inauguration
night now.
Figuration night we did a podcast and
here with Jeff Ross and Jeff Ross was
freaking me out.
He's knows trump.
He roasted trump is like,
he's never leaving.
He's going to be there for twentY years
and he'll leave,
but It'll help make sure that somebody
who's his friend gets elected and he'll
be as advisor and he'll be right there
with them.
THen his son will get in.
He's like,
that's it,
it's over.
Now he's in that says wow,
and then the moment he gets in,
he takes the lbgt page off the white
house and he takes.
No,
I know that happens with every
presidential change.
I read a whole thing about that.
They take the lbgt archive everything.
They take everything from everybody's
thing and completely scratch it
and then they put up the new page,
the new president.
It doesn't give a fuck about lbgt.
Who doesn't give a fuck about you?
Climate change and it doesn't give a
fuck about civil rights.
Same thing.
Still the same thing no matter what,
like what he decided to remove and
replace,
but I think it's like a process that
right,
is it?
I don't think they would have a website
in place.
I read a whole thing and maybe I can't.
Again,
I can't cite the source because like I
told jerry earlier,
smoking twice as much as I ever have
before in my life.
So like.
But I read that that's the thing that
happened when barack took office.
Like a lot of this stuff by the way
that's happening is stuff that is a very
regular thing,
like people are freaking out about his
cabinet picks,
but I read a whole thing on that where
it's like,
yeah,
that's how this stuff works still to get
approved by this and it.
His cabinet picks tell a lot about his
intentions.
You know,
like the guy,
the former exxon ceo and.
But don't you think that's sort of good
to have a.
Do you know that you put a five year,
like he's the first president to say
that you can't just go join lobbies,
you can't be a light switch,
you're not going to get rich off of me.
So I think maybe if that guy who he
interviewed who's trump known for hiring
people,
that's what his specialty is.
It if he hired that guy for a reason and
if it's because he's such a fucking
freak that he might be one of the people
that fix the economy.
Look how much money you made mobile
exxon.
I'm just saying that if he's right then
fuck.
That'd be so great.
I'm rooting for the guy.
It seems scary,
right about what the problem is.
Everyone knows is a real transparent
deal that obama blocked or exxon was
trying to drill and they were trying to
make this deal with Russia and exxon
got,
they got cock blocked by obama and now
that obama's out and then the Former
exxon ceo is in like and people were
wondering like,
are they doing something that the
environmentalist thing could potentially
be a huge disaster and then they doing
it for profit.
I don't know.
I don't follow it enough.
That's when I'm not optimistic though.
That's when I get nervous,
you know?
But then again Like things like this
dakota pipeline,
you know about that,
right?
The dakota pipeline,
they were trying to.
I mean they fucking did man.
They arrested people for trying to
protest them.
This government decided and this
easement,
they decided to put through people's
private land that these are.
THese guys had ranchers.
There's a river that runs through them
and they wanted a drill this pipeline
right under the river and if it blue,
you know,
which they do all the time.
If it goes bad,
this whole river system gets totally
poisoned and they successfully blocked
it,
but people had to,
they had to put a lot of blood,
sweat and tears into it and had a
protest for a long time.
They got shot at with water hoses and
that cold weather
that happened under obama's watch
though,
right?
Yep.
So I mean,
it's one of those things where it's
like,
absolutely.
At least we're learning that if you do
have to make some sacrifices and
protests and certain situation like
that,
that maybe it will work.
I guess it is interesting that it
happened under obama's watch and he
didn't do jack shit about it and he
didn't freak out.
He had to have been aware.
He had to know that these people are.
They're protesting a very dangerous
situation.
It's all fucked up,
man.
There's so much profit to be made and
then these guys have to think,
hey,
you know,
if we don't do this,
then we're reliant upon the salt.
Number nine is gold underwear,
you know,
because that's the only place where
we're going to get our oil from.
Right.
We have to get our oil from the middle
east.
Should we get it ourselves?
Should we get it this way?
Is that better?
Is it better for our country?
How do we do it without fucking up the
environment?
Can you prove to me that we're not going
to fuck up the environment and then they
think they do and then they go out and
they'll go,
oh sir,
we've got a problem.
Earthquakes have increased by 500
percent earthquakes.
what do you mean earthquakes?
Well,
we didn't anticipate this,
but apparently when you frack and drill
holes in the ground,
the earth shifts and we have some
serious earthquakes and unfortunately
because of that shifting,
some of the shit has gotten into the
water and that's where.
THat's where they are right now in
Oklahoma,
they're having a fuck ton of earthquakes
and they trying to figure
out what to do because these guys are
just digging holes in the ground.
I mean,
we're crazy.
Monsters were like termites.
Termites were digging holes into the
ground and we're sucking up all the
juicy stuff so we can light fires.
That's what we're doing.
We're lighting fires,
were leaded gas fires in oil fighters.
We just contain them inside these mental
blocks.
I mean,
that's what we're doing the world were.
We need all this stuff for is combustion
engines and make the make plastics so we
could choke birds.
That's what we're doing.
We're choking birds,
choking birds,
enlightened fires.
They're going to tap our natural
resources on federal lands according to
the first energy plan on the white house
website says we have a quote from,
we must take advantage of the estimated
$50,000,000,000,000
and untapped shale oil,
natural gas reserves,
especially those on the federal lands
that the american people own.
That's super interesting.
That's terrible thing.
That's a terrible thing.
Yeah.
That's a terrible thing because that's
what we're talking about with teddy
roosevelt,
the public land and having public land
and how it's such a huge issue in such
a.
An amazing resource like places like
yellowstone,
like all these places where you can go
and hike and camp and fish and hunt and
do whatever you want.
Enjoy is insane piece of nature that we
have here or this insane piece of
wilderness.
We have an amazing public land system in
this country and there's a bunch of
people that are working really hard to
keep that in place,
but when they start talking about,
taken out the natural resources and
drilling into it and shit,
it doesn't look good.
Alright.
Everybody's checking their watches time
again out of here by 1230.
We should have enough.
We did like two hours,
right?
And maybe two houRs.
Two hours.
Two and a half.
Two and a half hours.
Jesus christ.
Enough.
Enough already.
Okay,
everybody.
Bye.
Say bye.
We'll probably do this again.
Hey,
maybe next one.
We'll deal with trying to do on stage.
Who knows or we'll sneak one in here
where we don't have people coming down
and knock on the door and trying to take
selfies in front of the door.
Hey,
come see me.
Do stand up comedy for me.
You're talking to the listeners.
Oh,
you're coming back.
and san antonio this weekend.
All weekend.
San antonio,
san antonio,
the river center improv.
All these dates are tony hinchcliFfe,
datto know that existed.
San antonio is an improv.
Yeah,
we're one of the royal rumble on sunday.
Me and a whole gang of people here.
We're in.
They're all doing the shows with me.
IT's like a dream weekend making gay.
Oh yeah.
The guy that falls asleep and movies
because he's got the
body of a go on.
Brian.
Tony hinchcliffe.com
for all this towards tony hinchcliffe.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Brian.
Wherefore art thou a.
How about this?
February,
first at comedy store.
Main room and some other shit.
Go to death squad to squad.tv
show sons bitches to
rogan.
Just to kill time.
I just did kill,
terminate,
judge young comedians and killed tony.
Episode two hundreds coming up in the
main room.
And my shield tony,
we did.
Today was a good one.
The girl at the end.
What was her name?
Uh,
kirsten.
Dirty,
dirty hippie comic.
That's a dirty hippie comic on twitter.
She's fucking hilarious.
She's really funny.
She was good.
She killed me.
And we filmed tonight in vr.
So there's two streams.
Jesus christ.
What more do you want?
You've got it.
All right folks.
That's it.
See you soon.
Bye.