I remember I took some mushrooms one
time to a,
a party in high school because I grew up
in an area where you could just get
mushrooms,
psychedelic mushrooms grew on
everything.
They grow in your fucking cousins back
and we took a long enough nap,
let you grow up in Louisiana.
They grew everywhere out there or they
grab work because everybody had
something shitting in their yard and
then it would rain every single day for
about a half hour.
Right.
So it was just.
I mean,
you see people picking them and eating
them and families out there and join
them in the afternoon.
I mean it was.
Everybody was,
oh,
it was psychedelic heaven.
So we would ride out and go get them.
I remember one time getting a trash bag
of probably about 35 pounds of
mushrooms.
Right?
And one time a golden retriever came
running at us across this field and we
thought he was pissed because we were
tripping.
And then he got to us.
We ran for like a half mile,
he got to us finally.
We're crawling away from thinking he's
evil and he just fucking love this.
And licked mean golden retriever.
He thought he was mean for us because
the hair,
his hair was kind of slick back like an
evil golden retriever.
So no,
I took that back and busters to that
party and a bunch of people ate a mood,
never had them before.
And then we played a game of hide and go
seek.
Right?
I was like,
no,
you know,
hide in another dimension.
I'll count you guys go hide.
Right.
And I never went to fucking look for
Tim at the.
I've never seen that dude again.