Hello Freak bitches.
Now,
the reason why that upsets me is because
it's,
it's grants people a false sense of
security and hope.
You know Islam is wonderful,
but we need to attack this separate
thing called Islam Islam.
Well from day one,
1400 years ago,
Islam was Islam,
Islam.
Now that doesn't mean that there isn't a
spiritual element.
That doesn't mean that most Muslims just
want to practice the spiritual part,
but there is no set of doctrines and a
separate book called radicalized Islam,
Islam.
It all comes from the same texts.
It comes from the Koran,
it comes from the Heidi's,
and it comes from the Sierra,
the biography of Mohammed,
so,
so this kind of false narrative that
people are prominently gating so that
they seem as though they're not
frontally attacking a religion while
laudable.
While Nice,
I get that reflex,
it's false.
And so again,
to go back to our point of talking
honestly,
we need to talk.
Honestly,
there's only Islam.
Some people choose to practice it fully.
Some people choose to ignore the ugly
parts,
but there is no such thing as Islamism.
Islam.
Islam is part of Islam.
Now you're a person that goes out of
your way to say,
no,
we're not talking about the kind sweet
Islamic people that just want to raise
their children now.
So how do you sort of manage those two
ideas that they're the same?
Like when the term radical Islam gets
thrown around,
right?
So radical Islam simply means I really
take my Islam seriously,
right?
It's,
it's.
Let's draw us a silly analogy.
If I don't eat pork,
uh,
my radical Jew,
or am I a Jew right now,
I happen to be Jewish.
I simply ignore the kosher edict that
says,
don't eat pork.
That's why do you do that though?
Because in my case,
I simply identify as Jewish in the sense
that at Judaism is a multi attribute
identity.
It includes a shared history,
shared lineage,
sh,
sh kind of erase.
It's what some could argue.
It's array,
so it's considered in a lot of people's
ideas.
So I could still in the same way that
you might identify as coming from Boston
and there's a shared history from all
people who grew up around the time that
you grew up in Boston and there was a
sense of affiliation and tribalism,
would that reality being Jewish as far
as I'm concerned and for most Jews is
exactly that.
We don't necessarily take the religious
elements very seriously.
Now.
That doesn't mean that we are practicing
a light Judaism or non radical Judaism.
We're simply ignoring those parts of
Judaism that we choose to ignore.
So there is no such thing as radical
Islam.
There are no books called radical Islam.
There is a set of doctrines called Islam
and then I could do what's called
cafeteria Islam,
which is I pick and choose the parts
that I wish to adhere to.
So again,
the discourse is a false narrative.
I understand the reason for it because
people find it rather Gauche to attack
frontally it religion at least to attack
Islam.
So they have to.
I call this the,
the,
the ISM magic eucharistic rite.
You add ism to something.
It makes it bad.
Islam as good Islam,
Islam is bad.
Yeah.
But that's,
um,
that's a characteristic that I see in
almost everybody that I respect.
They all think that everything they do
socks or at least they have very,
very high standards and an often
disappointed by their own work.
Well,
you know,
I think I have some of that,
but I also have that idea of like,
it's something that I've,
I don't know if I talked about my dad
with you,
but um,
he was my wrestling coach in high
school.
Uh,
he was also my,
uh,
earth science biology and environmental
studies teacher.
She was my teacher.
Well,
what a drag you went to school,
your dad being the fucking.
I learned a lot because he was no joke.
He didn't pull any punches from me.
He,
you know,
he drove me as hard,
if not harder than his other students.
He didn't show any favoritism,
but one of the things that was always
his thing on the mat,
and I'm kind of paraphrasing,
but basically you,
you either win or you learn,
especially in that high school college
setting,
you're,
you're learning about yourself.
If you,
if you went out there and you got your
ass handed to you and you just got beat
and didn't learn anything,
well yeah,
you're a fucking loser.
Take the moment,
reflect on it,
build on what you did wrong and you now
you're actually gonna.
Wave one.
Now you know more about yourself.
You know about where your your
limitations are,
what you need to improve and expand your
talents are your limitations.
So I guess whenever I'm doing a thing,
I'm always looking at it from a learning
perspective so there aren't necessarily
mistakes unless they're fatal and then
you wouldn't know anyway.
So whatever that really is the right way
to look at everything.
You win or you learn.
You know you have great experiences
because you were successful or you have
very beneficial experiences because you
realized what went wrong.
What is just one more wrinkle,
one more piece of information or one
more experience that you can add to your
database of knowledge and it'll make you
better at everything.
So that,
and a lot of ways,
that's my biggest frustration in life is
when there is something that Kinda goes
wrong and I can't figure out what it was
that's frustrating for me because I
can't,
I can't build on it.
I can't learn from it,
but I don't understand what went wrong,
but whether it's a relationship or
whether it's something I tried to build
or something I did or how often does
that happen?
A lot,
you know,
there's a couple of times I've actually
had an opportunity to do,
have a uh,
vocal with somebody else as a guest
singer and I know rehearsal was great
and then you blew it for the,
for the main event.
And I'm like,
what did I do wrong?
I did everything the same.
And until you can actually pinpoint that
and figure out what it was,
I'm a fucking mess.
Like I'm slipping.
I'm waking up in the middle of the night
trying to figure out what the fuck went
wrong.
And then when you're done with that,
you've got to figure out a way to get
that thing from dead deer to meet.
And all the other things.
So it's just so complex.
How would you ever expect somebody to
just to be,
have like a desire.
You were like that at some point.
Well,
Rinella opened the door for me to have
that super lucky forever grateful
because when he took me into a wild back
country,
Montana.
Yeah,
you gotta get to the nuts.
The first year it was a three breaks in
the Missouri breaks in October,
nine degrees out.
Freezing your dick off every night and
attend like lifeless Steven Ella.
That's kind of.
What was it?
He loves suffering.
He loves it.
But I love that he loves it.
He's legit as they come.
He really is.
I think that's it,
right?
There is just this,
there's this big gap.
And my father got me into it,
but I,
my brother doesn't.
Doesn't hunt and.
But I think he has a respect for it and
understands what's going on.
But he just,
I think at the time that I was
introduced to hunting,
my brother was more interested in going
out with his friends and Saturday
mornings were not for getting up early.
And so we're essentially the same
person,
but I just went this way and he didn't
go that way.
Right.
So it's a weird.
So you could be in the same house with
somebody in a different way.
Well,
Rinella has a real good way of looking
at it too.
He's like,
uh,
I don't expect people to go out and get
rid of their own sewage.
Why should I expect them to go out and
hunt their own food like you don't have
to?
Well,
and he's,
I think he probably said this at some
point,
um,
or somebody smart did.
It was like I choose,
I believe it.
I choose to for meat to be the one thing
that I grabbed ahold of to bring into
my,
to my skill set.
I don't knit my own clothes.
I don't,
I don't make my own shoes.
I don't build my own houses.
You know,
we were just looking at some
construction stuff a little bit earlier.
I'm like,
dude,
I don't know what.
Yeah,
what are they doing?
What are they doing?
Yeah.
I couldn't do that.
I just picked this one thing because
it's also part of my passion,
so you couldn't just ask someone who's a
construction worker to go like,
go hunt,
get some meat.
I know you have a desire for that,
so that's just another hard part about
hunting and and non hunters by proxy are
essential to hunting always in industry
and opinion and because we could
legislate ourselves out of being able to
hunt.
That can happen.
One is a privileged man.
That's not a right and a lot of ways and
so that's another whole nother can of
worms,
but it could.
It could go away.
Yeah.
I think the.
The issue is that so many people are
opposed to it because they're so removed
from the realities of the wild and they
just feel some sort of moral superiority
by either not eating meat entirely or by
not killing their own meat.
The not killing their own meat is really
ridiculous.
Like my wife was having a conversation
with someone.
They were out to dinner with a bunch of
people while I was on El con and the guy
was eating a steak guy from England in
England and will hunt or they've do
these,
these like foxes and
horses and shit,
and they were like,
tweed pussies,
Kesari England.
We love you guys carving a steak.
And my wife goes,
oh,
he's actually out elk hunting.
And the guy goes,
he hunts.
That's deplorable.
The guy said,
does deplorable.
He's carving a steak,
was saying something the other day.
And I got.
I got a lot of,
like,
people were looking at me like I was
weird at work.
Uh,
one of my buddies at work was eating a
chicken sandwich from chick filet and I
look on the bag and there's a cartoon
chicken on the bag.
And in my mind I'm like,
well,
that's like building a swimming pool by
the lake.
That's fucking weird and irony that,
that were like saying,
Hey,
I'm eating the chicken,
but here's a cartoon version of it so we
can celebrate the fact that we just
murdered this chicken and we fried it
up.
Like that doesn't make sense like a
swimming pool with a lake as smart
because it's Paris.