Five,
four,
three,
two,
boom.
And we're live Ramey warrant
international man of adventure.
How's it going?
Good to see you,
man.
Good to see you.
I purposely didn't ask you or talk to
you about the grizzly bear attack
because I wanted to save it.
You want it?
You want,
what is it like to have survived but
literally being two feet away from an
attack and grizzly bear.
You could have grabbed it.
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Easily.
Oh,
it was,
that was just nuts.
It was one of those things.
Okay.
I've thought about it a million times.
I'm sure.
How long ago was this?
This was.
So,
that would've been early October.
Mid October.
So you've answered three months,
three months to kind of wait around.
Yep.
And uh,
yeah man,
it's just one of those things that I've
thought about it so many times in my
head and I've always been.
I think Steve was the same way.
Like,
oh,
it'd be pretty cool to survive a bear
attack gets scratched up a little bit
after that experience.
I thought to myself,
if that never happened to me.
Okay.
Yeah.
Steve used to always say steve or no,
we're talking about from the mediator
podcasts and he has a two part series on
this particular bear attack,
but he always say he wanted to get
clawed across the chest and have like
not a tattoo but like a big closet.
I'm like marketing,
like what?
What are the odds that that happens?
Yeah.
I think that in order to get that you
have to go through a really,
really horrible experience.
There's guys that have had those attacks
or there's guys that have had those
detects a lot,
but yeah,
I mean I've been around a lot of wild
animals and seen a lot of things and
been charged by bears and this was just
different.
It was that kind of attack where while
it's happening,
you're going,
this is not gonna Pan out.
Well,
somebody who's going to die something
either you're just looking at this bear
and it's coming in hot and just
everything.
It's a weird experience.
You don't.
Your memory's a little foggy.
I mean everything happened so fast,
but it felt like it was so long.
So the adrenaline overwhelmed brain.
Yeah,
and if you don't even think about,
I just remember it was,
it was a weird situation.
So maybe I'll just kind of recap the
story.
Um,
so we're,
we're on a fog neck island and we're
hunting in a fog.
Neck island is off of Kodiak.
Yeah.
So a fog neck island has some of the
largest bears in the world.
They're brown bears are,
they are big brown,
various,
it can be over a thousand pounds.
So we're hunting elk there.
My brother and myself have hunted elk on
that island before and it's just a
miserable place to be.
What's a fascinating hunt the way you
guys were describing it,
because the,
the,
just the fact that you would choose out
of all the places you can go,
you pretty much can go anywhere,
want you chose to go on this brutal
adventure hunt because it's so difficult
and says he wants.
Because like Rinella was talking about
this once in the way he described it as
like there's things that are fun while
you're doing them,
but they're not fun later,
like rollercoasters.
And then there's things that are
terrible and awful,
but you'll think about them forever and
look back at them fondly.
Yeah,
that's exactly what this is.
Is that after the fact you think back
and you go in the moment you go,
I will never do this again.
And then about a year later you should
do that again.
Weird.
And what is it about the place?
It's so miserable.
It's just,
it's hard to walk through.
It looks,
it looks easy.
Hiking.
And there's just this big mountain where
you can get to with a plane,
you've kind of got to climb this big
mountain and the vegetation is so thick
and it's so steep that it takes forever
to go somewhere.
So to put it in perspective,
to go say a mile might take five hours.
Whoa.
That's how much verdict.
Like a map mile.
So the way the crow would fly if you're
just going a mile and then another
distance could take you half that time
recorder that time.
But there's a big mountain in between
where you need to go plus the vegetation
and it's really steep.
So you've got all that kind of working
against you,
plus you can't really walk and just a
straight line there.
You've got to navigate around all kinds
of stuff.
You from place them in this journey that
was and is gay.
So that was after the bear attack.
Well,
I'll have to figure out because I poke
right after the bear attacked.
I pulled out my phone and just kind of
like recording everyone's reactions and
then I put it on my instagram story,
but I'll try to find it tonight and I'll
post it onto some.
I'll figure out a way to.
Yeah.
And they let you save them now.
Now this was like three weeks before
that.
Unfortunate.
So this place is miserable.
It's raining all the time.
Rain,
high winds,
thick,
dense vegetation and literal monsters.
Yeah.
I mean giant bears and then big.
Um,
the elk are probably with they way they
wait,
they can wait up to 1400 pounds either.
It was way bigger.
Yeah,
it was like the size of two normal elk
weight wise because like an average elk
would probably be around 500 pounds in
most places.
Really big one.
Like we were talking about the
California ones that the whole.
And sometimes it can get to a thousand.
This is another 400 pounds,
but exactly.
It's a lot of digging and there's bears
that eat those giant ant,
so those bears are giant.
The barriers can be over 1200,
1500 pounds themselves.
Eleven feet or more?
Yeah,
11 feet and feet.
It's not 11 foot bear.
No.
This one
that attacked you guys.
How big do you think it was if you had
to guess?
I would say,
well,
I would say it's 11 and a half feet
because I know because actually after we
went in there,
my friend who's a pilot there in dropped
us off.
He called me about a week or two later
and he was like,
they shot that bear.
They went after you guys.
Somebody went in there,
same place.
Bear attacked them.
They killed it in self defense.
It was 11 and a half feet and I think
almost 1200 pounds.
So there's very good odds that that was
the same bear.
I would imagine that it was.
I mean,
because marry had just taken over that
area.
Seemed about the same.
So when I,
when it came in,
I thought that's a big bore.
It wasn't one of those ones you think,
oh,
that's a.
It looked like a big mature animal
in the piecing together.
What happened in my mind later.
But yeah,
so we're hunting elk on this island.
Steven's up getting an ell.
We hanging in a tree.
We do all the stuff you're supposed to
do.
Get the meat away from the carcass.
But we had yet to see a bear up until
this point and when my brother and I
went in there a few years earlier,
we just saw bears everyday.
We'd see six beers a day.
So your mind's just bear,
bear bear.
When you're seeing them all the time
when you weren't seeing them all the
time,
you get a little lax and that's where we
really screwed up because the attack
went down.
No one was prepared,
we were just sitting around having some
sandwiches and one of uh,
so we're,
we're,
we're filming and there was six of us
altogether and I think that large group,
that six is what saved us because when
the bear ran in,
it was six of us sitting kind of in a
semi circle strange circle and when that
bear came in we did that scatter effect
and I think that scatter was kind of
like if a lion is going after a zebra,
they use their numbers and stripes to
confuse the lion is that scattering of
things just going everywhere that,
that caused confusion for the bear.
So I think the bear went in thinking
whatever's under that tree,
I'm going to kill it.
And it thought it was one thing and when
we blew up into six different pieces,
it just tried to kill everything at once
and couldn't actually get one person.
God.
But so lucky.
Yeah,
it was crazy because we're sitting down,
we decided,
oh,
we'll have lunch before we hiked back
because the day before we,
we hiked along ways.
We got back to camp at three in the
morning or something.
I can't remember.
Two or three in the morning.
We'd barely eaten.
So everyone was just thinking let's have
lunch,
regroup,
hike out.
So we're pat.
When the other guys that was with us
brought the jet boiled boil up some
coffee.
So I was going around collecting water
from everyone to get coffee going
around.
And when I sat down I took my pack off
and the whole week I had been doing this
thing where I take my pistol from
the PAC belt and put it on the holster
on my body when I dropped my pack and I.
It was a weird deal where I took the
pack off and I'm thinking about
switching and I'm like,
no,
it's fine.
You know,
and I thought I'll just sit because
there's few times I'd set my pack down
and was like,
I'll just sit or lay on my pack like as
a chair backrest and then all flop the,
you know,
have the pistol right there.
So it's within arms reach and I'll be
sitting there while I go around and get
the water.
And someone had moved kind of where I
was sitting so now,
so I sit down across from the pack where
my pistol is and then thinking I was
thinking about me that pistol,
but I just was like,
man,
you know,
you don't want to be that guy.
Like,
Oh yeah,
the guy.
That's exactly right.
We not everybody had pistols,
just me.
And Jada said a pistol and then,
and then pat pat's behind us.
He goes,
I hear something and I look up and
that's,
that bears like dead set.
So Steve would be where you are.
The bear behind Steve.
So Steve was between me and the bear,
his back was to it.
Like how far away?
Not Far.
I don't 30 yards something the first
time you see that?
Thirty yards and ends the marriage.
Yeah,
it's dead run super fast.
And I just locked eyes with this thing.
I mean I see it coming in the whole way.
Just beady eyes locked in on me and I
think this thing's gonna kill me.
And so I'm thinking,
you know,
when I say I'm thinking,
I don't know if I'm thinking,
I'm just,
I just remembered what I was kind of
going through my head at the time.
I thought,
Oh fuck,
I'm gonna die and my protections,
right?
They're like,
I'm going to die.
This is a situation where I'm dead and
they talk about it and he could have
saved himself but his guns on the ground
and I think that that was like,
go for the gun was my whole thing.
So I start to go for the gun Yonis who
would have been here as I remember it.
And so I start to go for the gun and
realized,
fuck,
I don't have time to get to my gun.
And it's three feet away.
That bears like right there,
comes to me so fast.
So I kind of do like a football juke
move left,
right?
And then we'll around,
right.
Do like a spin with my back and they
start running to the left.
And at that point Yonis it.
I didn't know this at the time because I
looked at some pictures afterwards,
kind of piece everything together.
So Yannis was sitting right next to me.
I think he got up to turn.
There was some trekking poles right
here.
He grabbed a trekking pole,
so probably while I was joking,
he reached around and grabbed the
trekking.
Pole swings around,
hits the bear in the face of Jesus.
So then the IC,
the bear running off.
Then I see someone going down the
mountain with the bear.
I'm thinking he's got someone.
So I grabbed my pistol,
start going down the mountain,
yelling,
Oh,
I guess I count off.
And everyone's like,
one.
I'm like,
Oh shit.
And then Garrett pops up out of the
bushes and his eyes.
He's like wide eyed.
So Garrett,
Aka dirt,
dirt myth.
He's the one who was on top of the.
Somehow he's on the bears back.
So I think when the bear wheeled around
you like hit him and he ends up on the
back.
So I saw just legs and bear going down
the mountain.
I saw his legs on the back of the bear.
So the bear had them in his job.
Yeah,
that's what I was thinking.
Well,
I mean,
what,
who,
who would think
like if that was in a movie,
you'd be like,
get the fuck Outta here.
I think.
What was the anchorman where the guy's
like writing the bear.
Exactly.
Yes.
And then we kind of circled up around
the treat and the real scary part was
that bear.
So it was so thick.
You really couldn't see.
You could see maybe as far as the wall
is from us with.
Was that with the tree?
Eight feet?
Yeah.
And just real thick brush.
And you'd hear the bear charging again
and we only have the two pistols.
Yonis I and the wind was so strong.
There's no way we could use bear spray.
So we hear the bear charging in and me
and Jada like pistols out ready waiting
for this thing to pop out at point blank
range.
And then he would in your yelling,
hey.
And then that thing stops and then it
would just crash off and then would
charge in from the other direction.
She ain't got to like circle around the
tree the other way and did that I think
three times that was just under.
It's like a horror movie where it keeps
coming in from different angles.
It was weird.
It was not a fun feeling.
You just felt so small.
So you guys had come back to the carcass
that was hanging in the tree and it had
probably claim that carcass.
We don't know who he was there.
I,
I assume now the weird thing was,
is it came in with the wind so the wind
was blowing pretty stiff and say into
our face and the bear came in with the
wind so he wasn't going into the scent.
Normally they go around,
they catch the scent and they charge in.
So I don't know if you'd heard something
if he was there.
We saw what slightly looked like.
Bear sign.
Both Steve and Steve and I kind of
pointed it out,
but we weren't.
We were thinking maybe it was something
older you wouldn't you say bear sign?
You mean bear shit?
Yeah.
Bear Shit in the base of the tree.
And so I think we did some things that
are wrong,
but in in the instance what saved us all
now if we were to do it 100 times over,
I would say I would do it differently,
but it worked out how it worked out.
So I obviously wouldn't.
I would never opt to just have nothing
and have this weird scatter effect.
But I think what saved everyone from
getting anyone from getting hurt,
which is a miracle,
was the fact that when we scattered it
just confused that bear because he kind
of had this look after you started,
you started wheeling around kind of like
trying to pick a person trying to go and
he couldn't target one individual and
then things started hitting him and
somebody is on his back and I think it
just freaked him out and he went off to
regroup,
keep charging back in,
but never made that full
charge all the way back in again.
Wow,
that's crazy.
How many people have ever gone through a
bear attack unscathed like that?
In a group of six and the.
And the thing about it was it wasn't
just a bear attack,
but had looking at it later,
had someone even been grabbed and mauled
to death but injured.
I think that it would have been very
unlikely that that person was survived
because we.
The weather that came in was so bad.
I don't know if it was a hundred mile an
hour winds.
I mean,
you aren't getting rescued in a hundred
mile an hour winds.
I wouldn't think.
I don't know those coast guard
helicopters.
I'm not really sure what they're capable
of.
Maybe someone would say,
yeah,
we'd,
we'd go,
but that would be a very hard thing.
The gusts were so bad when we came back
over the ridge to our camp.
Now we're all on edge.
You just want to get back to camp to put
it mildly.
Yeah.
Every now and then of course we see
bears on the way back and we're like,
thinking,
is this bear gun?
Follow us this.
How many beds do you guys see on the way
back?
One one another.
So we saw a bear on the front one.
Yeah,
I'm smaller,
but still after that.
Yeah,
you're thinking now before that happened
were thinking,
no,
bears will attack us.
After that happened were thinking every
bear will attack us and we start to go
over the ridge back toward camp.
I think at that point I was in the
front,
Steve and someone else was behind me.
As we go over this little saddle,
the wind hits,
knocks the first three people over.
One of the guys have like a pack cover
on his pack,
ripped that off and just sent it in.
The never evers.
I mean it went up and it was crazy.
I've never seen anything blow away like
that.
It just went flying,
so then we get down the winds or gusting
the rain's pouring.
We look down the two main tensor
destroyed steve and I's tensor flopped
down on the ground.
I see somebody,
a sleeping pad blowing away,
sleeping bags,
getting soaked.
So now we have a,
a real situation of hypothermia.
If the bear didn't get us,
this hypothermia might and we now no
longer have a camp that we can just go
to.
So we've been attacked by a bear.
Our camps destroy.
We get down there,
one of the tents is jacked up.
We take all the camp down,
relocate behind the spruce,
gather up everybody stuff.
Most of the guys sleeping bags or wet.
Uh,
we ended up like restringing the bear
fence around this new camp.
This is after you've just had a full day
and been attacked by a bear and by bear
fence.
You're talking about one of those
electric fencing?
Yeah,
that's a little electric.
How do those things work?
It's a battery operated deal.
You run electric fence.
It's a ribbon to electric fence,
just like a cattle yard would have you
run that around and then it's just off
of I think six d batteries.
That's it.
Pulses and it just,
it tingles just a little bit.
It doesn't really.
If you touch
it,
it doesn't really light you up.
So I think they just,
I don't like that feeling,
especially if it got like their wet
nose.
They might feel it with their nose first
and shocks them and gets them to run off
hopefully.
Yeah.
I don't think I'd like cuddle up with a
dead carcass inside that fence.
I don't trust it that much,
but yeah,
it was,
it was just a nuts a day.
So how did you guys eventually set camp
back up?
So we,
there was a spruce that we're using and
we got behind that spruce tree and input
one of the GP tents up,
kind of tied it off to the spruce and
then Steve and I had too small a
backpacking tents that we put underneath
a few of the limbs,
cut out some limbs and got up under
there and it's still 100 mile an hour
winds.
Yeah,
70 to a hundred,
a hundred and something gusts out there.
And then uh,
some of the guys we actually cut
wouldn't stashed it under the tree
earlier.
So that was good.
We had semi dry wood and we tried some
out in the tent before and the carpet
kind of fallen over it.
So we had a little bit of dry wood were
after a couple of hours we're able to
get a fire going inside the inside the
tent
and then they could dry out some their
sleeping bags and stuff like that.
Jesus Christ,
it was crazy.
How long did it take before you guys got
off the island?
Um,
so what was,
I guess it would have been the next day
in the evening.
Did you get any sleep?
Yeah,
I slept pretty hard.
Wow.
I was ready for bed.
But how could you sleep knowing that?
The fucking things out there.
Yeah.
It's not like that for me.
It was Kinda,
it was Kinda.
I was thinking that was awesome.
We serve when it's over,
you're fine.
I was fine with it.
You didn't think like we're still on the
same island.
The same bear still there.
And we only walked like,
how many miles?
Only three miles.
Three miles.
It's nothing.
Yeah.
Firstly for a bear,
for a bear,
that wouldn't have been a problem for
us.
It takes five,
six hours,
seven hours or something like that.
It was crazy.
But yeah.
And after it happened,
once we cleared the area I was okay,
but in the moment I thought,
this is it,
this is how I die.
It was a weird feeling.
I've had that feeling a few times in my
life and I just don't like that,
that helpless feeling of like thinking,
but what scares me the most is that
thought of thinking while you're dying.
You're thinking about that,
like while you're dying,
knowing that this is that last thought.
I don't like the idea that last thought,
like if I was hearing the plane and the
plane's going down and you think,
well,
I know I'm going to die.
There's nothing I can do in those
thoughts that go through your head.
I don't like those thoughts.
Just not see it coming because those
thoughts are the worst part.
I've thought of that before,
like how do you deal those thoughts?
The feeling right before the plane hits
the ground,
right?
What?
What are your parachute doesn't go and
the same with the bear attack that bears
coming in.
You have no.
If you have a gun,
you're focused on your task and then if
the bear got you crushed your head,
maybe you have that task to focus on,
but you're focusing on the inevitable is
going to happen.
There's nothing I can do.
I don't like that thought.
It's the worst.
They are crazy animals.
They're nuts.
Been a Adam Green tree who were talking
about before the podcast,
did this 28 day backpack trip in Montana
and Colorado and elk hunting in
September and a solo all by himself and
took a bunch of instagram pictures and
putting them on instagram story of him
holding up a pistol with a sow.
Grizzly standing on two legs,
looking at them in the distance while
it's snowing out and she got within 15
yards.
She bluff,
charged them within 15 yards.
She's just trying to get them away from
her cubs.
Different situation than with with you
guys because the sow when they have the
cubs will just try it.
They just don't want their kids to get
fucked up by you.
They don't want you anywhere near them,
so they try to scare you off.
There's Adam.
Yeah,
I remember.
I saw that.
That was crazy.
Yeah,
that was in Montana I think.
Look at the bottom,
bottom comments,
some dickhead Chutney.
Ninety four.
You are a current and then his next
comment.
Hashtag Vegan.
Hashtag animal rights.
Hilarious.
You fucking idiots.
I hope that guy gets eaten.
Yeah,
it's really.
I don't really know what you get eaten
Chinese,
but you silly.
Fuck.
Yeah.
It's not a fun feeling.
Those bluff charges are still extremely
scary because you never know if that's
going to be the one.
Yeah.
They said
10 has had quite a few lately.
You know,
there was a really crazy video where the
guy had half his head hanging off,
like a scalp was hanging off his head
and he was explaining what happened and
bit his arm and he apparently was just
was just scouting
and that guy if I recollect right.
I think that was him.
He was kind of one of those guys that I
think even my taught classes on bear
safety and other stuff like that.
And I think afterwards he said,
yeah,
it's a fucked up deal.
Happens.
Well,
he was lucky he had a backpack on
apparently because he was down and the
thing was just tearing them apart and.
But he was,
you know,
pedal in the backpack.
So a few years ago when I was in Alaska,
I met this guy and he was an older guy,
I don't know if I talked about this
before,
but he was a older guy that was on that
same island and he got attacked by a,
I think it was like an 11 foot brown
bear while you're skinning a deer and
killed the bear with a knife.
But he got destroyed.
Yeah.
Killed it with a buck knife.
He's,
he's probably 80 something now.
Uh,
there used to be.
I remembered reading stories about it
and outdoor life magazine when I was a
kid and then somehow I got to kind of
interview them and get
the whole story firsthand and recorded
it on a video and stuff.
Where's the video?
Um,
I've just got it on my hard drive.
I'll,
I'm going to do something with it.
Yeah,
I got it.
I'll put it out this year is cool.
How big was the knife?
Uh,
it was a 500.
Says yes.
Six inch buck knife,
something like that.
You know,
the black handle kind of almost like a.
yeah,
like a solid straight blade knife.
Yeah,
and the bear like attacked him.
He kept stabbing it,
fighting it off.
Um,
what does this.
Yeah,
that's the video.
That's your video.
No,
that's not my video.
Oh,
that's the guy.
That's the guy.
That little tiny knife,
that little thing.
Oh my God,
that's not a big knife.
No.
So where did he kill it?
Uh,
he stabbed it.
It was like he kept getting it in neck
and then the bear would go off and then
charge him again.
And then finally the bear went off.
He said it was pretty sick,
like getting wobbly every time you
attack it'd be less and less.
And then I think he actually grabbed his
rifle and shot it last time we,
a bear was laying there because he was
able to get the bear away.
He was,
he,
he was really fucked up.
And there's a part of the story.
So there's a cabin there that I've
actually been by.
They got him to that cabin and they had
the cabin.
They have these things called Arctic
doors where it's a to keep the cold out
when you open the door,
it's like a two door system.
Well,
the way that the Arctic doors set up,
the emergency responders couldn't get a
Gurney in there,
so the owner of the cab and rips out a
chainsaw and cuts his wall open low to
get say I mean saved his life because
then they got the Gurney in the coast
guard got him out.
He was in the hospital for a long time.
Skin graft after skin graph and all
kinds of surgeries and he survived.
The problem with those stories is that
gives me hope.
I always have these stupid fantasies,
like if a mountain lion ever comes after
me,
I'm going to stab it in the net.
You want to put my arm in its mouth and
think about.
Yeah.
You think about all that stuff until
it's just right on top of you.
Yeah.
Oh Shit.
None of this is going to work.
I'm looking up at the thousand pounds,
so I think.
No Way.
I think we're.
I mean,
I know we're really weak,
like we were so weak,
you know,
strong person is really,
really.
Exactly.
You feel really strong up until the
point.
This breaths on you.
I'm going to happen.
When I was on news radio,
we did a scene once with a chimpanzee.
I don't know everything you've ever made
air.
I think it got edited out,
but we had a baby chimp.
It was a tiny champ like I think it
might've even had a diaper on,
but this little chimp I'm was like two
years old or something like that and it
was on top of me playing around with me,
you know,
like you want hold them accountable,
hold
it and I'm holding it and it
just hits me a couple times on the back.
Just fucking decides to smack me a
little bit like a puppy and I just
couldn't believe how fucking strong this
little thing I had in my mind like,
like you think of a chimp that's like 30
pounds or 50 pounds.
You Go,
oh,
that's like a person that's 30 pounds or
50 pounds.
Like it is a totally different thing.
Like it's body was hard,
like would like,
it felt like this table,
like everything was hard.
Like you have it in your mind like,
oh that skin and muscle,
that's like my skin and muscle.
No,
no.
Crazy.
There's so.
There's so much stronger and they ain't
shit compared to a bear
little baby chimpanzee in a day.
It's so crazy how weak we are.
I mean,
it's amazing how our brains and the
development of our intellect and our
ability to use tools and houses have
protected us from all these animals.
And I wonder what we used to be like.
I was thinking about that the other day
and I was kind of debating in my head
whether our tools.
I think our tools are the only thing we
hide behind him.
Oh,
for sure.
I think that's the only thing that kept
us alive for so long.
I wonder what we used to be like though.
I wonder if before the tools we were
more like the chimps,
maybe why we,
we,
uh,
we were showing photos of Australia
[inaudible],
which is like one of the oldest human
beings and it looks kinda like a chimp
person,
you know,
it's all covered in hair.
Oh,
I'm sure they,
they weren't very big.
You know,
it's about chimps size,
maybe a little bit of the underdog.
The underdog is apparently we're only
like five feet tall,
but they weighed 200 pounds.
Really?
Yeah.
Five,
four,
maybe something like that.
Probably guerrilla type drink.
Stupid Jack.
Giant bones like probably waste stronger
than us.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
We just figured out a way to build stuff
and I guess we just got soft.
Yeah.
And the way it's amazing that we made it
this far though.
What do you think bears like that and
all the various animals that we must
have encountered along the way.
I think that's why when the pioneers
came West,
they thought,
let's get rid of all the bears.
I see why they got rid of the bears.
Imagine those guys back then cruising
crossed the plains and constantly being
attacked constantly.
They had a legit fear of bears.
Oh yeah.
Because it wasn't.
We don't understand it in our society of
having these natural predators be actual
threats to you in your daily life.
Yeah.
Well,
not only that,
but back then they didn't even have like
a real legit map of the territory.
No,
they were just trying to figure it out
as they went along.
Cruising around,
stumbling in the stomach thing and yeah.
Well the last guy in California to be
killed by a bear.
They named the town after him.
It's a out near Bakersfield.
It was the last guy in California to get
killed by a grizzly bear,
which is interesting is that's the
California state flag as a grizzly bear
on it,
but we killed all of them.
You're like,
fuck this.
Well,
I feel like the California grizzly bears
I.
This is just from my opinion,
it would have been semi coastal,
so they would've been very similar to
the brown bears with a mild climate.
They probably would not have needed to
hibernate,
like they would have been very large
bears.
We should reintroduce him though.
I'm all for that.
Well,
I think there's probably some people
that would agree with you.
Yeah.
A lot of the people that want to
reintroduce wolves everywhere I say for
everyone they reintroduced somewhere
else.
Let's reintroduce a bear somewhere.
You know,
in the Monterrey San Francisco area
where they naturally were all those
cmos.
Jesus Christ.
Imagine I couldn't.
I couldn't.
Yeah,
I think people really have no idea what
that is.
They think of it as some sort of a thing
that they've seen on,
you know,
the discovery channel or some cool
youtube video or you see them wandering
to the fields,
but until you're there with it,
well it was going to say about with Adam
said,
like Adam said,
he's like Mike.
He goes,
he gets a fucking monster monster.
he goes,
people are out there looking for
monsters.
He goes,
that fucking real.
He goes most as a real.
He goes,
he goes,
it's not their fault that the monsters
put that fucking month is the worst.
Adam Green spot on impression,
that was exactly like him.
He's around me.
I could do it better.
Might have that thing where they talk.
Well at the end they've always goes up,
but he was talking about out.
It was charging him from 15 yards.
He could see the muscles and the hair
was standing straight up and it was
looking at him and rippling and he was
saying is this it?
And then he found out later that the gun
had the wrong bullets in it.
That's crazy.
So the bullets were too big for the gun
and the only way it would have worked as
if he got one in the chamber.
He had,
he couldn't cock it to put one in the
chamber.
He would have had to individually put
one in the chamber and then who had had
one shot?
Yeah,
that wouldn't work too.
Oh yeah.
The weird.
I remember it almost seemed like slow
motion.
The way that hair is just waving back
and forth.
This shouldn't be locking eyes with it.
I just saw one grizzly once ever in the
wild at close range in Alberta and it
wasn't a big one.
It was like maybe six,
six and a half feet,
but they'll look.
It gave me,
was so different than,
look black bears give you.
Yeah.
This is the zero fucks look.
They just know.
You just look at you.
They look through you through you.
Yeah.
Look at you like your food to figure out
if it was going to eat me and how it was
going to eat me.
It wasn't looking at me like I was
scary.
Like black bears look at you like,
what are you doing man?
I'm like,
can I come over here?
They bought smell you.
I'm Outta here.
And then they take off.
But the,
the grizzly was just looking at me like
these marble eyes like black.
Yup.
Those eyes man dead.
They are dead eyes man.
Like Shark
eyes.
Yup.
Yeah,
it's nuts.
They,
uh,
with all the ones,
all the videos you see bears tear in.
That cap might preserve where they've
just eating fish and they're chomping.
Oh,
the young ones because they have food.
Now.
Imagine,
imagine if you just took all those fish
away and put one person there.
That's the look that those bears would
have just completely changed.
Yeah,
we.
We showed a video of that.
Pull that video up.
Jamie have that.
There's a crazy video of this guy who's
a photographer who's taking pictures of
what it looks like.
15 plus brown bears and this one river
and one of them walks up beside them and
just sits down,
like literally sit down about 10 feet
away and apparently this one particular
area is so rich with salmon.
No one's ever been killed there.
Yeah,
that's.
That's probably the.
I think it's kept my preserve.
I think that that's what they call it,
but now you have to get permits because
it's just such a popular place.
You go and you fly in there and you just
take pictures of the bears and they're
just.
They have so much food and there are so
habituated that they don't.
But if you took the food source away,
yeah.
This is it.
Look at the size of that thing.
See that gun sitting there?
That's not what you want to do.
I've decided,
yeah,
that seems like an issue.
It's
go over and grab that gun,
you know,
buddy for your launch or you'd be.
You'd be so crushed before he even got
to that and it's given me some volumes
so you could see it
here at breathing.
Let me that thing.
Fucking arms on that thing.
What is the name of this video,
Jamie?
So we can give the people credit.
Says bear sits next to guy
it just sitting now.
Is that bigger or smaller than the bear
that attacked you guys?
That's probably smaller.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah,
that's.
Leave that thing.
I mean that's.
That's a like,
that's not a very old bear there to see.
I was chest is kind of smaller up in the
top I guess.
Yeah.
This video freaks me the fuck out
though,
that this bear was just sitting right
next to this guy,
but I mean you look at that and they
just look so peaceful.
Nice.
You wouldn't ever think it's two
completely different worlds.
When you go to somewhere like this.
Now you see how close that thing is now
in that video,
it just looks like a docile,
fuzzy animal.
Now Watch this,
look down there
bed so crazy.
That is literally like 15
huge fucking bears.
Just pulling salmon out of that river.
Yeah,
that's not.
I mean I think they're beautiful.
I think they're amazing and I'm glad
they're there,
but it disturbs me to no end that people
don't really understand what they are
and they treat them as if there's some
sort of a mythical creature in some
Disneyland movie and they don't.
They don't understand conservation and
controlling their populations,
which is what they did understand when
they killed them all out of California.
They were like,
look,
people are getting fucking killed at a
regular basis.
This is a is a real problem
and now British Columbia's in this weird
situation,
my friend Michael Hockridge lives up in
the woods in British Columbia.
He lives in the real,
the real BC,
but the population centers,
all Vancouver Vancouver,
which is this amazing city,
great restaurants and everybody's like,
what killed baron?
Fuck that.
You don't need to kill the bears,
but if you fly in to where my friend
Mike Lives and talk,
those people out there,
they can,
first of all,
they can hunt as many wolves as they
want.
You could shoot 100 loaves a day.
Yeah.
There's no lack of wolves.
There is.
They're everywhere.
We heard them,
you know,
I didn't,
I didn't see one when I was up there,
but you could hear him off in the
distance,
but he said that he's got one in his
house that jumped at him.
He shot in the air,
jumping off of a ridge at him.
Wow.
Yeah.
He was making a Predator call and this
wolf closed in on him and literally
jumped at him and he shot it in the air.
So in his house he's got his house like
this.
He's got the wolf mounted like in the
same position it was in when it was
trying to eat him.
Yeah,
that's great.
People.
People have to realize that like,
I love wolves,
don't get me wrong,
but you know,
once I started hunting and then I
started really looking into wildlife
conservation and then the consequences
of letting apex predators get out of
control.
Like it's scary.
Yeah.
The,
the wolves I've never really been afraid
of,
but I did one time I was in Idaho is
springtime and I heard something in the
real thick brush again and here's
something and all of a sudden this wolf
pops out like five or six feet away,
just fold dead run.
And I like freak out.
Hey,
I was about ready to kick it and it
veered off the path and then I hear and
then another one comes running in and I
grabbed my gun and shooting the ground,
not when it like from me to you,
Jesus Christ.
And uh,
and it ran off.
But I didn't know.
My initial thought was they were just
chasing each other playing and I just
happened to be in their way,
but I don't know,
you might've been lunch.
Who knows?
And maybe I scared it because I had
this.
Well,
they hung them in Idaho,
so they probably,
this was before you can hunt them.
Oh,
okay.
I was just an,
I had a,
you know,
like got my gun off after the first one
was just thinking,
well,
I don't know what's going on here,
but just in case some trays,
you know,
John has a crazy story.
You ever talked to him about it?
No,
we talked to.
He told us on the podcast.
But um,
there's a video if anybody wants to
listen to the actual story on the
podcast,
you can find it.
But he shot a wolf.
Excuse me.
He shot an elk in a pc,
you know,
and uh,
oh no.
Our Alberta Alberta thing was Alberta
shot an elk and um,
didn't realize that where the elk went
down was literally right in a wolf's
den.
Oh Wow.
There was these bones around and shit.
It was literally like a scene from that
movie,
the gray,
like it's like broken jack bottles.
So it was him and John only has a four
Arrow quiver,
right?
Yeah.
He shot one arrow which used to take
down the elk.
So he's got three hours left and he's
got a guide with them and the guide has
a rifle,
but the guide only has a handful of
bullets.
He's got like three or four bullets.
So they're standing there,
they're trying to take this elk out
there,
quartering it up,
and then we'll start circling them and
howling and then they realize like,
oh fuck,
like we're literally in the wolf's den
and one wolf makes a dead run out of
them.
He kills it with his bow.
Another wolf makes a dead run at it.
They shoot it,
another wolf comes down,
he shoots it with the rifle.
So John is shot to have his bow and the
other guy shot one with a rifle.
John's down to one Arrow and the other
guy has like maybe two bullets.
Wow.
And they're freaking the fuck out.
They have their back to a tree and
wolves are circling them and they're
howling because they've already lost
three wolves.
Yeah.
So he's literally getting charged by
wolves with his back to a tree with a
giant elk carcass behind them that
they're trying to claim.
That's crazy.
Crazy.
He said the Alpha male was standing on a
ridge.
He drew back,
uh,
on the,
on the wolf.
The Wolf looked at him and bolted and
took off in.
The rest of them took off.
Yeah,
but he said they were circling them
howling from like doing like a roll
call.
I try to see who's still alive like
what's going on here,
but even after a gunshot and two of them
killed with arrows,
they were still chart.
That's crazy.
Fuck Huh.
Two great story.
It's terrifying.
But just to let you know,
like people think,
oh well was don't harm people.
In World War II,
the Russians and the Germans had to call
a ceasefire because so many people were
getting killed by wolves.
They decided to call a ceasefire,
killed a wolves,
and then go back to killing each other.
That's crazy.
It's a crazy story.
World War One or two.
I think it's one to the two like fed on
the dead people.
Well,
I think there were so many wolves like
Siberia or Russia or wherever the fuck
they were.
There's a lot of walls,
you know,
and they don't give a shit if you're a
person or a chicken and they're here to
just go for it.
Yeah,
I mean it's cold.
It's tough.
Tough.
Tough living is one.
It was one.
So where we're one.
Yeah.
But um,
but it's a confirmed story.
I mean they were just,
guys would go out on scouts and they
would just vanished and then they find a
boot with like half a foot still in it
and like fuck.
And people don't realize like a wolf can
cut through an elk bone with its teeth.
Yeah.
When you,
when you see a wolf actually take down
and now it's pretty impressive if you've
seen it live.
Yeah,
I've seen it.
I've seen a single scene,
a single take down,
a spike elk ones.
And what it did was just so fast to.
It ran in and ran it downhill.
They're so smart too,
but it was the ELC was on a ridge.
The Wolf start chasing it down and it
starts chasing the elk through what we
call dead,
where a bunch of trees have fallen over.
So the ELC has to exert itself and jump
over things and then the wolves would
come in and bite its back legs and that
how old was so fast,
it could run almost between its legs.
Is that elks running?
I mean it was crazy.
And then it got it stomach open so it's
dragging its guts and then the,
the elk finally would get its guts
caught on the trees that it was going
over and then got it by the neck and
just held it until it died.
When you saw this from,
how far away?
Um,
I don't know,
probably 300 yards maybe.
Wow.
Yeah,
a lot of it.
Some of it you couldn't see,
you know,
it'd be because it was a hill across
from me.
So you could see it,
you lose it in the timber and then it
come out in the patch and then it was
right below us and then we just kinda
backed out and left it to them.
Dudley saw a grizzly bear swat the moose
down with one shot.
Really?
He said that the grizzly literally
lifted up.
It's.
Paul was chasing the Moose and slammed
it on the Moose back and broke.
It's back.
We're going,
yeah.
That's how strong a fucking grizzly
bears.
He said you couldn't use it.
It's like to to see it is like to see it
as one thing,
but to try to describe it as like
there's no way I want to describe
because the amount of power that thing
had and it's Paul.
He goes,
it just gives you a totally different
perception of what it's capable of.
You know,
you have an idea while the grizzlies big
and the Moose is big kind of a bra.
Nope.
Swats it.
Boom.
Just snap down.
Most just went like he got shot.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
When you see the power of you think,
yeah,
I don't know.
The whole getting scratched things
probably that's not happening and
getting scratched.
You're getting tore up.
So in BC they've recently,
they passed two laws.
The first law they pass,
they were going to outlaw trophy hunts.
So what they said is,
because eating black bear is a
traditional thing.
A lot of people eat black pair and a lot
of people that are that don't hunt or
don't have anything to do with hunting.
Don't know this,
but black bear is eaten by a lot of
people.
Yeah.
Grizzly bears not eating as much,
but some people eat it.
A lot of the indigenous people eat it or
whether they call first nations in
Canada day,
they'll eat brown bear,
some of them will,
but they decided no more quote unquote
trophy hunts so you can't keep the skin
and you couldn't keep the head,
but you could keep the meat.
Okay.
So it was a weird,
weird law that got passed and people
like,
well that doesn't make any sense because
people.
I understand that they would want the
people to only hunt for meat.
That makes sense,
but why not allow them to keep the skull
and keep the Cape and all that other
stuff too.
And it was useful.
It's wasteful.
Yeah.
Then they changed it entirely and they
said no grizzly hunts at all and it was
really quickly the one,
one law changed and
changed and they based it on a really
small sampling like the,
the um,
they had like a,
I think it was an email sample.
Pretty Bowman has a thing on it.
They did a podcast on it,
but they explained how it went down that
it wasn't,
they said 75 percent of the population
degrees,
but it's not really 75 percent of the
population.
Seventy five percent of the 3000 people
that got responded to the email and,
or online petition or whatever the fuck
it was,
but they have a problem now.
These people that actually live there,
like my friend Mike,
it's like,
okay,
if you're,
if you're not going to control the
populations of them,
like Mike had to shoot one that
literally had its face in his cabin.
He opened the door.
It was literally,
he shot it like we're literally right
there where you are.
It was trying to come in his cabin and
he shot it.
Yeah.
I think that the reason there's,
I've I've heard that there's more people
are attacked or affected by black bears
and grizzly bears or brown bears,
but it's just not as many people live in
proximity to them.
If you put a major metropolitan area in
the middle of fog,
neck island,
people will be getting jacked all the
time.
Yeah,
and that's what's going on.
Also in Montana,
I mean when,
when these most recent attacks,
it's just because there's a large
population of bears there and you can
hunt them and the good thing is that
people hunted them almost to the brink
of extinction and now through
conservation they brought them back to
the point where they're no longer
endangered,
but there's the dispute between the
animal rights people and the wildlife
biologist and the hunters and you know,
trying to figure out what,
what,
how big does the population you have to
be before you realize that you have to
chop some of them down.
Like you don't.
Nobody wants to eliminate grizzly bears,
but you don't want 100,000 grizzly bears
in the metropolitan thing
area.
Yeah.
And it's,
it's a weird.
It's kind of a weird balance when you
check them out,
hunting an animal populations,
and then you throw in predators,
because I don't think a lot of people
even understand how humans have affected
the environment in such a negative way
that nothing will ever be as it was,
right?
People go,
oh,
well the predators will control the prey
populations,
and so why would we need to control the
predators?
Well,
we,
we've upset the balance in such a way
that if we don't insert ourself into the
equation,
which is far as we know humans have been
in the equation,
hunting since the animals that are in
currently in North America have been
around.
Brown birds have always been hunted by
humans.
You know,
when you're looking at the way things
were,
I mean indigenous people on it.
Um,
people before,
you know,
settlers and whatever came in the bears
were being hunted.
So humans,
we're always a natural Predator of the
bears.
But the way that humans have affected
the landscape between obviously taking
up habitat and habitat and the number
one thing is habitat is gone.
Invasive plant species is crazy.
The type of plants that grow in places
they shouldn't be.
Now we'll never get rid of those plants.
So because those plants are there,
native plants that the animals
originally should be eating off of don't
exist.
They out competed by noxious weeds and
other things.
So the amount of food sources smaller.
So then the,
the prey population cannot there.
They've lost their winter range because
of developments and other things.
And then if you just inserted it and
said,
well,
all the predators will take care of
those numbers still.
Well that's not true because the numbers
can't get to what they were because
there's less availability starting at
the bottom level of food source and
winter range and habitat.
So what do you do about that?
I mean,
is that,
is it possible to kill all the invasive
plants?
No,
it's not possible.
Not even close.
No.
I mean there's.
There's no way that like where I'm from
Nevada,
he talked about invasive plants.
There's species of grass cheat grass
fires,
wiped through the native grasses.
Can't compete with that.
So the cheat grass takes over.
It has less nutrients and doesn't have
the same type of browse that the native
deer and whatever species,
deer and elk need mostly meal deer cheat
grass coming from.
Somebody brought it over because of was
ornamental and it's just gone rampant.
Most of our plants aren't native plants
now it.
Oh yeah.
You look at.
Yeah.
Most of the plants that take over or are
invasive plants.
Yeah.
Our countries primarily invasive
species.
Maybe someone will call me out on that.
Say That's not true,
but there's more invasive plants.
The native plants.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
The grasses,
most of the grasses that we have around
aren't from the regions.
Kentucky bluegrass in California.
Does it make sense?
Well,
it's always fascinating to me when an
animal gets into an area where it
doesn't have natural predators,
like a nutria.
Yeah.
Like nutri is down south and they just
have to hunt those things.
Like all over the place.
These giant rat thing.
Yeah.
Well,
I was just.
We're in Maui hunting access,
dear said,
the populations,
they're just have exploded.
Oh yeah.
It was.
No,
they don't have predators and all the
native species actually are being
negatively affected by the invasive
species.
Now,
were you there?
Um,
how,
how recently?
Was this yesterday?
Yesterday.
Yeah.
Oh,
so you just got back?
Yeah,
well I got back.
What is it like in relationship to where
we hunted in Lanai?
It's very,
it's very similar.
Different,
different terrain,
little more mountainous terrain.
Um,
so probably kind of cooler.
Yeah,
lot of lava,
a lot.
A lot of rock and cliffs and some other
stuff that goes to the ocean.
Um,
and then there's,
there's kind of all different.
There's more of a dry side of the
island.
It's more of that law of a type terrain.
And you've got bamboo forest on the
other side.
Once the deer get into that thick bamboo
type forest,
they'll never eradicate them.
Same with the pigs and everything.
They just can't get them out of there.
Yeah.
Well the good news is they've instituted
a hunters for the hungry type program
in,
in Maui,
right?
Correct.
Yeah.
So one of my,
one of my buddies that don't with every
there,
robin,
he,
he started getting some of that rolling
where they could go on the ranch's,
shoot the deer off the excess deer and
then give them the people that need
food.
God's amazing.
Which they should be able to.
Sure why,
why not?
It's,
it's the some of the best tasting meat
there is.
And they're overrun with these animals.
Yeah.
That's an argument for hunting.
It's really difficult for animal rights
people to argue against because you
already have this invasive species
that's overpopulating this island and
you're going to bring in wolves,
which is another invasive species,
which isn't that similar to what they
tried to do in Australia?
Yeah,
Australia.
They started to try to bring in a bunch
of stuff.
I wish was here.
They brought foxes and cats,
but the foxes and cats.
Well you've got these marsupials that
are slow and lay eggs and don't run
away.
The rats rats hide and her fast
platypuses don't nesting bird ground
nesting birds,
all that stuff.
So they just hammer the native species
and then the invasive rats and mice
still just take a toll on everything.
Yeah.
What is the solution to a place like
Lanai,
other than hunting?
I mean you'd have to give the deer birth
control or bringing predators or poison
or poison.
So they use that.
They use fair talks in New Zealand.
Oh God.
You imagine just,
they,
they use,
uh,
a poison called tent and they will,
the fair tax is mostly for a possums
that they use a,
a poison called 10 80 and it's serial
poisoning.
So they essentially cold cereal,
which would be like grains and rice and
other things with this extremely deadly
poison.
And then they just dump it out of
helicopters into the forest.
It doesn't discriminate.
No.
Just whatever's local as well.
Correct.
And you're,
you're putting.
I mean,
you're,
you're dumping poison.
It's crazy.
It's going to get into the ground water.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's so stupid.
What kind of,
what kind of solution is that?
If you think hunting's bad,
that poison is not an easy death.
No,
no,
it's awful.
It takes a long time too.
And the thing is,
again,
like you said,
that the meat is delicious if you just,
if they just had a program where they
went to Lanai and just shot animals just
for,
for hungry people in la who are in Maui
and they could have a lot of amazing
meals for people.
Oh yeah.
And not even just here.
What about sending that freezing it
somehow sending it other places in the
world?
Yeah,
we're doing that with other places in
New Zealand,
Australia,
whatever,
setting up programs like that.
Well,
people like that fellow,
that was the con Hashtag animal rights
and Hashtag Vegan.
This is,
this is where they run into a wall,
like an ideological wall.
Like what do you think should happen to
wild pigs?
Like what do you think should happen?
You think they should just go
run rampant and destroy all the other
wildlife.
They're not just an invasive species,
but a ruthlessly reproducing invasive.
Yeah.
And they can outcompete other things.
So by leaving one thing,
you're,
you're killing something else.
There's always,
there's always this weird trade off
where for some one thing to exist,
something else has to die.
Yeah,
that's unfortunate,
but that's just how the world is.
If you don't like the way the world
works socks,
it's kind of unfortunate,
but it's also kind of.
Look,
it's the way it is.
Yeah,
and I don't.
I don't want that elk to get killed by
that wolf,
but I would have loved to see it happen.
It's going to happen.
Exactly.
I mean,
we,
you got to see in my,
in my opinion,
you got to see something really fucking
amazing.
Oh yeah.
What are the odds that you're there?
Right?
When a wolf takes out an elk.
Yeah.
Not Very.
Not very likely.
Yeah.
Cam hands posted a few things.
We did that Una el con concerned.
Oh good.
Yeah.
Great.
Yeah,
that was great.
But Cam posted a bunch of videos because
a bunch of people were,
you know,
it's always gonna bunch of people
complaining about hunting.
Yeah.
What?
He posted a bunch of videos about bears
and one of them was a bear eating a big
grizzly eating this elk calf while it
was alive while the mother was off just
like just a 30 yards away,
freaking the fuck out.
And she's watching this big old grizzly
just tear her and it's going making
weird noises where it just gets mauled
and you know,
I don't want that to happen,
but it's going to happen and it's not.
I'm not happy that it's happening,
but it's fascinating to watch.
Like if I was there,
I would definitely watch that.
Yeah.
I mean it's just like it's live.
But I think that is the real ideological
argument and this is where like the
Vegan people fall short.
It's like I understand that you don't
want to kill animals.
You don't have to.
I understand that you don't want factory
farming.
I don't want it either.
I don't want any of that stuff.
But this is a.
you're dealing with a different thing
and it's,
it's a smaller thing,
like the amount of people that are
hunting for food and managing wildlife
and controlling populations too small.
It's a smaller thing than the amount of
people that actually eat meat.
But to target that.
Like you,
you're literally targeting the one thing
that's been thought out the most.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
You've created,
we've created these systems that we're
okay with yet if you really look at it,
they're just fucking weird.
Yeah.
No farming of animals.
We've done.
We've done that for a very long time,
but the way that we do it now is just
some kind of different strategies.
Yeah.
It's,
it's different.
You know,
you're putting things in your body that
shouldn't be there when you can go out.
I can go and shoot a Caribou that's
never had.
It's only been eating native grasses on
the Tundra and it's completely wild and
healthy in my body.
Even feels different when I eat
that sort of stuff.
Yeah.
Same with elk,
right?
Yeah.
And um,
I get their argument that not everybody
could do that.
You're right.
Not everybody would do it again,
but guess what?
Not Everybody is going to do a lot of
things.
It's hard to do.
It's not,
it's not an easy thing to do.
It's not easy to get a bow and Arrow and
go into the mountains and find an elk
and shoot it and then pack it out.
And most people are just,
they're not going to do that.
No.
And I think if you,
if you really.
Well I think it was kind of cool this,
this,
the last week I took my fiance hunting.
It was their first time hunting.
Really?
Yeah.
I mean like where she was hunting.
Oh,
okay.
So she's been with you before when you
were hunting?
Yeah.
But like when are you doing?
Are you done?
Yeah,
exactly.
But you know,
over the years she's seen me go,
okay.
She gets it,
she enjoys eating the meat.
She has always,
you know,
when we first started dating or ever
said,
oh,
I could never kill anything.
And I understood that not everyone can,
but through the process of watching what
I do,
the respect that I have for the animals
and going,
okay,
this isn't as bad as I had always
thought it was nothing.
It was bad.
But she gave it a try and just like,
okay.
And then when we,
you know,
she,
the first time she killed something she
cried a little bit.
But immediately after she was like,
I'm actually really excited.
I'm really happy that I got this,
this deer,
and then last night we cooked it up for
dinner.
When we got home.
She's like,
it does taste better.
I was like,
yeah,
because this is your dear.
This is you provided this meal for us.
This is your and well now you're a part
of it.
It's not.
You didn't go by that you killed it
yourself.
You knew what that deer was and you just
respect it a lot more now because you
were a part of that process.
You had to struggle a little bit.
We almost didn't get one.
You went through the whole thing of.
Well,
you know the whole process of it.
It's completely different.
It's just a different thing that when
you're eating the food.
Yeah.
When you buy a steak from a supermarket,
you have zero connection with that other
than the fact that he had to work to pay
for it.
You know,
you go to a restaurant,
you have even less because you're not
even cooking it and they just sit down
there.
Yeah,
I'll have the t bone.
Medium rare please,
and then it comes back.
We'll looks good.
Shopped up,
trump,
you know,
but when you do it yourself,
you know when you,
you described it once,
I think a great way like that.
When you pull out an elk stack from an
you shot,
it's almost like a sacred.
Oh yeah,
like you're holding it like a baby.
You will.
You've just,
you've worked.
So you just appreciate everything.
You work hard for it.
It's also that you were there,
like you understand this when you're
eating that meal,
that meal has a memory attached to it.
Whereas effort attached to it,
it has a comprehension.
You understand the process,
you understand where the Arrow went.
You understand the blood trail,
you under your,
you were there when you quartered it.
The whole thing is like,
it's all coming back to you as you're
eating.
There's no way you could reproduce that
without actually doing it.
I
know,
and there's,
there's that value when you look at.
We even just having a set of antlers
around people might,
they don't hunt think,
oh,
that's just trophy.
It's glorifying it,
but after the meats gone,
you're still in remembrance of that
animal.
Oh yeah.
It's like a very deep process
that you take with you for a long time.
Yeah,
no doubt.
I have my first elk that I shot on my
wall at my house.
The only one that my wife lets me put up
with the first shot over the bow and I.
I walked by that thing all the time and
I just.
I remember the whole experience.
I remember bugling coming up the hill.
I remember hiding behind the tree.
I remember drawing back.
I remember waiting till I could see it's
vitals.
I remember the Arrow hitting it.
I remember going,
Holy Shit,
we're watching it stumble.
I remember going down a vivid,
like super vivid and vivid in a way that
not a lot of memories are because it's
so primal because it's a life and death
and I,
I think,
I mean,
I'm not a neuroscientist obviously,
but there's some shit that's turning on
in your head that's like from the
caveman days when you shoot an elk with
a bow and Arrow and you see it go down,
you realize you like you're going to eat
this thing.
Like they're,
it's very,
it's very interesting.
It's almost like the way I am.
There's certain experiences in life
where once those experiences happen,
you go,
Whoa,
I didn't even know that that was a part
of my brain.
Oh yeah.
Being a father is that way in a more
intense way.
Like once you have kids and then you
realize like how much you love your kids
are like,
wow,
this is,
this is a part of my brain that I didn't
even know was there.
And that was like fully lit up and
overcoming all of my senses and
thoughts.
You know,
there's um,
some sort of strange deep connection
that we have.
And I always tell people like a good way
to let's that you,
you sort of feel that in a mild way
without too much craziness is fishing.
Yeah.
When you catch a fish,
like,
oh,
we got decided,
oh Jesus,
he's.
There's this weird sort of excitement to
it.
But people don't have a problem with
dead fish.
No.
Yeah,
it's weird because fish don't have faces
or something like title,
like your dog.
Something that you maybe just because
nothing you don't cuddle fish or
something.
Yeah,
it's in the water fish.
So the difference.
Yeah,
it's
in the water.
It's in a different world.
Yeah.
There's something that we have about and
then.
But then there's other animals.
So we're super racist when
it comes to animals over share,
like rats.
I don't give a fuck about.
Rats kills things gusting because they
have hair everywhere but their tail.
So it's just slimy ass fucking rep type
retail.
Yeah.
But you know,
something cute like a chip on click on a
little fella.
It was funny because today on my
instagram page,
I,
because I was doing some spear fishing
and stuff,
I caught an octopus and when to kill an
octopus,
you swim,
you bite their skull to kill him.
Really?
Yeah.
Skull.
It's right between their eyes.
It's where their,
I guess their brain is.
You bite them between the eyes because
otherwise it moves around too much,
so it's hard to cause an octopus.
They just latch on to everything.
You have to bite it.
You can't stab it there.
It'd be really hard to undo.
I'm trying to move and it's got,
you know,
it can is you stick the knife and it
would move around.
So everybody does it that way.
You always bite?
Yeah,
for the most part.
So you just write eyes and you feel the
school and you bite down and crush it.
Nobody had has a problem with you biting
an octopus in the head at least not yet.
Probably fucking smart,
man.
This guy's got one.
Yeah,
that dude's a kiwis.
Whoa.
That guy's an animal.
Jesus Christ.
Imagine if you're that poor octopus is
fucking savage with a beard.
Brian is my is running around before
now.
Wow.
And the thing is,
yeah,
nobody gives a shit about that.
But the thing is octopus are smart as
fuck.
They're weird.
Weird,
smart.
Yeah.
We've talked about that before.
Just the way that they hide the way that
they do stuff.
Well,
your show that you.
You're not doing anymore,
right?
Yeah.
Creditor Apex Predator was a great show
and one of the things that were for
people don't know what it was.
You traveled all over the place and
tried to learn from the way different
animals would hunt things.
But yeah,
I remember when you came in here and you
were talking about octopus.
I didn't.
By the way.
You can say octopuses and you could say
Octopi.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Whatever you want it both ways.
But I had no idea like when you came in
here like,
dude,
they're not even from this planet.
They're like aliens.
Yeah,
they're weird.
But they,
uh,
they are smart,
but in the ocean they're definitely at
the bottom of the food chain.
Are they really?
But they kill sharks will the big ones,
the little ones,
everything eats them.
Really.
If you're an octopus,
you are.
You are a savory dish for every fish I
guess are quite delicious.
Yeah.
When you're fishing,
that kind of octopus for bait works
better than anything.
Really.
Yeah.
These fish,
that's actually how he saw the one that
I got.
I swam down to go shoot a fishing,
usually pecking at it because they get
into the reef and just keep going for it
until it gets out of their spear.
Phishing is supposed to be really fun.
It's like hunting underwater.
It's.
Yeah,
it's really fun.
I.
You'd enjoy it.
I think you dig the hole.
You got to go that one of the best
things I've ever done in my life was
that free diving essentially like as
free diving class.
But that's one of the coolest things
when I guarantee you'd be able to hold
your breath for four minutes or so and
after you do that,
you think like,
shit,
I can do anything.
It's weird.
It's a weird feeling.
That was one of the coolest things that
I did and I did it on that apex
predators show.
That's what he did it for.
But then since then I've been doing
quite a bit of,
as much as I can,
try to go diving and spear fishing.
And the first time you held your breath
you couldn't hold it that long.
And then they told you how to do it.
Just a minute,
a minute,
minute and a half,
something like.
So what was the difference?
It's all mental really?
Yeah.
So what did they tell you to concentrate
on?
Just the fact that you aren't going to
die [inaudible] key and relaxing when
your heart rate starts.
So it's more about just controlling
things,
controlling your heart rate and other
stuff.
I'm no expert,
but I'm,
there's people there really have been
spear fishing and diving as much as I go
hunting.
But I try to learn as much as I can when
I'm out with people that know what
they're doing.
And uh,
it's just a cool experience of being
underwater and you get that little bit
of a panic and you start to use your
oxygen and then you just try to relax,
relax,
and you can stay longer.
And sort of this guy does he given you
like techniques,
tech techniques to breathe,
slow your heart rate and then just
knowing the fact of how to hold your
breath,
don't let it out.
And the fact that what your body goes
through the stages that your body goes
through when you are out of oxygen.
So when you get to that end period,
you actually almost feel like you don't
need to breathe.
It's really weird.
Yeah.
And that's when he got to breathe.
That's when you got to breathe.
Because when I,
when I was done doing the four minute
breath,
all that came out.
And the first thing he says,
breathe like x.
They tell you like exhale and breathe.
Because I got up and like,
oh yeah.
And then I'm like,
oh yeah,
shit,
yeah,
I need to breathe.
That's weird.
So is it sort of like hypothermia,
like as you get really,
really cold,
you start heating up?
Um,
oh.
Like you feel the opposite.
Like when people are dying of
hypothermia,
one of the things when they find them,
they took all their clothes off.
Yeah.
It could be something similar to that.
Wow.
I don't know.
Yeah.
So,
um,
when you hold your breath and you'd take
arts,
why is it better to hold your breath and
to have no breath in and just not
breathe because your body needs the
oxygen.
So the big breath like,
yeah,
that's better.
Just hold that.
Yup.
Because I was wondering like how,
what is the record for exhaling is all
your air and then holding your breath
before you take another deep breath.
Wait,
exhaling all your,
all.
You're taking a big deep breath.
Exhaling everything and then holding it
while you have no air in your lungs.
Like how long can you go on for too
long?
Really know you're saying you breathe in
and breathe all the air out and then
stop.
Yep.
Oh,
a few seconds.
Really?
Yeah.
You wouldn't.
Well,
I mean,
not,
not a few seconds.
Maybe a minute it with.
No,
no,
no worry.
Blackout.
Yeah.
Well,
I don't know.
You gotta breathe everything out and
then do 10 jumping jacks.
Oh yeah,
you're fucked.
You know what I mean?
Then there's no way he'd burn it out.
Totally.
Yeah.
Probably.
I'd probably be the fastest way to pass
out of Eagan.
Anyways,
a guy who fought in the UFC and he was a
free dive champion and I believe,
I want to say he went longer than seven
minutes.
Yeah.
In the ocean.
Underwater.
Holding his breath.
Yes,
and people are incredible.
I mean they can go five,
seven that some of that too is building
up your endurance,
but a lot of it is building up your
endurance and just really slowing your
heart rate
and not using up the oxygen that you
have and not freaking out is a freakout.
You get scared,
you're heart rate goes up and you use
them more oxygen.
It's one of those things if you're
running out of gas and you want to speed
up to the gas station and burn more gas
was instead of slow down,
drop it down to 35 and cruise,
you're going to go 70 if he can do to
really fascinating life when it comes to
like your experiences in the wild,
like how old are you?
Thirty five,
33,
33 year old guys have not been to as
many places.
Experiences.
Many wild things as you have.
I mean you've,
you've really had a very,
very unusual life.
That's.
Oh definitely.
Especially with wildlife experience.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean if I look at it,
I've spent the majority of my life out
in the wild.
That's crazy.
We'll normal.
Yeah,
I try.
I'm not honestly not that normal,
but we try to upgrade.
Or You were into you,
you,
you.
Who told you that?
I was him.
It was young.
Yeah.
No,
probably with.
Oh well when I was in middle school,
but friends into it.
You were a dancer,
right?
Didn't you like do like dance
competitions and chill?
I think that's one of those rumors,
you know,
those,
when you get really drunk and you pull
it out,
that party trick that you know when
you're 15 years old and it looks shitty,
but nobody else like,
it's one of those,
it's one of those things because people
like you won't believe it,
but it was like a dance champion of the
world.
Now it's true.
That is like,
that is not anywhere close.
I was in,
some summer was in me and my brother
went to Iceland in the summer when I was
in high school and the person that we
stayed with was like a break dancer and
just taught us how to break dance and
we'd just do it for fun.
It's the only those things you whip out
at like a wedding.
Okay.
So you never went anywhere.
That's hilarious.
That's one of those things that everyone
was one Christmas party with Zpz.
Everyone was just hammered and I
thought,
oh yeah,
someone was trying to do like the white
break dance thing,
which as my version is extremely white
and bad,
but I could do like a few no head spins,
but maybe some wind mills and some cool
stuff,
you know,
that might have been like,
and then it just goes from there.
That's what happened because the rumor
has spread like wildfire.
That's great.
Hey,
warren was a break desi champion.
I'm like,
does he have time for these things?
Thirty three years old.
Have all the places that you've been
[inaudible] you.
That's the first time I saw you was on
that show solo hunter,
I think.
Yeah.
No,
I think the first time I saw you was on
Steve Show and that I saw you on soul
hunter as well.
Yeah,
because I was actually supposed to go on
that first hunt with you guys,
but I had to guide that week when
Callahan and I wish I would have made
it,
but I was fortunate.
It would have been cool.
I love that area.
You have to.
You have to go into the woods with Brian
Cowen.
Yeah,
it's.
It's a problem.
You will not stop laughing because.
Yeah,
he's,
he's way than me like
with a captive audience.
Like he's like,
it's almost like he's wasted on stage.
Like a Bra.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Where he's at his best is a bunch of
friends just hanging around.
Small group,
just small,
and he would just,
he would just be.
He's so funny.
He's like,
it's almost like there's no art forum
for what he does.
He,
it's like he can take it to a stage in
front of a bunch of strangers and 300
people and whatever on a credit.
It'll be really funny.
Don't get me wrong.
He's standups really,
really funny.
It's one of the best standups in the
country,
but it's not as funny as when you're
alone with him in the woods.
He did this thing about he had a
character that he created called the
ravine calmer where he would jerk off
intervenes.
It's so stupid,
but when you're there and you're in
Montana and his fucking nine degrees out
and you've been sleeping on the ground
for five days and hiking around miles
every day and you're kind of half half
out of it and laughing and you're,
you're,
we're in the middle of a quartering,
a deer,
and he just starts,
guys,
let me tell you what to do,
what a dealer,
and he just starts like pretending pulls
his pants halfway down his jacket off
into the,
into a canyon.
That's it.
I'm not doing it any justice.
Purely that.
So juvenile.
It's definitely Juvie is.
But that's what cried.
When you're hunting.
You have to have that,
that sense of humor to keep you going.
And there's guys like that.
Just when you're out there sharing
things that are just extra money,
I don't know what it is because you're
just but see him when he's at his best.
When you're in a captive audience,
like I'm just,
I'm,
that's not me.
I don't,
I don't have that sense of humor.
I have a different kind of sense of
humor,
but he,
he's the guy where there's like five of
us,
like guys,
you got a piece on,
you don't.
Yeah,
like he'll just
making you uncomfortable.
The next thing you know,
who,
you know,
it just,
it's so silly.
So that trip and that's when I knew too,
like on the first hunting trip and I
knew he was like,
out of all my friends,
he's one of the ones that I knew would
be able to tough it out.
Like all the other guys that are urban
guys stand up Comedians,
like what are the odds that I can get
one of those guys to go to Montana for
seven days?
And then they'd be like,
fucking Rogan might bring me out here,
but column was a trooper all the next
time we do it.
You should go because we're were.
Steve and I are,
we're trying to put together something
now.
We might do it in Mexico.
Oh yeah.
I'm actually going there next week.
Are you?
He's,
I think he's there now.
Yeah.
Yes.
Yeah,
they're there with,
uh,
with Benno,
Brian and a pianist who's dear,
right?
Yep.
You say kooser cows.
Some people say cows.
It's,
it's,
it's one of those things.
It was originally pronounced one way,
like the state of Nevada is not Nevada,
Nevada.
Everyone who lives there calls it
Nevada,
Nevada.
In Nevada,
Nevada,
I think.
Yeah,
it's Las Vegas,
Nevada.
I don't know what I say.
Yeah.
I have to be alone without you
influencing me to remember when you,
when you think next time they'll call
it in Nevada,
you're going to be like a big ad
campaign,
but there's just certain things that
when you're there,
it set a certain way.
Well,
when we went and borrowed your truck
when we went bowhunting outside of Reno.
Yup.
That's when I got to see the Nevada that
you guys know.
Everybody thinks everybody thinks of
Nevada as Vegas.
Vegas and Barstow.
No,
this like mule deer and elk and mountain
mountains.
Yeah.
And there's more independent mountain
ranges in Nevada than anywhere else.
And more public land outside of Alaska
and there's more public land percentage
wise.
Wow,
that's crazy.
It's almost all public.
That's,
that's one of the reasons why I'm so
gung Ho for public lands.
I grew up in a place where you never saw
a no trespassing sign.
You weren't told you you couldn't go
anywhere.
That's amazing.
It's like the Anti Texas.
It's the,
it is the Anti Texas.
Nothing wrong with Texas,
but it's all,
it's all private.
So weird.
There's probably some public land where
guys hunting Texas,
right?
It was public,
but they sold it all off.
Did they sell it all off?
You know,
the states got the land and they sold it
off to people.
State hardly has any land.
That's the worry for places like Utah
and where they're shrinking their
monuments and they're starting to sell
off rights for drilling and mining and
you know,
people are really concerned about this
administration and their,
what they're doing with the
environmental protections because,
uh,
today trump signed some new thing,
allowing for offshore drilling,
like pretty much fucking everywhere.
He just went.
See if you can find that.
It's just,
it's,
it's rolling back all of the
environmental protections from the Obama
administration and his ideas like
economics.
Trumps trumps wrong word.
Yeah.
Trump's environmental and then will we
really need is to just maximize our
ability to earn money.
Yeah.
Trump moves to open nearly all offshore
waters to drilling nearly all offshore
waters to drilling.
That sounds so fucking crazy.
FTC,
the BP oil spill,
like how many of those can we endure?
Yeah,
it's,
there's a lot of scary stuff when it
comes to the environment because we only
get one.
There's only one earth.
Yeah.
We're so interested in Mars,
like just figure out how to manage the
shit we got.
Well,
I just,
he's all about business.
It's really weird to see a super pro
business guy that's in the White House.
It's quite strange.
The whole thing is quite.
It's,
it seems surreal.
Like every couple of days I'll look at
the paper and it says president trump
and I'll go,
oh yeah,
that guy is the president and that's why
for what I do,
I can just get to unplug for very long
periods of time just.
But that's not even the right way to go
about it sometimes because then there's
things that affect me and what I love
and of course,
and then I get hit blindsided by it
because they don't know that I'm gone
and out in the woods and enjoying what I
like and then I come home and
everything.
Everything's gone.
But do you have a hard time relating to
a lot of people your age that don't
experience the things you experienced
because your life is so vastly different
than the average 33 year old guy?
No,
I mean I think people.
I think people respect.
If you,
if you're really passionate about
something,
whether if you are passionate about
something that isn't even non hunting
lease,
I'm like,
well I give you respect your passion.
Yeah.
You're doing your thing.
And I think a lot of people get that
with me.
Whether they hunter don't hunt,
I can relate to anybody because
everybody's kind of passionate about
something.
We use that group of people that have no
passion and you're like,
wow,
okay.
I don't relate with them,
but I feel like they were raised wrong.
Somebody didn't come along,
introduce them to something,
exactly something.
I mean,
everybody's got their thing,
you know,
if,
if your thing is whatever,
video game or whatever,
that's not my thing,
but if you're cool,
if you like it and you're passionate
about it and I can tell that,
then we can have a conversation about it
because I think that's cool when people
are passionate about something.
Oh yeah.
I mean it's very infectious.
I watch people make furniture.
I don't want to make furniture that.
I've watched people that are really into
furniture like,
fuck,
that looks awesome.
Does something exciting.
My instagram feed is like woodworking
stuff.
I'm like,
yeah,
I don't know.
It's just like the people that are
really passionate about where we're
going.
It's cool to see them build stuff.
I into that.
I liked makers.
Yeah.
That's cool.
Watching gorging orange blades,
hammer them down.
It's just there's something about
tactile,
just actual physical things that you're
making and changing it.
I'm fascinated by that stuff.
Yeah,
so it doesn't mean if you,
if you do it or whatever.
I think everybody can relate on some
level to to things that they're into or
their passions,
I'm sure,
but what you've done is pretty unique.
Like I said that about that show solo
hunter.
I remember thinking,
watching that like,
Whoa,
this is.
This guy goes out there.
You're out there by yourself.
You don't really have a lot to save.
You know that.
That's my thing is I.
me and Steve are actually talking about
this on that a fog neck.
It was before the bear attack,
but it's just real shitty weather,
hard hiking and I'm just loving it is.
You think you'll ever get sick of this.
You just want to go on on a ranch
somewhere and drive around and not kill
yourself,
but it's a different.
That's my thing.
If I have two options,
option a is just this.
Go hunting in a place that there's very
few animals and you probably won't have
any success and it's just really shitty
weather and it's tough and big mountains
or there's this one where I'm guaranteed
that I'll get some big animal and I'll
have a lot of encounters and I can just
drive around.
I'm going to choose the really hard one
and that's just,
it's just how I am.
I like that.
I like the,
it's like a masochistic thing of I like
to struggle.
I like to hurt for it.
Like if I'm going to kill an animal,
I want to have had some kind of struggle
where I feel like I've earned some
respect.
Like I dunno,
it's like my payment.
I had to work for it.
It's my payment to the animal's life.
It's a weird.
So it's just my thing.
Don't you feel like also it's because
you've had so much success.
It's not like you're hurting for meat
desperado meat hunt.
Yeah,
and I think that that's part of it
because sometimes I might go,
if something's too easy,
if I go somewhere and I think,
oh man,
this is too easy.
Then I'll look for an animal that might
be bigger or harder to find or a certain
one just to give myself some kind of
challenge and that was part of the thing
of filming myself while hunting and
going out there is that added challenge
of being alone.
The added challenge of filming myself,
all those challenges just to,
you know,
create that experience of the struggle
of it.
I guess.
It's like I crave that struggle a lot as
well.
So weird.
So weird thing.
It's weird,
but I think a lot of people do that and
different stuff.
It's like exercise.
It's like I,
I firmly believe that a person who
doesn't struggle with anything is going
to be a miserable person because I don't
think you're really going to truly
appreciate relaxation.
I don't appreciate relaxation unless I
work hard.
If I worked like if I come home from the
gym,
I worked out hard.
I worked all day,
worked out hard,
come home from the gym,
I'm fucking exhausted and I can put my
feet up on the couch and I can enjoy TV
show.
I can really enjoy it.
It's one of the only times I can because
if I wake up in the morning and I eat
breakfast and I turned on the TV,
I'm like,
why the fuck you watching TV?
Shut that shit off.
They'll get something done if I've
already done.
I think this is the reason why people
like working out hard is because your
body desires struggle and I think that's
the way human beings evolved.
I think we evolved to have a certain
amount of our reward system geared
towards us accomplishing difficult
things because that's how people
survived.
Yeah.
I think there's a lot to that.
It's a,
it's an accomplishment feeling that you
get.
It's kind of releases those endorphins.
You okay?
I feel good about.
And you really see the real hard times
really make you appreciate the easy
times.
It was just all easy.
You just get stagnant.
Like a rich kid,
not be happy.
Born with silver spoons and you go,
oh,
you don't.
Yeah.
I can't just keep buying.
I can't.
Yeah,
you need.
You need some sort of struggling.
Like I just,
uh,
I don't know if that's been mapped out.
If people understand like you need x
amount of struggle to have this amount
of happiness,
like a really,
most people just think,
oh,
you know,
just get a job and do your thing and
you'll be,
you'll be happy and if you're not,
you take paxil.
Yeah.
I think a lot of people's goal plans
don't.
They try to find the way around that
struggle part and I kind of seek out
that
or just a different.
Your experiences have taught you that
that struggle is where the happiness
comes from and most people are.
They think that the happiness is
avoiding the struggle.
It's a real cat.
It's a trick.
It's like that feeling that your body
gives you.
Like when you don't want to go to the
gym,
like,
Oh,
come on man,
don't go.
But if you push through that,
then afterwards,
like I fucking did this time.
Yes,
I've now I feel.
And then also you see the results in
your body.
Whereas if you just give in to that I'm
lazy thing all the time,
then you just have this dumpy doughy
body.
Then you feel like shit when you're
naked.
A lot of problems.
Yeah.
You're your experience.
He's still doing yoga.
I had not.
Not like I should because my back's all
jacked up now.
I think probably from not doing it,
I need to get back into doing it for a
while.
Right.
I was.
Yeah,
and I actually,
I actually never felt better.
Just the,
well,
I mean since I was probably 18 years old
for most my most,
my year was in,
was guiding hunters and that involved
packing out animals.
So if you think about it,
I don't,
I probably should.
I'm one day I'll sit down and try to
figure out how many animals I've carried
out,
like heavy packs,
a hundred pound pack probably in.
I don't even,
I wouldn't even want to guess.
It's a lot more than probably most
people a strong back from that,
but it's a weird.
Yeah,
it's really.
it's just very.
And now it's only been
17,
18 years of really doing all the time.
You just start feeling like,
oh,
the back end here and oh no.
And I think when I was doing the yoga
more,
I didn't get those pains a little bit
more flexible.
Yeah.
The decompression,
that's a big part of what yoga is.
Yoga makes you move your body in a way
that's almost the opposite of carrying
weight
I think.
Yeah,
that's exactly it.
I mean,
you just got so much weighted down,
so much compression.
Oh,
the toddler Jujitsu people have turned
to yoga now.
The to realize that they,
like,
there's a lot of guys that for the
longest time me included,
what we did was uh,
like working out with weights,
maybe kettle bells,
like heavy,
heavy explosive stuff,
box jumps,
things on those lines.
And then Jujitsu.
So the idea was that the working out
with weights would prepare you for the
Jujitsu and,
but then everybody gets injured.
But a lot of guys have turned now
towards yoga in Jujitsu because there's
something about the rugged smashing and
crushing and pulling and Yanking of g of
Jujitsu that it's complemented by the
stretching and elongating and holding
static positions and completely
non-explosive actions of Yoga.
I think there's A.
I was actually talking with one of my
good buddies,
David Wise,
he's actually a Olympic gold medalist
for halfpipe freeskiing.
I mean he's just like the top of his
game for what is happening.
What does that mean?
So he does the halfpipe like said it'd
be like half a water bottle.
Cut Pipe.
Does it tricks in it?
Oh Skis.
It's Kinda like what Shaun white does on
a snowboard or skis,
but we were talking about exercise that
controls those little muscles for
balance because he's big into hunting
too.
It was like,
and he's when you're moving through the
mountains,
you've got that heavy on.
Sometimes when you see an animal it
means the difference between you getting
it not is it the speed that you get
there.
So you just have to have that,
that ability,
that agility.
So when you set your foot on something,
know that that's that word.
That's where it's going to stay.
Right.
And you don't get off balance because a
lot of the stuff I hunts mountain type
stuff cliffs and especially in Alaska
and New Zealand.
Other stuff is dangerous country.
People die in that.
I mean,
cams friend died in an area that I was
hunting that same year for,
for dall sheep,
you know,
and that's just like,
yeah,
and that's a guy that does it all the
time like you need,
it's very important to have that
balance,
that balance,
those muscles that you can't lift for.
It's the weird being able to stand on
one leg and move around in every
direction because especially when you've
got weight on your back,
packing something out,
that kind of weird agility,
strength training and those guys that do
those kinds of sports like skiing and
snowboarding and all that,
and they're like cats.
You can not tip them over.
I was like,
I want to be like that.
Like even Shane Dorian and I guy when he
walks in the mountains,
it's,
it's different.
Like his balance,
he's so centered.
It makes him quiet and it's just like,
it's cool.
Right.
So from all the surfing.
Yeah.
Um,
do you ever do a Kettlebell?
Windmills?
That's a great one for that as well.
Yeah,
I've done that a couple times.
Something about holding that overhead
and then bending all your body down,
touching the floor,
and then extending backup it.
It put strength into the core or weird
way,
especially if you can do it with heavy
weights like you can.
You have a church Turkish get up.
That's what I've been doing.
A Turkish get up there,
so there's so non-glamorous.
You're right.
Everybody else do curls,
press and stuff and get jacked,
but for functional strength is very few
things that are as good as a Turkish
getup.
There's something about pressing that
weight on your back,
getting up to your knees,
anchoring your body up,
standing all the way up,
and then lowering yourself all the way
back down again.
It's just phenomenal for all these weird
muscles.
Your back and your neck and shoulder
stability and all these gifts that
people ignore.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's it.
In the off season I'll try to do.
See I'm.
I'm out there a lot with the pack on all
day long,
so for me I'd have to find something
that's not that right to get more
benefit and I think that that's why the
yoga thing,
because if I go for to work out and put
a heavy pack on and go for a hike,
well for work I do that for 12 hours a
day.
So like the one hour I go do it when I'm
not working.
Isn't gonna do much for me.
Your back must be like really fucking
strong for you think about 17,
18 years of doing that?
Yeah,
I mean your back must be ridiculous.
You know,
it's,
you know,
you aren't carrying a heavy pack every
day,
but there's been a substantial number
of.
Even if you're doing it once a week.
Yeah,
yeah.
There's definitely.
It would probably help you.
That's what you get strong.
If you're doing it everyday,
I'd probably break you down.
Yeah.
But doing it once a week,
that gives your body a chance to break
down and then slowly recover.
Most.
I'm that guy that's like 55 years old
and can't walk.
Have you seen that outdoorsmen
trainer?
That thing's amazing.
Yeah.
That's cool.
I love hiking with that thing on,
so it keeps the.
It keeps the weight real centered.
I haven't actually used that.
I'm
just because the time it takes to take
my bag off,
I've only got it
one of them,
so I haven't actually used it,
but it,
it doesn't make sense.
It looks pretty cool.
No,
it's very cool.
It's a lot of athletes are using that
now to.
It's a,
they like it better than weight vests
and just sits on your body better,
you know?
That's cool.
Yeah.
It's uh,
for a person who lives,
like say if you live in the Midwest,
like say if you live in Kansas where
it's all flat and you want to prepare
for an elk hunt,
what do you do?
Well,
yeah.
What the fuck would you do?
I guess box steps with like a weighted
pack over and over and over again.
You know,
I get asked that question a lot and I
kind of,
when I start,
when I say late teens or whatever,
trying to,
I'd see elk and then just trying to be
able to get that endurance where I never
had to stop and what I would do is I
would go out and I would do something
that was prolonged to where the point
that I had to stop,
I wouldn't stop,
but I would switch the way that I did.
Did it.
So say I pick them out or stairs or
whatever and you can run and then the
point that you'd have to,
I'd have to stop.
I turn around and start walking
backwards and then I would turn to start
sidestepping and I would refuse to stop.
So I'd pick a point that I knew I
couldn't or almost couldn't get to if I
walked up a mountain one day and thought
I have to stop now.
At that point where I had to stop,
I would just switch the type of muscle
and movement that I would do.
So I thought,
okay,
like if you're some kind of workout,
whatever that workout is,
like some kind of say stairs or
whatever,
if you're running stairs and you go
until your body's like absolutely I
cannot go anymore.
But keep moving in just a different
muscle group
backwards.
Like I do,
they don't want to bag.
But if I'm,
if I'm doing like kickboxing on a heavy
bag and I'm exhausted,
like say if I'm throwing punches and
roundhouse kicks,
I get so exhausted I'm almost done and I
know there's still a minute left to the
Brown,
then I'll switch to front kicks and
weirdly enough I have energy to do that.
Yeah.
It's like I almost can't kick the way
I've been kicking butt.
I can kick otherwise.
Yeah.
It's a weird way that I started just
building endurance to the point where
then I never had to stop.
But if you're a guy lives in a flat
area,
you'd.
Ah,
that's,
that's exactly it.
I don't know.
You'd have to get like I've seen guys on
those stair machines where it's a
rotating stairs and they have a backpack
on like a heavy backpack.
I think that'd be the way to do it and
then not.
And then try to go for like five or six
hours.
Fuck,
nobody's going to do that.
No,
that's the thing.
You,
you no one's ever prepared.
Well that's the thing is,
I mean,
I hate to say it,
but how do you prepare it?
Will you just have to do it?
You can't,
you can't actually go into a go into a
gym and think that you're going to be
able to carry a heavy pack for days at a
time.
No,
there's no.
Like for what I do at a hiking speed,
carrying a pack,
I'm really good at that.
But this year we went in,
we wanted to go in to the spa was a
little bit further and I got on a bike.
I got smoked my 65 years old.
I mean he rides a bike all the time.
I don't write them.
I don't even know if I knew how to ride
a bike when I got on it,
but it kicked my ass so it was just
different.
It was like,
no,
all the hiking every day with the pack.
I thought,
oh no,
this will be no problem and I get on
that bike and get my ass kicked.
I was like,
you cannot,
you have to do to do in a certain level,
but there's certain things I could.
You could probably do.
You could,
I could pedal,
you know,
and a little bit.
And then I'd be like on a stationary
bike everyday and then you'd have more
muscle memory for that type of action.
So if you did the stare thing,
I think that's probably the closest you
could get to get that muscle memory.
Yeah,
I think it would be a stair thing.
Yeah.
Or finding actual stairs.
Actual stairs,
running up flights of stairs.
Yeah.
There's a good place out here in
Calabasas
that has several.
It's a up the side of this hill,
like many,
many,
many stairs.
It's probably like a quarter mile all
the way to the top and I'll run it up
and go down and run it up and go down.
Awesome.
Let's do it.
People in the midwest where it's flat,
she'd open up gyms like rent stairwells,
you just have packs at the bottom and
people get a membership and you can just
go up the stairs as many times as they
want up and downstairs.
It's amazing how just carrying your body
uphills is so difficult.
Like it doesn't to a person who never
does it.
Like,
oh,
we're hiking,
walking.
What?
You're walking outside.
No,
it's way harder.
It just doesn't seem like it should be,
you know,
every,
every ounce of weight on your body or
you,
she even your shoes.
People buy these real heavy
mountaineering boots because like those
are the.
And then they never wear them in a
mountain and then they try to go up the
mountain.
It's like,
what did they say?
Every pound on your foot's like eight
pounds on your back and get a pair of
five pound boots and it's a lot of
weight,
but you do need some sort of stability.
Right?
I mean the reason why those boots
exists,
like if you were going to go to the
Alps,
you need that stuff.
So yeah.
Yeah.
And you have to actually walk different
and um,
a lot of people don't realize that.
Yeah,
more of a rocking step.
And then a,
uh,
almost like ski boots.
So ski cubits and you've got to walk on
your lot of people don't walk on their
toes.
Big problem.
Well,
it's modern shoes will have started
going heel to toe,
heel to toe.
Humans are supposed to go ball the foot
down to the heel ball,
but that's how we're supposed to run.
So we're supposed to walk.
But modern shoes that particularly ones
with heels,
they just accentuate that heel to toe
thing,
which is real weird.
Weird.
Yeah.
It's not.
Well if you'd like people.
When I was a kid I learned to walk with
the pads of my fingers just quiet.
Right around.
Do you,
uh,
do you stalk animals with socks on?
Do still do that?
Socks
or barefoot?
Mostly,
yeah.
Just depends.
Have you ever tried those?
Like five finger shoes?
Those Viv says before?
Yeah,
I've got pretty tough feet,
so it's nothing to just take my socks
off shoes and just walk my socks and the
real quiet.
It would.
If you're in like a rocky area,
I'll still do it.
Really?
Yeah.
Like were you were hunting in Nevada?
I mean that's the idea that barefoot
with socks.
Yeah.
I'll go a couple miles and that stuff.
You just.
You just,
you get used to it.
You never.
It's kind of a weird because I always
thought,
oh,
your feet get tough that your feet
really don't get any tougher.
You just get used to the sensation of
your feet hurting you.
Exactly.
Well,
they do get tough if you go as far as
that.
You ever see that dual survivor guy?
What's the guys name?
Corey something or another.
He had the most disgusting feet ever.
Just.
He just walked everywhere barefoot.
Yeah.
He would go to the forest.
They would do these survivor shows.
It was like there was a series of shows
after survivor man came out that were
ripping off survivor man in a way,
and this was one of the weird ones
called dual survivor.
It was hammered.
Everybody something.
It was like so staged,
like,
what do you think we should do that we
need to make a bone marrow?
And they'd be wandering through the
forest and you see this guy's fucking
disgusting feet,
feet.
I mean,
that's barely a human foot.
Yeah.
Now that in that case,
I mean,
I guess I take that back.
Your feet do get tough for you build
calluses,
but you can get a rock right in that
arch area.
I'll still hurt,
but the bottom of the hill,
we're just there.
They're dark like a soul.
It literally looks like he's got
something on his feet because I really,
I take pride in my foot calluses.
They just,
if I ever lost them,
I feel like I'd start getting blisters
and fewer deal.
Those are,
that's next level.
Well,
I've seen some people that go to the
woods and they go hiking and they don't,
they,
they're not prepared for it.
And they give these horrible like areas
of their foot where their skin gets
rubbed off,
rubbed raw,
especially in the back,
like the heel area.
When I first started guiding,
this guy was from Pennsylvania and he
just,
he just kept pushing himself,
was just cool.
He kept hiking and I always tell them,
you know,
if something,
you know you're aren't going to keep up
you just because you aren't used to it,
so just stop and I'll stop this,
that and the other thing.
And I was like,
if anything is wrong,
let me know.
He started to get a blister,
but he didn't say anything and his foot
started getting rubbed down.
Why would he just had him duck tape it
up.
Ended up getting gang green.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Just from his foot getting rubbed inside
of his shoe and then just keep pushing
himself.
Pushing himself.
Or how many days did it take to get gang
green?
Not that long.
I think it was for five days.
The fifth day he had gangrene.
So what happens?
You got to get him to the hospital.
Yeah.
You get blood poisoning of some kind.
I think so.
Weird.
Wow.
I didn't get gang green from hiking,
you know,
you just didn't just toughing it out and
I'm just going to it out and didn't do
anything
for it.
I don't and I probably didn't hear it
because it hurt.
Take the sock on it so he's probably
right.
I don't really know what his situation
was,
but it wasn't good.
You know,
putting the.
So you probably had it in a boot
sweating all day,
rubbing on it,
getting sweat and bacteria.
Who knows that it just had gotten
infected.
It was nasty.
I mean you,
you could smell it.
It was rotting flesh.
It's disgusting word.
Otherwise folks put some duct tape on
that.
Just some duct tape on it.
You take a lot of guys out that have
never hunted before.
Yeah,
quite a few often.
You do that every year.
A couple times a year I would say.
What does that do you enjoy that is that
I had experienced.
No,
it's fun for me.
It's mostly guys that have.
They may have tried and may have been
successful or it might be their first
real big game type hunt or whatever.
I like it because a,
I get to be a part of the experience and
kind of helped shape that first
experience because you could go out with
some.
I mean I kind of say some hunt.
There are hunters out there that fit the
stereotype and it's a shame I think
somebody that's getting into hunting,
if they go with somebody that fits that
stereotype and they're probably going to
have a bad experience and that's not
what hunting is to me.
So I think that by me being able to kind
of help form that first experience and
make it about the experience because for
me,
when I go hunting,
it's not just about killing something.
It's about the entire experience around.
It's the,
that's what hunting is.
You go out into the woods,
you,
there's just certain things that I do
that other people might not do,
but there are a lot of people that do
it.
Say I pay attention to the plants that
are there.
I pay attention to really everything,
you know,
the things that I noticed someone else
might notice that I point those out to
them and,
and just like give them an overall good
experience of why we're out there and
what we're doing.
And that's fun.
Well,
I think a lot of people have an idea of
what a hunter is from television or from
the movies or from duck dynasty or
something like that,
and a lot of that is maybe even Trieste
and hunters who are maybe overweight not
fit and yeah,
they don't understand that western big
game style hunting like you do is really
an athletic endeavor as well as a skill
as well as a like a really comprehensive
knowledge based approach to problem
solving.
Like you have to know what you're doing.
There's so many factors
so much that goes into it.
I mean you're,
you're backpacking,
you're,
you've got.
You also have to have a certain amount
of Bush skills and I call it like
there's a lot of people that do it,
but they don't have those,
those little nuance skills that you pick
up over over time.
There's a lot of things that I do that
maybe people that have hunted their
whole life's won't even notice.
Just the more you do things,
the more the better you get at it.
The more you notice,
the more you've had times,
two more times you fucked up and then
figured out why that got messed up and
then you try to remedy it in the future,
don't do it this way and you just start
paying attention to really small things
that other people might not pay
attention to.
Just like the way that I.
it's really weird.
I've noticed even went from when I first
started hunting until now,
the way that I do things is just
completely different.
It's almost like I have a method and a
system,
but it's all based on the millions of
times that things haven't gone right and
trying to to progress into be a better
hunter.
Right.
Like you see this situation like,
okay,
I fucked this up before.
Exactly.
No,
I know what's going on here.
Why is the wind at the back of my neck?
I got to get out of here now.
I got to back down,
go around,
go around trying to push it.
When you pick areas as people that I
hung with all go into a new area and
I'll be fairly successful for not going
into that area,
but I've done it enough times to where,
okay,
I do things a certain way and it's
constantly changing too as the
environment changes,
but you know,
if I'm going into an area instead of
going down that hill,
I go around the other way and look at
the hill facing me or things that I
don't know.
It's really hard to explain to like when
I'm out there I can explain it a lot
better.
I can explain,
okay,
this is what I'm doing and this is why
I'm doing it,
and then there's other stuff that you
do.
The easiest is just more of an instinct
than anything and I think a lot of
people have those hunter instincts.
Those are the whole point of that Apex
Predator show was to talk about just the
instincts that humans have that we may
not even tap into.
When you say as a father,
I think you just.
You have that instinct to protect your
children at all costs.
I'm not a father,
I don't have that,
that instinct,
but I'm sure it's in there somewhere.
It's like that.
Nobody has to teach you that you just
kind of all of a sudden go,
yeah,
that's a switch,
which is something goes off if I,
I think that most people would,
if they were carrying their child in
some kind of danger,
they would do some kind of natural
instinctive movement to get that child
away from the danger for sure.
I mean,
that's literally walk human being
survived as long as we did in hunting is
one of those primal things that tap into
and there's some things that are just
instinctual and there's not a lot of,
uh,
there's not a lot of lessons that people
can talk about as far as like what
instincts are.
Yeah.
It's something that you just have to do
it.
That's why it's an instinct is not.
You can't put it into a category.
You can't go to a class.
You can,
you can't read a book on instincts.
You can know what they are,
but that whole instinctual,
it just has to happen.
The grizzly bear charges something else
takes over,
but it's not.
It's not a Stevie said.
He's like.
It wasn't even a primal level who is not
fight or flight.
It was just this,
this weird.
You just did what you had to do in that
very second.
There was no thought.
Yeah,
I don't know.
it's you're.
You're almost like your DNA.
Your DNA is like,
oh,
we've seen this before.
This happened to a fatty maximus 1500
years ago.
Your great grandfather was eaten by a
bear.
Those genes
passed on.
Well,
that time too,
if you've got,
when you're hunting and you go like this
animal,
whatever,
and you just have that feeling like,
I should sit here and then it works out
and you go,
right,
I got to go over this region.
It's just some kind of instinct that
says,
to survive you need to do this.
It's hard to tap into it and you're out
there enough.
You start to pay attention to the things
that work and things that don't.
Well,
guidelines that has so much experience
in the woods.
I would imagine that you're kind of
like,
it's like your data chunking.
It's like you've seen so many,
like you're like,
oh,
I know what this is.
Yeah.
That's the way I.
I,
I kind of like think of instincts is
like a bunch of ones and Zeros and your
computer,
so you don't really think about all the
ones in zero patterns that are in your
head.
You just enter a situation and then
something you know,
your,
your instinct is that data processing
of.
Okay,
slow down.
It might be there.
Yeah.
Something.
Yeah,
there's,
there's definitely parts of us that we,
I don't think we were ever going to
really experience it unless you're doing
something physically,
you know,
you,
you don't even probably know.
You have the instinct to get the fuck
away from a bear as it's charging or to
Juka bear until it actually happens.
You go who that was more like the fuck
out of here,
but the fact that your brain was capable
of coming up with that move in that
moment while it's 11 and a half foot
monster.
Fucking bear was coming down on you.
Well,
and I think the whole Yannis man hitting
that thing in the face with the
tracking,
that's crazy.
And he probably also,
I don't know,
you'd have to ask him,
but it probably didn't even process what
he's saying
dealing and as big as this table.
Right?
It's true.
Just huge.
Just and that turned into,
I had no clue that he did that because I
wouldn't get was on the back.
He's like,
I was on his back and I was like,
yeah,
he juked it in the bear ran away and
it's just like,
no dude,
I hit it in the face of the trekking.
Well,
that's why I ran away.
I was like,
Oh yeah,
okay.
The whole thing that Aspen unbelievable
is that that's the most intense
experience you've ever had in the woods.
Uh,
intense in that in a different way.
It,
I've had a lot of just momentary.
They're just intense in different ways.
Um,
but yeah,
that one was,
that one was pretty intense in the way
that I thought,
oh,
this bear's going to fucking kill me.
A big part of what hunting is to is
being able to stay calm in that moment.
Yeah,
and because you're,
you're looking for an animal,
you're hiking,
you're exhausted day in,
day out.
You're out there for long time and then
all of a sudden it comes down to one
moment and that wall moment literally
might be five seconds.
Holy Shit is coming out from behind that
tree draw and it's right there.
And you have to just be able to be
there.
Yeah.
You can't be thinking about something
else because you just fucked
and you can't be freaking out.
You can't go,
you to go,
oh my God,
I can't believe this is happening.
You can't think that either anybody does
have.
I mean,
you do freak out on or even I've done it
a thousand times.
You get that rush of,
I guess it's that rush of adrenaline.
Do you have,
um,
something that,
that you say in your head,
like when you draw back your bow or
anything like that,
do you have like a series of things like
a checklist that you go off?
A few things.
I just,
I guess with my bow,
the one thing I think because I have a
trigger release so I just try to feel
the trigger in my finger,
in the corner,
my finger.
So I mean I know that I'm not going to
like slap or punch later,
so if I'm thinking about that,
but mostly I'm focusing on where I'm.
Yeah,
I guess I,
my checklists would be like,
drawback,
pick a spot,
feel the trigger,
let it go.
Did you ever have any classic archery
training?
No.
No,
no.
I probably would.
Should you at this point in time?
Well I was talking to Debbie about that
and he's like,
he's like,
you could pick up a rubber band and a
pencil and kill something with it.
Like you just have the instinct to do
it.
But I,
I've noticed when I started hunting with
a bow I just kind of tried to pick it up
myself and I did everything wrong,
but I would go to these three d shoots
and winham not like,
not like real tournament's but just like
local things and I know I'm the best
shop around.
That's great.
And then you guys would be like,
Hey,
you're shooting wrong,
you're doing.
And I just would slap the trigger and I
never thought about holding still.
I had always just shoot with movement
because I started shooting a,
a like a long bow and I would watch time
tnn outdoors.
There's guy named Byron Ferguson.
Have you ever seen his stuff?
This dude would throw up and aspirin and
shoot it out of the air over and over.
Yeah.
And his whole thing was be the arrow.
That was my only archery advice.
Be The arrow.
That's all I knew.
So you just be the arrow.
It made no sense.
But I'd be out there.
I had a ball on a string in the backyard
and I would like a softball and swing
the soft ball back and forth and just
tell myself beat the Arrow,
shoot it made no sense.
And then when I got a compound bow I
just be the arrow.
So I just move.
And when it felt right,
I let her let her rip.
But you've obviously made adjustments
because you don't move.
Yeah,
I in the shot right now.
So in the process of switching the way
that I shoot at developed a few bad
habits,
which now I think if I would have just
stuck with it,
it had been fine,
but now that I've tried to switch,
then I kind of try to all those bad
habits that I had originally tried to
creep back in and it doesn't really,
in the end I do really well so it
doesn't really matter,
but I like the idea of trying new things
and there's always room for improvement.
You should talk to Dudley.
Yeah,
we should go over some coaching with
them.
What's interesting to me is that,
uh,
I've seen a bunch of guys who are like
very accomplished hunters,
very accomplished archers and
they,
they get real weird around him really
because they know he's a master.
He's a master of form and technique and
he does it absolutely the right way and
people do not like to get in shootouts
with him.
Like when you have little competitions,
he's too fucking accurate.
He's,
he's ridiculous.
He shot,
we did a video for on it where he shot a
Kettlebell handle at 120 yards.
He shot in the handling.
Yeah,
at night and the sparks because he did
it at night,
like he said,
a lighted nock in there and aim for the
lighted nock and shot it through and you
can see the sparks as the broad head
hits the bottom of the,
a handle the,
the,
the top edge of the Kettlebell.
He's ridiculous shot.
But everything he does is text book and
he's like a technical.
He's.
Yeah,
he.
And he does that when he's hunting too.
I mean,
but he does that with everything but so
it's real weird.
Like guys almost have this thing in
their head like I don't want to fuck
with it.
It's already are already very successful
doing this way.
I don't want to change anything.
Like I'm not listening to you,
blah blah blah blah blah.
Like some guys will try to revamp their
whole system but a lot of really
successful guys won't.
And they get real weird around him.
It's very interesting
watch.
I can see that whole if it's not broken,
don't fix it,
but I'm not that type.
I don't really.
If somebody is really good at something,
I want to learn from them.
Like,
you know,
if he came to me and was like,
Hey,
I want to know my thing isn't technical
archery.
My thing is being out outdoor skills,
survival skills,
hunting,
being in the woods,
you know,
if he's like,
hey man,
I want to know some more stuff about
stocking mountain goats in wherever
you're like,
okay,
cool.
I can tell you what I know.
And I asked him the same thing,
like tell me about some archery stuff
because there's always areas where I can
improve and I'm not so stuck in my ways
that I need to do it the way I've been
doing it.
I'm not.
There's definitely better ways to do
things,
but you can definitely get by the way,
you're doing it really well here.
Here's,
here's John.
So he put a light on it.
That's what he did.
Yeah,
check it out.
But you want to talk about a guy who
loves archery?
Yeah.
He loves coaching.
He loves doing it,
like that's a perfect thing for him.
He loves it and he loves teaching people
how to do it too,
but if you watch his form,
it's just
absolutely perfect.
Yeah.
That's cool.
And that's what I mean.
I love bow hunting.
That's my passion.
And I'll still go rifle hunting
depending on the hunt.
How often your rifle and every year.
That's a good question.
You know,
am I doing one or two on senior?
I always,
uh,
the one hunt generally because I guide
during the elk season in Montana.
So my thing is El Camino is my number
one thing that I want in the freezer,
so I generally save a few days at the
end of the season to go out and try to
kill an elk with a rifle.
It's mostly just because I want that
meat in the freezer
and I don't.
And there's nothing wrong with rifling
in there.
The thing about that I,
if I take a rifle,
it's also that challenge thing.
So I might go into an area where the
odds of me getting something with a
rifle even would be 100 or say multiple
multiple times less than the odds of me
going into an area with a bone and
getting something right because it's low
density of animals so he didn't see any
animals or even.
Well with Elc I think it's actually
easier to get an elk and maybe people
will be like,
no,
that's bullshit,
but it's easier to get an elk with a bow
than a rifle.
Yeah.
During Europe,
because most archery seasons or during
the Rut,
that's the easiest time to.
It would be like a no brainer with a
rifle and during the rut because the
animals were all distracted and when
they're trying to hump and it mostly
across the West.
The elk season with a rifle and general
elk season,
is it the absolute worst time to finding
out?
Just seeing an elk is the struggle.
You might go five days and not seeing
elk in some areas.
That's probably really cold.
Really cold hartree equipment might not
even work and some of those temperatures
sometimes you draw it back.
Well icicles on you're frozen and it
gets wet and then it's frozen and then
try to shoot.
And how did you start going to Montana?
My grandpa actually lived there.
I just went there summers and I grew up
kind of in hunting that area and stuff.
The bitterroot valley.
Southwest Montana.
What's that?
Near Missoula.
Missoula.
Okay.
South of Missoula.
And I just grew up hunting there.
And you know,
with.
No,
there's no grizzlies there.
Some areas of Montana have them.
Some don't.
Yeah,
correct.
What's that about?
Um,
well they have them in the park and then
the main population and then they did
the reintroductions and say,
so glacier has them,
a yellowstone has them.
They reintroduced grizzlies to certain
areas.
Yeah.
Real upside of glacier in some other
areas you,
they do the problem grizzlies and trap
them or something or as far as I know,
yeah,
they did do some transplants or
reintroductions.
Um,
but those parks have had them.
And then the ones in that greater
yellowstone area of spread out and in
that glacier if spread out.
Montana is a very unusual place.
It's such a small population,
but the people are like,
I've only been to Bozeman and billings
when we went and hunted the Missouri
breaks.
But yeah,
people are very nice.
It's really cool area.
Interesting.
It's like they're not,
they're not Hicks.
Yeah,
no,
they're tuned in.
Well Weird Montana is a small
population,
but that population explodes in the
summer with all the,
with the parks there.
Right.
So it's tourists type people coming in.
And that's why,
I mean it seems like.
I don't actually have the stats,
but it seems like the law almost every
year somebody dies from a grizzly now or
multiple people.
It's been.
A lot of people have been getting
attacked and
I think it's just the amount of people
that are there and just think that
they're cuddly,
cute animals and they don't really have
precautions.
Because I think if you go on a hunt in
Alaska where we went in a fog neck,
you're probably a lot safer than the
tourists going into a yellowstone just
because you,
you're,
you should be prepared.
You've got the idea that these bears are
dangerous and they're probably going to
come at you in some way.
You need to be ready at all times.
Then you go into yellowstone or glacier
park.
There was a lot of attacks around
delisted bears there,
right?
Yeah.
They're,
they're delisted.
No,
but they don't have a,
a season open for hunting.
But that's under debate.
Correct.
So the ideas there are populations of
reached a steady or maybe even over the
that level.
Yep.
Yeah.
They're no longer,
they're no longer threaten or
potentially in danger.
There's no.
They aren't going to go extinct right
now.
And did you ever see,
um,
a short face bear?
You ever see images of the bear that
used to live somewhere in the bearing
landmass between the US and Asia?
It's a way bigger than even a grizzly.
Very large.
Yeah.
They think that's what made of might
have kept people from migrating to North
America quicker.
It's crazy.
Well,
they say they say that a polar bear's
still actively hunt people,
which is a.
those bears.
They do have a different temperament
now.
I think that the bears in Montana,
we just keep going back to barriers,
but the barriers in Montana,
landlocked grizzly bears just seemed to
be slightly more aggressive than the
larger coastal brown bears just because
they don't have as much food.
There's always slightly pissed off.
They always see everything as a,
as a potential meal
and everything is like.
They look at mammals moving around on
the ground as a meal as opposed to like
the bears and the coastal.
They'll connect salmon.
Salmon most of the year.
Yeah.
They're not thinking of things walking
around as being food.
Yeah.
Well the salmon are a very large food
source,
but only in the fall.
So for a quarter of the year.
Did you ever see that
BC special or the guy they put him in a
giant plexiglass box.
Yeah.
And they dropped him off somewhere where
there's a large polar bear population.
Oh No,
I thought it was.
I saw one where they did with the brown
bear and the got to attack the thing.
No,
this is.
This was a polar bear.
Yeah,
the.
They put the polar bear,
they put this box there and the guys
inside the box and the polar bear comes
up to the box.
This is it.
Oh,
so is this like super thick glass thing
with steel and bolts and rivets?
I mean it literally looks like some sort
of a like something you would drop out
of a fucking spaceship and this bear
comes up and sees him and start smelling
them to tries to bite through the thing.
Look at this.
Wow,
fuck this bad.
He's tightening everything down.
Freaking out.
It's licking everything and
systematically trying.
That's a big thing,
but there's times where it opens its
mouth.
Yeah.
And the guys inside of it and it's.
It can smell him through these little
holes,
see where it's going through that hole
and is trying to eat them.
Oh yeah.
That thing is trying to snack on the ice
right there.
Yeah.
I mean it's not curious is trying to
figure out a way to get them.
Fuck man,
that's pretty cool.
Well,
there are so ruthless that they're,
you know,
all of them are cannibals.
That's what's really crazy.
I mean there's not a,
there's not a lot of food up there now.
The sources that they do have,
the seals and things are just high fat
content so they don't have to eat as
much in Wales.
Like the.
Yeah,
picture crazy.
It's got its mouth open trying to bite
through the class and its head is so
fucking big.
Yeah.
I mean there's a heartbreaking video.
I don't know if you saw it.
It was going around a couple of weeks
ago of a polar bear is starving to death
and you know,
they're attributing it to climate
change.
I did see that little nat geo thing.
It's weird that you do not want that to
happen,
right?
I mean the last thing you want to see as
a polar bear starving to death,
but I also don't want to get eaten by
that fucking thing.
We'll just go.
It's just.
I mean that's the balance,
right?
We want them to thrive and survive.
We just don't want him anywhere near me.
Yeah.
I think,
I mean,
I,
I've never been anywhere that there are
a polar bears.
So would you be interested in going?
Yeah,
I'd go check it out.
I think it'd be cool to see.
Do they have a,
what are those big,
furry things?
Muskox.
Are they anywhere near a polar bears?
Yeah,
they are.
Yeah.
They've got them in the Arctic.
The polar bears hunt.
Those muskox says,
Nah,
I don't.
Not that I know of.
And they're mostly go for seals and
other things.
Well,
what's next for you?
Man?
You going to do any more TV shows?
Because I really enjoyed that.
Apex predators.
Well,
I'm still doing the solo hunter stuff
and uh,
we did.
I did some cool stuff in Australia this
year and did a buff Huntington,
like a solo little mission there.
I was with some people,
but then I did all the hunting alone
just to get out there.
It's pretty far out.
I'm still doing the solo stuff and then
yeah,
I've got some stuff in the works,
uh,
for the coming future that be,
it's exciting.
I just can't really divulge a lot of it
yet,
but I hope you do something that
allows people that are more mainstream
that aren't on outdoor TV to get a look
at your approach and your philosophy and
the way you look at things because I
think that guys like you and Rinella and
campaigns and Dudley very valuable
because people have this sense that you
said,
well,
you're talking about like the
stereotypical idea of what a hunter is.
They have this idea of what it is and
they see a guy like you and they go,
oh,
well this guy is like more like an
athlete.
Like this is more like a pursuit.
This is more like an endurance skill
thing on top of being a hunting thing.
Like there's a lot of,
a lot of variables here that most people
don't take into consideration.
It's why I think it's so important to.
That's why I really enjoyed having you
on a podcast and having guys like you on
to talk about this stuff so people get
an understanding of it in a different
way.
Yeah.
Thanks.
I appreciate that.
Yeah,
it's nice to be able to kind of share
what I do with a population that might
not really understand it because I think
if you really look at it hunting in
general and the way that myself,
and I'm not the exception,
there's a lot of people that hunt the
way that I do,
especially out west.
I think that if you really understand
that way,
then you kind of start to get a grasp of
it's not bad.
It's actually a better system and some
of the systems that we have around now
and I think some of the stuff that I'm
going to be doing in the future will
really,
uh,
just give people more access to that.
And you know,
right now you can go get their solo
hunter episodes.
We have a,
we,
we decided to put them all on our
website and do like a solo hunter all
access kind of thing.
Just like a subscription and you can go
on there and just watch anything that
we've done.
There's.
I don't even know how long.
That's awesome.
I think that a lot of times what's
happening with the
stories that are being told about
hunting,
it's.
It's all everyone's preaching to the
converted.
Yeah,
and occasionally something comes along
like this podcast where people maybe
would have a prejudiced idea what it is.
Then they get introduced to a guy like
you or Rainelle and go,
oh,
these aren't meatheads.
These aren't dumb people.
Like this is a different thing,
and then they realize that this is
actually a very difficult,
honorable pursuit and very respectful
pursuit and really hard to do.
When you were talking about like what
the kind of physical fitness levels that
are required of you,
the the knowledge and understanding.
This is not some easy thing where you go
into the mountains and just go find an
animal that's trying to survive and kill
it.
It especially with a bow and Arrow,
it's not easy.
Not Easy.
I think if anyone.
I used to hear those comments that
people that don't hunt,
oh you big hunter,
go out there and kill an animal with a
gun or boat,
whatever.
Go give it a try,
give it a try,
see if you can do it because it's not as
easy as you might think.
It's unbelievably difficult is.
It's very difficult.
I mean they smell you hundreds of yards
away and I'm like,
fuck,
this guy gone,
gone and you're never going to come
close to him.
Yeah,
and a lot of people's interactions with
wildlife or an urban zones are in
national parks.
It's like it's like Disneyland.
It's like going to the zoo.
It's not like where I go into remote
wilderness areas where the animals are
completely wild and you have no support
system,
new net of safety and you just have to
rely on your skills and your ability and
you're just another like you're just
another Predator out there on the
mountain and there are things in some of
those places that want each you and you
just.
You have to adapt and deal with it and
be prepared and,
and go off the skills.
Are those solo backpacking trips your
favorite ones?
Oh,
by far,
yeah.
I love that.
I love it.
And in those mouse there's some,
there's some hints that I used to do a
lot of that.
I try to like,
they're actually looking back on man as
way dangerous.
I probably shouldn't do that alone.
And then I still go do it,
but there's going to be some point I'll
probably.
Well we're,
we're rinella night hunted and got
attacked by the.
I've been in.
They're very,
quite a few times,
probably
three or four times alone.
Solo Watts?
Yeah.
Hunting deer and other things in there.
And,
and I think about it and go God that
stupid,
terrible,
terribly steep.
And,
and to be honest,
there's times that I've been in there by
myself and taking precaution and I
remember one specific time I was
stocking a black tail and I,
I had my pistol in my backpack,
which now obviously I would never do
again,
but I had my bear spray on my hip and my
pistol.
I pull it out,
have no bullets in the thing,
and I'm on a fog neck island thinking I
would be dead.
I would have been dead if that would've
happened and I wasn't by myself and I've
been in that.
The shitty thing is I've been.
The thing that really kind of pissed me
off later was thinking the amount of
times I've been in those situations
alone an and just thinking,
man,
I got to lax on that.
Why did you not bullets in the gun?
Is that just one of those things?
You just been there too many times and
think so and I did.
I did have bear spray.
I think,
Oh,
the bear spray is good enough,
but now knowing the way that that bear
charged in bear spray would have been
completely useless.
They'll just run right through it.
Well,
the wind was blowing so,
so fast in our faces.
We would have blinded ourselves.
Now whether you're coated with bear
spray in it,
words the bear off,
I don't know,
but I wouldn't.
You want to whip out.
You want to whip out bear spray and 70
mile an hour winds that blown in your
face.
Maybe that time you'd probably 40,
50 miles an hour,
but that bear spray is not gonna work in
that.
No,
that's ridiculous.
Bear sprays.
I mean I bet it works some of the time.
Yeah.
I think in in some instances is probably
a lot more effective friend Johnny
Rivets that he sprayed it right and the
grizzlies face and the grooves of walk
right through it.
It just closes his eyes and then shook
his head and then walk right through it.
Yeah.
I think that there's now I think I just
carried both because there's certain
instances where that is probably better
than option.
Yeah.
Because I'm shooting something that's
charging you with a pistol is very
difficult in that situation.
I think that was a 44 magnum.
I think in,
in that situation,
you're really relying on it when the
bears on top of you.
It's just a last ditch effort.
Any of those and even those,
any kind of deterrent you have.
I think it's just hard to,
uh,
hard to really,
like when it comes down it's either
going to go down and you're going to get
away and they are,
you not,
don't.
Do you think anything you can,
but horrific experience made that place
more attractive to you in about a year?
Yeah,
I think so.
I don't answer before I asked it.
I was hoping you'd be surprised.
The weather sucks.
It's hard walking around now.
I know that the bear attacks are leads
yet.
Okay.
Let's go back.
I'll go.
I'll go back there next year.
And hunt deer for sure.
Yeah.
And I echoed in for tags in different
area in there,
so I'll go back.
I wasn't,
it wasn't one of those type of
experiences where you go.
I think even if I had got tore up a
little bit,
I would still go back as.
Yeah,
it's not tore up a little bit defined
like lived through it.
Oh yeah.
What if you like lost half your nose?
I'd probably go.
I'd probably start bear hunting
grizzly.
Um,
yeah,
I have.
Once it was,
it was one of those things I thought,
well,
I'll,
I'll do it.
I had an opportunity and I wasn't.
I'm not,
I'm not really just,
I'm not big into bear hunting.
The meat to me is,
is good.
It's okay,
but I just,
it's not like,
it's not,
no,
it's not my thing.
And you can't eat it medium rare.
No,
exactly.
That's part of it where you want to eat
in.
And uh,
and the other thing is there is a,
like some of it might just be like you
have emotional connections to certain
things.
Like I would,
I don't have any desire to go hunt and
African lion.
It's just not like you just whatever,
you know.
Not that I don't know.
I mean now if it's a thing where it's
like you just to save the species,
you have to go hunting and African lion,
then I'd probably do it,
but it's not something that appeals to
me.
Yeah.
But that's like to say to save mankind,
you know,
you,
you have to go,
fuck Jennifer.
Jennifer flashdance with the lady.
Where was she in my head,
Jennifer
is that flash dance.
But um,
I did.
I didn't hunt bears.
What's wrong with my memory?
That's weird.
I couldn't come up with a current hot
chick
out.
Weird.
You did?
I did.
Yeah.
And I,
it was like a weird.
So the area that I went into,
it was a,
um,
a Predator control area and it's an area
that the state of Alaska,
so the state of Alaska works different
than other places,
so I actually went and met with a
biologist and kind of like,
it was like,
what's the deal with this?
And so the deal was that there's change.
The state of Alaska has to manage their
wildlife populations for subsistence
subsistence
food sources.
It's mandated by the state.
So in that particular area that the
Predator population is got so high that
the moose populations and populations
were in severe decline and in danger of
not being able to provide food,
inadequate food source for the people
that lived.
And when I'm talking to people that
live,
people live in these remote areas.
Yes they do.
And seeing the shows,
yeah,
it's a lot more real than the shows,
but they,
they live in these areas where there is
no access to other food sources.
One of the guys that I met,
the only thing he eats for an entire
year is bear meat.
He has no other.
I mean I don't know if he gets some kind
of grow,
some kind of garden forages as well,
but his main food source through the
winter is bear meat.
Which gun?
Black lives right there in that area or
Brown.
It didn't matter.
Whatever you could get.
So there,
there's people that live in certain
places that the only way that they live
is from the animals that live there.
And that's the only way they could
survive.
I like to get the scientists to study
that guy.
Yeah,
that'd be interesting.
He's an interesting guy.
I mean the guy who just eats bear,
what does he like?
If he's like ridiculously strong,
will they get them to the left?
No,
he seemed like his normal as somebody
that lives off grade is.
That makes sense.
Very odd.
Yeah.
So they,
um,
but anyways,
this particular area,
the bear population was so high that it
was severely hurting the undulate
population to the point where there
might,
it'd be very hard to repair.
So then they open up these special
seasons,
like for people to go in to hunt bears
in this particular area with a certain
objective and since they opened it,
now that area has been starting to
recuperate and then they stop the
Predator management thing.
They,
they still,
you can hunt certain,
but they have.
So they've got a,
uh,
an interesting balance and they put a
lot of time in research and into this
whole deal.
The soul.
There's something very bizarre about
those television shows because they're,
they're captivating those people that
live off the grid.
But there's something really ironic
about a person who doesn't even have a
television in their house,
but they're on television.
That is weird.
Weird.
Yeah.
This guy is living as close to the land
as possible,
but yet there's some millennial behind a
camera.
Tell him,
tell him,
hey man,
can you,
can you pretend that you just found that
again?
Just put it down.
Pick it up again,
like,
Whoa,
I can't believe this is here.
Just give me one of those.
Yeah.
I think some of those people,
I,
I've met quite a few people that live,
like in that aren't on television that
live in the,
in they're fairly strangely normal
people.
It's kind of,
you would think that they,
some of them have the,
might live in a shack,
but they've got some kind of Internet
service off their generator that they
run every once in a while.
It's weird.
I see that vice piece on that guy that
lives in,
um,
eastern Alaska.
Uh,
hi Mo.
Why mo?
Right.
Heimos arctic adventure.
No,
it's amazing.
He's been there since the seventies and
he came out there I think as a guide or
a forestry or something like that and
built a cabin and he's the last guy out
there that has the,
uh,
has rights to a cabin and that they
alloW that has permits to keep this
cabinet out there.
Heimos arctic refuge.
That's what it is.
Hi,
mo course.
It's amazing man.
He's a hunter and he lives off of
caribou and he takes these caribou and
he,
they're all frozen because it's all
cold.
They're hanging froM hanging from trees.
He saws it and throws it on the grill,
you know,
like saws a frozen steak and throws it
on the grill.
But he's remarkably intelligent and
articulate.
He's not,
he's not crazy.
He lives up there with his wife and you
know,
she's a
nun I guess.
And um,
so what you would say?
Yeah.
WheRe is it okay to say eskimo?
Because some of them prefer eskimo.
I'm not sure where the line is there.
Some people think that eskimo is a slur,
like you're not supposed to say,
but other ones say no,
you should say eskimo.
So it's like rinella was trying to
explain it to me and it went in one ear
and out the other probably just where
they live.
YeaH.
But this guy lives in this shack that's
smaller than this room,
smAller than the studio and it's just
log thing.
And uh,
during the show,
a bear tried to eat his dog.
So he ran out in the middle of the
night,
it's dark out,
he's blowing his shotgun off,
boom,
boom.
chasing this bear through the forest and
shooting it.
Wow.
And then had to skin it and send the
skull in and you know,
had to uh,
tell the wildlife people.
Okay.
It's been tried to,
tried to kill my dog so I had to shoot
it.
Yeah.
Defensive life.
Shoot when we're defensive life or
property technically.
Yeah.
But this guy again,
like you're saying,
remarkably normal.
Yeah.
It's kind of strange,
but yeah,
in that,
in that area I did,
I went on that hunt and then um,
the,
I eight because people have always said,
oh bear whatever.
I ate it.
And it was fine.
It was better than blackberry meet.
I thought,
what was it really?
Yeah.
So the whole like,
you caN't eat him as a weird deal
because my own,
my one thing was if I do this,
I'm going to eat it.
And I,
you know,
I didn't see anything
wrong with them.
So it wasn't coastal.
It was,
it was coastal.
So it was eating fish is eating seals.
Navy seals tastes better.
I don't know.
Oh,
it was.
It was summertime too.
So it would've been,
it would've been eating fish and seals
and whatever can find dead dead seals
mostly
because I remember rinella telling me
that he shot a black bear one,
so it'd be nothing but fish and that
they smoked it and that terrible
borrowed a friend's smoker.
He didn't say it was terrible,
but he said he borrowed a friend smoker
and he said,
hey man,
you got to clean that smoker out.
And he goes,
why?
He goes,
oh,
it smells like fish.
And he goes,
I've never smoked fish in that thing
ever.
And he was like,
what?
Really?
And they realize like,
oh no,
it's coming off of the actual meat,
like the bear ate so much fish that it
tasted like fish in the fat.
And tHen when they,
um,
they,
they smoke this bear ham and
then slice it thin.
It literally tastes like salmon
carpaccio it's not.
Yeah.
See,
that doesn't appeal to me.
I think if you get your head past it
like salmon.
So why wouldn't I like that?
Yeah.
That's a weird.
Like a weird bear.
Salmon combination.
Yeah.
Was somebody asked me the other day,
well me and ronelle on mediators eight
that coyote in Mexico.
That was weird.
Yeah.
And it wasn't at the time it just tasted
like meat.
It was weird meat.
It tastes like goose or something.
Thinking back on it,
it's like I have no desire to go out and
eat coyote again.
No,
no,
no.
That's just the things that are close to
a dog.
Yeah,
that's too weird.
I kind of like coyotes.
I liked it.
I liked to seen them around.
I mean I feel like our weird neighbors.
So this is this year I got man.
I got charged by a lot of stuff this
year.
The,
I was a hunting.
Where you.
I sent you in rinella.
I went back there.
You got charged with something up there?
Yeah.
So this is just,
this is weird.
So I'm sitting there in this.
Just see like that white sandy area up
in there.
It was like this weird white dirt up
there.
So I'm sitting in this weird white dirt
in the middle of the day,
100 degrees out,
so I'm trying to get in the shade and
I'm,
I'm actually had a trip coming up that
we did a caribou hunt that we filmed
with under armour for one of their rigs
reaper series,
which I've done a few of those that um,
you,
my brother,
you did one and then me and my brother
did a moose hunt.
That was just before that green trees.
Australia on cam has a couple of the on
cam's got the,
he had the elk this year and then the.
Is that Australia has got the time.
Will chose him working in the job.
Yeah that was good one.
So anyways,
um,
I'm leaving for that shortly.
So I'm sitting out there makIng a list
on my phone and I'm full camoed up,
but I had no gloves on and I've got my
phone there and I hear this slight noise
behind me and I turned around in,
this coyote is running full speed at me,
like full tilt and I cocked my fist
back,
that punch in the face and it like hits
the brakes and start skidding because
it's running down hill.
So I think my estimation of what
happened was I'm sitting there with my
hands and cammo and saw maybe the flash
of my hands working on the phone or
maybe something in the flash in the
phone and thought it was a small animal.
Probably thought it was a rabbit or
something.
I'm not sure.
This is just what I'm assuming it ran in
so fast and so quiet.
I don't know what I heard,
but I happened to turn around at the
right time and when I turned around at
things eyes I swear just doubled in size
and he hit the brakes and his ass
started skidding toward me because I
was.
I was going to punch it,
had no clue what else to do and it it
started like skidded and this started
rolling and then got up within could
have grabbed it and just reeled off the
other direction 100 miles away,
but it was in full on attack mode.
I don't think he realized what it was
attacking.
I don't think it knew that I was a
person.
I think it just thought movement,
movement,
small thing,
attack and when I scared the shit out of
it,
it's crazy.
Your hand.
Little little squirrel.
Squirrel or something.
It was just coming full tilt.
So quiet.
It's just so quiet.
I see how they can grab stuff.
Have you ever had a mountain lion sneak
up on you?
I'm not sneak up on me,
but I've been in very close proximity.
I was in Arizona,
hemanchu's deer with my bow probably.
I don't even know.
Maybe even 10 years ago now,
and I was going through this wash and I
see it drag mark and tracks.
I'm like,
oh,
a lion killed a cow and drug it through
this wash and I'm like,
sweet.
I was filming.
I had my video camera in my backpack so
I'm bent over getting my video camera
out because I'm going to like film the
tracks and the drag mark and then maybe
finding the cow.
Well in the wash it's like sand and then
each tree and some real tall grass and
I'm bent over going through my backpack
and I look up and maybe three,
four feet away.
Is that cat crouched down?
Just looking at me through the grass.
three or four feet away?
Yeah,
within.
Yeah.
Two arms length.
So 40 feet away.
So like right where I am.
Yeah,
exactly.
And I look up and I lock eyes with it
just and it and it like slinks back,
goes underneath the log and pops up at
maybe 15,
20 feet and turns of stairs like oh
shit.
And then I get the camera out and then
it just sauntered off like digit on
film.
Um,
I think I got it walking away but I
didn't get it when it was close.
Cause now I'm like,
now I'm digging for my pistol brushes.
And where was my pistol?
It was in the bag too.
I don't know what my deal is to keep my
pistol in my bag or steven.
I'm so.
Then it went off well what it had done,
it had drugged the calf into that,
into that patch of grass and then they
kind of bury it and it just been gorging
on it and it was laying on top of it and
I didn't even see any of that because
I'm so focused on the tracks and
everything else.
I didn't even notice it and it was the
way it was the lane that the cow is
tucked up under the tree and covered in
stuff.
She couldn't see it until I went through
the thick grass and that cat must have
just heard me in slunk down waiting for
me to go by and then it was probably
just so full.
It had no end.
They're faring fairly shy animals as
well,
but I was very vulnerable position.
It could have easily jumped on me,
easily know the only thing I saw was its
eyes and there because it blended in so
well.
I was.
One thing that I was shocked
by when we were in Nevada is Nevada,
Nevada.
It is.
So now I know I say Nevada that we were
in Nevada.
How many domestic cows wander through
those areas?
Grazing and that they,
they spend,
I don't know how that works.
Like they,
they pay money for permits to allow
these cows to graze.
Yeah,
you lease a lease it and then you pay x
amount to the forest service for
grazing,
atonement,
certain areas and then generally you
have to have him off.
but October 1st.
So like me and dan dody were on a stock
and we're moving through this area and
then we hear some noise and this fucking
cows standing in front of us.
Like tHis is just weird.
Like you feel like you shouldn't be
here.
Like at my end,
some farm somewhere.
But you're not there just just running
their cows grAzing.
Yeah.
And then they'll go up in horses and
just round them up.
Push them down into the field.
Yeah.
So odd.
I,
I didn't understand that.
I always thought that cows were in pens
and that's just the way it is.
But no,
there's a lot of cows that are just
wandering around on grazing land.
Yeah.
It's all open range.
That was with all that bundy stuff up in
Oregon was about right.
It was about it.
I'm not an expert on it,
but I remember them talking.
IT was.
Yeah.
He didn't pay his,
his fees.
He said have to erica.
She was on blm land,
which.
Okay.
Yeah.
I mean with bureau of land management.
And so yeah,
the fees aren't,
weren't even that much.
It's a lot cheaper than having an on
private land.
Yeah.
well there's something that happens to
white people when you leave him alone
with guns.
YeaH.
Get a little muddy.
Please leave me alone in the forest with
guns.
They almost always get a little
squirrely.
Yeah,
the poor.
That was a weird stand up though.
It was very strange because there was
shootouts with the federal rallies and
everything and they take over soMe kind
of a,
like forest reserve area.
Um,
something happened.
Refuge won some kind of federal little
building out there.
And there was,
I can't remember.
one of them was shot and killed.
Yeah,
I mean it was like a big uproar.
Well,
a bunch of other fucking yahoo's white
dudes with guns flew there to sort of
help out.
That's when It got real weird memory of
those big standoff.
Yeah,
that's good.
See my mile thought on it is,
it's,
it's public land.
It's not your land.
It's our land.
So you can't go do commercial shit.
It'd be like,
oh,
you know what,
I'm just going to go open up a hotel on
the forest service land over here
because it's my land.
It's government it,
I own it.
No,
it's everybody's,
everybody's shit.
Yeah.
But people have weird ways justifying
anything.
Maybe if he's giving out as beef for
free to everyone who owns the land,
that's the one thing,
but he wasn't doing that.
So,
uh,
before we wrap this up,
do you have any,
uh,
interesting places that you're headed to
soon?
Um,
I'll be going down to Mexico next week.
And then was that sonora sonora?
Yeah,
that's,
that's always been there.
Yeah.
It's amazing down there of real Mexico,
right?
Yeah.
That's cool.
It's awesome.
Do you want that ramps that steve goes
to all the time?
Um,
similar area.
Different place.
YeaH.
I thought that was amazing where they
showed how they preserve buffalo,
where they would cut it really thin and
hanging on clotheslines to dry it and
make machaca as
a I went.
I've been to that place a couple times.
That place is pretty cool.
Where they've got those buffalo down
there.
Is that what you did?
That episode of solo hunter where you
put the wolf skin?
A apex predator.
Apex predator,
sorry.
Yeah,
and we still those apex predator
episodes,
you can still go apex predator.tv and if
you just want to get them,
you can get the downloads still.
I think that's the only place that
exists now.
But um,
yeah,
I did that.
That was cool.
They show up sometime on dvr because I
have you as a season pass,
like sometimes they'll just throw one
on.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
On the channel and it'll just pop up.
Yeah,
that's what my buddy was like,
hey,
they're doing an apex predator marathon
time.
Can they do that?
Did you want to do more of those?
Yes and no.
I really enjoyed doing it,
but the other thing is I also liked
everything else I was doing and there
was a lot of tv networks are dying.
They just,
it seems like they don't want to,
they don't want shows it or it was a,
I thought it was extreme.
It was an extremely high quality show
for that network and those high quality
shows Costs too much for that network to
make is whether it ended up being,
um,
now is there a way to do something like
that for the internet?
Because I know that netflix is starting
to do rinella.
Shows,
flicks and he's still on regular tv too,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
I think they're just reruns.
I don't think there's any new stuff.
I'm not sure new stuff is just going to
be on netflix.
I don't know.
I'm not really sure how interesting.
Yeah,
I have to ask him,
but uh,
yeah,
I,
you know,
I think there,
there will be a plaCe for that kind of
stuff in the future when I think,
you know,
but I,
I enjoyed doing it but I also didn't
want to do 15 episodes of it a year
because there was other things that I
enjoy doing.
I enjoy doing those under armor pieces.
I enjoy giving solo hunters enjoy doing
a lot of stuff.
I don't like just doing one thing.
So when you do a lot of New Zealand as
well,
so I'll be going over to New Zealand
this year.
yeah,
because that's a place where again,
it's all invasive species,
invasive species in New Zealand and
Australia.
I really liked Australia when I went
there actually that a video with green
tree and cam actually swung by kind of
crash their party for a couple of days
when they're taking is cool as fun.
I had a good time over there and then I
went and did my own thing after they,
after they left for their buffalo,
I kind of went off and did my own thing
somewhere completely different.
Yeah,
you went by yourself,
right?
Um,
yeah,
I,
I have a friend over there and so we
drove out into arnhem land which is like
aboriginal land.
We got special permission
and got all these permits and everything
and we drove out there and went hunting
for a week and a half,
two weeks,
something like that.
And uh,
and then we,
because we only had one vehicle between
the two of us,
so I dropped him off somewhere and then
I'd drive out and then go hunt and then
the next day he would take the vehicle
and I would go out and hunt.
So I was hunting by myself for most,
most of it,
which was,
I liked that experience because it's
kinda dangerous and buffalo,
but it's when you only have a bow and
you're completely by yourself.
There is no,
you aren't gonna get medivaced out of
there in a helicopter because you're 13
hours by vehicle from the nearest town.
Yeah.
I don't know how you even get out.
He'd be in a world of hurt.
You hear that adult greentree fuck that
place.
He's keeps trying to get me to go there.
Stop it at him.
Yeah.
It's a cool place.
I enjoyed it.
It's a certain type of person will
really like it and other people will
hate it.
Yeah.
People like you.
That's why you need to have a television
show or not,
if not a television show.
Some real in depth show that that they
do on the internet.
That shows like the preparation that's
involved.
I just think it's something that most
people are ignorant to think,
so I'm kind of obsessed with that.
The idea of explaining it to people.
Yeah.
I think that that hunt.
You can.
I filmed it for solo so you can watch
that and I thought that turned out
pretty good.
That was really cool.
I saw it,
but there's just something to you about
north american hunting and we have so
much.
Awesome.
We have a lot of awesome places here,
but a lot of people live close to them.
Probably don't even take advantage of
them,
but there's a lot of cool places and a
lot of cool things you can do in the us
and in the western us and it was just a
lot of cool places around.
Well,
one of the things that I said when we
were in Nevada,
set it right,
right.
Yeah.
Got it.
When we were up there,
uh,
outside of reno,
it's like three hours outside of reno,
somewhere like that.
So I was saying,
but yeah,
this might as well be some alien world.
Like there's nothing up there.
No,
it's a lot.
A lot of public land and not much in
between.
And these big giant hills and valleys
where there's nothing in them but
animals.
And it's just weird.
Yeah.
It's not flat.
No mountains or
13,000 feet.
Yeah,
it's on one of them.
It's pretty incredible.
But it's also incredible that so few
people understand that this is all
public land.
You can go out there anytime you want.
You can go travel this stuff.
And that's one of the reasons why people
like back country hunters and anglers
and conservation groups are so
important.
They preserve your access to these
places because there are so many places
like that that are just fantastic and
they're there for you and most people
don't even know about it.
Even if you have zero desire to go
hunting,
just go and visit.
Just go and wander through those woods
in Idaho.
Just go.
Yeah,
there's some cool places that there is.
It's just cool to walk into a spot.
Especially Idaho has got huge wilderness
areas.
Walk in there and look around and think
it's what everything looks like when
there's no roads.
When there's.
There's nothing you might be the only
person for.
It's a cool feeling to be know that
there's no one else around and it's not
much different than it was 5,000 years
ago.
It's not.
It's not much has changed.
All right,
I've got to get out of here for.
So stop.
Start coughing up a storm.
Cool.
Fighting off a little bit of a cold here
in redmond warrant.
Oh,
That nasty.
Flu virus.
The flu virus.
I just have a mild mild cough.
It's no big deal.
It's really,
it's all fine.
How often do work out?
I'll show you what it is.
A virus,
a remy warren on twitter,
remy warren on instagram.
And uh,
how else can people see your stuff?
Facebook.
Facebook?
Yeah.
Mostly instagram.
Ramey,
warren.
And then hunter persona solo h n,
t r.tv.
All right,
remy warrant.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Mm.