Okay.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net and click on
the link for the fleshlight and entering
the code name,
Rogan,
you will get 15% off the number
one sex toy for a minute.
Did I give you one last time? You
got my brother? Nice tight one.
All right. Buckle up bitches.
Michael Chavela was in the house.
This would be the spot where it played
the music, but I don't have any here.
My, my assistant is not here. So we're
going, we're going commando style.
It's good to be back here,
brother. Good to see you.
My friend [inaudible] nationally known
and locally respected Michael Chavela,
my pal, my, my, my colleague.
Yeah, you're like, uh, we are,
we have a, an interesting
friendship. You know,
where this is only like a few
of us that do a, this, uh,
martial arts commentary shit, you
know, professionally a small handful.
Yeah. You know, so it's, uh, it was
always, it was cool when I first met you.
You know, it was cool. It was cool. You're
a good dude. It was fun to hang with you,
man. You too. We first met
in Edmonton. Yeah. After your
show there. Yeah. Yeah. It's,
it's always nice when you know someone
else does what you do when you actually
liked them, you know? Very true.
Very true. Thank you. Yeah, for sure.
No one's better at the k one shit
and there's no one better at,
at Moitai commentary than you, man. You're
the greatest. I listen all the time.
I watch that HC Nan, I told
you when you got here, when it,
Mike and his wife got here, uh,
I was, or his fiance rather.
I was fucking working out in the
garage with his voice on the TV.
Yeah, I got it set up. So there's a TV
back there and that's all I ever watch.
You'll sit up out there is insane, man.
It's so nice to, it's crazy. I can never,
I have no excuse for not being in shape.
There's you as a gym right there. Yeah.
I can't, I don't have to go anywhere. I
step out of my house and water into it,
man. It's nice. Nice. That's good to
be here. This has been a long trip.
It's in the final stretch now.
Michael's thinking about moving here,
ladies and gentlemen. Yeah. He might
move to United States of America,
so long way to travel brother.
Every two weeks from Melbourne to La.
Then wherever we do the shows on
HD net and all the way back home.
Then when I have to go to Europe,
like before I came here,
this trip I was in Europe in the last
month I was in Europe for Bama. It's just,
it's how far is it to Europe
from Australia to get to,
let's say Italy were just
ones before this trip,
35 hours from the time I left my house
to the time I arrived in Rome was like 35
hours. Oh my God. Yeah. That
doesn't seem like it would be right.
It seems like you're in the wrong way.
It seems like there must be a quicker way.
Can we go the other way?
Can you go over the pole,
the wheel back around like superman?
Did you otherwise? I mean that's like,
that's like flying from Sydney to
Melbourne by going all the way around the
planet. Yeah, but going the opposite
way. Really. Yeah. Well where is,
is there another way to go? No, there's
not like it would be a way to go.
That's shorter. We have to go from
a, we got Melbourne up to Hong Kong,
then from Hong Kong we switched planes
and fly across China, Russia, Siberia.
I need a of the [inaudible] to
really wrap my head around this.
I'm gonna need to look at a map of the
world. It's nuts, man. We very far away.
That's what I was used.
Travel so much.
You know you were just on a holiday
recently and you said you saw a lot of
Aussies around.
You also use a traveling because Al
Della is good and you'll della sucks.
So it's a good time for us to travel.
Yeah.
Everything's cheaper than the moment
does at work, man. After all is killing.
You'll della for the first time. I can
ever remember in mind in my life. Well,
I never knew whether or not you guys
have a strong dollar or a weak dollar,
but what I, I'll never understand
the dollar. I'll never understand.
I don't understand how shifts and moves
and I didn't understand how it has is so
strong.
It's such a small population as well.
How there's the same amount of people.
Okay.
There's the same amount of stuff
and then somehow or another boom,
there's not as much money and
things are closing like it's, it's,
it seems a logical,
it seems like if you look at it just from
a pure resource based standpoint, okay,
there's a certain amount of
oil is a certain amount of
wool and they're starting
to my plastic,
certain amount of material to make things
certain amount of desire and need for
these things. So once money gets moving,
it pretty much stays moving. What,
what is it that creates some giant hiccup
that fucks the whole system sideways?
I mean if you watch like inside
job or any of these movies on it,
you get to find out what it really is
and see how deep the corruption is.
But to a lay person like myself who
knows very little about economics,
it almost seems like it can't happen,
but just even countries getting
into debt and I'm like, grace,
grace is almost bankrupt on what did
they do when they run out of money?
Now what does someone by grace,
we're right there too.
You know you guys were on the brink of
it as well and what happens when that
happens? I mean they'll know.
It's like several trillion
dollars, trillion dollars.
Who Do we have the money to understand
who your barn is it other countries?
If every country in the world is in debt,
is that the game?
That would be the most ridiculous shit
ever. If that is the case, that would,
it would really, it's someone
needs to write a book about that.
The world as bankruptcy
because if that is the case,
every country in the one that we have to
figure out who they might own the money
money too and once you find
out who they owe the money to,
then you find out the new world order.
Exactly.
When you find out the real CFR and that
might be grace and now America is taking
me to listen from Taiwan,
how to spend too much money and
not be able to pay it all back.
We were talking about this before,
you know Michael's been doing the k one
commentary forever and all the great k
one events,
the grand prixs,
the k one max and the Max Grand Prixs
and the finals and fuck you call it some
amazing fights,
but apparently it's just not as popular
as it used to be and now I'm there.
They're hurting financially unfortunately.
Wouldn't be Tom Financially,
most of their top fighters money that
a lot of this stuff, money as well.
It's just not coming,
coming through.
So without the money to be
able to pay for is how do you,
how are they even going to
stage a grand Prix this year?
How is the rain going to get to defend
the title if you can afford it? Yeah.
Alistair's and your butter,
Harrison,
he's sent me Schultes and
you're removing on jet skis.
I really don't see how
that isn't a home run.
If somebody wanted to pick
it up, you know, and I,
I talked to Dana White
about this, I said, dude,
if you ever thought about
buying the k one and it's like,
can people don't give a fuck about k one
and it's like, you know, people you know,
don't want to see kickboxing and sort of
like pka karate kind of like ruined it.
Like there's some really good
fights but people, you know,
MMA is so huge and it's so popular that
it almost be like, and I saw his point,
it's like almost like creating your own
competitor or something like that or
building up a business
that doesn't exist and but,
but that they product
though is pretty much one,
somebody sees it then you're hooked on
it. Yeah, but that's what I'm saying.
It's like, you know, you,
people might say that like some kickboxing
never took off or maybe maybe he's
not.
As,
I know Dana doesn't spend nearly as much
time watching kickboxing as I do. I'm a,
I'm a huge k one fan and I love
watching it. I watched it all the time.
There's guys who don't get into like Eddie
Bravo can't get into it, man. He goes,
I tried to watch, I can't watch
it. I mean maybe it's just,
cause I started off in
striking base martial arts,
so I can appreciate that Giorgio Petrosian
or the massage autos and those kinds
of characters. But to me, man,
how the fuck do you not want the k
one heavyweight Grand Prix? I said,
ever been anything but fucking
crazy. Exactly. Every year.
I don't think I can remember a
boring grumb pre might be like,
oh three Oh four when Remy want to both
times and both times you went like the
distance in every fight,
every other Grand Prix has been amazing.
Really is an interesting case,
isn't he? He's so technical.
He's an interesting guy and we're
a lot of fighters don't like him.
A lot of fighters don't like
his personality. They don't
like what he represents.
Remy, he's an interesting
guy. A gentlemen. Yeah,
like an absolute gentleman.
So well mannered. But then you also have
to wonder if that is not just foreign.
It's in public. A lot of the fun is not
unlock remi. I personally liked the guy.
He's a cool guy. I don't know if
he's a guy, could spend 24 hours.
We thought hanging out at nightclubs
or parties with always a gentleman.
But you know,
I never see many of the other fighters
hanging out with remi for the people that
don't know what we're talking about.
This is k one deep inside shit.
Remy is Remy [inaudible], who is
one of the greatest kickboxers, uh,
to ever come out of Holland,
which is one of the greatest kickboxing
centers in the world where America has
really kind of lost touch with kickboxing.
Holland has really embraced the
sport and it's gigantic over there.
Guys like Peter Hertz at guys like
our Nesto who Stan, you know, and,
and hiring spoke enormously popular.
Rob came in,
there's a great friend of mine, Ramon
Dekkers. So there's so many great,
great fighters that come out of there.
They're huge celebrities over there.
It's a different, it's a totally different
experience. Holland is a small country,
but they're kickboxing is a legendary
for this one small part of the world.
They've produced some of the
greatest kickboxers of all times.
And the respect over there for these
guys is very mainstream. I mean,
two years it might've been no,
2008 it was,
and it's doe who Scott Knighted by.
I don't know if a royal family or the
government must be the royal family of
Holland obviously got knighted.
So we were joking Japan. I'm like,
Ernesto tried to call you sir
enesto now, but how crazy is that to
think it kickboxer gets knighted made.
Could you imagine that happening
in America, in America,
apart from happening in Britain,
even no way Michael Bisping's can
become so Michael Bisping anytime soon.
In his own mind.
It is unusual.
And if fighters want to learn
kickboxing in this day and age,
there's two places in the world
that they traveled to the,
he will even travel to Thailand or
they'll travel to Holland. Yeah.
It's that simple. If you want to learn
the genuine art of Muay Thai, you know,
which is Thailand's national martial art,
dating back thousands of years and as
long been their military martial arts
still is there. The military martial
art, uh, you know, you've got to,
you got to Thailand to learn it. Any of
the great camps over there from, you know,
fair tech, stick your
tongue, um, the WMC camping,
Ko Samui and you learn the knees, the
elbows, the grappling and all that.
The Thai techniques.
If you go to Holland though,
what your primary learning is modified
tie. It's the, the, the punches,
the kicks and the knees with limited
clenching and pretty much no elbows.
You know, they have elbow
fights over there obviously,
but the main rules are modified tie,
which is knees and, and no elbows.
And why did they eliminate elbows?
Just something for the reason that, uh,
you know, the cuts, first of
all, stop a very good fight.
As much as I love seeing a good elbow.
There are a lot of times,
especially commentating moy tai where I
rue having elbows in the sport because
as I've seen some great battles with
two guys are going back and forth just
pounding on each other for rounds. We
go into the fifth round, you think God,
this is going to go down to the wire,
could be anyone's fight and then some
guy throws one elbow that cuts the other
dude and the cut may not be that deep,
but most times they'll tend to stop a
fight now for cuts over the eyes and is
going to running to the eyes and I've
seen perfectly good fights stopped from
cuts. I see it that way. But
I also see it the other way,
like they're so effective.
You can't route if you take them out,
you're taking out a part of
what makes it a martial art.
If you're talking self defense,
like I believe more times one of the
best you can learn for self defense.
It's so complete self defense reasons.
Yeah. For entertainment purposes though,
and especially for television purposes
and where you're trying to grow sports
like in Holland back in
the day and in Japan,
how they grew kickboxing
since you know mastery,
she invented k one 1993 and the theme
was all about television ratings in,
okay one used to have a longtime clinching
rule where you couldn't put on a more
Thai clinch and grapple with the
guy like you doing Muay Thai.
But now it's like a roller until Alistair
came know Bob Sapp came along and guys,
good handle hang on to beetle and just
bludgeon them. So now it's like one hand,
one clinch knee and release. But it's
all, it's all for television purposes.
You know, in in Thailand you have to
fight with elbows. You can't fight it.
Modified tire,
I mean there's a lot of rules when you
find a proper sanctioned bout in in
Thailand you've got to where the Hmong
coal and the flower shop around the neck
and a lot of guys were that the other
project of the arm bands and they do this,
the significance of all that stuff. It's
all superstitious. So the ties of very,
very superstitious always have
been in usually the Hmong call,
which is what they wear around their,
it looks like a like a like a a tennis
racket. Yeah, that's compulsory.
If you fight for the WMC in particular,
which is the will sanction body to where
among call on your way to the ring,
you have to do it.
You also have to do the when the
why crew [inaudible] which is a,
a preflight ritual of a tie
fighter that looks like a dance.
I suppose a mix between a dance in a,
a yoga routine almost.
And what they are doing there
is, it's, it's very deep,
meaning their blessing their corner and
asking the gods to bless their corner.
I they trainer and also bless the opposite
corner and hope that your opponent
doesn't get hurt too much and you have to
perform this before every single fight.
Uh, you know, WMC in Thailand
in particular and it got these,
I can go for a long time.
Some of them I've seen had been up to
five minutes long. You know, it's, it's,
it's crazy, but it's all part of
the, the beautiful formal history of,
of the sport that they're maintaining.
Do you know Sam Sheridan? You know, EMS?
I was the writer of a fighter's
heart and a fighter's mind.
He's actually married to
my friend Patty. And, uh,
I got a chance to hang out with that
dude and talk to him. He's a really,
really cool guy. And he, um,
he went over there and lived
in Thailand and you know,
stayed over there for months and had a
Moitai fight and they documented it for a
TV show. It was a really fascinating
experience, man. It's really,
really cool to watch. He did the full,
the dance, the white crew and the red boy.
Yeah. He did all that before, you know,
all traditional. Yup. You know, and uh,
it was fascinating.
He got really set up.
They set them up with some Yakuza type
dude covered in tattoos who was a bad ass
kickboxer and they tried to say
that this guy was like an amateur,
but the guy wasn't in that good
a shape and he tired out and,
and Sam got him changed.
He got hurt before that.
He got cracked by this guy and he's,
you know, relative, relatively amateur.
It's crazy. Everything. It's just
so popular. You know, it's on TV.
Every night is on channel
seven show it show a little.
The fight to channel seven has their own
stadium. And as you know, in Thailand,
it's not so much about
being a world champion,
it's about being a stadium champion. And
the two main stadiums are lung, Piney,
and registered moon stadium.
And if you're a champion of evil,
either one of those stadiums,
you're like the man, you know,
you're like top of the
sport. WMC champions. It's
WBC champions. It's like Eh.
Then I consider them that highly. And
Thailand, if you're a stadium champion,
you're the man.
Wow.
So is it like this is my house and
then everybody has to come to fight.
You and your house pretty much offend
that title. So a stadium champion,
it's the stadiums are so popular that a
fighter like say dodger stadium and the
guy would be the Dodgers stadium
champion, don't just study them, champion.
And then people would all come
and have a ranking system. Wow.
And then you get to be number one
contender and so and so for the, you know,
the dodger stadium title. And that's
the thing. It's, it's, it's huge.
And they start really young,
right? They stuck alone.
Five, six years old, you know,
got, you know, kids are fighting already
by the time that they reach a, you know,
18, 1920 years old. They've
already had 150 fights, you know,
we'd come and setting Thai guys, send shy
central. I saw king start youtube him.
He's amazing. Does these acrobatic
cartwheel kicks, you know,
form of leukemia and regimen champion,
multiple champion and,
and you know, commentating him just
to fight that he had in Queensland,
Australia a few weeks ago
against Cook Fin. Liason Yeah.
Dude's got like 230 fights,
240 fights of common sighted guides
with over 300 fights and it's full tie
rules.
That's knees and elbow.
And in my opinion that style is the
most effective style for standup. Yeah,
there's a lot of techniques that don't,
that you can you find in other martial
arts like wheel kicks and turning side
kicks that are real knockout techniques.
But if you want to look at
one comprehensive package
for striking it's soul,
it's so economical with the leg kicks
that this short movements to create big
power,
the emphasis on power,
especially the emphasis on power leg
kicks where they know there's only a
certain amount of these you can take.
You know,
there's a lot of fleshy techniques,
as you said before in other martial arts.
But think about it for
self defense purpose.
If you're in a nightclub and some drunk
guys belled you up against a wall,
you're not gonna be able to pull
off a spinning hook kick, right?
Grab his fucking head.
You're grabbing me the fuck out of him,
an elbow him and go to
work on him on the inside,
which about Moitai does perfectly and
you know Moitai is one of the most
brilliant at that. That ability to
control the neck and throw guys around.
Like until you've had a guy like Cayman
or someone you know who's like a a world
champion and grab a hold your neck and
throw you around from that position,
it's amazing how much control they have
over you control your neck like a handle.
You control the body weight, you
control the opponent's motion, which is,
I'm surprised that actually we don't see
in mixed martial arts people utilizing
the Thai clinch the way the Thais do.
You get per takedowns yet again,
you watch someone like you know WMC
champion tongue Matsui or sand shy and you
see him look up with the
guy and when he fought,
like Kurt fiend license in Australia would
look up with curt and just punch into
the canvas.
And the Thais also follow you down onto
the canvas because what they'd like to
do is lead the way. Drop a neon.
You, you know, near your head.
Now you're on the rib
cage on underway down.
So if you look at that from a
mixed martial arts position,
these guys are often ending up in a mentor
most if not inside control from this
beautiful ranching takedown and they
can throw even grapplers around with it.
Man, it's like a marijuana Anderson
got ahold of rich Franklin.
Rich Franklin had no idea that
Anderson would ever do that to him.
His thought was at Anderson is
going to want to strike with him,
so he's going to want
to keep his distance.
When Anderson just grabbed a hold of
him and the walk those two forearms
together, it's like you're
caught in a vice grip man.
If you're finding a good Moy Thai fighter,
you're not getting out.
I've seen small ties to,
you know,
small tires doing seminars in Australia
and and watching them try and throw
around big guys. Now you see like
a 55 kilogram tie throwing up,
throwing around a guy that weighs 85 90
kilos, just rag dolling it. It's easy.
It's an amazing position and
people don't utilize it enough,
but it's one of those things
that's going to slowly come over.
You know the the real high level versions
of we're going to come over into MMA
and then we're going to really see
people appreciating it. I see. You know,
you see the Anderson Silva version of it,
but there's some
guys out there like bull cow,
just grab that motherfucker,
grabs a hold of your neck. He gets those
elbows planted and clips that hand.
Man, you're locked. It's like
anything else. There's levels of it.
There's the Marcello Garcia rear
naked choke, which isn't, you know,
and all due respect is not like
a Mark Coleman rear naked choke.
You know what I mean?
There's levels of the technique.
Mark Coleman gets your back.
He's got to squeeze the fucking shit
out of you and put you on conscious.
But he's a gorilla brute force power
Ressa even though he knows the technique,
he doesn't have it.
That laser sharp effective
technique like a Marcella Garcia,
like the highest end Brazilian Jiu Jitsu
and that's no disrespect to call it.
It's just like these really super, super
technical guys. You get a guy who super,
super technical back clinch and really
understands it and the thing is that the
tie fighters, you know these
guys are doing it with 12
ounce, 10 ounce gloves on,
just so hard, you know, to look
in a clinch like that's so tight.
The way they do it. These, these large
gloves, these aren't mixed martial arts,
four ounces,
you know there's a button they have the
benefit of not worrying about someone
taking them down. Very true. That's
really what a big, big part of it is.
And it's like one of the things that
I would tell people about taekwondo.
Taekwondo is not the most
effective martial art,
but there's a few things in it
that if you get really good at it,
you can fuck people up with it and they
won't know that you know how to do it.
Because for most people it's a, it's
a very, very difficult thing to learn.
Like spinning hook kicks,
head kicks on those techniques.
And the reason why people get so good
at it in taekwondo is because in Tiguan
don't tournaments you can't punch to the
face and you tank can take a guy down.
So you only concentrate on all
these crazy leg techniques.
And in doing so you get an a level of
dexterity that you would never get if you
look at the whole thing. Yeah. So that's
like the argument in martial arts,
in mixed martial arts of
being the specialist instead
of being someone who's a
jack of all trades, you know, someone who,
being someone who's a killer at Moitai
or being someone who's a killer at at one
particular aspect of mixed martial arts
is way better than being pretty good at
all of them. The other thing
gets me about, you know,
you're talking that kicking
in the various martial arts,
it's just how you think to yourself.
If you don't know anything
about martial arts,
you think how many possible ways are
there to throw around kicking somebody.
But the fact is there are so many
different ways. Shushing karate throws a,
I'm a Washer,
Getty different than around kick from
taekwondo and different from around keep
from Chicago,
different from around keep by Sabat
fodder different from a ground keep from a
moist tie fighter.
So many different ways to,
they throw them between the art and it's
amazing how you know these are adaptive
of hundreds of years.
Well the question Mark Craig is really
just starting to make its way into MMA.
I mean really starting to be more
effective and that meant something to calc
hushing guys have been throwing
for taekwondo guys forever.
It's the wheat and taekwondo. He would
call it the fake front round kick. So you,
and basically the idea is that it comes
like a front kick and then turns over
and nowhere and, and the, the opponent
has no idea it's going to hit his face.
And those are the ones that really fuck
you up if you want to say them like you
glare by fight Tosa or Francesco Puleo
and that's why they called it the
Brazilian won't get the Brazilian
Cape because of those two gentlemen.
Exactly why these guys were bad
ass killed Christian fighters.
It made their way to k one. Yep. They
both had that technique down, you know,
otherwise known as the upside down kick
or question mark. Kick. Nice. I love it.
Brilliant kick.
And you know,
we still don't see the front leg
roundhouse kick from taekwondo style.
There's a fast taekwondo
front leg roundhouse kick.
But the thing about a taekwondo guy is
that if you get really good at taekwondo,
you were going to have to be the kind of
guy that can stop and look at it and go,
okay, but I suck it all these
other things. Now I've got
to go get my ass kicked,
uh, at at something that I suck at
instead of go to the gym and be a hero.
Now you're going to the gym and
getting capped out all the time.
When you do that lead leg Gramke
can talk window. You switching up,
will you throw it off the
lead right off to read leg.
Really slide in your slide and it's
going to amazing amount of power. Yeah.
And it's very fast.
Yeah.
It's almost like a fence or coming
forward to trusting the Saudia Iraq on the
leaf. You know, he used to do it,
but he did it. Thai style was Paleo.
Paleo had a very good front leg roundhouse
kick. Yeah, he was was more Thai style.
He put a little more hip to it and
more power, I'm sure if his landed.
But the thing about the taekwondo one was
you slide in on it and you slide it on.
It's very effective. Yeah. Very
quick technique. Yeah. There's just,
and like the spinning back kick. I mean,
it'd be because of a few guys, you know,
because of, um, uh, Dennis Seaver,
he's got a wicked one. Yeah. You know,
a few guys throw it in a really good at
the Charles McCarthy, a knockout of that,
um, uh, shit, I'm blanking on his name.
Who?
Oh, I can't believe I can't remember
his name. No, I'm just stuck to,
okay.
You want to see the best
turning Becky, Mike Bernardo,
Mike Bruno, sorry. Andy Hug.
When he knocked out Mike Bernard and
the Grand Prix final or Andy Hug have a
motto,
crazy texted talks to the thigh and
nobody had ever seen a turn Becky to the
fight before and it was brilliant. So
Youtube, Andy Hug versus Mike Bernarda,
you'll find it there. K
One Grand Prix, you know,
final and a flight that nobody,
man that nobody fought could
get to the top of the sport.
Cause Andy Hug was a big time Hakushin
legend [inaudible] world champion and you
know, entered k one is as
the smallest fighter ever.
Pretty much in one of the
launches fighters ever
couldn't box to save his life
at the start because like
taekwondo caucus, she never
allows face punches. Yeah.
In any of their competitions and taught
himself how to box and persistence and,
and became the biggest superstar
in, in k one history. And there's a,
there's a bit of controversy behind
him because he got really big.
He got really physically big and a
lot of people going, okay, like what?
What's that guy doing? Like that guy
just gained a fuck load of weight.
[inaudible] this was a little controversy
loss. Actually we had a heavy,
it's surrounded Andy's death as well that
the leukemia came on so quickly and so
suddenly there's always that
sort of little background rumor.
Well was it cause he was on something,
you know that therefore speed up this
process and you got to wonder man.
You know when you're in such a dangerous
environment like k one k one is,
if you've never seen it, it's, I'm
a fucking huge fan of it. I mean it,
it really is almost more gladiatorial
den MMA in a way because guys have to
fight
multiple times a night. That's one of
the few places where they still do it.
Three fights in one night to win the
Grand Prix, you have to fight and you,
you got to fight three semi Schiltz three
Badr Hari three Ma Remy bombed jazz.
Three good counsel. And it's
crazy. That guy's on the up,
man. Go Con Saki is on the up. He's crazy.
If you go look, go con Saki, look
and Daniel Geeta, he's another one,
Daniel Geeta with those leg kicks man,
this little video clip with him in Japan
a couple of years ago and I said to him
at the end of the cleaning, you
know, throw Lakey to my leg.
I got Daniel just like really, really
light. And Dan, he's a great guy.
One of the nicest guys just threw this
tip, tap leg kick on me, but I'm like,
shit for the next three days,
man.
You know the reason I do want to take
that butter hurry, one over in Holland,
what are the, the voicemail
says about a hiring, you know,
a lot of people ask me about that.
I'm like,
well I was going to take a leg
kickoff Barda and dude, he's eyes Joe,
he's eyes when he lines up to kick this,
they'd change.
Like he becomes possessed.
He's turned shark like black.
And I genuinely shit myself cause I'm
standing there standing in front of butter
and butter goes to me, Mikey, if you've
got insurance, I'm my here, whatever, man.
He goes, no, no, no. If you've got
insurance and then, but as coach man,
Mike from Mike's team's like,
yeah, do you have insurance?
And Alastar start talking Dutch to each
other with these like concerned looks
for me. I'm saying to my producer,
Daryl, what the fuck's going on?
What are these guys talking about?
And the,
and the Melvins sort of just gives me
this look as if to say, don't do it.
Don't take the lickey Melvin
Manhoef men off yet. Listen man,
when Melvin Manhoef is
telling you is dangerous, uh,
due to go to the page with a dog collar
on a guy who looks like a god Damn
Superhero comic book.
And I put the pad there and I was
ready and then I just shoot myself,
gave it to my passenger and I
said, hell, you take the kick.
I needed to hear the thud. You know, when
you watch the show and, but do that man,
but is intense. I love the
guy. He's my favorite fighter.
Motherfucker is scary man.
He's eyes just go black.
Just no emotion in there. Yeah.
By her higher, he's no joke.
He's a terrifying one of the all time,
high,
highest level guys to ever come out
of Holland as well. Scary, scary,
scary skillset.
Now the power that he throws to knock
people out and you see his knockout of
like Roselawn cutter ev, we puts the
nose in slow motion through the head.
Crazy. While we were talking about this
before that he does a lot of stuff.
Did they tell you not
to do like these swings?
Full power with every shot sometimes and
he leaves himself open because of that,
but it's like, it's not Mike's
gym do or die style too. I mean,
Mike hypes these guys up.
I'm still not sure exactly
what Mike says to those guys,
but if you ever watch a Melvin entrance
robota hurry entrance, you know,
you see my just absolutely Skitch out
of the guide when they're at the top of
the catwalk and for some reason he is,
owns them.
Get them in the zone and fuck your
works, man. It's nuts. Nuts. It's a,
it's one of the,
he's one of the best at doing that about
hyping guys up before and when you can
tell those guys, believe in him,
man, that guy's a badass coach.
Are you still going to get a whole? And
by the way, I do have to go to Holland.
I'm going to get a hold on it.
Go.
Come with me one day with all the travel
and I do with the UFC and with comedy
and you know, and it's, it's hard man.
It's hard to schedule some other time.
I'm just hoping that eventually
there'll be a UFC in Holland. I mean,
I think there's some laws
against it right now,
which is outrageous when you consider
their great history and kickboxing that we
talked about Holland called
politicians don't be stupid.
You can make a lot of money and
the world needs to see it there.
You guys are the birth of the greatest
form of kickboxing the world has ever
known. In my opinion. I think the,
I mean I love the ties and
the ties created more time,
but I believe that the Dutch
took it to the next level.
They took it to another level.
You know, guys like rob came in,
he took it to another level. I've been
able on Coupa, Ballantine, the pioneers,
they went to Thailand and fought,
then brought this stuff back over to
Holland and then took it from there.
And when you watch Ramon fight, Ramon
Dekkers fight and we fought in Thailand.
He was doing some shit that
they were his hands, you know,
that's what the Dutch did.
They added much superior hand tech.
But this thing of the times its size
always and still to this day start very
slowly. The reason being that in
Thailand they bet on the fights.
So even while the flat starts
they still taking bets.
So traditionally what the ties would do
would be to start very slowly and let
the bits come in and not turn on the pace
until the third round as to what they
do to this day. Still when you find
most Westerners fighting a tie,
particularly in Thailand,
I always think the best thing to do is
just go for their jaw lines straight away.
Bulrush them go hell for leather on the
ties jaw because usually he's going to
start very slow.
He's going to sit back with that style.
Cities Paste to the music and you know
that music picks up in intensity as every
round goes on.
For those that don't know Moy,
Thai traditional Mai Tai is
always accompanied by music.
And usually in Thailand it's a live
band. Ringside, they have an oboe. Uh,
they have the little symbols,
they have like a fucking thing.
It looks like a guitar and they
play the music to set there.
It's like a metronome.
So they sit their time to it.
And as the rounds go on in music
gets quicker and quicker and quicker.
If you've watched kickboxer, you know
the movie, you'll see it on there.
The music in the background and you know,
the ties always traditionally start very,
very slowly.
First two rounds can be an absolute
fucking cure for insomnia when you're
watching my tie,
if you don't know what you're
watching in the third round though,
this fucker's just turning up and then
it starts slamming those leg kicks and
they're not big combination fighters,
you know that it's measured with his leg
kicks and just chop down with, you know,
disarm goes back,
which was also one of the big and
doings of the ties to cause the ties.
All I did that the chop kicks but they'll
throw the kicks so hard instead of
leaving their hand up here they chopped
down because I knew that there was not a
chance that an opponent,
because boxing is like the,
the lowest scored technique in my tie
that it's don't consider boxing very high
at all. So then I worked on it as much as
I do their kicks in the knees and their
elbows. So the ties were
traditionally chopped their hand down,
tick kick with more power and a lot of
westerns that used to be able to hook
them and be able to pick them off.
Cause this hand to come down.
Nothing to cover the side of the face.
Whereas now a lot of western kickbox
ECC in particularly a lot of the Dutch,
they'll throw their keep but still
managed to keep the forearm up to predict.
They go with less power and they go with
something that they could land. Exactly,
exactly.
And you've seen someone like about a
hurry that when an opponent throws a
chopping,
he can shop with their hands,
but has got that reach to be able to
scale up the Santo Straight Rock Cross and
just knock guys out reaches
a huge advantage. Man.
People don't realize when you see
a guy like Jon Jones fighting,
Jon Jones has got like,
man,
what a monster advantage that is getting
inside that Vitali Klitschko box that
you get inside that Chad.
This is why when he fought David Haney
and I was watching it with a mic back
home, who's British, you know, and he'd
been on debit high and he's like, Nah,
he's going to be too fast and too slick.
And I said to him, Bro, there's no way.
Hey fucking gets inside that jab to land.
Anything of consequence on Klitschko as
long as Klitschkos in shape and as long
as he is in good condition and motivated
and as no knee problems so he can move
well,
your odds are very slim.
You got to run in and get that Chin
really quick to the block. You know,
Alistair Overeem recently saying he'd,
he'd want a box. The Klitschko brothers.
I'm like, are you fucking serious? I love
LSD, man. One of my favorite fighters.
But he is getting owned in a
boxing fight against fatality.
Klitschko well both of them. A lot
of mirrors. Well Vladimir is a,
the more technical boxer just Vitaly is
thought to be the tougher guy. Right?
He's like, it used to be a decent
kickboxer back in the day. Yeah.
They're both assassins and they're
both fucking like doctors, right?
They're both brilliant man,
highly educated.
They speak like five different
languages. They live in Germany. They're,
they're fucking their scores for
like their, their, their, uh,
how many people watch their shows just
for getting the ratings for their fights
in Germany can't be believed.
Like there's no reason for them to
ever even consider fighting in America.
They get seen by like 19 million fucking
people and that's who the Europeans
like an eloquent technical fighter
like that pulls in the audiences.
Going back to Andy Hug,
you're talking about before when Andy
used to find in these broadcasts, he's,
he's, he's fights were
broadcast on switch to TV alive.
It would outright the tennis matches and
Martina Hingis and outright the switch
national soccer team.
I mean,
just fucking extraordinary
figures that they used to do.
And Andy liked the Klitschkos
was well spoken, clean cut call.
The educated could speak three or four
languages and there was nothing to
dislike about the guy.
I never got to meet him,
but I did get to interview
him over the phone, uh,
probably about two years before he died.
And just talking to him, he was just,
it just eloquent. Just could just tell
a story without, without a flinch,
without an, I'm on her nerves.
Just tremendous. How old
was Andy Hug when he died?
He was pretty young, right? He was
young, was maybe, I can't remember.
Maybe mid thirties when he died. It
wasn't a very big guy. There wasn't nine.
It just barely six foot barely is bill
foot couldn't book when he was fighting
in k one he had to fight
it. Heavyweight. Right.
There was only one weight
class I might close, open wide.
So heels fighting guys
that were bigger than him,
you know Bernardo weighed a lot more
than him. And when he first started
kickboxing, what was his weight before
he went into k one now heels, heels,
very lane.
When he started he was like one 67 I've
seen some old photos of Andy if he's
seen in his caucus,
Shin Gay in that very very lean and then
just you know you put on the sizing k
one however he did it,
he did it and you know,
learned out to box which was with my and
doing because especially back in those
days,
you're talking (939) 049-0590 six a lot
of traditional karate guys weren't cross
training and boxing like
they do these days. Yes.
Andy came from strictly a full contact
karate background, which as we said,
no face punching but also, which is why
we said why he had such great kicks. Yeah,
because dude couldn't
punch it to the face.
You could get really flashy with your
techniques and Andy's main kick was the
[inaudible] and the [inaudible]
is extraordinary. If, if,
if you guys who are
listening haven't seen it,
you know it's called the
[inaudible] because it comes
down and you're like an x.
The heels brought down onto there,
the collarbone or key broke down to the
forehead and your wind the leg way up
over the opponent.
That down it comes,
one of the most brutal knockouts I ever
saw in taekwondo was his guy, herb Perez,
who went on to win the Olympic gold medal.
And this was that one of
the national championships,
I believe it was in Ohio back when I was
a kid and I was just just starting to
compete on the national level and he
was the champion and he acts kicked this
fucking dude, I forget the dude's name,
but he was this big solid African dude.
The guy was just like a check
Congo living character. Just,
I wish I remembered his name because
he was a bad ass guy as well.
Also won the title at one point in time,
but he hit him with this fucking
axe kick that was so fat,
which while the Ham slam the heel
to his face, he was the same base,
planted this like he's liquids, a Lester
size. He'll get up to taller opponents,
you know,
the healers like one of the hardest bones
in the body and just that coming down
on you and you called it just gotta
be so unpredictable, you know,
and it'll be fast because the
trajectory for next get to travel,
there's a lot of time for a quick
opponent to be able to capitalize a,
her Perez was one of those guys that
actually thought about getting into MMA.
And I think if anybody from the taekwondo
world would have been good at MMA,
it probably would have been him because
I got to see him compete a bunch of
times. He actually, he actually
knocked out one of my friends. Um,
he would knock out a lot of guys and
he would punch a lot of guys too. He,
he had like a different style,
like this different real attacking
power style of taekwondo.
If you learned like real
boxing and learn how to sprawl,
he would fuck a lot of guys up cause the,
the speed of his legs that,
you mean the guys wouldn't have been able
to handle those kicks coming at their
face. They wouldn't know it would get
there that quick. You know, it's a lot.
A lot of it is a timing thing, you know,
it's just whether or not a guy like that,
those high level taekwondo guys,
if they want to spend the time and
learn all that other shit and become an
amateur, you know, when
you get into Jujitsu,
I don't care if you're an Olympic
gold medalist that as a white belt,
purple belt mounts you and starts choking
the fuck out of you every Tuesday and
he goes looking for you. When you
think of yourself as this bad ass,
you go to the gym and the public.
But my friend went to play.
He wants to choke the fuck out of
you like he always does. You know,
that's some humbling shit and a
lot of those guys are not willing,
which I think is really,
really unfortunate because what
made a guy like a her Perez,
not to use them as an example,
but when I was a kid,
he was like one of my favorite taekwondo
guys to watch. It was like an idol.
So I bring him up. But what, what
made him so great is that, you know,
he figured out how to follow through to
like the highest level of a particular
martial art. But the goal is
always to be an effective fighter.
You can say that it's all to compete
inside the taekwondo rule frame, but man,
at the root of it,
you want to kick some dude's ass and
it's hard to accept that you're kicking
guys ask only because he's
not allowed to take you down.
Because if he was around
and take you down,
well then he could just fucking do that
all day and then your kicks are useless.
Yeah.
So it's like there's,
there's a certain aspect of it that a
lot of those guys didn't want it except,
you know, they, they want to still think
that there, this assassin when they are,
as long as the rules are very specific.
For seven and a half years,
I edited the Australian equivalent of
black belt magazine called Blitz magazine
and uh, you know, running battle,
the different martial arts
and the traditional arts.
And we do sequence frames,
you know,
to show defenses against knife attacks
and defenses against boxing and all this
sort of stuff. And you look back
at it now after the, you know, the,
the propagation in mixed martial arts
and the popularity of mixed martial arts
that exposed so many of the myths.
And I flick back through some of the old
magazines. I'm like, what the fuck man,
this shit just,
just would not work guys coming out
with a knife and you're going to,
oh guys coming in with the clubbing and
you look at fucking XD fence and then
you know spinning, hook it to the
guy and it's like, come on man.
There was some ridiculous shit going on.
But a lot of the guys that
would believe that shit so much,
and this was one of the things that
absolutely put me off working for the
magazine towards the end was hating
having to write about instructors and how
humble they were and you know
that they had no ego whatsoever.
And these are the same guys
that are ringing you up saying,
I want to be on the front
cover of the magazine.
I want a poster of myself inside. I'm
going to buy five pages of advertising.
I want to check the story out and
make sure the write ups good Ben,
you got to ride out humble,
appreciative bowing and doing it for
very little money. And it's just like,
it's just sort of give me a very bad
taste for some traditional martial artists
that, that believable a lot of
their own hype. That said though,
I'm a big fan of traditional martial arts
because I love the aesthetics of it as
well. Traditional martial arts, uh,
much like any sort of school of philosophy
where one person knows more than you
and they're going to teach you,
you're going to get two different types.
You're going to get true masters.
And by true masters,
I just mean someone who really,
it truly is a person who has some
knowledge and they want to bestow it and
that's the, the life they're living
in. That's the way they're living.
And you're going to get some charlatans.
You're going to get a lot of people
just like caught leaders, you know,
they're in,
there are people out there that I believe
that are legitimate spiritual leaders
and by what they are,
is there a person that's on a road and
they're further ahead than you? You know,
if the guy's been living at a
Buddhist monastery, you know,
eating a very raw vegan diet and
meditating all day for 10 years,
that's an experience that very,
very few people have ever attempted.
And if you hung out with
that guy or talk to them,
I guarantee you can pick something
up from him. But that same token,
there's a lot of charlatan.
Coleen is in martial arts and there are
so many of them out there that have more
than not more than not exactly the way
that the students look up to these guys
and put them on a pedestal. It's
like, like that messiahs almost.
And it's a shame to see
a lot of instructors take
advantage of that just for
monetary gain. And there's so many
of them out there and you know,
I've seen instructors around the world
and several stories of instructors who
have taken advantage of students now
for sexual purposes and stuff like that.
Just because the,
the control,
the steaming mind control they have that
they implement in those students. It's,
it's, it's, it's cultish. That's,
it's crazy man. It's really common.
It's really common that if you look up
like scandals and there's always things
happening in karate schools to ultimate
power corrupts ultimately or absolutely
or whatever. You know, it's, uh, it's,
it is like being in a cult
when you have everybody going,
Usr yum can become some asshole and
really believe that shit. You know,
that's the thing that I least liked
about taekwondo when I was a child.
But in all fairness,
that intense, you know,
yes or no sir. That is what
I needed. It disciplines.
You mean when I had kids mind that I'd
love to get my kids in the traditional
mosque slots just for that discipline,
that rigorous discipline. It's just, it's,
there's levels of respect. Like my
taekwondo school that I, I mean,
I literally spent my entire life from
age 15 until I started doing standup
comedy.
That's all I did was fight with.
All I did was taekwondo and kickboxing
and Muay Thai towards the end. More time,
kickboxing when I was 22 my
last fights or kickboxing,
but my whole life was
all this taekwondo shit.
And I would go from this world
of very little order, you know,
which my life was to all of a sudden,
you know,
some guys that fucking screaming at
you and you know, so yes sir, you know,
and he's saying you go and then this,
this whole bowing and this respect thing.
And then, and then actually
like becoming a black belt,
like all of that to me was
like, this was like, it, it, it,
it forced me into thinking at a higher
level at forced me into like composing
myself, presenting myself
on a higher level that I,
I had a higher calling to answer to.
The funny thing back then as well,
I remember talking to you about this and
when we did the voice versus, you know,
was the, the uh, the, the, the uh,
the black power, how, how much people
have thought of black belts back then.
I remember, and I've told you this story
when all the c level is still looking,
I was 12 years old.
I remember at high school,
kid come up to me and we'll talking
about karate and being a black belt.
And he's like, yeah, you
know, here in Australia,
you're not allowed to be any more
than a fifth Dan black belt or you're
considered a lethal weapon. You've
got to leave the country. I was like,
what do you believe that shit back then,
while I was in the,
I was in a plane with boss Rutan and uh,
we are,
we're getting on board and the woman
goes, where do I know that guy from? I go,
that's the boss Rutan I go,
this is a former UFC heavyweight champion
when the greatest martial artist ever,
he's a legend. And she goes, oh,
well my boyfriend is a big into martial
arts. I go, yeah. And she goes, yeah,
yeah. He actually had to get his hands
registered. Jackson said this, right.
So I go over it, I'm a fucking asshole.
Of course I have to go over it. And I go,
boss,
the woman over there said
that her boyfriend's a big
fan of a mixed martial arts
and he's such a bad motherfucker.
He had to get his hands registered.
And of course, you know, boss ruin. It's
like this is not true. Just not true.
I don't do that. Don't do that.
What tells you this? He's liar.
So that's so well he was pretty
polite about it, but man,
he couldn't stop til it gets
fucking guy. Come on, come on.
You know he's boss. Boss ruin is
a killer man. And you, you know,
you ignite that spark inside of him
with some bullshit and you know,
especially a guy who's
dedicated his entire life to
fighting. You can't do that.
The boss ruin some troopers out there.
Maybe even crazy.
Even people that are getting
awarded these. Dan's,
there was a guy in Australia and you know
he was like 45 46 years old and was a
10th Dan Indian Jitu 10th 10
fucking Ninja where all the shit,
the fucking fucking shit that they were
a shurikens and all that sort of stuff.
It's like a 10th Dan, you're a 45
year old, 10th Dan White Ninja.
Who the fuck is, I mean is there
a real school of Ninja tune me?
Can you really directly studying in
Jitsu cause wasn't being a Ninja,
being an assassin. It was a secretive
to some shit. They just tell why people,
you know,
what the fuck is the fucking call stricken
and the fucking Catana are and all
the rest of the shit crazy man.
I don't even need you to has a Carter.
There was one guy that I
was absolutely fascinated.
This is before when I was
younger I hadn't developed my,
my current strategy of using
people as science projects.
There's some people that are
like, I decide, well this
guy is my science project.
Like what's this guy doing?
This is,
I'm going to study him every couple of
years and tune in to him and see what's
going on.
I didn't realize I was already doing
that with this guy but there was this one
guy who was a Ninja master and he was
in all these magazines is black belt
magazines and this guy
was completely crazy.
This guy was drinking miso soup
in the morning and you know,
eating traditional Japanese food all day
and then doing his Ninja training and
like, he would have all these articles,
like, what would a Ninja do if
I got comes at you with a stick?
Oh fuck.
You can't fuck with an engine
with a stick to that said,
my uncle due to cough was a fucking bomb.
Helga was American Ninja back in the
ideas, man. I met that guy to cough a man.
That was fucking awesome. Um, you
know, the last time I did your show,
I did the voice versus,
and you and I sat and we talked about
black dudes doing Kung Fu and the park.
Y'All did a lot of black dudes doing
Kung Fu in the park. I very mad at me.
Really? Yeah. You know, because
I was making fun of like,
what would they do is not,
there's nothing.
Not saying that hitting someone using
Kung Fu techniques wouldn't be effective.
Of course,
it'd be effective.
What we're saying is this method of
training that these guys employed in the
park is,
is basically
a really antiquated old way of
developing techniques for martial arts.
And what it is is one guy pretends to
hit you and then you pretend you get out
of the way and then hit him
with a bunch of other shit.
But that stuff doesn't really work
because when someone comes in to hit you,
they don't just come in and hit you
like that. They want to figure you out.
They moved, they, they've, they faint. You
don't want to wrap my point as well.
I say it's not,
it's not effective to train that way. No,
it's not effective to you step forward.
The guy throws a bunch of, you know,
so the guy's like, yeah, Joe Rogan.
How you could say that out,
hit you with a monkey fist in your face
and your eyes water and you're telling
me it ain't going to hurt. It
will. Most certainly will hurt.
Please don't hit me with a monkey Paul
to the face. That's not what I'm saying.
When I make fun of your
training. I'm saying that's
not the way to do it anymore.
It's, it's silly to this. This is about
the fight. What you do as a sport.
Shut the fuck ups.
I said to me,
the stuff that works on trained killers
is the best stuff and any you crazy kung
fu guys,
it's still think you can hang in MMA,
get in there with just Kung Fu training
and the high level guys are going to
take you down and they're going to choke
the fuck out of you and they're going
to leg kick you and they're going to
blast you. That's just the way it is.
You have to train in
mixed martial arts to be,
to be able to compete with those guys
because it's the best style of fighting
and that's exactly right.
It's what I was going to say.
I mean you look at something
like wingsuit, winterim,
tracking hands, sticky hands.
There's a few things about that than we
used in self defense that effective you
in close range.
But if you're going to rely on just that
sheet during a mixed martial arts fight
and try sticky hands against Anderson
Silva. True. True. But you know,
if you're in a fucking room where you're
getting your coat and some guy's drunk
for sure you can use sticky hands
to then sit up. There's guys,
there's some of those guys that can
fuck up pat on that and you can do those
chain fist to your face. That
shit's real. And this way,
Bruce Lee was the innovator yet again,
cause personally started in when children,
which by the way was develop our none
when you can actually was invented by
chick. Yeah. Yeah. Real in
tune was invented by a nun.
Oh you told me this before this though.
I don't know the full history.
I just know that a woman,
a chicken invented when children and
then of course you know most of the great
masters of it where we're men yet man
was Bruce Lee's teacher of course.
And that she probably got tired of
Dude's trying to fuck her virgin. Yeah.
If you're,
if you're a chick and you're,
your whole style fighting is
based on staying in one line.
I mean that's obviously a check.
Did not want to spread her legs.
And then he went against the wall,
very techniques with the kicks,
very short little kicks till the bottom
of the just snapping techniques as what
Bruce Lee was smart, you know,
he, he then realized, okay,
we need to him gave him the space and all
the shell in wouldn't dummy stuff that
they practice on or there's trapping
hands and you know, from there though,
he started to cross train hills the first
real one to to do it. He was a genius.
He was way ahead of his
time. And people, you know,
they look at Bruce Lee movies and
they're fun and everything, but the tech,
if you know really about Bruce Lee,
the techniques that he used in his movies,
he just use,
because they look cool.
Like his fighting style
of g Cuno the Dragon,
the first time that
mixed martial arts was on
movies, right when he
fought, uh, uh, was it, um,
somehow who was the guy who fought,
right?
Takes him down and arm bars and they got
a four ounce gloves on. I was like, yeah,
it can mixed martial arts here in the
70s we're seeing it on the screen.
Who Know, who started to train him and
grappling, right? Judo is, you know,
Jean Lynnville out, you know, he
was into all this different shit.
If you don't know judo,
gene Lebell is a mixed martial law,
is legend and just a real great guy,
a real character. But he's also like,
there's bear of a man,
you know,
he's got these giant hands and even
in his advanced age that he is now,
he's still, he's a beast. He's
a fucking beast. Back then,
my God, back when he was in
a a US champion judo player,
I mean cause an animal man,
he was a fucking beat suck.
So a guy like Bruce Lee who didn't
know any grappling, you know,
well let me show you something here.
But in the 135 pounds and you get that
motherfucker hoist and you through the
air, all that trapping hands is
doing nothing. Nothing at all. Yeah,
he's going to hit you with the earth.
You know,
judo guys are the scariest guys ever
to fight. If you're wearing clothes,
because this is grab a
hold of your clothes,
it's fucking throw you through
the air on your head. Judo.
And a lot of people
underestimate Trudeau as well,
which I think is an awesome marsh, right?
Guy Ms. Guy said to me one day, he goes,
brother, he goes, I judo throw you on
the carpet, you're going to a hospital,
I judo throw you on the street, you're
going to fucking morgue. So for me,
that summed it up perfectly.
That's Judah.
That's how impressive judo can be done
by a good, you know, good student of it.
Oh yeah, it's fucking lethal. Any real
high level wrestling judo is good.
But you know,
if a guy fucking really
knows how to wrestle and gets
your back and suplexes you
on the canvas, you're fucked.
You know what I mean? It's, it's,
it's anybody who can control your body
and then slam you to the ground, you know,
and there's stuff that happens
in the UFC fight and it, it,
the guy survives it and the guy will
be okay, like a perfect example.
Is that random and fade or flat or random.
And suplex fatal or right
onto his fucking head.
Luckily for fate or this is on
a padded floor and you know,
there's like give to the flight. I don't
know how, give me the Flores and pride,
but uh, the UFC is definitely got some
give to it. It's changed over the ears.
It's changed over the years.
Yes. He got a lot of times I'm a,
it fucked when it got from that
day, but he recovered, you know,
it's fucking swinging and
eventually one economy.
I caught him the Camorra shortly after.
Yeah.
But what I was going to say was that,
that was on the concrete days. Forget it.
You're,
you're hitting him with the earth.
It's like hitting it with a giant
rock that weighs 300 pounds.
There's two of you flying through
the air, you know, and you're,
you're slamming into this earth. Have you
ever been in a self defense situation?
Not since I was a kid. Not really.
You know, once I'm fear factor,
some guy got in my face, but it wasn't
like I didn't really have to do anything.
I just grabbed it. I got them into Thai
clinch. Actually that's what I did to him.
I'm like, no, it was like 16 months ago,
16 months ago, man. Really?
So we're out and about,
um, some friends have some coffee, we're
in a belt with some friends
and uh, you know, I,
and I honor her sister and her cousin and
her brother in law and we were driving
back home and I'm sort of parked at the
lights and this guys and as I just got
my brand new car,
by the way,
and the girls are sitting in
the backseat and was Irene who?
She started brother in law and her cousin
was in the front seat with me and his
guys has come across the street and
has gone on the window of the car.
The gills are fucking freaking out.
He's got this fucking smack my window.
All right. I thought he'd
broken something. So I'll
pull my car over, gotten out,
check the window and he's there sort of
like being a fucking clown. I'm like,
the fuck man, you fucking hit my car.
My girlfriend in the back of this,
he's still fucking chicks in the back
and I started to walk towards him.
He ran away. I'm like, fuck this man.
I'm getting an apology out of the sky.
So I chased the, I'll just, I'll
just fucking flipped out, man.
We ain't fucking bullies. I chased him
for an apology. I was that fucking angry.
Chased him for apology, wrap the street
and uh, found him and he must have been,
I don't want to drug use on,
he's sitting in the fucking ground like
he's going like this back and forth
rocking, right. My two of the fuck
he hit my car. You fucking freak out.
My girlfriend and her sister, like,
what the fuck is wrong with you man?
You're wondering on the street, you
get, get fucking run over. You know,
he was like, concern for him was concerned
by his mom. I was like, I'm like, dude,
you fucked up. I'm usually like that
because it's stupid. I'm like, dude,
you gotta fuck yourself. I'm getting
hurt. Run over, run over her.
He bounces up and just starts fucking
throwing punches at me and I'm like,
Oh shit, here we go. All right, so
blockies for those that don't know,
I'd studied more Thai for about three
and a half years back in Australia with
mark [inaudible].
So the Moitai lessons came flooding back,
some blocking his punches,
blocking his punches. And um,
I remember that mark had taught
me a technique back in the day,
which is not a Moitai technique, but
mark is uh, uh, a bouncer for many,
many years and it's actually his stories
that my best selling book Bouncer, uh,
were based on and he caught
it, bounce bounces. You got
a book called bounce? Yeah,
my,
I've done four books.
My first one was 99 called bounce and
based on real life nightclub bouncer
stories, no shit and cute. Can I get it
on Amazon or, yeah, you can get on Amazon.
Yeah, try. Amazon should still
be someone in his own idea.
He wrote books this syllable,
that's pretty bad ass. Hey,
my taught me this choke
or the bouncers choke.
We're basically just shoot your hand
out and rent the fingers around.
The larynx and just looking to squeeze
as the roadhouse. The roadhouse bounces,
drag queen. He called it something
like fucking blocking. I thought, fuck,
what am I going to do?
I'm just going to fucking
go for the bouncers tried
to shut it out and was like,
I got him perfectly start squeezing
his larynx and as I'm squeezing him,
he's like choking or put him down on
the ground and I'm on top of him still
choking him. I'm like, you're
going to fucking calm down now.
I don't want any trouble. Just
fucking calm down and I'll let you go.
All with the fucking Jedi Knight Dude.
Fucking around his larynx. I'm squeezing.
I could almost feel my
fingers coming together, man.
This guy's face started
to witness his defense.
Is he trying to get a hand in there? No,
no, no. He's just on the ground. Just,
just wondering why the fuck aren't I
breathing at the moment. I'm on top of it.
I'm a heavy guy pulling your
hands. Nothing. No. Nothing
at all. Nothing at all.
Terrible technique. Yeah, nothing at all
song. I weighed a lot more than he did.
Okay. And then I show once in a lot
more, cause this is a pretty decent guy,
but it might be had, I'll probably
had, would have had 12 kilograms on it.
Let's say, what did you learn from
this? There's more, there's more weight.
So he's on the ground. He got, he's
trying to not, so I'll let him up.
I might do just fuck off.
Enjoy your night.
But this time Irene and her cousin and
her brother and we'll come around the
corner.
So this guy walks off and then I walk
off to join them and then I turned around
and he's below a fence and he takes a
punch at me and actually caught me cause I
wasn't expecting it grazed me with like a,
I think you missed the,
he's watched or something grabs me. It had
to be grazed on my, on my, my, my, my uh,
foreign and he's walked off again.
And then for some reason he turns
around and he's about 20 feet away.
Just starts going, it takes a run up
for me. It takes a fucking run up.
And I'm like, Oh shit. Irene
standing right behind me.
There's no way I want this guy to start
punching me, get him on speed, Lsd,
something is on,
so I'm just thinking that was dean.
I don't know what else do they give any
people in Australia comes charging you?
I sit myself and then just,
I just from kicked him off
the real leaders boom to
the heart is a folding half
man folding house and he's too in
your front rainy and I was tying,
there's some boom into his chest and
his two mates came around and helped him
off and he was fucked up man. Wow.
W did you learn anything from us?
Probably not to chase the guy
for an apology next time. Not to.
Do you really need an apologia some
from some causes in a weird mood man.
It's just like a, hey bullies, I
cannot stand bullies and I stand there.
I'm not a violent person and
I cannot stand bullies and
it was just, it was fine.
But I think it's very
important in any situation.
And he real live situation like
that to always think row the pop the
probabilities and possibilities into the
old computer and come out with what's
worst case scenario here. Worst case
scenario, it could be pretty fucking bad.
You could die,
you could get stabbed,
you could have done some stall and break
your leg as you're chasing after him.
Then he beats you to death. Look,
it's not good. That's not good man.
Oh yes. My silly story ever is
not even about martial arts.
Do you mind if I tell you a blind
date story? I would love it. Okay,
so I'm so thankful to talk about martial
arts. We just nuts. I didn't plan on it.
We just started this way and we just, you
know, that's what it would, it became,
let me tell you,
I'm so happy now cause like Irene is
let the best woman in the world and you
know, we're engaged now. I proposed to
her in Rome like a couple of weeks ago.
I'm so thrilled because some of the
experiences I had with women in the past,
Joe, seriously, let me tell
you about this blind date.
I never used to go on blind dates and he
used to work on radio on a very popular
station in Melbourne called Kicks Fm.
And because I had this nice voice that
everyone thinks that I still think is
that good,
but I used to have gills ringing the
studio all the time asking me to go out
with it. I don't think your voice
is good. No, I never locked my,
what do you call yourself? The voice.
I don't, I was given that nickname.
But You keep it. I keep it to
Twitter name. She stuck with it.
I stuck with it.
There was,
give him to me by Andy Raymond
on Fox sports in Australia.
Someone was asking me about that.
It's always good to have a nickname,
which is was good name. It works.
Um, I'm sorry, go ahead. Yeah, cool.
This is a cool story. You gonna like
this one. It's a bit of a long story,
but you'll be entertained.
So anyway,
there's girls used to run the radio
station every day wanting to go out to go
out when it's go out and like,
no, no, never that. This one,
she rang up and her name was Elizabeth
and she had the hottest fucking voice on
the phone. Beautiful voice and, and,
and I thought to myself, fuck man,
I don't even get any action lately.
It might as well go on a blind date and
just see if I can maybe ways chicks is
hot and fucking get my, get my dick wet.
So Elizabeth rang up and I'm like, ah,
yeah. Okay cool. Maybe we'll go out. Tell
me, what do you look like? She was like,
I'm blonde and I've got a beach body and
blue eyes. I'm like, all right, cool.
We're good. Let's, let's hook up.
Let's go out. So night comes to go out,
my first blind date ever,
I drive to her house,
which is up in the fucking
sticks in the middle of nowhere.
I'm thinking to myself,
this guy,
but if he fucking hot cause
I'm driving all this way,
pull up at her house pack
in the gravel driveway,
front door opens and out walks this thing
that she looked like she should have
been living under a fucking bridge.
Okay. If she had a beach body,
it was the body of a fucking
beached whale or blonde greasy hair,
acne on her fucking face.
She's wearing this like blech.
Surely sort of dressed us,
draping on a lot fucking more
Tisha but not thin more teacher.
This girl's like twice my size.
Manage a fucking beast. Cut to you.
Naked White as right fluorescent lights,
Europe boning her and this popping in your
seventies music day.
She walked in,
I should have put the foot on
the gas then and gone do, do, do.
No, no. She walked out.
She was in barefoot walking on the gravel
driveway holding still letters in her
hand. I'm like this fucking dirty bitch
of the duty free going to get in my car.
Now she hops in the car and we're driving
into town because I booked a Sushi
restaurant and a movie and then to go to
a nightclub that my made and just open
up the sliding, I say I'll be right
back. I forgot something else still.
And I still am so much of a gentleman
that I just, I couldn't do it man.
I couldn't bring myself
to just drive off on her.
So driving into town and it was raining
and the reason I can remember it was
raining cause cause I had the windows
up and the reason I remember that is
because I'm driving.
I'm like
Oh this chick reaped of the worst
fucking beo you can imagine bro.
Imagine going to the gym for a week
and not showering. She fucking writ.
So I'm driving one hand on the wheel.
How many years ago was this?
This is a 2012 2011 years ago.
One Hand on the wheel smelling my other
hand to try and get rid of her fucking
smell pong and up my car.
So getting into town,
I thought fuck the Sushi restaurant are
going to spend money on Sushi for this
pig and then take a Tgi Fridays.
Alright,
so we're going to Tgi Friday's and we've
got to move. We were going to go see,
and I hate missing the trailers to movies.
I'm like fucking Elizabeth.
Finish your dinner in half an hour.
Movie starts at eight 30 we're
going to get a films. Okay.
You think it chicks on a date and
she's trying to impress you. She'll,
she'll get a,
a decent dinner but nothing,
be sure doesn't fucking brontosaurus
burger baby back ribs. Right.
And when they brought it to where you
think this fucking pig had never seen food
before,
she was like scooping shit into her
mouth and I'm just watching be muddled
going.
What the fuck is this chick doing?
Five minutes to go before
the movie starts. I'm like,
all right Lisa, you've done,
you finished. No, I want dessert.
She says, I'm like, all right, fuck.
So she orders dessert.
This like chocolate turtle thing.
You get a t jars or fudging cream
and ice cream and chocolate.
She's Scottish thing, like she'd never
seen a dessert in a life and trust me,
this fucking troll, it's in a lot of
desserts. She finishes up, I pay the bill.
I like having a chip, goes through
a person lace, but fucking,
she didn't go for a purse.
I slam and 50 bucks on the table
like the gesture the first yesterday.
I like the gesture,
but it's just your,
I appreciate we're going up
the escalators to the movies.
She's just seeding this too, cause
fucking dinner, right? She grabs my arm.
She goes, oh, I want a slushie.
I'm like, oh wow. I want a slushie.
Put the fuck's a slushie. She
doesn't even say opera. I swear.
Oh my God. Child. She's points
to a picture of a slurpee.
We call it in Australia and she goes,
[inaudible] points and grants.
So I go to the candy bow.
She went to pop a chop top ice cream at
big box of fucking popcorn and a coke
slurpee. It doesn't reach for her
money. I get nothing. All Right,
put 20 bucks in the fucking popcorn
counter. Sitting in the movies,
watching some romantic fucking Julia
Roberts film these bitches smelling up the
cinema.
She is dipping her ice cream into the
popcorn and eating it right and then
sleeping on this fucking slurpee.
What? She's pumping up the cinema.
I'm texting my mate on the phone going do,
there's no way I'm being in that bring
this fucking pink dog to your nightclub.
I'm going to get rid of earth.
So you another time.
So the movie finishes and she's like,
oh,
are we going to go to your mate's
nightclub? I'm like, yeah, Nah,
he's not there tonight. And
shots, we'll go another time.
How about I drop you home? So driving a
high and I'm thinking to myself, fuck,
this fucking animal is going
to go for the good night kiss.
If she goes to the goodnight kiss,
I'm fucked.
She'll pick me like fucking Hulk
Hogan pinned me down and kiss me some.
I think Michael Think, how do you get
out of the goodnight kiss with his pig?
And then I started, I thought,
Ooh, bit of reverse psychology.
So I start talking to her about kissing
deliberately. Yeah, I love kissing.
I'm a, I'm a good kisser. It's of my
specialty is one of my fucking awesome.
And she's like, good Lord,
juiced up in the car, Bro.
She's getting juiced up in the car and
you can see it like, yeah, really, really?
I'm like, yeah, I fucking love kissing. I
got her all worked up and then I as I go,
yeah,
but you know Lee's,
I was brought up a really good
Catholic boy and I was always taught,
never kiss a girl on the first day,
get to know her for three or four
dates and then maybe, you know,
kissap just try to bullshit by the way,
I'll fuck or go on a first date if I can
when anymore because I'm engaged in the
old days. And then her face
just like changed, like, oh,
breath. Really disappointed.
So get to her house,
she still goes in for a kiss on the lips
and I hated when fucking people do that,
by the way,
if they're not my girlfriend,
I hate people greeting
me by a kiss on the lips.
She goes to the a little
library. It's odd, man.
I got some female friends that do
it and, and I, I don't like it.
She goes to the kiss on the lips.
I turn the cheek,
she picks the shake out of the
car into the tech from hell.
Right there is an epilogue.
Okay. Date from hell.
It happened a week out
from Valentine's Day.
So next weekend comes Valentine's Day
on the Saturday cut to you. Why does
do,
well if she had away,
you're not too far off because on Sunday,
the night after Valentines,
I got a call from her best friend Wendy
and Wendy is like, hi Michael. It's Wendy.
Oh my God, you're so romantic. Oh
my God. Am I windy? Cool, thanks.
Um, why? She goes, oh my God,
the giant teddy bear and the flowers
and the chocolates you send to Elizabeth
for Valentine's Day. We're so
romantic. I'm like, Huh, what?
She goes, oh, the chocolates and the and
the teddy bear and the flowers. I got,
what do you mean Wendy?
Oh well are in Liz yesterday or last night
and she couldn't talk and she was all
breathy and panty and said she couldn't
talk to me because she was in bed with
you. Why fucking lost the
plot? I hang up from windy.
I rang Liz. I'm like, you
fucking based of a woman.
You're not only was there date
the worst fucking day from hell,
which is why I didn't ring you.
I guide them.
I actually felt sorry for you when you're
sick yourselves yourself chocolates
and a teddy bear and fucking flowers on
Valentine's Day because that's a sad,
lonely person that does that
and tells all her friends,
but the moment you insinuate I'm fucking
your ugly ass on Valentine's night and
go telling everyone my brother,
this is related directly to
you chasing down there. Dude,
that knocked on the web
really is all the same.
It's also creating unnecessary
conflict in your life.
This poor girl is genetically
fucked by Thor's Hammer.
You are rubbing salt into the wound
because her sad ass is pretending to be
fucking, yeah, I was sorry for
when she sent herself the gifts.
But then you go over the flipping a
gums at your fucking mean. Listen,
you got delta, a couple of
aces. Some people get to tos.
You know that's just the way life is.
Get this one that.
I'll tell you another freaky girl
experience from the past chicken. I mean
you're getting,
you're getting into this conflict
with his woman the unnecessarily.
This other one. I'm in her life
chasing that guy cause I want,
I'm going to a club this do
you know, feel, but you don't
feel bad for that beast.
The NMR the woman.
Yeah.
You don't feel bad for someone who's
just fucked intellectually fucked,
physically fuck socially knowing pieces
off the fuck socially cause at least
learn to buy a fucking
bottle of antiperspirant and
stick it under your fucking
arms. At least learn the decency to
walk to my car with your shoes on.
Who knows what lighthouse is led,
you know you're stepping into a life
that's already in progress and who knows
what the fuck has gone.
She called herself a beach body man,
unless she has a fucking beached whale.
Like I said,
last person man to this other
chick shrine, this other don't.
We'd like Catherine Zeta
giants was fucking hot,
so I met her at a nightclub and
got her details and she goes,
come over to my house.
So she lives down in Broadmeadows,
which have someone from
Melbourne's listening board
is the wrong end of town to
be on. It should have been
a warning sign again for me,
but it wasn't dry that the broad meadows
sitting there on on a, on a cipher,
her couch,
and we're watching some Johnny Depp
film I'd never seen called cry baby.
It was a five at 58 cocktail talk
to the watch and faggy movies left.
She was hammered when I got there on
fucking Jack Daniels and cokes. Right.
She was handed by the time I get the
head of it and like two six packs in the
kitchen was churning through, sitting
there watching this, watching this, this,
this.
It was a video type actually watching it.
The first thing I noticed was there's a
little coffee table to the side of the
couch where I was sitting. There was a
fucking butchers knife, brother. That big,
just sitting there as a mate there.
Nothing, just a fucking knife that big.
That sort of freaked me
out. I'm like, all right.
Sitting there watching the movie
and all of a sudden I hear this
fucking baby crying. I'm like,
the fuck was that? She goes, oh,
that's my three month old daughter. Just
a moment. I'm going to give her a bottle.
Oh fuck this chick's got a three month
old daughter I didn't know about.
All right. She goes in the kitchen,
she makes up the baby's formula,
puts it in the microwave nukes.
It goes back in the baby's room,
comes back and joins me like 30
seconds later. Impressive plan.
The video is amazing when you think
about how little a person has to know you
before you're over their house. Like
you don't even know that she has a baby.
That's how limited your interaction has
been and all of a sudden you're over her
house. But this is the
thing though. I usually,
it's my journalistic background
asks so many questions,
but for some reason she didn't tell
me this and she goes and gives a kid,
the bottle comes back 30 seconds later.
I'm like, actually gonna feed the kid.
Then you smack the bottle. Oh yeah,
don't worry if she gets hungry,
she'll pick up the bottle and feed herself
up. Three month old with a hot bottle.
Whoa, whoa. I'm like, okay, this chick
is fucking freaked out by this time.
I'm totally put off her complete.
Even though she looked like Catherine
Zeta Jones, I'm put off when I'm put off.
That's it.
I'm put off.
So the movie ends and she tries to get
a little frisky and I'm less likely not
real. I've got to go. I gotta work
tomorrow or whatever on the front step.
And she's like, she's tanked off her nut.
She'd drunk by this stage. She's like,
no JB with the three month old drunk
with a three month old with a bottle and
it's cre bright. And she was
like, baby baby don't go yet.
Let me show you this party trick pro.
She takes her top off on our front
doorstep. She got this big ass tits,
grabs a Boob, lifts up to
her mouth, starts licking
your nipple. If Front of me,
I'm just like,
that's the Worki,
the whole baby butches knife.
You're drunk Johnny Depp,
you'd be fucking tip not working.
I leave her drive home two days later
I'm in a business meeting at like midday
and she calls.
So I let it go through to voicemail.
She calls again cause again cause again.
Cause again,
fun leaves a message for
me prior to the message,
the next hour after our meeting and
finished the most abusive fucking message
you've ever heard. You fucking come
to you piece of Shit, mother fucker.
Every swear word you can imagine, you're
just like every other man. Never call,
never texted this and that.
Don't pick up the phone when I call you.
This fucking lost it at me. Yeah.
Wow. That's par for the course.
That's par for the course
was human beings. Oh Man.
You know you can say it's checks. It's
cause that's who you're dating suicide.
If you were dating dudes, stories
would be even more pathetic to Ida.
Chick threatened to slit her wrists
because I want to take her out of your
fucking savage. Look at
you. That's what it is.
You know why she can't help herself.
She was a bikini model.
She thought she was that hot and she was
hot. She texted me photos of herself,
but I was busy at the time and I'm like,
yeah, maybe I've got to go away overseas.
Maybe I'll like,
you know,
we'll hook up in three weeks time as she
cracked the shit that she wasn't high
list of my priorities. Send me all these
pics of her in a bikini. I'm like, yeah,
that's all pretty big. As
long as if I haven't seen a
fucking models before. Dude,
like relaxing you stud. Do. She sat
in the Bathtub, import Melbourne,
rang me and threatened to slit her wrists.
I got a think there's more to the story.
My more I just cannot listen to,
there is no back. Just not
your part. Oh No. My life is
a fucking wreck. Yeah. Yeah.
You stepped into a bad,
so she fights having a head,
Schumer just to try and get me to
call her back and then she apologized,
said none. I wasn't hit him. I was lying.
The next day she sends me a text message
saying my box hurts her box and box and
I'm like, what do you mean? She goes,
my box hertz and then tried to tell me
she had cervical cancer and by this stage
I'm just like,
this is really bad because I had people
that have died from cervical cancer.
I'm like, that's just don't talk stupid
fucking shit to try and get my attention.
You need a life coach, brother.
Dude, all those days are over.
This is many moons ago.
Mind you go out chasing derelicts,
punching your window.
The life coach broke.
Amazing that something ever in a
situation like they're calling me up.
I will be up, we'll smoke a joint
together and we'll talk this through.
It sounds good, man. See,
he's some advice. Crazy. Say
beaches. How it say go. Oh Wow.
For real tumor. Damn. That's not gonna
stop me for fucking you, isn't it?
You go good. And he'd come over
and fuck the shit out of her.
And then she tells you she's wonder
woman. You go, that's awesome.
I'll call you next week.
And then you leave so that what you do
is whatever craziness she says, he go,
oh wow, that's crazy. That's
fucking crazy. I hope you're
okay. Listen, I gotta go.
I'll call you later and we still got
to fuck. And then she'll say yes,
and then you show up when you fuck that
crazy bitch and that's what you do.
I'm scared to for crazy bitches.
Then they don't do it.
But the crazy ones are often the most fun.
Yeah.
Our friend Tony always says it best.
He said that erotic and psychotic,
our next door neighbors, my, my mic
picked up a crazy chick in a bar.
I think I told you the story last time
and he gave him Melman finger finger and
she had the Melvin name.
Oh Mel Meninga. It's,
and I'm a very famous Australian rugby
player. Melman Mel Meninga Melman.
So at school we used to say,
oh I gave this chicken Mel
Meninga three finger mal Meninga.
So what does that mean?
It means he finger three fingers.
Why is he have a name for fingering piece?
Just cause he rides with
finger mal Meninga. Oh,
so you haven't had a skill at this girl's
story is like finger and other players.
Melman Nina, the girl and she
had scabbed inside a pussy.
Well words gabs inside a fucking
pussy. I don't know. It's possible.
What she'd scratching on the inside that
you feel this gams no, it wasn't me.
It was my mate. He just like, dude, I
fingered her and the fucking scared up.
They'll hire your friend might be full
of Shit. Now you've done some dirty shit.
Yeah. Then that's pretty foreign to
have scabs inside your pussy. Yeah.
If you should scabs and a fucking,
it was like she likes it'd be playing
a shit if you hit those like wow,
that was fucking hurt to do.
You know what you got to find a neat
one day is the willed six games or
something, right. It was held in like
Japan or something. It's a funny as shit.
They have a ring like a boxing ring and
they have couples in each corner and one
of the ones was the guy has to stand
there and look, feel the chicken,
whichever chick close. The first wins.
There's all these like six games.
There was another one where
there was like a an alley,
like a long jump sort of alley.
They had measuring parts on it.
The girls would sit there with their
fucking legs spread finger themselves and
see who could blow the furthest.
It's on the Internet.
You got to find it somewhere like
world six Olympics or world six games.
All this crazy fucking Asians fingering
themselves blowing everywhere so you
could blow the whole squirting thing.
I'd just, that is fucking foul.
I don't understand the appeal of that.
Even if it's not pissed,
it's suspect.
I that's 20% piss for sure is,
I mean it was still there,
right?
We're actually getting all the fucking
juice from fuck. Is that kind of,
what is that?
That's salty and it'd be like,
I don't want to know what it tastes like.
Oh, I don't want to experience it, dude.
I figured this girl once and I couldn't
get the smell of a bad smelling poon off
my hands for like a week. Only once,
once that was all to the clean life once,
and I think they'd be spots on my
finger and I'm ringing my make going,
what the fuck is this chick dancing?
I've got spots on my finger and
I can't get the smell off it.
I washed and scrubbed that
fucker and just what I had, uh,
one of my first girlfriends
ever had of stinkbugs disaster.
What are you doing man?
He was a disaster and he fucking eat.
I had to go with a steep talks.
Tough. But when you're 17, you're a,
Dick is so hard.
It's this carbon fiber cock.
Dick just doesn't give a fuck your
Dick as willing to, you could,
you could have a dead squirrel in your
mouth and your dig would still be hard.
What's worse though,
if a chick has the fucking rotten box or
like an Hungarian Chicago been out with
ones, has lobbied the luck fucking
curtains. You've got to find out.
I don't mind that. I like real
the fucking flag, the labs,
Juicy Pussy Lips and bother me at all.
I don't give a fuck. That feels good.
That's like a big grippy cause he oh,
big strong box milky speaking of
lips on and those Polish Gill,
the looked like Natalie Portman.
She was fucking hot and she's
known amongst my friends.
When I tell the story of being bottom
lip Kisa this chick would only keys with
her bottom lip. Okay. There are
no top lit, no time. Just uh,
I, I broke up with her because I,
after six weeks of going out with her,
I'm getting with her leap in the
car cause I'm getting with her,
I'm getting with their lip with passion
and the Cup passions in Australian word
for Kesha. Did you ask her to kiss
with the upper lip as well? As I said,
at least two. I'm going to think that
weird lizards. I'm like these one.
Have you ever kissed like the top
lippy Tanga as she just was like,
well this is the way our kiss.
If you don't like it then don't kiss me.
And she was fucking hot and I'm
like, Oh fuck. Okay Sir. Anyway,
but she wasn't put a chicken check
when they talk like that or not.
She was the moment the girl said
something like that and go, listen,
you seem like you're in a bad mood.
Somebody send you home,
can you take care and I'll call you later.
So He'd wherever you go,
my shoulder when he could meet me,
cause that's the reason I dumped her.
Eventually after six weeks
were making out in the car,
I lean over to put a hand on a tip
on top of her clients. You suck. No,
I want it to be special. The fuck.
After six weeks I can't even get it.
Fucking tits. This is all shit that I
happened to me when I was in high school.
It's true about Australia.
Like you guys like catch on late.
Like things happen later for you.
How's the light blue man?
I was the biggest fucking
nerd when I was young.
It took me get your first slice
of Pie. Fuck man. My first,
you know what my first kiss was at 16?
My first slice of Pie was not until like
21 tap damn with a French maritian girl
that I was dating who was like there at
times marine French murder. It's like,
Whoa, this French maritian girl named
Anik qls hot too. Yeah. But uh, man,
I was a late bloomer, but I might
approach it in due time. Listen man,
you're always gonna run into weird
people if you're trying to date because
you're going to go and run into weird
people just randomly try to make friends.
You know,
the problem is people are so horny that
they're not that particular about who
they stick their penis and inside.
That's why you wind up with so many
fucked up situation. So you have,
the thing that shoots me,
and maybe you can relate to this as well,
is that ice when I stood date chicks
and the got the chicks knows like chicks
that I used to like they
didn't like me back then,
but recently because my profile's gone up,
you know,
working on TV and people are
seeing my face on TV and stuff.
Those chicks like send you
a message out of nowhere,
find you on Facebook or find
you on Twitter or you know,
they suddenly have your number back in
their phone. They're like texting you.
Yeah, let's go out how you're doing. Been
thinking about, it's like the fuck man.
Only because you've seen me
on TV or something. You can
fucking squirming visit,
take advantage of that and
just stuff you're cocking
sounds to me like the throngs of
Pussy near all indignant about it. Uh,
at least to be very selective about my,
my pussy selections may need a life coach.
I'm telling you,
I can help you to do I ever
tell you that in my service.
I have to tell you what happened in
Vegas the first time I went there at rate
actually racist or doesn't
even know this story.
I can't believe I'm about to tell it now.
Freight listens. He'll kill me. Dante,
I'll tell it. Fuck it. Throw Ray under
the bus. No, right? Wasn't there.
It was all using Ray's house. Oh, I
was in Vegas for the first time ever.
This is like going back
in 2006 or 2007 for k one.
And after the show we'd say to Bellagio
for k one and I stayed at res for a few
nights,
but he was going to Japan.
So I had a whole house to
myself and I met this girl at a,
at Caesars beautiful black girl, man.
She looked a bit like Janet Jackson Ish,
sort of really hot.
And I had a number and I thought I'll
give her a call and see what she's doing.
Right. Had a big fucking house in Vegas
with a Jacuzzi out there. And I'm like,
hey, this will be impressive. So I've
written this girl and she's like, oh yeah,
cool.
I'm not doing anything.
I'll come over with my cousin is that I
came and I'm like, sweet, come on over.
Got a whole house fridge, stocked of
alcohol, fucking a fridge full of food.
Come on over.
So she comes over with a
cousin and a cousins crack
and hot as well. I'm like, oh,
this is too good to be true. And
she goes to me, um, do you smoke?
I'm like, no, no, not
really. And she goes,
do you want to have like a puff in the
Jacuzzi? Oh fuck it. Which was like,
we'd just talking about weed. Weed,
right. I got, okay, cool. She goes,
do you smoke blunt? And I know what's
going no. Then on what plenty is,
I know what's planted.
Is it like marijuana?
She started describing the
fucking process, whatever to me,
but she got like a cigar that was at that
big and somehow slice it with a razor
blade and hollowed it out and stuffed all
this blunting there. So we're going to,
the word it is, is, is two
different ways. Okay. In England.
A lot of times they'll leave enrolled
their joints with a tobacco in it.
They'll roll like cigarette tobacco
and somebody's doing in Australia too.
They do that to make it burn longer.
They'll burn out. Don't do that.
It's terrible for you and it ruins the
whole thing. And then the other ways,
the blunt, there's two ways of doing
that. Sometimes with tobacco inside of it,
but most of the time not,
but using the tobacco leaf,
which is the cigar case,
you know,
the different students of Gars and joints
or cigarettes is that if you smoke a
cigar, the you are actually, there's
a, an actual leaf that's covering it.
The whole thing that you're smoking
is pure plant manner, you know,
and a good cigar. Especially like their
prized for their leaf and the rapper,
you know, it's a special plant that they
grow just particularly for that purpose.
Well, you know, when you inhale it
though, you don't inhale a cigar.
When you smoke a cigar, you take a
breath, you keep it in your mouth,
in any blow it out and you taste and
you get a buzz from the nicotine,
but you inhale weed.
So when they roll these blondes,
their inhaler and this
deep heavy tobacco plump,
the type of weight or just the way
you roll away roll is a type of way.
No nightgowns away. Rolling. Okay.
Gotcha. So she, well she called us,
she rolled a blunt.
She printed this God backhoe.
It's tobacco and weed together because
of the tobacco leaf is going on.
She puts in this big ass Nigga.
We got to the Jacuzzi. I'm like,
this is fucking mad is too hot.
Chicks either side of me in the Jacuzzi.
It's like nine o'clock
paper getting it.
I'll take two puffs on this
thing and dude, I'm fucked. My,
my mind felt like it was just
floating over there and I'm like,
this is fucked me up. I'm
going to get back inside.
Came back and saw him walking.
I can feel my body walking, but my
mind's wandering off until another realm.
You know, I plunked down on Ray's big
chair and then the girls come in like,
you know, 25 minutes later and
they're drying off and I'm,
the cousin starts to sit on my lap
and mess around and going to be sign
aggressive cousin and then the other
girls is helping us sell in the fridge,
eating, having some drinks, whatever.
Cousins are loving me on this. Just cool.
Still off my fucking brain. She goes,
don't you want to go upstairs? I'm like,
sweet. So then you're upstairs.
The other one robs you.
Rob's Ray's house upstairs into rise
bedroom and raised beds was like fucking,
he had this bed with posts
like a jungle fucking bagels.
Really pimp his wardrobe was the
size of this room. Fucking huge.
So lying down on the bed,
getting naked, you know, blah,
blah blah or mucking around. It'd be, it
erases. Got One of his world title belts,
neither Baden, right? She was
like, do you like being spanked? My
hello, whatever you want to sell. Phones,
world title bounce. She gets the right.
His world title bout turns me over
and started whacking me on the arch.
We these world title it's in, there's
kickboxing world title belts, the speeds.
A fucking heavy man. Whoa
again, you need your life coat.
He called me up here.
John met Ray Sefo with the
world's heavyweight champion.
This bitch wants to hit me with his
belt. What do I do? You say no, the fuck
I turn back over.
That's when it fucking or by now and
she's [inaudible]. She's talking too much.
She goes, me, baby. If he got what I need,
I'm like, oh yeah, it's in the bathroom.
Just go get a condom and I'm told
toiletries bag in the bathroom and cool.
She goes, no baby. If he got what I need
to fucking rubbers in the bathroom,
go grab one radio.
Fucking what you need right here.
These cocaine. She goes, no, baby.
You see my car's in the pound and it's
going to cost $400 to get it out and I'm
really strapped for cash too. I sobered
up in a hurry. I'm like, Oh fuck.
I go, you fucking hooker.
Oh baby, don't be like that.
I just need the money for my car and
I'm like, are you a fucking hooker?
And she like admitted to it. I fucking
grabbed her, threw her off. Me.
How many girls rock the hooker
world that way? Ran Downstairs.
Cause then that picture of a mom
thing to someone's me at Ray's house,
Rez got all this fucking cool shit and
chooses sitting on the sofa reading,
fucking eating and drinking a grabbed her,
grabbed her cousin,
threw them out the fucking front door.
Should have went with the cousin,
the cousin and she's the
one if 160 bucks later man.
So do you think that that's how the,
she rocks it all the time.
She shows up a guy's houses and just ask
them for money when she gets him horny?
I think so.
Cause I was ready to go and then at where
to get killed is going to get killed.
I all's ropable man. I grabbed
her, grabbed the girlfriend again,
think about how quickly you get intimate
with someone that you don't even know
how crazy that is. You
know? I mean, it's like,
that's the weirdest thing about dating
is how quickly people are willing to get
intimate with complete total strangers.
And The lady with the three month
old baby lets you in the house,
you don't even know this fucking brought
out a baby and you're already alone
with her and she's looking at her tits,
you know, it's like with a knife. Yeah.
If you had to make friends
the way you try to get laid,
like if it was like really important,
like you needed a friend every couple
of days, you know, I mean, Jesus Christ,
your friendships would be fucking chaotic.
They'd be crazy if we needed
friendship as much as we need sex,
which by the ways it's real possible.
You know? Has he ever dumped a friend?
Like you would dump a girlfriend? Yes.
You have done a friend dump of a guy,
not a million times of a dude.
Yup. Yeah. What did you say to him?
Can I hang out with you anymore?
Just negative. Straight off. Yeah.
There's some dudes that you will,
uh,
you will have good times
with in the beginning,
but then somewhere along the line, as
you get to know them better, their,
their character flaws are exposed,
exposed,
and they're not willing
to be honest about it.
So then every time you're hanging
with that person, it becomes
a problem becomes all around that person.
It becomes this person's character to
flow that everybody has to like sort of
deal with, whether it's jealousy or
whether it's being overly aggressive,
whether it's being dicky to
women, you know, do whatever
the fuck it is. You know,
there's,
there's certain dudes that are not
willing to look at reality and then not
willing to evolve.
And the real problem is if you surround
yourself with someone like that,
that all your evolution stops as well
as there's all your progress as a human
being stops, as does theirs.
So when you're out with them,
that if they're enacting
conti and Douchey, you're,
you're locked into this conti,
douchey life. You know, this
is, this is your, your crew.
This is who you're hanging out with,
man.
And if you don't surround
yourself with likeminded people,
you don't grow together.
So when you're with someone that you
feel like is a roadblock to your own
personal enlightenment,
it's important for you to separate
yourself from that person.
We have a heat from this guy again.
And when you did the Oakwood,
Guilford has been a full time. It was
a few different guys, not just one man,
a bunch of different guys over the years,
you know, just people just, um, you know,
and I'm, look, I'm a very good
and loyal friend and um, I,
I pride myself on,
on keeping good and loyal
friends and you know, and,
and making them appreciate,
making them realize how much I appreciate
them and making them, you know,
I think friendships are one of the most
important things you could foster in
this world. You know, to develop,
to be able to hook up with
people that are interested.
Like the one of the most beautiful things
about this podcast has been the fact
that I've exposed a lot of people to the
friends that have cultivated my friend
Brian Cowen and Duncan and all these
really brilliant people that I know that
are really interesting
cats and I mean that's my,
my proudest achievement in
life is surrounding myself
with an interesting group
of friends. And I shouldn't say
proudest but most most satisfying. Yeah.
Wow. This is amazing. I have such, I'm
so lucky to have such cool friends.
The only way you can
have that is if you call,
you have to get rid of ones that don't
keep up cause that not everybody keeps up.
Just like not every girl,
like you have this great girl in Irene,
but look how many comments you
had to go through to get to her.
Well that's just the way it
is with friends as well. It's
the same thing. You, you,
you, you will appreciate people
that have their shit together.
When you deal with enough
people that don't, and there
are certain point in time,
some people are just not willing to
take personal responsibility and grow.
And when you run into those people,
you got to,
you got to separate from them because
their roadblocks, they become problems.
There's,
there's no growing and it all becomes
dealing with them and their issues.
And as you get older,
you realize,
don't you see how many friends you had
when you were young? And as you get old,
you call it and call it and call it.
And Dude,
I've got like five friends that I keep
really close like my inner circle,
but no shit about me than everyone else
is a big fucking perimeter around that
inner circle. You know, it's an sorry,
but the more you travel as well and you're
away from home and a wife from those
friends,
you realize how much you love them and
how much you do need them in your life.
Yeah. And close to you and giving that
love too in that positive energy to you.
So that you can survive in
your own life. Yeah. Yeah.
You grow together. You know, we human
beings if like I always of of of,
you know my,
my closest friends that like my friend
Brian Callan is a perfect example.
Like if Brian consider something and he
brings it to me and tells me about it,
I know that it's going to be well thought
out and I know that I can consider it
almost as,
as if it's my own thoughts.
Like I can appreciate his experiences and
his interpretations of his experiences
so much I can,
I can trust in them so much that I trusted
them almost as much as I would trust
in my own because of the genuine friends
that you know have no personal agenda
that we have crossed that give you what
I recommend is going to be solely for
your own benefit and nothing to gain
from it. Solely honest. Yeah, exactly.
Cause there's folks that you talk to
where you, you don't get that man.
You don't get the honesty.
You get this weird amalgamation of the
truth and fiction because they don't want
to come off looking like a loser or they
don't want to come off looking like an
asshole when in fact maybe you know,
some more shit was their fault and you're
not getting the full version of it and
they want you to back them
up. You know, if you're,
my friend did back me up like no,
if I was your friend,
I would tell you when
you're being a Douche bag,
you know that idea that you know, a
friend has to only be positive, you know,
all the time when you're being negative,
they can't be honest about it. Yeah,
it's a, it's a real problem that people
have fostering good friendships and good
relationships.
And you know,
that's one of the happiest things that
I've been able to do with this podcast.
I've talked to so many people
that we've met, you know,
all over the country that don't have
people that are thinking like this around
them.
So they're not exposed to a lot of the
stuff that we're talking about in their
neighborhood or their community. And their
and their circle, their social circle,
you know, and you got to find people
like this, you gotta, you gotta,
you gotta find people that you can
trust and that and hang out with because
they're out there,
they're out there.
You could have a bunch of negative
conference and just think that all your
friends and all the people that you
ever going to meet or negative comments,
and then all of a sudden you'll
just find some oasis of Nice people.
And if you're not a negative
con and those people like you,
then all of a sudden your life
in measurably gets better.
If your friendships are good,
your life is a measurably better.
That's why I always tell people in
bad relationships and bad friendships,
just fucking get out.
If you're confident that it's not you,
if you're a nice person,
if you then just get out.
Did I seen some people stick around
in marriages or relationships,
which fucking abuse? Yelling matches
every night. You know how it's like,
how the fuck do you stay there?
And there's some people that would tell
you if you don't yell, you don't love it.
It's hilarious. It's motion, man.
I've never yelled at Irene. You know,
we've never had a yelling match.
We might have disagreements,
but they fucking over in 30 seconds and
then I get nasty. No yelling matches.
Just like, why would you
yelling matches usually come.
I think in relationships with someone
is trying to point score under a partner
and get the upper hand and always
think to myself, if you love someone,
why the fuck would want to try and
point score on them? You know? It's all,
it's all in how you getting raised?
I think a lot of it,
a lot of it is people
growing up with horrible,
horrible relationships and sometimes
people grow up in horrible relationships
and it actually makes them better at
relationships because they realize,
well fuck, I don't want to be like
my mom and dad. Yeah. You know,
I'm not into fighting. So you
know, I've met girls that they,
their parents fought like crazy,
so they were like really cool and calm
because it seems so much stupid shit.
And Men the same way.
It's like, you know, the,
the real reality of relationships is the
idea of finding one's human being and
you've lived 30 plus years of programming
and changing your personality and
molding to your environment and,
and adapting to all the shit
that you see in your world.
And then add a known where you introduce
some new player and you've got to
decipher like the
fucking Dead Sea Scrolls.
So you've got to go back and figure out
where all this comes from, where's this,
where's this attitude?
Why is that attitude of why?
Why does she get indignant when
I don't know, open her car door.
Like when is the root of this?
And you know,
how much did she really believe in
this God thing? You know? And then you,
you know, like you said, meeting that
person, you think to yourself, okay,
there's 6 billion people in the world.
Let's call for three and a half billion
of them women and you're trying to make
this one and you're trying to meet
this one. Pretty much. We came,
what a 20 kilometer radius of your house.
Do you know,
trying to meet her into state or
another city around the kilometers.
What does that in miles have no lifting.
Let's have a cool 20 miles of your house,
30 miles of your house,
and your ratio of where you go out to
your perimeter circumference where you hit
out too much. You know, you'd have to
get too much pussy quotes. Exactly.
And that's a minuscule, like the betting
odds on that must be insane of funny.
That person are you getting in Los
Angeles? There's so many fucking people,
you know, it's not going
to be the perfect. I mean,
you know what is the perfect
poppet person, you know,
and it's like everybody's got their own
different version of what the fuck that
is. But the reality with most people
is they don't like themselves,
so they're going to be a shitty
relationship no matter what.
No matter who they get hooked up with,
they're going to be self
defeating and self sabotaging.
That's the majority of people,
especially people struggling,
especially people that
aren't happy with their,
their art or their career or their chosen
profession or whatever the fuck it is.
They're pursuing and they're in some
state of turmoil where they're trying to
accomplish some things.
A lot of people out there unhappy with
themselves man and they're not going to
be happy no matter who the fuck
they're with. They're going to,
they're going to get comfortable with
anybody and start being dicky with them
cause they're dicky with themselves.
And like you said that the pip you don't
want to pay around cause a negative
energy is just fucking intense man.
You know,
he was saying before about the friends
and how you'll close friend friends
sometimes therefore to like
similar to your thoughts. Yes.
Do you believe in stuff like um, if
you have a research Ed Casey, you know,
who could apparently medically treat
people by apparently be able to tap into
the worldwide consciousness of everyone
and pluck any information he needed from
any mind in the world to be able to dog
knows someone I haven't heard pro and
con for Edgar Casey,
my friend Eddie is a big proponent of
Edgar Casey but he's also big into Ufos.
He loves sexy things.
He loves ghosts and spirits and
channelers and he loves all that stuff.
Me, I am a, um, I'm a cautious optimist.
And so I think it's,
it's interesting to me that there could
be a possibility of some person who has
some incredible extra sensory perception
to the point where they can read your
future or your past or
find out things about you.
But I'm now convinced I'm not convinced,
and I'm also not convinced that people
are being objective about their accounts
because I know like many other things,
people want to believe that shit works.
Here's an example.
There was a stupid fucking thing going
around where people were wearing these
holograms rubber band and one
of the guys that was selling it,
uh, came to Vegas and God, man,
all these really talented athletes
who were swearing by this man,
it was kind of crazy. I was watching this
mass hypnosis. I mean, fucking Shane,
Karlyn was telling me how great they were.
Yeah. It really, really has helped me.
This, I'm like, dude,
you're a goddamn engineer.
You really think this chip a plastic
rubber band around your fucking risks.
It's a total placebo.
You'll actually drawing these positive
energy too. It's just like religion, man.
If you really do believe that you're,
you're, you're fucking gods soldier,
you're out there doing God. You really
truly believe that man, you will be bad.
Who positive energy.
If you believe that praying to God
brings you what you want in life.
We really doing, he's just
transmitting your positive energy.
I want the swivel drawing these to me.
I've got to manifest in my life. Yeah,
and I mean it really does
work. Yeah, but so anyway,
so these guys are selling them in Vegas
and they're doing these carnival tricks
to sell them. The guy's like, okay,
straighten your arm out. All right,
now I'm going to give you the bracelet.
Now straighten your arm out and like,
what the fuck are you do? Like you
don't think I understand leverage.
You move your arm. You're in a different
position. Now this is like this.
This is working on MMA guys.
This is,
people want to believe
bullshit is my point.
This is 2011 and these crazy people
are still wearing these God damn rubber
bracelets with these holograms. So in the
life we live in the society we live in,
people are always looking
to get that upper hand.
You're looking to get
that slight edge or wow,
if this bracelet can give them an x slide
edge I my opponent edge of my work and
then want to believe that the price
is going to give them that edge.
Of course they give,
they made that.
They give themselves that edge naturally
by this self belief. Yup. Yup. Okay fine.
If the bracelet helped you do
it, but the price, like you said,
it's self does not have any magical power.
Isn't that the same in Australia?
It was a newspaper article that came
out exposing those prices for Torsion as
total complete, utter
horseshit. It's thievery.
These people are liars.
It's, it's really simple.
They really believe that a god damn
piece of plastic is going to change your
magnetic frequency. Shut the
fuck up. Okay. You know I,
I I in Hayden, I don't want you
arrested. You know, you made your money.
Congratulations. But it's
craziness. Yeah. Yeah,
but a lot of people want to believe in
it and it's interesting to me that people
are so anti performance enhancing drugs,
yet they'll wear a rubber band with
a fucking Hologram on it. You know,
like it's going to reprogram your system.
Like, wait a minute man, what do, what do,
what do you, what do you do doing that?
That's not natural. Is that, that's okay.
What if the, what does that Hologram
made you? Superman. Would the,
you know what people still be
complaining about it with the Hologram.
You put it on and all of a sudden you're
jumping over tree tops. Yeah. You know,
I mean,
would you say now we have to take it off.
It's too good performance
enhancing drugs if it works at all.
It's performance enhancing. If it works at
all. It's natural. Yeah. It's so strange.
What arbitrary line in the sand
we draw as to what is a vitamin,
what is an athletic supplement
and what is performance enhancing?
What level does it yet,
because there's all that
shit is performance and ants
and goddamn vitamins are
performance enhancing a headache tablet.
Because you got a headache before
find its performance enhancing,
it's going to enhance the performance.
You know,
anything can be constructed as performance
enhancing it. So it's vitamins are,
I mean if you're,
you're eating regular food and you get
to a certain amount of nutrients from
food and then on top of that you're
force feeding yourself massive doses of
vitamins B12 and fucking guess what your,
your that's performance enhancing.
I completely think it should be legal
and I think it's very healthy for you and
it's very beneficial for your body.
And I'm not saying that athletes
shouldn't take, and I'm saying what line,
where does that line get drawn?
What do you think about the,
here's a perfect example and I wanted
to talk to you about this coming on the
show. What do you, cause you
don't have a horse in this game.
What do you think about
this whole testosterone
replacement therapy thing like
this? What's going on with Nate
Marquardt and all these other fighters?
That's a tricky little thing isn't
it? It's difficult. You know you get,
if you go to testosterone depletion union
body and you need to take the drugs to
boost your levels up to that of a normal
personal event of the person you're
competing against.
Listen though we've Kaiser who I've
had my problems with in the past,
the head of the Nevada state athletic
commission took a very strong stance on
this and I support him and one of the
reasons why I support him as he won't
allow testosterone replacement therapy
for people who have tested positive for
steroids before.
And you know why?
Because people that test positive or
stars you ruin your fucking body when you
take steroids and you're nuts don't
work anymore and that's what's going on.
Right,
right.
Any fun cheeky club becomes like a dick
and I see his argument in that there
shouldn't be as far as you want to compete
as an athlete when you've ruined your
body from cheating, you
know there is, there is,
there's a strong moral statement to be
made there that I do see that point.
I'm not necessarily sure that I agree
with it because I think you should be
allowed to make mistakes in the past.
And I know how much performance enhancing
effect a cycle that you did six years
ago is going to have on today and it's
nothing. You might have damaged your body,
but it doesn't mean that you shouldn't
be able to stand up as an athlete and
perform.
But I think you probably should have
to do some sort of public relationship
explaining and maybe perhaps you
know, letting people know, hey,
please don't do steroids cause my balls
don't work anymore. You know what I mean?
You want to,
you want to compete as an athlete and
they should be much more stringent in your
testing when you're testing.
They got to watch you all year round.
They can't just because guys will get
super juiced and then they level off right
before they get on a cycle
and then they hide it.
There's there's masking factors you can
use the harder the way you it I believe.
I'm not sure. Maybe someone can tell us
as blood testing, he loved tech guys.
You can,
you can even detect human growth hormone,
which they're not doing in Nevada.
They're not doing blood tests.
He loved to play around a lot of this
and they recently got criticized by some
anti-doping,
something organisation was talking
about what the Nevada state athletic
commission is doing. And they're
saying there's two reasons why their,
their system is very ineffective, you
know, and then they're doing their best.
But the two reasons are, one, they're
doing just urine tests testing,
which just doesn't show enough to treat.
Man.
I've heard so many stories of so many
fighters and there they've cheated.
You're on tests to show
up with a nonhuman piss.
Like Kevin Randleman had some guns,
like got some possum pissed guys in
Japan that if you use Fike penises,
so the other guy standing next to them
and here in America and they're going to
fight fucking plastic deal that
actually has someone else's piece in it.
So this squeezing out of the deek
someone else's piece that's clean,
obviously it's a urine wizard eight or I,
some of the commission is going to
get in touch that they can check.
It's for real. You know, it's
like, it looks like, right? Yeah.
It's hard to figure out so they
have to stand like right over you.
So I guess these guys have to just get
that pissing with the fake dick down.
They've got to get really good at it yet.
But this is why he's a paypal Moscow.
If a guy's not shy though, you
can go, let me see your deck.
Let me say it and attach it
on and I would touch fake
fake death. Paula, I'm gonna
pull on it real quick. Pull on.
It just comes on and off. We're getting
shaken in front of them. Like a jellyfish.
You mother fucker.
This is a fake Dick.
How privileged you think growth is in
the sport? Huge. I think huge. And uh,
you know, there's been a few
controversies. There was a, you know, wow,
I shouldn't talk about that.
But look,
here's the bottom line
thing that helps you.
Anything that makes your
body perform better for sure.
Someone who's living is stepping into a
goddamn cage and throwing their bones at
somebody.
And the only exceptions are going to
be someone who's an elite athlete who
doesn't need it. There's a lot
of guys who don't need anything.
Young guys who were recovering at a,
at a high level still
and they don't need it.
They're just high nutrition and taking
care of their body. But older athletes,
man,
when you get into guys you know that are
in their late thirties and for like you
see a guy like Bernard Hopkins,
I am not going to cast any speculation
as to what Bernard Hopkins is taking or
not taking.
I'm a Bernard Hopkins Fan.
I'm a fan of his technique of his
heart as a boxer, but that said,
isn't he like 46 years old? 46 and
he'd just be Pascal, you know for the,
for the the, the light heavyweight
belt, right. Was it light, heavy weight?
He found out the theme of the people
don't realize too is that guys,
I'm taking growth hormone just to get big.
That's what the common perception is.
Just want to kidnap.
You can get strong recovery recovery
time for the money and there's a lot of
singers that take it too.
I know of know a lot of famous singers
and actors that are getting on in years,
especially singers that have to go under
the duress of doing a lot of concerts
on the road. High intensity
style of living to take growth,
growth hormone just to keep young,
just to maintain a youthful
look and be able to recover.
The stressed I put on their bodies,
it's not just strictly limited to
athletes and the athletes for sure.
The ones who are going to need it because
they're the ones who they're worried
about their actual health.
When it comes to competing,
they're the ones who are really going
to need it and really going to want it,
and I always stress this you,
this is a finger.
The stopping steroids or stopping any
of this is a finger and a dam that is
eventually coming down because of science.
There's going to be a large scale
ability to manipulate your own genetics.
There's just, it's just
eventual it's going to happen.
There's no doubt about it.
They're looking into all
sorts of artificial organs
and recreating Oregon's and
labs and they've been successful in doing
this and successful and transplanting
these,
and they're,
they're working on manipulating the human
body at a very high level and they're
not going to stop.
So it's eventually going to keep going
in the same direction it's going.
And one of the direction is of course,
performance enhancing drugs,
anti aging drugs,
things that make people younger.
They've already discovered all sorts
of different ways to manipulate the
genetics to make,
you know,
my stronger than those things
called Myostatin inhibitors
that they've done with
mice.
And there's,
there's photos of whippet
dogs and apparently whippet
dogs are more susceptible
to this because of the way they
breed them and that, you know,
if they breathe them incorrectly,
if there's some sort of a mistake
in their pairing or whatever,
that one of the off shoots,
one of the,
the fuck ups is this lack of
Myostatin inhibitors and these,
these whippets are giant super muscle
dogs that don't even look real.
They're going to be able to
do that to people, man. And
how fast we've become, man.
Can you mentioned being alive luck the
13th or 14th century when they had no
fucking medicine. Look, we
have now when a surgical tools,
we'll fucking knives and
souls and shit like that.
And you couldn't take a pint
hemp I painkiller headache,
tablet and nothing like that. I
was just like a Hawaiian, you know,
I was reading about the great
history of Hawaii and what,
what happened and how it became an
American state and all the whole deal.
And one of the things was about how when
a white people first came over to why
one fifth of the population died
from disease, really one fifth.
Ah, could you imagine? And
that's incredible, man.
That's just from 20% of your population
just and massage a couple hundred years
ago. No, I mean that's, that's
the amazing thing about it.
It's just a few hundred years ago, we'll
talk about that. Do you know that, that,
that,
that downscaling of,
of humanity from you go back 5,000
years ago and the ancient Greeks and the
Egyptians in the ancient Romans
just was so fucking intelligent man.
When mapping constellations
where mapping countries,
building machines back then that all
of a sudden in the dark ages just all
disappeared. Like everything just
fucking went downhill in a big way.
People are so flawed that is as
high as the heights can reach.
There's always going to be a
potential for a, a regress.
It was always like the tide comes in
and it goes out and I think it's always
moving forward,
but there's always a potential for
a Michele Bachmann type presidential
situation and religious
fanaticism overcomes the
earth and fucking nuclear war.
There's always a potential for that,
and then there must be a rebuild,
like it will always move
towards the positive and
towards the more comprehensive
and more evolved, but there's
always the potential for relapse.
So you don't want him to,
to luck, the Dogan tribe,
I think they're called an Africa.
These guys were fucking thousands
of ego mapping out constellations,
those kind of ones in their tribe,
in Africa with other guys who thought
they were from Mars. I think so, yeah.
Well visited from, from people
that took them in, in, in crafts.
The could show them a constellation
he ever get behind that,
that Mars theory shit and started to
looking at some of the things that are
people. I love reading that sort of
stuff about that. I'll have David Eco,
one of my favorite authors is a read
that sort of shit, but keep an open mind.
There's a stone right down the street
from my house when we were driving back.
I'm a point this out too, cause it's a
fascinating stone. It's just a rock band.
It's just a rock that sitting there,
but it looks like it was cut square.
It's not totally square, but it just
randomly turned out to be this rock.
The way it's shaped.
And you,
if you didn't know any better or if you
had a satellite and you were looking
from Mars, you know, and you were
studying earth and you saw that rock,
you'd be like, look, this is proof.
This is proof that intelligent
life is created this rock. But no,
it's just a rock.
Did it comes again from people will
believe what they want to believe.
When I was in Italy just a few weeks ago,
I went to my sister's wedding down in
this mountain town where she lives in
southern Italy. Towns. Got like 900
people in it. Okay. And it's nothing.
The town's one fucking bar.
It's old. Hundreds of years old.
Clooney and the Americans,
nothing there man.
Nothing there to see his fucking old town
up in the up in the top of a mountain.
But this town has this window and as soon
as we got there, this old dude's like,
oh got go to show you the,
the, the window of the Madonna,
that window of the Madonna, it's so
famous. The pope came here to our town,
you know, years and years and years ago,
the boy and checked it out. So I'm like,
okay, text me home. This
little alleyway techs,
Irene and I behind this alleyway and like
little fucking window. And he's like,
look, you see the Madonna?
Well the fucking what? What,
what are you talking about?
Cause the second window
across right on the inmate,
the Madonna tells this
oil stain on the window.
Like fucking someone had thrown
cooking oil on the window.
Then if you sort of looked at it and
he had that picture in your mind that
someone's telling you, it looks like the
Madonna, like the Virgin Mary, you think?
Yeah. Okay. It looks maybe like a
chick holding a baby as like, oh,
this is their big thing and the
Virgin Mary holding the baby,
the Madonna or a sign
on the window and it's,
for some reason there's fucking village
has managed to keep this oil stain on
his window for like the past
30 years. That's amazing. Yeah,
that's a, it's a fucking oil Stein. Pets,
people want to see what they want to see.
People want to see unto the Virgin Mary.
People go there and fucking pray to with
a pope apparently or rocked up at this
village fucking years ago and
yeah. Okay, cool. Listen, man,
there's a broad spectrum of human beings
and there's some dummies out there in
that and that's an intelligent tests.
That's what that oil painting is, man,
or that oil stain is,
it's an intelligence test and this is
going to be a lot of people that fail that
test.
That's just the way it is.
It's unfortunate and I don't see any way
around it until we figured out a way to
have like super intelligent robots that
do all the menial tasks that they need
really dumb people.
And when we do have that happen,
then it's going to be even more of a
problem because it's going to be some sort
of a, a weird, bizarre
welfare state where you know,
we're going to have to take care of all
these morons that we had given shitty
jobs before because they really don't
have anything to contribute to society.
She going to Tasmania fix it. You can't
do that. You can't export. You know,
as our society becomes more and more
self sufficient and more and more reliant
on computers, and then we don't need
people to do mundane retard tasks,
what the fuck man? It's, we're
going to have to figure out some,
there's going to be some sort of an
adjustment period where there's chaos,
where the, where the morons, you
know, what their rights, you know?
Yeah. For real man. I mean,
look, we, you, you can't turn a,
a group of people into little babies that
always need their daddy and then just
cast him loose in the woods
and said, sorry, no more
daddy. Daddy, they're going to,
they're going to hate that daddy.
They're going to come back.
I'm going to want revenge.
You know?
And there's a lot of people out
there that believe that they're,
they're guaranteed jobs. And that's what,
you know, politicians always talk about,
we're going to create jobs. Yes. Give
me a job. You won't be a fucking job.
You know?
That's the,
the point of this whole idea of everyone
working together is that everyone has
something to contribute. But the
reality is the way the system is set up,
there's a huge chunk of people that
don't have anything to contribute.
So they have to find some way to
plug themselves into the bureaucracy,
plugged themselves into this
complicated economic situation.
And that just defeats the whole
fucking purpose of the machine.
The whole purpose of the machine is,
everybody's got a little piece to play.
Everyone's got a little thing
to do and this is this place.
We're in such a weird state as far as the
evolution of society that we're, we're,
we're just getting past the need for
that. And when we do, what the fuck, man,
what are those poor
people are going to do?
That's why the elites want to drop
everybody down to 500,000 people.
If you talked to like Alex Jones, that's
what it'll say. The new world order,
they're going to drop everybody
down to 500,000 people and then, uh,
they're gonna,
they're gonna work with it from there.
When you think worldwide, I don't think
that's what we'll want. 500,000 people.
And I don't think there's not enough
people, man, that's not enough.
Not enough at all. But these
were just closed down. You could,
if you look two people,
10 people per city,
the idea is if you could kill most people
and then rock all the resources in the
world and have life extension and
that's the idea that you would have some
incredible ability to stay alive forever.
And you know,
if you did have like some crazy
like super technical life,
Aubrey de Grey life extension
technology that owned Neal,
the elites had a hold up and you
could live to be a thousand years old.
Well then you know,
you could have like harems and shit and
if there's only 500,000 people on the
earth, you could rock it just like a
king. But then who does all the shit work?
Give robots to do other robots doing
unless [inaudible] robots do all the shit
jobs.
There's only 500,000 people and you just
fuck everyone and you'll live forever.
So polygamy just running along
Caligula style, Bro. Fuck man.
That's probably the future. That's
what everyone's scared of, right?
When they talk about the apocalypse and
it's always talks of gluttony and mean
every story is the same. You know,
every story is this, this, this,
like the fall of Rome when what's told
to us, it's always the same thing.
They're fucking little boys and drinking
and vomitorium where they throw up and
go right back in to eat
again and they're just,
they were out of control and then they,
they fell apart.
It's always the same goddamn story.
And if that is the same store with the
fuck are we doing right now? Yeah. I mean,
if we're not paying, we've
got to pay attention, pay
attention while we're doing,
would we win wars all over
the fucking planet? We're,
we're involved in all sorts of fucking
filth and craziness and the way we're
polluting the environment and fucking
devastating world economies and fucking
people over in third world countries and
providing what loans they can never pay
back and then Jack and all their
resources. I mean it's, you know,
it's one case after the other to show
that this is happening right now.
Do you mean back in those old days when
they were raping and pillaging that
right first then pillage or pillage
person then? Right. It's a combo package.
Whatever's going on your jollies off first
and then political, the golden sheet.
Would you go fucking take
all the golden shooting down?
My ripe a woman thing and half the fun
of the rape as you rape in front of
everybody while you're pillaging,
cause you just show you such a wild fuck.
You just see you're in the room.
Riping
oh you right into the stray man
everywhere. The comfort Roman days, Bro.
There was no comfort Raymond.
They'd write it down on the logs and rock.
It feels good for her. As long
as it feels good for you. Yeah,
there were just so much better. Right.
But these sites, which I'm glad, I mean
it's really good on the Internet. No
ma'am. And in Australia the break was,
it seemed to be trendy for criminals
and the IDS and [inaudible] nineties but
not many rapists these days.
Well,
you know what Australia wised up and did
legalize prostitution. Yeah, that's true.
That's a good point. It's a buffet. Forget
you guys don't have that a lot here.
Yeah, he's a big goddamn difference.
And even if you don't want sex,
you just want to go somewhere and get
jerked off in Australia during your lunch
break and get a 15 minute a hand job for
like 40 bucks. I don't know, brothel.
If you find one, you know there's plenty
around and it's clean and that's a wrap.
It's just a hand on your cock.
Just a nice little massage.
It's the big deal that a handle
the fucking cock. Exactly.
What's the big fucking deal? If you're
working with some chicken, you say to her,
listen, to give me a fucking
toss in the toilet cubicle.
What's the big deal of a chick putting
your hand in your cock and just if it was
only it was only that,
but they're worried that you're going to
leave and become in a relationship with
this swelling is really good at jerking
you off and then you're going to leave.
Yeah, that's what you know. That's
what the, that's what it's set up for.
Businesses employ a professional hand
job artist to come in and service dude's
like during their lunch break.
Just fuck. There you go. Next next,
next for the afternoon set up, ready
to go. It's set up to keep the family.
It's set up to make sure that
there's no threats to the family.
And one of the threats to the family
unit is the man getting pussy and other
places and he's like,
why am I American this pitch?
Why am I supporting this system?
And that man will not pay as many taxes.
You won't be as successful. The money
will go talk to the woman and it's,
it gets distributed totally differently.
There's benefit and the man being involved
in the family, there's benefit in,
you know,
for a society mean if you go back to Rome,
the way they mapped out
how society should be,
one of the things was to
connect people with families.
That way men can be trusted
and become reliable. You know,
when men are single and they
don't have their own children,
they don't have a dog or a plant,
they're just wild fuck machine.
It's just that the mail goal is to just
fly to different spots all over the
planet, shoot loads, and then
get out of there. You know,
until they have responsibilities.
So it's very difficult to collect the
appropriate amount of taxes and to be able
to control that man. You know, it's you,
it's very hard to control
the wild single man.
That's why nobody wants a
single president. You know,
you want someone to go apps.
Do you really? Australian prime minister,
although it's not. Mary is a girl.
Julia Gilman,
she's probably eating pussy like a champ.
Chuck and bitches and Harry Reid had
to pussy to fire pushy. Is She gay?
Uh, no. No. Well, no. Apparently not. She
has a boyfriend is, I forget his name.
A partner, but she's not married.
No kids. Not Married. Good for her.
She'll be a good solid. Well, you look,
it takes every kind of people that
make this crazy world around them.
Maybe that's what it works
when you don't have an army.
But in America we would
never tolerate that shit.
I'll just tell you that right now. Maybe.
I mean, do you have an army in Australia?
Mustard? I'm just kidding. An Ami.
Yeah. Yeah. We're going to Australia.
Real specialty is lockout special ops.
And even the Americans will tell you that.
It's like the Aussie guy guys a nine foot,
let's say Afghanistan,
they send out guys in first like scouts
reconnaissance and we check out the
fucking scene and scope it out and then
the Americans and everyone goes in.
But that's what the
Aussie is a specialty at.
Is it fucking going in first scoping out
the fucking like Crocodile Dundee could
get like really close to the enemy's camp
and they wouldn't even know he was in
special forces. Uh, I think
it's called Sig special line.
So you have the CPS with
a sneaky little fuckers.
We go in early and we scared the
fucking shit out. That's a calling.
The Americans bombed the joint. All right,
you guys coming in and fucking, Ooh,
what a convenient relationship
that we have then. But yeah,
we're in the first where
was in there first?
So you do have an army and a woman
president, a female prime minister,
because we use the British
legal system per procedures.
People that think that could work here.
This is the next wave,
this Michele Bachmann wave.
And this Thera Pailin wave.
And here's what's interesting about it.
If you don't know Michele Bachmann is
married, first of all, to a gay guy.
She's married to a wildly gay character
who operates a pray the gay away clinic,
pray the gay. Oh one of those people tried
to pray the gay out of not only that,
they take, I believe they take tax
money for these fucking clinics.
They are allowed to somehow or another,
he's,
at least this has been
told to me on Twitter.
I shouldn't even repeat it
until I look into it. Uh,
but from what I understand that they
operate on, on some sort of tax money.
So some somehow or another
they operate on taxes.
I need to look into it to find out
that's true. But what is true for sure,
whether that guy knows it or
not, he's gay as fuck. He is.
He is gay as Ricky Martin and
airport hangar full of Dicks.
This guy's gay and he might,
he might not know it,
but the way he walks and the way he talks,
and he was talking about gay people being
barbarians, he called them barbarians.
And so all these gay dudes dressed up
as barbarians and went to his clinic and
there's a youtube video.
I tweeted it a few days ago is a youtube
video of these guys. And I tweeted,
the guy sent, sent me a thing like,
thanks for tweeting it and I go, dude,
is that you?
You're a fucking hero.
They showed up at this guy's
clinic and then they start,
they start acting like barbarians like
her and they're wearing like really campy
barbarian outfits. And
then at the end they, uh,
they take a photo and the guy's name is
Marcus Bachmann and all together they go,
Marcus, what's in your
closet? I mean, it's just,
it's so ridiculous.
They throw glitter on like Newt Gingrich,
they throw glitter on Michele Bachmann.
Like to, you know, to like, you know,
let them make them, make them, force
them to stay aware of, you know,
gay rights and gay needs. But do you
think sky Elton John or Ricky Martin?
I think they're probably equally gay.
More Elton John because he's been around
back when there was no internet and you
could just go for crazy freak or ga
with sunglasses on and he gives it a,
receives it out in.
John gives it,
I would say Hilton's a giver except head
or think he receives the head but keeps
the fuck on and gives the
asphalt and Ricky, I say both.
He does whatever, whatever depth. Really.
He's fucking moving around
and he's moving and shaking.
He's not adverse to any kind
of experiences. Hey, you
say, oh, but you know one.
If you were gay you would say,
Oh the other way.
I have a friend who's gay comic and he
said, first time I saw pussy, I was like,
it.
When's it going to heal?
We used to have the sign when we're young,
we're talking about chicks.
Chick's pussy slide. Show
us where the exit. Yeah,
that as well when I was very young, but I
didn't remember. It shows for the media.
Oh Man. What did I have? Elton John
and Rick. Why did you ask me that?
That's cause you're used to doing that.
Usually they will that whole fucking
voice versus you always have two quickie
questions. Throw people off. So with
Elton John and to be knocked out,
chug out Wedgie or head job of another
guy put the ball of fried train,
the Elton John's been around
for a long ass time. Dude,
he had some killer hits
though to fucking hell.
He had a weird relationship to like one
guy would write the song and he told him
and would write the songs and the ultimate
seeing them and Elton plays the piano.
Fucking genius artist,
genius artist.
But there's something I really appreciate
a guy who writes and produces all of
his own shit for whatever reason I,
it's like like a comic.
Like if I find out that
a comic has joke writers,
I don't like him as much as a comic that
doesn't have joke writers, you know?
And for whatever reason, man,
it's the same thing. Like,
I know that Elton John's
brilliant and I love his songs,
but I would like a more of he wrote them.
You know what I mean?
Does that make sense?
Are you still into to country music?
Cause last time we did the voice versus
your local get up country music industry
like Dwight Yoakam.
I like some country music and I like
some music that you wouldn't consider
country. Like I like Leonard Skinner,
right? Which is really like southern rock.
There's a lot of country and southern
lot like this is a song called the ballad
of Curtis Lowe. That's a
goddamn country song. You know,
it's a great song. There's,
but there's a, there's a
lot of, uh, it's just like,
it's a style of a American music that
I don't think that gets enough respect.
There's some jam and country songs.
Sorry, going back to gay people.
Apparently mixed martial arts has a
huge gay following. Oh, of course.
Huge gay following up men with perfect
bodies. Then get on top of the man.
I was talking to Andrew, Andrew Simon,
the CEO of HD net a couple of days ago,
and we'll talk about ratings and you know,
demographic of viewers and that needs
like huge gay viewership course huge gave
you or she, yeah, I would
imagine. Yeah, I would imagine.
Especially ones who like brutes.
Well he mentioned a guy going on like in
an abundance of a Broccoli, isn't it? Oh,
I've seen gay couples at fights
before. Oh really? Yeah, for sure.
Gay couples enjoying fights, guys who
you just know are gay, you know one guys.
Yeah, no doubt. No doubt.
I've seen it a bunch of times.
A guy goes to get the same reaction
that if he fucked a girl in the ass,
a Gill Neoss what do you
mean? Okay, so a guy got,
we'll fuck another gay guy in the ass.
Right?
But what a gay guy be opposed to
fucking a girl in the ass. I mean,
the house is still on us. I
think gay men. Look at women.
I'm a much more sexually than a straight
guy could ever look at a gay man.
You know what I mean?
Like too.