Hello Freak bitches,
uncomfortable for short bursts,
don't eat so much
exercises.
So everything you just said,
you know,
there was a really interesting study
that just came out,
um,
a couple of weeks ago where they looked
at the rates of aging in young adults.
So they looked at different time points.
So they look at,
they took the,
there was a whole,
I think it was like over a thousand
people and the study started when they
were like 26 years old and they measured
like 18 different biomarkers of aging.
So they looked at like DNA health.
They looked at telomere length.
So tila mirrors are those caps on the
end of your chromosomes that protected
damage.
There are markers for aging.
They looked at hdl cholesterol,
they looked at c reactive protein,
which is a inflammatory mediator.
They looked at 18 different things and
they looked at these people that were 26
years old and then it did it again when
they were 32.
And then they did it again when there
were 38.
And what they found was that even though
these people were all the same
chronological age,
their cells looked very,
very,
very different people age at different
rates.
Some people,
if you looked on the cellular level,
they look 10 years older and some people
look 10 years younger than their
chronological age.
And I was looking at some of these
graphs of people and you can see some
people started out like they started out
bad where they looked old and then they
started getting better.
You know,
they probably started changing their
diet,
their lifestyle.
Other people started going worse.
Some people stayed the same,
you know.
So there are lots of different,
very variables going on here.
But I think what's really interesting.
Oh,
and by the way,
that their physical appearance also
correlated with not their chronological
age,
but their biological age,
what is,
what it's called.
So if the,
if they showed their picture to people,
random people and said,
guess what age they are,
they would guess their biological age,
not their chronological age.
So if a person was 38 but they look 28,
the person would say,
Oh,
they're probably 28 and if the person
was 38 but they looked 48,
they just looked worn and you know,
rough.
Then the person would guess that they
were much,
much older than they were.
So there was a correlation between
physical appearance and the biological
age.
And this is.
I found this really,
really interesting because I think it is
strong evidence for the fact that your
diet and your lifestyle play a major
role in the way you age.
You know,
I,
if I was in the movie world,
I would call somebody,
but Melissa Mccarthy will be the whale.
Oh,
how dare you.
And she's the funniest woman around a.
she's very funny.
She's very physically funny for sure.
She's a very talented.
Yeah.
It's funny because Billy Gardell is a
funny comic.
You know billy,
right?
Yeah.
They don't like on the show.
He's like,
almost like a straight guy.
Of course wouldn't want the husband get
one over on the wife.
What'd you joe?
They don't allow that.
Nicholas,
why is that?
What's on?
What's up with that fuck has jerk offs
run Hollywood?
Is that what it is?
It is what people want to see.
The people want to see that.
I don't want to see that you don't
fucking.
Holly has been hijacked by fucking
feminist.
Wow.
Am I wrong?
If you guys can't relate that I'm
fucking leaving.
Do you ever noticed a pattern of
emasculation and movies and in fact the
last 20 years,
I think there's people that are
seriously concerned with coming off as
progressive and even if they think
differently than what would be the
progressive choice,
they will make the progressive choice
because they get like social brownie
points.
Uh,
definitely think that's true.
But I don't think that pertains to
sitcoms.
I think like,
it's not as funny if the dude gets over
on the CIC for someone to come on.
This is a story.
I might have told you this on the last
time I was here.
I had a deal with a,
this was years ago at Dennis Larry's
company.
And we come out here and take a bunch of
meetings and I felt like they had a
sitcom idea.
And at first of all,
every meeting,
75 percent of the room was female
executives.
And of course the first question and
every meeting was,
what's the wife's role?
Every fucking one.
So by the time we got to NBC,
which was the last one and I had fucking
had it.
And they're like,
so what's the wedge I go.
And again I was just kidding.
But I go,
uh,
I don't know.
I see like in the pilot she's pregnant
and I push it down in the cellar stairs
and I'm expecting like Dennis to start
laughing and in Serpico Jimmy Syrup
because.
And they all just look at me.
You could have fucking her and append.
So the next day,
next day,
Jimmy Circle,
we had to send a dozen roses to the lady
from NBC.
You wonder why I can't get a Gig.
Thank God you throw me a news radio and
a few grace under fire.