Four,
three,
two,
and boom.
That's a nice hat I've told you already,
but live,
I got to tell you,
that was a nice.
It's,
it's very,
uh,
kind of Indiana Jones,
but it's not quite that cowboy.
Yeah.
You're like in the middle of that,
dancing on the edge.
What can I have a really fat head.
And so there's this website called like
big heads.com.
There's a website,
it's a total website for,
to get my friend Paul Burke Chrysler a
hat.
Then put his hat on.
I couldn't believe how big his head was.
Like there was like an inch gap over in
my head.
I thought I had a big head.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
if you know your head,
your head size,
do you know your head size?
No,
I do not.
So,
uh,
so it turns out if you know your head
size,
that that number comes from somewhere.
Can I tell you what it is?
Sure.
So if you measure the circumference of
your head,
just get a tape measure,
like you mentioned your waistline,
but do it around your head and take that
number divided by Pi.
Then that's your hat size.
Whoa.
Just seems complicated.
Abide by to your waist.
Thirty two is what you're wasting.
It just is what it is,
right?
Just why it can't just be the
circumference,
right?
So what it turns out to be.
So what that means is if you're dividing
by Pi,
you're getting the diameter of the
circle that has the same dimension as,
as the circumference of your head.
So if you have an oblong head,
then what it's doing is finding out what
the circle is.
The diameter of the circle that has that
same circumference is your head.
That's what that's doing for whatever,
for whatever.
Whether that helps the hat,
the hat maker.
So immediately I started thinking about
Dan Akroyd and siren and live as a cone
head within India.
Tall hat for that to get it.
So do you still doing stand up?
That's great.
Constantly loving it.
Yeah.
And they caught you a few months ago.
You were emceeing some MMA,
was it?
What was.
Well,
I'm always doing that.
Kept some of it.
Then stayed in shape because I'm,
I'm a.
I'm a fat Slob,
right?
Back in the day,
and then I,
and I was like some street credit back
then you exercise at all now.
It's not that I don't have the energy
to.
It's,
it's trying to find the test.
You back in the day looking at you it.
How much do you weigh back then?
Oh,
oh,
go on once.
No,
no,
no.
I'm 6,190
pounds in that.
Oh exactly.
I have big thighs and stuff.
Um,
other wrestlers would have skinnier
thighs and things.
So I was also taller than anyone I
wrestled.
So since we're the same height,
it meant they had bigger muscles
actually.
So because we're the same weight.
Right.
But I'm sorry,
did I say that right?
I'm taller but with the same weight.
So that means they have bigger muscles,
right?
Because none of us have fat.
Right?
So I had to do things that my lankiness
would enable me to do and to accomplish
that they couldn't.
So I have long reach this sort of scoop
an ankle,
that kind of thing.
It's great advantages to having long
limbs in martial arts space,
particularly in wrestling grappling
because the leverage.
Yeah.
Also if you're quick and with Linda and
I was both,
but if they got me in their grip it was
hard for me to get out.
So what kind of exercise do you do these
days?
I know I'm trying.
I'm trying.
When I'm in I'm good,
but I've just got so much going on.
You have to like make the time.
That's a problem,
right?
When you become a little bit for your
own food,
there's a lot of food documentaries,
you know,
trying to get you to eat differently.
So I thought I'd watched the wall.
I've binged on them one weekend while I
was doing other stuff and I got hungry.
No one of one.
One of the guys,
he was trying to lose 100 pounds or
something,
so every 15 pounds he lost.
He put a bowling ball up on the counter
and said,
that is what I'm not carrying around
with me because of bowling balls.
About 15 pounds.
I said,
wow.
He's measuring awaiting bowling balls.
That's something because we say I'm
three pounds less than two pounds.
That doesn't hit you emotionally the way
a bowling ball does after you've lost 15
pounds because no one wants to be
carrying that around.
So psychological,
I thought that was quite potent.
That is potent.
I think we do need to.
I usually use like plates.
I think of weight plates or Dumbbell.
Okay.
Yeah,
that works too.
Yeah.
I uh,
I started doing intermittent fasting
pretty recently where I only allow
myself to eat 10 hours in a day.
Oh Wow.
10 out of the 24 hours.
Yes.
So I had a terry crews on my radio show
on start talking that boys,
my boys ripped.
He looks great.
He's still and he's like 47 or
something.
I mean he's so he doesn't eat until 12
noon and that he doesn't eat until after
10:00.
That's right.
Yeah.
Ten minutes that he doesn't need after
10.
It's a 10 hour thing.
And so he has to.
He's watching everyone else have brunch
and breakfast and so he's got to
overcome that.
But uh,
so it's a little bit of fasting each
day.
Intermittent fast just to keep the
discipline.
I think at the end of the day,
it's really just discipline that it also
forces your body to burn fat instead of
carbohydrates and when it forces your
body to burn fat,
that state of Ketosis is actually easy
to maintain because you don't.
You don't get hungry.
Yeah.
Then there's no rollercoaster.
Yeah,
the crash that.
But the carbohydrate crash that you get,
is that outside of the realm of
possibility for,
you know,
I can totally.
I'm a ketosis guy.
Anything involving science,
maybe it's in there.
I.
I once got raked over the coals.
Not by everyone,
but I tweeted once.
I said,
if there was a diet book written by a
physicist who will contain one sentence,
consume calories at a lesser rate than
at a greater rate,
consumed calories at a lesser rate than
you burn them.
That is sort of true.
That's the one sentence.
Do know.
It's more complicated than that and
everyone just try to get all this is
that and that and one of the great
things of physics when you,
when you do physics is all the details
are just cut off the window dressing and
you get down to the window itself and
that's what the analysis works on.
I have rarely seen you attacked,
but I did see you attack when you were
celebrating a Sir Isaac Newton's
birthday.
Oh No.
I was like,
people were so mad.
People lost their mind lost in mind when
you were,
by the way,
incorrect in the date of Jesus's
birthday.
That is not the date of Jesus.
Jesus did not.
Was Not born on the 25th.
Right?
Plus I didn't even mention that.
Well,
so what I said was,
by the way,
that to this day is my highest retweeted
tweet.
I tweeted it.
So you remember,
it was actually a couple of years ago.
Yeah,
so it was on December 25th comes.
Here it is.
You've got to transform the world.
Happy Birthday on this day.
Long ago a child was born who by age 30
were transformed the world.
Happy Birthday,
Isaac Newton,
born December 25th,
16,
40 to 79,000
retweets.
Thousand life people just lost them.
So mad they're angry.
And I thought,
well,
it's interesting because I'm just
speaking the truth here.
Yes,
he transformed civilization by boy.
Actually he did it by the time he was
26.
Um,
so yes,
it's provocative because you're
expecting the Jesus is going to end
that.
But I thought I'd share it some extra
actual truth with people and so some
people celebrate it deeply.
Religious people.
One had a headline,
St Neil degrasse Tyson is trolling
Christians on Christmas Day.
And I said,
I said Newton at least has the benefit
of actually having been born that day.
And then later on it,
it's actually more subtle than that with
Newton because he was on the Julian
calendar which was,
which is 10 days shifted from the
Gregorian calendar.
So if you ask what would his birthday be
today,
it would be January fourth,
December 25th.
So yeah.
But when he was born,
his mother was celebrating Christmas.
So that's really what matters for that
tweet.
This is a bizarre thing anyway because
if you're a real Christian,
you would understand that the birthday
was shifted in order to comply with
pagan religion.
That's exactly it.
It landed.
I don't know how many people know that
actually.
I mean you're a well read guy,
but.
So if you give me a minute to just
explain that.
So December 21st we know his first day
of winter,
shortest day of the year,
and what makes it short?
Shortest daylight of the year.
And what makes it short?
The arc of the sun across the sky is
very low.
The Sun doesn't get very high and it
doesn't stay up for very long and it's
been coming a lower and lower arch every
day on route to December 20.
First,
the ancient peoples were worried about
this because everyone worship the sun
because it made your crops come and he
gave you warmth and you say,
wow,
if this keeps going lower and lower in
the sky,
we're going to lose the sun entirely.
December 21st the sun slows down and it
stops this load.
This drop in,
it's moving across the sky from day to
day,
so that stopping of the sun is solstice.
That Latin stationary son like
armistice,
stationary arms,
right from the end of the first world
war,
a weather November 11th,
that was armistice solstice,
so,
so the movement of the sun lower in the
sky stops,
but that doesn't mean it's going to come
back.
It takes a few days for it to slow down,
stop and then reverse.
He said,
oh,
it is coming back.
Let's celebrate that,
and that's a few days after December 20.
First was about December 25th of Pagan
holiday celebrating the return to the
sun.
Christianity is trying to take foothold
where there were were pagans once roamed
and you.
You put celebrations that match.
There's just so that the the shift is
not as hard for you and the unknown
birthday of Jesus within a signed this
Pagan Day of celebration to make that
transition easier for the Pagans to
become Christians.
And sure enough,
it remained Christmas day and ever since
the birth of Jesus,
the speculated birthday of Jesus is like
the spring,
the spring.
I,
there's some,
there's some passages,
uh,
of course in the new testament that
reference with the sheep were doing plus
there's a sense of being taken by the
Romans,
which is what,
and Mary goes to the manger,
the animals are not in the manger and
not at the.
So the,
there's secondary evidence for that.
It's probably happened in the spring now
with the advent of commercial space
travel.
No.
Seems,
seems,
seems inevitable,
right?
Love you.
Love your Segues d,
do you think that it's possible that
maybe you could even offer up a flat
earth believer tour where you take them,
like at the very least,
take them up to Alaska where it's light.
So 23 hours of calling into you.
Is this at tweeting me constantly
telling me constantly,
yeah,
call me a sellout.
I'm a sellout around earth sellout.
Like as if there's some round earth
money while you're on the payroll
checks.
I'm getting some ground earth,
Earth Pale.
Or for your show,
I'm sure you've seen the basketball
player who graduated from Duke,
from Duke.
That was hitting the news the last
couple of days.
I saw the leaves that dinosaurs are fake
and that the world is flat.
Okay,
so here's the thing,
Joe,
I've thought about this.
I bet you have.
As an educator,
I've thought about this.
Okay?
So
here's,
here's what matters.
All right?
We live in a free country.
People should be able to think what ever
they want,
whenever they want,
provided it doesn't subtract away from
someone else's rights.
Okay?
So thinking the earth is flat doesn't
harm anyone unless you to run for office
or you want some position of power over
other people.
That's when it's dangerous.
I thinking of elevator banks where they
have numbers,
you know,
I,
I have a photo essay of what elevators
look like inside.
I know it's just,
I mean,
the gears.
No,
no,
not even that Geeky.
Just what are the numbers on the panel?
Uh,
without the 13 you mean?
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
So about 80 percent of buildings taller
than 12 stories don't have a 13th floor.
Okay?
And so this tricks a deck of phobia is
again in a free country,
if you,
if you want to be afraid of the number
13,
go right ahead.
It just seems to me you should not be
tasked with designing elevators.
If that's your fear.
Find something else to do.
Holding aside the fact that I'm a little
scared that in this 21st century United
States of America,
we have people walking among us afraid
of the number 13.
What does that mean?
I don't know in the long run,
but if you keep to yourself,
don't harm others.
Think what ever you want so that the
rubber hits the road is you now have
power over others.
And that's where the failure of the
educational system actually manifests.
Well,
that's all societies and cultures
collapse,
sweat,
but it's not that they don't know that
there's a 13th floor and that you're
just calling it the fourth.
I want to take my sharpie cross out the
14th,
the 13th floor.
You're not fooling anybody.
Now when you see it on an elevator and
you're like,
you see no,
13 and plus they try to fake you out.
So they go one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10,
11,
12,
and then you have to go to the next road
to begin to for the 14th.
So you'll see 12 and right next to 14
and some other,
some modern buildings will put their,
their,
uh,
their heavy machinery like the h vac on
the 13th floor so that there's no
residency.
Right?
But they could still say it's the 13th
floor and then there's the 14 foot.
Does anybody ever have a dummy 13th
button where you press it?
It never lights up.
Like I don't get it.
I can't get it.
That's interesting.
That's what I would do.
Oh,
you just put it there to satisfy me.
But still nobody lives there.
That's to Colorado.
This is one of the 20 percent of people
that make sense.
This is what a great building.
And meanwhile there is no 13th slow.
It's just a dummy button.
Remember that twilight zone episode with
the mannequins?
They went up to the 11th floor,
but there is no 11th floor.
And the mannequins come to life at
night.
Oh,
I forgot about that.
They leave the store floors and they've
all go up to 11 and have a cocktail
party and they vote,
which one of them is going to go out and
become human for a day.
A twilight zone was so good.
There was the best television there ever
was like still to this day ever because
so many great premises,
great premises,
great actors,
Great Cinematography,
and it was in black and white,
so shadows were completely dark.
Shadows don't have much meaning when
you're filming color because everything
is just there,
but in black and white
shadows create moods and yeah,
so I watched to serve man.
The other hadn't seen.
I hadn't.
I had it on the Dvr and played lurch on
the Adams family.
Yeah,
that was a great one because it was just
like,
it had all the elements of people going,
well,
you know,
they seem nice.
They seem nice and they solve all of our
war and our God.
That was great.
That's a good one.
Was the,
the invaders do to remember this one
knew this was a.
This was a one woman performance and I
forgot who it was.
It was it not agnes morehead,
one of these women of that era,
uh,
it'll come to me in a minute and she's
living alone in a farm house,
no electricity.
She's got a farm and she's alone and
some alien spacecraft lands on her roof
and it's got these devices,
has got these saws and blazers cutting
through things and she's freaking out.
She's got the pan in the pots and the
rolling pin and she,
then she'd get the gun,
the shotgun,
and she's attacking this thing is,
and you don't know what it is.
And it's got lights and the thing and
it's this tiny little thing.
It's like three inches across.
Right?
And it turns out that's the thing that's
attacking her.
And then she finally comes.
That's it.
See the little,
the little robot.
Okay.
And,
and,
and then I got to give you about the
shows.
Forty years old.
I can give the punchline.
Okay.
So she actually successfully damages the
thing and then you zoom in on it,
right?
And then you hear a radio transmission
from the aliens that are inside and it
says,
um,
yeah.
Hello?
Uh,
Houston
giant.
Who's trying to attack us?
We need help.
Send backups.
Oh,
it was great.
Like,
whoa.
We were the invaders.
That was us landing on her home on some
other planet or some parallel earth from
some other dementia.
It's just a art we.
No,
no,
no.
I get it.
So she's.
What's another planet?
She's the.
She's the giant where they're saying
there's a giant attacking us,
but the whole show you or have her point
of view the these aliens are trying to
hurt her.
When they were just.
It was our space probe just trying to
explore it's environment,
but isn't it possible that it's like
another dimension.
It's us in another dimension and they
are landing on earth.
Excepted it.
No,
no.
I mean they were speaking English.
Parallel evolution.
Isn't that the definition of infinity
that somewhere some.
If,
if there is really an infinity,
there is not only a you and an I,
but there's a uni and everybody else
we've ever met in all the exact events
in the exact same order have gone down
an infinite number of times.
This conversation
except except there is how many people
know this,
but often it's mind blowing when you
learn that some infinities are bigger
than others.
Joe Rogan just lean two feet away from
the microphone.
Not all affinities are the same size.
It's infinity then it's infinity.
It's okay.
Don't you remember when you were a kid
and said,
what's the biggest number?
You know,
a million or a million and one.
Right?
Okay.
How about a billion?
A billion and one knew the annoying kid
was added.
One.
Two,
okay.
How about infinity,
infinity and one day?
Well,
turn to offending anyone and affinity or
the same number?
Okay.
So here's the.
So for example,
the number of,
of counting numbers.
So one,
two,
three,
up to infinity.
Okay.
Right.
The numbers you would use to count
things,
that's infinite.
The number of irrational numbers.
So the numbers that you cannot represent
as a fraction.
Okay.
That there's more there,
more of those than there are counting
numbers by far.
So these are orders of infinity.
Then there are more,
there are more transcendental numbers.
Then there are irrational numbers.
What's a transcendental numbers?
So that's a number that you'll never
find as a solution to,
to an Algebraic equation.
So Pi is a transcendental,
number B is a transcendent.
These,
these are magic numbers that show up in
mathematics and there's turns out
there's like an even bigger infinity of
those than there is of these other two
classes of numbers.
And they use the,
the,
um,
the Hebrew letter,
uh,
less,
in,
in ranking.
So as I left,
one left,
two left,
three elephants.
I think there are five levels of
infinity.
So my point is I'm just,
because there's infinite universes to
me,
doesn't mean there's infinite
conversations that have happened and I'd
want to really explore the depths of
infinities before I say and agree with
you that this conversation has happened
a million,
an infinite number of times in just this
way,
except you have a different engineers
sitting next to us,
a or an infinite number of times where
it's been Jamie too,
right?
Yeah.
In principle.
I mean,
that's the argument that's given,
but I think that there's some nested
infinities in there that deserve some
explanation.
My explanation is not handling this
well.
Well that's,
that's fine.
As I've said,
as I say in the,
in the,
uh,
epigraph of,
of the book booked is not available yet,
but I have a copy,
ha ha.
Astrophysicists for people in a hurry.
Astrophysics for people in a hurry.
But you got to say,
Hey,
let's just say astrophysics for people
in a hurry.
Oh yes.
A quick.
You got to say,
Hey,
because you're in a hurry.
So,
so the EPA,
the EPA,
Graham on that is the universe is under
no obligation to make sense to you that
that's Rasha.
And I did that before.
And so it makes sense to you that the
universe is under no obligation to make
sense.
So it's okay if your brain hurts when I
say there's a ranking of infinities,
but um,
but you shouldn't say that doesn't make
sense.
Therefore it is not true.
I definitely wouldn't say that.
But what confuses me is the word
infinity because I had always taken the
word infinity to mean something that has
no end.
So how can something that has no end be
larger than something else.
So the way they do that mathematically,
the way to demonstrate that
mathematically is used.
You map one item in the set of this
infinity to corresponding items in the
set or the oven.
Other infinity.
So you do this.
So you take the one and you map it to
like the first transcendental number six
a to two.
The second you just keep doing this.
And when you do that mathematically what
you find that one infinity outstrips the
other infinity.
Wow.
And then you left with more,
with more numbers.
So that shows you that you have a bigger
infinity.
Now when you find,
I mean there's a,
there's a new NASA announcement that's
supposed to.
Is it Monday that's supposed to be
announced or types of plans tomorrow?
The exoplanet is a Wednesday,
a Wednesday.
I don't,
I don't have a secret.
I'm not authorized to have juicy
details.
Let me invent some juicy details that it
could be.
So NASA.
So.
So He's been good at segwaying lately.
He doesn't,
he just jumping in,
jumping out.
You got to get that red.
I just,
yeah,
I'm flying back to.
Thanks for fitting this in show it
opened this place up at three in the
morning for you,
man.
No,
I'm,
I'm very,
um,
I feel the love.
So thank you.
Um,
so,
uh,
here's some things that could be because
NASA is saying that it's,
it's a,
it's a stunning new announcement.
Well,
what could be more than the fact that we
already know that there are,
uh,
there are earth like planets orbiting in
the goldilocks zone of the nearest star
to the sun.
Proximate Century.
Can you do better that than that?
For me?
NASA?
I don't think so.
Unless you got some extra stuff you're
going to tell us.
Like what's been a cottage industry in
the last couple of years is the
observation of planet atmospheres.
As the planet passes in front of the
host star life from the host star passes
through the atmosphere and it is all and
the light signatures altered by the
chemistry of the atmosphere.
So depending what the chemicals are,
it'll influence the spectrum that you
get.
And when you do that,
you can say what the chemical
composition of the atmosphere of that
star is.
There's certain,
there's a certain combinations of
elements that we would call biomarkers.
No,
we can't look down to the surface of the
planet and look at cities if there are
any.
But there are consequences in the
atmosphere to there being life on the
surface such as is there oxygen there.
I used to think when I was watching star
trek when I was a kid,
because I saw it in real time.
That's an old.
I am a.
When it first came out,
original series star trek characters
never wore spacesuits.
Yeah.
You ever wonder.
I mean,
you ever thought about that?
Okay.
What happens is they visit planets that
have nitrogen,
oxygen atmosphere.
Jim.
All right,
well that's what our atmosphere is.
Nitrogen.
So they find planets with nitrogen,
oxygen.
They go down,
they don't need a space suit.
So I've actually thought about that and
that's their solution.
So that must mean there'd be planets
that you could find that.
Well,
here's the thing,
we have oxygen on earth only because
there is life on earth.
Not any kind of life,
photosynthesizing life,
we have life that takes sunlight,
turns it into chemical energy,
into itself,
into wood,
into plants,
and one of its byproducts is oxygen.
Oxygen is chemically active.
If you took away all plants tomorrow,
that oxygen would slowly get absorbed
chemically into the environment and then
you would not have oxygen there to be
viewed by aliens.
Trying to see if we have life here.
And it's pretty surprising to people to
note that we're mostly nitrogen in.
All right.
Oh yeah.
We're.
We're 78 percent nitrogen in our
atmosphere.
Toy.
You know what happens if you have too
much oxygen?
If you have like let's say 50 percent
oxygen and that part of it,
no one knew.
What happens is like a forest fire would
never go out.
Oh yeah.
Because oxygen feeds combustion and so
you could basically burn all vegetation
in the world if the oxygen went above
certain thresholds.
So you needed high enough so that you
can still have oxygen metabolism but not
so high that it's bad for lightening
triggered forest fires.
But my point is so,
so if,
if in this,
if I don't know the announcement,
but I'm just guessing here because it's
been a cottage industry the last couple
of years,
let's find these biomarkers.
Do you have unstable chemistry going on
in that atmosphere?
Because if you do,
it means something's generating it and
certain combinations of chemistry tells
you there's likely to be life of some
kind.
Now,
just a couple of decades ago,
we had speculation of other planets,
but we really didn't have any tangible
proof.
In fact,
anyone,
anytime I give a public talk,
you can do this.
You are in your gigs,
asked who he was born since 1995.
Okay?
And you,
uh,
you,
your audience leans young.
So there'll be some fraction of the
audience will raise their hand.
And so what I do is I,
I night them as generation exoplanet
because 1995 was the first year that,
that a planet outside of our own solar
system was discovered.
So they have been alive only during a
time where we've known each other star
systems.
So crazy generation x.
that's what I want to start that
movement.
It's so crazy.
That's so recent.
I mean,
it is.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I was living out here.
It's 20 was 24 years ago.
Was 22 years ago.
Yeah,
that's insane.
If you stop and think about how,
what a short period of time that is,
and in that period of time when there's
rising through 3000 exoplanets,
this was the advance of that.
That's not just science events,
that's engineering and technology and in
telescope quality and imaging quality.
And it is a lot that goes on to the
advance of science.
It's not just how clever you are in an
Einsteinian way.
It's,
do you know good engineers to build a
device to make the measurement?
This is how we discovered gravity waves.
Now what's your take on that planet
that's supposed to be outside the Kuyper
belt?
That's planet planet nine so far.
All the data look convincing.
So what they've done is they've looked
at other objects in the Kuiper belt and
looked at.
These are colleagues of mine at Caltech.
Um,
so it's,
it's uh,
Mike Brown who,
you know,
I get blamed for killing Pluto,
but I was an accessory for sure,
but I definitely didn't kill blue.
That dude killed Pluto,
right.
He found another object that was
basically the size of pluto out there.
So either you make that a planet where
you demote Pluto.
And how much smaller is Pluto there
onsite?
Our Moon.
Oh,
so,
so don't get me started.
Our movement has five times the mass of
Pluto.
Wow.
So the moon,
Pluto was lame from the beginning.
All right.
We thought it was big.
We wanted it to be big.
We,
we,
we made it,
one of us,
one of the nine and its size didn't
settle out until the late 19 seventies
when we had better and better,
more accurate ways to measure its size.
And that's when we learned it's small
even compared to our own.
But granted,
we have a big moon,
but if you're not going to think our
moon is a planet,
you're certainly not going to think that
Pluto was a planet.
So,
so this,
let me just tell you how they did.
So they found these other objects out
there,
the same team,
I'm a constant team back together,
pronounce his last name,
but in Jan and Mike Brown,
but both at Caltech and they found these
objects in the outer,
so the Kuyper belt of icy bodies,
of which Pluto is a member.
You track their motion and you say,
okay,
if I add up all the gravity that's
affecting them and they should move this
way,
but they don't.
They move another way,
a different way.
So either Newton's laws of gravity are
failing in the outer solar system or
this some object out there whose gravity
you have yet to reconcile with the
motions of these objects.
So they said,
let's assume Newton is right.
What object we have to put out there at
what distance and what size to influence
the movement of these copper belt
objects in the way we see it.
And then they do this to bodes law.
No,
no.
We're way pat went up later.
Thanks for remembering boats law,
but both law was a early a measure of
where you might find a new planet and it
was based on mass and gravity.
No,
no,
both law was a simple arithmetic tool.
All it did was basically double the
distance with a certain additive
parameter,
double the distance of the planet.
So for example,
um,
uh,
and,
and there was a little a factor in there
that helped the inner planets come out.
Right?
But let's look at Maurice.
Maurice was like two and a half times
earth's distance from the sun.
Uh,
what comes after Mars?
Jupiter,
Jupiter is five times or assistance.
Saturn is 10 times two and two and a
half to five to 10.
So bolds law is just a simple arithmetic
scheme.
It's not based in any known physics.
It was only based on the solar system.
It's under social system itself.
That's right.
So,
and it worked and yet you have to fudge
your way to get mercury to work in.
That wouldn't,
didn't have pluto.
Pluto wasn't a planet in any way,
but anyhow it was a,
it was a flood Gigi way.
That was mostly right by accident and
this was in like,
what year was this?
Oh,
that was a,
uh,
1800 spaces.
Yeah.
So now we have advanced computer
programming,
very high precision modeling,
and they're saying there's got to be a
planet somewhere here in this arc of the
sky,
let's look for it because we think
that's what's effected the orbits of
these other objects and that is a
completely noble way to discover a
planet.
That's how Neptune was discovered.
And because everyone looked at the orbit
of Uranus and said,
you know,
Uranus is not following Newton's laws.
Maybe.
Maybe Newton's laws don't work that far
out.
He's never been tested that far.
And they said,
well,
let's,
let's assume it works and ask what would
have to influence it and whether it's a
difficult mathematical calculation
because you're not saying,
here's the object.
What's the gravity field?
You're saying,
here's the gravity field I need.
Where must the object be and how massive
must've be.
That's a much harder mathematical
problem to solve.
And so once the,
the,
the errant orbit of Uranus was known and
calculated,
they started looking for another planet
and that's how they discovered planet
Neptune.
Wow.
So now when they're looking at this
planet nine,
hope I said that right?
It was the,
the movement of Uranus's orbit was not
following proper laws.
And they infer the presence of Neptune.
They said,
look here tomorrow night.
And they look there and they found it.
Wow.
Yes.
It was a brilliant display of.
No,
we're going back to the 19th century.
So I mean,
people,
people were bad ass at every
generation's got their bad ass.
Scientists know how much further out
from the known solar system is this
unknown planet.
So I'm not quick to call it planet nine
because so far it's 20,000
times farther away from the sun than the
earth is.
So I'm not sorry you're not in the
family.
You're not in the hood.
No,
sorry.
I'm not feeling like Colin Connecticut,
New York City.
I'm not feeling it.
And so.
But it's something massive,
right?
It's like six times the mass of the.
I forgot what mass they were assigning
it,
but yeah,
it would.
If that were in our solar system,
do we?
No question.
You would label it as a planet and it
wasn't there one time,
speculation that it was some sort of a
burnt out star that exist.
Not that mass.
No,
no,
no.
You might be thinking you if that's what
I think you're thinking.
You got good memory too long ago in a
galaxy far away,
so I'm talking about 19 seventies people
looked at the extinction record on earth
and every 20,000
years they found a little blip,
a little dip,
and the fossil record where we lost some
species and people were wondering why
could there have been some flux of
comets raining down periodically on the
earth wreaking havoc on the ecosystem
rendering species extinct in these
periodic intervals.
So if there is,
maybe there's some double star to the
sun,
some binary star system.
So they invoked it and then they called
it.
They gave him a name or they called it
nemesis when God gave it a name.
And so you know what period?
Orbital period.
That object must have,
it's got to match the extinction
periodicity and so it's got to be a
20,000
year period and so.
But people look for it,
they couldn't find it and then you
reanalyze the extinction records and it
was,
you had to fudge it to make it look like
it was periodic.
So basically we've abandoned the idea of
net of nemesis and aren't binary star
systems really common.
Yeah.
More than half the star as you've seen
the night sky or binary or multiple
systems.
In fact,
the iconic image from Star Wars,
the original star wars movie before they
numbered them,
I think.
What would star wars for?
Well,
yeah,
whatever,
whatever that that,
that,
that desert planet that Luke was on and
he comes out after visiting his was
what?
The step parent?
No,
his adoptive parents.
I don't remember whoever,
wherever he was visiting,
he comes out and you see a double
sunset.
So that's basically the only accurate
science and the entire series star wars
series.
I really enjoy taking a part of gravity
gravity and how many people got mad at
me,
so I stopped coming.
Come movies.
I don't need to Piss people off when I
watched your movie.
I'm having those thoughts anyway,
so I might as well share them with
people if you're interested.
So I did just that.
And then people.
The last time I did it was for Star
Wars,
the force awakens,
Star Wars seven.
I had a series of tweets,
you know,
one of them was um,
Bba,
a smooth rolling metal spherical ball
would have skidded uncontrollably on
sand.
People got angry.
Someone tweeted back,
shut the fuck up.
Okay.
That's.
So.
So I said,
okay,
I'm not here to get people angry.
I'm just here to enlightened,
to help people enhance their movie going
experience.
But to the extent that is not
accomplishing this,
I don't need to do it.
I'm just saying I don't.
I'm an educator.
I thought I was being nice.
I don't need to do.
So I haven't tweeted about a movie since
then.
I got to stop.
You.
See I have tweets I can post about
arrival.
Please give us a little bit of a shutter
off.
Okay.
Now you've got to give it a chance.
I,
as soon as I see a movie that starts
out,
I don't,
spoiler alert,
starts out with a sick kid.
I'm like,
fuck you.
No,
no,
no.
In fact,
it's very not about the kid.
I'm sure that's what I keep is totally
not about the kid.
Jamie hated it.
Oh yeah.
So you just give it a chance.
But anyhow,
so I just stopped.
Maybe I'll come back,
but I'm.
Yeah,
and people need to know the gravity.
That was good that you explained that
not only is it's not plausible,
those two satellites on anywhere near
each other.
They're like,
Gosh.
We're said,
oh,
there's the,
there's the international space station
and I'm on the Chinese space station.
Let me just jet pack my wave.
Do you really?
Excuse me lady.
Hey Lady.
Do you know how far away these are from
one another.
You can just jet around from one space
station to another.
No,
can't do it there.
Tens of thousands of miles from one
another for goodness sake.
So,
but anyhow,
so I,
yeah,
you remember the tweet?
It was like 15 tweets and I didn't know
that was when I realized like the press
was reading my movie tweets and those
tweets.
There's now a couple of years ago when
gravity came out with Sandra bullock
and,
and um,
uh,
what's the dude's name?
George Clooney.
So I tweeted it and they got talked
about on the,
on the today show,
set the set,
the weekend today show on NBC.
Then it was talked about on NBC nightly
news.
Then my tweets were talking about on
Saturday night lives,
the weekend update.
It was like the NBC Trifecta and I said,
oh my gosh,
this was,
had not,
that was not the point.
I didn't seek this if fine,
I'm glad they,
they are reacting this way because that
means they care about the science may
be.
But what?
Seth Meyers there,
because he was doing weekend update at
the time,
he said a astrophysicist Neil degrasse
station harshly criticized the movie
gravity a saying has,
contains a number of scientific and
accuracies,
for example.
There is no way George Clooney would
have spent that much time talking to a
woman his own age.
That's hilarious.
I think Sandra bullock's still younger
than George Clooney though.
They should've got their facts,
but not.
Yeah,
but not by much.
I mean,
yeah,
there were.
There were in the same neighborhood.
Yeah.
I think it's important.
I think that you enjoy the movie.
It's great,
it's fun and everything like that,
but it's important to point out what the
science areas are.
I think I,
I think that the,
I think the movie could have done
better.
Honestly.
I thinks they could have made the same
movie.
People thought I didn't like the movie
when all I was doing was pointing out
things they got wrong.
By the way.
They did some stunning things correctly.
For example,
this was,
this is brilliant.
If you're in zero g a fire basically
puts itself out.
So think about when you burn a candle on
earth.
Uh,
so you liked the wick at this.
People have candles anymore.
They forgot what a candle.
You light it with a match that you used
to get from smoking lounges at bars.
All right,
so you light the candle and it stays
lit.
The fuel is the wax.
The oxygen continually comes in because
it heats the air around it and the air
rises,
hot air rises and fresh air comes in
from below.
It has fresh oxygen,
so the candles stayed lit until it burns
all the way down in space.
If you light a candle,
you can light the candle.
It'll heat the air,
but the air will not know where to go
because it's not lighter than everything
because it's in zero g,
it'll stake clustered around the candle.
The candle will use up all the oxygen in
that bubble and then it'll put itself
out.
They did this in the movie,
so why do they have some good science?
Because they make.
You can't think of everything so they
just have you on.
Staff will know they can.
You know,
she couldn't think of anything if I.
So you can't think of everything.
So I wasn't judgemental so much as this
movie.
The fact that it got so much right is
what put it on my map to criticize what
it got wrong.
That makes sense at.
Does that make they make you older hair?
Her bangs should've been floating,
floating all over.
Now you might think,
am I the nitpicky?
No,
because we will get any picture of
somebody with hair.
Okay.
In space in zero g there.
Here is flying everywhere.
It's the first thing you notice about
them.
It is so obvious.
Like,
wow,
that's the coolest.
You're not thinking about the spaceship
or the tie technology.
You're looking at the hair doing stuff
you will never see happen on earth
unless someone is like underwater and
they're jiggling their head.
So they would have to film it all in
zero gravity.
They would have to film it on when those
drop things.
Yeah.
Or to drop thing and they'd have to be
clever about it.
And she only had bangs.
That's all you had to figure out how to.
They did other clever things.
So anyway,
that's all I did play by the way.
In all fairness to movies,
I'll call out something that's good.
The science,
that movie got right.
That otherwise got no science,
right?
I'll be the first in line to do that.
Like what?
Oh uh,
in the movie monsters inc.
Oh my gosh.
YOu didn't think I was going there.
Did you?
Uh,
those doors were four dimensional
portals to,
to another.
That's possible.
Well,
if you had four dimensions,
that's what it would look like.
Do you remember the movie opened?
They take the doors home?
Yes.
They opened the door and they're in the
closet of the kid that they're going to
terrorize.
Yes.
That's a wormhole.
That's what that is.
What access to the fourth dimension
looks like?
Do You think scientifically that's
possible one day?
I hope so.
I hope so because here's the example.
We've got a nice broad desk.
We hear it that at this interview,
right?
So desk is two dimensions.
It's got length and width and I can
start putting papers on this desk and I
can lay them out mosaic style and then
all of a sudden I have no more room to
put a sheet of paper.
If I'm an aunt living in the surface of
the desk,
I say,
no more room,
but wait a minute,
we are three dimensional people and I
can put an organizer and stack things
vertically so I can take a sheet of
paper and now I can put it higher up
than the surface of the desk.
The aunt will say,
where Did it go?
Oh my gosh.
It disappeared in some portal.
We're no,
no.
What?
What is that?
It went into the third dimension and the
ant bound and obviously as a three
dimensional thing,
imagine it only lives in two dimensions.
You would have made that paper disappear
into a third dimension and it will have
no clue where it went because you had a
portal you had access to that extra
dimension.
So look at how much you can store on a
desk when you have access to a third
dimension above it,
vastly more than just papers mosaic out
on the surface.
So now let's up this example by a
dimension.
You're storing boxes in a room or I ran
out of room.
No you didn't.
Let's open this four dimensional door.
You open it,
put the boxes through the door,
close the door box has gone,
there'll be awesome for hoarders.
You,
you,
uh,
you look around the other side of the
bar,
the door,
there's nothing there,
right?
The,
yoUr side of the door,
nothing there.
It's just a door that is a portal to a
fourth dimension that can hold vastly
more content than what is what you're
stuck storing in the three dimensional
space of your room.
Now that's so the tense of brilliant
concept and even though it has monsters
that don't exist that all speak english
and is one of them is a cycle ops and
one of them is a,
you know,
I'm not judging the biophysiology of
these creatures,
but they got the physics of,
of four dimensional portals completely
accurate.
Now the concept of dimensions is where
it gets really abstract with pete,
I love me some dimensions and it is
abstract.
It is,
and that's why you take.
Let the math take you into those higher
dimensions because our intuition will
not,
will fail for us.
RighT?
But that's where it gets weird.
When you say take the math,
let them take you.
So like when quantum physicists use
these legal notepads,
those yellow pads and write all that
crazy stuff down that nobody but you and
maybe them understand and when you look
at all those equations,
no,
it's them,
maybe me.
Then you probably understand it,
right?
But I definitely don't.
My point is What are they exactly?
Figuring out that allows them to say
there are.
I think they say,
well at one point in time was 11,
but I think they've expanded that,
right?
What they say,
I don't have the latest dimension count
on the universe,
but what the way it works is you.
You're trying to make sense of the
world.
Right?
And so you take some leaps.
So some,
some philosophical leafs leaps,
some mathematical leaps.
You say,
alright,
may be all particles that manifests as
an electronic proton,
a neutral may,
but the quarks,
maybe they are just strings of energy
vibrating at different frequencies and
we sense these different frequencies as
different particles.
Let's just go there for me.
Well,
if you're going to do that,
what are the consequences to it?
Then?
And how many dimensions do these
vibrating strings require to have the
properties that we see in our
dimensionality.
So,
so the exercise of explaining what you
see takes you to places that you've
never been before.
And that's fine.
Places at intellectual places that
you've,
that had been previously unplumbed.
There's nothing wrong with that.
We've done that before we.
That's why we know what is happening in
the center of the sun.
Have we ever been there?
No.
No,
but we know how matter behaves under
pressure and temperature.
We can do that in a laboratory.
We've got a son sitting out there with a
surface temperature,
a mass,
a certain luminosity,
and we'd say,
what must be going on down in the core?
let's bring our best physics or quantum
physics,
our,
our chemistry,
our nuclear physics,
bring it all together and we have a
complete understanding of what's going
on in the center of the sun.
And we're on to other problems now even
though we've never visited there.
So when they're going over this math,
the mathematics and observable things
that we have right now or at like the
atomic and subatomic level.
Correct?
We don't,
you can't see,
do you realize the electron?
Uh,
just uh,
okay.
So I met,
I did a whole series of this.
There's something calleD the great
courses lecture series was a sponsor of
this podcast for awhile with a really
great courses.
So cool.
So I was once invited to be one of their
professors for the great courses and I
taught a very short,
most of them are like 30 lectures.
It's like a whole college semester,
so I don't have the time and the energy.
So they let me do like short bits.
So one of them is only six parts and
it's called the inexplicably universe
and it's six parts of everything about
which we know nothing in this university
you might say,
well that's a pretty easy course to get
dark matter having a clue.
okay.
Onto the next lecture might be something
dark matter could be some we don't know.
Stay tuned.
So,
but it's interesting to learn how we
come to know what we don't know.
And so it's,
it's an exploration of our ignorance and
I'm very proud of it because it's,
it's not what you'd normally find in a
lecture series and it's still,
it's still out there,
but one of the things I will tell you
that in,
and I'll tell you now,
the electron has no known dimension.
It is smaller than the smallest we have
ever had the capacity to measure.
So as far as we concerned,
it is infinitely small.
Whoa.
We have no way to even know how to
measure.
By the way,
how do you measure something small?
You geT something smaller and find out
how many of those it is no.
about no.
Thinking about the challenges at each
extreme.
Asked me how big is the universe?
And I'll say it's as big as well,
I got nothing.
What am I going to say?
right.
There's nothing as big as the universe.
So at the biggest and in at the littlest
end,
there's not something else.
It doesn't work as well.
Okay.
To try to say what it is relative to
something else.
Do you entertain the possibility that
the biggest and the littlest end of the
same thing,
meaning that at are the smallest
measurable point that literally might be
a whole nother universe that might be
fracked.
It's fun to think about it all the way
down.
It's fun to think about again,
phonetically down like down or whatever,
and people,
by the way,
in the 19 twenties when we discovered
the atom and it's structure and that
there's an electron in orbit around a
nucleus.
It was at way we'd been there before.
We got planets orbiting the sun and so
this,
so maybe it's a mini solar system.
Maybe it's,
it's solar systems all the way down.
Well,
I'm glad you brought this up.
I'm glad we brought this up because I
wanted to bring this question.
I almost forgot there's a photograph of
a brain cell and side by side with a
photograph of the known universe and
they look eerily similar to.
Are you talking about the large scale
structure of the universe?
Scale of galaxies.
So I'll get to that in a minute.
Hold that up jamie.
OkaY,
so I'll get to that.
so do you ever tell him just pull up his
own damn images?
Yeah,
but I can't put it on the tv.
Said he has To do it.
So you a.
So here's why.
That's not likely.
Okay.
It was an entertained idea,
but here's why it's not likely.
The manifestation of the laws of physics
are different at the atomic scale than
they are at the macroscopic scale to
just simply different.
A planet can take any orbit sensible for
its velocity around a host star.
An electron cannot.
It's energy levels are predetermined and
quantized hence the word quantum,
the prefix quanta in quantum physics.
So if it was a continuum of matter and
energy following the same laws of
physics,
then I would say then it's sole systems
all the way down,
but the rules completely change and so
things can on the surface seems similar,
but when it comes time to understand
them and to analyze them and to
manipulate them and to exploit their
conduct and their behavior for other
means as we have done with atoms or
molecules for the entire it revolution,
you no longer are they the same and you
abandoned this romanticized concept.
So now with the neurons,
the network of neurons and the cost are
the clusters of galaxies and galaxy
superclusters.
That would be on the right neurons on
the left.
That's so eerie.
yes.
So,
so yeah,
they can look the same,
but they are operating under completely
different laws of physics.
So in other words,
the laws of physics that dictate what's
going on in brain cells have no
relationship to what's going on in the
universe.
Brain cells,
you're undergoing a.
We can tell you what forces are
operating.
It's,
it's,
it's electromagnetic forces.
Brain cells use electrical impulses,
chemical impulses.
This is why drugs can affect the brain.
All right?
There are chemical,
the chemistry going on in the brain,
in its natural state.
You disrupt that,
enhance it.
You just,
you just put down some,
some,
some chemistry and your stomach that's
now affecting your brain.
Um,
what'd you just drink there?
What was it?
Alpha brain algebra.
Okay,
so you're entering the chemistry.
So it's chemistry.
What's going on on the large scale
structure,
the universe is not chemistry.
There's some chemistry deep within,
but it's,
the chemistry is not what's making that
pattern.
And because of that it becomes an
artistic curiosity,
not something that has any kind of deep
scientific insight.
So it's just a fast.
It's disappointing similarity.
Yes.
It's a fascinating.
Similarly put them up together and it's
fun to think about it,
but it's not.
It's fun to think about it artistically,
but not scientifically.
No,
it's great if you're hanging out with
your friends going,
wow,
man,
high,
you are.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
When you're looking at subatomic
particles,
excuse me,
and you're looking at these,
like when they observed a particles in
superposition,
whether moving and stationary at the
same time,
and they blink in and out of existence,
like when you get down to that,
and I repeat the,
the,
uh,
the opening page of the book,
the universe is under no obligation to
make sense to,
oh yeah,
for sure.
Definitely does.
Yeah.
So at that scale,
things that go on with atoms and
molecules fall outside of your life
experience.
You don't hang out at the bar with
protons,
new claw,
nuclear weapons or other nuclear plans
or,
or molecules.
You just don't.
So what they do in their day is
completely foreign to you.
So now you shrink down to that size and
particles a popping in and out of
existence.
The,
the,
theY become conjoined quantum,
mechanically conjoined.
And it's completely weird.
And you would say,
This is,
none of this makes sense and this is
observable in a visual sense.
Uh,
well,
it depends.
Depends on how big the phenomena is.
Otherwise you can see other things that
would happen that you know,
that are the manifestations of that
happening.
But yeah,
so an electron is smaller even than
that.
Oh yes.
By how many factors?
No,
no,
we don't.
We don't know.
We don't know was no electric.
Never measured the size of an
electronic.
The concept of super string theory,
so a supo these smaller than that,
the strings would have to be smaller,
thinner.
It's smaller than the electronic self by
many that I couldn't quantify for you.
I got to bring in a string theory
person.
So iT's like at the bottom of what we
can observe.
Well,
that's a great question.
what is the bottom and the,
you know the word adam,
which was introduced by the greeks.
You knoW,
what adam means in greek?
It has a translation,
you know what I mean?
No.
Indivisible.
Ah,
so they imagined that all matter was
you'd come down to some thing that was
invisible,
figure that out.
They figure it out.
They supposed it and they were the first
day were,
you know,
they're wealthy and had free time and
when they weren't waging war or that you
could think and what we think of his
philosophy was traceable to a lot of
what they were doing back then and the
origins of what science is,
are traceable to back to back then that
you have an idea that applies to what
the universe does that enables you to
predict future behavior.
That is science.
And so,
uh,
so the atom it turned out is divisible
is divisible into sub atomic sub atom
particles.
So you get electrons,
protons,
neutrons,
and a whole host of other particles less
familiar there,
neutrinos and other things that it turns
out protons and neutrons are further
divisible that you get corks out of
those.
And as far as we know,
there are only four fundamental
particles in the universe.
The photon,
which is light,
the electron of which there are several
species that the anti electronic,
but just these are state simple here.
The photon,
the electron,
the cork,
and the neutrino.
Everything in the universe that we've
ever observed is made out of that stuff,
so those are the atoms of the universe,
the indivisible parts,
if you will.
Now,
this isn't by the way dark matter could
be made of yet another kind of saying
that we don't know yet the blood.
We got top people trying to figure out
what dark matter is.
We've measured it out there.
We just don't know what it is.
Well,
it's something like 90 something percent
of the universe,
dark matter and dark energy.
It's 95 percent of all that drives the
universe and we can measure the
existence of both.
Yet we have no idea what's driving them.
This is an awesome opportunity for you
to eliminate this.
Often it's all in astrophysics for
people in heart.
It's all it comes out in may.
You can preorder it,
which by the way,
publishers love it if you preorder it
and adorable,
but it's beautiful.
It's a good size.
It's adorable.
Preorder it on amazon.
You know the reason why they publishers
like you to preorder it is so that they
can take of me.
Yeah,
they just want to.
Didn't want to overprint they don't want
to under print that,
so they get a sense of the preordering
because you're not charged until they
ship it,
so it's a pretty harmless exercise.
While we're on this subject of subatomic
particles and weirdness,
I wanted to.
I want to,
if you could eliminate this often
misused explanation for the observer
effect because you know the the
particles waves and you watch them and
observed them and it changes.
The reaction is heavily misunderstood.
It's misunderstood because people want
to attribute it to magic.
The magic and the consciousness looking
at it but isn't in fact just measuring
it.
Yes.
Thank you.
Please explain next question because I'm
so tired.
Show show you.
Good.
It just drives me nuts.
Your people with you.
I try when I'm.
Where are you pulling?
What?
Where are you getting your people?
Well,
I Don't own them for sure.
Definitely not my people.
They vary greatly.
Kennedy been looped in together.
I know you haven't admirably diverse
following and then not many people can
claim that and it's probably because of
your diverse profile.
Right?
Well,
I'm as open minded as I can be smart and
you'd read and you're thoughtful and
you're also on some level of respect
people here at somebody out and you're,
you know,
you did,
you got your mma thing.
so no,
you're in a lot of places and a lot of
spaces and that's a good thing.
I mean we need more unity in this world,
so.
So.
Well,
thank you.
Thank you.
Please explain what flipped people are
getting wrong.
Okay.
So very simple.
It's much simpler than you think.
Okay.
Alright,
you ready?
Yes.
So I'm looking at you.
the only reason why I can see you is
because there's light reflecting off of
your face,
your body into my eyes.
So there's light.
Oh,
by the way,
these stars.
That's.
Yeah,
those are hubble photographs.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
Those are images from the hubble and I
walked in the sheets that you put over
the a fluorescent light cover.
And so when we look up,
we actually see the real,
real images.
You're pretending it's the night sky.
Yeah.
Well it be recording studio.
What I want to do in the future studio,
I want to actually build a glass ceiling
and have a full scale image,
a high resolution image of stars.
So a planetarium.
You're describing a planetary.
Exactly.
Call it that.
It's a planetarium.
Well,
something like that,
but I just wanted an image.
You know what you know?
Tell me how to do It.
I'll do it.
No,
do better than that.
You get a,
you get occurred version of those very
high resolution led.
Curved,
yeah.
Okay.
Then you put any image up there you want
and then the night sky tonight,
it's what the sky looks like from,
from alpha insuree.
Oh.
So lIke when you go to see one of those
star shows at a planetarium and they
show it on the ceiling above you.
Well,
yes,
but nowadays that the ceiling itself is
the,
is the source of light.
It's not projected from something.
So then you just feed that with image
data and then it becomes whatever you
want.
Can you hook me up with someone who
knows how to do that?
Yeah,
I can totally.
I'm excited.
You don't know people.
I got people,
I mean people that my people,
terry,
I mean my people because you're mobile,
you are,
you.
Are you happy that you know the people
teach the people.
so I guess so here what I'm looking at
you.
Okay.
All right.
Yes.
And I see you.
I want to know where you are.
So I turn on the lights and I say,
there you are.
All right.
Now let's make you tinier.
Let's make you mini me.
Okay.
Like in the movie,
right?
So that was a tiny version of you.
A mini me version of joe rogan.
Now your little.
I turn on the light.
You're still there.
Okay.
Because if the lights are not on,
I can't see you.
I don't know where you are.
Right?
It's that simple.
Okay?
Okay.
When you start becoming the size of
molecules right on down to the size of
an atom.
And I asked the question,
where is joe rogan the adam and I turn
on the light to see you there because I
think you're there.
The light,
the photon comes in,
hits your adam and pops you into another
location.
Hm.
The very act of trying to measure your
position prevents me from measuring your
position and as have jack shit to do
with your consciousness or your mind or
your eyes or anything.
It has to do with the fact that to know
you're there,
some information has to come from you to
me,
like shining a light on you.
And the smaller you are,
the more susceptible you are to the,
the,
the energy of the light changing your
position in space.
So my question is,
how do you notice like you ever.
This is still happen,
you're a quarter spills out of your
pants pocket on the back seat of a car
and it's there in the wedge between the
bottom and the back seat.
And so you try to reach in to get it.
And the act of reaching for the coin
makes the coin move farther away from
you.
Uh,
the act of reaching for it,
right?
Because we separated,
you separated and it just slides down
even further.
That's not your mind making that happen.
It's the,
it's the act of the measurement that is
affecting what it is you're trying to
measure.
And this was discovered in quantum
physics until the point where that's
actually,
it's the heisenberg uncertainty
principle.
It's one of the basic foundations of
quantum physics.
Now when it's round,
it's profound,
but when it's described in the eu will
weigh you.
They show these particles going through
these slots and then observing them
changes the pattern that they go through
with.
And there's a.
There's a horrible cartoon that you see
in that a movie.
What the bleep?
I couldn't get through that movie.
I tried.
Did you go crazy with the bad science?
No.
Can I tell you where I turned to?
Maybe I should say,
well,
here's what people don't know.
A lot of that is from a cult.
The woman that I didn't know,
the woman who is the lunch,
I don't mind a cult movie.
I don't know.
She's a channeler.
She's speaking as a character like di di
know that.
That one.
Oh,
blonde woman,
older blonde woman.
That's.
And she speaks when she speaks,
she speaking as a care.
Okay.
I didn't know that.
You have to like,
she's,
she's a part of this very bizarre sort
of cult.
And should I tell you where I tuned it
out or you want to finish this?
Okay.
So I tried to,
I just couldn't watch it.
Right.
There's a point where they're talking
about,
uh,
natives in the caribbean seeing european
ships.
Yes.
And then they said,
well,
because they'd never seen a ship before.
They brain didn't register it as
anything and then it just disappeared.
Bullshit.
And I'm thinking,
no,
that's not how the brain works.
Excuse me.
That's not how this works.
Okay.
What would happen?
They might not know what they're looking
at,
but they'll know they're looking at
something and it had ships.
They,
they went from island to island.
That's how you get from island to
island.
They say,
Well,
that's a really big version of what
weird.
We've never seen anything that big
before.
I don't know what it is.
I don't know where it came from,
but I want to find out.
I want to study it.
I'm going to protect myself,
whatever.
So just because you've never seen it,
doesn't mean you're not going to
register it.
Excuse me.
No,
no,
no.
I said,
no wonder I can't waste my.
I got other things I've got to devote my
brain energy to instead of instead of
this,
but someone else.
Oh,
it gets better later on.
So I said,
maybe I'll borrow.
No,
it does.
It gets more confusing later on and it,
it,
it does a better job of confusing you as
to what science has shown and what they
haven't shown now.
By the way,
just in all fairness to what they.
I think that the point they were trying
to make,
there are things that if you don't know
to recognize them,
you would.
They Would go undiscovered.
Yes.
Okay.
But that doesn't mean you wouldn't see
them.
Okay.
So for example,
let's say you're walking and you didn't
know that you were walking over this
huge burial mound because the slope was
really shallow and you just walking,
okay,
well you just,
you,
you didn't notice that.
Okay?
So you need a different way to see it in
order to know.
So from space,
from an angle,
measure the height,
whatever.
So there are ways to miss things that
and that.
And that happens all the time,
but if it's something there on the
horizon,
my gosh,
this is why we have eyes.
Okay,
now they're not the best day to taking
devices,
but it was come time to tell you whether
there's a shipper,
not a ship that you've never seen
before.
It's a ship.
Of course.
I'm just so much evidence of that when
people discover new animals.
Yes.
I've never seen anything before
anything,
anything.
There's no record of it whatsoever.
People find it and they could still see
most scientific discoveries.
You discovered something we've never
seen before.
Ramp the.
That was the woman's name.
That was the,
the person that she was channel.
That's a cool channeling name,
but you have to have a channeling name.
It ramped our chancellor.
I'd be ramp though.
I found that after the,
uh,
after the movie was done,
after I watched it,
I was,
they got me with a lot of things.
I was like,
wow,
is that true?
IS that real?
Then I started reading.
Fortunately that movie came out in the
two thousands instead of in the
nineties.
Because if it came out in the nineties,
we were all got duped.
Oh,
go and have the internet to research all
the shit that's wrong with it.
But in the two thousands I started
researching it and then I would send it
to my friends,
like,
look,
look where the fuck this came from.
And then.
And then you go,
oh,
that's a called.
Yeah,
it's a.
The ladies at color,
she's like,
she's talking like she's an alien.
She's supposed to be an alien.
Right?
Isn't that you see it in there anyway.
Again,
I don't mind.
I don't mind if people think their
channel or is that just don't put them
in charge of anything.
That's all.
Well,
It's not that I signed.
It's just that you should probably say
that when you get going with that.
Yeah.
So I know exactly what I'm saying called
nobody's ever said she calls herself
ramp.
They think it's real and genuine and
sincere and they're very sincere because
they've put themselves.
Well,
that whole thing we need is,
is,
is you.
Don't you need is some foundation of
science literacy so that you can
inoculate yourself against those who
would exploit your absence of knowledge
of how the science works for their own
gain?
Well,
not even for their own gain.
Just youtube videos.
I mean,
someone could make a very compelling
youtube video where they get you
convinced at all.
My god,
dinosaurs aren't real.
They start playing these things for you.
they tell,
hey,
tell us about phones can pop popcorn in
the cmc.
That one.
Oh,
I have seen that way.
Yeah.
You line up sometimes within the
department color you gotta like directly
to colonel someone that can't really
happen.
No,
of course.
of course not.
Here.
Imagine it could.
Jesus christ will be like,
what are we doing with these phones?
But there's a ton of those out there
where people see that's one of the
problems with,
uh,
with a lack of dialogue with someone who
just has one narrative.
Like you sit down,
he added something and you just talk.
ain't no,
it's a,
it's very similar to like,
even if you write a blog,
I mean it's one thing if you're writing
a blog,
like say if you're an expert in
electronics,
you read a blog about how a televIsion
works,
but if you're just a person and you
don't really understand what you're
talking about,
but you're right something and use the
right words and you say it in a very
compelling way,
like an attack piece on someone that
really has no basis in reality,
you can have someone convinced this
person's a terrible person just by
writing something without them having to
respond.
I call up stop,
never did that.
I tweet a february,
I tweet a few weeks ago and I don't get
their budget because it's,
it's way better as the tweet than I will
ever remember it as the tweet.
So it was one of the great challenges in
life is knowing enough to think you're
right,
but not enough to know you're wrong.
Yeah,
well that is a big problem with a lot of
people that watch his youtube videos.
that's what it is.
They say,
oh,
this is right.
Oh my gosh,
but they don't know enough to know why
it's wrong,
but this is what I wanted to talk to you
about.
Uh,
what is it about people that there's
this,
this very compelling need to find
something out that other people don't
know.
Like the world is flat,
like dinosaurs aren't real.
Like that kind of stuff is very
compelling to people.
So what I do in those cases,
in the,
In the,
uh,
yeah,
so what I do is I would say instead of
debating them and some of some of your
listeners are listening to this right
now,
it's what all I would do is say,
what is your best single bit of evidence
for what you're claiming and what would
it take to show that you're wrong?
All right,
well let's go get a simple one.
So,
so,
so that's what I would ask.
And
I've done
this exercise and it doesn't work.
You know why?
Why?
Because there was a guy who didn't
believe we went to the moon.
We spent a third of our time in our last
session.
Goes there.
So there's someone I know who doesn't
believe he went to the moon rather than
just say he's skeptical.
So I said,
what kind of evidence would convince
you?
He said images of the landing site of
the apollo missions.
So I said,
okay,
here's a website where we sent a.
If it wasn't west,
it was the chinese think the chinese
were europeans sent,
aced a probe to an orbiter,
to the moon.
So It was close enough because ground
based telescopes are not,
don't they don't have the resolution to
see the landing sites,
but if you get close enough to the moon
you can get It photographed the entire
surface of the moon.
And there were the landing sites and you
saw the rover tracks and the base for
the lunar module.
And so he,
that night he went home and found it and
then he came back and says,
well,
nasa could have faked that.
Well,
I'm done with you.
We have no more to talk about because
he's not ready to be convinced.
Well,
that's a weird.
Because he gave him the evidence.
He asked for exact.
That would convince him and it did not
convince them that we have,
I have no other conversation with.
That's a singular event which you could
say in one way or like it is possible
that someone could fake a singular
event.
They can't fake whether or not the
world's flat,
right.
Like that to me is the scariest one,
that there's so many people out there
that believes the world is flat because
you could,
you could literally see the curvature of
the earth from a plane.
I mean you can get to a parts of the,
you look at the images from the space
station where they circled the moon or
they circled the earth rather.
I mean there,
there's many,
many satellite images of the earth in
its entirety.
You know,
and one of the thIngs that,
the argument was,
is how come every photograph of the
earth is a compilation of photographs?
Well,
because they're all taken from 300 miles
up.
The earth is huge.
Here's a way bigger than 300 miles or
have to take a compliment,
do this.
The only way to get.
Except for the apollo photo,
the polish 17 coming back has the earth.
That's the famous one that was africa
and antarctica and view the full earth.
Very few.
Full earth's is very hard to get a full
earth single photo.
Of course,
the astro and when we went to the moon,
the moon missions,
when they're coming back,
think about it.
To get full.
Earth means the sun is behind the
astronauts on the way back to earth,
which means the side of the moon facing
earth is not lit,
but that's the side of the moon they
came from,
so they want to visit the moon while
it's sunlight there,
they don't want you to need flashlights
when they get to the moon,
so they visited the moon while there's
sunlight earth.
The view of earth at that time will not
be full.
So apollo 17 was there long enough so
that by the time they left the moon was
basically a new moon.
Earth was full,
moon of earth was full earth,
and then he got a fuller throat up.
Those packs that they have on their back
that regulate the temperature,
that allows them to walk on the surface
of the moon when it's 250 degrees above
zero,
the side is facing.
The sun is more than 200 degrees and in
the shadow,
the 150 degrees and below.
Yeah,
yeah,
so ken,
it switched back and forth between those
two environments.
Know what you need,
know what you just insulate the.
It's insulated and so when you're
insulated,
those temperature extremes are not felt
the minimized and it's regulated by the
pack.
Pack those warm oxygen and no it
maintains the temperature,
but in the case of warming and cooling
in the face of what's going on,
it maintains the temperature.
That's how you need to thInk about it.
Okay,
so regardless of what it is,
cooling one side of you and chilling the
heating,
the other side,
it's maintaining a temperature for you
and when you are in space like say,
well,
they're doing a space can click on the
space station.
Same thing as being on the surface of
the moon is real atmosphere on earth.
You are in this,
in this cocoon there I say,
of atmosphere,
so all the air in this room is the same
temperature because the air can
communicate a difference in temperature
to itself.
Equilibrating it across the whole room,
right?
If you don't have air than your
temperature is measured by where's the
energy coming from,
the teaching you,
and if the sun is hitting you,
all that energy will be raising your
temperature and the side of you that's
not facing photons.
That temperature will drop,
so you need to.
You could survive it if you put yourself
on a rotisserie,
figuring out the right rotation rate,
and even then you'd have to spend pretty
quick in order to actually calculate
that.
Yeah,
you have to figure out what the right
rate is.
Now when you get in a debate with a guy
like bob guy,
I don't debate people.
Okay,
well when you discussed the saying goes,
when winning argument lasts more than
five minutes,
both sides are wrong.
Well,
that's a terrible saying.
It was definitely something wrong and
the other person's stubborn.
It definitely lasts for hours.
Yeah,
that's true.
It's true.
Eighty percent of the time,
but you got into would that wrapper that
thinks that the.
Here's,
I'll tell you why bob,
because in his twitter stream he was
saying he was invoking physics and so I,
I gotta I gotta deal with this and so he
showed a picture from bear mountain,
which is a mountain in,
in slightly upstate New York where
manhattan is in the sight line of the
summit of this mountain.
And he says,
give her the curvature of the earth and
this formula,
you should not be able to see manhattan
at all.
Okay.
Um,
and it depends on the height that you're
viewing.
Well,
thank you.
well,
so,
so you,
you do the math and it turns out
manhattan,
the island would not be visible at all.
That's true.
But any building taller than 15 stories
would rise up above the curvature of the
earth.
And you will see it.
And if you look at the photo,
you see the tall buildings
rising above 15 stories.
It's exactly what the correct formula
shows and not his formula,
which was wrong and misinterpreted a
claims to show.
Well,
it's just bizarre because snipers had
been using the literal curve of the
earth to plan where bullets go.
That's how you want it.
That have to,
when you shoot a mile,
you know when you're shooting like well
out over a thousand yards.
those,
those factors.
So let me think of mile.
I have to ask how much curvature of the
earth you get after a mile drop
question.
You get dropped in curb to be gravity
drop.
Yes.
And then curve.
Yeah.
So both of those.
Well,
is it good?
It's here.
Here's the thing to say someone,
if you have a bullet in your hand and
you shoot a gun,
uh,
which drops faster,
right?
They generally,
they get the wrong answer to that drop
at the exact same rate.
Go hIt the ground at the same time,
exact same time.
And that,
that blows people's minds.
I can't believe that physics one-on-one.
Wow.
It's,
it's a physics demo.
So that's why physics is so important.
You know,
people always take biology in this
grade,
but don't leave out the physics because
that's where the fundamental operations
of nature are to be found.
Of the physical universe are to be
found,
so what you have is you have a gun at
one side,
it's like a thing that shoots out a
project to,
we'll call it a gun at one side of the
stage,
and then you have like a little stuffed
animal.
If the other side's case held up with an
electro magnet at the top of his head,
and these two are exactly the same level
as the projectile comes out from the
booth.
There's many cannon it trips and
electric circuit that releases the
electromagnet at the top of the stuffed
animal.
The stuffed animal begins to fall.
The bullets moves horizontally,
but also falls because gravity is
pulling them both and you watched the
projectIle curve down,
you watch the stuffed animal come down
and it hits the stuffed animal every
single time.
The only factor that would change that
would be if you put wings in the bullet.
it was dealing with the wind.
When the wind would affect it.
Did they have boats with wings?
I haven't seen that.
No.
They don't know.
But if they did,
you know,
if like you shot the bullet and then
they figured out like wings came out.
I saw that on some James Bond movie I
thought.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
Yeah.
It's,
it's just got to be frustrating for you
when these things come back around.
Like there was no flat earth theory when
I was in high school.
So the other things though,
think about it,
when you were in high school,
there was much more astrology going on.
Oh yeah.
The president,
reagan.
Nancy reagan has an astrologer.
Uh,
so today you don't see much of it.
You,
unless you talked to steve maxwell,
what?
But it's still there.
It's just not,
it's not manifesting in public policy.
Some people believe in it deeply.
I agree.
But it's not up there in public policy.
That's what I'm saying.
Okay.
Well we're the.
Nancy reagan was really the only one
that made it with public policy then.
But at the bar to you,
do
you hear people saying,
what's your sign?
Is that still pick up 100 percent be
true?
Listen,
dude,
you're married an american man.
I'm out of it.
You don't understand if you want to get
laid,
you got to talk nonsense.
People got sucked.
Well,
I'm a scorpio.
If you're a taurus,
we should just stop.
I'm sorry I missed that.
I misled myself.
I thought it was fading.
Oh,
nancy reagan was the big proponent of
it's nonsense.
Astrology.
Now it's not like someone who really
understands astrological charts and can
plot it and the moon's in retrograde and
you were born and you know,
celsius is rising and all that crazy
crap that they tried to.
I don'T know what they're doing on a
talk show with finished roger a real
one.
Apparently.
Yes.
She.
She's real or fake one,
right?
She says she's real and I trust her
because she talks about how fake other
astrologers are a hater.
I don't trust her.
And she was saying that the kennedys all
died during a lunar eclipse.
Scary.
And you know that this is a very
checkable statement.
She just says this and everyone's
listening and believing in.
Wow.
That's.
That can't be by accident.
Well,
I don't know when other kennedy's died,
but I know when Jack Kennedy died and it
was November 22nd,
1963,
so.
So I don't need to know if there's an
eclipse then I just need to know what
phase the moon is in.
Right?
Because you can only have a lunar
eclipse when the moon is full.
So the moon was nowhere near full.
It was like two weeks away from full.
Even if there was an eclipse,
it didn't happen during an eclipse is my
point.
Right.
Okay.
So of course,
because it was daylight.
Well,
well no,
you can have a lunar eclipse at anytime.
Okay.
You can have solar look anytime too.
It's just dark.
It's just how it would be for the world.
Right,
right.
Don't be so silly centric centric.
In fact,
when there's a lunar eclipse,
anyone on this side of the earth that
sees the moon will see the lunar
eclipse.
So,
so by the way,
lunar eclipses you get several per year
by the way.
A partial eclipses as a minimum and
every couple years there's a full and
rich ellipses.
So these are not rare things to start.
They're not rare.
Okay.
So I said,
you know,
he,
he was shot when the,
I forgot what muna was first quarter
moon and she said,
oh,
well this counts if they're anywhere
within two weeks on either side of the
eclipse,
that's a month.
That's a month out of 12.
What?
I said,
let me just shut up here and let her
keep sharing the time.
It was a thrill.
Had a talk shOw.
We will talk to him.
So.
And he likes science by the way.
And he,
he wore the nasa shirt at the,
uh,
at the,
at the academy award group photo.
so I got to give him some props for
that.
But.
So,
but we're.
So I just said I'm,
I'm have nothing more to say here.
Hence my argument with her lasted less
than five minutes now.
What are they when,
when they're trying to decide like what
your personality would be and what you,
you know,
what you can dictate from your birth
date and what time you were born.
What are they exactly.
Trying to connect.
So I had a deeper awareness of this
recently when I learned that people take
the names of things very seriously.
Okay.
The names mean things to people
regardless of what the thing actually
is.
Okay.
So What might we mean by this?
Uh,
so uh,
let's like astrophysics,
I say we have this thing called dark
matter.
We don't know what it is.
Well,
it's got to be some kind of matter.
No,
no.
It shouldn't be called dark matter.
It should be called fred.
All right.
With no,
it shouldn't lead you to think anything
about it because we do not know what it
is.
We shouldn't really call it dark
gravity.
It is,
it is gravity that we have measured.
We don't know what's causing the
gravity.
Just call it dark.
Matter implies you think it's matter.
Some people do,
but we don't know.
So explain to me what,
what is this based on?
Like When you say dark matter,
what is it based on its.
I'd like to just call it fred for let's
call it fred and I'm saying we don't
know what it is,
right?
What Is,
how is,
how is measuring the gravity of this
stuff?
Okay,
it's out there the six times the gravity
of stuff that's ordinary matter.
we don't know where it's coming from.
We don't know the source.
We don't know the arctic.
Is that a parallel universe?
Is that we don't know and how are we
measuring it by its effect on the
motions of object.
So a certain strength of gravity will
force you to move at a given speed as
you near it.
And as you pull away and we see this in
galaxies,
galaxy clusters,
binary galaxies and large entire
galaxies that are made completely out of
this fred,
at least 80 percent of the force of
gravity manifested in these galaxies is
fred.
Yes.
And,
and that's why.
Why are they calling it dark matter?
They shouldn't,
in my opinion,
she called dark gravity because that's
literally what it is.
So its gravity that cannot be measured,
a gravity,
gravity and poorly understood.
It's not understood.
Correct.
So it's,
it's mysterious gravity completely
measured to measure it.
We can't narrow down what you measure
against gravity.
Precisely.
Right.
Okay.
So you measure it,
but you can't.
So my origin,
because some,
we don't know what it is that my point
is because someone called it dark
matter.
It has swayed everybody into thinking
that it is matter of some kind.
It has constrained people's thoughts
about how to think about this problem.
Okay.
So now the ancients looked up and they
saw these stars and they put their
culture on the sky.
So there centaurs,
there's,
you know,
um,
uh,
when it was sent to archer.
So it sagittarius.
We have a ryan,
the hunter.
We have tourists,
we have sea serpents,
we have rivers,
we have stuff that mattered to people
back then.
Okay,
we have an aquarius.
What does it,
what's the water bearer?
Oh,
the warner bear.
That must mean that when the sun is in
aquarius,
it's going to rain more on earth.
Why?
Because the ancients called it the water
bearer a okay.
And all of a sudden the name reigns
supreme over the fact that it is a
random set of stars widely separated in
space that don't even look like people
holding a pitcher of water of the 88
constellations,
about six of them look like what you're
told they're supposed to look like the
rest require opium induced imagination
to establish what they are.
So they all have names.
Then you go to the astrologers tables
and they say,
oh,
this is the rain sign,
or this is a dry drought sign.
And then you take the names of things
and those names are what they interpret
based on where the moon is.
The sun is where the planets are and all
whatever the angle configurations they
are.
And each angle has a certain latitude
over which they'll count it as a hit
rather than as a miss.
And so this gives extraordinary capacity
of the astrologer to tell you what's
going on in your life.
Uh huh.
So it's bullshit.
But they did have this real,
a fascinating connection with these
certain constellations and all of the
different things that they thought were
attached these certain constellation.
You know,
it's,
you know,
it'd be like,
it'd be like I'm a geologist going up to
the border of Colorado trying to
understand the shape as a geologist.
Hm.
It's,
it's,
it's an arbitrary shape.
Colorado was a square on a curved
surface.
It's amazing how much confirmation bias
is attached bY a river by a.
Yeah,
that's right.
So the wiki has a great website on
cognitive bias and there's like 20 or so
well known by every person.
It should be.
This should be a course called cognitive
bias.
One-on-one,
not forget college.
Every high school should have a course.
Cognitive bias and the entire course
should be about all the ways we fool
ourselves.
don't you think?
So,
I've tweeted this to science.
The only of the scientific method is to
make sure you are not fooled into
thinking that something is true,
that is not,
or thinking that something is not true.
That is,
that is the only point of the.
And therefore the scientists could be
anything you invent.
Just take better notes,
take a chart recorder,
uh,
be more awake next time you take the
data,
bring a friend to observe it with you.
Whatever it takes to minimize the
chances that you will miss,
interpret what you're looking at so that
you don't think something is true that
is not or thinks something is not true.
That is do whatever it takes to support
that,
that a mission statement.
That's what the scientific method is and
that's what we do as scientists and
that's why when you bring all of these
things that people do,
so it's the astrology and the crystal
healers and the and who are the,
the,
the therapeutic touch people and you
don't know that's real.
You don't even understand.
This goes on healer.
I'm an intuitive.
He goes on and on and on and on,
and these are the things that fail in
the double blind science.
Any why do you do double blind?
So you don't fool yourself into thinking
something is true.
That's why you do double blind if you
don't and you want something to be true,
even if you even if you're surprised by
something that might've been true that
you were against,
still you need someone else to check it
out and you only get an emergent
scientific truth when you have agreement
among different people's experiments is
there so even if you get a result that
you're happy with,
it is not yet a scientific truth until
you can confirm it by other people who
have no investment in you who don't care
about.
In fact,
we're trying to show that you're wrong.
This is what made einstein so great
because no one believed as relativity
and they kept devising evermore accurate
experiments to show he was wrong and it
ended up showing that he was right by
ever higher precision.
Do you think that we're doing ourselves
a disservice by not teaching people how
the mind works,
how confirmation bias and and it's you
shouldn't teach things in school.
I'm working on this one a few years,
in a few years,
I'm going to have something by now
because I'm busy.
My kids are in school right now.
Excuse me.
I can't.
I understand,
but let's discuss it because I think it
curriculum has to include an entire
course on cognitive bias.
Yes.
If we are going to emerge as adults,
no longer susceptible to charlatans.
Yes.
Okay.
Who are either well meaning and just
misguided or who are explicitly
exploiting your ignorance and and it's a
major factor in our culture,
a major factor when it comes to
politicians dry factor when it comes to
bosses,
it's a major factor when it comes to how
you choose what you do for a living,
human interaction and human interaction
with nature itself.
I mean we are constantly trying to
manipulate and control other people's
biases,
behaviors the way they think,
the way they act.
And we're very vulnerable in some senses
because this is not something that's
taught to us at an early age,
you know,
and I think that were,
it takes a long time to figure it out on
your own.
And I've often thought like,
man,
why wasn't I explained this when I was
young?
Yeah.
Because the curriculum was dee dee
wasn't thinking about that.
When we're thinking about just giving
people facts instead of teaching them
how to use this vessel into which you
pour information and nowhere and at no
time are we trained how to turn effect
into knowledge,
knowledge into wisdom and wisdom into
insight.
I think that full Sequence needs to be
in there,
in the academic system,
k through 12,
13 through 16,
13 point of view.
A college has got to be in there
somewhere.
Without it,
you're just this vessel effects.
Even if,
and even the people we call smart in
class,
these are people who get a's on
everything and they know everything,
but do they have the deepest insight?
Are they,
do they really understand what it is
that they're putting back on the test?
I don't think all of them do.
I think they have good short term
memory.
Some of them and they do well on the
exams because of that fact.
So they're good at acquiring data and
maintaining it,
acquiring information,
and then bringing it back on command.
Uh,
not all summer are deep thinkers and I
don't want to take that away from them.
All I'm saying is that the curriculum I
think needs these other dimensions of,
of survival really.
So that's what it is.
It's survival in a world.
And when a scientist says this is true,
you can ask,
well,
why do you think that's true?
Exercise some healthy skepticism.
I don't have a problem with that.
Say because of look at this evidence.
Do you know how to read evidenced by the
way?
And look at this evidence,
look at this chart,
look at this experiment,
and this is why we conclude
overwhelmingly that this is going to
happen in our future.
Uh,
I choose out of your pointy headed
scientists.
What are,
you know,
by the way,
give me my cell phone so I can call my
grandmother while I use gps satellites
to know when to make a left turn,
right?
I'm going to call my astrologist to tell
them these scientists don't know.
They got their head up their ass.
So,
so yeah.
Well,
I think also it'd be really beneficial
to teach people how to manage
perspective.
And how to look at,
look at life in a way that's gonna be
beneficial to you,
but we're not really give them the tools
to match the mind,
like philosophy,
a philosophy class,
but even philosophy not all flustered
because where the philosophy of law,
you know,
just how to think about decision making
and the causes and effects and
consequences.
Uh,
there's not enough of that either.
Maybe they're relying on that to happen
at home,
but not all homes are intact.
In fact,
perhaps most are broken homes or
separated homes.
And so I think the school system school
needs to be rethought.
And I'm trying to think that through a
few more years.
Well,
anytime you talk about alternative
schooling,
people look at you like you're some sort
of a hippie freak who wants your kids to
eat granola in the mountains and get
their own spring water.
You know what I mean?
That's what they think of when you say
alternative schooling.
Right,
right.
I'll train them at home,
man.
You good luck.
As soon as you say homeschooling.
Oh,
you're a religious nut.
I mean,
that's,
that's immediate perception.
Fastest growing sector of the homeschool
and center.
They don't want to cloud your head with
all that evolution talk.
Right?
Right,
right.
Do you ever talk to that ken ham guy?
Have you ever sat down with that guy?
No,
but bill nye has.
I mean booman.
I debated him.
I mean I can't debate people.
It's not what I do.
You just can't do it.
I just can't do it.
It's not what I do.
I'm an educator and I want to educate
you so you can think for yourself,
but then I go away.
That's it.
To debate someone implies that whoever,
whoever is most convincing is correct
and that's not how knowledge works.
So much charisma involved.
Whatever charisma level I have or not
have,
I don't want to hinge.
What is true on that fact?
Right?
Alright,
so I'm an educator.
I will.
I will teach you the causes and effects
of what science,
knowing what science is and how and why
it works,
which is why it's critical that you
continue to criticize science fiction
movies.
It's very important.
Don't you back off now?
We need you.
There's a lot of people that wouldn't
know that that chinese space station is
nowhere near the space station and that
to her hair would be moving all over the
place.
There would be everywhere,
but my favorite one is you remember when
he's at the end of the tether and she's
drawn to save him but she doesn't ever
have oxygen to do it,
so he lets go of the tether and that way
she can't save him before she can save
herself and and then he flies away.
It's like,
no,
they're like floating in space.
He lets go of the tether.
It just stays there in his hand.
He would be right there and it would be
right there.
Nothing.
He let's go.
Nothing happened.
Wouldn't be like a bungee cord.
Now if he,
if she was swinging him in circles and
he like,
oh yeah,
he fly off at a tangent but that's not
what was happening.
And nor were they rotating.
I would check the what they were
relative to earth below.
That waS not what was going on.
So then you don't.
She could just give it a slight tug and
then he would have drifted towards her.
That could have even been a little
romantic,
a little baby tub would do it and they
would slowly drift towards one of the
helmets would hit,
you know,
and then they went me mad.
Oh.
And then the helmets would break and
then there'd be freezing it instantly.
Right.
When you just suffocate that too.
And then freeze to death.
Right.
What movie nailed that?
That was one movie when space and they
overdid it a.
Well.
There was a.
People want you to like explode in
space.
No,
no.
I mean,
well,
you,
they want you to freeze solid to
instantly,
right?
No,
no,
there's.
And even in,
was it armageddon where the sun rose
over the,
over the comment,
and he didn't have his visor down and he
was blinded by the side.
It's like the same son in our daytime
sky.
The atmosphere doesn't protect you in
any way.
The earth's atmosphere takes out,
you know,
a few percent.
That's right.
Oh yeah.
A few percent of all in the middle
stage.
One daylight at the top of the sky to a
few percent.
Now he'll get more uv.
He'll get more uv.
That's important.
Get a little brown.
yeah.
But um,
Uh,
death in space is nowhere near as
spectacular as movies would have you
think?
Yeah,
they make it seem like if you take that
helmet off,
you just have immediately freeze up.
Yeah,
yeah.
no,
no.
I mean You can go into very.
What happens is there's nothing making
you cold other than you radiating heat
from your skin.
Oh.
So you only get as cold as quickly as
you can radiate away heat.
That's all.
So we take quite a while.
You just have no air.
So you'd suffocate quicker.
You'd suffocate.
Oh yeah.
You said okay.
Long before you saw anything,
uh,
anything like that happen.
So,
so just think about it.
There's nothing touching you that's
making you cold.
It has to wait for you to radiate away.
That's what's happening.
Okay.
And so that,
so yeah,
you will feel very cold very quickly,
but you're not going to die from that
fast.
Now when stephen hawking,
and by the way you also have dissolved
gases in your body which will try to
come in in the vacuum of space,
you don't have the air pressure tamping
down the dissolved gases,
so you take away the air pressure,
then the dissolved gases will begin to
bubble out of your blood and it's the
same problem with when you have the
benz.
Oh,
when you come up from low altitude and
you go to lesser pressure around your
employees and so you want to do that
slowly so that it's a very slow thing,
but the hazards of.
But why would you be button naked in
space?
I mean,
you going to have a space suit on,
so I just want to prove to everybody
that you could do it.
So I like.
Well,
they did it in 2001 a space odyssey.
They basically did it right.
The guy without his helmet went through
the airlock,
just held his breath.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
That's all he did.
That's way more reasonable.
Well,
because it was a reasonable movie.
That was a good movie that had real
advisor stanley kubrick.
Well,
he was a really interesting guy because
he was a mathematician,
stanley kubrick about it,
but I knew he cared about that level of
detail.
He used to do complex math and it's for
fun.
So there's a,
there's a,
there's a fail bit of physics and
[inaudible] one day I'll talk about my
gut.
So the model,
which was middle,
so remember when he's,
uh,
he's on one of the moon crafts and he's
orbIting the moon and they give him
food,
right?
and there's a tray of nasty food.
Obviously it's like astronaut food.
remember,
this is 1968.
So everything here is a,
is a visual,
uh,
the taste of the future.
So he has another packet where he
extends straw from that plastic packet.
Okay.
Oh,
there he is.
ExcelleNt.
You get in the good photo.
you're good.
You boys good?
Right here.
Okay.
Yeah,
there is.
So he sucks up the straw.
Right?
And this is in zero g,
so stuff is floating.
When he suck up the straw,
then he goes to another straw and the
liquid and the straw goes back down.
That's gravity.
Oh,
they fucked up.
Uh,
he totaLly fucking.
No,
no.
So that one,
obviously he can't get everything right,
but it's fun to notice the things he
couldn't get.
Right.
We didn't think to get right.
So to me it's a celebration.
Here's another one.
Okay.
The rotation rate of the space station.
I calculated that and I calculated what
g force would you have on the outer
perimeter of the space station in 2011.
And I did the math and I forgot the
exact number.
Something like between two and three
g's.
Oh.
And I said,
why would you do that?
That's stupid.
You wouldn't do that.
And I realized if they've rotated it at
the rate that we give you one,
gee,
it'd be way too slow to make an
interesting scene.
So I gave it to him.
So I'll give you three gs because the
strauss waltz,
as the thing turns and the space shuttle
that's approaching it matches its
rotation rate with the opening in the
center of the space station.
This whole bow lay this entire ballet.
Wow,
that's cool.
Again,
happens at a stately,
but real pace.
Okay.
But that pace gives him a three g,
three g's of gravity.
So it's three x the correct pace.
The correct pace may have been two and a
half,
but I forgot the number,
but it's,
it's multiples to high.
So good.
And so I let him do it.
It's so I'm not going to.
I'm that.
That's artistic license.
That's mark twain.
Ian licensed where he saYs first get
your facts straight,
then distort them at your leisure.
That is what I'm holding artists too.
So now when you're looking at a space
station,
like they're in zero gravity when
they're in the space station.
No,
they are in one g on the edge of the
space station.
On the edge.
On the turning edge.
Yeah,
that's what I mean.
That thing.
So I mean the issue thing.
Oh our space station.
Oh,
oh,
zero g now it's.
but it is possible zero g because it is
in free,
fall towards earth.
So it's constantly in free fall,
but it's just going around the freefall
earth.
But it's going sideways so fast that the
amount that it has fallen equals
precisely the spinner.
The curvature of the earth,
is that more proof of the earth is round
if you've had physics one o,
n yes,
but is it possible that the gravity and
the space station,
the only if you rotate it wrote tests,
not gravity.
It's a simple,
but according to einstein,
they're indistinguishable from one
another so you can do it.
So there it is possible to do something
where you can send people into deep
space and generate
gravity through some sort of rotation of
two,
at least two ways.
One of them you just rotate it and all
the good scifi movies have rotating
sections of a space station.
Right?
And some they have rotating opposite
ways so that they can spin up against
one another.
Right.
And uh,
so there's some clever ideas out there
with space stations of the future for
long voyages.
Were you bad commander hadfield on the
podcast came back from space and was
talking about the excruciating
difficulty he had readjusting to gravity
after being in a zero gravity
environment for so long.
he just showing off because he'd like
setting records for was.
It wasn't until like six months ago.
It was a long time.
he was.
Well,
he's showing.
Yeah,
I couldn't,
I couldn't handle life with you locally.
Earth people.
He was talking about his body like it
took like over a year before his bone
density came back.
And this is partly addressed in the
film.
The,
uh,
the,
the martian kid who's born on mars comes
to earth.
Which ones?
One on mars?
Yeah,
the kid born on mars.
Got to research this.
like now that was the name of the movie.
It's recent.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Oh,
that's the space between us now.
What the hell is that?
You got to get out more,
dude.
I do.
Yeah.
That's so,
so this is a martian colony.
The.
We're the first community.
Who's,
what movie is this?
This came out a couple months ago.
Really?
Oh my gosh.
Oh yeah.
Oh man.
I'm not on itunes.
You.
So that's the martian colony.
And one of the female astronauts,
they send that one there happens to be
or they learn is pregnant and they can't
bring her back.
And so she gives birth on mars to the
first person who,
uh,
was ever born on mars,
and then they,
then they keep it a secret and then he
comes back as a teenager that falls in
love.
See?
There's the fetus.
So.
So anyhow,
he has a hard time on earth because his
heart developed in martian gravity,
which is only 38 percent earth gravity.
Oh wow.
Man on earth.
He just couldn't do that to,
you know,
figure out what to do with them.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's on mars.
The kid was born on mars.
Okay.
Yeah.
Don't spoil.
Alert me jamming.
That's why.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
what were,
we were generating gravity.
One way to rotate it up.
Another way is if you're headed
somewhere,
I just have a huge fuel tank and just
always run your rockets.
Oh,
there's always a g force.
So if you sell or accelerate it,
one g right towards a destination,
then you will always have gravity and
you'll get there awesomely fast.
But you'd have to have so much fuel or
rely on something.
You filling stations en route,
this sort of thing end.
If you do this,
you,
you accelerate one g halfway there,
then you turn the space ship around,
then you decelerate at one g for the
other half of the trip so that when you
get there,
you're not whizzing past it in a by that
we have one g the whole trip.
That's how you would do that.
Wow.
So the momentum when you had precisely
halfway there at one g.
Oh my gosh.
You hit near the speed of light very
quickly.
Whoa.
Oh my god.
I forgot.
What is it in a.
I have to calculate it,
but it's,
it's the acceleration of earth's
gravity.
If you actually move that fast,
that's,
that's head snapping.
Now,
would they have to have some sort of a
crazy propulsion system in order to do
something along those lines?
How fast we're one g get you there?
Yeah.
So,
uh,
yes.
So wow.
When she would take a one year plus the
distance in light years approximates and
tory four point two light years for
example,
would take five point two years.
So the distance in light years plus a
year.
So that's,
that's,
that's.
So that gets you basically a 20,
25 percent the speed of light.
What happens if you just run into stuff
on the way like there's a lot of stuff
out there,
right?
Yeah.
So he's not a giant issue in getting to
mars is actually quite empty.
But if you do hit something that's the
end of everything.
So it's a low risk,
high consequence thing.
But you gotta you gotta put in play.
Now how much of a risk is the space junk
that we've left in the environments?
We were started freaking out the other
day about how many are up there.
He got.
So there's countless thousands of bits
of space junk from chips or paint that
fell off of just some bolts and nails
and retro rocket boosters.
Yeah,
it's all,
it's all up there.
And um,
and I'm wondering whether we haven't
been visited by aliens yet because they
saw the space junk orbiting earth and
said,
forget that I'm going to visit some
other planet and risk my life.
So short sighted approach to space
travel,
the nasa orbital debris office website,
you can actually see the debris that
nasa is tracking basic almost in real
time.
It's crazY.
They'll show it to you and it's like a
beehive around the earth.
So you got.
Yeah,
there it is.
Okay.
That's the debris around the earth.
That astra,
astra,
that nasa tracks and that's failed
japanese experiment to try to that outer
ring that you see,
that's the,
the altitude of geosynchronous
satellites and that,
that should be.
There should be a video of that,
uh,
despite.
Yeah,
go to the bottom right,
go to bottom,
right,
right there.
Click on that.
Play that video.
Not a video.
Why isn't that a video?
I'm sure there is a video somewhere.
There's a video on that site so you can
just see the movement of these pieces
and it's launch windows.
Have to know when to not hit stuff.
So,
so when you have lunch with,
it's not just,
is everything aligned,
right?
Is what we'll use successfully get past
the,
the debris.
And there was a japanese,
um,
they had an experiment to try to capture
it with nets.
It was a recent motion yet I so didn't
work out.
So the problem is the low orbit stuff
will eventually
fall in and burned up.
The high earth orbit stuff will never go
away.
There's nothing to destroy it.
And so they can't capture that stuff.
Well,
you need a very clever.
the of this stuff is moving 18,000
miles an hour.
So what's your net?
Just what are you doing?
That's so crazy.
Oh yeah.
Here you go.
The video go higher.
Rez on that.
Sure.
I know there's a higher risk.
God,
that's 10 80.
No,
it's not from nasa as youtube parents
from somebody else.
But that's the kind of.
So all of that.
That's debris that you're looking at
there.
So anyway.
Yeah.
So you're concerned for debris as well
placed and we may,
we may be putting so much debris in
space that we will close ourselves off
from space travel because of the dangers
it would take to get through our own
garbage heap.
that's so crazy.
And this was all started in the 19
forties,
19 fifties.
When did they start shooting stuff up
there?
Oh no.
NineTeen fifties.
Sputnik.
Yeah.
Nineteen 57.
That was the first satellite,
right?
First anything.
Yeah.
Anything in orbit.
God and in that short amount of time.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
It's like,
it's like a dumpster.
Sixty years.
Planetary don't ruin the whole thing.
They had it for billions of years.
Sixty years.
They filled it up with junk.
Yup.
oh my god.
That's terrifying.
Yeah.
That's going around the earth.
Oh my god.
And has anybody ever hit anything while
trying to do something?
Uh,
well.
So,
uh,
what exacerbates it is,
remember when China,
when was this?
Nineteen or 2004.
Two hundred and three.
China destroyed one of its own
satellites.
Orbit.
I remember some of them.
Yeah.
And they basically did a Connecticut
kill on a satellite.
So Connecticut bill for those don't
know,
is you don't need explosives if the
speed of the projectile and its kinetic
energy is higher than the energy that
would be in the explosive shell itself.
Oh.
So fascInating.
A calculation to make so,
so here it is,
so I have this delivery system with a
warhead and I put some balm device in
the warhead and you can calculate how
much energy that is.
Then I send it and it hits and it blow
something up.
But suppose I send this thing really,
really fast.
Really,
really,
really fast.
I can calculate how much kinetic energy
this thing has the will be a point where
I give it so much kinetic energy.
The kinetic energy is greater than the
chemical energy of the conventional
explosive that I put in the warhead.
A shoemaker levy.
Well,
well,
for example,
I gave you a terrestrial example.
Um,
it's.
So it's what we call a high speed
collision.
This is more than you bargained for in
this,
in our time together,
but I will tell you now.
Okay.
You ready?
Perfect.
The argument for the longest time that
the craters on the moon work calderas
from volcanoes and not asteroid impacts.
The geologists argue strenuously.
These can't be asteroid impacts.
They've got to be calderas these
thousand craters on the moon.
Who?
Why?
Because everyone is a perfect circle.
And if asteroids are coming from space,
they would come from all angles and if
you come in at a shallow angle,
you get an oval and even shallower it'd
be more oval.
So you'd have a whole range of circles
and ovals and ellipses.
And if you don't see that,
they must be calderas law was not
caldera,
volcanic volcanic crater,
volcanic crater.
That's all.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's a volcanic crater.
That's all.
Um,
and it's just a little more poetic at
caldera,
but it's a,
it's a crater left by a volcano that has
exploded,
like the boom was so big,
the mountains gone and now it's just a
big hole.
Or at the top of the mountain,
there's a crater at the top of the
mountain,
like crater lake,
that's a,
that's a round hole in the top of a
mountain.
Um,
was that once a volcano?
I don't know,
but it's a whole.
Okay.
So in the 19 seventies we were able to
do calculations with high speed
computers with good computers.
and what we found was if the object is
moving faster,
if the kinetic energy of the object is
higher than the energy that's holding
the thing together,
oh,
okay.
So what's holding together a rock,
the chemical connections of the silicon
and the oxygen and I,
everything that they ironed,
all everything that's making the rock is
holding it together.
You can calculate how much energy is
holding it together,
and if it's going 45,000
miles,
right?
That write down that number.
Now I send in the asteroid with a
kinetic energy higher than the energy
that's holding it together on impact.
It explodes because all that energy goes
back into the rock because the thing is
in moving anymore.
We did the Connecticut treat energy go.
It digs a crater,
number one,
by virtue of putting all that energy
back into the stone and that explodes
it.
So on impact,
even at an angle,
it is a singular point explosion.
And that's why every single crater is a
perfect circle.
we call that a high speed impact,
where the speed is greater,
the energy of the speed is greater than
the energy that's holding it together.
That's amazing.
Now you have experience in this.
Okay?
Have you ever thrown a do this next?
Oh,
you were in California.
Sorry.
Snowballs.
Take us know.
Put a big bear.
They have taken,
snowball it face.
What's a barn wall?
And throw the snowball at it and it'll.
It'll make a little circular mark on it.
Now change your angle to the wall and
throw the snowball again.
It'll still make a small round mark and
it'll keep doing it.
You know why?
Because the speed with which you through
the snowball,
that energy is greater than the energy
that's holding the snowball together.
Because hardly energy.
Hardly any energy is holding the
snowball together.
It's just loosely packed snow.
So when you do it against the wall,
you see the snowball completely
disappear in a,
in a mini snowball explosion,
if you will.
ah,
so this works for any comparison,
a projectile speed and what we call the
binding energy.
The object itself.
This is why the intercontinental
ballistic missiles never carried
conventional warheads because their
speed coming out of this of space
because they leave the atmosphere,
go from one continent to the other,
and then they fall out of the sky.
That speed gives them more kiNetic
energy than any conventional warheads
would've had.
Whoa,
but then we figured out how to make
small nuclear warheads.
the nukes.
Now you're talking energy.
The kinetic energy of the icbm is not
higher than the nuclear warhead that we
now put,
and that's why all icbm or nukes,
wow.
the v two rocket basically didn't need
an explosive warhead in its tip,
became out of the sky going five miles
per second.
There was none of this that that
implies.
You're hearing the thing,
dude is coming and supersonically.
You're sitting there at a cocktail table
on a block and then the block has gone,
is obliterated in the next incident.
You didn't even know.
You didn't even know to look up.
Wow.
So that's the add an explosive anyway,
but they.
They probably didn't need to.
Now go back to a shoemaker levy.
That was a comment that slammed into
jupiter and jupiter is a gas giant.
I've always been confused as to what
that means.
Oh,
most of its mass is in the form of gas.
Most of it's.
Oh yeah.
Ninety something percent of.
So when shoemaker levy slammed into
jupiter and going so fast,
the gaseous atmosphere was like hitting
a brick wall.
Whoa.
That's how fast it was moving.
So that's why the explosion was exactly.
So it's slow.
All of its kinetic energy that it had
got put back into the object itself
because it's slow down very quickly
relative to its speed relative to the a.
So.
So here's this comment,
I forgot how big shoemaker levy was.
So now it goes into the atmosphere and
you say,
oh,
isn't that just clouds?
And it can watch how fast it's going.
You can,
you can ask the question over how much
distance will it plow through its own
mass worth of gas?
That's it.
That's the question,
right?
That's,
that has to plow that much mass out of
the way.
That's an important resistive force,
right?
So how much atmosphere?
Well,
it's a lot of atmosphere because it's
gas and this thing is solid.
However,
the thing is going,
what?
15,
20 miles per second.
It's falling into jupiter at $20.
Whatever the speed was.
If you go at 20 miles per second,
you will cover that much atmosphere in a
fraction of a second,
so at a fraction of a second you go from
20 miles per second to zero or to a tiny
fraction of that speed.
All that energy has to go somewhere.
It goes back into the system.
It's a comment made of ice.
Ice is not held together very easily.
The whole thing explodes on impact.
That was another terrifying statistic
that I read about the impact that hit
the yucatan and killed the dinosaurs.
That how deep it had gone into the
earth's surface within the first second.
Oh,
oh yeah.
These are.
These are numbers that are staggering.
Once you calculate what they are,
and likE I said,
if you come in fast enough,
earth's atmosphere is a brick.
Might as well be a brick wall to you,
and by the way,
you go 60 miles an hour down the road,
rolled down the window.
Just stick your hand out the window.
You have to use muscle energy to not
have your and your hand blown backwards
against 60 miles and hour of air against
your open palm.
Just try that next time.
See what kind of energy that requires.
and that's 60 miles an hour.
Now imagine five miles per second.
10 moles per second.
Twenty miles per second.
You're toast.
How deep did the asteroid that hit and
killed the dinosaurs?
How deep did that thing going over?
so what was that?
That was a 150 mile diameter crater or
something like that.
I forgot the exact numbers.
Uh,
so there's,
uh,
there's a relationship between the depth
of a crater and the diameter and the
mass.
So the thing.
so no,
it goes miles down.
I mean,
it's,
it's miles.
Oh yeah.
oh yeah.
Well,
let me think.
An earth rang for like a million years.
What happens is,
let me pull,
take that back.
I don't know if it's miles.
It's,
um,
I think it was what I had read.
I don't remember the exact statistic.
Well,
excuse me.
no,
it's gotta go miles that because the
thing is miles is the,
the,
the asteroid itself was the size of
mount everest.
So the extra associates like five miles
across.
So it's,
it's deep.
No,
you just don't mess with this.
By the way.
The crater in Arizona called meteor
crater for obvious reasons that can sink
a 60 story building and it's not even a
mile across.
And now we're talking about a crater
more than a hundred miles across that
took out the dinosaurs,
that famous one in Arizona,
Arizona,
a 60 story building.
You,
if you,
if you put dirt up to the rim of the
crater,
you can bury a 60 story building.
Had an instance where you,
this is your whole calculation about
explosions and about the amount of that
they were looking for,
the raw materials that caused that
crater.
Correct.
Dot that they could mine it,
correct.
They first thought is volcanic and the
geologists thought it was volcanic
again.
And the but one geologist in particular,
um,
eugene shoemaker who was in line to be
on one of the lunar missions and then he
had like a heart murmur and then they
sent a check,
schmidt to in his stead who's also
geologists turned us senator from
Arizona.
Where was he senator from?
I forgot.
Uh,
but,
uh,
can you look at a Jack Schmidt where he
was senator from.
Forgive me for forgetting [inaudible].
I knew I'm friends with him,
so I should known that.
Nasa,
jack schmitt,
s,
c,
h,
m,
I t,
t is not,
there's no dna.
Uh,
so,
uh,
but tesco.
yeah.
So it's right.
So in New Mexico I said Arizona,
New Mexico.
So he,
um,
uh,
but anyhow,
he say,
no,
this is,
this is an impact crater.
And well,
if it's an impact crater,
where is the media?
Right?
It must be buried down here.
And so there were miners.
They were there were there iron miners
who bought the land so they can get this
huge media that they were sure which is
sitting down there that they could mind
for its natural resource.
They could not find the meteor.
Uh,
that's because it hit at high speed
velocity.
It was a high velocity impact,
which means it's collision energy was
greater than the binding energy even of
the iron atoms itself.
And 90 percent of that thing vaporized
on impact.
Wow.
No iron.
More impressive even than I remember.
Okay.
The pieces.
That's nice.
Low angle shot.
So you get the shadows of the rim.
And that's an Arizona.
We're in Arizona near winslow,
Arizona.
Where would that be near?
Is that like if someone wanted to fly in
to see that?
Oh,
here it is.
If you go to the grand canyon then you
drive to this and it's a couple of
hours,
two hours.
Okay.
There's me.
Your map was coming up.
And where's the grand canyon?
There's meteor crater
and grand canyon because it,
which is also an Arizona.
Kenny has to park.
You can drive that.
See that grand canyon to credit through
flagstaff.
Yeah.
So you're not going to fly that.
You'd just drive it and yelp reviews to
look at that highlighted.
It's got five star reviews.
Why does it have all the stars?
Look,
I know it should have every goddamn
star,
every three point nine people are so
picky.
It's not that big a deal.
I could dig a little bit better myself.
Oh,
by the way,
so this whole was this,
this meteor crater was doug and like,
you know,
a few seconds this crater was made and
how many years ago was that?
Fifty thousand years ago.
that's not proximately nothing.
So there's probably
some form of humaN living here then.
oh yeah,
yeah.
Early humans.
I don't know if they were in north
America.
Yeah,
I say $40,000.
The most recent.
Right when they crossed the bering
strait,
that's when they would adjust a ryan
knutson.
Oh,
that's cool.
I'm going back to that multiple times.
oh yeah.
Is it freaky?
Freaky about it is you walk up to it,
you can't see it because the rim of the
crater,
it just looks like a ridge original
line.
Uh,
the rim is raised above the plane of the
area,
right?
Because when you press down it raises it
up a bit.
So you just walk up to it and then you
come up to the ledge and then you
realize what it is,
is nearly a mile diameter hole in the
ground.
Oh yeah.
It's a stunning,
stunning encounter with the forces of
nature and the fact that there's so many
of those particles just floating around
out there.
that's.
How big was that when you think?
Oh yeah,
that was a bow.
Uh,
um,
uh,
about 20 yards across something.
That's nothing.
Twenty yards.
Yeah.
It may be between 20 and 40 yards.
Twenty yards is the size of.
That's right from that garage to that
front door.
No.
Make that kind of circle yards.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Right.
That's not the end.
That's the kind of thing they can get
close enough that you don't even see and
then it's too late.
That's not gonna make us extinct.
but it will make a very bad day for a
city.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well,
yeah.
City's done and most likely the power
grids jack for a long time to right now
the detail now you have 10 more minutes.
So I had to get the stePhen hawkings
quote out for you.
I'm stephen hawkings was talking about
the,
um,
the possIbility of alien life
discovering us and that it would be a
terrible,
terrible thing if it did happen.
If you look at what has happened to
other primitive lifeforms and we
discovered them apparently have cultures
and we have discovered them.
Do you share that same opinion that if
something did find us a.
I don't have a strong opinion on that
question,
but I have an analysis of his comment.
Okay.
He is worried about the possibility of
aliens enslaving us.
Oh,
based on the reality that we've done
that to ourselves.
Yes.
Just think about that.
His fear of aliens derived not from
actual knowledge of aliens,
but from an actual knowledge of
ourselves.
AnytIme a more advanced civilization is
copano,
let's,
if it technologically advanced civil,
it did not bode well for the less
advanced civilization.
And that happened in north America,
south America,
north
America with,
with european,
south american,
spanish,
uh,
um,
Australia,
with the,
with the brits never boded well for the
less technologically advanced
civilization.
His factual knowledge of that leads him
to suspect that aliens would be exactly
the same,
and I,
I'm not that skeptical.
I don't think all life forms in the
universe have the basil,
primal,
violent attitudes that we do as a
species have not been given reason to
think so,
but don't you believe that things
advanced because of competition and
competition forces things to be fairly
ruthless.
It has been argued that if you colonize,
if you a civilization that colonizes the
galaxy,
that it's a self limiting exercise.
Why?
Because here you've got you ready?
We start here on earth is you and me,
boy.
All right,
and you take that plan.
I take this pLanet and now we have both
have offspring that are just like us and
we want more planets.
Alright?
We reach a point where expansion is not
possible because we are worrying with
ourselves to gain the territory that
each other has obtained.
So it has been argued sociologically
that the very act of wanting to colonize
is self limiting against successful
colonization of the galaxy.
Because to colonize the galaxy,
it has to be done in an organized way.
All right,
you take this sector,
I take this sector,
but if I want territory and I want it
now and my kids want it now I want that
territory,
not this other one.
In fact,
I want it all.
That kind of attitude breeds violence.
It breeds war,
intergalactic war,
so it may be that the very kind of
civilization that could peacefully
colonize a galaxy is not the kind of
civilization that would colonize the
galaxy at all.
Well,
that's heavy.
Very heavy.
What about the idea that.
That's my first comment about steven.
One he's got,
he made another comment about we should
be a multiplanetary species and check
ourselves against an asteroid rendering
one extinct.
It makes a good headline and it sounds
like it makes sense,
but I'm not.
I'm not there with it yet.
Of course I want a backup.
Of course.
Let's be a multi planet species.
Fine,
but.
But I,
I would do it for different reasons.
I would do because it's cool.
Not because we want to protect human,
the human species from extinction.
No,
that wouldn't be the reason to do it.
Can I tell you why?
Please list every reason why you think
we go extinct.
One,
we trash earth another and we can't live
off of it anymore.
An asteroid is coming through.
Some nanobots gone astray.
Okay?
Pandemic virus,
pandemics.
Okay,
so it seems to me that if I want to be a
multiplanetary species,
mars would be the one because it's a 24
hour day.
it's got seasons we would have to
terraform at first,
but then we all moved there.
Who to ship a billion people there.
HeRe's my.
Here's my point.
Would every takes to terraform mars and
ship a billion people there.
It's got to be easier to deflect the
asteroid,
whatever it takes to terraform mars to
turn it into earth.
If you had the power of geoengineering
to do that,
then you have the power geoengineering
to turn earth back into earth.
But there are occasionally,
uh,
things that we miss,
right?
Because of the way that.
So,
so,
so you say,
okay,
whatever it takes to geo engineer mars
and ship a billion people there,
it's got to be easier to create a
perfect viral serum that makes us immune
to all possible disease.
It's got to be easier,
whatever that takes,
but isn't it possible that there some
asteroids that we just will not see
until it's too late?
Then you put up with whatever that
takes.
I mean,
whatever,
but their time about being labels ship a
billion people there.
A bill w why?
Of course,
why wouldn't it be?
We have said,
what do you put 10 people there?
What?
You want to split your species,
right?
Okay,
and if an asteroid is coming that you
can't deflect,
which would surprise me if you could
ship a billion people.
TomorroW's you just let them all die.
What is that?
What you plan to you to let all the
earth people die in the mars people.
Sarah,
just so you can save this.
Don't save everybody.
I'm not buying into the premise this
cable car ology premise that you have to
save one to not save the other and you
know,
cable cardiology,
youth.
I see what you see.
The cable car,
you know someone's in the tracks,
you let them go,
you let them go.
You've,
you've steered out of the way,
but then you actively kill two people
instead of passively killing one person.
What do you do?
I'm not buying into that premise for
this question.
I'm Simply saying that whatever it
takes,
it's got to be easier to put up some
kind of net that finds any asteroid that
could possibly harm us and zaps them out
of the sky has got to be easy.
As the last question is,
is it possible that the reason why we
are never visited by extraterrestrials
is because the way civilization,
the space debris one,
is it because the physicians they have
visited,
they visited during comicon,
like cosplay costumes weren't as good as
ours.
Three,
three,
they've observed us and judged there no
sign of intelligent
life on earth.
Okay,
but is there another possibility that
civilizations don't ever get to travel
like that?
Because what happens is as they advance
and as our technology advances,
they become,
instead of a biological entity seeking
to spread its genetics throughout the
universe,
they become some sort of symbiotic
artificial life that as they create,
as they advanced their technology and as
they continued to innovate,
they reach a limitation in biology and
that eventually create artificial life
that sees no desire whatsoever to
travel.
Oh,
interesting.
So I would say that's a great
philosophical question.
I would say that the day we create ai,
if the ai is everything we are except
more or not emotional,
then I have an urge to explore.
maybe otherwise wouldn't have create
those doors like in monsters inc and
start going dimension to dementia
instead of fucking around with jetson.
Yeah.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah.
They figured out the fourth dimension.
Wouldn't that be the best way to do
things?
And then they figure it out and then
they would figure out a way to travel
better than any way we could.
But if the fact that we want to travel
and we creating versions of ourselves
called ai,
why would it be?
I wouldn't want to travel,
but why would it be curious if ai fit is
us this logical,
then it's not?
Well,
if we create every neurosynaptic ma map
right,
of our brain into silicon,
into a computer and recreate our
consciousness as humans,
the human brain,
but wouldn't the human brain version of
ai would there be like an infinite
version of ai that ai could create
itself?
Because why would it limit itself to all
of our emotions and sexual desires and
jealousy and all the ridiculous things
that are holding us back?
It could.
sure,
sure.
Now I'm not as fearsome of ai as others
are.
Uh,
I,
you know,
we,
we're not going to make an ai looking
human being because the human form is
not the best or ideal forum for
anything.
Did you see x makena?
Yes.
I love it because you love.
It is good.
It was good.
That's good moments that he didn't love
it.
No,
it was good.
I loved it.
I want to marry it.
Do you want to marry it?
Oh,
okay.
Well that's the first thing you bought.
It's not even that.
That's where the money for sure,
for sure.
Yeah,
But I'm just saying it's one of my
favorite movies.
I want to marry the movie.
It was just awesome movie.
So then marriage would no longer be
about sex or just to be about
reproduction because you just go to your
room with your sexual.
I'm hoping that that's one of the first
things that people figured out they
shouldn't do anymore.
What else?
They get smart enough to symbiotically
attach themselves to.
Artificial intelligence was watching.
What was it?
Family feud.
One of the questions was,
uh,
if you're.
We asked 100 married women,
if you could have a second husband for
only one purpose,
what would it be?
Something like 70 percent of them said
just for sex.
Whoa.
Damn.
Second husband for only one purpose.
Just just for getting stuffed.
Just just said.
That's a fucking wake up call for a lot
of guns out there guys.
Let's end on that.
Neil degrasse tyson.
Astrophysics for people in a hurry.
But thank you so much sir.
You're a gentleman and a scholar of you,
man.
I love you too,
brother.
Thank you so much for coming here and
thank you anytime.
Open invitation middle of the night,
and come down here.
We'll open it up and you got to wake him
up.
He'll do it.
He's down.
He loves you too.
all right.
Thank you sir.
Appreciate it.
[inaudible].