Let's go live,
Doo Doo,
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo man on fire.
Ladies.
Gentleman available right now on
Netflix.
Pause this podcast and go watch to even
better.
Enjoy comedic stylings of crystally.
Somebody.
What's up,
man?
Dude,
your shit is out right now.
It's actually done so happy.
I'm doing this and we're going to talk
for a few hours because I can't stop
checking my fucking phone on twitter.
Like an asshole.
I know,
I know it.
I,
I think I think,
oh,
I won't do it.
And then I'll be like,
don't do it.
Don't do it.
And as I'm doing it,
I'm thinking I better not be doing it.
And I'm like,
I'm doing it fucking right now.
You got to have other activities.
No,
I know I work out,
but then and then I,
I,
I do stand up and I know it's a problem.
It's a problem.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Well you're,
you're very dedicated to it.
You love it.
And when you love it,
you think about it a lot.
When you think about a lot,
and little.
Let me check twitter.
I know it's also such a safety kind of
just move that you,
you,
I mean we talked about this before.
It's just like fucking you put up,
put your phone down for a day.
So I'm,
you know,
what I've been doing lately that has
been more productive when I know I can't
give in to go over my notes.
That's good.
What I find man,
I find that like what I'm,
what I'm doing is just distracting my I,
I was talking about this on my podcast,
man.
I used to,
I used to think I used to just spend
time thinking like just spend time in my
house or apartment,
just thinking about things.
I don't do that as much anymore because
I just think what's,
what did this fucking guy stay on
twitter?
It robs you of your creativity.
So it's like,
I mean it's hard to be prolific when
you're just looking at your phone and it
does something to you when you just get
mindless tweets and you're still looking
at them.
It's just,
it's like a numbing agent.
Yeah,
it's weird.
It's not.
I mean,
because what are you going to see?
Somebody likes your special.
Okay,
good.
Well,
I do follow a lot of cool people that
will post up some cool shit and some
articles and shit.
When people send me those,
I try to retreat the ones that I think
are interesting.
So there's a benefit to it there.
But sure.
The real you get lost.
Like checking how people like things
that show.
Was that a good channel Sharon?
My tire now.
I know.
Yeah.
But you're right.
Like your time is better spent trying to
do more stuff,
do more comedy,
but it's a thief of your time really is
really.
Is,
is it really is designed for them?
No,
I,
you know,
I don't know.
I don't know what to do.
I ever see a person who's got epilepsy
where they can't watch one of those
animated Gif files.
I had a buddy of mine and I thought he
was joking.
I didn't know was being honest.
I had this message board and on my
website,
a message board.
Someone made me like this really flashy
image for the face where it's like it
turns on and off.
You know,
pulsates if an my friend's wife has
epilepsy and he's like,
dude,
you got to take that down because of my
wife looks at it.
She'll have a seizure.
Whoa.
Like a
Jeff?
Yeah,
like an animated Gif or Jif or Gif or
Jif.
I don't know.
I had a big debate,
jeff slash Gif,
but he can't.
She can't even look at it.
Looks at it.
She will go into an epileptic seizure.
Well,
how do you police that?
You just don't look online ever.
I guess they have to be real careful of
like what she sees.
I guess like maybe if she turns away
real quick,
maybe she'd be okay.
I don't.
I really don't know how it works.
Maybe she has to wear special glasses
when she looks at a online,
so I don't know what's like.
Could you imagine you've got some sort
of a weird misfire were just lights will
make your body shut off.
It's like someone hacked your brain.
He could shut it off with some light,
some flashing shit.
That's like some.
Yeah,
that's like the superheroes weakness
where you're like,
well,
get with flashing lights,
crypto new.
Right.
Because Kryptonite doesn't even work on
us.
No,
it doesn't do shit.
I'm such a pussy.
I ain't no.
And in one of the superman movies,
they didn't even have Kryptonite in the
one in the one superman movie was.
But before the one before it superman or
Batman,
I saw it and the bad guy didn't even use
Kryptonite.
So you couldn't destroy Superman.
So is this what the fuck is this movie?
Even a movie because people are stupider
now.
They had to tone it down to like back in
the Christopher Reeve days,
you need to have like an antagonist and
protagonist.
He didn't have a lot of people today
like,
Oh,
don't want super cute.
Because then there'll be some sort of
group that finds it offensive.
Oh,
that's true too,
right?
Yeah.
So these flashing things,
when I found out about it that flashing
animated files and then I found out
there was a television show in Japan
that they had to take off the air.
No,
because all these people were watching
it and having seizures in Japan.
Yes.
I feel like every show in Japan is
flashing lights.
I feel like they have a show called
They have the flush with athlete network
and they're just can't.
I mean,
isn't it every every clip I've ever seen
in Japan is like pink and blue and like
what if all they saw us as fear factor.
That's probably what they would choose
to watch,
but maybe they have some cool shit over
there,
but we're only seeing,
you know,
like when,
how many donkey Dick Kenya smiles.
True what,
what is this?
And poking a band pokemon episode that
gave children's seizures.
I mean I thought the whole point was of
Pokemon was to give people seizures.
My God,
700 children were on their way to the
hospital.
After watching that,
30 minutes after the show,
700 children went to the hospital for
seizures.
Is that what it's really saying?
That's incredible.
Could you imagine a room of 700 people?
It's like you're killing,
right?
If you have a stage.
Oh yeah.
If you had a stage.
I always think of it in terms of that
dude,
I always think of how many people in
terms of like how big of a room with
that Phil as a standup to say I got
already should fear to feel really good
about his twitter following back when he
only had 2000.
I go,
dude,
you have a fucking sold out theater.
Totally.
He was like,
yeah,
you got to sold out theater.
People are paying attention to you.
I was like,
yeah,
well what am I do?
I go,
yeah.
You say,
well,
you're looking at Britney spears.
She can't do that man.
Fuck your head up.
She has $100 million.
Right?
But uh,
yeah,
there's something about that is crazy
man.
700 people having a seizure in front of
you.
Imagine if you are on stage and the
whole audience just seizures.
I would just be like,
Whoa,
I'm next level band from New York
seizure and people,
we should have taped this one too to
Leanne's this pit.
He strips down to his underwear.
It's underwear,
a bright silver and started doing
cartwheels and people seizure.
I've never seen anything like it.
Yeah,
that'd be a hell of a claim.
Well,
you could probably pull something like
that off.
I wonder if you could make someone
seizure with comedy.
You would have to imagine if you have
like some sort of back screen on your
punchline,
your punchline,
you rip your track suit off like one of
those velcro things.
Those basketball players have terrible
and they pull their tear away.
Yeah.
And underneath it you have strobing
lights on the punchline.
The punchline.
I said,
yeah,
there is.
And just everyone with epilepsy just
falls to the ground.
I wonder if it would be silent though.
I like to hear the noise whenever we
would certainly hear thoughts.
Imagine that a group thought that
crosses across the city here the fuck
was.
That would be 700 people falling down
their heads.
I'm terrible for you.
Definitely don't want to flesh that out,
but I don't like,
you know,
flashing lights anywhere.
There's flashing lights.
I'm not epileptic anywhere.
I tend to avoid that place.
Yeah.
I wonder what that's doing to you.
We May.
Maybe if it's a person like you or
doesn't have epilepsy,
maybe it's just a certain amount of
time.
Maybe you could only endure a certain
amount.
I would think so.
Right?
Because when they torture you seen those
videos and shit.
Where do they like,
I mean not torture videos but like re
reenactments or like things in movies
where they're flashing lights and
torturing the guy.
That's part of it,
right?
The senses.
Sensory deprivation,
the water,
Chinese water torture.
Every would just little drips drips.
Yeah.
Have you read that Jon Ronson Book?
Men who stare at goats?
Yes.
You've had them on here,
right?
I have.
That book is crazy.
How they would torture people by playing
like hip hop music or whatever the fuck
it was.
There's been a well with Panama.
What the fuck is that guy?
Manuel Noriega what they.
I think they used to play death metal.
I think they used to pay them.
They like that kind of shit,
but I get that because if I'm in
anywhere and then that happens.
I leave.
I think they played uptown girl too from
Billy Joel and I'm not kidding.
Really.
I think that was one of the things they
did.
They played uptown curl and bring beer
song too.
I think that's a bad pr.
Good pr for them.
One side.
Good.
One time you hear that song,
you're like,
oh,
I remember this song is good.
I have a theory about that song.
What billy Joel is an incredibly
talented musician,
but not the best looking guy in the
world.
Can we agree on that?
Oh yeah.
Yeah,
of course.
Sure.
Right.
He's.
I'm Josh Duhamel.
Yeah,
right.
Who is another one that's like perfect
to mount a Chris Pine.
Chris Pine.
Yeah.
He's a good looking guy.
There is a good one.
And Chris Pratt.
There's another one,
but he's a good looking guy.
Yeah.
Great looking guys.
You just Elba.
Perfect.
You added a little diversity.
I want it to go a little too.
Good.
Mood enhancer.
Bastard.
Billy Joel is an average looking fella
and then he hooked up with arguably one
of the hottest woman that stuff.
Christie Brinkley.
Yeah,
and that just fucked him up.
What do you mean?
Oh yeah.
That's where it is.
He was chilling.
Love.
He wanted to tell everybody this story.
Uptown girl,
he's downtown guy,
he says he wants to think of themselves
as like this rugged,
attractive,
rebel bad boy motorcycle and she's this
perfect featured supermodel with him.
Impossibly valuable eggs.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Rectal couldn't handle it,
but.
But he got even bigger after that.
That doesn't matter.
I,
I hear what you're saying and she was so
hot,
but he's not.
She's still hot.
She's like 17.
My favorite is her in the Chuck Norris.
What do you call it?
Total gym.
Oh,
that's right.
When they would do the little dude,
I,
I would watch that info.
I love infomercials.
I watched them late at night and that
was my favorite infomercial and then
they remade it.
Oh yeah.
And I didn't like it as much as the
original.
That's how much I watch because the
original was so good because Chuck
Norris was like,
let's just fucking get through this.
And Christie Brinkley was doing it
really well,
but it was just so funny to see Chuck
Norris has faced during that and then
read did it and he figured it out.
He figured out how to do a little better
and I didn't like that dude.
I met Chuck Norris.
I met him a couple times.
This was the proudest moment in my life
and Chuck Norris knew who I was.
Oh Wow.
For Real.
For real meat.
And Chuck Norris,
he comes and gives you a big hug.
I was like,
Holy Shit.
Chuck Norris from just the UFC.
I'm sure you know,
this was not that long ago.
No.
Oh Wow.
My first met him,
I think maybe it was 10 years ago.
Wow.
Okay.
And then I met him again,
I think about two years ago.
I met him again.
That's funny.
I wish I was thinking about guys like
that that were like big that got big off
of martial arts in the eighties and
nineties and then the UFC came along and
like kind of made those martial arts,
you know,
fighting sense,
obsolete,
right.
You know,
like if they would be that.
I guess that's not gonna happen anymore
really.
I mean,
I don't know.
It is know what you're saying,
but like Kung Fu movies are obviously
more beautiful than a.
what's that movie that Calvin did?
The play.
Don,
what was that?
Yeah.
Well,
the thing about Chuck Norris though is
that he stayed current.
Chuck Norris is a black belt in
Brazilian Jujitsu.
Oh,
he is?
Yeah.
He's legit under the Machados and on top
of that he was a world champion.
Kickboxer,
right?
Yeah.
It was like he could grapple at a very
high level and he can.
Oh,
I was a world champion striker.
Chuck Norris has a bout as legit as any
like movie character,
tough guy about as legit as they've ever
been.
Especially a guy who went on to do all
these great movies like Bruce Lee was a
phenomenal martial artists in a
brilliant guy in terms of how we put
things together.
But as far as like actual competition,
Chuck Norris is the man.
I mean he was.
He was the guy.
Like when I was a kid,
dude like Chuck Norris movies of the
reason why I got into martial arts
really too.
He was huge and jeans on with a special
crotch jeans.
They had a special crotch cutting the
jeans so I can fucking side and cowboy
boots on.
I saw the,
I found out about action jeans a late in
life and I was like,
that was a fucking thing,
dude.
I W I basically wear them.
I mean w what I wear now is more
ridiculous than Chuck Norris is actually
tells.
The Times have changed.
I mean I have jogged genes which is like
fucking.
They're strengths what I'm talking
about.
Yeah.
That's what I'm wearing to.
It didn't sound much more comfortable.
Way more comfortable.
Yeah.
These were bullshit.
Like when you had a stroke,
kick blind your legs.
When we would get pants,
if I got pants,
I always got pants that were too big for
me just so I can kick people.
Oh,
a quarter.
Make people just in case it never
happened.
Never happened.
Ever.
My,
my buddy,
when I was,
when I used to train,
you know,
I trained when I was like 20 to 26 and
my buddy was like,
why do you do that?
And I was like,
I don't know,
just to like protect myself.
He was like,
yeah,
but what's happening to you?
And I was like,
well,
you never know.
And he said,
yeah you do.
And I was like,
yeah,
you're kind of fucking right man.
Most of the time you do.
He's kind of writing in these.
Definitely not right all the time
because obviously people get fucked up
all the time of course,
but he was like,
you kind of know where you're always
going to be and it's going to be fine
and it Kinda time.
Most of the time I know you just meet
General.
Obviously you never know what's going to
happen,
but.
But he's right in the sense that you put
so much effort into self defense and it
almost never comes up.
Right?
Right.
Like eating like,
wow,
your whole life is preparing for
something that never took place.
And then you get to a point where if
you're known for it,
like you,
like nobody's gonna fuck with you.
So it's like den,
it's definitely never going to have
true.
No,
you're right.
You probably got fucking assholes that
want to fuck with chocolate Dell.
That's so great.
That's so insane to me.
Yeah,
I mean chocolate,
Dell,
if you ever look in his eyes,
he,
the eyes of a leopard seal,
like you look in his eyes fucking
straight up like anybody who talks shit.
And by the way,
Super Nice Guy,
like,
don't get me wrong if you met him on the
street,
he's the nicest guy.
He's super friendly.
Saw his thing with,
uh,
like undisputed or whatever the hell
that show's called with A.
Yeah,
you seem like a nice guy.
Anyway,
dude,
I was at a club with chocolate though,
way back in the day when chuck was the
UFC light heavyweight champ and some guy
said something to one of his friends and
it was like some douche moment who knows
what was going on.
Just a bunch of silly pizza,
you know.
And um,
his buddies,
everybody's meatheads meatheads on both
sides.
This guy came over and said something
and Chuck Odell stood up,
turned around and looked at him and this
guy looked like he saw a fucking ghost.
He looked into chuck's eyes.
There's like a,
there's a,
there's a type of dude that you don't
start fights with,
right?
Yeah.
But meanwhile still people fuck with
them.
To this day,
people fuck with that.
I guess it's kind of the equivalent as
somebody going up to a comedian thinking
that they're funny and doing a job,
they will walk up to the scariest
motherfucker on the face of the planet
and start shit with them.
I'm afraid you bitch.
There's got to be guys who do that to
allister or brock lesnar people are
retarded.
So weird.
All you gotta do is shake one of these
guys' hands and you're like,
oh,
you're a tree.
Unbelievable.
Good tape.
Fletcher's hand.
You're like,
oh,
you're a fucking your cattle.
Do you know what I mean?
He's,
yeah,
he's a small moose.
I mean even you do it.
I honestly,
one of the times we've said,
hi,
I s I shit you not and I'm not blowing
smoke.
We said,
hi,
we did one of these and one of those
fucking side hugs you my jaw hit your
fucking shoulder.
And for two days I was like,
I think it's okay to kind of get out
more.
You get it,
it's good for you to get that.
But like,
it just hit the wrong way,
you know what I mean?
It was like John's or weak man.
Just stupid design.
It's the unfair part of the human body
besides Dick and balls.
Yeah.
Have you ever been dropped?
You ever been punched and dropped in the
balls?
No.
No children?
No,
no.
It's the weirdest thing,
man.
I've been rocked before,
but I got dropped once in a kickboxing
fight and my legs just gave out.
We're like,
it's never happened like that before
where it's like a switch shut off.
I was totally conscious.
I could see the guy.
It clipped my chin and my legs just
stopped working so it just went out from
under me and I see.
I feel like if I,
if I got hit in the jaw with a foot,
I.
my job would just break.
Yeah.
This was a punch.
I got hit with a left hook and a I just
dropped.
But it was,
it was weirder than anytime I've ever
dropped before.
It was just,
it was a everything shut off like.
But my brain did,
but my legs just stopped working.
And so did you remember?
It totally went unconscious.
I was totally conscious.
It just my body went.
Once he clipped me,
my body just wasn't working anymore.
It was like,
took a break.
I tried to get up,
my legs were rubber and I got up to my
feet and I covered up and he hit me with
a couple of upper cuts and drop me
again.
Um,
but the whole time,
like my body was just not working
anymore.
Once he clipped me.
Oh really?
Like,
even,
even minutes afterwards for sure.
Wow.
I couldn't move.
Like I was trying to get up and just
wasn't working.
Right.
Oh my God,
that's got to be frustrated.
Well,
if you get hit really hard there,
then the whole thing just shuts off.
It's such a stupid design.
Yeah,
I think it's relatively hard to knock
someone out unless you hit.
Oh,
that's weird.
Like people get caught in strange ways
and they get not like there's no science
to when you get knocked out.
Well also you've got to worry about like
when you're hitting the ground too,
like that could fuck you up.
Well,
there was a UFC fighter named Tim Hank
who just died a week,
a week or so ago,
about a week ago,
um,
he was in a boxing match and apparently
it's suffered quite a few knockouts in
the last uh,
year or so,
and they really probably shouldn't have
been fighting it all.
And he got knocked out and as he got
killed,
his head hit the ground hard because he
was out cold.
He bounced off the canvas of the,
a boxing ring and it sounded horrible,
but it was even,
even though it was Kansas,
I mean that's hard,
but still,
I think it's canvas over wood though.
I mean they have like thin,
like a UFC belt.
You got a good thick,
fairly thick canvas because there's so
many take downs and you know,
broader slams and stuff like that just
to give to that floor.
But on boxing rings it can be
considerably stiffer.
And there's different schools of
thought,
like some people like a really soft
floor because it makes it harder for
guys to run.
Like it's almost like running in sand,
you know.
And then,
and also safer if you get more of a
matte.
Yeah,
more of a matte.
Yeah.
But the UFC is like,
it's like a matte surface,
but it's covered in canvas,
which is kind of fucked up because you
never grapple on canvas until you fight.
And occasionally you'd get ripped up.
Everybody gets torn apart by the canvas.
Yeah.
I went back rough.
I went back and did a,
uh,
you saw the video I did with the Joe
Garcia.
You Know Joel?
Yes.
I don't know if you guys met but we
never met.
But uh,
I was big fan of his.
Yeah.
He um,
he submitted.
Fuck.
Who Was it?
Was it saccharide?
No,
it wasn't soccer.
I Asian guy.
Right.
A room in a though he submitted to pen,
Ya know,
I don't know,
think it was.
Maybe it was in Japan.
He went overseas.
I know,
but it was a huge deal because Rwanda
Sato at the time was one of the biggest
mma fighters in the world.
Pull that up if that's what it was.
Mostly that I think it's ruined.
I believe it's sotto.
Sotto was like a super high level
Jujitsu competitor as well as a mixed
martial arts fighter.
Yeah,
because Joel said that he.
It was like the.
I can't remember he was saying he wasn't
sure how practical his knowledge of
fighting was until then.
Huh?
That's interesting because he got the
guy in an arm bar,
um,
after going right to the ground and he
was like,
it was over right then,
you know,
you know what man,
there's dudes out there that you don't
know the fucking world class.
The thing about Jujitsu is there's guys
out there.
Yeah.
That was.
This is it.
Is this it?
Yeah.
This is it.
Um.
Oh,
this is good down.
It's not long.
I guess it's four minutes,
but I feel like this is the second
fight.
I think this is the one and he gets him
down on the ground and that doesn't
honor bar.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I don't know dude.
Didn't they fight twice?
Didn't I?
Once.
Oh,
this is it.
Yeah.
I think he fucked his arm up and
obviously.
Oh Dude,
that is incredible,
man.
Oh look,
look how bad it's been.
Mash.
That is death to look how he squeezes
with his calf against the Chin and Tuxes
foot under the shoulder that that dude
is submitted a lot of fucking people.
Guy Was a big
Jujitsu guy that he fought.
I didn't know that.
Sato Sato is a big MMA fighter,
but known for his grappling.
Really.
I think they fought again in a straight
grappling thing,
if I remember correctly.
But anyway,
that was a giant wind for that dude.
Yeah.
So you did something with him?
No,
I went to his class because I was in
Toronto for like five weeks doing a
movie and was the movie.
It's called life in a year and it's a
drama.
I don't know if you plan it drugs.
Are you being serious?
Yeah.
I don't even know which will probably be
funnier.
Was it weird?
You know what's weird about it is like,
you know,
I do so much comedy that it's so fun to
do comedy because even in between your
takes,
you're still in that mood where you're
fucking around.
And I was doing this movie where
literally I'm taking care of Cora
Delavan who is dying of cancer and it's
like so heavy and then in between takes
or like sad.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So it's like it was work.
I mean it was,
it was definitely,
I definitely wanted to do it.
Um,
it was just,
you want to do it because it's a new
thing.
Yes.
I want it to do it because dude,
I,
especially after my third,
I had just filled my third special and I
was like,
what the fuck am I going to do another
special,
you know what I mean?
Like I want to do something else.
I didn't want to do another sitcom
because I did two of those,
you know what I mean?
And it just,
I don't want to do the same thing over
and over and over again.
And so that's why this even on this
special that just came out today,
it's like I talk more about myself than
I did in my first two just because it's
like,
I don't want to teach.
You keep making fun of the same shit.
Right?
Yeah.
I hear you man,
I hear Ya.
Yeah.
And like doing different things is where
you get new ideas from.
But yeah,
that acting things,
that grind.
Yeah,
I know,
I know
you complained about acting and I work
in a coma.
Know it's,
it's uh,
it was,
it,
it was just boring.
I mean,
I don't want to disrespect it like that,
but it's like,
not that you're disrespecting you,
but it's just like the shit we do is so
exciting going on stage for an hour and
everyone's listening and you're in
control of what the fucking mood.
But then when you're just like the fifth
lead on a movie and you have one really
great scene and the other scenes you're
just kind of in with four characters and
you say shit like,
Oh yeah,
I remember that or something.
Do you know what I mean?
Oh,
well she was always a wild one.
You know what I mean?
When you say it's like that,
and you had to do that 19 times in a row
because I got to shoot it from different
angles.
And even though Cuba,
Cuba gooding junior's in the movie and
you're like,
oh,
it's quite good to work with Cuba
gooding Jr.
That's cool for like four takes and then
you're like,
I'm fucking hungry.
Where's my phone and why is There no
wifi in this bullshit?
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah.
So yeah,
when people get bored working with Cuba
gooding jr,
by no means am I complaining,
just like I realized doing standup is
just such a fast paced,
fun lifestyle.
I mean,
and it's worked too,
but you know,
it's like we know it also.
It is standup as you like,
it's just you,
you do what you want to do.
Whereas these other things is.
And that's a weird thing to say.
People are like,
whoa,
you should enjoy work with other people
and sure and career to have it.
And that's great.
But there's something about like knowing
that you put together your whole set
beginning.
Then you figured out which way the shit
should go.
And then like you go do somebody else's
stuff,
you're like,
eh,
this isn't as engaging unless you're
playing for me.
unless you're playing like a real
character or like a or something that's
funny and you get to ad lib and fuck
around,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's a bit like some people thrive on
it.
Some kind of thrive on it.
To me,
I know I've been,
I mean you lose a lot of them.
They start to just go to acting,
stay over there.
Somebody was telling me recently that
they were bummed out about how and they.
And it was a good point about how,
you know,
people like fortune feemster who's
hilarious,
like she doesn't have an especial yet
because she's doing so much acting work
and she's like a true comedian.
I think she's really fucking funny,
but It's like,
well duncan trussell doesn't have a
special.
That's insane.
There's another one that's insane,
but does he act?
No,
he just does.
What the fuck's he doing?
Yeah,
he's funny as shit though.
He's hilarious.
He's also nice as shit,
man.
It's the best.
But I mean for a guy that is as advanced
as he has,
he should absolutely have a special day.
She'd have another special for sure.
Especially because everybody has a
special now.
Yeah.
I mean they're not even.
Especially when you call them specials
anymore,
they're hours thing.
Yeah.
Maybe it's an hour.
Just call it an hour.
Yeah.
Diaz is going to do on netflix.
Oh yes.
You know that fucking guy.
Joey diaz coming in?
Netflix.
That guy is so funny.
I wonder if I'm not supposed to say
that.
I might've made a scoop.
Well,
maybe you're wrong.
I fucked up.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe you're Wrong.
Maybe I just made it up.
Maybe you just fucking saying shit.
Maybe I'll just talk it out of my hands
were high.
Could be um,
yeah.
Uh,
that guy's so fucking funny.
I mean,
I think in burst,
no one's ever been funnier.
The burst of joy diaz can create
onstage.
I've never heard anybody funnier.
Yeah.
It hurts my,
my cells.
Bone cells,
her laugh and he's like,
like him.
Brody makes me laugh hard just because
he's ultimately holtzman is.
I mean that guy has killed me.
There's unknown ones.
Ones though.
It will.
They're free and they're the people.
Yeah.
People don't know what to make of him.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Yeah,
but the unknown ones,
man,
there's like a ton of those guys.
There was that one guy from long island?
what the fuck was his name again?
Bob?
Didn't we do this already?
Did we do this before where I was trying
to figure it out.
No,
not bob nelson.
Nelson.
Wasn't that guy with the boxing gloves?
Yes.
Jiffy.
Jeff's.
Jim.
Yeah.
He would hit himself and I mean,
how much comedy has changed.
Imagine doing that now.
I like 10,
15 after you or me.
You can't even have props anymore about
this.
The other day With judd apatow,
we were like,
it used to be like a legit form of
comedy,
like prop comedy.
I even feel like guitar,
you can't even bring a guitar nowadays.
There's a few of those guitars.
There's out there,
right?
There's a few.
Yeah.
It used to be a fucking hard thing to
follow on some different thing.
Yeah.
If someone killed with a dirty song and
then he had to go on after him,
I'm like,
damn,
all this dirt.
He's han.
But those guys,
uh,
they were like a bunch of those guys
that would do shit like,
like harry bazell with,
with the movies and.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah,
yeah.
That shit killed back in the day.
I mean,
dude,
why up until 2010?
I woulD say the guy that left after I'd
be like,
these people are dying.
I haven't seen them recently,
but no new kids coming up have a big bag
of fucking santa claus bag of props.
Like grant during some cringe when the
grinch stole all the toys from the town
and having to brIng a bunch of shit
though.
That's one of the things I love about
not being a musician.
Yeah.
You know how people say like comedians
secretly want to be rock stars.
Dude,
I couldn't think of.
I'd rather be a fucking crack dealer
than a rockstar.
Anybody who says that has never killed.
Maybe like,
what are you talking about?
MaYbe the rockstar.
Get out of here.
I don't want to do that.
That Seems like a lot of work.
yeah,
it does.
Plus you got to be like with your
bandmates all the time.
That nerves,
like you can't work with other people.
We can work with other people.
Like we know what the neighbors would
get together on the road and the next
week you could do a good gig with
someone like you and no one goes,
hey,
what the fuck bro?
We're a team.
It's no like comedy teams like that.
I know.
That's good.
Oh,
that's just like the movie thing.
Plus you're on your own.
It's nice to deal with other people's
bullshit.
Yeah.
It brought a new drummer bro.
We'll take a chance to san francisco
with mike.
Man.
I always play the drums bad.
You know?
It's fucking bad.
As a single unit man,
you would have to be like a singer,
singer songwriter.
Like a Gary Clark junior hires his own
people.
Like if gary Clark's juniors drummers
like,
fuck this,
I'm out of here.
People were like,
all right man.
Yeah,
you have to show your good.
but uh,
it's all,
it's all about the lead singer though,
because I mean,
unless you become like maybe the lead
guitarist or something or like the
violin player and the dave matthews
band.
Yeah.
Like he was kinda see then even there
though,
it's still the mother fucking david.
No problem with that son.
No,
I know.
But when it,
that's when it gets deep.
That's like a dictatorship when it's
like the dave matthews,
tom petty and the heartbreakers.
Right.
But when it's like rush,
right then the rolling stone kiss.
Yeah.
Kiss every people in there.
No,
no,
no.
You can't.
Can't switch the cat out for fox.
Okay.
That's not cool.
Oh man,
that's true though.
I never thought about that yet.
Name.
It's something.
Then everybody's kind of the group.
Everybody's in there.
If you're a heartbreaker though,
you're gone.
You're gone.
You know what you are.
You're a guitar and not get by.
Anyway.
Charlie daniels band.
Motherfucker.
What does it say?
Steve miller as a site?
Charlie wilson says charlie fucking
daniel's dryly because it's my band.
You piece of shit.
Yeah.
Nwa.
You can't get rid of fucking guy.
You can't get rid of any of those guys.
Yeah.
And all those guys became.
Except for maybe one when David Lee roth
let fan,
halan and van hale was named after van
halen.
How bout that shit?
Fucking van halen is the lead guitarist
David Lee roth left and everybody went.
God damn crazy.
Yeah.
Cause it's van halen.
It's too of a name.
Even though it's your last name.
It's not the eddie van halen band.
Because if that was the case I'd be like
okay cool.
I get it.
Different people.
It's like carlos santana.
Different people sing for them
sometimes.
Right,
right,
right.
But it's still the carlos santana band.
Yeah.
Just don't be a fucking heartbreaker
man.
But van halen seems like a like a thing.
Yeah,
it is.
Yeah.
I didn't know.
I didn't even.
I guess I didn't even think I even put
it together that it was his last name,
even though I knew that it's like a
vehicle,
like a van halen.
It's a strong.
Yeah.
So it's like a hindenburg.
yeah,
it is.
Yeah.
You rogan.
That's good.
Delete is not a good one that got the
apostrophe.
Fucks it all up.
The apostrophes are weird.
Why are we still using?
No,
do we forget how to talk?
It's okay.
It's very weird.
I used to.
Yeah,
you don't have to tell me how to fucking
pronounce it.
Just drop it by the way.
It makes it worse because people are
like leo,
leo,
add fucking ells and shit.
When you go to like a restaurant,
you know what the worst is is when I
pull into a gate,
you have a meetIng anywhere and you've
got to give everybody that's thing.
And,
and I sit and then they say you're not
in the system.
And I'm like,
try a with or without the apostrophe.
Whichever one you didn't do.
And then they're like,
oh,
there it is every fucking time.
Every fucking time.
You should change your last name
spelling to de d,
h a h l e a h.
I don't know if the,
uh,
the uh,
I was little when I was little.
I told my dad,
I was like,
can we get rid of the apostrophe was
young.
I was like 12.
And he was like,
huh.
And I was like,
it just sucks.
like why?
LIke,
what is it?
Like people always mispronounce it and
he's like,
you should be proud of that.
And I was like,
I'm not.
And then I remember thinking I'm not,
it's just 13.
That's rough.
Yeah.
And then,
and then,
and then I started to like it,
you know,
because I'm like,
yeah,
I guess it is my name.
Fuck it,
you know.
Um,
but when I was little I wanted to
change.
I remember,
I remember asking my parents if I could.
I mean,
this is embarrassing.
I remember telling my parents that I
wanted to change my name to damien
monroe.
Yes.
You want to change your kristala to
damien?
Damien,
the monroe.
Imagine.
Imagine if my name was damian.
We're enrolling.
You would have hated me immediately.
No,
I wouldn't.
I know.
Because you're open minded.
Yeah.
But feel von [inaudible] name ever.
My name is theodore theodore.
But think about it.
But think about.
This is why you didn't even know why,
why I wanted to do this,
because this is so embarrassing.
I'm whatever.
But because damien was is the devil,
right?
Okay.
And then Marilyn Monroe was pure in my
head,
so I was like,
you have both this.
This was like a showbiz name id.
I don't know.
I didn't get very far with it.
Obviously this time.
Yeah,
same age.
Like young.
What am I was like,
well I could call.
My name is damien monroe.
Oh my god,
I would hate that.
Hilarious.
I mean,
you all do stupid things as a kid.
I didn't get to do that.
Obviously my parents would have let me
do that.
Thank god I was a fucking weirdo man.
I would ask them my parents.
I would,
I would ask my peers because I always
sat like this at the dinner table and I
asked them,
I was like,
can you call me crazy legs?
And I remember thinking like,
oh,
that would be cool.
Like if my family called me crazy legs,
hey,
it's damien crazy legs.
And then they were like.
And my dad was like,
no.
And I was like,
but just like maybe just at least at the
dinner table,
I remember saying that.
And you will be like,
I'm not fucking calling you crazy.
Like you need to chris.
Oh my god.
That's so funny kid shit.
That was even younger.
the crazy legs thing was like,
it was probably like nine god.
Kids.
Ideas are so stupid.
They're so dumb.
They're so fucking funny.
I remember,
uh,
these women laughing in my face once at
me trying to be cool.
And I was like 12.
I had these fucking sneakers on.
I don't know,
like they were like these brown suede
sneakers and I went through a period of
time.
This is very embarrassing.
And I went through a period of time when
I was like 12,
12,
13 inch where I got really into tom
sawyer and huckleberry finn.
Oh boy.
I even tried chewing tobacco.
Oh geez.
They would tell you chewing tobacco when
you were a little kid.
You can be 12 inches bite.
Chewing tobacco for whatever reason.
That wasn't like cigarettes.
Right,
right,
right.
you could just by chewing tobacco,
like I bought it.
I didn't have to hide.
That's so weird.
It's fucking crazy me let you.
But you would come in this wallet
looking brick and you opened it up and
you break a piece off like real old
school.
Lee fucking clinics would style chewing
tobacco.
I was retarded.
Okay.
So I had these,
these shoes on that were like a brown
suede that were really goofy looking.
And these next door neighbors in this,
we rented a house.
It was me,
my sister,
my parents.
And then one of our friend's friend of
my dad's rented one of the rooms in the
house upstairs and the next door is like
a very small house and next door was
another small house.
And these young kids lived there.
Like the downstairs people,
they had a band and they were fucking
horrible.
But they were like super committed.
So they practice all the time.
And they had,
they had carpet everywhere man.
Like you'd go down in the basement and
what they had done is taken like 30 or
40 sheets of carpet and like made doors
and pack the walls.
And they essentially turned the basement
into like a practice soundproof thing.
But you could,
you could hear them super clear and
okay.
I remember they're,
the band's name was death in the
shopping mall.
Oh my god.
And the song called my baby is a mutant.
You remember this?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I got a crazy memory man.
And so these guys like
the baby is.
But that's okay.
I love my baby.
It's crazy.
I can't even remember this shit.
Fucking practicing below in their ear.
Jumped out there were cool as fuck
though.
They let me go over there and watch when
I was 12,
let me go and hang out with these guys.
One of them scooped ice cream.
He a giant forums and everybody was
like,
look at his forearms.
Managed scoops,
Ice cream scoops,
ice cream all day.
So these jack forearm and all the young
kids like 12 would be like scared of
this 19 year old dude with his giant
forums because he'd scooping all the
time,
but they were all super friendly.
But there's these two freaky looking
girls that would hang out with them.
And I,
you know,
when you're 12 years ago,
can you believe group?
Yeah.
So I have these stupid sneakers on.
I say the girl I go,
she goes nice sneakers,
like she's kind of mocking me.
I go,
yeah,
I don't like codes and my sneakers.
It turns me off and they burst into
laughter.
Not laughing existence,
but like,
look at this fucking dork and I'll never
forget the feeling when I said it.
Like,
yeah,
I don't like colors in my sneakers.
It turns me off like the feeling of
like,
oh,
you fucking moron.
You thought you were being cool and
quickly while you were saying this and
you're like,
oh,
this is not utilized.
That's hilarious.
I was 12.
I realized as you're saying like how
stupid are you really get checked by the
opposite sex when you're that age.
I mean there was one time I kept like,
I remember heisey yeah,
I was probably still around.
I don't know,
but obviously I don't
drink it,
but there was great pets them.
Oh my god.
Wow.
Whoa.
They have a youtube video.
Definitely shopping malls.
This was a five year,
four years ago that these guys are 80.
Oh no,
it says that this was in 1981.
They recorded it and 81.
Wow.
So that was right around the same time
because 81 was where I went to high
school in 81,
so that would make sense.
That was like,
so I was.
I guess I was 13 and in a little later
in the career,
but dude,
that's two years later.
We're talking about [inaudible] 79 in
1979.
I'm pretty sure that was the age I was
pretty crazy because I was 13.
Yeah,
because it was right when I first moved
to boston.
We were living in Jamaica plain.
We were living on a god damn.
I don't remember the name of the street
for remember the name of the street.
It would help,
but anyway,
I'll.
That haunted me.
Those girls laughing in my face.
Funny haunted me for years.
I still think about it.
It's interesting.
I think about.
I think about shit like that.
That's I think about shit like that that
like you carry with you like you know
how sometimes it's just.
Yeah,
but sometimes it's just like that's.
I mean nothing it.
But what happened was you were too young
to have dealt with a situation like that
yet.
Yes.
So that was why you remember it,
because you're still,
oh,
this is new.
Oh god.
you know what I mean?
I was aware of personally aware of how
we're stupid.
I sounded right.
Which,
but as a kid you don't have that.
Right.
You knoW.
So the first few times you,
you changed your name to damien monroe.
so were both forgiven.
I remember that I had to.
Yeah.
I feel like it was a different version
of that.
I had,
I had a,
I see,
I was in kindergarten.
Yeah.
Kindergarten I think.
And um,
it was before first grade,
wherever that is,
kindergarten and I'm the high c straw.
It wAs great.
Paicey I remember and I squeezed it
wrong and it shot up on my face and I
was with a table where there were girls
there and it was lunchtime.
And I remember thinking,
oh,
it's probably purple on my face,
around my eye,
like kiss or something.
Cool.
Yeah.
And,
and so I was like,
kisses cool.
Like I'm going to just chill with it.
And just because it happened by
accident,
so it's not like I tried to do it so
these chicks are just going to see me
with this cool purple thing on my face.
I mean god,
I mean,
same age,
no kindergarten.
Oh,
so however old that jesus christ.
So youngest shit and thinking all these
thoughts and then thinking,
oh my god.
And then thinking,
ah,
I can't wait to like mac on these girls
like young girls.
And I mean it was whatever.
But it was before first grade.
That's kindergarten.
Yeah.
Kindergarten,
yeah,
mrs antoine's.
And so say you got graPe soda.
So I got great,
great.
Not even soda juice,
you know what I mean,
on your face.
And um,
I remember thinking like I remember
leaving it there and it was very sticky
because it's high c and it's candidate
basically.
So.
And was,
I believe it though because it's cool.
I remember thinking like,
just stick with it because it's very
cool.
And finally it was so sticky that I was
like,
I hope that this is like paying off
because I got to wipe my face.
And so I asked the girl like really
insecurely,
like next to me,
I Was like,
hey,
uh,
I was like,
is it like all purple on my face,
but like wanting it to be purple,
you know?
And she goes and she just goes like
this.
No.
And then I was like,
can I go to the bathroom?
And I washed my face,
like what in the bathroom?
And then I looked at my face.
It was just my face,
zero purple.
But,
but that was like an,
those were actual thoughts that this
idiotic fucking kindergarten or had I
was like,
oh,
I look like a rockstar is what I
thought.
This moments you can remember when
you're just a little kid where you're so
fucking stupid,
they will haunt you deep.
think about that all the time.
I think about all the time it's probably
shaped me,
you know,
it definitely has like one ass kicking
in highschool could turn you one way or
the next left or right.
Like people have been,
some people have been bullied in high
school and it fucked him up for the rest
of their life.
Well yeah,
they a lot.
Yeah,
I mean and even before high school,
like junior high in grammar school and
shit,
some people just never recovered from
it.
So weird inclination that people have
bullies in schools like to find one kid
who fucking nervous and start fucking
with them.
YeAh.
That's very normal to me.
Where you going after school?
Nelson?
Besides sucking my dick in the woods.
I never understood that big giant gay
dude wants you to suck his dick in the
world.
You got to go to high school with him,
fight him off every day.
Parents don't believe you.
Yeah,
I mean I,
I loved always making fun of people but
not bullying.
Yeah,
no.
Well I think there's a lot of kids who
get physically abused at home.
Yeah,
I think that's a Big fan and they get
their power back.
Yeah.
And then there's physical bullying that
way,
but then the psychological bullying too,
and then there's a certain amount of
natural pecking order shit that kids do
to each other.
They're competitive with each other and
one will say something shitty and the
next will say something shitty back and
then they form teams,
cruz,
chris,
piece of shit.
Right.
You know,
and then you're like,
you know what man,
mike and I were just fucking.
You guys get to pick a team going team
chris for Mike Lyons,
bro.
Yeah.
there's a lot of animal behavior.
Like I have chickens and one of my
chickens,
like one of them,
something goes wrong,
like the other ones start fucking with
it.
They peck at it.
Really?
Yeah.
It's weird.
You know,
I don't eat the chicken.
Just eat their eggs,
which are non fertilized.
Ladies and gentlemen.
All you crazy vegans out there.
Not getting enough protein in the eggs
from chickens.
Throw your pets.
They're going to run around.
You can even if you want to,
you feed them vegetarian diets,
which you really shouldn't because
they're not vegetarian is little fucking
dinosaurs bro.
But the thing is when they see like
something wrong with one of the other
ones,
it's a real problem.
One of them gets injured,
the other ones start pecking at it.
Weird.
Yeah,
iT makes you think that that's how we
are secretively.
Well,
I think at our base level,
no,
but I think what is so like one,
it's interesting about all these anti
bullying campaigns is that they didn't
exist when we were younger and whether
or not you make an argument for people
figuring out how to get along through
the natural methods that we've
encountered,
like finding good people and bad people
and finding who you like and finding out
about your own behavior and how it
affects other people.
Either way it's a w,
w,
w.
What I think's going on is we don't want
people to fuck with people anymore and I
think in the old days everybody just
accepted that people fucked up people
and now we realized we're going older
were really.
But what's crazy is that we're figuring
this out as a culture in the last 20,
30,
whatever the fuck years it's been human
beings have been around now for.
But it's,
it's,
it's social media though.
That's what it is because now everything
is exposed.
It is thAt.
But I think it was on its way there just
through traditional methods like books
and regular media and colleges and
universities.
That's one of the reasons why college
and universities are so important for
changing thought,
especially were there kind of in a
fucked up place now,
but there was a thing where you would
leave your environment and go to this
new environment,
right in this new environment would be
filled with intellectual,
right,
filled with people,
they're trying to change the world and
you'd be exposed to ideas you never got
before and so through those ideas,
then you learn about your shit and then
you'd go out with this idea that you're
going to go do this or you're going to
go apply your knowledge now there,
or get a degree here and everything
would sort of compound in your
understanding of the world would be far
better than the people that came before
you.
Because just the fact that humanity's
accumulated 20,
30 plus years of information since the
time your parents were in school.
Right?
Right.
so all that aside,
as that goes by,
that gets you a certain way.
It gets you a certain amount of steps
past the barbarians and the fucking
romans,
all the psychopaths of our history,
but now once social media kicks in,
now everything's accelerated in a way.
We can't even control completely out
everybody's hands.
that's why trigger words and safe spaces
and everyone's going fucking crazy.
It's too fast for us to catch up with,
you know,
but it's moving in the right direction.
like even all the ridiculous like
trigger word safe space and stuff.
All that stuff is like,
it's in thE inclination is to be nicer.
Yeah,
that's a good thing for sure.
Yeah.
So some of it's ridiculous.
It's not well thought out,
like you're better off having people
communicate and having safe spaces.
You better off figuring out a way to
bake people just not shitty to each
other and screaming and yelling at each
other,
like find a better method of
communicating now.
But uh,
the point is,
it's like they're moving in that
direction.
They're moving in a really good
Even these ridiculous like liberals at
shut down that evergreen college and
they're going nuts and they didn't want
white people to show up for work for a
day.
Their inclination is probably correct.
I just want to balance things out and
when things are right now,
they feel like black people are still
like in a bad position as far as like
racial injustice and by pushing white
people down they're going to bounce a
black people out,
but they just don't understand humans.
Right.
It just doesn't.
It doesn't work.
Like that works.
You know what?
We're breaking it down crystal.
I know man on fire.
Is it hard picking a name
for your special or this one?
It was not because you have a bit.
Yeah.
But uh,
yeah,
I find it difficult.
Yeah,
they do.
Yeah.
I was actually before yours came out,
I was like,
man,
somebody should do like trigger warning
or something.
Yeah.
I jUst did a great title.
I did it because I knew what they were
upset some people,
but that's.
But that's.
But that's who you are though.
And that's what that.
I mean,
you talk about all the things that would
trigger somebody well,
like just talk about what's ridiculous
about those things and with that special
particularly I knew like the bruce
jenner bit,
I'm like,
oh this is,
this one's coming home heart is it?
They need a trigger warning.
I don't even know.
I'm a physical comedian.
I don't even know how you made that fit
work chair and all that shit.
No,
but I mean not even just that,
the,
the build and everything.
It was just like he became a bunch of
different things.
Like it started out,
it started out a little different.
It started out,
it was a little more calm and then I
realized like,
you know,
the only way this is gonna work,
like worth people gonna really think I'm
a demon because I try to think this is a
fucking goofy thing to admit,
but when I'm doing that bit,
I used to do this bit about tigers
fucking.
And one of the key that I figured out
the key to the bit.
At one point the key to the bit was to
think like a tiger and to move like a
tie.
Not think of myself as a comedian.
When I did that bit I was thinking of
myself as a demon.
Like I was thinking of myself as a card.
It kicks off.
So then my inclination was to just climb
on the stool and just like in getting
this weird sort of gollum hunched over
stance because.
And plus I figured because I'm really
flexible,
it'll look weird.
strange,
you know,
that's funny.
My son was,
my opener is like,
how do you do like to act out like that
and I'm just like,
you just believed that that's what you
are for a little.
But
it's so dumb.
But.
But if you could do it,
if you could pull it off,
you know,
you ever see jimmy schubert's bit about
eagles meeting?
No,
it's a hilarious bit.
But when schubert's doing it,
it's becAuse eagles have this crazy
thing where they fuck while they're
flying.
When they fuck,
they stay connected untiL to come.
So like they don't make it.
They fucking crashed into the ground and
die.
Which is hilarious,
but his bit,
you know,
he's like got like while he's doing it,
even though you know what you're
thinking about,
thinking like an eagle.
It's funny.
He's,
he's an eagle right now.
He's in his.
He's in his element.
That's funny.
It's have a truck back now,
that's for sure.
Not too loud,
right?
I mean that's so core and doors.
We're nowhere near that truck because
they say you get your money pages back
up,
bro.
Yeah.
Not everything has to be white,
white,
white sox.
Someone new sneakers every day.
The sun,
the wrapper.
I saw a rapper the yesterday,
got a papa smurf,
a diamond encrusted chain man.
They're just trying to outdo each other.
You know what I've been thinking to
doing.
I've been thinking of live in two
separate ways.
Thing going to get into a cabin in the
woods,
right where I live.
Like I have a well solar power.
Just chill out there for half the year.
The other half of the year I get the
dopest house I can afford in beverly
hills.
Just walk around and furs everywhere.
I like how it might be a lineman.
So you glasses outside at night?
Always.
Yeah.
That's great.
So you have to.
You're your one half year.
You give the other a limo with my face
on it.
You make the driver wear a mask of you.
I'm going to get a a grill that I could
only put on for six months,
a year.
So after six months they take the grill
off and then I go back to being the
woods guy.
Board being one person.
I think you know,
I mean to that.
Well,
yeah,
because look,
tupac had the songs about how lyft are
women up and then he would be the other
guy.
Be like,
fuck bitches too.
Yeah,
it's very confused.
Figured it out.
Yeah.
Well he was a poet and also he was a
reporter.
He was reporting on what's going on in
the streets.
Are you not?
No,
no.
Bipolar.
I just want to do it for six months out
of the Year.
he's just fun outside of the.
Oh this is what I'll do.
I'll get a crib in downtown la,
like one of them penthouse cribs.
We're overlooking the city.
Yeah.
What a pool on the deck.
Would your family be with you both
times?
Fuck you talking about bro.
One of the half of the year.
No,
I'm a different dude,
but I'm a different dude.
Okay.
I got it.
Yeah.
I don't even have a family anymore.
Let me look.
I saw a video of a guy where they were.
This guy said he was a trans age.
He was a young girl.
He was like,
he identified with being a young girl.
He was like a 50 something year old man
and the identify with being a young
girl.
He has children and they let this guy
dressed up like a young girl and people
are accepting it.
It's family's accepting it.
He was talking to people.
He's saying how he really feels.
What's to stop you from being a totally
different person.
I get it to identify as like a korean.
Just identify as a different guy.
Like right now you identify as kristala.
Yeah.
I'm wondering now
host out of the character.
What's damien?
What damien?
Yeah.
Dude,
was I ahead of my time.
You might've been ahead of your time.
This is what I'm thinking.
You could be this as the guy trans woman
lives her life as a six year old.
Yeah.
Has a family.
Has children at someone's daddy.
She decided.
What is the girl that he thinks he's so.
What was he doing for six years ago?
It's still the guy six years ago.
He hadn't been born yet,
bro.
So can he.
Does he ever.
Was he ever turned seven?
No.
No,
no,
no.
And there's always.
This identifies age is irrelevant dude.
Okay.
You can't age someone just like you
can't gender someone a piece of shit.
Shit right now.
I am.
God.
That's him as a woman.
But what am I going to get one day?
A incorrect.
He will forever called it.
So there was,
he had a gang of kids and then fell on
his head or something.
What?
What caused it?
I dunno.
Maybe just decided.
Well,
so what's.
If you can do that,
you can do that.
That's who you identify with.
Now.
You're a girl.
You could change your name.
You can change your name,
your becky.
Now I'm becky.
I'm caitlin,
I want you to be.
I'll be nine said,
well,
I don't mind going to six,
so I've been six ever since.
Well,
whoa.
Wow.
I don't know what to make of that.
Jesus christ.
Listen to this nonsense.
Well,
I have a mummy and daddy and adopted
mommy and a daddy who are totally
comfortable with me being a little girl
and their children and their
grandchildren are totally supportive.
In fact,
her youngest granddaughter,
when I was eight a year ago,
she was eight,
so she's getting older.
When I waS eight a year ago,
I was eight and she was seven and she
said to me,
I want you to be the little sister so
I'll be nice.
Oh wow.
I said,
well,
I don't mind going to six,
so I've been six ever since.
Well,
so now he's just changing it though we
are living in a world of nonsense.
I mean,
you can't just change it so that he
doesn't identify with it if he just
keeps changing it.
I'm not even going to have real diamonds
on my grill.
I'm going to tell everybody they're
real,
but they're going to be cubic zirconias
because food's going to get caught in
man,
who gives a shit.
It doesn't have to be real like they
identify as real diamond platinum on the
outside though,
for sure.
Wow.
For sure.
Platinum and then I'd get it taken off
every six months and I become a words
guy.
What's guy?
Yeah,
I'm into it,
man.
I'll vouch for you.
I'd be like,
no,
he sTill people did.
You keep telling me you can't be a
different person.
You could totally be a different person.
You feel different a lot during the day.
You feel like one way.
Some morning you're sad and then at
night you're like,
oh,
thIs is a great life.
You know?
Remember that bIttersweet symphony song.
A million different people from one day
to the next bit.
Probably symphony this.
Remember that.
Not the way you're saying it,
but maybe.
But there was a band called the verve
and it was a great song.
I know.
Yes,
I know the song,
the verb,
but they lost all the money because the
opening riff,
santa just stones.
Remember that I heard something recently
similar to this.
Did you know that?
Uh,
that song I'll be missing you.
That puff daddy mad about that has made
all of the money from that song.
Yeah.
Every breath you take $166.
Million dollars or something like that.
How much?
Like 60 or $70?
Million dollars.
Just that one song that doesn't share
with the police.
It's just his money,
but also the police see that's way
fucked up the police.
But he wasn't,
it wasn't stinging the on the edge.
No,
dude,
you can't be the edge.
That's what youtube,
right?
Youtube is good.
The edge.
What's the edge,
bro?
What's that band?
One of the guys in the band.
But he calls himself that he's a white
guy.
He's a whiTe guy and he calls himself
the edge.
Hey.
No,
definitely.
No.
Yeah,
don't be a thing.
I just love.
I just love when rappers are like,
that's why they call me fucking the
edge.
And you're like,
you asked people to call you that dude.
That's why people call you that.
You can't do that.
They call me the love professor.
No,
no they don't.
They call me.
When you say they call me,
I stopped listening.
Yeah,
they call me the psychological
coordinator.
That's a good one.
That could be one of your guys.
Guy psychological coordinator.
I just sit and write books on people.
This is what I think of a few of them on
television.
Yeah.
I mean why can't you be a different
person if you can identify as being just
decided I'm nine or I'm six.
Did you see the one about the guy who
identifies as an alien or.
No,
he wants to have his because he wants to
be an.
Well,
he's done his whole body.
He's a ton of money.
Is he not allowed to say he?
Can we say z,
z,
z.
Z has spent a ton of money,
has fake lips and done some petty shit
to z xyz.
That's $50,000
at over a 100 procedures.
First of all,
stop.
Stop right there.
That's not true because that means each
procedure is how much you've done 100
procedures.
50 divided by 100 or 50,000
divided by 100.
How cheaper?
These fucking procedures.
$14 each.
Yeah.
This is ridiculous.
100 procedures will go down as the
seizure is a thousand dollars.
It would be $100,000.
So you've done 100 procedures at $100
each.
Five for one dude.
That plastic surgery is fucking
expensive.
That's one of those things.
It's like a burger.
You want to pay the most?
Yeah.
I mean unless he's got a friend,
it's hundred.
Just $100,000
or $50,000
on a ledge right there.
That's from taking so much dick that
your,
your cave caves in.
But,
but he's slick when they drilled for
cold,
they don't do the proper seismics
studies.
So he doesn't have a uh,
uh,
exactly.
Jina aura.
A peanut or she's an alien.
Whatever is.
He's an alien that's.
She's trying to become a genderless
alien.
It's an interesting look.
I mean why not man,
you know,
people want to get their face tattooed.
Why not get wacky and do this?
And who the fuck am I to judge?
My arms are covered in tattoos.
No,
I mean it fucking.
If it makes the person happy or the
alien who got art all over my arms,
but keep that picture up,
man.
What you doing?
you want to keep it to yourself.
By the way,
do you.
Do you.
let me see the top one.
The top one with the face one is the
weird face one.
No,
no,
no.
The one like the top.
Top one.
That one is fucking trippy.
What was he doing?
What is he doing?
Twosies eyes.
Well,
vinny is makeup artist vinny.
Oh,
22 from los angeles,
California.
It has plans costing over $160,000
to become genderless alien.
He's already spent $50,000.
those were probably 10 photos.
Yeah.
Jesus raise.
Is that the other's contacts?
Contacts.
Oh,
those are the contacts,
but it might also be.
Oh,
he looked kind of normalish,
right?
That that is normal.
Osha.
What kind of pain you have to be in to
want to be genderless,
genderless alien.
Who,
but who am I to judge?
Who is anybody to judge kristala?
Wouldn't this world be better if we
didn't?
A judge.
We didn't exist.
You and I wouldn't exist.
We wouldn't have a job.
It's a problem.
That's like that brethrens joke when he
was like,
who could only god can judge me.
He's like,
no,
a judge can judge you because funny
joke.
thank god he does.
Stupid tattooed on shit.
You're right,
judge can judge god dammit.
I know you fucked up.
That's why.
by the way,
I'm like,
before I get this done,
is there anybody else who could judge
me?
Put me.
hey bro.
Nobody can judge you.
But god,
nobody.
Nobody judges and occupation.
Um,
what it is.
Did you know that a chiropractor is not
even at,
did you?
I,
I love tattoos.
I always wanted to get that to us.
But like I just don't be scared of.
Well,
it's just,
what if I don't like it late.
Exactly right.
ThAt's the fear with it.
So let's go to a good tattoo artist.
Yeah.
But what if I'm like,
oh,
I love what I got super lucky.
The guy who did amaze,
a gentleman named aaron dasilva dova
from guru tattoo in san diego and he's a
world renowned tattoo artists.
Does the style of tattoo that I like,
like big,
bold,
lots of colors and stuff.
He's just.
I got lucky that I got.
It took a long time now I had to get,
I got to wait and get an appointment and
this one took like,
I don't want to say this one took like
50 hours.
This one took like 40.
So you got that done.
Done.
You got that all done in pieces and
pieces,
but eight hours.
then I come back again and they would do
like one part for eight hours.
I understand that.
But you,
that whole thing was a design.
It wasn't like.
Oh wow.
Actually.
Yeah,
because usually a lot of people just add
to it.
Started small,
right?
I had this little idea and he was like,
yeah,
it's like you have too much shit you're
trying to do in this one little thing.
I was like,
hm,
so what should I go like half sleeve?
He's like,
well,
it's make your dry up a half sleeve,
and then I'm like,
fuck it.
Let's just go all the way in.
So all of a sudden then you were
tattooed?
Yeah.
All of a sudden,
well took no more than a year,
but it seemed like when people like sort
of piece them together like one little
tattoo at the time,
there's something about big pieces,
like when someone has a big flowing
piece,
like if you're going to get something
done,
it's all personal choice and like,
um,
you just have your arms.
Yeah.
I like them.
They don't bother me.
I always think they look cool.
Like,
you know,
even conor mcgregor and shit like that
looks cool.
He's got and wacky carrillo on his neck,
on his neck,
you know,
girl with a crown.
But it's like cool.
It's him.
You know what I mean?
Are you going to pay money to see that
fight?
I got,
I,
I got to see that.
I mean,
I don't really follow it too much,
but I got to see that.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
I wouldn't see.
I would say yeah,
I would definitely watch it.
I'm working that night.
I'm trying to figure out how I'm going
to avoid finding out about the.
Yeah,
let's take your chicken.
Watch it.
Yeah.
I mean there's no.
I'm in.
I'm in dc that night,
so I got to figure out how I can watch
it without finding out what happened,
if that's is a possible way.
But what about,
what do you think you do?
You have an idea what's going to happen?
I think floyd mayweather.
It was going to win a boxing match.
That's what I think.
It's like how he's going to win and
whether or not he's he's challenged and
whether or not he's put in danger.
He could be put in danger for sure.
If connor puts,
connor's got to put himself in danger
and he's got to be confident enough to
like he's got to get ahold of them.
I think he's got a rough him up and he's
definitely not going to win a straight
boxing match against the best boxer
ever.
Right.
and uh,
I don't think he thinks he would do that
either.
I think what he wants to do is clip him
just like go after him making big sprint
right away.
Try to clip.
I'm trying to hurt him.
Try to rough him up.
The more time goes on.
What happens with a guy like floyd is he
starts,
I mean he's been boxing for so long,
he starts doing things.
Then anticipating your reaction to those
things.
Timing,
yeah,
she'll do things not even so that he
could hit you,
but to see how you react and how fast
you are and maybe if he did this and
then came over the top or maybe he did
this and stepped over here and hit you
with a left hook and he gets it in his
head and he starts moving around and he
puts you in like he sort of has these
parameters for your movements.
Almost like he's a super computer.
You'd see like anderson silva used to do
that too.
You could see him like measured timing.
He would see how you react that he would
just drop that front kick on your face
or something like that.
He just sees that there's an opening
there.
He knows how fast he can execute a
technique.
He how fast after watching a move for a
while that you can move and he knows
whether or not you can get them.
Whether you can get to her like how
fast.
All right,
so once floyd has those numbers in his
head,
then you just get your face boxed off,
then you get your face.
It's interesting that a guy can be so
good at that and,
and,
and work so hard and not get brutally
ruined it to the point to become a and
then become a champion.
You know what I mean?
there's a bunch of faculty,
the training and shit.
I mean obviously guys get hurt and then
can become a true champion.
Yeah.
To be that guy that's gotten to that
point.
It's just amazing.
Floyd's got a bunch of factors on the
side.
One,
his uncle is a fantastic former
professional boxer.
Roger may,
whether the black mamba corner guy,
he was a world champIon.
He was a bad motherfucker and he would
start guys with one punch,
but he had a totally different style.
And then his dad,
floyd made with their senior phot sugar
ray leonard and had a really good fight
against sugar ray leonard,
if I want to remember,
he was stopped,
laid in the fight.
I don't remember when.
But um,
so his dad was an outstanding box or his
uncle was an outstanding boxer and he
grew up boxing,
so he grew up knowing technique at a
very early age when,
you know,
at a really early age you can get really
good at it because you can get good at
it later.
There's a lot of fucking unicorns,
like people that don't make any sense,
but when you're young you don't hit that
hard.
Yeah.
So you and your buddies and hit each
other and you don't hurt each other.
So you'll learn how to box and you don't
have the consequences.
If you learn how to box and you're 180
pounds and you're boxing other dudes
that are 180 pounds,
you're fucking savages.
And you throw in lead at each other.
We're boxing scary and dangerous.
But when you're a little kid,
he can't even hear each other.
Huh?
That's what actually joel carson was
saying that,
uh,
it's way easier to teach kids how to
like throw.
Oh yeah.
Because you know your,
your body fucks up when you're a 100,
200 pounds trying to throw somebody else
200 pounds.
Yeah.
When you're 40 pounds,
you throw in another 40 pound or no one
gets hurt.
Yeah.
Floyd's just as good as they've ever
been in.
In terms of boxing.
He's got a unique style.
He doesn't take a lot of damage.
He's the best defensive boxer of all
time.
In terms of the amount of time that he
gets hit,
nobody gets hit less.
Yeah.
I don't know much about boxing or
fighting at all,
but the I,
I have.
I mean I got to see that.
That's a freak show.
It's not a boxing match because connor
doesn't have a lot of boxing matches.
It's not like we're looking at canelo
alvarez when he was challenging floyd.
We're going home.
You think canelo can get to them?
Well,
we can go back and look at this fight.
He did really well.
You can't look at anything.
Yeah.
AnD also look at anything.
Doesn't the wind the stamina?
I mean like a box or stamina.
He's got to go 12 rounds,
right?
True she is what,
a five rounds for championship fight,
but right.
It's five,
five minute rounds with kicking and
wrestling.
Right.
Fucking way easier to go.
Three minutes boxing than it is to go
five minutes of mma fucking ways.
I guess I didn't know that.
I'm done grappling and shit.
No comparison.
Now that I've done either one of them
professionally,
but I'm just telling you as far as the
amount of work that you put out in a
three minute round with just using your
hands versus wrestling,
fighting off submissions,
getting your legs kicked,
kicking,
all those things require tremendous
amounts of energy.
I think ufc athletes are some of the
most conditioned athletes in the world.
Oh yeah.
The high level.
Like when you get to like a mighty mouse
level,
when you know he's that guy can go five
rounds,
full clip and never get done.
Guy.
I mean we were talking about that guy
who knows how much he gets hit.
Don't nobody hits my new mouse these
days.
He's on such another level right now.
He's already several levels pass mighty
mouse,
demetrius mighty mouse johnson,
who you talking about the asian guy know
who was the asian guy that kept getting
punched in the face?
We talked about them.
We Talked about,
uh,
the korean superboy joy.
Yeah.
that was the crazy fight with cubs wants
totally different.
Mighty mouse is the pound for pound.
Best fighter in the ufc.
Flyweight champion.
Okay.
Do.
Whoa.
Joy is one of the most exciting 145
pound contenders.
And he had a fucking crazy fight with
cubs won.
It was crazy.
Oh my god.
It was just,
that was the blood and guts fight of the
year because they were playing at the
comedy store when it was on onto the.
Yeah.
That was a crazy fucking fight.
It's um,
it's,
it's all about like whether or not
connor could hit him and he probably
can't hit him.
I mean,
just,
you've got to be honest.
Probably cannot.
We cannot,
we cannot.
I mean,
floyd has been doing This for so long of
boxer.
Yeah,
it's a different.
It's a different world,
man.
It's a different world is no leg kicks.
There's no take downs.
There's no.
It's a different world.
Was it you that was saying somebody was
saying something about I'm connor has
something.
Has the one thing over floyd that
nobody's ever had over him and that's
that he can say I can kick your fucking
ass.
Yeah,
I can fuck you up.
Is that you a chance?
Yeah,
it is me.
If there was an mma fight,
it would be.
Connor has a chance in a boxing match
because he knows that a poach.
Hansen zero,
zero.
Its leg kick to take down to smash to
strangle every day,
all day for the rest of your life.
A baseball player in the octagon.
Yeah,
because for sport even can't even punch
him if conner's kicking them.
Like if they just let connor kick.
If they said,
okay,
listen,
you can't do mma,
but you can kick.
Oh my god,
I'm putting all the money on con.
Really?
ONe hundred percent of it.
100 fucking percent.
You let them kick jesus christ.
How?
How many leg kicks you think floyd
mayweather jr can take even if he's
blocking to and he'd connor's going to
sidekick his knees.
The legs.
Yeah,
that's the worst county.
Fuck his legs up.
It's never going to get close enough to
hit him.
He's going to side kick his legs.
He's gonna sidekick.
His body.
He's gonna.
I mean there's no chance.
No chance,
but first take the legs away and no
chance for conner.
Not no chance for connor,
but boy,
if you have money,
you know,
boohoo.
You bet.
I remember the first time I,
I felt a kick to my leg.
I couldn't believe how hard I bad at.
Horrible.
Yeah,
it's horrible.
dude,
there was this guy named pedro.
His was a one of the top ufc
heavyweights fought all over the place
and um,
he used to leg kick guys and he was this
big fucking brazilian dude.
This was a long,
long time ago.
Back then he would submit guys just by
kicking their legs,
break your leg.
He'd break his leg kicks were so heavy.
You would hear them like ring side.
It Would just sound different to say,
oh no,
this guy's going to let him kick him.
No,
this is not always going to low kick a
journalist.
he's going to hold the pad.
Yeah,
that's pedro.
His.
Oh no,
don't do it.
He's going to let him kick his leg.
Now look at the size of pedro.
He's giant,
huge.
Don't journalist.
This guy's going to let them do that.
come on.
They're not going to do it.
Did he get just.
That's not even an exaggeration.
He touched you like that with his leg
and you have a charlie horse.
I'm not kidding,
dude.
He was a gorilla.
he's the hardest,
hardest leg kicks I've ever seen because
he was a big ass heavyweight.
Is this guy going to hold a pattern?
What was going to go flYing?
This is going to be awful for him.
Even with the pad here goes.
No,
come on son.
That dude just flew through the air and
flipped and landed on his face and it
didn't look like it was nothing for him,
for the other guy.
Dude.
That's how hard pedro,
his own kicks.
You got to understand that there's no
way that was 100 percent either.
Oh,
probably was really.
You want me to say it again?
The dude flew through the air.
that was 170 pound man.
He went flying through the air.
THat guy flew.
He was terrified.
At least he went with it.
He fought rigo rodriguez.
Rico was one of the top,
uh,
ufc heavyweight.
So at the time.
And he hit him with a leg kick and he
could see the look of rico was like,
what the fuck is that all about?
He just had a different amount of power
like that.
It was like George Foreman punches,
but with the legs just had a totally
different thing going on.
You were you a big fan of boxing back?
Yeah.
Huge ufc and all that.
Oh yeah,
man.
I still am.
Still am a big fan of boxing.
I love boxing is exciting because like
when you see a guy like a sergei kovalev
first versus andre ward looked last
fight,
you're seeing like the margin of error
that each guy is operating in is so
small and it's just two things.
It's just left hand right hand.
These are two weapons,
right,
and the margin of error that you have.
One,
one guy's an expert and punching people
in the face and the other guy's an
expert at punching people in the face
and you're moving around trying to find
your openings and these like world class
top of the food chain guys are trying to
smash each other with their punches and
that's all they have to rely on.
So in making sometHing like very limited
to me,
especially because I've watched so much
mma,
it becomes interesting because I'm like,
okay,
now I don't have to think about leg
kicks.
You don't have to think about takedowns.
All I have to think about is which guy,
you know,
like which guy is gonna be able to solve
this puzzle.
And it's very fascinating to me to the
point where people.
I like fights that people get mad at,
like they get,
they go,
that fight suck,
excited because they thought it wasn't
exciting or whatever.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
Well that's why I've always been a fan
of floyd mayweather.
Yeah.
Because of what he's able to do,
defensive,
like nobody can do what he does.
That's cool.
Yeah.
He saId he's an amazing defensive boxer.
I mean every fighter should watch them.
Everybody should learn it.
Just like how he could stand right in
front of you too.
I mean we stood right in front of guys
just fucking.
There was a video on youtube.
I was watching where the guy was like,
I want to show you guys that had moved
that I'll just make sure you don't want
to even block,
but that's how I'll never get hit in the
head.
And,
and he goes up to random people on the
street and he's like,
hey,
I've seen that guy.
It was like go ahead and try to punch me
for like a minute and I'm not going to
block.
I knew the guy was like,
okay,
and then he just never gets hit in the
face because you're doing this fucking
head bop.
Yeah.
But he's got to fInd the right guys.
Well,
I mean he's not finding professional
boxers and you roll up on deontay
wilder.
Alright,
I'll do it.
But still,
I mean,
you know,
that's interesting.
I wouldn't have thought about that.
Yeah.
A guy who could move his head like floyd
mayweather or wassily loma chenko like
that,
that kind of guy.
The guy who can stand right in front of
you and you can't hit them.
That's one of the most terrifying guys
to face.
Fucking crazy.
You can't hit them like it's just not
there.
And then he's hitting you all the time.
He's sending,
getting frustrated and getting your.
When you're getting winded or missed a
punch and you realize your spiderweb.
Yeah,
you're slowly getting lit up.
That's what's going to be interesting
too,
to see what happens to connor.
If he does find himself in the web,
he finds himself in a web,
whether or not he tries to distance
himself with floyd,
floyd and stay on the outside.
Whether or not he tries to clinch up
with them and bullying or whether he
does something like really confusing the
floyd doesn't expect like it's like his
coach,
john cavanaugh,
the guy who's coached him in mma.
Very,
very smart guy and a brilliant tactician
and together their team is.
I liked their approach,
they're very,
very unique approach and one of the
things they do is they come up with
these really unorthodox training
routines because his statement that
really rings true with me is he says we
want to upgrade the hardware,
upgrade the software without damaging
the hardware.
Kevin.
Oh,
says yeah.
So they do a lot of drills instead of
like constant hard sparring.
And the idea is that when you do hard
sparring all the time,
the problem is like it's hard for
experimentation because punished if you
fuck up and it's hard to download new
stuff.
And then the other,
the other hand doing things like just
doing drills over and over again,
it can get kinda boring.
so they come up with all these
innovative cool to incorporate new kinds
of movements and a lot of it's weird,
like they throw throw cards at him.
He's got this guy throws cards out of
many punches.
The cardS.
I've seen that effective if at all that
is,
but it's a freak show.
That's what's.
I mean,
the crazy thing is what a fucking connor
when.
Yes,
that's,
that's like kind of bad for boxing.
So awesome for conor mcgregor.
Oh,
it's great for him.
I don't think it's bad for boxing
because conor mcgregor can box.
I mean he really can boxer.
The question is can he box man?
Right,
right,
right.
Big difference.
You know,
conor mcgregor is the biggest star ever.
Oh yeah.
never if he knocks out.
Floyd mayweather.
He's the biggest athlete of all time.
He becomes,
first of all in europe,
he becomes the king of europe.
They just give him crowns and they make
a castle forum as crazy did.
If he,
if he knocks out floyd mayweather.
He is like literally probably the most
popular athlete of all time.
HE might surpass like,
he's like in muhammad ali levels,
right?
I mean he's already,
he's already.
Yeah,
I think mohammed ali was probably,
it wasn't our time,
but I think he was probably at a totally
different level because muhammad ali
also represented the civil rights
movement,
right.
Represented the bigger than just the
resistance to the Vietnam war.
He lost his license to fight for three
years.
It's a story.
Yeah.
He's,
he's a,
he's a symbol of a generation.
connor is just an amazing fighter,
so takeaway muhammad ali,
and I think he's probably on his way,
but if he loses and he gets embarrassed
by floyd,
even still,
it's not a sport.
He's got nothing to lose.
I mean he's making $100,000,000
anyway.
Who the fuck knows?
I'm sure it's a ton.
Okay,
so many people are gonna be watching.
How could it not be.
The craziest thing about connor is that
four years ago he,
nobody knew who the fuck he was.
Yeah,
I mean that's,
that's crazy.
That's like there's no profession where
like all of a sudden you're that big of
a star,
but it doesn't even exist in mma.
You to understand.
Nobody else does that.
It's just him.
So.
So what happened?
He's,
by the way,
he's like 28.
Jesus christ.
Twenty eight,
29.
I tweeted him when he won the cage
warriors title or you made it might've
been defending his title.
I think it was cage warriors,
but he flatlined some doodles like this.
Kids fucking really?
Yeah,
and I tweeted them,
congratulations.
And I said,
I hope to see in the ufc some daY and
that was like 2013.
Wow.
That's because the access tv shout out
to access tv,
formerly hd net.
They had so many good fIghts online.
Actually.
maybe it was the internet.
I might have been on the internet
actually now that I think caught your
eye just looks sensational.
Hope to see in the ufc someday.
That's cool man.
God that's crazy.
Two thousand 13.
January of 2013.
But to think that he tweeted that then
and then and then now the biggest
fighter on the planet.
That was
before he even came there.
That's just prEtty dope.
so basically you're saying he rose so
quickly because he's just something
special.
Yeah,
I got you.
He's something special and he knocks
people dead.
you know,
he's except everybody except nate diaz.
Nate diaz.
That just shows what a bad motherfucker
he is.
He's the most underutilized fighter in
mma period.
In terms of like his star power,
like capitalizing on it.
I don't think the ufc even knows how
fucking huge nate diaz is.
And nick his brother,
nick.
Branding wise.
you're saying and just everybody loves
those guys.
They're fucking characters.
Yeah.
like an american version of snatched.
That's fucking funny,
right?
Is it snatched or snatch?
Snatch.
Movie snatched.
Was the goldie hawn?
Yes.
Amy schumer talking about snap get
confused and there's another snatched.
The snake.
Snatched is maybe like a tv show on the
id channel.
Should,
I mean I always snatched.
It'd be great if it was either alien
abductions or a guy works on supposed to
see dr.
I like to trim them.
Extra.
Snatched your cleaning up this wider
pussy.
You know who dr.
Yeah.
No.
Uh,
yeah.
But that guy to me,
nate diaz looks like a fucking a guy you
don't fuck with.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
He's huge.
People don't realize how he is.
Nate is in between fights.
motherfuckers walking around like 200
pounds is huge.
It's big fella.
Big and super good.
So how did he.
Oh,
he just leaned out to fight conor.
Yeah.
Just.
Well they fought at one 70 both times.
That's so much weight to lose as a 200
pounds.
But,
uh,
you do it slow,
you know,
you do it over the course of a,
like,
I'm sure he's carrying some body fat now
when he got down to 1:50
5:55
before when he fought at 55,
before the conor fight,
he fought Michael Johnson,
one of his best fights at 55 and 1:55
dude shredded at the weigh ins.
Insane in that fight for the weigh ins.
He was obviouslY in like crazy,
crazy shape.
SMokes weed by the way,
hollow.
Well,
now everybody thinks that weed makes you
lazy.
Come on.
Well,
no,
I mean lazy makes you lazy.
He smoke weed like that.
Shredded.
Wow.
Is that from that fight?
That's it right there.
Look at that.
Boom son.
That's our cuts.
Mean looking motherfucker.
He doesn't have no fat that uh,
he's had some sensational ufc victories
to,
um,
well,
I mean the guy should be.
I mean,
he made a shitload of money on the conor
fight and the rematch.
I'm sure we've made a shitload of money.
But now what though?
What's he going to do right there?
Jesus christ body.
You could set him up with some good
fights.
That was when connor was severely
dehydrated.
That's a 1:45
pound picture,
I believe.
Yeah.
It's fight night.
So that was a 1:45
pound picture.
That was before you had the notorious on
his abs.
Fucked up,
man.
Do that.
Vicious abs.
Just scribbled on them.
But Yeah,
when you see him at one 70,
like when you fought eddie alvarez at
1:55
or a genius.
Yeah,
he's the 1:55
champ now.
What's really fuckeD up because he was
the 1:45
pound champ.
And then he just left the title one,
155 pound title.
So now he had two world titles in the
ufc and then he just sort of take the.
See that picture right there is way
bigger there.
Yeah.
Jacked.
Wow.
That's the nate diaz rematch.
He was jacked.
But how tall is he?
Tall,
right?
Um,
he's five.
Nine.
Yeah.
Nate diaz is what's assets to it too.
So that's the alvis fight.
Okay.
So that's one.
That's him at 1:55
actually to nate diaz fight.
Well,
I bet they're were real similar in
sizes.
That's the nate diaz fight his lat.
Now that's alvarez because it's a.
He's jacked,
isn't mcgregor.
oh,
does it?
Oh,
you're right.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
Ufc 202,
right?
Yeah.
Okay,
so that's.
That makes seNse.
Because he's won 70 in this picture.
Yeah,
that's incredible.
That's not not.
I would have said,
hey man,
put that somewhere else.
Put that shit on your back or something.
fuck up your abs on a.
But you know when it comes to
personalities,
personalities and finding.
See this.
See the difference.
He looks.
He looks different,
huh?
Yeah.
He was so sucked in for that first
fight.
Jesus christ.
He looks like he looks at the on the
top.
He looks like a guy that will like yell
at you on the street corner like a crazy
person.
You're on the bottom of his faces.
Nice and full.
It looks so.
He's going to kill you.
He's.
I'm going to make a lot of money.
Whether or not he could beat that guy
either way.
It's going to be fascinating to see.
It's going to be fast,
isn't it?
Isn't it not to talk about this too
much,
but it isn't it,
isn't it like soon to have the,
like they didn't have time to train.
Exactly.
Which is why I think what flOyd wants,
like floyd was probably in great shape
and I think I'm actually.
It's probably good to do it this way.
I think they prepared for it for quite a
long time before they actually committed
to it.
I hope at least I know he was preparing.
He didn't take anY mma fights.
Didn't even think about it.
This kind of soon though.
August.
Just around the corner.
which she wasn't working well,
so can't,
can't.
They make so much money if they waited.
I don't know,
man.
This is such a freak show.
I think it might be playing it,
right?
Yeah.
Maybe.
Yeah,
because this ain't some thing like
you're gonna plan out for six months.
People might lose steam.
Yeah.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe.
Right.
You know what's the most dragged out
fight of all time?
John claude van damme was going to have
a,
a.
Was it a kickboxing fight?
I think it was a kickboxing fight with
some cat,
some thai guy who won the gold medal in
the olympics and they went around for
years and never deposing having like
offs and shit.
Yeah,
I never did it.
Never did it.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
Oh,
he had the best reality show.
John clark.
John danny.
There was my favorite.
I love that Dude.
That volvo commercial or whatever the
fuck it was.
It was.
And he's got his legs spread between the
two trucks.
It's real.
I mean,
you definitely do the splits,
but I really don't think they want to
rescue this way.
It's ridiculous.
I mean,
is it god that guy.
I remember I watched street fighter
twice in one day.
Who was he in streets as the guy?
A guy.
Old guy?
Yeah.
I'm going to kick that son of a bitch.
Bisons his sword.
He would say,
so the fucking killed me.
I said,
he's an award.
What is this?
Oh,
I'm a statue in brussels.
Wow.
Powerful.
John claude van damme.
Look at him.
So happy sunglasses doesn't give a fuck.
I know what a character.
He's got Russia.
He has people,
he just looking at john claude van damme
has to have like you can,
it looks like a guy who would have the
darkest sexual life,
who,
you know what I mean,
like,
like has a white cottony blah blow
security right now.
Oh,
it makes the life cycle of security
guards too.
Sucky.
Stick.
Wow.
No doubt.
I don't think so man.
Well that's how he looks and he has his
sunglasses on.
It's nighttime.
That's it.
You're telling me.
Come on,
I look at.
I'm looking right there.
Boom.
Security right now.
That's it.
I know guys who've had that happen where
they were with a guy and the guy wanted
his wife to suck their dick.
A friend of mine said that this guy was
coaching his wife through sucking his
dick and he had just met the two of them
that night.
That's some different.
Uh,
I don't.
I mean like what does he get?
Bored or what a.
Yeah,
something like a thing that is with you
before that and then it just comes out
or.
Because that's.
What is that like?
That's like that.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's a good question,
like it can't be,
it can't be one day or just like,
you know,
suck his dick,
it's not like that.
It has to be when with you before that.
Yeah.
I would imagine.
Has to be.
Yeah.
Who knows?
I don't know.
Might be.
I don't know though,
you know,
it's one of those things we got to think
why does it bother us?
Well here's the deal,
man.
Being being in an open relationship is
different than watch.
Well yeah,
but still why does it bother us?
I see what you're saying.
Why does it bother us?
But it does like you.
Like for the most part.
Yeah.
The idea that somehow or another you
could blow a fuse and then you're right
next to a guy going,
you liked that?
Huh?
Honey work the balls.
I suck.
One was balls in your mouth.
Do the thing.
I like put your hand to him.
Jerk your hand off.
Like where your fingers are facing him.
But it's,
it's a fucking weird thing man.
It's super weird because I was like,
what?
What do you.
It's a power thing right?
It's a power thing,
I guess.
It's also like I'm a freak thing.
It's like we're being naughty or doing
something dangerous.
We're,
we're rebels were something,
what are we going to get?
Some weird stuff.
But I've had a,
I had a fan once their driver came up to
me and he was like,
hi.
Um,
I was instructed to come over here and I
want you to meet this guy wants you to
meet his wife and sleep with them.
It was in chicago with her.
You mean to hurry?
Either way I'm not doing it for all,
but I really wanted to fuck him.
That was the thing.
This face.
Imagine if there was like a guy out
there sort of how that like picture
makes epileptics have seizures.
Yeah.
There was a guy out there that makes
your dick hard and just didn't expect it
at all.
out of nowhere.
Like you might not even have to like see
them in person,
but if it's a god that's so pretty,
like they figured out a way to have the
perfect amount of masculine but not even
pretty.
Just the kind of vibe you like,
his vibe,
like a bear,
like a John Hanson crystal guy because
like I'm not gay.
I was like,
look,
I'm not gay.
I never had sex with a guy,
but if I was going to I think I would
pick like a big guy.
A nice looking guy.
Not like a pretty guy,
right?
Like tom selleck aNd it's prime shoes.
No socks.
Red car.
Chris,
what's up with the flowers and your
shirt,
bro?
That's how you hit on it.
Hey man.
What's up with the flowers and your
shirt?
What are you doing later?
How come you were a socks?
You feet stink.
Don't lie to me bro.
He's a handsome guy.
Guy in white man right there in Hawaii.
I always used to think when tom selleck
was in Hawaii,
magnum pi was in Hawaii.
I would always think like,
does he hate being in Hawaii?
After awhile?
You get to about like [inaudible],
like last and then they do who I follow
there.
By the way,
that guy.
There's a guy,
there's a guy that was on both lost in
Hawaii.
Five o.
Well,
he probably loves it down there.
It must listen man.
People who lived down there,
you're living in paradise except for the
occasional hurricane.
OTher than that,
you live in paradise.
Yeah,
but it's also.
I mean,
dude,
it's so humid,
man.
I mean I was in,
I was in west palm beach this past
weekend.
I was like,
yeah,
it's beautiful,
but like it's too hot.
Ninety two degrees feels like 4,000
degrees.
yeah.
it gets funky and then you close it out
to la and you're like,
oh,
this is the best.
It's dry.
It's the best.
Yeah.
Like phoenix.
Phoenix can get hot as fuck.
Phoenix is just.
Yeah,
but you're landlocked too.
I feel like nice.
If you're a true right,
you just get in a boat.
If shit gets rough and I have a load on
your deck,
like tie it down.
Even if you're just in santa monica or
like the valley as a tsunami hits,
you get indexed and you always like
freeze dried foods.
Would you want to be the guy gets hIt in
the head by the asteroid or would you
want to be the guy that has to figure
out how to rebuild civilization again
because they get hit in the head.
The nice and quick view,
if you got to rebuild civilization,
count how many moving in,
how many?
Forty,
40 people.
That's it.
Yeah,
that's it.
I probably won't get hit in the head.
Then you have to fuck your sister in
order to make people.
I don't have one.
thank god.
What do you do?
If it's just you and your sister and
you're the only two people that want to
get hit and head for sure,
but if you are alive right now and she's
alive and she wants to stay alive and
you're like,
look,
there's only one way you can make more
people and just have people with that.
Don't you have kIds with down's syndrome
and shit?
Not yet.
I think it takes a while.
Takes a few generations,
but even worse than that,
you bang each other and then you have to
bang your kids or the kids have to bang
after because otherwise that's it.
It stops right there.
So then it has to be,
it's got to get to a certain point with
30 or 40 people.
Everyone's fucking their kids and then
you have to make new rules.
Okay,
let that planet people who can't fuck
your kids.
And right now your kids,
by the way,
this is how it used to be guys.
We can do it.
Well,
that's when was this?
Four hundred years ago before the big
rock from the sky.
Shut off the power.
I can't fill the Wifi,
but my sister's hot.
They'd be shit like that.
I know you mentioned like he forbid
bidding now,
but your mom and dad were brother and
sister.
you guys are fucking hypocrites.
That sounds like a fucking hulu series
that I was thinking the hallmark channel
now hulu.
Then you get to see like tits and shit
in it.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
You remember that?
Uh,
do you remember that movie brown bunny?
Where vincent gallo the theater,
and I brought my ex wife,
uh,
you know what it was since she didn't.
And she was like,
what is it?
I was like,
it's going to be good.
Want to go?
Because I love vincent gallo and uh,
I went to and when she sucks his dick in
the movie,
my ex goes like this.
Oh,
it's a porn.
And I left.
I left.
what's crazy is it's a whole movie kind
of one scene at the way.
It doesn't matter.
I know.
Isn't that hilarious?
Yeah.
I like big vincent gallo,
does it?
He's so fucking weird.
That's really kInd of crazy though,
right?
Like if you have a movie one six,
if you have a movie where everything is
like hilarious,
but then someone dies like a lot of
comedies,
like someone dies.
You don't say it's still a still a
comedy.
It's a comedy.
But if you had harrison ford,
cate blanchette in a gripping thriller
and then at the end they fucking,
you see in anodic shots like that.
It's a porn.
You can't,
you can't not call it a port.
That's hilarious.
It's weird,
right?
It's funny that like no Matter what else
happened and like coming on her chest,
you can't do that.
You can have a scene where like you see
them,
like there's curtains you see is as you
can sees,
right?
Her legs
wrapper as long as it's tastefully done,
she's kissing.
but if you actually see a prIus and a
vagina or a penis and a mouth or it has
to be in it though.
Right?
Even if your penis and vagina is not
porn,
do you ever see house of cards?
No.
There's a scene in house of cards where
the president,
spoiler alert is going down on a
reporter.
He's,
he's eating.
This report is box and like his face is
right on her box,
but it doesn't show us on the phone with
her dad.
It's rough.
Netflix will fucking show whatever.
There'll be like,
you'll watch the fucking the ranch with
ashton kutcher and you'll be like,
you have to stick.
It's just like weird.
Yeah.
You can do anything.
I just showed my dick and my special.
Did you how many times?
Just for.
Wow.
That's all in the beginning though.
That's a lot for you for an hour staring
at the coMedy store.
I guess once you get ramped up,
you know you're doing a special.
It probably should have done it,
but I was excited.
I was in Canada.
Oh,
in Canada.
you could show your dick freely.
There was a french.
Yeah,
you can apparently walk around toronto
with your breasts out.
So there was this video that was
released online earlier today of this
woman activist who was being interviewed
by this guy and she says it's totally
legal to take your top off.
So she takes her top off and you know,
she's a feminist almost immediately
after she takes her top off.
This dude is black guys think,
I don't know why I have to say black
guy,
but it's headed to there.
Brazen.
When they hit on,
girls sneaks behind her and grabbed her
tits.
No behind.
Yes.
And she screaMs at him and they scream
at them and they blurred the black guy's
face out,
whIch is kind of funny,
but they didn't blow the titties outta
that.
Didn't blow them titties out.
Interesting.
That's very racist.
So the black guy's face,
but not the titties,
because whoever doesn't want that guy to
get implicated in a crime,
it's.
I mean,
even though he just found it.
Yeah,
I want to see it here.
Watch this.
So she's yelling at this dude.
So she's yelling and she takes her top
off.
Look,
see your full full breasts.
Now watch this dude with the blurred out
face.
He comes up behind it.
Oh shit.
Oh wow.
Everybody's like,
no,
you do not.
You do not do that.
And they,
they even lose track of him.
He sort of lingering in the background
there in fighting with each other.
Now tim,
he was so confused.
I got to tell you,
he was smooth as fuck away.
Did that shit?
Well,
he's probably met girls like that
before.
Next thing you know,
old jeddah,
Millionaire gobble,
gobble switches.
And she's like pointing her finger at
him like he was using the body's
natural.
but what are they arguing about?
What the fuck's going on here?
Who cares?
They're arguing because they were poorly
parented.
They never learned how to phone.
The whole thing's ridiculous.
These are just people today,
people losing their fucking minds.
This is the shit that they will play for
future generations when they talk about
the downfall of modern western society,
they'll play this kind of shit when
young kids
were just so soft and living a life so
easy.
Look for microaggressions at every turn
and then also girls puller to these are
guys grabbed him because that's what
some dudes do.
You know,
you can't just pull your titties out in
front of soMe dudes that girls still
walking around with their titties out,
right?
yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
I think so.
Super impressive.
So far,
only one grab.
Yeah.
That's amazIng so far,
but that's just because there's always
other people around.
Realize the danger people will make act
different.
Isn't that the thing in New York city?
You can walk out with your.
I think you can.
They had a gender thing.
You can walk around with top of the
shirts off.
Women don't.
Most places.
Most places for women.
Yeah.
Where do you think it's illegal to go
topless?
If you had to guess.
Well you can't do it in la.
Wouldn't be funny if it was vegas.
Can't do it in la.
I don't think so.
Hmm.
I wonder if you can.
I mean if they can,
they can breastfeed so they can.
But that's different.
It's like a guy can pretty much
everywhere.
Everywhere.
Plus yeah.
I can walk down the street wondering
what like if there's a certain time at
night with arrest you,
like if you're.
If you have no shirt on and it's
midnight in la.
Yeah.
The cop might arrest you.
I'm like,
dude,
what are you doing?
Like why don't you have a shirt on?
Right.
But if it's like noon and you have no
shirt on,
you're sunbathing.
Yeah.
You just hanging out.
Just trying to catch some rays.
This is chili dude.
But if it's like 7:00
AM,
like what's this derelict dealing with
no shirt.
They would definitely keep an eye on you
unless you're jogging.
Then you're like,
this guy's an athlete too.
That's really funny.
That's like a carlin bitter some shit.
Probably a certain amount of time to
have a shirt off at 7:00
AM.
Yeah.
As long as yo running.
It's.
If it's 5:00
AM,
you probably should put a hoodie on just
to let people know you're serious
because if you have no shirt on at 5:00
AM,
like did you just have no shirt on and
start running?
If you're running with no shirt on a
5:00
AM,
someone's chasing you.
Yeah.
And probably running at 5:00
AM and keep running to 7:30.
If someone sees you at 7:30,
they assume you just started.
Didn't assume you've been running sinCe
like left the club.
Right.
So basically we'll try to marathon right
out of sobering up as you're running.
I looked down at his shoes.
He's got fucking loafers on what is
going on here is the got is brighton
drink ticket?
Racialist is.
I showed my id bracelet and then he
still has his sunglasses on from last
night to be cool.
But now they're functional.
That's so perfect.
That was good.
Had the what?
A douche.
Move wearing sunglasses outside at
night.
Nothing worse bro.
Fashion wise,
nothing worse.
It is.
So douchey.
Yeah.
And black gUys can pull it off so much
better than.
Well of course.
Yeah.
I'm not even offended when I see a black
guy at a basketball game.
If he's like ll cool j and he's got
sunglasses on,
this bothers me.
It doesn't bother me,
but if it's a white guy like take those
fucking things off you.
It doesn't matter the race to racist
when it comes to sunglasses.
When it comes to sunglasses white here,
you're fucking real racist against white
dudes.
You've always been racist against white
White dudes and sunglasses and like he
nef.
Yeah,
it's dark out.
You could see fine if you're doing tv
shows and shit.
you know what do you sit on the tycho
and they have a sunglasses.
I,
yeah,
I've seen people do that.
Yeah,
sunglasses on.
Tough crowd.
He did a show about comedians.
That's ballsy.
Dude.
Didn't work out well.
Would they made fun of him,
rIght?
Well greg geraldo shit all over him
because they were going back and forth
and every time greg would say something
funny,
dennis would like mock the fact that he
was saying something funny.
It was.
He never seen this.
No.
It's one of the weirdest interactions
between two comedians ever.
It's very odd.
Yeah.
Between geraldo and lyric.
Oh man.
A classic.
I gotta to watch.
Yeah.
No,
that's weirdly.
Or we will get yang yang,
right?
Probably right.
Has that anymore?
That show was funny,
man.
It's fucking great.
Did you do it?
Yeah,
I think I did it twice.
It was great fun show colin quinn's
shit.
Yeah,
it was just a great idea.
I mean he's basically like a podcast on
comedy central.
It was before podcasts,
right?
I mean it really was kind of in some
ways like.
Well the,
I think the original podcast,
the stern show,
and then once the stern show went to
satellite radio,
then it became an uncensored and then
opie and anthony sort of.
Same thing,
but I'll open anthony even more like a
podcast because you just shoot the shit
and then tough crowd came along and now
it's on comedy central.
I have no idea why they stopped doing
that.
Must have been a.
Because that was.
It wasn't.
It was kind of short lift.
Oh,
was it?
I thought it was.
Maybe not.
Maybe there's a few.
Maybe was like four or five.
Colin quinn's and interesting dude,
he might've just got tired of doing it.
I meT him in,
um,
where the fuck was I?
Vancouver actually that night I did my
special afterwards and he was just the
nicest guy,
man.
My dad loves him and he was like,
can I be colin quinn?
And I was like,
yeah,
like my dad never.
so I got a picture of them two together.
It was like a really sweet fucking night
would call him.
Was the nicest.
He's a,
he is one of my best examples that I
personally use when I say you have to
see someone to stand up in the flash,
live in the flesh to understand how
funny they're like.
He's one of those guys,
just him because his act is so.
It's so absurd.
It's so silly and odd.
Like you almost have to see him live and
then you want to see a long set,
you want to say like a headline set.
We see it filled up and get weirder.
Well he got a lot of attention for the
last specialty you did.
I know.
He's funny,
man.
It's a funny fucking dude.
He's always been funny,
but that show was a great show.
How long was it on for jamie?
Over?
Just under two years to see.
Wow.
I would've thought it was like four
years.
Wow.
That'd be a cool show to do.
Well,
what the fuck happened?
Is there a wikipedia and that?
She must've been.
How is it not a hit?
Maybe it was just too many shows back
then.
They were like a lot of shows though.
Yeah,
and like pits too.
I
feel like.
I guess there's more shows now than ever
though.
Right?
Well,
but only because of probably the
internet and shit,
but there's too many channels.
Like when you found out something that's
not true tv,
like wait,
what?
Right.
Or is that right?
Right,
right.
How do we even find them in?
I know.
What is that the,
the tv land channel.
Do you watch tv?
You don't watch netflix and hbo.
Right.
And occasionally I watch hunting shows.
What do we got here?
What does it say?
Does it say why it,
why it ended up notes from comedy
central at the same time the chappelle
show was on and.
Oh,
no demographic.
I don't know.
Oh,
so they fucked it up.
The executives fucked it up.
How we went and wrote a blog about it.
Oh,
okay.
Makes sense.
Executive fucked it up.
The last show contained a monologue by
quinn's who attacked his distractors,
uh,
such as the New York times for being
hypocritical and elitist for their
negative reviews.
He also defined comedic integrity is the
ability to critique the hypocrisy of
society.
But to be honest enough to admit that
you are just as guilty of it as anyone
else.
Yeah.
Well they fucked up.
That was a great show and it could have
been an amazing show,
but they just bring it back.
Bring it back.
Comedy central.
You need to hit cancel the show.
And also also you can just make a.
Well he probably didn't want to do it
now,
but yeah.
Well it's just weird man.
They like got rid of moshe kasher shaw
already.
I did.
I heard.
Might have fucking jumped the gun on
that one too.
I think actually,
I don't think they.
This is what I think.
I think it was like somebody else's show
and that exec,
whoever was running things is gone.
Oh yeah.
That shIt is be talking shit.
I don't know anything about show
business anymore.
I'm barely in show business.
I'm a non showbiz entity.
I have no idea what's going on except of
getting fired from comedy central with
the show.
The story telling you.
Well maybe you're wrong.
No,
he's definitely not nine.
I'm just saying.
Did you do that show you were.
No,
no,
this is not happening.
He always asks me to do it and I always
wanted to do it,
but I never had a story that fit the
theme and then I was just like,
I don't know how to do it and I just
never ended up doing it.
That's the problem.
I think it's a great.
I think it's a great fucking awesome
idea.
It's a.
It's a show designed for joey diaz.
Yeah,
because joey diaz has more stories than
any human being that's ever walked the
face of the planet.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But he was special.
He is out.
Oh,
you excited man on fire?
I am,
yeah.
No,
the brazen attempt to craft a new hour,
you know?
Oh yeah.
It's like,
You know,
when you start a new one and then it's
like I have like 25 new minutes and I'm
like,
is this stuff really though going to be
in my hour?
I don't know what I mean.
Yeah.
You don't even know gettIng,
you don't know.
Do you write down physically do right.
Physically never.
And I know it's a good idea to do that.
I just,
it's,
it's so much less.
It's so much more work for me to know
what I'm going to say and get up there
and it
than it is to go up with an idea and
work it out on stage and I have so much
more fun doing that,
you know?
And,
and for me,
I,
you know,
I like am able to,
not to get too heady but like explore
that bit way more onstage because I
fucking have to in that moment.
Because you're trapped.
Yeah.
There's 250 people there for seven.
Even if there's a few.
But like,
um,
yeah,
I just liked doing that and that's how I
get,
like,
I get like I have really long bits,
you know.
So that's how,
that's how that happens.
A lot of people do.
I mean everyBody's got their own style.
I think the only thing that's really
consistent is that you need to pay
attention to it.
You can do like really focused on stand
up.
Oh yeah.
That's the only thing.
That's really how you do it.
Like whether you do it like in your car
while you're driving,
you shut the radio off and just think
about it.
But whether you do it in front of a
computer or whether you,
you know,
whatever,
whatever you do or you do a lot of sets,
you do a set of the improv instead of
the store and the set of the factory.
It's all just about how much,
how much energy,
how much focus put on it.
Well,
yeah,
because if you think about it,
really the only time,
the amount of time that you're actually
doing standup.
Yeah.
An hour and a half at night.
Unless you doing two sets a night,
you know,
that's why weekends are so good.
Right.
You get to do two on friday,
two on saturday and do an improv
somewhere or something.
But then like I came up with a new bit
two weeks ago.
That's like a six minute bit.
Oh and,
but it's,
you know,
it's fun finding.
I know something happened and now I'm
talking about us.
The universe opened up an idea for you.
I know,
I know.
It's so awesome when that happens.
Right.
And then so I've been working it but
I've only been really working it on the
road so I in my head I'm like,
I have to get to the comedy store to see
if it actually works.
Right.
You got it.
That's how I feel.
Oh,
on tuesday night.
Yeah.
Yeah,
the oh,
on tuesday nights a perfect defining my
percent Because people are like,
first of all,
it's still tired cocaine,
they did on saturday.
They're there,
they're there.
They're unimpressed waiting to see if
they pass the audition.
One hundred percent or a lot of them are
fucking russian.
You know what I mean?
Just a lot of people have been flying to
the store.
Why wouldn't they?
Just to check out the line to why
wouldn't they?
Yeah.
Those lineups are fucking unbelievable.
It's crazy,
right?
Yeah.
It's kind of confusing.
It is confusing.
I remember how it used to be.
Yes.
When I first got there,
nobody was.
Was hit.
They were doing well,
but they,
they would do well on stage,
but nobody knew who they were.
We got to show more love to the laugh
factory.
We've got to keep that fucking place
alive.
It will be alive.
Yeah.
I mean I,
I like going there.
I go to.
I'm there wednesday,
wednesday night meeting.
We'll plug.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
Ten pm.
Wednesday you,
kristen,
leah.
Who else was on that show?
I don't know.
It's a good show though.
A lot.
A lot of fine people.
Yeah.
What else going on?
I think I have a pitch up.
Should we keep going?
I don't.
That's up to you,
man.
Huh?
How long have we been doing it anyway?
Two hours.
Really?
That wasn't quick.
Come on dubar.
Fuck.
What are we?
Professional talk knows what we.
What we do bro.
Fucking allows.
As I was saying,
it is good to come back because when I
first did the first one I fucking barely
knew you and I was intimidated and now
at least we're friends and shit.
Then the baby jesus,
we could just bullshit,
but I still get people that are like,
hey man,
sewing on rogan and I'm like,
jesus christ.
That's fucking awesome.
Do you ever think when a guy's talking
to you like that,
they're really just doesn't know what to
say and he really wants to blow you.
Maybe actually explains a lot what
happened afterwards?
Like,
hey girl,
hey,
I saw you on two broke girls.
Fucking funny.
I would love if you did an episode of
two broke girls by the way.
I would do it.
That's whitney show.
Well,
it's not on anymore,
but uh,
you know,
it literally got canceled like two
months ago maybe.
What was it like?
I don't even know what it was about two
broke girls bro.
But why would it be funny if I did an
episode two?
Because why the fuck you would never do
that?
What do you mean?
Be like joe rogan did that.
Why?
For goof?
Yeah,
I'd do it for whitney.
Yeah.
Yeah,
he would.
But then you still tight with her?
Yeah,
she's great.
But that then you should do the not,
not you should,
you should ask your agent.
You don't even have one right?
I haven't eaten.
Okay.
So you should ask your agent.
You one of those guys would be like,
nah,
fuck agents.
I still get rid of one eventually.
So you should ask your agent to find one
episode to do one.
Like I would love it if you did one
episode of csi,
like the,
the new orleans one,
like not even the one that's like,
you know what I mean?
Not even like the one but like,
but one episode in like three scenes.
That'd be fucking hilarious.
Being interrogated,
interrogated,
and not even like promote it and then be
like,
what the fuck is joe rogan doing?
And you're like,
I don't know where I,
you know,
I didn't mean to.
I hit her too hard,
you know,
like,
be fucking hilarious.
How many of those fucking crime shows
can they have one point of time the
network executives go,
we got to stop.
I don't know.
On believable.
When did we get this murder fetish?
This,
this fucking crime scene.
Investigation fetish.
The only ones I like are the forensic
files,
the ones where they reenact it and they.
And they show.
Yeah.
Those are real stories.
I watched so many of those when marvin
hutchinson came home early evening to
find his girlfriend in bed with his
brother.
Yeah,
just always arrest the spouse because
it's them always.
And they always go to like the,
the most extreme lengths where it's like
just arrest that person and then check.
Sometimes it's the creepy guy at work
that's in love with a woman,
but very rarely.
Yeah,
you're right.
But,
but,
but those,
I've,
I've watched so much forensic because by
the way,
when you're on the road hln the network,
it's just forensic files all day long.
Yeah.
It's like.
And then nancy grace for an hour.
What did it used to be?
Headline news.
I don't know.
I guess.
Is that what that stands for?
Because they give up on whatever this
format is.
Like country music,
television.
We're going to do fucking drag races
now.
We're going to have a bass fishing
competition.
What?
Wait a minute.
I thought you were guitar.
No,
no,
no.
I'm going to give josh wolfe a show.
But he's not a country guy.
Yeah.
Uh,
I've watched so much of that that all
see the same murder on the different
episodes,
like forensic files.
We'll do it and then I'll be watching
snap and I'll be like,
oh,
I saw this one on forensic files.
We'll get different reason.
They all have their own reenactment of
that because it's the new.
Because this topic,
it's like,
it's not their subject.
It's not like they wrote it.
Yeah.
They have to allow another guy to do
another recreation.
They probably cheat like gold,
like what'd you get some of your
footage?
Well,
they did that with.
I don't like the angle they,
yeah,
show the murder.
Like there's a really good one.
There's a really good one on,
I don't know what child part of the id
channel,
but uh,
see no evil and they go through like
with forensic files,
all they do is um,
they,
they work out who did the crime with
forensics,
but on this one they find out who did
the crime only using the security
footage.
And it's really creepy and really
interesting because like you'll see a
guy walk into the elevator and then
leave with a briefcase and shit or like
a suitcase and the bodies in there and
you're like,
oh,
it's really great because it's real
footage.
Yeah.
See no evil when you see a real body,
even if it's through a security camera,
so clubs somebody over the head and drag
them backwards.
Like,
whew,
that's a real body man.
Like what I don't understand is I like
heat of the moment.
Murderers.
I guess I can wrap my head around
because it's like you just got so mad at
the person and it happened,
but like to plan it and,
and think,
oh good,
I'm going to make 20 grand off this or
the for the life insurance and to think
you're not going to get caught is like
you're going to get caught.
Yeah.
People get caught,
but people are stupid as fuck.
Dude.
There's a lot of people out there that
lie so much that they don't have a
connection to reality.
Yeah.
They've severed their tether to reality
so they think they can bullshit people
all the time and they think that they
can sort of con artists people all the
time.
I knew a guy like that.
Brian kelly.
No,
I'm kidding.
I'm kidding with you.
I'm completely crazy.
This guy was a fake brazilian jujitsu
black belt.
What have been fake fake wasn't really a
brazilian jujitsu black belt.
Told everybody he was.
And this is the early days of brazilian
jiu jitsu black belt where there weren't
a lot of them,
so you could almost kind of get away
with it like people didn't know.
And then he said like,
oh,
it was like a japanese jujitsu brazilian
does.
I'm not really like a black belt.
Black belt.
Change his name,
I forget his real name was because he
got caught.
No,
no,
no.
Oh me a fake name.
And a fake brazilian name.
Be a pro
referral.
Tory close.
So he was friends with eddie and he was
banging this married chick and killed
her husband,
brought them to the gym and strangled
her.
Killed her,
killed him,
brother killed him.
So I say her,
I didn't say fake black belt.
He killed the fake black belt,
killed the husband of the wife that he
was banging and killed him and then got
caught and he tried to get this other
dude that I know that it's an mma
fighter to try to get him to kill him.
I Tried to offer them some money and he
was driving the dude's car round after
he killed him.
What a micron do.
Drove the dudes got seen driving the
guy's car in a small town after he
killed him.
Yeah.
So he's in jail now,
but he went to the woods and,
uh,
with,
a bag,
like a big ass fucking duffle bag and
told his friend,
hey man,
drop me off.
I'm gOing to a secret no rules.
Kuma tay karate tournament in the woods.
And his friend's like,
oh,
okay.
So this fucking dude goes into the
woods.
Okay.
WIth a bag,
with a bag that like you would fit a
trophy in uk.
Comes ouT of the woods the next day with
a trophy.
So he opens the bag,
pulls his fucking trophy out and says,
hey man,
I want this karate tournament in the
world.
Oh my god,
this guy is insane.
That's.
I mean,
he's literally,
he's in jail for being insane.
Yeah,
dude.
He went.
He could put a fucking trophy in the
bags.
Like no one's gonna suspect this to
totally gonna.
Forget about this.
That's one of those.
Yeah,
that's what it was like.
This is so crazy.
There's no,
no one's going to believe it.
Everyone's going to believe it because
why the fuck would I make it up?
He says,
drop me off in the woods,
bro.
Because secret karate in the woods.
This is back in the day.
like so.
What did You said in the early nineties?
And he just leaves that out in the
woods.
Probably camped paleo.
Maybe this trophy.
Just a bunch of all the noodles.
Can't wait to show this to my friend.
Oh,
it's a famous story.
Whoa,
I haven't heard that.
So check this out.
I was talking to this guy,
gerald,
my friend gerald,
who was the guy that wound up testifying
against him that he tried to pay him to
murder them.
I was talking to him about it on the
phone and the phone was being tapped.
So then the cops called me up and they
say,
hey,
what do you know about this?
And I was like,
I'll tell you everything,
I don't know shit.
But he'd already been arrested and it
was already like a thing where they're
going to trial,
but I'm like,
all I know is that he was a fake black
belt who lied about a lot of shit and
god at the time I didn't even know
whether or not he really killed the guy.
Right.
So full of shit.
If he told You that he killed his wife's
husband,
you'd be like,
yeah,
just like you won the karate kuma tay.
Just like you're a brazilian black belt.
It's so hard to tell with a guy like
that.
But then to do turned out to present,
I was like,
wow,
I'm pretty much never can somebody who
brings a trophy out of the woods.
I mean,
can you imagine the idea that you're
going to take this fucking duffle bag,
put a trophy inside of it and no one's
gonna notice when you jump back to the
duffle bags missed.
That's really funny.
It was this big map.
It's shaped like a trophy.
She the fucking fence,
like the rocky statue,
this fucking guy.
Wow.
But there was a lot of that back then.
Man.
There was a lot of fake martial artists.
It was like super common.
They still to this day,
they'll catch a guy who's a fake black
belt.
Yeah.
White belt,
like put a black belt on and go to a new
school and.
But he really doesn't know anything.
I can't go.
But you're going to get exposed.
Why would you do that?
In jujitsu?
Yes.
But in other martial arts?
No,
it's because they're mentally ill.
It's alwaYs because they're mentally
ill.
And this guy,
rafael torres actually had a fake fight.
He had a fixed fight.
I'm king of the cage with one of his
students.
So he actually had a professional mma
fight.
And you know how my friend eddie knew
that he was full of shit?
No,
any new associate because eddie taught
them this super complicated move called
the twister twister is eddie's signature
move and it's basically the guillotine
or the guillotine from wrestling with,
uh,
an added,
a couple of added twist in the way.
Secure as the finish.
Eddie has like a very specific way of
escripting the top of the head and also
locking down the opposite pharcyde leg.
So when he does it,
it's like a terrible position to be and
he's crushing your fucking neck,
you're getting all yanked up and it's
really rough.
It's really hard to deal with and it's
hard to pull off on people super hard to
pull off,
like to just even to set it up and then
to roll into it you have to be a,
you could get a brazilian jiu jitsu
black belt who's a high level black belt
and you could teach them how to do it
and you could probably pull it off on
someone just because you understand how
to move his body and the grappling
scenario.
But for a guy like him,
it wasn't really a black male was
really,
really clunky.
he went to Thailand and and fought in
some mma fighters.
That dude,
hey man,
one in Thailand.
I pulled off the twister and eddie hung
up the phone.
I was like,
why?
He's like,
what?
dude,
I think something's got to be full of
shit.
And he was high as fuck what we're
saying having this conversation.
He's like,
dude,
you can't.
You can't tell me he did.
I can't believe he did that and so I was
with eddie in the car when he confronted
him about being a fake black belt.
He confronted the three of you in the
car?
No,
eddie was on the phone.
Oh,
I was driving and eddie was right next
to me in the passenger seat and he was
confronting him about it and the guy,
the guy was like,
no,
I really am.
And Then like cut to six months later
the dudes in jail for murder.
It's crazy.
So here's him.
So by the way,
this is a fake name,
right?
Because real.
That's him.
Yep.
So the other dude was like his student.
So this is the fake fight.
Yeah,
this is a fake fight.
So he,
he organized this.
I mean this guy had gotten deep into the
world,
man.
How does it break?
I mean he had a few martial arts skills.
He wasn't totally unscheduled.
Right,
right,
right.
This is it.
Yeah.
So he's on the bottom here and this
dude's already tell that he's not,
but they're not really hurting each
other,
you know,
they're just like,
he's just pushing them.
It's really funny man.
Like these guys are acting here.
Like he hits him with a couple of
punches but not hard,
you know?
I mean this is like some pro Wrestling
shit.
So he takes him down steps over the leg
and the guy's punching them.
But I think these are nothing punches
man.
It's like nothing to this.
And this is,
you know,
for a fact this was.
Okay,
fine.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Everybody knows this is like,
they tried to make it what we would call
a hard shoot,
you know,
where you make it look real like pro
wrestling style.
So then he just drops down,
it gets out leg and he's tapping these
tap in like right away,
go,
go back up a little sick and see the
setup.
Because it's set up is like what?
Like here,
he just grabs it.
That is so bad.
It's so bad.
He's so high up on the knee that he
wouldn't even be putting pressure on the
knee because he's not controlling the
lower leg or the upper leg.
Rather.
He's pulling on the lower leg,
but watch that again,
like when he's pulling on the upper leg,
look at the gap.
Watch when he goes out.
You could tell he's not a black belt
doing no.
No.
Super sloppy.
Big,
big,
big giant gap and see where he's
yanking.
The dude's already tapping.
He doesn't have control of the upper leg
at all.
He's just pulling on the shin like
literally his ass is with the knee is in
his.
He's pulling on the shin,
which means you wouldn't be putting
pressure on the knee.
It's such horseshit and it's guys like,
oh my god.
He wrecked my knee.
It was a total fake fight.
Yeah,
so that guy went on to be a murderer.
I think he might be up for parole soon
or something.
Do it.
People are horribly murdered.
Somebody too.
That's the crazy thing.
People get out of jail for murder to go
to jail for murder and you're in the
back by the way.
No,
that's a new one.
That's what males got to.
It's got to now,
bro.
That one he did on tv.
Oh,
crazy man.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
I mean,
people have pulled off some sloppy ass
knee bars.
Don't get me wrong,
but I know for a fact.
That's fact.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Dude.
Not people do,
but that's the real nutty things like
people trying to concoct an artificial
identity.
Like my dad's brazilian,
my name is damien monroe.
People are just as people are just so
afraid of being nothing.
You know what I mean?
Is that it or does he identify with a
half Brazilian,
brazilian jiu jitsu black belt?
Maybe we let them just with.
How much different is that than identify
with being a six year old girl?
It's only Different when you get your
ass kicked.
Well,
if you're a six year old girl and you go
to school with my kid and it turns out
you're 50,
I might beat your ass.
I'm going to be a black belt.
I might not trust you.
Maybe I might start asking you some
questions like he has adopted mommy and
do you see that?
Yes,
I saw that.
Yeah.
I'm just trying to think.
We're getting trolled.
Maybe trying to think.
That's not even real.
It's just everything's a south park
episode now.
That's what it feels like.
It feels like it's right in itself.
It does.
Who'd you vote?
Do you vote?
No,
I honestly couldn't do it.
Couldn't do it.
Yeah.
I'm hoping to.
Al franken runs saying they're here
right now.
Really you think?
I think al franken can be the best
president we've ever had.
I really do.
I think he's gotten tremendous ethics
and he's a comedian.
That will be amazing if is a true
patriot.
really is that guy.
Can.
You know al frankin can draw the United
States and draw all the boundarIes for
all the states by by memory.
He actually can draw the outlines of
each state.
All 50 of them.
I've never seen him do that.
No,
that's crazy.
Pull it up.
There's a video of it.
It's fucking amazing.
He walks up to a whiteboard and just
draws the United States and the right
shape,
like he could be a match.
If he was living in the 15 hundreds,
you will be.
He'd be the guy,
he'd be the most famous guy in the world
to be the map maker.
I would maybe be able to do califorNia
and that's it.
I think I could get the line right.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
The inside line.
Watch them do this.
This is beautiful.
Go full screen.
It's crazy.
Well,
that's already crazy,
dude.
He's amazing.
He draws the great lakes in the right
size and shape and he does this all By
hand seat because a lot of people think
of al franken as you know,
he was a comedian and he's on saturday
night live people.
Uh,
I don't think they truly appreciate his,
his intellect.
He's a brilliaNt guy,
but he's also to self deprecating and
too wise,
too humble to want to be the president.
He just doesN't have that desire in him.
That's such a shame because to be a
president,
like you almost have to be the type of
person who would never.
Who should never be president in order
to run?
Yeah,
yeah,
I hear that.
But like if he wanted to be the
president,
I think he could be like our best
president ever.
Who the fuck else could do this?
You want to talk about patriotism?
It's fucking guy.
Really.
that would be a good thing to run on.
It'd be like,
I could draw the pitch.
Hey Donald Trump draw.
But that's crazy though.
What?
He must have practiced this or he's got
to have a crazy mind.
That's just like.
That's what I'm saying,
man.
He just drew Alaska son.
Now he comes Hawaii.
Get the fuck outta here.
Are you crazy?
back that up to the 2009,
Minnesota state fair.
First of all,
he loses points.
We're going to the Minnesota state fair.
That's amazing.
Yeah,
but also my views is that if I was to
have a billion but it probably has a
million,
2 million,
$300,000,
that's more than one video.
I'm doing this to.
He it,
it doesn't like a lot.
Oh,
so it's a lot of tricks.
Cool parlor trick and he gets pushed
here for that.
Probably drives it all up,
but then this one is on me to draw
America.
I have to go,
oh,
he's doing this one on a piece of
cardboard.
Oh,
you could do it on any surface.
Crazy,
bro.
I wonder if he does it on the sidewalk
with chalk.
Can you do it in the sand?
And that would be.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's amazing.
We definitely need a better president.
You know,
we definitely need something new.
This,
uh,
this system we've got going on right
now,
just everybody hates each other.
So that's a bad thing.
It's terrible.
Everybody on the left and everybody in
the right,
everybody's at each other's throats.
I used to think it was the right that
was the dangerous,
but now the left is so they're so mad
and shit and they're responding to the
right.
It goes this way.
And then it goes that way.
You know,
people get super fucking angry when
obama's,
the president as the right you have to
worry about and then try it comes the
president.
Everybody gets super aggressive on the
left.
What's interesting is they said that gun
sales go up when a democratic president,
because they get scared.
People get scared.
They're going to take your guns.
What's crazy,
as trump was a lifelong democrat,
I know life long democrat,
but if anybody's ever had like the back
of gun owners,
oh,
trump above all a lot because his sons
sons are hunters,
especially donald jr.
Big time sportsmen.
Conservationists very much into animals
hunts a lot.
Like legitimately he's,
he's,
you know,
like a respected hunter.
But uh,
the um,
the doesn't shock me that people buy
more guns,
but I guess I didn't think of it like
that.
And then once I heard,
I was like,
yeah,
that makes sense.
If that's the big fear that people have
is that one day the government's going
to step in and they're going to take
your guns away and they're going to
control you with an iron fist and tell
you what to do.
And people say,
no way.
That's never gonna happen.
But I'm not advocating everybody go out
and get a gun.
But if you say,
that could never happen,
what's happening right now with people?
If you go to North Korea,
it's happened.
Right.
Okay.
How's it?
How's that going on?
Right now?
In 2017.
First of all,
you don't have an armed population.
You don't.
You know,
you don't have a free press.
There's a lot of factors,
right?
Yeah.
But the government could take it over
anyway.
The problem with saying that is we are
the government,
so if you say the government can take
over the United States of America with
soldiers,
those soldiers are citizens.
They might be soldiers,
but there are people that like you and
I,
they're not global.
Gotcha.
Yeah.
Not one percenters who own a,
like it's going to be very fucking hard.
Right.
Some young guy from Kentucky to pull a
gun on his neighbors because in America,
dickhead in a suit that,
you know as a senator or whatever the
fuck it is,
tells them what to do.
There's just a fine line of control that
you have some really good.
When you say the military will take over
the country,
the military is us.
They're just regular people.
Right?
Right.
It's when they get to the highest levels
of government that gets weird when
they're completely set,
when they were in a war room and they've
never actually been in a war and making
politically based decisions,
that's when shit gets squirrely.
It's the network as the executive
network executives because getting a guy
to do that though,
like getting.
Especially in America,
I mean this is not North Korea,
man.
We we have a way different attitude
about each other and about human beings.
It would be incredibly difficult to get
some regular kid from northern
California to join the military.
I just shut down schools and take away
people's guns in a door to door raid.
I guess I just always feel that people
are such followers that it would happen,
but yeah,
you're probably fuck it.
Hope you're right.
People are followers until some shit
goes down and if some shit goes down,
people will rise to the occasion like
that.
That is what happened after september 11
when they woke up a sleeping lion and
people were excited about going to war
again.
It gets real dangerous when something
happens because people love like there's
a great book that I just read from,
I'm sebastian younger,
it's called tribe and it's all about
bonding during war time and now people
are losing their connection to each
other by not encountering difficulty and
not struggling and that he lives in a
poor neighborhood.
This guy's like a super world famous
writer and he lives in a poor
neighborhood and the lower east side
because he likes being around like
regular people.
I mean,
his books are very successful.
I got to imagine he makes a good living
and he's a very famous war journalists
and correspondent and just,
uh,
he's,
he's got.
It's his idea is that the,
the people that live soft lives and the
people that like,
your body's on designed for it.
It's not good.
It's not healthy and that's why people
feel like shit and that the happier
people are the people that are under
stress and that if something did happen
to us,
we would probably feel better.
And really they say,
yeah,
they say that their guy more likely to
kill himself as the businessman who was
on the top floor,
that fucking lost it all.
Then the guy who just kinda has had a
rough life because it did not deal with
it.
There was this bernie made off episode
of radiolab,
radiolab where he's talking to this guy
and this guy made like a.
I think he made like $9,000,000,000
with bernie.
And he had a gift.
He had a giveaway,
gives 7 billion of it back and burning
was trying to get him.
Not bernie sanders.
Bernie madoff.
Say bernie sanders.
I was thinking bernie sanders for some
reason.
I think he fucked his name up.
Anyway,
I'm bernie madoff was telling this guy
that he had to give the money back.
You know what you did right now.
We were in this were caught.
We've got to give this money back.
And the guy killed himself.
So he's got 2 billion.
He's like not enough.
What they found on the bottom of the
pool,
$2,000,000,000,
not enough wonder if it was the shame
that made him kill himself.
A clang.
Clang.
Shay,
that'll make you kill yourself,
man.
Well,
I think if you have $9,000,000,000
and you're a guy that is just constantly
obsessed with money,
you're probably bawling,
bawling,
out of control and maxed out across the
board.
You probably got multiple ferrari's on
their way to you right now.
I need a bigger jet,
you know?
Oh,
how much the island.
I'll take it,
right?
You have 9 billion and then you're like,
you say,
okay,
I got an I need to make 300 million a
year just to pay my bill.
Right?
Imagine let me scale back,
and then all of a sudden someone says,
hey man,
you got to give seven of it back.
Like,
I don't have it.
I don't have to be how it was.
Well,
I think the shame too,
dot maybe Just died of a heart attack.
Maybe I didn't fell in the pool.
yeah,
that's a tough way to kill yourself.
Jump in and start breathing through.
They need to make this a fucking
forensic files episode,
man.
We'll find it.
We'll get it.
Probably exists on the hallmark channel.
Probably does.
Yeah,
so he's like a some study ex spouse,
right?
Sometimes a woman.
Yeah.
Well they have that show for that.
They have like sinful woman or whatever
the hell it's called.
They call it a scorned.
Good.
Get wives are.
You know what I mean?
It's always.
Yeah.
When,
when is it going to happen?
I'm one of those reality shows like
those real housewives.
When is one of those bitches?
Someone ax murder one of those other
chicks.
I mean it will happen.
How has it not already?
They fight.
They claw each other.
Right.
I fucking hate that.
That's a show.
Even Just so they're so popular.
I know.
It's crazy.
A friend of mine went to a,
just one of the real housewives ladies
has a restaurant in beverly hills in
front of mine.
Went to the restaurant and she said that
when the ladY walked in that everybody
treated her like royalty.
WHen she's here,
she's here,
she's here so crazy just walking in with
their dog and you're famous for being a
piece of shit.
I mean you,
you,
you are though.
like they,
they glorify at least in my show.
I'm not saying the person actually,
but like yeah,
those people are a piece of shit.
Yeah.
You piece of shit and they're like,
oh that's.
But she wasn't on the show.
That's one of the things.
She was like one of the more good one
side.
Sure.
Yeah.
I mean I don't know much.
I don't know enough about the shit I'm
being.
It's just bizarre that you would have so
much money and still want to expose
yourself to that because like the amount
of nuttiness and hate,
but maybe It's just more exciting than
whatever else they're doing and maybe
when you're on xanax it's not so bad.
Maybe just pop a few xanax every day.
Cameras are going off.
You don't even seizure.
Yeah.
Anybody ever sees you from the
paparazzi?
Find google pop razzi causes someone to
seizure.
Guaranteed.
It's happened a lot of flashes.
If for some maybe wacky dude was screw
loose and then started spasming to
famous,
we would've heard about it.
Right.
But if it was a famous person,
who would you imagine like johnny depp?
Like he does coke everyday for a month
and then,
or like the cameras go off and it's just
whatever the fucking fine wire in that
field is in his brain,
blows out like an old light bulb.
You find something.
And the only person I could find is a
david beckham's son.
Oh,
the 10 year old kid.
And he started freaking out.
So we just freaked out.
But he didn't have a seizure.
Did he?
Well,
I don't know if it led to nashville
seizure.
It says,
uh,
he says he's got epilepsy.
Leave him alone.
Oh,
he does have epilepsy?
Yeah.
Might be what?
Find out google that why two flashing
lights cause people to have seizures.
Hmm.
What do you think?
Crystal?
You know,
but I think that I would never think
about that in my life.
You wouldn't think about that because it
would never affect me.
So I'd be interested in how the human
mind works and the flaws of the
operating system.
I am a little bit.
Not that much though.
Huh?
Well I want you to tell me,
but I don't want to have to look it up.
It says it's from epilepsy.com
for about three percent of people with
epilepsy.
Exposure of flashing lights as certain
intensities.
Slow.
Yeah.
So it's not even.
I didn't know that.
Well that makes sense because I would
have heard of it.
Right.
You think you would have heard of it,
but for my friend it was his wife.
He's got the thing to you remember?
Shit.
I don't remember shit.
So I'm just gonna forget this anyway.
Which sucks.
You don't remember.
Definitely shopping mall from when I
was.
That's what I'm saying.
I can't believe you remember that.
That's ridiculous.
That's really impressive.
If you're out there boys.
Thanks for having me in your basement.
It was cool to think that maybe their
fucking incubus now you have no idea.
You know what mean?
I don't think so.
Yeah.
They're probably not around anymore.
Du du du du,
du,
du du du du.
I think chris,
leah,
check down traffic.
He's like,
it's fucking 4:00.
Broken lives in the fucking suburbs.
It wasn't as hard as I thought.
Did it?
Yeah.
You gotta stick to the roads still the
muellers ways.
That's the way it's the best.
Oh,
that's the boob you drive to some weird
neighborhood.
It's people are so pissed.
People that never had any new
neighborhood.
It's be.
How does it not catch on more dude?
Because people don't talk about it that
much.
And chris lee a check though.
I check out too bad.
Sometimes.
Podcasts or where you got to?
It's a sustained.
I can do like an hour and a half.
We're like two and a half hours in now.
Wow.
Really?
Well,
that was quick though too.
We're friends.
Chad was the last time we did two years
ago.
The first one we may be even more.
We've become good friends.
We see each other all the time.
Yeah,
we're colleagues.
We're out there in the battlefield,
the pedal field of jokes.
It's so cool to do the fucking comedy
store man and like to be.
I just,
I trY to think about like,
I'm so fortunate to be a part of that
like ever since you came back and like,
you know,
it's just so and it was always cool,
but like I loved the club always and I
think you did too,
you know,
always.
But then like you came back and then
like other guys kept,
other guys came up and they,
they,
you know,
they let.
It's also eric and adam too.
Yeah,
they're.
Yeah.
Eric and adam,
they've changed the atmosphere of the
place.
It's now super comedian friendly and
supportive.
It's just,
it's different place.
Crazy how great it is now.
Yeah,
and everybody enjoys it too.
Like everybody,
like we look at each other,
we're like,
whoa,
know,
you know,
it could have been born in Afghanistan,
could have been living in the middle of
the mountains somewhere in Nepal.
We without sucking go tits,
trying to get some moisture.
We could've been all.
We all could have been trying to win
trophies in the forest.
Men win Trophies in the roads,
in the forest,
the coma,
no rules come back.
Hands are perfect.
No cuts,
empty duffel bag maybe rubs on his face.
I want dude killed them all on the first
round.
Everybody did.
Something gets seven year old would come
up with,
hey,
this is what I'll do.
I'm going to get a trophy.
I want to write deadliest man the world
and I'm going to put that trophy and a
duffel bag.
Then I'm going to go gently expand in
the world around the world.
I never forget when I was first starting
to take martial arts.
There's this kid who came to my high
school and he's with this girl and uh,
the girl was like really pretty and she
didn't talk much.
Yeah,
she was like in my class and he wasn't
like,
he was from like another school and uh,
he had a Jean jacket on.
He looked like fucking billy jack.
This guy was like real skinny and like,
why are we looking at.
And someone sAid he did karate.
I did karate and he was smoking a
cigarette and I remember he had a.
He had someone hold their hand up so he
could demonstrate as moves in front of
everybody.
Everybody scared and he did it inside
crescent kick swag swag.
That guy's hand and there,
but it's like,
ooh,
that's the real shit.
That's the real shit.
I'll never forget that.
I remember thinking that guy was
watching them going,
I think that guy's full of shit,
but I didn't know anything back then.
It was now here.
Oh,
100 percent.
Oh he was.
Now it'd be laughing,
but I looked in it back then.
I was like,
something wrong.
I think that guy just knows how throw
his leg in the.
I don't know if it's a real kick.
It was something that bad.
I was like,
that is not a real kick.
You could just lie man,
and just.
I'm a fucking,
you know,
pilot.
The way he drew it,
it was like,
it was so stupid.
His leg fucking went up in the air.
It just was so ineffective in a real
life scenario.
Not that the crescent kick doesn't work,
it's just the way he did it.
Something my brain read,
but I didn't know anything back then.
You can remember I told you about that
book.
Gift of fear.
Yeah.
About how you can send shit like that
and then you know,
you know what,
even though you don't know.
You know what?
That's blink malcolm gladwell's blink,
blink st,
but blink malcolm gladwell's book thing
about that.
Got it.
yeah.
Just read it.
It's um,
it's all essentially about how there's
certain things where you know
immediately.
Yeah,
yeah.
I just finished the audio but we're
conditioned to cover it up and be like,
no,
that's not right.
But it's like,
that's why you talked to all these women
and they were like,
I knew something was wrong before,
you know what I mean?
Yeah,
yeah.
A lot of times you know something.
And there's one great story in the book
where they were talking about this
statue that was this incredible ancient
roman stat from roland or ancient greek.
I forget which one,
but um,
it was a forgery and,
but it was perfect,
like the way it looked,
it was amazing,
but they brought in front of these art
collectors and they looked at it for a
second and went,
this is not,
this is not good,
is not good.
ThIs is fake.
Like the immediately there was something
about it,
like they had done testing on the
surface of it and know what,
what it was.
They knew,
they felt it.
They knew that the stone came from a
certain part of the world is ancient
part of the world that was ancient stone
by the amount of some sort of a mineral.
While on the outside of it they realized
that it had been sitting in the ground
for thousands of years.
They thought turned out bullshit.
They just do.
There's a method that they use to create
this artificial surface.
And the whole thing was a fraud.
It was all fake and they,
you know,
they put it in like famous museums and
shit.
It's a fascinating story.
But the art experts,
just whatever the fuck it was,
they just knew immediately and they
called bullshit on it when all these
other people had already signed off on
it and even paid for it and even asked
one of the experts asked,
can you get your money back?
Oh,
well now like what?
Blink,
huh?
Yeah,
I definitely would like to read that.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
It's really interesting about split
second judgements,
like weird things that you make.
Like you think you know something they
ever tell you the counts story.
But this one,
one of the craziest girls you ever
dated?
I don't think so.
I meet calvin at the ones that place the
irish pub pub that was onsite dublin's
dublin's taste to stand up.
I meet carolyn at dublin's and he's
like,
I want you to meet this girl I'm dating.
He brings a girl over.
The girl says hi to me.
I look at her and I go,
come here.
And I pull them aside and go,
dude,
listen to me.
She's fucking crazy trainer.
And he's like,
what?
I go,
she's crazy.
He goes,
how do you know?
I go,
I know.
I know crazy.
You gotta listen to me.
I go,
that's a fucking insane person.
That's a dangerous person.
Yeah.
Nah man,
she's cool.
She just gets nervous around you.
Cut too.
She's doing math.
She's a prostitute.
She has a pimp.
He finds her like,
like after a breakup he runs into her
street walking she street walking.
He sees her in front of the coach and
horses walking the street.
She's like,
lowest level of prostitute you can get.
Right.
How did he not come on time,
but yeah,
that it's that first,
that first reaction,
whatever the fuck it is.
That guy that never done that before.
I've never done that ever.
I've never looked at someone really said
to my friend.
That girl's fucking.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's a bit of a stretch because with
callan,
almost every girl he dated was nuts
until he met his wife.
There were all out of there.
It collins off to me about how he's
like,
you gotta meet my friend.
Yeah.
And I'm like,
oh cool.
Like four times I did it and then I'm
like,
like a fucking.
LiTerally at like a turtle will show up
and I'll be like,
you know a turtle.
He's too nice.
Yeah,
fucking counting.
Just likes everybody.
Oh my buddy.
And now you fucking texted me all the
time because buddy's crazy math.
It's trying to get you in the olympics.
I'm like,
I'm working out too hard for this shit.
I don't like stretching.
Oh,
that's my favorite blink story though.
I knew someThing about it.
I'm like,
what?
I just looked at him like,
oh,
this is not good.
Yeah.
I believe in that shit for sure.
Especially with women.
Women's intuition,
but haven't you been called?
I've been fooled before that rough tour.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah,
of course.
Let's see with him.
But in this,
in the book a gift of fear,
they say that like you always knew
somehow though.
Yeah.
But I think you always think that when
shit goes wrong.
True retrospect.
You're like,
god damn fucking.
No,
no.
I knew it.
Didn't follow my instincts.
Could be some fill in the blank.
Bullshit.
Speaking of fill in the blank.
If you're looking for something to do
tonight.
Chris delea is new.
Netflix special.
That's how you should do your podcast,
man.
Shit.
Do just a bunch of random plugs out of
nowhere.
It is.
It's on netflix.
Is this your second or third one on
netflix?
Special.
Second one on neTflix.
What was the other one comes centrally.
Centrally?
Yeah.
Netflix don't take over the game.
I did my first one on comedy central and
it was,
it was still.
That was still the place to be.
Yeah.
And then my second one I was like,
I'll do it on netflix and now it's just
like,
you're pretty prolific too.
Like when did you do your first one?
I was 33 and then that's no 31.
Uh,
so four Years ago.
So 2013?
No.
So what wIll be my last one came out in
2014.
Oh,
okay.
And then my,
the one before that came out when I was
31.
So 2012.
Yeah,
I did kinda to back to back.
Right.
And then my agent was like,
I was like,
I want to do.
I wanted to do this one last year.
And he was like,
my agent was like,
how many specialists do you want to do?
And I was like,
that's a really good point.
I'll wait.
That's not a good point.
fire fucking agent.
Listen,
listen,
fuck face.
You tell me what I'm working in toledo.
Don't tell me he wasn't telling me what
to do,
but I was like,
he was making you as bitch.
That's what I think.
I'm his bitch.
Well,
the way I feel about dalea is he says
agent,
he's the dude is fucking hilarious.
He's a great guy.
But he is his age.
They were.
What's a collar on him just to keep them
in when,
when he goes to his office and the puts
it,
call him.
He's asked me,
we want a glass of water.
It gives them a bowl bowl on the ground.
Right christa?
Thanks,
mom.
It's on.
Thank you.
And you have your own podcast.
Me about your old school.
Congratulations.
And I really like doing it.
It's a perfect name for your.
It's fun.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's a good one for me.
It's a good graduation.
She retarded.
That's a good one.
So yeah.
And that's available on itunes,
stitcher,
google play on youtube.
Alright ladies and gentlemen,
that's it.
We'll wrap this up.
Bring this bitch home tomorrow.
Uh,
Youngest ever ufc heavyweight champion.
And mY good friend josh barnett will be
here and we'll see you soon.
Bye.