Who did you do to?
To
another episode of the Richard Jeni Fan
club?
He's.
He's a guy that I've been telling
forever is probably the most underrated
standup in the history of standup.
I think he's one of the all time greats.
Henry's got a body of work because he
did a one hour back before everybody was
doing one hour specials every year.
He was doing that shit back in the
nineties.
Oh yeah,
on showtime.
Like when I was just starting out,
so I think it was like 89 or 90
somewhere around the one.
He had a showtime special.
Yeah.
And then he had a male.
Yep.
He had a bunch of hbo specials,
but the last one that he did before he
died in 2007.
That is his masterpiece.
Yeah.
It's called a steaming pile of me and I
was listening to it one night coming
home from a club and just laughing out
loud in the car and clapping,
clapping,
and I'm like,
God damn.
This guy was good.
Yeah.
What a good.
I mean he was one of those guys that
dressed.
He put on a sharp outfit,
pleated pants,
you know,
really fucking Corny,
like nineties looking,
you know,
call it the collar with the rounded
priest collared shirts.
Well he was from Bensonhurst.
Oh,
is that right?
Yeah,
yeah.
It's the old school mentality from
Brooklyn.
Yeah.
And he would,
uh,
he would give you lot.
I can remember like at least three
times.
He would call me an hour after my set
and give me taglines to bits.
Wow.
Yeah.
And they were fucking good.
He was almost like on the spectrum with
the.
Yeah,
totally.
He wouldn't look you in the eye.
He'd be like looking down and go really
fast and talk with his hands.
And uh,
and he,
I think he obviously,
if people don't know Richard,
Jeni sadly committed suicide in the end.
And what was tough for him was that he
was that good and he never really broke
through.
He had a sitcom short lifts Sitcom
called platypus.
Man.
That was on like one of those a upn
eventually.
And after that it was like he was the
guy who used to fill up his book in
January,
you know,
he was,
he was on the road 45 weeks a year and
you know,
making 100 grand on corporate dates,
50 grand on corporate dates with,
you know,
15 of those a year.
Yeah.
I'm sure he was living well but,
but he felt like a failure.
Yeah.
And to us he was a hero.
Like I remember seeing him in east side
Comedy Club in New York and um,
it was me and Joey Cola and a couple
other guys.
I only saw one set,
but um,
God,
I forget who the host was,
but the host said he did didn't.
Different hour all four shows.
Shit,
what?
I was so humbled because I was like,
I don't even have.
I had 20 minutes back then it was like,
what,
how did he do that?
How can you do that?
And they were like,
he's the best.
He's a.
But it was a weird thing.
It's like
he came along before Netflix because if
he was around today and people got to
see his netflix special.
Yeah.
It's just one of those things that would
have caught on.
Right.
But in the hbo specials,
you either home when it aired or you
weren't,
you know,
there was no dvrs back then.
Maybe maybe set up the vhs tape to
record maybe.
Yeah.
I could never figure out how to fucking
get that thing to record when I wasn't
there.
Oh No.
I could tell them now the time or you,
you'd end up recording like days of our
lives or something and golden girls,
potential twats being written.
There's a bunch of old women in the
scripts are written by old Jewish guys.
Oh,
you know,
I just saw menopause joke.
He said one of the saddest cases to me
because I just don't think that.
I don't know like how many friends he
had,
like in comedy.
I know he's really good friends with
Chris Rock and he worked with Chris a
lot.
Like he was like a punch up guy for
Chris a lot,
but I don't,
I don't,
you know,
I don't know if anybody was there to
just be as.
I think that's a big thing for us
because we're so like,
I think comics are some of the weirdest
fucking people.
Yeah.
But I gravitate towards them.
Like I've always said if I run into a
comic at the airport,
I'm like,
oh look,
it's one of us,
you know.
It's just weird.
It's a weird job where weird people were
all crazy.
I've never met one of us that isn't
crazy.
And I think sometimes we need each other
to go.
Yeah.
It's all right.
You're right.
Everybody loves you,
man.
Like,
yeah,
going to the comedy store for me is
definitely like a therapy session I
feel.
And it's partly,
it's that you're performing and you're
getting the positive feedback and part
of it is that you're running into
people.
And I mean it could be anybody,
it could be a,
an Asian female comic,
it could be fat,
can be Don Barris,
like the spectrum of different types.
But like you said,
there's something that,
there's a thread that runs through all
of it,
which is like this,
this feeling that like mma,
we're going to get in the ring.
We are,
we are going to face an audience at some
point that night and there's a charge to
that.
Like there's a fear.
I don't care who the fuck you are.
You can deny you're afraid when you go
on stage every but it's in there
somewhere.
We've just gotten so good at dealing
with it that it doesn't show and
sometimes we're not even aware of it.
And if it's not there,
that means you're probably not taking
any chances.
Right.
That's not good.
Then you'll have that doll thing going
on stage and then you'll bomb.
And then you'll really have fear when
you're doing jokes that you think are
killer and they've just eaten plates a
ship up there because you don't have
anything left in you.
Yeah.
Like last night,
it's just murderer's row man.
I'm walking in and fucking Bobby Lee's
crushing and then Chris Delea is
crushing and then I go up and Thiel,
vons crushing,
and then it's fucking Ian Edwards smash.
And that's like,
yeah,
good Lord with a lineup and you're
hugging everybody.
I'm hugging barris.
I see him a hug Whitney Cummings.
I see how
everybody's just like.
It's just this big comradery place.
Yeah.
We're so lucky
here.
We survived.
You know,
and there's so many guys that I came up,
you know,
we came up with guys that I would have.
I was competitive when I started out and
these guys I had bad blood with and I
see this guys now and they're like my
brothers because we went through it
together.
Yeah,
I know the competitive thing.
I've talked about that.
Like I had to give that up.
I had that when I was a kid when I was
21 ish because it was still leftover
from the martial arts days,
martial arts competition.
Then like I would want people to do bad
and then I realized that God is so
stupid,
like that has zero effect on me.
Like when they're up there,
if they're doing good,
that'll just make me better.
It would just make me work harder.
Yeah.
But if they do bad,
like I was like that's the thing that
some comedians do.
They will take a terrible comment on the
road with them so they can look like a
hero.
It's a common thing,
right?
It's called stacking the deck.
Look,
they'll stack the deck.
They'll have like just some torturous
act for half an hour and then they go up
and look like a monster.
Yeah.
And that's not the way to do it,
I don't think.
I think the way to do is the opposite.
Just have a bunch of murderers on in
front of you and have fun with it.
Yeah.
And everybody have fun.
I think that you.
I love,
I mean there's,
I don't like going on you layer.
There's like one or two guys that I just
don't like going on after and,
and,
but in general,
why don't you like going on after
deleted?
I just feel like he's so physical and
big and that doesn't really.
It shouldn't affect me,
but I just feel like when he gets off
the crowd is just like in this mode of
like euphoria and it's Kinda like,
all right,
I'm going to,
I'm going to take it down a couple
notches and just talk.
And I feel like sometimes that's my
weakness that I can adjust to that.
Joey Diaz,
same thing.
Oh,
it's just like the room is just,
they got to put their socks back on and
you're up there and I,
and I'm writing dry shit.
I'm trying to be a little ironic and
they're just looking at me like,
you're small,
you're insignificant.
You're,
you know,
in all your insecurity.
Start coming out sometimes.
And I've beaten that like you,
you come up in New York and you can't be
like that because you go on after a
towel and Louis and whoever.
And so I came to terms with,
with trying to realizing that you don't
ride the wave,
you let the wave settle and you start
your own way.
And,
and I would make that mistake early on
is I'd come up then and I jack up my
energy and I,
and it wasn't me and then it would
falter.
Yeah,
that is,
that is true.
You have to bring the audience to you.
Yeah.
And of the best place to learn how to do
that as the Olr right now because first
of all,
you really,
you only have 15 minutes and there's all
these other guys that have 15 minutes to
and they go on these rides.
So everybody's going on a new ride,
like,
okay,
just got done with magic
mountain or space mountain.
Now we're going to go on this ride.
And it's a small world.
Oh,
small world.
Slower.
He settled down.
It's not as crazy.
We're all the lights.
You got to settle in.
Yeah.
It's a great fucking place for just just
figuring it out and working on your
shit.
I'm in this weird place right now with
my act where I'm getting ready to film a
special.
I'm hyper examining.
Yeah,
everything going over everything with a
fine tooth comb.
But the problem with that is you go over
everything too much and then it starts
getting real blurry looking at what is
this?
Yeah.
And you start landing.
I find that I start landing on the
punchlines too hard instead of talking
it out instead of like being like the
more ideal at the more.
I know,
all right,
this is where they laugh and I sort of.
And there's sort of lucky I stick it too
much instead of flowing.
And so when,
when you do the special,
it's almost like you got to take,
take a little time off before you do it.
There's a number of sets you do where
you're,
you're in the groove and it's tight and
everything feels good.
And then there's a number that you do
too much and everything gets kind of
flat.
Yeah.
You've got to find that right.
What is that?
No one,
if they have that,
another thing.
So like if that's a must be the case
with bands right when they toured,
they must get so sick of fucking singing
the same song over and over and over and
over again.
I mean,
I saw the beach boys recently and uh,
they fucking love it.
They love being up there,
you know,
you can see it,
you can feel it,
you know,
I think it goes to another level.
I think it becomes a communication with
the fans,
with bands that we don't necessarily
have the same thing.
It's like for them areas,
a very communal experience that's
happening.
And with us it's more like,
we're going to dominate you for an hour.
Right?
We're going to take control of this
room.
You're going to listen to everything we
say.
We're going to bring you up,
take you down.
It's salt,
you bring you back in.
You know,
crowd worked is like a whole thing,
but it's all being orchestrated by you.
Yeah.
Another thing we were talking about
about traveling to places like the
further you go,
the harder it is to get there,
the more happy they are.
Right?
That's a,
that's an interesting phenomenon.
Like if you could do,
like I was saying that Ari and I did a
Gig in Anchorage,
Alaska a few years back.
Fucking amazing.
Yeah.
Get up there and this weird town,
you know,
and the coolest fucking people.
There've been anchorage now,
Dude.
Crazy.
We've got up there and uh,
I'm expecting,
I'm going to see people covering for and
everything's going to be covered in snow
and the rod dog sleds everywhere and
shit that they were so normal,
uh,
drove by this group of people holding up
signs.
Said Honk for diversity.
Have Nosha like they're holding rainbow
flags up and shit.
Do they have diversity?
Yeah.
No Shit.
It's,
I mean,
it's a real city.
it's small.
Yeah.
How many people you think live in
Anchorage?
If you had to?
20,000.
I'm going to go with 50,
50 people.
Yeah.
No,
50,000.
300,000.
No Shit.
Wow.
Shit.
That's huge.
Yeah.
That's three times the size of boulder.
That's really big houses in Juneau.
I remember I was in Juno and there was a
burger king and I was like,
what the fuck is a burger king doing in
the middle of Alaska?
And then they were bald eagles going
through the dumpster and picking a
fucking big MACs
is a symbol of America right here.
That's the first time I've ever seen
that.
You go live.
Was it Alaska?
There's a weird animal look at.
I know it's a weird animal to pick for
your bird to like start national animal.
Yeah.
Ruthless fucking evil raptor.
That comes out of the sky at a nowhere
kills.
Oh yeah.
You know,
they say that there was an eagle at one
point in time that they think was
preying on early humans.
No Shit.
No.
They think that there's been some giant
raptors in the past and they found some
old primate bones,
some old ancient ancestors of human
beings that had what looked like claw
marks on their skulls.
Their brains had been picked out of
their skull and caught out.
Yeah.
There was an eagle like that and it's
New Zealand was called the Haast Eagle
was an enormous ego in New Zealand,
like way bigger than any of the eagles
that we have alive today.
I think it might have jack to few
people.
Wow.
Well,
Colorado,
I'm sure when you lived out there people
you can't leave your dog outside.
No,
my dog had eaten there now.
No Shit.
Yeah,
I had a bit about it in my act.
No Shit.
My little dog.
What kind of dog was it?
He was,
um,
a Pomeranian American eskimo mix.
That's a decent sized dog that he was
real little.
He was like this big.
It was like maybe 30 pounds.
Tiny little guy.
Yeah,
he got Jack.
Did you see him get ya know?
But we saw the cat hanging around the
property.
We saw the cat in the area and then
there was,
there was definitely evidence that
something had gone down.
Yeah,
no,
fuck yeah,
it happens all the time.
One of the things that they found in
California is because California has a
lot of mountain lions that live on the
outskirts of cities.
They purposely hanging around the
outskirts of cities and come into town
at night and eat people's dogs and cats
and they found that when they examined
the contents,
they expected it to be way more like
rabbits and deer and shit like that.
But it was half domestic house cats and
dogs.
Yeah.
Half of their diet because they're easy.
The fatted calf.
Well also they can just jump over
everything.
I mean,
any fence,
you have that group over it,
grab your dog and they're so powerful
they can take your dog over the top of
the fence.
Right?
Fucking nuts.
Shit.
No.
I came home one day and there was a
possum in the driveway.
And the Cro,
you know,
fucking.
Are they ravens?
Are Crows in la?
Those giant black birds.
That's a good question.
I don't know what the differences,
because I said they were crows and my
friend's like,
no,
those are ravens and they're,
they're big.
I mean there are good two feet long and
it was on top of a possum and it was
fucking picking it apart.
And the thing was alive.
The possum was alive.
Yeah.
Really?
And so I,
uh,
so I tried to scare this,
this a blackbird away and he looked at
me like I'm not going anywhere.
I got to fucking possum here.
And so I got a broom and I like pushed
him away.
He took off.
Yeah,
he let you get that close.
You could touch.
Oh yeah,
he wasn't leaving the possum.
Whoa.
And then he,
uh,
he stood like 12 feet away and I got a
shoe box and I put the PA submitted.
But the possums,
they hiss at you,
they open their mouths,
they just go like this and they got
vicious teeth.
You've got to be really careful with
them.
But I got it in the shoe box and I
called animal services and they came and
got it.
We'll get you out there saving.
That's right.
I love possums.
Do you think for them?
Yeah,
they're cute as shit.
I love him and they just so mysterious.
You know,
they come out at night and like where
are they hiding them?
The day one of them used to sleep and I
had some shrubs on the side of my lawn
and it was,
you could,
if you looked inside,
you could see him hanging upside down.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's right.
They hang.
Yeah.
What a fucked up animal I now,
have you ever seen a quad a Monday?
Never even heard of it.
A quad a Monday is a an animal that's in
South America and a friend of mine was
telling me he ran into one or I was
listening to his podcast.
Rather he ran into one of them in
Arizona and that it looks like a bear
fucked a monkey and it looks like half
bear,
half mcgee.
Leave that thing.
No Shit.
Cool thing and it's a climber,
dad,
dude.
Well they're big.
They're like 40 pounds and they're
predatory and he was making noises.
He was deer hunting and this thing came
running out of the woods.
He was trying to call it by making like
a wounded animal.
Sounds like
this thing.
I can't run it out of the out of the
grass looking at him.
Look at that thing.
We just fucking crazy little animal go
wolverine.
I didn't even know that existed.
I had no idea that thing existed.
I mean it does look like it's a member
of the Badger family and look at its
face,
but then it has a tail,
like a big crazy long tail
teeth look like a,
like a rang of tank teeth.
The way they curve in like sharp,
I didn't even know that was a real
thing.
Apparently it's,
there's a lot of them in South America
and then in the United States they are
expanding their range in Arizona.
Wow.
Yeah.
The way you spell it is c o a t I m u n
d I,
quantum Monday.
Isn't that a Spanish speaking channel?
It was actually coming up like that.
Kuda Monday.
Oh,
interesting.
Yeah.
But people spell it with a C in America.
I went with the phonetic spelling,
that type of thing actually with Acu.
And this is what came up was the key.
Interesting.
A,
um,
I think what,
uh,
what,
how is it spelled in another one if you
scrolled down that one we just looked at
it.
I think you spelled with a c.
yeah,
I think that's how you spell it.
Cla.
Yeah,
whatever.
It's awesome.
And people apparently the game and fish
department in Arizona,
they get calls all the time where people
like there's a monkey running around in
the woods.
I saw a monkey,
but it's that thing that,
that could just be a racist.
Call it Arizona is this weird place.
Arizona is a incredibly interesting and
its climate,
right?
Like you've got desert and then you have
like some of the craziest forest.
You have all kinds of weird shit.
They're like,
oh,
incredibly diverse wildlife population
in Arizona.
Yeah,
right.
They gas birds,
birds and deer and elk and all kinds of
weird shit.
Crazy.
Like you're in the middle of Phoenix and
you got this fucking giant cliffs
sticking right up in the middle of the
city.
Great hiking.
I did that one time there.
They have an influx of Jaguars now.
Oh,
there's a quantum Monday wars.
Yes.
They're moving in from Mexico.
Look at that fucker.
Things says they make good pets too,
apparently.
Really as you can train them.
Whoa.
Hold those fucking teeth.
At first.
I'm pretty sure we saw one of those in
Costa Rica and my daughters were calling
it a Kinkajou.
They made up a name for it,
but he was just hanging out near this
resort in Costa Rico.
Yeah.
Look,
it is a little fuckers just chilling.
They got long tongues,
so are there any editors too?
I bet.
I bet they fucking eat everything.
Yeah,
I mean it's hard out there.
Look at him.
Just know.
Oh my God.
The guy's patting it.
That is crazy.
These are wild.
Oh,
okay.
That's a resort.
See,
that's Kinda like what I experienced in
Costa Rica.
These things would just combine.
Hang out.
What a cool looking fucking animal that
guys belly did not yet as in front of A.
Yeah.
South America.
It's,
it's crazy how like if you've gone to
south,
have you ever gone to South America now?
Oh yeah.
Chili,
the wildlife there.
It's just incredible.
Costa Rica has all these different kinds
of Costa Rica.
They have howler monkeys.
Right?
Those other small.
Yeah.
We had a howler monkeys.
Right?
It was like a one because it's the rain
forest and we had a one mile like path
that went around the house that we're
renting and yet these howler monkeys
would go right above.
You scream.
No fear.
It was fucking dogs everywhere.
We had like two dogs that just work.
They must have come with the house.
They were just there and you feed them
and they follow you everywhere.
Oh Wow.
And then you drive up and there's a,
the black river,
I think it's called and it's right on
the border of Nicaragua and uh,
they've
got those Caymans,
you know,
this little alligators and you take a
boat through these like waterways and I
mean it is filthy with came and they're
fucking everywhere.
Wow.
It was so scary.
And we were,
we were just like
paddle.
And through them they have real
crocodiles in Costa Rica,
they have those big ass crocodiles.
We would do that.
Yeah.
We went on a tour and they take on a
boat and they take you like pretty close
to these things.
But I'm freaking the fuck out.
I'm like,
one of my kids falls overboard.
They're dead.
Right.
And you're just on this little boat,
you know?
And these,
these people are so relaxed about like
safety and she isn't so not Disneyland.
You Go.
Did you go to the middle part?
Like Lake rnl with went to a couple of
different spots,
but we went up to the rain forest and
did the zip line,
which is a mile long.
And I'm like,
Ooh,
fuck is checking this.
Who's making sure that this is the
stability of this line is intact.
All right?
And then they had this,
they have this volcano that's in,
um,
I forget they will.
Lake Lake area is the area and they've
got these,
uh,
this hot springs and there was like 14
pools that went up a hill and you could,
you could swim in each one.
And the bottom was like cold and the top
one was so hot,
it was practically boiling so you could
just kind of work your way up into each
one.
And then,
uh,
and then these,
you know,
this woman comes up to me and she goes,
you want a massage?
And I was like,
yeah.
So we go out to this little,
like a,
it's off to the side and there's like a
little their sheets around a bed and I'm
laying there and I'm like,
this is fucking great,
you know.
And then all of a sudden I hear my
mother's voice and she had gotten
solicit and she was getting a massage
like six inches from me.
And I'm stark naked getting rubbed by
this beautiful Costa Rican woman.
And I could hear my mother who doesn't
stop talking for the entire.
They're thick bronx accent.
So how long you been here for you from
here?
That's a relaxation crusher.
Yes.
We just want to just melt into the rain
forest and rubbed on down through that
little horseshoe with your face in it
and look at those little Costa Rican
feet.
Brown rounded little toes.
Oh,
that's so weird.
Massages are fucking weird,
man.
Yeah,
it's weird.
I mean it's obviously there's,
there's a physical aspect to it,
like you want your muscles to be
manipulated because it's very good for
them and you get loose some kinks in a
lot of like weird stuff that's not
adopt.
But there's also the pleasure aspect of
it's pleasurable,
right?
Like it feels good to have someone touch
you.
Oh my God.
I mean your skin is your biggest organ.
And they talk about emotionally and
psychically what it means to have skin
to skin contact.
And for an hour somebody is devoting
their skin to your skin.
I mean,
think about you have sex with your wife.
You're touching for,
you know,
15,
20 minutes.
One part of you little groping you cry,
but to have a sensual touch like that
know for an hour.
Yeah,
and also like the energy that you must
get.
Like when you're a person who's doing
that all day,
like you're putting out a lot of energy,
you're getting energy from those people.
Like some people must feel weird.
Yeah,
I've talked.
I've talked to who say that they have to
discharge energy after a massage.
They do in.
These are more like touchy feely kind of
misuses.
Quinsy told people.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That one that she,
she would put crystals in my belly
button.
Oh.
And then my arm would be down and she
would hold my arm and tell me to raise
my arm to see what the pressure was and
then she could tell by that which herbal
remedies I needed for my allergies,
Jesus Christ,
to so many of these people out so
fucking crazy.
And then it works.
And you're like,
what the fuck it worked.
I guess you can believe anything.
How did it work?
I,
she gave me allergies.
So these herbs,
because I was like,
just fucking sneezing nonstop and I stop
sneezing and you know what that,
that,
um,
that would he homeopath,
they take like a barrel of distilled
water and then they'll put in like a
mint leaf and like a couple other herbs
and then they just take the bottle and
they fill it with that water and that's,
that's homeopathic remedy.
Most of them are like that.
Did that diluted?
Yeah.
A lot of it's bullshit.
Like I remember somebody gave me Arnica
once.
What's that?
It's like some little little pills.
They're little tiny,
tiny little,
almost little little things that
dissolve in your mouth.
Oh yeah,
right.
It's like sugar,
right?
I go,
this is sugar.
And someone's like,
Nah,
the sugar in it.
I go,
well,
why is there sugar in it?
It's supposed to be medicine.
Sugar's not good for you.
What the fuck is this?
And it was homeopathic or some sort of
homeopathic remedy.
I'm like,
okay,
do I have to believe this stuff works
for it to work?
Because one of those things,
because that's a real thing,
right?
You know?
Well,
what do you say to people who don't
think that vitamins are helpful?
Well,
that's silly.
There's a lot of studies that show the
vitamins are healthy.
What does a lot of studies that say
they're not?
Yeah,
not really.
I mean too much.
Vitamins was excessive.
Vitamins doesn't make any sense,
but the studies that show that vitamins
are beneficial.
They're pretty specific.
There's pretty specific in terms of like
if you get your blood work done,
right.
For instance,
and you are short a lot of people short
of vitamin D dot vitamin D is a big one.
Vitamin B is also a big one.
Bb Twelve,
which is the one you get from the sun,
that's d two.
D three is a good one too and that one's
good for muscle development and a lot of
other functions.
There's a lot of shit that vitamins are
good for.
Fish oil is fantastic.
It's very good for reducing
inflammation.
There's a lot of supplements that are
100 percent legit,
but there's a lot of doctors that don't
know anything about nutrition and it'll
tell you all you need is a balanced
meal,
a balanced meal.
Well,
if you had a balanced meal,
kind of,
yeah,
if you really made sure that you ate a
certain portion of vegetables,
green leafy dark vegetables that have a
lot of vitamins,
and if you made sure that you have the
right amount of protein and fruit.
Yeah,
fruit,
some,
some fruit.
You're not a proponent of eating too
much fruit or identity.
Tell me like a sugar in it.
Like juices.
Most juices are too high in sugar.
If you drink a big glass of orange
juice,
your body has a really hard time
differentiating that between a big glass
of soda or fucking high c or some shit
like that.
It's like if it has 30 grams of sugar,
it has 30 grams of sugar and that's what
it is.
It's 30 grams of sugar.
The fact that it's coming out of an
orange,
that's great,
but you're not supposed to drink it like
that and the orange is supposed to be
something you eat when you eat it.
You get all the fiber,
your body breaks it down slower.
You're just getting this fucking
mainline a sugar right into your system.
I drink a glass or like if I go and I
have breakfast with a big glass of
orange juice,
I fucking crashed.
Hard like an hour later.
Yeah,
it's a little insulin dump.
Well,
they just did it.
I just read yesterday that there's this
study now that losing weight is not
about caloric intake.
It's all about sugar and processed
foods.
Crazy.
Yeah.
No.
Could they say the amounts don't matter?
You can.
You can eat way more than you think you
can.
As long as you're reading the right
shit.
Will weightwatchers have completely
changed the way they recommend food,
like eggs or zero points.
Now,
Joey,
Joey Diaz and Brian Redmond.
Brian red beds onto.
He was telling me that eggs are zero
point zero.
You can eat as many eggs as you want.
You can eat five eggs.
Yeah.
People used to say,
well,
eggs have cholesterol and hello.
This is terrible for you for fats and
all this.
Nope.
Fucking great for you.
Sorry.
We will live forever.
I was fucking reading to my kids a
little while back.
We had a Dr Seuss book and it had the
food pyramid and I go,
this food prayer was bullshit.
Like,
what is this?
It's all fucking.
The bottom of it is all cereal.
Yeah.
It's all like cereal and bread.
That's like the most important thing.
What are you to have the zero point
foods on the.
Never list.
Boneless skinless chicken breast,
boneless,
skinless Turkey breast ground,
lean chicken ground,
lean Turkey,
thin sliced deli chicken,
bro.
So it's all fish and shellfish.
Wow.
Does not include smoked or dried fish?
Huh?
Why wouldn't include smoked fish?
That seems weird.
Can fish this packed in water or brined?
I eat canned tuna to food or smoke to
this.
We're all like zero.
Nonfat Plain Regular and Greek yogurt.
Nonfat ain't good for you.
Nonfat anything is nonsense.
Eggs,
plain soy yogurt,
milk,
fresh frozen and canned beans and
lentils that are packed without oil or
sugar.
Yeah.
Beans and lentils are huge.
If you could just eat all that stuff on.
Mikado is not on there.
I guess it's got some fat in it.
Well,
it's got healthy fats,
right?
Avocados.
Unusual because it has mostly
unsaturated fats,
but it has saturated fats too.
Yeah,
it's really good for you.
Avocado is a fucking wonderful food.
Wonderful.
I'm 155 pounds,
but I had a fucking belly just because,
uh,
you know,
I was writing on crashing last year and
they would have,
we'd have like five meals a day,
muffins being handed out and I put on
six pounds and it always in my belly
breads and process shit.
And so January first I cut out all
bread,
all pasta,
all sugar,
and I've been working out like five days
a week and the belly just fucking
disappear.
You seem like you've got some pep in
your step.
A little bit,
little bit,
little bit extra Ritalin also helps.
Does it a lot of coffee.
Do you ever get your hormones checked?
No.
You probably should see if the
testosterone levels there.
Yeah.
You know,
that's a major factor in depression.
No Shit.
Major factor.
A major factor in people with head
injuries.
Yeah.
People that have come back from war that
have been,
um,
you know,
like a lot of ied has been around,
a lot of explosions been jolted,
a lot of football players,
of course,
boxers,
MMA fighters,
they lose testosterone as they get
older,
get pituitary damage.
Your pituitary gland apparently is
incredibly sensitive and some people get
it that are jet skiers or into jet
skiing because just the
right all that bouncing and head banging
his head banging his fucking terrible
for you.
Play soccer and he heads these,
the goal,
you'll kick the ball all the way down
the field and I'll see him headed.
I'll be like,
dude,
just let it fucking bounce.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's heavy impacts.
It is in a soccer players get it a lot.
He got a concussion from heading against
another guy wants.
He was out for three weeks.
They collided heads.
Yeah.
Oh God,
yeah.
Your fucking head.
It's so hard.
It's like running into another,
like a rock,
like a bone.
Yeah.
Someone could beat you to death with a
head
and you're whipping your head.
You're whipping your head at the ball.
So like both slamming into each other.
Oh yeah.
I played hockey my whole life though and
never had any major involvement.
My neck,
I chipped a vertebrae in my neck.
That was the only thing that happened.
You do that?
My,
I was small but I was a good skater
because I grew up near a lake.
So we just skated back before global
warming.
That lake froze at Christmas and it went
till March.
We were out there every fucking day.
Afterschool,
all weekend.
All we did was play ice hockey.
So when I got to high school,
um,
I was,
I was the only kid who could really
skate backwards.
Well.
So the coach was like,
you're on defense.
I'm like,
I'm a hundred and 15 pounds.
So he taught me how to check of usually
check with
your shoulder,
your hip.
He taught me how to check guys under the
Chin with the top of my head,
which I,
which I got good at.
And then I did it one time and just
click and it.
And I had,
I got a,
I got an extra and they're like,
yeah,
that's,
that's chipped.
It's nothing we can do about it.
To this day,
my,
my tendons will get caught in my neck on
that chip and it will just lock up like
once a year,
lock up for a couple days on me,
like the tendons rub against that area.
It's tendons or ligaments or whatever is
right there around.
You're a vertebrae.
Fuck the next dude.
Yeah.
Terrible.
Terrible thing to injure you.
Are there good exercises for neck?
You don't have a thing called the iron
neck.
Have you ever heard of him now?
Oh,
that's fucking amazing.
It's out there.
I'll show it to you after the show.
It's a halo.
I've put it on my head and then I pump
it up with air and the air locks in
place and there's a giant Bungee cord
that's on the end of it and I pull it
back and the bungee cord is a 50 pound
resistance,
but they make it lower.
They make like several different weights
of Bungee.
You pull it back to.
It's like fully polled and then you can
adjust the resistance on the halo itself
and so you do these like as you got to
pull it back,
you turn
turn sideways and I do look 10 reps this
way.
It'll do sideways that way and that'll
turn all the way behind and face the
opposite direction and do 10.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
And then you do stevie wonder's where
you do this,
you do a bunch of different exercises.
Magic and a girls suck your Dick with
that thing on
what?
She would wear it.
She would wear it and then you wouldn't
be good because her record would be in
the way you run the cord between your
legs
and then you put your penis in her
mouth,
but your Dick is going to rub up against
the court.
I don't understand why you want to do
that.
That's the thing like that.
Oh,
I see.
I got two of those.
I bought one for my house to a fucking.
Love it.
Wow.
I love it.
It's so for Jujitsu,
it's so important.
My neck fucked up in Jujitsu where I
was,
um,
I was getting numb hands.
I had a bulging disc in my neck and I
just,
I think a lot of it came down to my neck
just getting just too much abuse and not
being strong enough.
Yeah.
No.
So,
so I love that thing.
Yeah.
That's why I've never done Jujitsu.
I've wanted to,
but I know my neck would get fucked up
immediately.
Everything gets fucked up,
but it's fun.
Yeah,
it's awesome.
It's like your body's not going to make
it.
Yeah.
It's like how much abuse do you want to
give it before it breaks?
Totally.
A good question.
You know,
I mean,
Anthony Bordain that fucking savage,
58 years old starts doing Jujitsu.
Start it.
Started.
No shit started.
Wow.
He's a bad ass because he been on the
show.
Yeah.
Long time ago.
So we always talk about doing it again.
But yeah,
he travels so fucking much everywhere.
Literally everywhere.
I love that show.
I,
when I'm on the road at sometimes CNN
will run a marathon and he shows I'll
just sit there and watch everyone.
Even when he's in the US,
it's always interesting.
He finds like he'll find a pocket of
Cajun
people that have like a 78 people in the
family and they make this special kind
of jumbled Leia.
Yeah.
He's,
he's,
he found his thing.
Yeah.
He really did find his thing.
Was he a musician before?
What did he do?
So chef,
who's the chef,
he's a chef and he wrote a book called
kitchen confidential is really good
book.
And then after the book became
successful,
he started doing a show on the travel
channel.
I think it might've even been called
kitchen kitchen confidential.
Then did another show that was called no
reservations.
That's where I met him.
I met him when he was still doing no
reservation,
so that's when he did.
He did my show back when he was doing in
my house.
And then,
uh,
I did his show.
I did it recently too.
I did it recently in Montana.
We went pheasant hunting.
No Shit.
Yeah,
it was pretty cool.
Oh Wow.
Yeah,
it was awesome.
Did he ever run into drugs?
He was a serious heroin addict.
That's what I thought.
Yeah,
but he kicked the heroin and still
drink.
Still drinks.
I know.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
Well he's,
I mean he figured out how to do it.
Yeah.
But he works out every day.
Yeah,
the trains every day.
I mean he brings his Jujitsu ski with
him everywhere he goes.
He goes on the road,
like when we were in Montana,
he went to,
um,
we were outside of Bozeman I think
somewhere outside of Bozeman.
So he found a Jujitsu club in Bozeman
and met them and just went there and
trained with them during the day.
I was like,
you're a fucking animal.
No,
she's addicted to it.
He goes to like,
he was in Croatia,
you told me it was in like,
I forget where it was,
but some Asia type place.
Some Serbia is one of them fucking
Albania with one of them crazy places.
And he said he was shitting out bone
chips because these guys were just
smashing them.
And I was like,
dude,
fucking doing that.
They were old school crossing Gracie,
top control guys and they're fucking
crushing him.
And he's like,
dude,
I'm shitting bone chips.
I'm like doing of yourself.
That's amazing.
But he's like,
he's at an age where a lot of people
would,
they would back off,
they would think,
oh my body is frail.
I'm going to ride this off into the
sunset.
It's like,
fuck you.
Well all exercise is really sub
sublimating pain on some level.
I mean even even a light jog,
you are in pain and so you don't have to
do it.
I think you're doing it wrong.
Oh,
I'm always in pain.
I feel like when I jog I feel like I
feel afraid.
I'm gonna die.
And I think when people see me jogging,
they think I'm running from something.
Like I'm scared.
Like that's the panic on my face.
What hurts my back.
I think the next settled into my back
and I have slight scoliosis.
So,
um,
and then my,
my wrists and ankles for some reason
about a year ago started to get sore.
Like I can't do pushups anymore.
I had to buy those,
those grips that you put on the ground
because I couldn't,
I can't put my hands flat.
What part hurts the whole wrist?
The whole.
All the ligaments in the wrist hurt.
Hmm.
And they hurt.
Does it?
An overuse thing?
I'd get hurt from now because it's both
of them.
I don't know what I could have been
doing with both of them.
Have you tried doing it since you cut
bread and everything out of your diet?
I think it probably is better.
It is better.
I bet it is.
Yeah.
That was the first thing a therapist
told me.
Physical therapist.
She got not a mental therapist.
Like cut bread out.
Yeah.
You got mental problems.
I'm no,
a physical therapist told me she was
like,
you'd be surprised if you cut bread out
of your diet.
Just inflammation.
Inflammation.
How much your back would feel better and
feel better.
I thought it was 100 percent horseshit.
I was like,
oh,
this is like hippie chiropractor.
Talk.
Good luck.
Yeah.
And then I did it and I was like,
oh.
Like everything feels better.
You don't realize it.
Like that puffy feeling that you get in
your face though.
I get,
I get fat face if I,
uh,
if I eat too much bread and pasta,
I get,
you know,
you start getting a little gut,
but that's also in your joints,
man.
That's everywhere.
Everything's inflamed.
So it's all like not good.
Your body's like,
what is this shit and how do we get rid
of this?
It's fucking hard on the road not to eat
bread dough.
It's so hard to find a meal.
It doesn't have bread and unless you
want to eat like,
you know,
some,
some salad from starbucks,
so uninspired salad and it was made by
somebody with a hair net that was also
making like stale,
stale tasting muffins.
They come out of the oven,
they're already stale tasting.
I was at a starbucks recently and there
was a played out with,
you know,
they put the muffin pieces while you're
waiting.
And so I,
I eat more than I should,
you know,
you should probably just have one I
think is the protocol.
And I have like three of them.
And uh,
this woman comes up,
she goes,
why are you eating my muffin?
It was hers.
I go,
I'm so sorry,
let me buy you another muffin.
And,
and instead of going,
Nah,
don't worry about.
She was like,
yeah.
So I bought her another muffin and she
wasn't really like laughing about it or
anything.
She was.
Yeah,
yeah.
You were saying that.
I was like,
I don't know that they do that.
Oh fuck yeah.
Fuck off coffee shops.
Starbucks.
Yeah.
But why was there a muffin chopped up
into little pieces that seems weird to.
I was crummy.
It was kind of pulled apart crummy.
Hmm.
Yeah.
Okay.
Seems Weird.
Have you ever,
um,
gone to Katz Deli in New York shore?
Remember when the Ludlow Stromae for
you?
Yeah.
And the corn beef and they give you a
little bit and you're like,
Holy Shit.
Like while you're waiting,
they chop it up and slide it forward and
best Pastrami in the city.
Yeah,
we just looked it up the other day.
That place started out in the 18
hundreds.
No Shit.
Yeah.
Wow.
Largo was a half a block away,
so if you stand up there and I always
stop and get a pastrami sandwich.
There was a a no Luna Lounge.
He was.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
There's no place like that here except
canter's cancers.
All right.
It's
a,
you know,
I,
I find their astronomy's just doesn't
have that.
That tenderness that you get Second
Avenue Deli in New York.
Never been.
That's the best.
That is the best.
Yeah.
I think.
I think cancers is good.
I think it's the best in La.
I do too.
I just don't think it's that good.
Well,
he just not gonna it's hard to get those
immigrants to come all the way across
and settle in and be successful out here
and have like a real spot.
Right.
But there's a lot of Jewish people out
here.
You'd think there'd be more like Jerry's
Deli is good.
Middle of the road.
Yeah.
They have good chicken noodle soup.
Right.
But they don't have.
It's like there's a difference between a
real Italian restaurant in New York City
and an Italian restaurant in studio
city.
Yeah.
Right.
Just fucking different.
Yeah.
There's just no getting around it.
If you want to survive and like I needed
just to survive.
You can have linguine with clams at some
nice place to studio city,
but it won't be the same.
Yeah.
Now that place car a car.
Mine's.
What's our.
Our tourists.
There's a place on Mulberry Street that
was the oldest Italian restaurant in New
Year in a little Italy and it just
burned down.
Dude,
I remember when you lived in little
Italy in a mob owned building.
Yeah.
Tony and gladys
from my landlords.
That's right.
And they had a.
they'd had the apartment.
They raised their kids there and they
were like,
they were like in their late seventies
and so they,
their,
their son Gregory who was in
construction and lived in directly or
quotes in construction and so he bought
them a condo around the corner because
it was a,
it was a six floor walk up and so one
free.
You can pull it up on the screen.
One 42.
Mulberry.
Explain to people that don't know what
that means.
That means you walk up six flights of
stairs,
couches and shit.
Yeah,
right,
right.
Well,
they're all,
their furniture was there when I got
there,
they let me keep and it was,
I'm not making this up,
plastic on the furniture and I found,
uh,
I found,
an ease of phone eavesdropping thing
like where you could record phone calls
in the drawer and um,
they deiced to pay them the rent once a
month,
not by check.
They wanted cash and it was George
Mcdonald live with me and we would walk
down this end and Lauren debraski would
walk down the street to Spring Street,
go to their condo and we'd give them,
if it was $600,
we'd give that to gladys and Tony look
at it,
right?
Yeah,
there we go.
And they would make cappuccinos and
Canelo lease.
We'd sit there and talk to them and then
Tony would go in the next room and we
give gladys another 150 [inaudible].
That was her bingo money.
And Tony don't need to know about that.
Oh,
that.
that's right.
Yeah.
And uh,
they were having a Lauren Dubroski she
passed away.
No cancer.
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah.
She ended up as a big executive producer
at mad tv for like 10 years.
Really?
Yeah.
You know Bobby Lee,
she,
she sponsored a lot of people to get
sober.
I mean,
you,
I know a half a dozen people that she
sponsored to get sober.
Bobby Lee is one of them.
She was,
she was a comedy team with.
Yeah,
a couple of,
couple of broads.
I don't remember what their name was.
Who was the,
I think it was called a couple of broad.
uh,
the other one was uh.
Oh,
is there.
Fuck.
Rick Jenkins used to date her.
Yes.
And she ended up doing a film.
She moved out to Hollywood to make it
and uh,
about a year and a half later this
softcore porn came up with her in it and
she had the sickest body smoking and
that was a vhs tape to kept passed
around.
That was greasy.
Covered in DNA.
Yeah.
Um,
but lauren was a really sweet,
special person.
She was great.
She's a very nice person.
Yeah,
that's right.
I forgot that she passed away.
I never ran into.
I ran into her once out here a long time
ago.
More than 15,
16 years ago.
Yeah.
There is those comics that are that like
Colin Quinn is.
One of them were just.
They have saved so many comics in
trouble.
It's amazing.
How's he?
Oh yeah,
a great guy.
Yeah.
He helped,
uh,
well tried to help Geraldo.
I shouldn't name people's names if it's
program stuff,
but a,
well,
some people are open about it.
Yeah.
I think all comics are,
becomes a part of your fucking back.
Right?
Right.
And who,
who,
who gets sober and doesn't start talking
about it.
Yeah.
That's like Jesus Christ.
Why wouldn't you mind that?
I think a lot of comics start in a
rooms.
They get up and they,
you know,
they qualify,
which is when you speak in a room and
they go,
oh yeah.
Remember Dave,
right dave out fucking one great joke of
remember this one great joke that he had
about being in Catholic school and he
did something wrong and the priest
smacked him in the head and he goes,
which is exactly how I think Jesus would
have handled it.
And she,
this method of delivery,
you know,
he was just a funny guy.
Like he was one of those guys that you
saw him on stage.
You Go,
oh,
this guy's got to be funny.
Oh,
I mean it's,
it's amazing.
Some people that the deck is loaded,
you walk on stage.
He's had this gravelly voice and this
big square head.
And he just said yes,
as soon as that thick.
I think he was from East Boston,
that thick accent.
And He,
when he was a fucking mailman,
he was like a real blue collar guy and a
lifetime of stories.
Yeah.
He's a guy who became a pro real quick.
Yes.
I remember like being real impressed
with him because he was like a little
bit ahead of me.
I was,
I was starting out as an open mic or,
and he was real maybe a year ahead and
he was starting to get work and I'm
like,
this guy fucking took it seriously.
Yeah,
because he was older.
I think he was 40 when he was getting
started and so he
had his notebook and he was like really
organized with his bets and he had like
some philosophy about like why he would,
why would take a pause and why he would
rush this part where he would take that
part and I was like,
this guy's putting a lot of thought and
effort into.
I remember going down to see Paula
poundstone perform at the comedy
connection and he was the feature act
and he went up and as the feature got a
standing ovation.
I was like,
Holy Shit.
That doesn't happen.
No,
he was good.
He got sick.
He got sick and died as well.
Yeah,
right.
I think this is just a lifetime of drugs
and alcohol just caught up to him
unfortunately.
Right when he was right when he was,
you know,
getting his shit together.
Right,
right.
There was so many of those guys.
I mean,
how many guys did we start out with that
were alcoholics or former alcoholics?
Yeah.
Fucking everybody.
All of them.
Yeah.
And they're all.
And that was the thing about when you
were an open or a Boston,
it was like the criteria.
Where are you funny enough to cover 15
minutes to open number two,
do you have a functioning automobile
that you can take these dui headliners
to the Gig with?
Because none of them had licenses.
And so I can remember like picking up
Gavin Pickin up sweetie,
picking up Mike Mcdonald and having to
drive these guys out to wherever.
And then you couldn't leave early
because you were driving them home.
They'd give you a few bucks for gas and
you were happy to do it.
You're like,
Holy Shit,
I'm going to be in a car with don.
And so one time nick's next stop calling
me up and they're like,
you're working in Framingham.
You get to drive the feature and the
headliner out.
And I go downtown to pick them up in
front of Nick's.
And I've got a uh,
I had a 1976 Volkswagen Rabbit,
four cylinder,
rusted out floor boards and I get down
there and it's Mike Sullivan,
Irwin who weighed about 300 pounds.
And John Pinette is about to 75 and they
saw my car and they both started
giggling like school girls.
We're going to fucking go to a Gig in
this car.
So we,
we pack them in and I couldn't get on.
I couldn't get the car go on above like
40.
So instead of taking the mass pike at
West to Framingham,
I had to take a route nine the whole
way.
Forty miles an hour.
Hilarious.
Like you carry lumber on the roof.
Fucking 800 pounds of humans in my car.
I remember Mike Sullivan,
but I remember when he was Mike
Sullivan,
they became like Sullivan Irvin.
He's the first guy that ever met that
took his wife's last name.
Is that why?
Yeah,
he was a feminist first male feminists.
Self proclaimed male feminists that
everyone too.
It's hilarious.
Very nice guy.
Yeah,
sweetheart.
Super Sweetheart Guy.
And uh,
that didn't work.
He stopped doing comedy,
right?
I think he died.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
It's a bummer.
It's a bummer of a podcast.
I think he died as well.
And John Pinette died as well as well,
you know.
Yeah.
That's why.
I'm glad you're doing cardio.
That's right.
Well,
you know,
I'm 51 and my dad died at 51 of a heart
attack,
so I take that shit seriously.
Eating right and exercising.
I mean he also smoked three and a half
packs a day and was an alcoholic.
So different,
different circumstances.
It is crazy
how much of that shit is genetic,
you know?
Yeah.
And I've always admired that.
You figured out when we were really
young.
I mean when I met you,
you quit and you know,
we were both in our early twenties and
you were like,
fuck this.
I'm not,
I'm not going down that road.
And you didn't need anything.
You didn't,
you didn't need alcoholics anonymous.
So you're like,
no,
not doing it.
I did some therapy.
That helps.
I just needed to realize that once I
realized that and I had gone to Alanon
because of my dad,
adult child of alcoholic meetings,
which helped me phenomenal amount just
to realize that,
um,
that it's a disease and that,
you know,
you're powerless to it.
And that for me,
I was able to apply what I learned in
there because I went to a couple of AA
meetings and in Boston it was like guys
would get up and they were like,
and then I blow a guy for a sandwich and
I passed out in the fucking and said,
you know,
it's like I couldn't relate.
I mean,
my thing was like,
I fucked a fat chick,
you know,
that was my bottom.
I had a three way with a couple girls
who were a plus net.
And so,
uh,
so I could,
but I,
I read the literature of the 12 steps
and it helped me because it made me
realize that when I wanted to drink
something was going on and to this day I
just have that reaction.
I know that I still want to drink all
the time,
but when I really want to drink I
stopped and I go,
alright,
what's stressing you out?
What do you need to deal with?
And then I just kind of focus on it.
No,
yeah,
there was,
um,
when I was a kid,
my,
my dad was an architect.
And so I worked on a lot of construction
sites and I met a lot of junkies,
a lot of junkies,
lot of people in construction sites are
either alcoholics or drug addicts.
And there was this one guy that I really
liked.
He's a funny guy,
man.
Really Funny Guy.
And he's in a band,
his name was Robbie.
Funny fucking dude.
Loved hanging around with them,
but just stay off the coke wow.
Couldn't stay off the coke and you could
totally tell he was.
And he would,
he'd be honest about it to see how he
went off the rails and you know,
and you know,
and he would,
we would be working together.
He was a carpenter and I was like,
uh,
labor.
So I was like an apprentice.
And so he'd be talking to me,
why?
Explain to me how to do things and stuff
like that.
And I was like,
yeah,
you know,
I'm just fucking tired of this.
I'm getting my shit together.
The bands getting back together again,
we're writing songs and this and that.
And then he'd come in Monday looking
like shit,
just looking like shit real grumpy.
Didn't want to talk,
had a headache and you know,
and he didn't get it,
went off the rails
May.
The saddest thing is that when you first
start doing drugs,
and I don't know about you,
but I,
I had a phenomenal time doing cocaine,
mushrooms and all this stuff I did as a
teenager was like beef.
I never got hooked on it and if you do
it,
you know,
maybe I did coke 50 times without ever
getting hooked.
It's a blast.
That's the,
that's the best kept secret.
But then once you get hooked,
you're not even having fun anymore.
You're just maintaining.
You're just feeding it so you don't
crash.
You know,
with,
with heroin,
you're just trying to avoid withdrawals.
You're not even feeling that great
anymore.
I think with Robbie to,
part of the problem was he was very
disappointed in himself.
Yeah,
know it was booze too.
He would just go off the rails and try
to keep it going.
You know,
it's like
there's a lot of people out there that
they have a dream and then the pressure
of trying to reach that dream,
like his dream is to be in a successful
band.
Right.
And the pressure of trying to reach that
dream and see it to fruition,
it's just seems it seems unreachable.
Yeah.
It seems too far off.
And here you are,
you're in your thirties and you're
working a construction job and you know,
you fucking work all day in Boston in
the winter.
You're tired as shit when you get home,
you don't want to go to band practice.
You get home at 6:30,
have dinner now it's 7:30.
You got to get up,
right?
You've got to get up in a few hours.
What are you doing?
When are you going to bed?
You know,
you've got to get up at six.
Then you got a band
practice and the drummer doesn't shell
up so you can't practice.
So our 45 minutes late,
his car breaks down and you're fucking
pissed and you're screaming at you.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And then try to have a relationship on
top of that.
Tell that girl you can't go out on
Saturday night ever because you're doing
gigs
and then the gigs suck and you're not
making any money.
And she should get a job.
The gigs.
You should get a job.
Yeah.
And then you're in a band.
So girls,
they've thrown themselves at you having
an affair.
She's got some coke.
No,
it's good.
No story turned around.
Turned it around.
Now it's exciting again.
Sometimes when I've worked at casino,
there will always be that band in the
lounge just playing like born to be wild
and all the songs and like you'll see
people that are like 57 dancing and you
see them in their dancing and it's like
they're just reliving the only joy they
had in their life,
which was like when they were young
dance in Iraq and this band is fucking
their gods.
To them
you the,
the time when you're young,
when you're having fun is so fleeting.
Yeah.
Then all of a sudden responsibility
stuck up and all of a sudden you know,
you have to pay bills,
you have obligations,
you have so much that you have to think
about.
Yeah.
For so many people,
there's just.
There's this period of their life where
they look back to whimsically like that
was the time when I was free.
I was young,
my Dick got hurt all the time.
I could go two or three times,
three times in a night like,
shit,
man,
I can't believe it.
And you think anything is possible.
I mean,
that's really can happen.
That's the loss of innocence is when you
realize that a certain point that you do
have to pick a path and stay on it,
you better [inaudible] you gotta pay the
bills with it and you know what's so sad
is you see people that work so fucking
hard for not a lot of money and you
know,
Bill's just add up and then they save
just enough when they get their vacation
twice a year,
the good like accrues and they'll just
drink nonstop for a week.
At the end of it,
they're just hung over.
They blew the excess money they had and
that was it.
That's what you worked all year for out
a friend of mine and working in
restaurant and uh,
one of the guys who worked with saved up
his money for eight years,
went to Vegas and ballooned in one day.
It was the most heartbreaking story.
This poor guy,
I think he was a dishwasher and he
worked there for eight years.
Set aside 50 here.
Twenty five.
They're set aside for eight fucking
years.
Yeah.
And I think it was some good amount of
money,
like $30,000.
She went there with a plan.
This is it baby.
I'm good at blackjack or whatever the
fuck he played.
He read a book.
A lot of guys read books.
You can win money,
you can win money playing blackjack,
but you know what's fucked up when you
do,
if you get good at it,
they ban you.
I know.
It's crazy was.
Yeah.
The other crazy thing is in black jack
there's there's like multitech and
they're single deck blackjack and the
payout on single deck is less instead of
three to two odds you get paid like,
I forget what it is,
but you get,
you get less of a payout when you hit
black Jack and the rules and more
restrictive about like splitting aces
and all that stuff.
So the implication is with a single deck
you can count cards.
That's why they pay you less,
but if you get caught counting cards,
you get thrown out of the casino,
the fuck.
Did they catch you counting cards and
isn't it normal that you are using
strategy to try to win the game like
crazy.
Like you can't try so hard,
right?
That's like if you're playing pool and
you aim the aim Ayman
or when they don't let you use drugs in
sports,
man,
they make you better.
They definitely make you better.
Why should we not have drugs in sports?
Well,
because were out of your body because
you don't want the children to get the
wrong message.
You're writing and drugs are the only
way to win.
Yeah.
I think that should be a supernaturally
and the natural league.
I like it.
Yeah.
Supernaturally is you just go get one of
them fucking Russian guys from that
Icarus documentary and you just.
What do you got,
baby?
Let's do this shit and you find out what
happens.
The problem is legitimately,
if you do go whole hog and take the
fucking full steroid route,
you're definitely redlining your body.
You're doing some shit to your body that
your endocrine system is gonna.
Shut down.
You're putting ungodly stress on all
sorts of parts of your body because the
workload that your body's putting out is
just super human.
But for those brief shining moments,
you can absolutely performed better on.
That's what it's about.
And as a viewer,
I want to see them run faster and hit
harder and jump higher and you know,
and honestly they're jocks.
This is what they were bred to do.
They are,
they are the jock class,
pe.
They did it their whole lives.
They've dreamed of the shining moment.
Let them have their shining moment.
Right?
But what about the natural athletes?
What about the Hershel Walker's out
there that don't need it?
All right.
Well,
they're in the other league.
for them they're like,
well,
you shouldn't be a fucking athlete and
know I need it.
Right.
Or I don't need it.
You need it.
Yeah.
But I always wondered about those guys
because they'd be honest that they don't
take it.
Like Hershel Walker look deep into his
forties,
was claiming that he never took anything
and uh,
that he only ate a bowl of soup and a
salad a day.
No,
shit doesn't make sense.
It didn't,
didn't his mother do the Campbell's soup
commercial.
I don't know.
The thing about Herschel though is that
he also has multiple personality
disorder or no shit.
I think he has um,
stress or trauma induced trauma induced
multiple personality disorder.
So it's entirely possible that when he
says,
I only took a bowl of soup and a salad,
he's telling the truth,
but that's him.
There's like five other people that live
inside his brain and they've been eating
steak all day steroids.
Right.
I don't know.
Fascinating.
I'm always the trauma.
Do you know?
Well,
I think he had a really rough childhood.
There was a lot of psychological abuse,
physical abuse,
and then there was football abuse.
I think all those things.
I mean there is no way you're getting
out of football for free.
You're getting fucking hit hard and
that's trauma.
So there's trauma,
psychological trauma.
I don't know.
He's talked about it pretty openly
though.
But what's interesting is even after all
that he still fought.
He fought.
A lot of people don't know.
He fought in strikeforce.
I didn't know that.
Pete the Fuck Addison people,
dude,
he's a legit martial artist.
Shit Dude.
He was in his forties like 46 to 48.
I believe he fought in strikeforce and
when I say he was jacked,
I mean Jack full six pack,
shredded 46 years old.
Just manhandling lesser athletes and
beating the fuck out of them in what you
Jitsu mma and he fought in strikeforce.
Strikeforce was a league that the UFC
one that purchasing and we took all
their fighters and it came over in.
A lot of guys like Gilbert Melendez
was champ over there.
Josh Thompson,
like real high level fighters,
Luke rockhold,
they all came over from strikeforce and
Herschel Walker was over there and it's
a lot of people like super skeptical.
Like,
what is this some freak show?
Herschel Walker is gonna fight.
Come on man.
Herschel Walker is an old football
player and then you see him.
You're like Jesus Freak athlete.
Just a freak of nature.
So you think he must've been using
steroids?
No,
no,
it's not.
Not.
Must have no need.
Definitely.
I mean always get suspicious when you
see someone who's a freak,
but there are real freaks.
Like just let John Holmes had a giant
Dick.
It didn't take steroids to have a giant
He just had a giant Dick.
Some girls have enormous tits.
Why?
Oh,
they just do like there's no,
there's no even body,
like there's no equality in physical
construction and some people just get
born with freak body parts.
Yeah.
And they just are.
There's,
there's athletes that are just way
better than you will ever be no matter
what you do.
Yeah.
I think Hershel Walker's unquestionably
one of those.
It's just how long did you maintain it?
I mean,
I watched the Olympics and I'm the
curling.
I love,
you know,
curling.
The thing is,
is it's not much to watch,
but I would pay a lot of money to just
fucking get high one day and curl.
Really?
How much out of money?
$50,000.
Housing dollars.
Thousand dollars to curl.
One day.
Why?
But I mean that's for all my friends,
it pays for the whole curling corey the
whole day.
Everybody get bored after like 10
minutes.
I don't know really.
I mean I love games like that.
Like I love a ladder ball,
you know,
where this like a two sticks and it's
got like a ladder that goes between it
and its got a ball with a rope between
the two balls and you whip it.
I can play that for upwards of three or
four hours.
We have it in the backyard three or four
hours nonstop.
I just get,
I get so competitive and so obsessed.
Uh,
horseshoes,
Botchy Ball,
horseshoes or fun?
Yeah.
I don't know man.
Just get into such a groove.
Like Pool,
right?
Yeah.
No,
I mean you and I have played pool for
three hours easily.
Oh yeah.
Easily.
We could have today,
if we didn't stop and do the podcast,
we probably would have kept going.
Well son is a good luck to Sam,
Ohio today.
And the soccer playoffs third round
undefeated this year.
Do you like watching soccer?
I love watching it,
but I love watching my son play.
There's few joys in the world like
watching my son play soccer.
It's crazy,
right?
A person who's out there running around.
Yeah,
I know.
And you just see.
Well,
because no matter how old your kid gets,
you still see them as a little kid and
then when you see them out there on the
field with these and you see the size of
the other guys and how aggressive they
are and you're like,
Holy Shit,
my little kid is in there holding his
own and he's a physical player and uh,
it's just uh,
and you know,
you get to know the parents and the kids
and it's like a whole,
it's like being a fan of a sport,
but you actually know the players.
Yeah.
Uh,
there's,
there's something,
I think that's incredibly important for
kids to learn how to compete and also
learn what it feels like to lose and
that bad feeling.
Yeah,
it was a lot of people that grew up and
they were never involved in competitive
sports.
They were never involved in any sort of
competitive games and they just don't
know what it's like to lose.
And I think that's a valuable lesson in
life to.
I think it teaches you a lot about
rejection from the opposite sex or the
same sex we are in that shit.
Um,
I think it teaches you a lot about not
getting the job that you want a lot.
I think it teaches you a lot about real
competition in the real world and it
gets,
you used to that weird feeling of
competing at a young age.
So it becomes normal,
you know?
Yeah.
To Go.
Well,
because I think there's,
um,
there's a shame with being competitive
these days because everything is so
politically correct that you shouldn't
be an Alpha,
you shouldn't be progressive,
you shouldn't try to beat somebody down.
And in sports it gives you a safe place
to realize that that's a part of our
makeup that's a part of your,
your whole psyche is to want to compete.
You want to challenge,
you know,
to beat Darwinian and that there is a
place to do it.
And then there's a place to not do it.
Yeah.
Well it's easier to find the place to
not do it when you do it.
Right.
And this is the thing about Jujitsu that
I always try to explain to people.
Jujitsu practitioners are some of the
nicest people you'll ever meet and one
of the reasons why is they get all that
stupid shit out on the mats and they're
tired all the time too.
So they're like,
they don't want to start any bullshit.
Like I don't want to deal.
And plus they don't need their egos
stroked their egos getting beaten down
and stroked all the time.
Stroking and tap somebody beaten down
when you get tapped out and you have to
get used to it in order to get to a
certain rank.
Like if,
say if you get up to like purple belt or
Brown,
but with somebody who knows how many
hundreds of times he'd been tapped out
and who knows,
I have no idea how many times have been
tapped out,
but it's probably thousands.
No Shit.
How could it not be?
Wow.
All those years of doing Jujitsu,
20 years of doing jude,
20 plus years of doing Jujitsu and all
the times I rolled and the,
all the times our role people better
than me.
I've been fucking choked and arm barred
and you just get used to it.
It's not fun.
You don't enjoy it,
but what you do enjoy is that you've
experienced something that you didn't
have an answer for.
And so,
you know,
there's work to be done and that's
Jujitsu's endless.
It's endless.
You know?
Um,
there was a guy who explained this.
How has the explanation so far a
brilliant Helson gracie explained it to
someone who didn't understand your
Jujitsu and he's got this thick
Brazilian accent.
It's,
I do this and then you do that.
And then I do this,
and then you do that.
And then I do this for ever that's
Jujutsu.
It's like it's constantly move and
defense and counter and defense and
attack.
When I hear people describe it as a
chess match,
it is,
but chess pieces
only moved one way.
It's so dynamic and kinetic.
And so they're always adding new moves
to.
There's all these new moves and people
are constantly learning.
Yeah,
it's,
um,
but the thing is you're using your body.
Your body is what is being attacked and
your body's what you're using to attack.
So,
you know,
you see things give out while you're
attacking and things give out while
you're getting attacked.
And I think there's not enough to just
two guys who,
um,
I think if I was going to advise people,
one of the things that I would advise is
you should have a regular conditioning
strength and conditioning routine just
to strengthen your joints,
strengthened your limb,
strengthen your back.
Yoga.
I think strength and conditioning and
yoga are almost as important,
not as important as Jujitsu itself to
get good at it,
but almost as important to prevent
injuries and to allow you to reach your
full physical potential.
[inaudible] yeah.
So I mean,
in terms of that being a life lesson,
it's um,
I think when you can physicalize
something that then becomes like in a
workplace more of a mental thing,
you realize that being tapped out in the
workplace can mean everybody gets fired
on a regular basis.
People used to get one job and they
would keep it for 30 years.
You get a gold watch and a pension.
Now the average job,
I don't know what it is,
Jamie,
what's the average lifespan of a job?
Three years.
Four years?
I think so I think people tend to bounce
around a lot more.
And so I think that life people get
divorced and they have it.
They have other successful
relationships,
you know,
like somebody was saying,
we like today,
like that joke,
the Henny youngman joke,
take my wife please.
It doesn't make sense anymore because
you would have fucking left her.
You wouldn't be saying,
take my wife,
you know,
and so,
so I think that it's a life is filled,
more transitions and being able to
accept and almost be,
like you said,
learn from,
be empowered and strengthened by a
change as opposed to defeated by it.
Well,
no one gets through life perfect.
You just don't.
So if you think other people are getting
through life perfect and you're fucking
up all the time,
you feel terrible about it.
Yeah,
but you got to realize that those fuck
ups in those terrible moments,
those are valuable learning experiences
and the people that I know that the most
interesting have failed the hardest.
They've had these colossal fuck ups and
then they rebuilt themselves and then
understand it also gives you like a
certain amount of humility and
compassion for other people because you
know,
you've realized like,
Hey,
this is not like no one rides the wave
forever.
Yeah,
you crash,
you hit the coral gets scratched up.
You get fucked up.
I've never served.
I shouldn't use those analogies,
but you grow from it or you become evil
from it.
We had.
Well,
you could definitely can.
Yeah,
you could definitely become evil from
defeat.
But I just think um,
I mean it's a fucked up thing.
I mean,
it's a weird thing to say,
but I really think we all collectively
as a species need to emphasize and learn
how to be nicer to each other.
Nobody teaches you that.
It's rare.
They teach you in school,
be nice when you go to offices.
There's,
you know,
there's certain standards of behavior
that you're supposed to behave in,
but there's not like
an emphasis on kindness and just being
friendly and I think that that doesn't
diminish competition.
Like you can be friendly and kind to
people that you're competing with as
hard as you can.
That was also a thing that you find in
Jujitsu guys who were just trying to
kill each other all the time or like
really close friends really close and
you know,
very competitive.
Like motherfucker,
I'm getting you tonight.
No Bitch.
You not like that kind of shit,
but friendly.
Well,
because there's a safety,
because there's rules and in the
workplace the rules are much more
nebulous and what you do to get ahead,
kissing a bosses asked,
sabotaging a project.
Is that part of competitive or is that
over the line?
Whereas with Jujitsu you'll get called
on a foul.
Yeah.
Sabotaging a project.
Imagine working with somebody and
they're sabotaging.
When you're trying to accomplish now go
to the boss and talking shit behind your
back about your project and what you're
trying to achieve.
That's one of the most soul sucking
things about jobs.
The fakeness,
the the office banter,
nonsense fakeness.
I just think as a,
as a species,
just the human race,
especially us as Americans because we
are so God damn competitive color,
I'd be nicer.
I think it starts with manners.
I think it starts with.
I mean as a parent,
manners,
they seem trivial,
but it creates the paradigm for Nice.
Just thank you.
Please hold a door,
donate like don't eat until everybody's
served their food.
They're all little signals to people
that you care about them and respect
them and I think it spills over and it
informs your other actions when you have
good manners.
Right.
Look,
people in the eye.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It'd be pulled.
And when people do that to you,
you get a good feeling,
you know?
Well,
you know,
when someone holds open the door for you
or someone says thank you.
Like I said hi to some guy.
The other day I was walking by him in
the hallway of the hotel.
I go,
how you doing man?
He just stared at me and immediately I
was like,
why?
I was angry,
you know?
Immediately like part of my instinct was
like,
fuck you man.
Yeah.
Then part of me was like,
that poor bastard,
you know?
And I went with that poor bastard.
Like,
oh,
that's his life.
I just said Hi.
I'm just trying to be nice.
Yeah.
But he looked,
looked at me like I was almost like I
was weak and saying hi to them.
Right.
You know,
I was raised to like,
like if I see somebody with bags,
I helped them.
And it makes me feel fucking great.
It feels good to help people.
Yeah.
I think I was raised and that's the
thing about being raised Catholic
because I was raised.
Were you raised Catholic?
I was raised Catholic
too.
First grade after first grade we kind of
abandoned it,
but even up until then it's,
it,
it's,
it gives you a lot of,
um,
it's a life of service.
It's very much about helping people.
It's very much she,
you know,
he could say what you want about the
Catholics,
but you know,
they were in the trenches and a lot of
third world countries,
nuns and,
you know,
they,
they did a lot of good.
And uh,
and I think that rubbed off on me.
My parents both always did a lot of
charity work.
I do a lot of charity work with my kids
and you know,
that's going to stay with them.
I think we throw the baby out with the
bathwater when it comes to religion and
even just rigid ideologies.
I think there's,
there's something about religion that
can absolutely help some people.
And there's aspects of it that are very
beneficial.
Having that code to live by,
you know,
even if it's because of the fucking
spaghetti monster in the sky,
like whatever it is that you believe,
but if you really act that,
that thing,
act like that thing is watching over you
and that there's codes and tenants that
you have to live by,
like most of the tenants of
Christianity,
if you look at them,
if you really follow Jesus has rule,
which most people don't,
but if you really did,
you'd be doing a lot of great work.
You know,
you'd be helping people.
You'd be treating each other as if they
were your brothers and sisters.
The neediest.
I mean,
that's who Jesus helped the beggars in
the street and the prostitutes and you
know,
that was some hardcore shit he was doing
back then.
And um,
yeah,
I think it's like the 10 commandments
you can live by,
I don't know,
eight of them.
Eight of them are pretty good to live
by.
I'm still gonna cover.
My neighbor's wife Covet.
She's fucking hot.
Do you know what that was about?
It wasn't about that.
What was it about your neighbors?
She was possession.
She was covet like she was a possession
of the neighbor.
Like she.
He owned her.
Right?
Oh,
that's right.
Yeah,
and the same thing stood for the
commandment.
If you really read it says,
do not covet thy neighbor's wife or they
neighbor,
slave,
slave.
It's a donkey.
I think it's donkey enslave.
Really?
Yup.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Don't,
don't try to steal their slave.
You can keep slaves.
Just walk them from your neighbor.
It's just so obvious that what they were
talking about back then was all wrapped
around the way people thought about
things.
Then yeah,
you know,
but they knew even then,
even thousands of years ago,
they knew there's a right way to do
things and there's a wrong way to do
things.
There's,
when you pick up the people's bags,
you feel good.
Let's tell kids that.
Let's teach people that you pick up the
bags,
you feel good.
You hold the door open,
You help someone.
You feel good.
Like,
okay,
let's.
This is obviously we all want to feel
good,
right?
How do we feel like there's moments in
my life where I feel terrible where I've
done something wrong or a fucked up
something or just failed and I just feel
terrible and I always think when I do
have that feeling of,
Oh God,
I fucking hate this feeling.
Why can't I feel great?
Why can't I just feel awesome right now?
Well,
because it didn't go and this is
like the psychic reminder.
This is that jolt of energy that's
letting you know like,
hey,
you went on a wrong path.
You fucked up you tank this,
you crashed that you did wrong.
Like you're supposed to feel like shit.
Right?
So that you don't do it again.
Yeah.
But conversely,
when something good happens,
when you help someone,
when someone can't get their bag in the
overhead because it's too heavy and you
help them and you hand it to them,
they smile at you and you smile at them.
You walk off the plane,
you feel good,
you feel good.
You've got to teach that to like,
you have to remember that and you have
to go,
why do I feel so good?
Oh,
I felt so good because it helped that
lady.
Yeah.
You know,
I felt so good because I said hi to that
guy and like I say hi me back and we
looked at each other and go,
you know,
made some niceties or whatever.
Yeah.
And that's,
that's part of the joy of life is those
friendly,
fun,
Nice interactions with people.
But when you got your shit in order,
it's easier to have those experiences
when you don't.
My personal experience,
when I don't have my shit in order and
I've made mistakes and I'm,
I fucked something up.
It's very hard for me to enjoy anything.
Yeah.
I just go through the motions.
I just,
I feel like,
Oh,
if I have something that I fucked up and
then I have that terrible feeling,
but I have to hang out with my family
and my kids.
I just ride it out.
I just have to ride it out.
I try to be real friendly and real
sweet,
but I don't feel good inside.
I feel terrible and I go,
well,
this is going to go away with
contemplation,
with understanding.
It's going to.
This feeling is gonna go away,
but you got to ride it out.
You know,
and I know I can ride it out because
I've read it out,
wrote it out before,
but for some people,
man,
they don't know what to do there.
Don't they don't know what that feeling
is.
They feel like this is their life and
then that feeling,
if you don't conquer it,
you get comfortable with it.
You get used to it.
You used to failing,
you get used to that terrible feeling
and then you start pouring booze on that
terrible feeling or pouring drugs or.
Well,
it also becomes like A.
I was in therapy and I remember the
therapist told me that you,
we all have a narrative of our lives and
you can choose that narrative.
It's that fucking simple.
That's basically what behavioral therapy
tells you is that it's all a projection.
Everything in your life as a projection.
You know,
you say,
I have these attributes,
I've accomplished these things.
Or you can say,
I lacked these things and I fucked up
these things and you can live your life
putting that energy out to people and
it's as simple as just literally sitting
down and thinking about how you want to
see yourself and just keep,
keep reminding yourself of that and
you'll start to live.
And I mean,
this sounds so fucking hokey to
oversimplified,
but it's real,
you know,
and,
and part of the thing,
the downside of religion is that I was
raised with a lot of shame and guilt.
And so those periods you're talking
about where you fucked up and you're
feeling bad and you got to ride it out.
You throw shame on top of that and it
extends it and it makes it more
profound.
And it's not just about your action and
how it might have affected other people.
It's about original sin,
you know,
heavy,
original sin shed,
Garden of Eden,
where evil,
you know,
we're dirty.
We need to confess,
we need to be cleansed,
throw all that on top of a simple
mistake.
And again,
it makes it complex.
Okay?
Yeah Man,
the sin.
And the pain and the suffering that mean
island went through one year of Catholic
school,
but that one year when I was six years
old,
first grade,
I was like,
this is ridiculous.
These people are crazy.
Yeah.
I'm not this bad.
I just knew that my parents got split up
when I was five and then I was really
confused.
I was like,
I can't believe my mom and dad aren't
together anymore.
And there was screaming and hitting and
a lot of violence.
And it was just,
it was good that my mom got out because
I learned that when something is
terrible,
like you don't just stay and get smacked
around you leave.
But the bad thing was it just through my
whole life into chaos and I wanted some
order and things.
And one of the things that I turned to
for order was religion.
Even though it's five,
six years old,
like I remember my grandparents or you
know,
whoever was taking me to church,
like I got into it.
I was like,
this is the answer.
Like it's like what?
What does God want you to do?
Because when you're six,
like it's,
it's not a con.
I remember thinking of it and there's a
very narrow confined way,
like I didn't have a broad sense of the
world.
I had a sense of God as being like the
ultimate dad.
Right?
And then will the,
well,
this data that I have is failed.
So there's ultimate dad.
You've got to do what he says and that's
how you,
that's how life works.
Good.
And that's how you're happy.
This very small vocabulary that I have
this narrow view of the world with,
you know,
five summers of life experience.
And then I went to Catholic school and I
was like,
Holy Shit,
is this wrong?
I was like,
this is so wrong.
Sister Mary Josephine.
This is the only person I remember from
being six years old.
I don't remember anybody's name,
but I remember that fucking evil monster
of a lady.
She was horrible.
And I remember thinking,
she smelled like death.
She looked like how she just looked like
she was just in grief and anger and just
annoyed all the time and was so mean to
kids bat.
And uh,
it,
it fucking knocked it right out of me,
knocked it all right out of me,
all my ideas about religion and
Catholicism.
And I was done by the time first grade
was over.
I was like,
there's no way I'm going back.
When my parents had run away.
Wow.
I was like,
there's no fucking.
Yeah.
My parents went to Catholic schools in
the Bronx back when they just hit you.
I mean,
like every infraction,
they had a room,
literally they had the ruler out and
they wrap you on the knuckles all the
time.
And My mother said to me,
she realized she got older,
these nuns that were teaching very often
they became nuns because maybe they were
lesbians,
maybe they hated kids.
They didn't want to go down that road.
And so they joined the sisterhood to get
away from it and they stuck him in
fucking classrooms with 25 jacked up
testosterone written kids.
And it's their worst nightmare.
That's why they're so miserable.
We got a kid in the neighborhood that
became a priest and he was a nice kid.
I was in high school.
What?
He's gay as fuck.
Everybody knows gay as fuck.
It was so obvious.
He was just soft and this,
his face was soft and,
and he had no interest in women who's
like,
wow,
there's gotta be a way.
And he went right into the priesthood.
We were,
we started calling him father by the
time he was 17.
Wow.
I guess he was 18.
He was like a year older than us,
maybe two years older than me.
Um,
and I think he had graduated and he was
already like going into the priesthood.
Right.
I don't know what steps you have to take
to do it,
but people started calling.
Father started calling him father when I
was 16.
I think people are doing it,
but I remember thinking like,
oh,
he's gay,
obviously he's gay.
And now he's like,
what are the options and fucking Newton,
Massachusetts in 1983.
That's going to do.
Yeah.
What's it going to do?
You know,
didn't know where to go.
Became a fucking priest.
Do you think that priests in a rectory,
which Latin derivative rectum visit now,
do you think they're all fucking.
I mean the precert mostly gay,
they're not getting laid there.
They've got what,
23 hours of downtime every day when
they're not doing a to an a mass.
I want to know what percentage of them
are pedophiles and what percentage of
them were molested.
So became pedophiles.
It's,
I mean,
and people to get upset of this look,
you can't get upset at it.
It's like blowing tires on Nascar.
It's real.
Yeah.
Okay.
We'll.
Tarzan don't always fail.
You're right.
They don't always fail,
but they fail a lot.
A lot of people lose tires.
You know,
a lot of people crash cars.
It's just your,
there's a giant history of sex offenders
that become priests and molest kids.
Like what are the,
what are the numbers like if yet is it
10 percent?
And we just hearing about.
I mean if it was 10 percent of priests
is still a lot of people getting
molested,
is it 30 percent?
Was the number.
It's not zero.
Well,
what's disturbing isn't just that
number,
but the number of priests that know
about it that don't say anything or then
they even know about it and they shift
them to another church.
I mean the complicity of the church in
dealing with this problem.
It's a civil case.
This is rape,
this should be in the courts.
Police should be brought to the church
and they should be fingerprinted and put
in jail,
but instead we somehow say,
you guys deal with it yourself.
Yeah.
You remember when Ratzinger had to
leave?
He had a quick,
which is very rare,
but it was because they wanted to try
him for crimes against humanity like
that.
I was a fucking piece of shit.
What he did was take priests that were
molesting kids.
It just move him and he moved this one
priest,
this the guy that became pope,
right?
Yes.
He was in charge.
He was a cardinal or whatever the fuck
he was.
Whatever the name is.
Were you in Germany?
Take these priests and move them to this
new spot and I think it was in Arizona
or New Mexico.
I forget where it was.
It was somewhere in the United States.
I believe he moved this guy.
We're like,
well,
send him over there.
And the guy wound up raping 100 deaf
kids.
Christ.
Yeah.
What you hear about that and you're
like,
oh my God.
He imagine your baby,
your poor baby you can't hear and they
go to this place and they can't hear
anything and this priest sticking his
dick in their ass and then her mouth and
like now like this is God does God wants
this.
God wants this guy to do this to me.
And if there was a company where the CEO
allow that to happen under his watch,
nevermind facilitated it.
If you were the head of the company and
it happened,
you would have to step down.
Oh yeah,
this guy got elevated.
Pope
crazy.
Well,
they did it that way for so long.
I mean there's so many digital or you
ever see,
hear no evil.
It's a documentary about it.
Now.
I can't watch those.
Documentaries are rough,
man,
there's,
there's quite a few of them and I
usually make it like 45 minutes into
them where I'm just crying and I can
handle it.
Yeah.
It's just.
And here's the thing.
Most of those guys who were perpetrators
were victims at one point in their
lives.
Of course,
90 percent I would say fucking crazy.
What had horrible,
horrible system of,
you know,
not a system,
but you know,
repeating action in there.
And that's the thing about
that,
the way it spreads,
you know,
every time somebody molested they,
you're creating,
you're creating other predators.
No,
no.
Oh,
so crazy.
Yeah,
I don't.
We went,
we went to a pretty cool church growing
up and the priests were apparently,
I found out later were all having
affairs with women in town.
Really?
Yeah.
This one guy,
I won't say his name,
say it.
Father Mcdonough,
that piece of shit.
Not fucking a kid right now that are way
better.
That's the whole problem.
Bang.
And people's wives,
you know,
like we like eucharistic ministers,
like the eucharistic ministers are the
people that go to church,
but they're,
they're so special that they can
actually go give communion to people
that are home homebound.
Oh.
So the pre,
they were in the inner circle and the
priest,
I have a little fair.
So he would go over,
like maybe grandma was bedridden.
He'd go over,
give her the service,
then slip it to the daughter.
How's call?
No,
that's not what he did.
It was like the people that were the
ministers,
they became close to the priest because
they would have to go to him to get the,
uh,
the bread blessed.
And then they will take it in like a
takeout bag and they would deliver it to
the people that were,
um,
homeboy bedridden.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
they,
those religions become so ingrained in
people's behavior patterns that mean it
becomes a part of the community.
You can't be like,
I'm fucking quit in the church.
Like,
what are you talking about,
bobby?
Yeah,
right.
We go to church on Sunday.
The whole family goes,
we got up on a Sunday,
best on we'd go to church.
He becomes a part of your,
not just your life,
but the way you socially interact with
your friends and your loved ones.
Get everybody together.
It's like it's part of the Sunday
bonding.
Oh,
in your child being christened and
getting their first communion.
These are big like landmark moments in
your kid's life.
You know,
if you think about it,
like you get your communion around the
time that you begin puberty,
you know,
they're all based on cycles of nature.
You know,
Jesus was born,
uh,
in reality in April,
but according to the church,
December 25th,
which is right at the winter solstice
when the north star,
it's like,
it's all built into nature.
It's all pagan and its origins and all
the ceremonies that you go through are
tied into,
you know,
rites of passage and people's lives.
That's why it's so weird that like when
they were trying to convert pagans
during the Roman days,
the,
they're like,
wow,
you know,
we do this thing,
the winter solstice.
It's like what a coincidence,
a Jesus was born the same time and come
on board,
come on board.
Most of the pagan gods and,
and,
and most of the world religions,
the Messiah was born during the winter
solstice and there was a and many of
them died and rose up in the,
uh,
in the spring,
which is what the vernal equinox right
around Easter always lands right around
the vernal equinox.
Well,
you got to think for those people back
then,
like everything was about the crops
rising and gathering food and fertility
and that was everything.
Yeah.
Everything was about whether or not you
could make a baby whether or not you
could feed your family.
I mean,
if the crops went bad,
you had a late frost or something like
that and things died.
You were fucked.
Yeah.
Especially since you had 12 kids.
No birth control shoot loads all willy
nilly.
Yeah.
And you know,
and it was a,
it was a sin for a woman to say,
now you had to do it.
I mean,
you look at you really.
I'll fuck.
Yeah.
With the Catholic church,
you can't say no to your husband.
Really?
No Way,
man.
It's a crime to sin.
You can go to the priest and complain
about it on the priests.
Go give up the posts.
That's right.
Well,
yeah.
No,
no birth control either.
That's the other thing that's crazy.
Like,
hey,
you don't.
Well,
you got to create Christian soldiers.
That's what.
That's where these rules came from is
that it was about populating with his
many of our guys as possible so they
don't want to limit you having kids.
Well,
there was no birth control at the time.
I mean back when that was all going on,
but you can pull out and come in and
girls face legally
it's mandatory and so when you think
about like birth control today,
I think it's great that people have the
option for birth control 100 percent and
I'm not anti birth control.
I think it's amazing,
but it's very weird for a girl to have
hormones in her body that are
artificially put in there,
that tricker body into thinking it's
pregnant.
Yeah.
And they go through this whole cycle of
it and what's really fascinating is
women lose their ability to discern
certain smells that they get from men,
whether or not a man is compatible,
like they've done these studies where
they took women on birth control and off
birth control,
and they could smell men's clothes like
a woman off birth control can smell a
man's clothes,
just know anything about them and can.
This can discern whether or not she'd be
attracted to him certain days.
Certain degree of success.
Yeah,
but that's out the window.
As soon as they're on the pill,
when they're on the pill,
they just.
Their bodies all confused.
They're pregnant and they're not
thinking about that.
And so they lose this sort of weird
sense of compatibility.
Wow.
Yeah.
This was.
They start responding only to axe body
spray,
smell dating.
What is this the first time?
Yeah,
mall order mail order dating service.
Is that real?
Like.
Yeah.
You like mail a shirt in and
hilarious.
I send you a tee shirt.
You wear this shirt for three days and
three nights without deodorant you
return a shirt to us.
In a prepaid envelope,
we send you swatches of t shirts worn by
a selection of other individuals.
You smell the samples and tell us who
you like.
Someone has a smell you like,
likes the smell of Youtube.
We facilitate and exchange contact
information.
The rest is up to you.
Wow.
I'll tell you what,
my wife,
I remember like the first date I had
with my wife,
we rode.
We rode our bikes over the Brooklyn
Bridge and we.
It was,
it was a hot summer day and then we
fooled around a little bit and I
remember smelling her and fucking being
so aroused.
It was like to this day her smell turns
me on.
Yeah.
People are compatible with each other
and in smells.
It's real.
That's legit.
It's a very strange thing though,
right?
We'll look at every.
Every fucking animal.
Smells actually watched this planet
earth a special and it was about a,
I forget which kind of wild cat it was,
but they go,
they travel for like hundreds of miles
and there's certain rocks that they know
to rub their backs up against and leave
an odor
and the other one's in the territory go
to that same rock and they smell it and
they rub on it and then they decide who
to mate with based on these,
like a specific tree or a rock that are
like miles away from each other.
Wow.
Huh.
That's crazy.
It's really crazy.
When you think about how an animal has a
sense,
like their sense of smell is like almost
like we don't have a sense of smell,
like what they can.
They can smell fear and adrenaline.
They can.
They can smell all kinds of weird shit.
They can smell animals from hundreds of
yards away.
The wind blows up like they can smell
shit that we don't have a goddamn chance
of smelling.
There's no way.
Smelling is so fucking weird.
I was in my car on the 10 freeway the
other day and there was a small fire on
the west side.
I was seven miles away,
windows up and I could smell smoke and
you really think about physically,
how the fuck did that sent traveled that
far through my car and into my nose.
What?
What's crazy?
Skunks.
Yeah,
right.
They say skunks give you a sense of how
an animal smells because the parts per
million of skunk smell that you can pick
up is a lot like how a dog could pick up
the smell of like a robber.
When they give a dog a t shirt,
like there he goes,
go get them,
boy.
And they run around like that.
That's apparently very similar.
Very similar.
Like when you smell a skunk,
like you could smell skunk and you're
like,
oh,
it's over to the right.
Like you know where it is so weird.
Like you could be on the street.
You're like,
oh,
you're fucking smell that.
And you'd go like that to the left.
You go like that to the right and you're
like,
oh,
it's over this way.
You can.
You could smell skunk from blocks away,
blocks,
I mean,
imagine a smell that you could smell
from blocks away and it comes out of an
animal the size of a football.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
All right.
It's not a lot of sense.
This is a little bit of a spray.
That's like if you took a hairspray can
and just held it down for two seconds.
Like Shit.
That's what a skunk sprays.
Yeah.
I get it.
Sprayed once.
Did you?
Yeah.
We were in Newport,
Rhode Island.
We had this house and it was,
it was a converted,
a horse stable.
So there was just a,
it was,
it was 21 of us living in the house one
summer and there were people literally
they were stables that had cots in them
and people slept in those.
And I think there was like three
bathrooms in the entire place.
And so,
uh,
there were skunks,
skunks that lived in the basement of the
house and the house just smelled like
skunks.
And then one night I hear this clunking
out in the garage.
It's like clunk,
clunk,
and I opened the door and I walk out and
there's a skunk and he's got his head
jammed in as small hellman's mayonnaise
jar and he's trying to bang his head on
the ground to get it off.
Wow.
And I felt so bad for the thing that I
got.
There was a golf club in the corner and
I got the golf club and went over and I,
I hit,
I hit the,
uh,
the glass trying to break it off.
Oh,
Jesus.
And the skunk squirted me and then ran
outside and disappeared and I don't know
if he fucking died or whatever,
but that shit stayed on me for days.
Yeah.
My dog got hit when I was in Boston.
He got hit or she got hit.
It was a girl dark.
She got hit and I watched her in tomato
juice close to use.
It didn't work and it kind of worked,
but it didn't really work.
She smell like shit for days,
days,
just forever.
Yeah.
I don't know how he even wears off,
you know?
Yeah.
I guess it's a,
it's a weird defense mechanism,
you know?
Very weird,
you know,
they got the big stripes,
you associate them with the smell and
you stay article about it.
So alcohol file thing.
Here's the.
I was actually reading the part about
tomato juice.
Won't work.
Tomato juice
do it.
It's just a strong smell that attempts
to cover up the smell of skunk.
What you need is a chemical that will
change the composition of the thiol
group.
Fortunately baking soda and hydrogen
peroxide or cheap mild,
and we'll do the job.
Interesting.
So baking soda and Hydrogen Peroxide.
Mild oxidizing agents,
meaning they will attacks,
attach oxygen atoms to the sulfur atom.
And the thiol pairing and takeaway its
ability to stink.
Interesting.
And water makes it worse too.
Apparently the chemicals are flammable.
So under the right conditions we can
have a little stripe flame throwers run
around the woods.
Wow.
Take a skunk.
You fucking forced them to spray and you
just hold a lighter up to his asshole.
I think he got a new marvel,
a character skunk man.
Yeah,
that's crazy that it's an alcohol based
spray coming out of an animal.
Yeah.
And it's also like,
how the fuck does something evolve to
spray shit.
I now get of all the different possible
things that could have happened through
natural selection.
A skunk is one of the weirder ones.
Yeah.
Is there flowers to do that?
Is there a stink that's spray?
There's flowers that do think that when
they opened they smell.
Yeah,
I know what you're talking about.
I think that is a flower that is a trap
for rats.
The rats.
It smells like rotten.
Real.
Yeah.
You know how there's like a Venus
flytrap,
there's also one that attracts rodents
and it opens up and it smells like
rotten meat and they fall in it and it
just closes up on them and they can't
get out.
Jesus might not close up on them.
They might not be able to climb out of
it.
It's like a metaphor for marriage
right after you get to this day.
I love the smell of my wife,
but I can't get out.
If you could find that thing of a.
of a plant that eats mice.
Yeah.
There it is.
Newly discovered carnivorous jungle
plant.
Gobbles rats.
Whole who?
That poor fucking rat
maze a fuck bro.
I'm fucking here.
I think.
Fuck it.
I'm going to plant fucking plants.
Got Me Bro.
Deep in the jungle.
Prime evil.
What is,
how do you say that name?
Nip.
And the nip in this actin Oggie with two
eyes awaits.
It's furry.
Pray.
It's not a stuffy cat or poisonous
lizard.
It's a plant.
And each rats,
uh,
it's been named after the famous
naturalist and TV personality,
Sir David Attenborough.
Me Eating pitcher plants their pitcher.
Plants discovered by science and time
of,
I don't know who has is eating plan.
That's insane.
For an unlucky mouse or bird became a
meal.
It was a rare treat,
but this one is a vertebrate specialist.
So there are some that eat insects and
spiders,
but an unlucky mouse or a bird is rare.
But these fucking plants,
this giant plant is a specialist in
rats.
They lure rats with the promise of sweet
nectar,
but when the rat leans into the plant
that drink the saccharin liquid,
it slips on the pitcher's waxy interior
and get stuck.
And it's gooey sap.
Once it's trapped,
acid,
like digestive enzymes,
break down the still living road and up.
Come on.
How the fuck does that happen?
To better explain the whole process as
well as the life cycle of pitcher plant.
There's a video by a David Attenborough,
the poisonous pitcher plant.
You could find that the private life of
plants.
Plants are so fucking complicated.
Yeah.
It's so.
It's so fascinating that just develop
like that's one of the real gigantic
problems that people have with the
deforestation of the rain forest.
Is their stuff down there that we
haven't even figured out yet?
Yeah.
Is so little of it has been explored.
Did you see that new thing in Guatemala
where they're going through the jungle
and they found thousands.
They have some new technology where they
can like see like sonar ushers.
Yeah,
and they found thousands of unknown
structures like,
like building cities.
Like right.
There used to be a thriving,
some sort of a thriving community in
there.
He had and they say that it,
it proves,
it disproves a lot of theories about
were things that developed,
at what rate they were so far beyond
what we thought they were in terms of
irrigation and things like that where
you met.
I mean it's so weird because we only
lived to be 80,
90 years old.
Right.
And in that time you barely have enough
time to figure out what the fuck you're
doing your own life and you're like,
Hey,
what's that stone wall over there?
It's always been here like nobody knows.
I've been out of the ancient ones.
Dancer wants made it and then you die.
And then your grandchildren here the
same story.
Oh the ancient ones.
They built that wall and then someone
comes along and like 1990 and goes,
hey,
who the fuck are the ancient ones?
Yeah.
Like let's start doing some digs if
thank God for archaeologists and all
these people that are out there with
toothbrushes,
cargo
shorts,
with a fucking toothbrush for
days to scrape and things.
Trying to find little bits of pottery
and shit.
Did you see the new radio lab that came
out last week?
No,
I did not.
Marty plants.
Oh Wow.
That's going to freak you out.
There's.
It's only 30 minutes long.
It's a really easy listen,
but there's a couple cool,
cool,
cool story to tell.
Like plants might have memory
for instance,
and this sort of data.
They definitely know that they
communicate.
They allocate resources to the more
needy.
Amongst them,
they have some sort of a symbiotic
relationship with fungi.
Were they the fungi?
The microrisal relationship between
certain plants and fungus.
The plants in the fungus,
like exchange nutrients,
you know,
fungus actually breathes air that they
breathe air and exhale carbon dioxide
like an animal,
and then plants breathe carbon dioxide
and exhale oxygen.
Huh?
Fuck.
It's madness,
man.
Yeah,
there they are.
Plants are a life form and we have this
thing in our head because they don't
move all.
They must be stupid,
but there are in some way communicating
with each other in a method that we
don't totally understand.
Yeah.
Which fucks vegans hard.
That whole self righteousness and all
the craziness that comes along with
being a Vegan and cruelty free,
not to those screaming plants that you
can't hear because they scream,
they fucking scream.
Yeah.
They make noise like the end.
They know when they're being eaten.
That's one of the weirdest things.
Like when they.
Not only do they know when they're being
eaten,
if you place sounds of a caterpillar
eating leaves next to a tree,
some trees change the composition of the
tastes structure of the way the plants
taste to animals.
They becoming in the like,
what's the word?
Uh,
unpalatable.
They taste disgusting.
They're inevitable.
Like,
so these giraffes starve to death
because upwind,
certain drafts will be eating and then
the wind comes down and through either a
smell or sound or some method of
transportation that we,
or transmission that we're not totally
aware of.
Everything down when is changing its
flavor and it becomes disgusting to the
drafts.
Wow,
that's fucking nuts,
man.
It's amazing.
They're like,
someone's eating us.
Fuck it.
What's crazy is it's not just something
biting into it.
It's the actual sound of it.
The sound of it triggers.
Okay,
that's fine.
Uh,
one of the things that talk about is
Dave,
that's how they find water.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
No,
I've read about that.
They,
they hear the sound of water and they
grow towards it.
What's crazy is they've played
recordings of the sound of water and
plants grow towards the recordings.
So what the fuck is going on with those
things?
So they have auditory canals and some
said the roots have a very similar hair
follicle like we have in our ear,
which is you actually hear you here.
You're picking up vibrations on the
hairs and that's what their roots are
made up of.
Tons and tons of tiny little fiber.
Like heres that become a root fuck.
It's amazing.
And the difference is if I eat an
animal,
it's been killed and I'm eating the dead
flesh theory and a salad.
Some of that Shit's still alive.
Yeah.
Maybe that's okay.
Maybe it's okay.
I mean,
here's the thing,
maybe it's all okay,
but we have this idea that some life is
more important than other labs.
That intelligent life is more important
than non-intelligent life.
Right.
I know they did this whole thing with
the Olympics about how,
how many dislike 2000 dog,
a farms in South Korea where they breed
dogs for eating and you go there and
it's like they're just regular fucking
dogs.
A whole variety like you would see in a
pet store and you know,
and we were outraged by it and we've
sent out,
you know,
there's people that fly over from the
states and they adopt one pet.
Meanwhile there's like hundreds of
thousands and you get maybe 50 rich
Americans come over and adopt a pet and
bring it back.
I rescued her,
I rescued her from a Korean factory.
They made burgers out of her.
Yeah.
But that's weird.
I mean for some people a dog is food and
a.
well,
what does that Jamie,
you know,
pigs are like one of the most
intelligent animals.
What does that.
That's a dog farm to rows.
Cages that will be used for dogs.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
But meanwhile those chickens,
I wouldn't give a fuck billard well I
don't like that.
They have to live like that,
but I like chicken so
he ever like stop and go.
You're in the middle of eating chicken
and ego.
This is five meals in a row that I've
eaten a fucking chicken eggs.
Yeah.
It's crazy how much of those hormones I
must have in my body.
There's a big misconception about that.
Yeah.
Most chickens that you're eating don't
have hormones in them.
Hormones are expensive and you don't
have to give the chickens hormones.
The hormones that the.
The idea is that you give a chicken
hormone.
That's why they're so big,
but now they're so big through selective
breeding.
They've essentially like if you take
that girl with giant tits and you
breeder with a guy whose mom has giant
tits and everybody gets together and
then you have just a giant tip family.
That's essentially what they've done
with these chickens.
They figured out a way to breathe.
These chickens were.
They have preposterously large breasts
and they can't walk.
Sometimes.
They're all fucked up.
Yeah.
They're not like a regular,
like the chickens I have in my yard.
They run around,
they jump up in there and they fly a
couple of steps.
There are normal checks,
so they're flat chested.
They're,
yeah,
they're like little,
uh,
gymnastics chickens
as opposed to a stripper chickens.
You want to get some stripper chickens
with double e fake tits that can crush
beer cans.
Ever seen those gals and they hold a
beer.
Can they take one of their whoppers and
they just smashed that beer can with
them dinner.
We'll have glitter on the chicken and
she's got a backstory.
Why third dollar bill inside the
chicken?
Yeah.
So when you think that you're getting
hormones from
food,
most likely that's not the case,
but it's highly likely that,
especially with beef,
especially corn fed beef,
you're getting antibiotics because they
get sick,
so you're most likely not getting
hormones,
but there's some hormones in the animal
themselves and there's a certain amount
of selective breeding that I'm sure
would have more homework hormones than
less,
which would encourage the animals to
have like larger bodies and develop more
food.
But I think for the most part the
largeness is due to their diet.
Like if you take a cow and you feed it
grass,
it takes much longer than for them to
reach the size that they would like the
cow to reach before they butcher it.
But if you feed them corn,
they fattened up real quick.
And then obviously the,
there's extremes like that.
Why Goose Shit and Coby coby before you
get.
It's just literally a dying animal.
It's filled with fat.
You ever get those things?
Yeah.
It's like if Mike Sullivan Irwin was a
cow.
It's.
Sorry,
Mike,
rest in peace.
God bless you.
He's up there.
Um,
this,
this cow is essentially like they've
just given this guy this terrible diet
and they fat all over their body but,
and no exercise and even massage them,
I think.
Yeah,
I think they do in Japan that's like
part of the deal they did.
They give them beer and then they
massage them.
Is there a happy ending?
No,
because their steers.
So if their steers it means they don't
have any balls.
Know a steer is they take a bull,
like cut his balls off.
And that's what a steer is.
Most of the time when you're buying,
if you buy ground beef,
I think,
I hope I'm not wrong with this,
but I think sometimes ground beef is a
cow,
like a female and um,
they like maybe they stopped producing
milk or they get to a certain age and
they shoot them and then they grind them
up.
But if you buy steaks like USD,
a prime t bone,
you know,
nice t bone steak that's coming from a
steer.
So that's a cow that cut his balls off
and then they,
they fatten them up,
huh?
Didn't know that ground beef is the,
uh,
the cow sometimes think ground beef
sometimes can be steered to like certain
cuts.
But I think in some cases,
I hope I'm not wrong about this,
but I do know that most of the stakes
you get if you buy like a nice rib eye
or something like that,
you're getting it from a steer.
Isn't there also some chemical that's
released,
they say when they slaughter beef that
they get scared.
Adrenaline,
it then that you're eating some kind of
a chemical sometimes as a result?
Well,
there is a definite taste that people
think happens to an animal when they're
scared.
Um,
and you,
if you shoot an animal and it's wounded
and it scared and maybe you have to
follow up with a second shot or
something like that,
that animal will not taste as good as an
animal that has no idea what hit it.
Yeah.
That's why I'm.
There's a guy that I know that's a chef
of a very famous San Francisco
restaurant say song.
I think it is.
I think that's the name of it.
It was on my friend Steve [inaudible]
podcast.
Steve Rinella has a podcast called meat
eater and he's a pretty famous hunter
and chef himself.
But one of the things that,
this chef of this,
uh,
this like one of the very few Michelin
Blah Blah Blah stars,
I don't know how many fucking Michelin
Stars and ask,
but it's like very,
very highly rated restaurant.
He shoots the animals in the head only,
like when he goes hunting,
he's hunting and he only shoots them in
the head.
So he has to have like a close shot with
a very accurate rifle.
Shoots him in the head so they die
instantly.
They have no idea what happened.
Boom.
They're dead,
no adrenaline dump,
nothing.
And then that way,
according to him,
you get the finest flavor from the food.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's a harder shot to because that's
the thing that's moving the most on the
animal.
The head could be.
I mean it could just be sitting there
eating like a lot of times they're
eating grass or something like that.
I mean this is obviously we're talking
about wild animals,
you know,
it'd be really easy to do for a cow or
something like that.
They would have no idea.
They're just sitting there eating.
You could set up on a bench with a rifle
and just take them out and they would
have no idea,
but most of the time with cows,
they use that cattle rod on that brain
that that guy used in no country for old
men from that dude come around with that
and he put it on people's heads and
punk.
Yeah.
That's how they.
They killed cows.
They're being corralled into the,
into the slaughterhouse and they know
what's happening.
They know something's not good.
Yeah.
I don't think they know exactly what it
is,
but they definitely think they're
fucking hell.
I think if plants can tell that a
giraffe is eating from a mile away,
I think cows can tell that they're.
There is a killing field right in front
of them.
You know the worship is kosher ally.
The way they do it.
I don't know about this.
Slice their neck and the bleed out and
then they hang them up by their ankles
and flopping around bleeding.
It's terrible.
Cows.
Yeah.
When you buy kosher beef,
there's a very specific ritual that has
to be gone through.
That has to be accomplished.
In order to proclaim beef kosher,
it has to be a very sharp knife and I
believe it all has to be done by a rabbi
Steve.
That's true.
Damn.
Yeah,
but I've watched it.
I've watched in videos and it's like,
okay,
this is terrible,
but kosher hot dogs.
Pretty good.
They're delicious.
They're the best.
They really are.
I mean,
it's like it's.
It's like two different types of food.
There's kosher hot dogs and they're
shitty hot dogs.
Think Kosher also in it.
It has to be hormone free,
it has to be antibiotics free and I
think they have to be on a specific
diet,
doesn't have a bunch of things.
Regular hot dogs.
They put the fucking beaks and the fee,
everything.
Assholes,
dicks and I think with kosher that they
don't put all that shit in there.
Maybe that would make sense.
Hotdog in a while.
Yeah.
Well good fucking New York City hot dog.
It's hard.
Some onions on there are some relevant
you put on your hot dog.
I'm a big Sauerkraut guy.
Sally Brown.
Spicy mustard.
Yeah.
I love that.
Come.
I like gray's
Papaya on sixth avenue.
That's a good spot.
You get two dogs and the Papaya drink
for like $3 it's bought.
Yeah.
That's an interesting place to.
It's like probably hasn't changed much
since the beginning of time.
No.
As a matter of fact,
I know a gray.
Sheila Gray is the granddaughter of the
Guy who started them and the guy who
started them was a famous Broadway
producer who'd won Tony Awards for some
of the shows that he made,
and then he used the money to buy first,
the one on sixth avenue and then he
opened up another one up on 72nd and
Broadway.
There's another gray's Papaya and uh,
she's a great acting teacher.
I went to her,
she's a coach and I used to go to her
classes and then I went in one time for
a private session at our apartment and
uh,
when I was coming out she was like,
you gotta go,
you gotta go.
It's like a rush job.
I'm like,
what the fuck?
And I walk out and Mariah Carey standing
there waiting to come in and get
coached.
Right.
Carriers take an ironman was a weird
transition,
right?
Like it's a normal transition for comic
to become an actor or a singer.
I now it's like,
Huh,
alright,
rappers can do it.
No problem.
Rappers seemed to be make they make this
transition.
Yeah.
Twelve years now tonight's show Tupac to
the gangways.
Yeah.
Big.
He never did a movie though,
did he?
Nope.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Yeah,
he's my favorite.
He's my favorite of all time.
Yeah.
Uh,
only one who is knowledgeable in the
laws of slaughtering.
Know what does that Word Sha,
she wears red when we need them.
Call them up on his flip phone.
S h e e h I t a h shit say shit.
Shahita and proficient in its practice.
And who is a believing pious Jew may act
as the slaughterer show het in
performance of the commandment.
It is the prevalent custom that this
show hat must receive written
authorization from a recognized
Rabbinical Authority attesting to the
aforesaid qualifications.
Okay,
so you have to.
You have to have written authorization
from a rabbi saying that you know what
you're doing the shit to a must be done
by means of a swift smooth cut of a
sharp knife who's blade is free of any
dent or imperfection.
Wow.
The Shit Shea,
he's probably screaming at us.
Her sugars
entails severing the trachea and
Esophagus in according with the oral
tradition,
which requires that five improper
procedures be avoided less.
They invalidate that Shahita and render
the animal unfit to be eaten.
Wow.
There a hesitation or delay while
drawing the knife.
If you hesitate.
Oh No.
Oh,
it's all over.
Don't eat the cow.
Excessive pressure or chopping.
You can't eat it.
Burrowing
the knife between the trachea and the
esophagus or under the skin.
You can't eat it.
Diy,
making the incision outside the specific
area.
You can't eat it and he laceration or
tearing of the trachea or Esophagus,
which would result from an imperfect
blade.
An animal or foul that has been
improperly slaughtered or as already
noted that is not slaughtered but dies
of itself is considered carrion.
Nevada.
Huh?
An unfit for food.
God,
they're picky.
That's so picky.
It is forbidden to slaughter the parent
with its young on the same day.
It's in leviticus 20 to 28.
Leviticus set some hard core shift.
Yeah.
That's a hardcore book of the Bible.
That's the quote from pulp fiction that,
uh,
that uh,
Sam pond,
the what great veterinarians and furious
anger Zico is that you from a few kilos.
A weird to like [inaudible] the one that
the Ufo dorks always point to because
Zika equal,
um,
had some sort of a vision of a wheel
within a wheel,
like some sort of vision that they,
they think was some visitor from outer
space.
Oh,
no shit.
Wow.
I think they were tripping.
I think they're just eating mushrooms.
That's what I think.
Well,
yeah.
Well the last book,
the,
uh,
about the uh,
Armageddon.
That's fucking trippy.
That's a bad trip.
Wrote it all down.
Well they say that the,
I forget who wrote the book of
revelations,
but they say that it occurred at the
same time as the,
uh,
pompei exploded and that he was really
just describing what was happening
really in Italy when this pump,
hey,
I want to feel like I feel like 100 or
something add.
Yeah.
Right.
Well,
most of the Bible wasn't written until
two or 300 years.
Testament.
Yeah.
Well,
but a lot of it was like older stories
that they had to pick and choose what to
keep.
Yeah.
There it goes.
Seventy nine,
79 in the summer around August 24th,
25th.
Probably visited.
Did you go there when you went to Italy?
I did not plan.
It was pretty wild.
Yeah,
I did not.
I was having such a good time in
Ravello.
I just stayed up there.
And [inaudible] posten swam.
Yeah.
Is that on the uh,
the uh,
mafi coast mouth because yeah,
we went to Ravello which is up high and
then we went to Moffitt coast,
which is down low.
Yeah.
And then we went to Capri,
went to the aisle.
Oh,
you did?
I hear that.
That boat ride is a little crowded
though.
It's not the best.
It's just you just deal with it.
You get to the island,
you have awesome fish and seafood.
The fucking food there.
It's just so amazing.
Yeah.
I throw all my dietary restrictions out
the goddamn window.
If I go to Italy somehow they don't get
fat.
I mean,
you're in Italy and these people are
eating pasta and cheese and wine and
they just seemed get a little launch,
but that's about it.
Yeah.
Well they walked there was crazy.
Is that.
I also think that they're dealing with
heirloom wheat.
Wheat is a different kind of wheat and
it's uh,
you know,
the wheat that we have today and someone
corrected me on this.
Um,
I guess I use the wrong term when I said
genetically modified.
It has been modified,
but it's been modified to traditional
agricultural methods of splicing and you
know,
how the fuck they did it.
It's not like it was done with a dude in
a lab coat.
Yeah.
But nonetheless,
the wheat that you get today is very
different than the wheat of say,
200 years ago that we'd have 200 years
ago.
It was a small plant.
It didn't have a high yield.
And now when they,
what they've done through this selective
breeding is create this really thick
heavy wheat that has a lot of complex
glutens.
And that's one of the reasons why so
many people have gluten sensitivity
today.
It's just a more complex thing for your
body digest.
So if you're eating fucking wonder bread
and shit and all that stuff is just
sitting in your gut like that feeling,
that's what it feels like,
right?
When you have a big fucking bowl of
pasta,
you feel like there's like because
that's what your body's doing,
your body's trying to compress and
digested and what do we do with all this
stuff?
So this fucking glue,
this asshole just ate.
He just ate paste.
Not only that,
but why is it with pasta they give you
like it's the size of your head.
Do I need that much of this shit?
There's no other meal.
They give you that quantity of oil.
They used to be a restaurant in Santa
Monica called Il Grano and it's done.
It's done now.
It went,
it went under,
but when it first opened it was fucking
amazing.
And callen took me there and we ate
there and we had squid ink pasta and
they would give you like it was a multi
course meal where they'd give you like a
plate of this and play that in.
Every plate was about the size of your
fist.
Everything was fairly small.
That's it right there.
Woo.
That shit was good.
That's got um,
sea urchin on top of it,
which is amazing.
But squid ink pasta,
stuff that we had had a crab,
it had dungeness crab and squinting
pasta.
To this day,
I think about it,
it's like one of the most delicious
things I've ever eaten in my life.
But small portion and not the size of
your fucking head,
right?
Yeah.
He forgot to cheesecake factory.
The other fat people eat traits,
you know,
it's the worst book.
Epo or the best depending on if you
want.
I used to work there.
Oh they did in Columbus,
they give you a goddamn bathtub full of
Pasta,
family style.
So it's not for one person,
but yeah,
misconception they get crazy though.
They give you like a Rigatoni with meat
sauce and cheese and you're like,
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
Who the fuck is eating all this?
But if you're,
if you just want a gorge,
he just want to go deep.
It's amazing.
You know Lasagna big fucking trail is on
all four knows my oh dude.
Pizza and Pasta.
Woo.
That
was one of my favorite trump stories.
The trump story about the pizza with
little pizzas on top of it to verify
that that was.
That's what he was eating.
One of the stories of one of his
mistresses.
That's one of the things that she said
is that he ordered a pizza,
but for the toppings you want little
pizzas on the pizza.
I don't know if that's not real,
but that just like him.
He also got shit for when he was in New
York and he was running.
He ate a pizza with a knife and a fork
and he got a ton of shit about that.
Maybe doesn't get his hands dirty at
satire.
It is outside.
I mean it sounded so fake that it sounds
so good though.
That's great.
Sounds so good.
That is something that someone should
make pizzas a little pizzas as topping.
That's real.
The trump,
the trump part of it was fake like him
saying,
oh,
but there is really pizzas with little
pizzas on top of that.
Some restaurant.
I don't even want it.
I'll show you what.
I don't want it,
but I.
I want to be there when it gets made.
Well,
what is it that they stuff in the crust,
if pizzas now look at that.
It's a pizza with little pizzas on top
of it.
Wow.
That actually looks delicious.
Oh,
and it's a bunch of different kinds of
pizzas on top of it.
I like Pizza Hut.
Got Better.
Did it not pizza at Domino's.
Did it?
Domino's used to fucking suck really?
But now it's like decent pizza.
Wow.
Paid for by dominoes.
All right.
When was the last time you had it?
A couple of months ago was a bad.
It wasn't bad.
Yeah.
I mean,
I hate to sound like every other New
Yorker,
but it really is.
It's hard to find pizza out here in la.
It's decent.
It's the water,
right?
That's what everybody says so.
But has anybody made a real pizza where
they took the water from New York and
brought it over here?
Can you steal water from New York and
bring it to a business in la?
Can you just like open up a fucking
faucet?
Philip jugs?
We need it.
We're going dry again.
I love it.
We had a drought last year that was so
devastating that it was all anybody
talked about and we got,
what do we get a month of rain,
and then they just said,
okay,
all restrictions are off now,
and our course,
six months later they're like,
oh,
we got another drought coming.
It's like,
how about we just don't take fucking 20
minute showers permanently.
Yeah,
but they feel good and you're not going
to live forever,
so yeah,
fuck all these people.
Get your water from Portland.
Yeah.
Just put a pipe up in Seattle and bring
that God damn water down here.
That's what was happening during the
drought.
When,
uh,
what's the,
what's the rich town up by Santa
Barbara?
Mendocino,
Montecito on a cdot with Oprah and all
these people.
Apparently they were bringing in so many
tankers fill a water to water their
grass that it was like damaging the
streets of Montecito and the other
citizens were complaining about the
tankers that were coming to the tankers
were fucking up the road.
That's a.
There are some rich fucking people up
there.
There's a house that I saw that was up
there for sale for $85,000,000.
No Shit.
Imagine how a baller you have to be to
spend $85,000,000 and pay the taxes and
the maintenance on it.
Oh yeah.
Every month.
Yeah.
How about your mortgage?
What's your mortgage on $85,000,000
house?
Well,
I'll say it's like $150,000 a month as a
million dollars.
Million dollars of cost.
You about $4,000 a month.
Here we go.
So Barbara,
$85,000,000.
Estimated mortgage,
343,000.
Two hundred $95 a month.
Yeah,
that's the house.
Look at that fucking house though.
That is crazy.
I mean who lives there?
Jay Z does Jay Jay z by that house.
He can buy it.
I bought one for like 80 or something in
Bel Air.
Hollow.
12 bedrooms,
13 bass.
But that you paid all that money.
I would have to spend time in my house
all the time.
I wouldn't go anywhere.
You would feel like that unless you were
worth billions of dollars.
If you are worth billions of dollars,
you wouldn't give a fuck at.
They have like a horse if they have a
heliport.
Oh,
for sure.
They probably have like a time machine.
They probably all kinds of crazy shit.
Yeah.
Nineteen 31.
Wow.
Well there's a lot of that up there,
you know,
they built it up there,
that sort of model Italy.
There's a lot of Italians that live up
there and that's why it has an Italian
name and there's a lot of like really
legit Italian restaurants.
Yeah,
it's the same climate.
Dry,
mountainous on the ocean.
Yeah.
They grow out of wine up there too.
Yeah,
I was up there.
I saw Lucille Ball.
She was at a,
uh,
at a restaurant.
You saw Lucille Ball Shit.
Oh,
I'm sorry.
Carol Burnett now.
Wendy Lucille ball died.
She died like a long time ago.
Right.
Carol Burnett,
Carol Carolyn.
That's still alive.
I saw Carol Burnett.
She's having her little comeback now.
Fishing.
Well,
they had like the 50th anniversary of
her shell and so they did a big one hour
special on TV.
That was fucking great.
I watched them.
I Love Lucy.
The other day I watched him on youtube
and I was like,
wow.
Or somewhere online.
I was like,
wow,
this is crazy.
It's such a time machine.
It's such a weird.
Yeah,
I mean it was so like,
it was like a play.
I feel like there was one camera just
shooting them flat the whole time.
Yeah.
Just wide shots of the whole room
critique about like what I think about
is like how today sitcoms are all
everybody's young and gorgeous and then
you go back to shows like that and you
go look at the murder cases the fucking
57 years old.
Back then everybody looked like they
were all,
even when they weren't.
Yeah.
Look at that.
Look at the Mertz is.
Yeah.
Wow.
And he was crazy.
Everybody who was Desi Arnaz oh,
how could he not be big star?
It was actually really sad.
She had a booming career and then she
wanted to spend time with him and get
him involved.
So they started desi lou productions and
I think they
were the first talent to create their
own studio for their show.
So they could own it and so he was,
you know,
he was the executive on the show like
she was and she created this whole world
for them to be together and then he just
fucked.
Everybody knows what they did back then.
Especially back then
probably nobody knew what a star was.
A new thing.
Right?
Right.
W Like I played this video yesterday,
Jamie sent me,
I put it on my instagram of Elvis doing
karate
and it's a crazy video and you watch
elvis do this nonsense karate and he's
so obviously pilled out of his mind.
So obviously high that you're,
what?
You're watching it,
you're thinking we're not playing this
right.
What,
when you don't even play the volume,
but what?
So when you're watching this and Elvis
is going through all this,
you realized that with this guy was one
of the very first real superstars.
There was no roadmap.
How,
how this guy learned how to behave.
Yeah.
I mean,
look at him.
He's smiling high as a kite.
Now check this out.
Look at this.
Karate stay guys is laying on the
ground,
stomps on his stomach,
goes nita belly.
That's legit,
and look at this clause,
the eyes and the mouth at the same time,
and then they're like,
okay,
you're done.
He's like,
no,
no man.
I got some.
A little ideas.
Hold on,
hold on.
Puts his hand up.
Nope.
Watches.
Stay close.
Look at it.
Some cry,
cry moves.
I'm doing all over a bunch of karate
when he does all this crazy karate shit
and then it helps them up.
You Go,
I got a bread built better than a black
belt.
Look at this.
The guy throws a punch.
Steps aside,
I'm going to step to the side.
Throw a karate kick.
Wow.
It's disarming things in that video too
that are pretty funny.
Long video.
It's amazing because all my life I had
always heard.
Yeah,
Elvis was a black belt under ed parker
because Ed Parker when I was a kid who a
legitimate karate instructor,
like everybody knew who Ed Parker in Los
Angeles.
Boy,
that's a good question.
I do not know where he was originally,
but I know he had.
I believe he had places all over the
country.
Well,
your guy,
he grew up,
he grew up out here.
Yeah,
he.
He went to,
but I think Ed Parker had a chain,
like.
Do you remember when we were living in
Boston?
There was Fred [inaudible].
Do you remember Fred Velardes karate
studios that Fred Volare selfdefence
studios.
They were everywhere.
They're all over the place and what
they've basically done is figured out
how to teach karate in like a digestible
form that families could go to and it
just became this big business.
But Ed Parker was thought of as like
super legit.
Like that was one of the guys.
Like there's a few guys,
you know those American karate people.
There's American martial arts people.
Is Dan Inosanto.
There was,
you know Bob Wall.
There was Ed Parker,
like he was a legit guy and I always
thought that Elvis was legit.
I was.
I'd never seen until that video.
I'd only seen like a couple of things.
I came on stage throwing kicks and the
punches at the end is the craziest
because they're nowhere near the guy's
head.
I lego's hands are taped up to go take
her hands up,
man.
I'm going to make sure this guy's going
to throw a kick.
I'm gonna show you go ahead and
try it again.
Look,
he's got a fucking shirt with a collar
on underneath his karate gate.
Look at that.
Fucking karate chops up and then walks
away.
Walk away.
Elvis Presley.
What does it say?
Gladiators project 1974.
Where does God come on out now?
We'll just grab your arm and that guy.
He's like a real karate guys.
Like this is bullshit.
Look,
he's calling it the hands.
Oh,
he's a head a head.
Ah,
Yangon.
Oh elbow man.
I'm getting right here.
Hit him in the back.
He's like making shit up as he goes
along.
I'm all elbow and right elbow.
He's got a gun.
Fuck that gun.
I'm a karate you.
Wow.
But that guy,
I mean the,
the level of fame that he had achieved
was unfathomable.
I mean,
no one,
no one.
No one had any idea what that was.
And then Michael Jackson fantasy.
I mean he know marrying.
How old is Priscilla?
14 or that she was very young and just,
Oh,
y'all right here.
My Alma,
chop your ear.
I'm going to get behind them because a
lot of people lay behind you when
they're attacking you.
Get behind them.
I'm just ill will in the back.
Okay.
I'll come out your with Doug.
Palm strike to the head.
Try to get me with a gun.
Good look.
Good luck on pills.
He was on pills for a long time.
He's on pills right now.
Look at that.
Look at this.
Come over here.
He's got a gun.
But uh,
I don't give a fuck.
[inaudible] they're gonna gum up my hand
and he's going to stay put.
I'll get my hand.
Come on.
Peanut burn blendle sandwich.
There's no way.
He didn't accidentally punched those
guys in the face.
Constantly going probably to it.
They're probably mad at him.
Just kept taking it.
Well that's the thing about like karate,
there was,
there's always been bullshit karate back
black belts and they can kind of get
away with it because most of the time
you don't really spar and when you do
spar you kind of like take it light and
you're like,
ah,
I could have got you right there.
Like you do a bunch of that stuff.
Like I always saw a lot of that.
He can't,
that doesn't happen with Jujitsu.
Jujitsu because you can kind of do it
full blast.
Like karate can't really.
You can,
but it's not,
it's not wise and you can't do it very
long.
If you full blast,
punch and kick each other,
you wind up hurting everybody.
Everybody's going to get fucked up.
Right.
Including you,
um,
because you're,
you're,
you would be fighting like fist fighting
all the time.
But with Jujitsu,
because of the fact that you roll,
meaning you spar,
but that sparring does not involve
striking and you could tap out when
you're in a bad position,
you could literally go full blast.
So you really find out people that are
good.
So there's very,
very few fake Jujitsu,
black belts,
but occasionally there are some and they
get outdated and there's some hilarious
videos online of guys getting arrested.
Where does Steven Seagal fall on that
line?
He is a legitimate I quito black belt.
In fact,
he was an instructor,
one of the very first Americans to teach
at a Dojo in Japan.
So Steven Seagal.
But the martial art is the questionable
thing.
It's the martial art of ICO is it's
really a martial art that was created to
disarm people with swords.
The idea was that you lost your sword in
combat and someone was coming at you
with a sword.
Last ditch effort is you had to be able
to use someone's momentum against them.
You gotta be able to use.
Some guy comes at you with a sword.
You have to be very adept at catching
their arm and flipping them over.
Here's the goal.
It's very subtle,
right?
Let's.
Let's not use this because it's.
It's easy to poke fun at him when he's
old,
but let's go to that black and white
one.
See that black and white one down there.
Go to that.
If you go back.
See that one right there.
Steven Seagal.
Go to that one.
Now.
There's some some footage of him when he
was young.
Yeah.
This is go fullscreen.
He is legit.
He is very legit and he was thin.
It was a different thing,
but the thing is nobody comes at you
like this and a fucking ncaa wrestler
would shoot a double on him and take him
down faster than you can possibly
imagine.
I mean,
this does not work.
It's a dance.
Well,
it works.
It works.
If someone does know what they're doing
or if you have a lot of physical
attributes,
like Seagal is a huge guy.
He's a very big guy and he probably
could pull that off on a lot of people
who don't know how to fight and I hear
this is what it was about.
What I.
Quito is really bad.
This is Kendo though.
They're using swords,
which maybe they do use some of that.
Nikita.
Quito,
but would Akita was originally created
for,
I hope I'm not mistaken,
was learning how to disarm like that.
The guy comes out and with a knife and
he flips the guy and takes the knife
away.
He's using the guy's energy against
them.
That was the original intention of I
Quito,
but in terms of Japanese martial arts,
I was never thought of as the most
effective judo is far more effective
because judo involves people grabbing
people and flipping them and slamming
them on the ground.
Like there's a great video of an old
judo master.
See if you can find this video.
There's this guy he looks like he's
about 80 years old and he weighs about
13 pounds and he is lit.
You can tell,
especially someone who knows martial
arts.
You can tell when someone's just giving
in the problem with a lot of these
demonstrations by Ketos guys are just
giving in like this old dude watch this
old dude.
The old dude in the right hand side is
so much bigger than the other guy and
they're walking the guy around and like,
he's really throwing this guy right?
This is legit.
Like this is trying
not to get thrown and he doesn't know
what to do.
Like trips him to the ground there,
but this old guy is tiny,
but he's using perfect leverage and
perfect technique and fuck.
He looks really old in this picture,
like the guys trying to throw him there
and he can't pull it off and he can't
pull it off because the older guy has
perfect position and perfectly.
What is the name of this video?
Perfect
leverage.
Look at this
nine years old.
Judo master is the name of the video
online and I don't know if he was really
90,
but he certainly looks like it could be
but this old guy just knows how to
notice.
Also the back of his heels are always
like lifting up.
He's moving.
This guy's trying to throw him and he's
just.
And the guy who's trying to throw him
appears to be a black belt.
At least he's wearing a black belt.
Fucking incredible men.
It's really amazing.
So judo was a much more effective
martial art and judo was actually what
was taught to the Brazilians.
Um,
when count my ada went to Brazil and,
uh,
taught people in Brazil,
Peru,
particularly the gracies,
they taught them Brazilian Jujitsu.
The gracies took what was judo at the
time and they took the ground attacks of
judo and just perfected them and then
hone them and changed them and made them
more technical and really worked on
utilizing leverage and utilizing
submissions and they,
they turned that into Brazilian Jujitsu.
So judo is standing as well as ground?
Yes.
There's a ground aspect of judo
obviously,
like Ronda Rousey is probably one of the
most famous submission artists in the
UFC.
And her background was in judo.
She was a judo player and very good at
judo.
She was a bronze medalist,
so when she would get ahold of people,
she would just fucking throw 'em on
their ass and flip them and toss them
and slammed to the ground.
She just had phenomenal judo but also a
wicked arm bar.
And that was because the Ne Waza the
ground attack version.
Part of Jujitsu comes from judo.
So there you go.
Yeah.
My father did judo and he taught it to
me and my brother and then I remember my
brother was bigger than me and he used
to flip the fuck out and then he did it
to me one day and my father grabbed him
and flipped him down on the ground
because like,
this is not good.
This is isn't like passing on knowledge.
This is just a violent family.
Added control was dead drunk.
He was six foot two cigarette in his
hand.
My cigarette.
Yeah.
Oh fuck.
Judo is legit.
Judah is way more legit than a kito.
Something like does not legit.
I was like,
it's a lot of pressure points and
holding the wrist in different ways.
Yeah,
yeah.
Most of it is throws and learning how to
take an attack or like if you just
charge forward and an Aikido guy and you
have your,
your right hand come on like cocked and
ready and just run out of it.
Throw that punch.
A really good Akita.
I was going to grab that and flip you
and slammed me on the ground,
but you know,
how often does that come up?
Most,
especially today when people actually
know how to fight,
it's just the,
it's,
it's too limited,
but there's a lot of martial arts like
that.
Like there are certain aspects of karate
that are applicable,
but there's a lot of it that's really
limited,
you know,
and it's just,
if you're going to teach your daughters
like,
my daughter is 14 and I'd love for her
to get into some martial arts,
what would be the most effective Jujitsu
selfdefence,
Jujitsu,
100 percent,
100 percent.
Because with Jujitsu,
uh,
first of all,
you use a lot of your legs and a girl
has strong legs.
Your bodies,
you're carrying your body run all the
time with your legs.
You can catch a guy in a triangle or an
arm bar and break his arm or choke them
asleep with your legs.
I mean,
there's a lot of girls that would fuck a
lot of guys up on the ground just by
using armbars and leg locks and things
on.
Because an Armbar is your whole body
against someone's arm or a triangle is
your whole body,
particularly your lower body,
but you're using your upper body to pull
down the head against the guy's neck and
arms,
so you're squashing the neck and the
arms together and then you're pulling
down to head.
A girl could absolutely put a guy,
a girl can put me to sleep.
A girl's got a good triangle.
It was like a legit black belt and I get
caught in a triangle.
I will have to tap out,
man.
Yeah,
fact.
You know legs are strong men.
Yeah.
Think about what you do with your legs.
You know you can't.
How long can you walk in your hands?
I mean,
who?
Who?
What's the world record for?
Walking on your hands.
So like an hour.
How long if you walked to Disneyland?
I mean,
it's fucking your hours and hours on
your feet.
All right.
No problem at all.
What's the world record guy walked in
his sand?
A woman actually did it.
Five thousand meters and eight hours.
Whoa.
Damn.
She's a savage.
Five thousand meters.
What's that in American
in 13,400 feet.
How many hours?
Eight.
How did she eat?
How do you eat upside down?
Just didn't.
Each took.
Took eight hours off.
Eat.
Fuck.
Can't do it.
Can take it out.
I did gymnastics for like six years and
I could walk like a motherfucker on your
hands.
I can still walk on my hands and you
really.
I don't know what the risk now.
Who knows?
But like I could literally,
I would walk around the house on my
hands when I was a kid.
It's a cool skill to have.
It looks cool.
Backflips to back to standing back flips
that Jesus Christ record for defending
50 stairs.
Jesus Christ on your hands.
Did it in 14 seconds.
Fourteen seconds.
Look at this fucking savage.
He's got some pads on his hands,
but he's guards.
He's walking down those stairs like he's
on his hand on his feet.
Look at that.
That's crazy.
That's amazing.
Wow.
That's bounce.
These Asian,
they're not regular white people,
right?
Russians.
They're stronger.
Fuck Ya.
If you think about that part of the
world,
man,
that's a fascinating part of the world.
Have tough.
You have to be.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Siberia and Shit.
Now those Russians,
gang gangs came to New York.
It was like a whole new world of
organized crime.
Like much more hardcore
Italians.
You think about like the old gangs,
like the mafia guys now they seem like
kind of soft and cuddly.
Like a godfather.
The Godfather,
but these Russian guys,
let's just still fucking cut your
Achilles tendon out because you own 10
bucks.
Happened to me once.
Somebody cut your Achilles tendon.
No,
no.
I knew you were faking because you had
the hint of a joke in your face.
But part of me was like,
really?
What you want to told me that already,
but I just remember seeing these.
These Russian guys,
they just,
they look hard.
They've just been out in the cold.
Their whole lives.
Women to heart.
Beautiful,
powerful genetics.
Yeah.
That lost a shit ton of men in the wars,
right?
You know?
Yeah.
How many Russian soldiers died in World
War II?
Millions.
Starved to death.
Apparently,
yeah,
yeah.
It's just a hard part of the world,
man.
Not like la today.
It was 50 degrees people like,
oh my God,
it's so cold.
I got,
I got a winter coat in the car running
today and uh,
I ran into my friend.
She,
uh,
one of my neighbors,
she had gloves on and a sock hat and
like a,
a fucking one of those.
Uh,
what are those fucking Patagonia,
like puffy jackets?
I geared my daughter,
you know,
she serves.
She was out six in the morning.
She was in the ocean this morning.
Damn,
that's core that you raised some
hardcore kids,
dude.
Yeah,
she does it year round or an animal?
Yeah.
Tougher than me.
Both deafer than me.
That's amazing.
Congratulations.
Yeah,
she's a bad ass.
Where you going to see your son play
today?
So let's wrap this fucker out and bring
it home.
Greg Fitzsimmons,
you're on the road soon.
What are you doing well this weekend?
Bananas,
bananas and Hash Mark Heights.
New Jersey.
You ever been there?
And one is my first time.
It's a fun place.
Yeah.
I'm excited about that.
And then I get dates coming up.
March 17th,
St Patrick's Day.
You want to do it?
When is the Improv?
March 17th.
I think I'm out of town.
I'm in.
Hold on one second.
Yeah,
I'm in Orlando.
All right.
And then we got A.
Sorry I'm.
I got dates coming up in a little while.
Rochester,
New York,
May 11th,
2013.
What's the website fits,
fits dog fits dog.com.
DC May 18th through 20.
And a poughkeepsie.
June second and third.
And fitstar radio.
You can get on itunes.
It's still on Sirius.
Sirius xm Monday nights.
Boom.
That's it.
Goodnight fuckers.
Godspeed.