Try by day Joe Rogan podcast by night
all day.
Cause that's a fighter dude.
It's a very dangerous sport.
I see any glimpse where I can get an
advantage.
I'm fucking like floyd mayweather and
victoire teas.
I know that.
I have no problem with that.
Was that to me was fucked up.
It's,
oh,
it's a fight.
He came by.
He came up and said,
hey man,
sorry.
I already said sorry twice and he goes,
come on man.
That's bullshit.
Bullshit.
I'll tell you what it was Victoria's,
he's at a mental breakdown.
Yup.
He was succumbing to the pressure.
He was fouling floyd had these head
headbutting him and he got penalized for
it when he got penalized for it.
He wanted to make friends with floyd and
in the making friends part like,
I'm sorry bro.
Look,
a lot of times you can't have that in a
fight.
You can't have that in a fight because
of the disruption of your focus.
It's adding in this emotional connection
with this person.
Now this person is your buddy.
Okay,
we're Bros were bros.
Right?
Let's go back to Friday.
Pepe boys like fuck you right hand,
go to sleep.
You know cheese is known for that
breaking.
Yes.
Well she got knocked up by Berto.
Cold blooded.
Yeah man,
I think he's done right.
He,
it seems like it should be.
I think like,
it seems like when he got really famous
and things started taking off,
like didn't he did dancing with the
stars movies?
Yeah,
the expendable.
He's doing well.
W against Berto the first five rounds
like shit,
here he is.
Cause you remember they built him up as
the next Oscar de la Hoya.
He was like the golden boy and then it
just never worked out.
Two fights.
I want to see us Golovkin Canelo and I
want to see a Kovalev Andre Ward.
Kovalev and Andre is going to be crazy.
It's happening for sure.
Yeah.
That's happening.
I can't wait for,
Andre Ward is so smart.
He just has to fight more.
He's so smart.
But that might have viva nef might not
be enough against Calvillo the Max so
hard.
Well he's not just so he's skillful as
fuck.
[inaudible] yeah.
[inaudible] and he's father at all.
No,
it doesn't give a fuck.
How about uh,
and it's kind of stupid talk about but
it has legs.
Floyd Mayweather,
conor Mcgregor,
you don't,
and if we know,
we know cause didn't have any legs,
it kind of does.
It does.
It kind of does.
You know why?
Because Floyd wants it.
It doesn't matter.
New Ufc,
he's not going to let it happen.
But see I the only reason why I disagree
with you there is because Dana goes,
if floyd wants to make that fight
happen,
call me.
Dana is a businessman.
They care about money.
No big.
That fight would be how much money do
you think they could make if floyd
mayweather fights conor mcgregor biggest
biggest paper you of all time?
No,
you don't think so?
[inaudible]
it might be.
What do you know the biggest draw
already in UFC mma where there's the
biggest paper,
you draw a box in both time.
You mixed the world.
Everyone would tune in,
including your dad.
I would say you telling me you wouldn't
tune in now because I was so full of
Shit.
You should very uninteresting to in two
hits instead of the little baby fairy
eyes turning fight.
No,
it's fascinating.
I spark.
Okay,
so,
so what,
what happened was floyd mayweather would
box with conor mcgregor and basically
move around and be like,
all right,
here goes and it'd be a spectacle.
It's just not a fight.
It wouldn't be a fight where you are
fucking party pooper.
The guy.
Yes.
And in our cheer.
This is the thing you gotta remember
though.
The one thing that Dana and floyd
mayweather who would be responsible in
this fight together and conner for the
matter,
all they care about is money and
numbers.
That fight would be money and fucking
It would break pack.
Y'All may with a canteen.
Okay.
I know,
but what I'm saying is that,
how would,
how would they,
how would that fight,
what would they do and that fight?
So floyd probably can knock them out
anytime he wanted,
right?
No,
no.
Connor has a very good shin.
Um,
I mean,
kind of got knocked out by Nate Diaz or
he got knocked down and hurt Walden
wobbled by Nate Diaz.
Yeah.
Little gloves.
First of all,
nate's really good puncher needs a big
guy,
a nate.
Nate's fought at one seven and he's a
lot bigger than floyd.
Like physically alive.
Yeah,
but floyd is a guy who's broken his
hands many,
many times and he's not known for like
really uncorking all of his might and
try to knock guys out knockout artists
in the least bit.
But he could,
he certainly could.
You know it's not,
the floor doesn't hit real hard but when
you box real smart knockouts come,
the opportunity comes like the Ricky
Hatton fight.
That's a perfect example.
That knockout came,
it's not like he went looking for the
victor of tease five.
Victor just fucked up and he just left
hook right hand dumb and he was,
he was a total sucker punch.
Like you had no idea what was going on.
The weather has issues against gay,
like May Donna,
if you suggest the first second fight,
he box the shit out of him.
But if may dial it,
like if,
if,
if I was college coach in that fight
were to happen,
I'm like,
hey man,
don't be pretty and sit on the outside
and hit this guy.
We make this a dog bite.
You're the bigger guy.
You think connor would actually give
floyd mayweather a boxing match?
Is that what I'm hearing?
No,
that's not,
wasn't anybody saying no,
this thing,
the thing you're saying,
he's the biggest draw.
I'm saying that I don't think floyd
would just go out and try and knock them
out in the first round.
He'd box.
I think you would canelo Alvarez him,
but he's,
you know,
obviously Canelo's way more skillful and
boxing.
Yeah.
I mean Canelo is a world champion.
One Punch knockout artists,
boxer.
I mean that fucking Amir Khan knockouts.
Hey Jesus.
Louisa was a super fucking home run on
the button to floyd got hit.
He said after he got,
when he fought Canelo,
he got punched in the thigh by Canelo,
had trouble walking for two days.
He literally creeks that he's,
he didn't show it at the fight.
He was like,
dude,
my thigh,
he punched me in the thigh so hard.
I am having trouble walking.
That's why floyd was never going to
fight mma.
Cause if connor would fucking break his
legs like literally mma,
that it would be discussed.
The more embarrassing than conner doing
just box way more than you would get.
Way more embarrassing because common is
a big guy.
Employed would have to like Bach smart
out in connor.
I think connor would have just
unbelievably difficult time even coming
close to hitting him.
I mean,
I think he's going to have straight
boxing with tying grades and stuff.
He's probably,
yeah,
you're talking about if not the greatest
boxer of all time and his defense is
good.
It would be a great show.
Say Good.
It'd be the best defense ever.
But for sure.
WHO's gets defensive?
Offensive Floyd.
And now you're taking a guy who is an
elite strike in the UFC,
but boxing's a different game,
man.
Okay.