Gosh. Dang. Is this working? Hi,
this is Bill Gates and you're
listening to the Joe Rogan podcast.
We were just talking before you can
hear and ladies and gentlemen about
unsolicited testimonials
or soliciting testimonials,
right?
Yeah,
but it's not really a testimonial because
you're just asking a celebrity to say,
ah, you're the audience is listening to
the Joe Rogan podcast. Like, you know,
hi, this is calling for him.
Is that your phone on my phone?
I don't use that stupid ring.
This is highly unprofessional.
Okay,
here we go. The Joe Rogan
experience podcast is brought
to you by the fleshlight.
If you go to Joe rogan.net, click on
the link for the flashlight in her,
in the code name, Rogan blahdy
blahdy Blah. Save some money.
You get a 15% off number
one sex toy for men. Um,
I actually used it the other day.
Remember I've tip too from you. Yes.
I attempt to, and I
used one like maybe, uh,
two weeks ago and I took two cause
I knew I didn't want to wash it.
So I used it and threw it away.
It was cool. It was it. That's it.
You just a one hit it and quit it.
That's it.
No need to save it. Well, you can
always get a new one for me, buddy,
anytime you want. Yeah, I
did. That'd be cool. You know,
whenever the missus is out
with the fandoms or with
the family and Bakersfield,
you know what I mean? It's
perfect. Yeah. It's uh,
it's a very underappreciated product.
You know, women that women should,
women that are afraid that their
husbands are cheating and all that shit,
they should be giving their husbands
these fucking flashlights. Come on.
You imagine the amount that the
percentage of, of cheating that would,
it would cut out instantly.
Cut out a lot of it.
But I think a lot of cheating is
psychological too, but I think overall,
generally if you got a wife that was,
yeah,
of course you're not gonna let you cheat,
but she was giving you
like every week she just,
it was part of the groceries and shit.
She brought him out in fighter tortillas.
Fucking Cup of flashlights.
You're like, I wanted six.
You only got to show what are you
going to be gone for two weeks,
what am I going to do? What
to do? Like a half an hour.
You're not down with cleaning
them. You don't clean them.
Yeah. That's the problem.
They need to make them so cheap that you
could buy them for it. You know what?
For five bucks, Shit,
I'll buy like six. Well,
if you think about how much it costs
for if a dude like essentially pays for
sex,
you know,
if a dude takes a girl out and she fucks
him because he took her out to dinner.
Yeah. How much is that? That's gotta
be like a couple hundred bucks,
at least right flashlights pending.
Take a girl to like swingers or something.
You can get away with like 60 bucks.
You don't want it to go to Katana.
It's Katana is your fuck.
It's like three 25 and Oh,
you've got to Fogo de Chao. Damn.
You better have just gotten paid.
Isn't it funny when you're dating people
and you barely know him and you have to
spend a lot of money on him to impress
them and how cool is it when you get to
that point where you could just,
you know, what do you want to eat?
And they're like, I don't care. And you're
like, El Pollo Loco, you'll fuck out.
I'm like,
Damn.
Like when you cross that threshold of
going to El Pollo Loco on anything,
like a big deal. Like you don't have
to impress the bitch. It's nice. Wow.
That's crazy. So is it like, do
you, do you think, why? Why, I mean,
why is, why is it so important for guys
to impress girls where they take them?
Well, the girls want to be impressed, man.
No girl wants to get picked up and I
had shit jalopy and taken her Donald's
right.
That's not going to happen.
I know girl is going to be down with
that unless she's like 16 and she's just
happy that motherfucker has a car and you
know what I mean? They'll go anywhere.
Yeah. Girls are not really
into dudes with fucked up cars.
You really can't keep that going for too
long. You gotta be a bad motherfucker.
Of course, in a fucked up car. Yeah,
it's a weird thing. And then you know,
it's like no one wants to say, I
mean, it's not entirely common.
It's not every woman.
It's on every woman in the world who
only wants guys to do that, you know?
And a fucked up house man. How long
you've known me for a long Goddamn time.
How fucking nasty my house,
my house is nasty.
Up until up until like 45 years ago,
I was living in basically a doll house.
It was a one bedroom house.
It was the smallest house ever was a war.
It was a house, but it was a one
bedroom house and had the living room,
had a bedroom, tiny. And when
I first moved to Hollywood,
I moved with a buddy of mine,
James. We split that motherfucker.
My whole existence was the bedroom and
there's a whole existence was the living
room is Christ. Oh, let me get
the commercials out of the way.
We've got to keep going with that thought.
This,
I got to get a more effective way
of delivering commercials. Oh,
my tee shirt company.
Hire primate.com hire-primary.com
people keep asking me about it.
I hardly ever talk about it,
but yeah,
I have a tee shirt company and it's all
a psychedelic mushrooms and monkeys.
It's all like monkeys playing
chess monkeys and aliens
playing chess monkey's in
space. It's just weird. Psychedelic
monkey imagery. That's brilliant,
man. That's all I've been
fascinated. Even selling a lot. Yeah,
they sell pretty well,
but I don't tell people about them.
I'm like the worst a advertiser ever
when it comes to that. I just saw,
I always feel weird,
you know,
talking about shit you're selling like
so I don't do such a good job of selling
shit.
You do a great job at that.
Mushroom had stuff that's
mushroom Alpha brain.
What is the mushroom that I'm
thinking about? Shroom tech. Yes. Yes.
You do a great job because every time I'm
here and you'd give that commercial it.
You're so passionate about
it. You know what, you,
you're not only you're
passionate about it, but it's,
it's a totally different commercial.
Every time you're telling people
to go make their own shit,
they're not necessarily, you
know, that's, that's, yeah.
Well I eat the most important thing for
me always with any of these things is to
make sure that no one feels
like they're getting ripped off.
I do not want a single person having
a feeling like they're being ripped.
Totally. That's the most important thing
for me. Everything else is secondary.
So there's that,
you know,
and then there's the way we have it
set up where anything you buy from
[inaudible] dot com like when you buy
like the first order of 30 pills of
anything, there's a hundred
percent money back guarantee.
You don't even have to bring it back.
All you have to do is say this shroom
Tech Shit didn't do enough for me or this
Alpha brain did do nothing for me.
These are the best nutrients and
supplements available for this,
for the, for these particular functions,
for nootropics and for, for the,
for sports athletics.
When it comes to like a performance
and endurance supplements.
Shroom tech is like one of the best
endurance supplements I've ever tried.
One of the only ones that I've ever tried.
It's super effective.
It's got a lot of B 12 and eight in
this quarter steps mushrooms and it's,
it's fucking,
it works great for me and I get a lot
of reports from people that use it for
working out and it's crazy and they love
it when people say as I've always been.
I've been at vitamin freak
before we even started here.
I've always been a massive vitamin freak
still. You influenced me a lot, ma'am.
I'm on,
I'm on honest since serious diet
vitamin plants since I was 22,
23. I was just obsessed
with it and um, I just,
I just wanted to, it was all about, uh,
making sure any cancer,
cancer phobia,
making sure your body gets the
building blocks it needs to stay young,
looking as long as possible.
I want her to look good as long as
possible and drag it out. You know,
I'm not ready to throw in the towel.
So that was a lot of that
going on on my right.
And I would get into arguments with, with
people and they wouldn't, they'd say,
how do you know what works man? How do you
know what works? And I'm like, well, um,
you know, I'm doing all I can but if
you want me to break it down for you,
how does it work?
Uh,
is there a difference between
chocolate cake and a chicken salad?
Okay. Yes. Yes. What's the difference
between chocolate cake and chicken salad?
The nutrition. What's
nutrition? It means what?
What nutrients are in the
chicken and in the south. Oh,
so now what are nutrients?
They've isolated these nutrients that
you can take massive amounts of them.
The only way it wouldn't work is if they
weren't actually putting those vitamins
and minerals in there. If it was just
some fake ass milk powder or whatever,
then yeah, it's not doing shit. But I'm
doing what I can to make sure, you know,
cause there are nutrients and we have,
science has known this is basic shit.
Nutrients are needed and and all disease
is caused by a deficiency of certain
nutrients.
It's really basic shit.
If that vitamins I'm taking,
if they really are what it says
they are on the bottle for sure.
It's good for you.
Absolutely. Yeah. I've uh,
I've always been into vitamins,
but when I started hanging out with you,
that's when I really kicked my vitamin
game up a notch because I was like,
this mother fucker,
it's like super,
you were real disciplined about
it and I was like, you know what?
I need to be as disciplined as he is.
That's really a smart
thing to do because I know,
I feel I took two weeks off of vitamins
recently just for whatever I just said,
let me see what it feels like to
take two weeks off of vitamins.
I took two whole weeks off of vitamins
and dude, I felt lethargic. I just didn't,
I didn't feel connected. Right. Be Like
I was not getting enough from my food.
And I'm a, I mean,
pretty clean. I mean, I,
I've fucked with some
cheeseburgers every now and then,
but I'm eating a lot of salads, a lot of
Greens, a lot of Kale shakes and shit.
Still do not feel as good as I do when
I'm taking like basic multivitamins,
multi minerals.
I take a lot of fish oil,
take like 10,000
milligrams official a day.
And then I take these nootropics and
of all the nootropics I've ever found,
two of them have worked great for me.
One of them was called neuro one
and that's bill Romanowski stuff.
I told you about this right? Any,
there was a guy named no name,
he's a Dj up in San Francisco and he
became friends with Roman Nowatzski Roman
house. Can, you know, he's taking like a
bunch of head injuries from concussions.
So he came out with some
shit called neuro one.
And it's like all the best nutrients
for your mind. All the, you know,
like it's very similar, very similar,
but it's Kinda like a caffeine to it too.
It's good. It's like a little bit, a
little bit caffeinated, I believe. Here's,
here's the little, uh, build knowledge.
I'd like to share with all the Jujitsu
players out there. Guys that train MMA,
this is some serious knowledge.
Believe me, trust me.
You want to keep ringworm away.
Take acid office every day.
Thousand percent 1000% of you take an
acid off lists every day or eat a big
thing of yogurt everyday cause that's
why yogurt is good for you because of the
active cultures, the friendly
bacteria, that's what you need.
Acid office is bacteria that your body
needs. You actually need bacteria.
Believe it or not. You know, I thought
it was kind of weird. I don't know.
There's good bacteria. The fuck does
that mean, but yes, unless the signs,
unless they're lying to me that we
need friendly bacteria and acid.
Doubtless that's what
friendly bacteria is.
We're actually taking pills that contain
millions and millions of good bacteria.
And what it does, this
is, this is what I read.
It eats the uh,
ring ringworm attaches to your skin.
It eats certain things on your skin.
So ring that fungus will grow and
it's eating something on your skin.
Acidophilus eat,
ring warm food first.
So ringworm can attacked
itself as itself too,
and it has nothing to eat. So you never
get ringworm and at it sounds crazy.
There's guys how that, how do you
know where's the proof? Trust me.
Trust and have used to get really warm
all the God damn time. I was always,
I had Lamisil ready to go and if you get
really warm, get Lamisil, don't get low.
Trump man, don't get nothing else.
But Lamisil cream, you're grinded
in with acute tip.
That shit will kill it in five days.
You want to have ringworm for three weeks
or a month. Use Loma trend or that, uh,
any other shit. The only thing that
works is Lamisil. Trust me the cream.
Oh my God. That stuff. I got Loma trend,
go back to the store and get
Lamisil. The cream. Trust me on that.
And you know, I used to get ringworm all
the God damn time God at Exxon jocks,
man with the g,
believe it or not rent.
Lauren was just like once every
three or four months, God damn it.
And I'm out of training for like three
weeks or whatever cause I wasn't using
Lamisil, it wasn't out yet. And then
I read somewhere that acid off lists,
um, eats, uh, bring one food.
I don't know where the hell I read it.
I just read it and I,
it made sense to me and we should
probably Google this little yeah,
look at you know, what? Look at it.
Okay. Yeah. But you're right. Right.
Once you start and you run it
when anytime I get ringworm,
it's when I run out of Acidophilus and
I'm too God damn lazy to go to the store
and I let it, I don't go to the store
for like a week. Boom rain. Where am I?
My arm somewhere. I know it
works 1 million percent. Yeah.
How does it look? A little
advice for y'all? How do you
spell acidophilus? A c. I. D.
O. P. H. I. L.
Okay.
You or some shit like that.
I got lost at the hand.
Yeah, he did a little bit.
Okay.
Hmm. Yeah, this is a,
yeah.
Well, I'm sure there's something that's
going to explain it to us technically,
but basically that's one of the home
remedies to cure ringworm is that yogurt
and it prevents it.
If I'm on ringworm and or a an acid
office for a year straight guarantee,
I going to get ringworm.
There's no way. Yeah,
well I haven't had ringworm
in years. It's, it's true.
And one of the other things are taking
another form of a live culture is
Kombucha tea. That's an easy for me, I
liked the way it tastes. You've had those,
right?
Those big synergies.
I think I've had one in the Ed tech
kind of an acquired taste, right.
It's like you swallow it a little bit
of loads in there. There's some like,
I mean there's like some live
organisms you're swallowing.
Like I tried to get Anthony Giordano on,
he was like, oh I can't get through that.
You'll read your
swallowing the live thing.
You are swallowing some like live loads.
We're still in the middle of
this commercial. Tactically,
uh, go to Joe Rogan.
Not Net.
Click on the link for Alpha brain and a
written the code name rug and save 10%
we've, we've said enough about
nootropics. You know what it is folks,
and if you're interested in it, you
should go read about it. Google it,
and if you think that our
stuff is too expensive,
please just steal the ingredient. Let's
go make your own. I don't care. Just,
I don't want anybody feeling ripped off,
but if you want to buy it and it,
it is good and I use it.
I use it on a regular basis.
I use it before anything important for
my show. When I film my show in Atlanta,
it took four of those bitches.
I'm like, let's, I want to be
fired.
I want to be on all cylinders.
I 100% believe in it and if you don't,
you can always get your money back
first 30 pills, he just send it back.
You don't even have to send it back.
Rather you just say it sucked and we
send you money back. That's how I feel.
Exactly. That's, I could easily
charge 20 bucks, 25 bucks,
30 bucks a month for your membership on
my website for all the techniques that I
upload.
I talked for 99 I could have
went nine 99 or 1199 easily.
You don't want anybody to feel ripped off.
Not only that,
I don't want to hear any complaints.
Yes, me too. You know what I mean?
Anytime someone complains about,
cause they're basically buying episodes
that are filled with technique and I put
them out every two to three
weeks. I just, you know, it's,
it's a lot of work and every now and then,
uh,
it, the episodes come out late and
the guy will come and go on the board.
What the fuck man?
Like dude,
you're paying for 99 for
everything I teach at school.
It's not separate techniques that I
film specifically for the website.
It's the techniques that I'm teaching
to my students at headquarters that that
gets filled in and every technique
I teach goes up on the website.
You have access to the whole system for
four 99 shut the fuck up for 99 a month.
There's really not that much money.
When you consider how much Jujitsu cost,
what is it, a cheap school,
100 bucks a month cheaper.
The most inexpensive like a hundred
right. And I tried to 130 a month. Yeah.
There's a lot of schools that charge one
90 to 10 over 200 they make you sign a
year contract or you don't even want
to talk to you. You know, I, you know,
130th fair. I was charging 105
for a while, but you know what I,
in almost 10 years,
I went from 105 to 130 no big deal.
The big deal and this new space is
expensive and it's fucking big man.
The legend legends is fucking huge as
far as like gyms in la where you can get
like everything done. Damn, that's a gym.
We can get everything done. You know,
that's a big wrestling class plus a roof.
I really,
I really like watching Chris Riley
train goes to Matt and Chris Riley's.
He's a bad motherfucker when it comes
to [inaudible]. He's very tactical,
very smart, very intelligent guy. And
look at the guys who brought up, uh, uh,
Chris Brady,
one of the amateurs that uh,
he bought his third pro fight Saturday.
Man,
his standup is so wicked and I
just gave him his purple belt.
He just submitted a guy with a good
team, you know, so he's a good dude too.
I love that kid. I got, got, got a
lot of good guys at that. Jim Collins,
who by how nice is that guy? The whole
gym is just filled with cool guys.
Chris, Chris, the MMA squad, they're
all coming up strong, like a force.
It's taken a while to build them.
Then they got to get,
most of the guys were strikers first
like Alan Gabon, Eddie Jackson,
Cubana and a lot of fights.
Right. And how many, I don't know,
but a whole bunch. And, and uh,
thanked them with Chris Brady.
They were just pure strikers for years.
We were both there that were in the
same building. They just weren't taken.
They really wanted me to just mostly time.
And then this was like 2005 2006
and as MMA rose as the UFC rose,
they started at the gym. I got
maybe I should do in the, you know,
Eddie's teaching Jujitsu,
maybe I should just jump in.
So they finally jumped in like
four years ago. I've had first.
So now I got these vicious strikers.
They're,
they're an Allen as well.
I gave him his purple belt as well.
They're really good at do Jetson now too.
It's fun watching this and this
is just the beginning, you know,
it must be really satisfying and watching
people like from the time they first
came to you when they didn't know much,
to watch them start to tap people and
submit people watching the progress,
it's amazing.
Must be incredible.
You know what's weird about that is when
a guide comes to me and joins my class
and it's his first day Ma,
my inside,
my initial reaction when someone comes
and I meet him for the first time,
I want them to say they've
been training a year or two.
It just gonna make my job easier if
they have some kind of base going on,
some wrestling. Um, but uh,
but the guys had come in with zero
experience, 100% green. I'm like,
Ooh,
this is going to be a hard one.
But the basically retarded
on the ground I crippled.
It's like you re going through rehab with
them putting their legs are just like,
they have no clue. But
when those guys, when they,
when those guys get good and
they start tapping people out,
it feels so much better.
The,
I know I took them from a cripple
and other tap and dude's out mad.
That happens a lot and that feels
really, really awesome. And it's,
I see it so much that when
guys come up to me and they'd,
they're all pumped up and I
see how enthusiastic they are.
And I know they got the fire.
I know because some guys come in and
they don't really want a roll or first
couple of days they're taking easy.
They're sitting on the side,
they're kind of just, you know, you know,
dipping their feet in the water a
little bit and they'd taken their time.
And then, you know what, let me, let me
get fundamental fundamental three months,
a fundamental classes out of the
way. Then I might spar, I don't know.
And then there's guys with no
experience at all. They come in,
they've had like three or four beginner's
classes and I make them take 24
beginner's classes before
they can take my classes.
There's some guys that come to me,
you know,
three or four classes and they're just
so down. Like I won't, I won't subject,
uh,
a veteran with one of them when they're
exchanging techniques and we're drilling
because it slows everyone down.
The beginners classes. So you know,
that the strategies, the terminology,
all that shit. So you don't slow us down.
In the advanced classes, we moved really
fast. I'm 24 beginner classes is enough,
you know.
But there's some guy,
I'll let you roll if you want a role
after the technique and you want to hang
out in role.
When those guys come up to me and they
asked me and you know I've only had five
beginner classes, but can I
roll? I'm like, dude, you're
gonna have so much fun, man.
You have the right attitude,
right? Like what? What role
means for folks who
don't know is alive spar,
I means you try to choke each other.
Do you pay real close attention
to a guy's first role ever?
Do you have like guys
that you see in Jenny? No.
This is going to be the first time he's
ever rolled your watch them closer? No.
Well I can't tell. I can't tell you
that. I remember anybody's first role.
It's almost like it's going to
suck really bad for a while,
for three months.
It takes three months for a guy
to come in and not know anything,
never played a sport in his life.
You come in,
your first month is going to seem like
it's going to be like trigonometry.
You're going to go holy shit.
But it's just as easy as learning.
The abcs is just as easy as the
first day I had learning the abcs,
your grown adult,
and somehow you didn't learn how to read.
It's going to be hard in the beginning.
You've got to learn 26 letters and then
you put them together and you form work
and then a sentence that's
way like it seems so complex,
but after three months babies can do this.
It's the same thing with Hugh Jitsu.
It's just as easy.
If you could learn the abcs, you can
do the Jujitsu, so after three months,
that's the point where I
notice people start getting,
they start getting the taps in because
in the beginning it's like you just
joined a league or you just joined a
class and everyone's really good at quake
and they've all been playing quake two,
three years straight,
five years and 10 years,
and the [inaudible] has been teaching
for or playing quake for 20 years.
Motherfucker helped invent that shit.
He's a programmer,
shit back in the day and then you come in,
you're going to get killed on quick,
you're going to get Jack, you're not
going to kill anybody for a while,
but it hurts you just as
much physical physically.
You're not going to get hurt in Jiu
Jitsu. You tap. No one gets hurt. I mean,
you get hurt just as much as you know,
playing basketball or whatever
we said that before. But um,
especially if you're all smart.
Yeah,
I've got to learn how to not muscle
things don't, don't go crazy.
You got to learn how to go full
clip, but use technique. Yes.
Some people are tests still terrified.
They look at Jujitsu and
it's terrifying to them.
It's incredible how terrifying it
is. The people. And it shouldn't be.
It's so that people need to understand
that most of the guys are just
sweethearts and nerves to train. They're
just, well, I think people in general, um,
have issues with human conflict.
They're scared of conflict of care,
scared of someone beating
them up. We are, you know,
and a lot of us who got into martial
arts like me and I know like you, we,
we really, you know, we got bullied
a lot. We were younger, we'd go,
we got in positions where we didn't know
if we could defend ourselves. You know,
that's like,
that's one of the reasons why guys get
into martial arts in the first place.
Yeah, man, my first day. It's important.
It's an important thing for
I think for a man to learn.
It really is absolutely for,
it should be standard.
It's your big like in PE class standard,
everybody has got to learn
how to defend myself.
I didn't teach taekwondo for that long.
I taught like mostly uh,
like full time from like 19 to like 22.
And that's when I stopped.
So I didn't have like a lot of
students that got real good.
But I did have one and it was
a girl who was this really shy,
awkward girl and she was really like,
she was really intense.
Like she,
like she didn't wear any
makeup and she was like,
I don't really know what her deal was.
My whole interaction with her was just in,
in teaching or in the class,
but she was like so intense man.
She wanted to learn so hard.
Like she was like so focused on it.
She was like really shy and kind of weird
and kind of embarrassed and I worked
with her a lot because she would like
want to enter into tournament's and I took
her from being a white belt to being,
this girl won this tournament.
She won a tournament.
I think she won like as a blue belt,
a green belt or a blue belt. But I had
basically taught her the whole way.
I had basically taught her the whole
way and watching this, this kid,
it's like real awkward kit,
like learn how to get enough confidence
to go out there and enter into a martial
arts tournament and actually win and like
kicked this other chick's ass and like
go after like this did the
whole thing to her was like,
it was so crazy in an empowering to watch
someone go from being a complete total
novice and to watch just the
stuff that I put in their head.
Just the training that she did with me.
She went on to become like really
good like in just a couple of years.
It was wild.
It was wild to watch.
It was crazy satisfying
with Chris Brady again,
he's one of that. Chris Riley's Muy
Thai prodigies. He's, you know, he,
I just gave him his purple belt.
We were working on like,
I'm not very good at the RM and gear team,
but we started three months ago.
I really started adding it
in and I'm not that good.
I started adding it into a weekly
workouts, just working on the squeeze.
It's getting,
putting people in the guard
arm and Guillotine cinched
in and the guy on top has
to defend and the guy on the bottom is
working on his sleeves, were just working.
That working, the ending of that
guillotine. I'm not that good at it,
but I didn't want my guys to be stuck
at it too and the and the arm and
guillotine. Any gay teens
are so important, especially
in Nma and the scrambles.
You really don't,
you really can't set up a good team.
The gates and you just got to snatch
it and it's gotta be under the Chin and
then you got to know how to close
it and twist it and tinny love.
Nate Diaz is bad ass.
Was that where he got it with one arm?
He had one arm just since through and he
knew he was not going to lose that arm.
His squeezes tight and he tucked that
one on through and then he adjusted his
hands and for people to train to get to
like if you've trained over 10 years,
maybe even at five years,
you can tell when a guy owns a move,
like before he got the tap, the way he
wrapped it up, the way he, cause it took,
you know when he wrapped up the neck it
probably took another 20 seconds to get
the tap. Maybe something like that.
There's a battle. Got Something
pretty quick. It wasn't right away. He
was battling with it for awhile. Made me,
I would say maybe 10 at the earliest,
maybe 2015 but during that period when
Jamillah was fighting the gear team,
you can just tell the way. Nick was like,
damn, I never do good things like that.
It's a one arm good team.
You know Einstein does one arm good
is the one that Chris Brady got it.
Just a basic and Ghia team and you
see how long Nate's arms are too.
That's one of the bad. How's
things about, I was guilty and he,
he put Marcus Davis Hall
with a good team too. Yeah,
he catches a lot of guys with that.
That's his shit for sure.
It's tight when he mounts you
too. God dammit. That's what I,
that's a thing of beauty.
That's beautiful and people that
don't train out there that try it.
You got to understand that. I'm just
like a video game. My video game analogy,
not everybody can,
even though most people,
most black belts can probably figure
out that guillotine and teach it that.
What Nick Diaz is doing that to have
it down so good that you can put it on
another black belt, a guy trained to
defend all that shit all the time.
Defense is way easier than
off fence to pull it off.
You have to put so much time into that,
move into that transition into the,
that movement in the squeeze and the bend.
There's so much that needs to be polished.
Not Very, there's not that. I mean,
in the UFC I would say
maybe there's at Max, uh,
10 guys that have a guillotine as good
as Nate Diaz, like that one. I mean,
you just don't see it. Even 10
shields, Jake shields, you know,
Jake shields is got a nasty
gear too. Yeah. But the one,
the one that Nate did the one down so
good. You could do it with one arm. Well,
Jake does the one arm. He, yeah,
you're right. You're right.
I remember he got Nick Thompson with a
one arm. Yes, definitely. Definitely.
I would say,
or it wasn't a drug for Jake.
Shields has one of the best
squeezes in the game. Yeah,
sure. Caught Robbie Lawler.
And with the [inaudible], he
gets a hold of next. It's,
he's a dangerous motherfucker.
The crazy thing about the guillotine is
it's probably the easiest choke to learn
yet. So few people have mastered it to
the point where they're finishing, uh,
people in big MMA fights,
but people don't realize.
Also there's a whole bunch of weird
different grips that people use for these
techniques to which greatly
alter the way you apply pressure.
It's all about what you're used to.
I mean,
you could make really any grip
work cause there's probably about,
I'm going to say I'm just
throwing this number out,
five to eight different gay teens
out there. Maybe there's four,
maybe there's not five off the top of
my head. Maybe there's more that I,
I just lost track of.
There's the Marcella teen,
there's the regular Armand [inaudible],
there's the arm and gates in the den.
He lives with the inverted Pretzel Grip.
Um,
there's de Verdad Pretzel
Grippers to Shit. Yeah.
I just watched a video of Marcello
explaining why he uses this grip for this
team and it makes a lot of sense.
I made a lot.
A lot of sense. When you go
in, right? You're going into
guys justice here, right?
They're going to defend like this,
right?
So they're going to hook the
outside that they're going to,
they're going to be between you and
your arm right here. See that? Right?
So you make room and then you
could stick this one on top.
See if you were going to do, uh,
like let's say this grip here,
they're hands are right here.
They're stopped.
They're stopping for folks on Itunes,
we're describing a bunch of different
ways to squeeze someone's neck.
Do you understand? I told him I
need this space. If I go this way,
I need this space. But that's where
their hands are going to be, right?
So Marcello's wise, he needs the
space in between my hand and the body.
I govern that. So even if you grab my
hand here, I could still pass this.
For the folks who are listening at home,
what he's doing is changing the way his,
his hand is in relationship to his
body where you squeeze a person's neck,
it's all about squeezing their neck. It's,
it's amazing how technical over this.
So people really don't know how
technical it is. I mean the,
the actual technique that's involved
in Jujitsu, it's, it's, it's,
it's a,
it's really an amazing and fascinating
sport cause it's like an expanded game of
chess. It's more fascinating than
chess because, and you said this,
you were the first person
to ever said that much.
Someone was talking about
Jujitsu be in chess and you said,
yeah,
but it's with chess pieces like
this piece can only go like there,
you know,
or this piece can only though with Jujitsu
it's bodies and strength and all this
other stuff. It's like you like it's way
crazier than chess. And I was like, yeah,
you know, you really stop and think
about chess. Checkers, competitive.
I mean you're, you're dealing with, I'm
thinking you're dealing with technique,
you're dealing with strategy
and he's dealing with patients.
You're dealing with Breanne,
knowledge of positions,
knowledge of the next
step to the next step.
Knowledge of if this guy does try to
count and he's going to do this and then
I'm going to do that.
And then if he does that,
the only thing left for him
is to leave this. You know,
when you have these little steps
that you have in your head,
if you're an intelligent person
and you could think far ahead,
and if you're going to go against the go,
doesn't have that,
you'll always be one step ahead.
So your mind is an important
factor in the whole equation.
It's not just about brute strength,
it's about knowledge and position and
keeping your fucking head together while
it's all going on. For people
who don't train, man, God,
you're missing out on a really fun
thing in life. It's a fun thing.
It's so weird fucking fun way to exercise.
I've said this before,
you find your nearest Jujitsu school. It
doesn't matter if it's 10th planet. Hey,
if there's a 10 planets, schooling
your city, join it. Y'All, you know,
you're going to deal with a bunch of open
minded, fun, loving, uh, computer nerds,
man that liked to, to play games of
death. You know what I mean? But fine.
If there's no 10 plan in
school, fine. Amy School,
just any Jujitsu is better than
no Jujitsu. It's so much fun.
It's the ultimate video game. I always
say that, but man, it's so damn true.
And what ends up is you end
up the people that can hang with
sparring without getting, uh, you know,
and they get tapped and they
don't get all crazy and all burnt.
Most people take it personal when they
get tapped it there, when they tap out,
they feel like their weakness has been
exposed and they run from the gym and
they don't want to tap out in front
of other people. It's so crazy,
their egos out of control.
But the people that do stay are the
people that can handle getting tapped and
they keep their ego under control and
it's all, it's all a mental game. You,
you end up with a great group of guys
that, you know, you could trust generally,
you know, douchebags do filter
through, but generally they'll,
they'll end up getting cut out. You're
just left with a bunch of great guys,
you know. And one thing,
one thing that, um, uh,
that, that, you know,
Jujitsu becomes so much a part of your
life that after five years all your
friends train Jujitsu,
you end up like cutting out the friends
that really don't train that much and,
and most of your friends end up coming
from the Jujitsu circle cause there's
like a such a giant pool of great
dudes, you know, it's, it's amazing.
It is true. You know, and
uh, it's a lot of dudes who,
I have a lot of friends that don't do
Jujitsu like Joey and Brian and Ari.
Joey wants to though he's,
he's been wanting to like
Joey's a big fan of Jujitsu.
If he was in shape, I bet
he would be into. Joey loves
Jujitsu. He's all about it.
But you know, he's got a lot of shit going
on, man. The guy's a busy dude. You know,
he's busier than ever lately,
but the cool Joey's headline and
all over the country now he's,
he's headed down to, uh, if you want to
see Joe, he's in Scottsdale this weekend.
Scottsdale, Arizona. I don't
know the name of the club,
but if you go to Joey's Twitter, I'm sure
he puts it up on his Twitter call them.
Is that what you're saying? You
think your phone at work? Yeah.
I got two bars.
Give it a shot.
We have the most [inaudible]
one bar signals up your socket.
But uh, but anyway, Joe,
we got this gigantic fucking standing
ovation when we were in New York this
weekend. Man. People love that dude.
It was, it was amazing. I got it.
Here it was. It was incredible, man. He
went on stage. They were right at the top.
No,
he didn't even go at the top when we had
Dunkin go up for us this time and that
Joey and then Joey went up. God
Damn Dude, he fucking crushed it.
This is New York. Yeah.
This is like for a minute.
This is Joey standing on stage.
Dude,
that sounds like a Coldplay. Countless
ones. This is just Joey standing on stage.
That's all he's doing. He just walked
out onto the stage. You hearing this?
This goes on for a minute,
dude. That's something
like a phenomenon, right?
Yeah. And I go, wow,
that's incredible. That's,
that's some rock and roll comedy
right there. That was crazy.
You've been saying it forever
and you've known him longer
than I have and you've always said he
was the funniest guy on the planet and I
started to agree with you back in 2005
when I got to really get to know him and
it makes me funnier. Joey Diaz brings the
party. He makes me feel better. You know,
it was really funny. I love
my manager. He's the best of,
have never had another event, one manager
since the time I was an open miker.
But when we were talking about the show,
they were like,
we think you'd be better
if you got introduced off
camera. You know, if you just,
you,
they just say your name and you come out
clean because otherwise like this guy's
introducing you and people like, who's
this guy? And I'm like, oh no, fuck away.
Joey's pregnant me up.
Like Joey's bringing me up.
The Joey always brings me up
with Joe when I worked with Joey.
I have more fun when I work with Joey.
It's more laughter. It's more hugs,
it's more, everything's
funner. And you know,
you know when he says funniest is cause
you know he's known for the Joey karate
reviews and all that stuff and,
and he says some funny ass shit.
But just like us, like when we were
talking about fighters, we can't,
we don't really say the same shit we
would if we weren't on air. Right.
You know what I mean?
Cause cause the things guys say to each
other about a fight and about a fighter
that crushed,
we would never say like 70%.
It's just like we're being real
on the phone. When Joey calls me,
he calls me Saturday,
he called the Saturday after the UFC
and he's fucking stoned to the gills.
Barely awake. He's like, he's like, I
can't even say it. I can't even say it.
But he just crushes people.
Yeah.
You can't say what he says but
he's always saying it to be fun.
Funny Shit.
That
shit was so funny.
People will never get to,
he never get to hear the best
shit shit that he could never say
only. And it's a fighter
like from like Uganda and he,
he's Joe is never going to run
into him and he's on his way out.
Like he just got cut. It was a fighter
that just got cut and never had a chance.
It will never come back.
The enjoyment then it might be
okay to give the green light dude.
He could say shit onstage that no one
else could ever say stage. Exactly.
He could say crazier shit stays in it.
Camp podcast on stage.
You can get away with
staging and get away with it.
But on a podcast you've got
to represent you on stage.
You could just be material
cause the real funny shit,
the Shit Talk Shit with your friends
on the street in New York when you're
getting deep and there's no fucking
rules and there's no one's recording shit
dude,
one time of the Goddamn comedy store,
Joey Diaz and this is in front
of a mixed audience, not just,
he's talking about some defensive
line and some strategy and football.
There was a night of a thousand nigger
and he's saying this on stage in front of
a, a mixed crowd. Joey Diaz crazy.
He doesn't give a fuck.
It was a long time.
He probably doesn't even remember that
there's so much of his best shit you'd
have to like remind him of.
He's like,
he's so free flowing when you're so he
can just go on and on about any subject
and it becomes hilarious. I think Joey
being, you know, a hundred percent Cuban,
I think a super Latin guy
with that New York. Oh yeah,
you can say Nipd g h I think
black people let him say,
are you really spelling it out?
Instead of saying it, dude,
I don't want people coming after me.
Dude.
It's become the new Mohamad
wouldn't even say that he met quite
to have never said Nig ga. Wow.
I won't go there. Wow. That's
amazing. What a powerful
word. Oh No, actually he did.
I'm sorry you wrote a song about it.
I was wrong.
For people who don't know Eddie is,
Eddie and I have been friends for a long
time and one time before I knew Eddie,
I would have advised
him against doing this.
He made a video and he made a video
of him playing a wrapper that whereas
actually, whereas black face, and it
was, the concept's really fucking, it's,
it was pretty funny mad it,
but people got really mad at you.
People got really miss
playing the concept.
The concept was that this
guy was pretending that he
had Videle Lygo and that he
was just, he had a cover his
whole body. Yeah. Just like
Michael Jackson. So he had,
he was just,
the makeup was just to balance out the
real color of his skin because he's
really black. It's like, it's crazy,
but here's like total black there.
Yet until he's wearing like black man, I
mean, it's ridiculous. And he's getting,
he had an Afro Wig on, right? An
Afro Wig. Yeah. Yeah. Well, um,
the characters, like he curled
his hand. It wasn't a wig.
He's just curled his hair and he's
only wearing blue. You when you did it,
did you curl your hair and
you have like a separate like
biography for the character?
The character actually.
Oh did I have is since I got a
home movie of how he ended up,
he ended up with the makeup.
It's the whole store. I got dude,
I got a story before he was even born.
His mother and his father like how
they got together and then had him.
He goes dude,
is that one of the reasons why you won't
say the word don't just the word Nigga.
You know what after I, I, I just came up
with that. I got really stoned one night,
this is in 2000 I was
watching a Michael Jackson.
I was watching Barbara Walters
interview Michael Jackson,
that famous interview and she, she asked
the hard questions. She said, Michael,
when you look, what do you see when
you're looking at me here? My uncle,
she asked him that and he goes,
Barbara, I don't look in the mirror.
And I was like Whoa.
And then he started in this interview,
you explained that the reason he has
all the white makeup is cause he has a,
a logo is a, he has it all over
his face, which by the way,
he very might well have
and, or have had, you know,
I in for people to not, I have it, he
could see them in narcos. Like I have my,
my knuckles like really white. You just
don't see it on much on me because,
cause I'm a white guy and he
was telling Barbara Walters did,
it was all over his body.
And so the brown spots that remained here,
he decided to like bleach those out
and then cover all this skin with you.
That's true. We'll do that. That
could all be true. But there's,
but there's black people that have,
but there's black people that have that
a logo and they're all white and they
choose the brown makeup.
Can you chose the white makeup?
He didn't have to choose why
anyways. Right. You know,
but if you look, if he did,
I think in his case,
if he's to be believed his,
he would've had to have
makeup all over his body.
Apparently he believes his whole body or
something. Yeah. Well, there's sprints.
There's some severe cases of it. There's
a lot of, it's stress. It's nutrient,
and that's one of the reasons, by the way,
my Videle lag. Oh, completely stopped.
And once I started taking vitamins,
hardcore completely stopped.
I believe it never spread. Who's more
stressed out than Michael Jackson? Yeah.
I almost went to jail from a lesson boys.
But anyway,
even if he does have a good excuse
for his face being all white,
you know what I mean?
Then you add all the other stuff.
The guy straightens his hair out.
He got nine nose jobs,
facial reconstruction to me,
nobody wanted to be white
more than Michael Jackson.
He want her to be white more than anybody.
And he got away with it in increments
because everybody that is around them,
no one's gonna. No one's
going to say, Michael,
what the fuck are you doing in your face?
They're out of the circle,
they get cut out.
So He's surrounded by a bunch of guys.
Like every time he did something
to his face or whatever,
people didn't even notice
it. It said, Ms Mr. Jackson,
your three o'clock cause here Mr. Jackson,
we've got some more boys in the backyard,
Mr. Jackson. You know what I mean?
They have a question him, they get cut
out. No one's sat him down and said,
dude look at the fucking mirror.
You look like an alien.
He kept just chopped. He
just kept going, kept going,
kept building fucking carnival
rides and all that shit. So to me,
the character back to the character,
I was watching this Barbara
Walters special and I thought,
what if a guy did it in reverse?
What if there was a white guy that wanted
to be black so bad that he used the
same excuse? Have you seen this video
of the tanning lady from New Jersey?
I saw a picture of her dude,
dude, you got to see the injury.
You haven't seen the interview. Nah,
you're not going to fucking believe this.
There is a lady who tan so much.
She's black, like Denzel Washington.
Dude. Wow. She's a white
chick and she's black as fuck.
It looks like a Saturday night
live parody. It totally does.
So it doesn't even look real. Is there
anywhere I could? Where did I say?
I'm going to pull this up for you. Hold
on. I have to stand down. I'll pull it up.
I'll pull it up a youtube.
I'll just think,
let me see Tammy,
if you go on youtube,
Google or search for
[inaudible] this is still up.
It's still up there too. It's
still up there. Quad tooth. Um,
it's uh, please forgive me.
I did that like 12 years ago.
I didn't realize putting on black,
like putting on black makeup was
like considered like blackface.
Like I didn't know the
whole history of blackface.
I just created a character guy wanted to
be black so bad that he lied to people
until people he had video blog.
But I didn't realize it was like
taboo to put black makeup on. Um, I,
I'm sorry to all my black brothers out
there and people get manager. Yeah.
There's some people that got mad at me,
man, there's some people that got mad.
They thought it was racist.
A lot of people thought I was right.
The guy who put it up on Youtube,
he thought it was racist.
He put it up to like ruin me.
I mean that video was on one
of my first DVDs or it's, yeah,
it's on my first DVD or summer,
my second one.
But I actually didn't put it on Youtube.
A guy who hates me,
who thinks I'm racist.
A white guy who uh,
who just took offense
to it for some summary.
This is real. She took her daughter
tanning apparently this crazy bitch.
But wait til they get to her.
Look at her. Jesus Christ.
Is that the scariest thing
you've ever seen in your life?
Does she think anything's wrong? I have
no idea. She talking about slowing down?
No.
Look at her and for folks who can see,
you don't want to hear this woman's voice
or I would, I would plug in the audio,
but shit,
you don't want to hear this lady's voice.
It will just depress the shit out of here.
And this person has a kid.
She took her kid into the fucking
tanning booths. Apparently.
That's why there they arrested her.
The rest of their, for having her, her,
her kid wants to get like mommy and
become, she looks like an aborigine.
She looks like she's out in the
middle of the woods, by the way.
I think aborigines, you know, I'll
say that. Or is it asking them? Well,
one of those a new thing,
you're not allowed to say.
Someone said, you know, really,
you can't ask him. I'll ask him.
I was bad. It's uh, it's, uh,
if they're working with, if there
were more neighborhoods of Eskimos,
you know what I mean? Then we'd have
something to worry about. Are there,
are you kidding me and Alaska Dude,
not an ally. Incredibly poor in Alaska.
There's Eskimo get ashore. Oh
yeah, for sure man. There's some,
the poorest people you would think
there'd be a, they just like Igloos.
How much does that come? I try to live
life. That's probably racist. Yeah.
You can't say that. Well, I do the jokes.
I mean I make fun of Sarah Pailin and
told her to get back in the Igloo. I mean,
I can't see how that would be. I lose
or you know, for primitive people.
That's why, you know, they're,
they're modern Inuits they're living
in 2012 they have the internet,
they're out there trying to get jobs,
you know,
but a lot of them have the same problems
that American Indians do. You know,
new people came in and took over the land
that their families had been used for
generations and generations is more
equipped for the fucking end then Eskimos
that she wasn't ready for it. How bad
I said then when you think about it,
some people that survived in a place
where it was cold as fuck and they're just
walking around walking around or Negroes
for real and they still make them.
But they had to make now,
I mean,
I'm sure somebody would if
there's bad ass pimp igloos right.
Got that live in caves, man.
I was watching this one thing.
It was a book that someone
read about a man who,
who got done with who he gave up on money.
Have you heard of this dude?
Apparently there's only intelligent guy.
Let me, let me Google this real quick,
but you know they showed this guy,
he's living in a fucking cave.
He gave up on money in like
2003 he just said, fuck this.
I don't want to deal with money anymore.
I'm just going to live off dumpster
diving and eating fucking roadkill.
I would rather live in a fucking one
bedroom. Egl did a fucking cave. Dude.
Are you kidding me?
Completely retarded.
But you stop and think about the snake
for the, came from land of the lost.
Remember? That's a good cave, right?
What are those animals that
were [inaudible]? It was
all lit up in there. Yeah.
What were those things called? Clean
stacks. Yeah. I would live in that cave.
That's it. You would look, that's
it. That's it. That's the only,
that's the best cave I've ever seen.
That show was so stupid.
I believed that.
Yeah.
This dude on survivalists.com apparently
he's an intelligent guy too. He just,
whatever,
for whatever fucking weird reason,
he just decided to just give
up or if that was a gimmick.
You know how he's famous now? He's
getting laid. It's a blogger. Just tell.
Just tell people you live in
case he blogs in the library,
but he completely gave up on
money. Yeah, he's a fucking idiot.
Look, money gets you soap and it's a
way that we exchange worth. Yeah, it's,
it's not perfect.
There's some socks.
But what you told me you wouldn't
want to watch game of Thrones.
You don't want to watch that show you.
You're an asshole. What's wrong with you?
It's fucking amazing. It's an incredible
work of art and it's on, you know,
HBO get a job so you could pay for
Hbo. You dumb. Fuck you cave dwelling,
asshole. You're missing
out on so much. Cool Shit.
Have you ever had beats by Dr Dre
headphones on? Have you ever wore those?
You'd dummy? No. Are those cool?
They're fucking amazing and yeah,
they're great too. And they'd noise
cancel when you're on airplanes. Dude,
they got that noise canceling feature.
So all you hear is the
sound you get taken away,
especially if you eat a pot cookie
before you get to the airport.
And he timed it perfectly,
you know,
beats by Dr Dre and this asshole,
no money asshole.
He's never going to experience that.
If you've never experienced being way too
high in a plane listening to some Jimi
Hendrix while you got your eyes closed,
while you're really freaking out,
you feel yourself kind of freaking out
because you're way too high to just be
hanging around a bunch
of people you don't know.
Laying down side by side
next to some total stranger,
there's some total stranger I could
reach over and touch them with my pinky,
like I have to stay all cuddled up so
that I don't roll over and touch this
total stranger.
Maybe we don't know the whole story.
Maybe like his wife fucked his son or
something and he's was like, fuck that.
You know, something horrible.
You know, maybe. Yeah, we,
there's gotta be some more,
more to it for you to give
up everything going to cave.
Your wife had her do some evil
shit. Maybe not. Maybe it's just,
it's a fucking dumb dude. You know?
Maybe he's just crazy. Who knows?
The world is filled with fucking
crackpots man is the world is filled with
people that think they got it nailed and
they found some new righteous course,
you know? Or the guy might
genuinely like being alone outside.
Who knows?
You know,
maybe foraging for food is the only thing
that keeps him from being depressed.
I don't know,
man.
There's some people that feel like they
don't get enough out of living everyday
life the way everybody else lives it.
Maybe this guy has some weird sense of
danger because he's out there live in
like with no roof over his head and
Kate use maybe that actually does give a
little spark inside of him. I'm just
talking shit. Hey, what do you think?
What do you think about what
they're saying on the Internet?
It could be totally bullshit,
but it seems like it's real.
It seems like all the
presidents are all related. Oh,
I've seen those.
I mean it's not been proven to be a hoax.
I think we should go to snopes.com
right? Nope. If that's real.
If because on,
on uh,
Obama on camera is talking about him
being related to Dick Cheney or or yes.
Yes. On camera. In an interview
they ask them about it.
Could you imagine if like that David Eick
dude was right and they're all really
reptilians. Could you imagine
if life really was like a,
a comic book movie? You know, Obama
said on camera, he's on camera,
he's like on some show and he goes,
yeah,
that's more of like the Reptilian side
of my brain that would react like that.
He said some shit like that.
Then I'm sure David Eick is
fuck has heads explode them.
When you hear shit like that,
you know, it w it appears,
it appears there's so much evidence in
different TV shows and news reports on
it.
News reports that George Bush is
related to fucking like kings.
There, there is a blood line,
there is a royal blood line,
and that all these guys that are
precedent, they're part of the, uh,
the 13 royal bloodlines.
How crazy is that?
It's pretty crazy.
What if it's true?
What if it's true that they're all related
and it's all like a royal family and
elections are just a
big fucking act easier.
It'd be amazing if they could
pull it off like that. You know,
it was funny how some people like
Brian Cowen, I love him to death,
but he never believed in conspiracies.
Neb believes no conspiracies.
But when we were talking about
Osama bin Ladin one thing, uh, he,
he believed that there was a conspiracy
on the Pakistani side and that they had
had Osama bin Ladin tucked away,
like near this big military
base. You know, for years
they haven't talked to him.
They knew about it,
but they kept their mouth shut even
though there was like a $30 million bounty
on his head.
I can't believe the Pakistanis that
there was a conspiracy on their side,
but that there was no conspiracy on
the American side. Hilarious. His,
his, his, his vision of it has to
always be Fox News. I love the Guy,
don't get me wrong, but it's, it's a,
it's a fascinating thing how he, uh,
he has this sort of, I mean, it's great
to have a guy like that on your side.
I wonder,
I wonder if he'd been tower.
Do you know if he thinks tower seven
fell because of fires? Oh yeah, he does.
He thinks of her fires like that.
He goes by the Popular Science reports,
Hearst publications that uh, the debunked
everything, all the nine 11 things.
The real, the real thing about
nine 11. The first two towers.
Don't freak me out as far as like you,
how, how did that possibly happen?
We've never seen a full jet airliner slam
into a giant building like that before.
We've never seen it. We've never
seen two of them happen side by side.
We'd never seen buildings that were
that tall before. Not only now.
We never seen buildings that were
that tall and that were made in when,
what were they made in
the sixties or something?
When the fuck did they make
the world trade centers?
I have so long fucking time ago. Right,
so these gigantic hundred and 10 foot,
110 story when my Hubby,
how big are those fucking things?
I mean they were incredibly Beatty.
Some stories or something.
Just think about how a hundreds years,
a hundred more than a hundred more than
a hundred that just think about how many
fucking stacks of metal,
something like that is and what
our content that is to clean up.
Imagine if that's the big conspiracy
that it was done because those fucking
things were falling apart
and the construction company
is to what it did it they
flew the planes in because they just
didn't want to be responsible for what
happened whenever they
just fell out on that.
Did the high wire from tower one tower
two he did a high walked around the,
I can't believe that. Is that what
the flying we'll lenders? No, no.
It's called the something.
Dude.
I can't watch that shit. Dude did it
illegally. Oh my. He set it all up.
No one was going to let that shit happen.
They secretly went on online.
They measured all the shit.
They fucking made it happen.
How did they get the wire in
between the two times? It was,
it was a very complicated,
there was like five people involved.
Can you imagine that shit?
How crazy that guy and that guy,
tight rope across tower one to tower two.
Then I got a hundred stores or something.
Alan saying as that guy
didn't did it and it worked.
I'm pinching my Dick together as you
say this, I'm like my legs. I'm like,
now I'm asking. Okay, so you said
basically we don't know. You know the,
the planes could easily
caused those skyscrapers,
but the crazy thing is most people,
most people don't know that there
was three towers that went down.
Three tower seven was
a 47 storey skyscraper.
That five different angles on camera
went down like a controlled demolition.
I mean, what does that mean? What
could that possibly mean? They control,
it takes weeks to set up a control demo.
1500 engineers and architects are all
banding together and they all say that
there's, that was a controlled
demo. How is that possible?
Why would you demo a skyscraper the
same day those towers went down?
It doesn't make any sense.
There's a lot of unanswered questions
as some fishy ass shit going.
Unfortunate that there is
so much fish. Yeah, Shit.
And it goes like when you look into
the whole Pentagon missile thing,
it's one of those things to me where
someone starts talking to me about,
there's a missile it depending on,
it wasn't a plane,
it was a missile at the Pentagon.
Just my instincts,
my automatic instincts are okay,
this guy's kind of a crackpot.
This guy's a little bit
crazy with the conspiracies.
I don't know what the fuck
at the Pentagon, you don't
either. Second was a muscle.
They've never released any of the footage.
I saw the footage they release.
It was only like a couple of frames.
I couldn't tell what the fuck it was.
It could, I don't know. Maybe
it was a plane.
I don't know what it looks like when you
take a picture of a plane that's going
500 miles an hour,
a foot off the ground.
I don't know what the fuck
that looks like. I don't know.
But when you find out that they really
did have the accounting offices right
there and that they really were trying
to cover up some incredible missing
money. What was, how much money was
it? Two point 3 trillion trillion.
Two point 3 trillion.
It was just announced by Donald Rumsfeld
the day before that there was a problem
and the two point $3
trillion is essentially been
swindled and they were going
to get to the bottom of it.
Well,
the office where they're going to get to
the bottom of it gets hit by a fucking
projectile that blows a hole through
the side of the building and into the
courtyard. Kills all the accountants.
That's incredible. Isn't that crazy?
That is one of the greatest all time.
Like if you wanted to have
like a conspiracy where
there's actual evidence that
makes you go, what the fuck does,
could it be? Could they be this crazy?
Could it be this crazy? What happened
to that two point 3 trillion?
It was it ever addressed again? Yeah.
And there's, you know, do you know,
or is that what happened to that
money and was it ever addressed them?
That'll have to do who's
going to address it?
But immediately I want to be when
you, when you, even if you, you know,
have an event like nine 11 after
the dust settles, you know,
so to speak, no pun intended, you would
think that after a while people would go,
oh yeah, that two point 3
trillion. What's up with that?
People know that some scary shit going on.
People know that,
that whoever pulled that shit off,
if you try to bust anybody out,
you're gonna die. You're
gonna die. So everyone just
keeps the fucking mouth shut.
They know is fishy, you
know? And then that,
the crazy thing is that you hear about
this Breitbart thing. What is that?
They're an Andrew Breitbart.
The Guy who died really recently is a
very controversial journalists character.
He apparently had some video that he
was going to release about Barack Obama,
and it was Barack Obama. And there
was some video that was released,
a Barack Obama giving like some sort
of a speech when he was younger,
when he was in college, I think when he
was at Harvard. And uh, just, you know,
it wasn't really that radical
at all. You know, it's like,
and but the word was that he was going
to release something that was going to be
damaging. Well, the fucking dude
ones up dying, right? No big deal.
He wasn't that healthy.
You'll look at him,
he's kind of big fat guy and he probably
had some bad Karma and you know,
there's a lot of wild shit going.
A dude's life is his ticker might've been,
who knows? Right. So the guy dies, rest
in peace. Um, and then after he dies,
his fucking corn or dies by poisoning.
So after his corner says
that it's natural causes,
then the coroner dies by
poisoning and then you go, okay,
what? That's when he got
to go. What is it? I mean,
I don't want to believe that the
government or who the fucking scene or the
Moussad or anybody decided to kill this
journalist and then they paid off his
corner and then the coroner winds up
getting poisoned and killed or they,
they threatened him or they use their
influence or whatever the fuck it was.
But when you hear a story
like that, God damn, it makes me go,
is anybody checking on this? Is it,
Oh, who's looking into that?
That seems, that's a little,
I would like to sit down with everybody
involved in that sort of a situation.
If I was, if I was the mayor
or the governor or whatever,
whoever the fuck would be the one who
would have jurisdiction over something
like that, I'd like to be the
guy who sits down. He goes,
what the fuck is going on here? Yeah.
And, and the Pentagon thing, they're like,
if a plane of is like a seven 47,
a commercial airline hit that, uh,
there've been lots of
planes that went down.
And what you find is a big giant
chunks of the Fuchsia Lodge and,
and, and suitcases and seats and
tennis shoes in legs and body parts.
That's what happens when a plane crashes.
There was none of that shit.
And the only pictures that they show, like
the debunker side, they show pictures,
but like real tight shots
of like, uh, burned, uh,
airplane tire and then they show next to
it. This is what it really looks like.
It's the same room. Yeah. Where is that?
Where did you even take that picture?
Give me a shot from,
from way back and show me all.
Show me that it's the Pentagon.
Why you showing that? The evidence,
our pictures up close.
You don't know where that is.
A dark room and you're seeing like, oh,
here it says United and the only shot,
by the way,
it would be very easy if the government
wanted to release Photoshop images or
images of other pieces of wreckage and
claiming how many people really had
access to the Pentagon at that day.
How many people were running around and
taking pictures along and I played it.
That's incredibly restricted.
So it's not like it was open season for
journalists to come and check everything
out with cameras.
So whatever photos they have,
who the fuck knows what really happened?
And then there's another photo where
it's like you see the lawn and there's a
little strip of like American
airlines like bitch, how eat,
show me everything all in
one big shot of everything.
Don't show me up close pay
Tony Metal of everything. Yeah,
a piece of metal up close. You are
you telling me that that's evidence?
That's not evidence.
They,
they must have like had like really
detailed images of every single app.
If that was an attack,
they would have detailed images of every
single aspect of that thing that they
can know.
One of the main witnesses,
the chick that was the black chick
that was on Jesse Ventura show and they
didn't that she said there was no
plane. She walked over, she goes,
she thought it was the whole time.
It was a bomb because I was no evidence
of any wreckage or seats or luggage and
binder. What kind of record you would
get though. You know, they have shown,
they've taken fighter jets and they've
remote controlled flied them remote,
flew them into a gigantic blocks of,
of concrete.
They're like built this huge
wall of concrete and they
flew jets into it and the
jets just incinerate.
It's really crazy. Like,
but I think they're going like way
faster and they're way smaller. Yeah.
It's a different experience.
If you look at nine one, one,
like a detective with an open mind and,
and you have to know what an open minded
first look at it like a detective would
like you're a c CSI. Look at all the
facts. Don't just say, oh, those,
those conspiracy kooks conspiracy nuts.
That's
not what a detective, uh, you'd get fired
right away by the way. You,
you've got to realize folks,
and this is absolutely 100% positive.
There are people that work
for the government that are
involved in what's called
disinformation.
And one of the things that they will do,
and this is a very smart
tactic and very clever,
they will mix truth with ridiculous
bullshit that automatically makes you look
like a Kook. So if, if you're, uh,
if you're reading something and it sounds
really good and fascinating and then
completely ridiculous all at the
same time, like someone, they,
then they throw something about alien
bases on the moon and that they have,
you know, the transcripts of these
aliens communicating with people.
Like then you go, okay, listen to this
fucking crazy bitch. Like, oh man,
they ain't no aliens on a fucking
moon communicating with Ronald Reagan.
You know, what do you, what do
you, what are you talking about?
But they'll mix some
real truth about the CIA.
So real truth about the way things are
run and that way it diffuses all those
real truths in people's minds.
You associate that shit with big foot
and psychics and it's just a bunch of
crazy silly thinking that is
a, as a, as a a full grown man,
I don't have time for, you know,
becomes one of those things. It's a,
it's a really clever thing.
So when you hear a naughty story,
we hear someone who's saying something
completely ridiculous but also makes
sense at the same time,
they're probably government
agents. Who knows, right?
If I've been accused of being a government
agent. That's amazing. That's awesome.
That's how they would do it.
They would train me up through the ranks
of being a fucking comedian and then
get me indicates fighting commentary
and then recruit me to save America from
the bad guys.
Can you imagine what kind of a government
agent, what I be telling everybody,
go smoke some weed. Relax,
do Jujitsu. Don't be greedy.
Don't be a [inaudible]. Back
to the original question.
Like there's a question.
Yeah. Why do you remember?
How do you fucking,
how do you feel about every president
being related and part of the bloodline?
Um, if it is true, what
doing good stuff research.
If you go to my youtube
page and go to my playlist,
I got the Illuminati playlist.
Go to the,
like the last one I added in the
last two. It's in deep shit, man.
I mean there's the president's
actually telling you he's related.
Like George Bush is related to,
uh,
like a bunch of people in politics now
and like high and the guys like John
Kerry and,
and he's related to John Kerry
or the bullet cousins and shit.
Really? Yeah. Dude. I'm telling you. I'm
telling you man, unless it's all bullshit.
I mean it could be all bullshit. This
could be a total huge hope. Well,
I'm going to uh,
behind the matrix.com
so let's see what they
have to say about it.
You got to see Obama saying it himself.
He's related to Dick Cheney. Dude.
How crazy is that?
They're talking about it on a show
that's not like some CGI shit with a
different Obama.
Obama is saying he's related that Dick
Cheney and then it goes deeper than that.
George W.
Bush is related to like old,
like kings and czars and shit.
Hmm. Wow. Okay.
This is the,
yeah,
there were apparently 44 men who are
president of the USA are related.
How crazy is this really true?
That's what I'm,
that's what I want to know is this,
is this Bob bullshit yards of all 43
presidents being related and this is just
randomly happen or billions to me.
Huh?
A billion to one is that, is
that the number? Didn't know.
The guy's saying billions. It's
just someone's editorial, I believe.
I don't know if he's right.
Oh, sources. Look Kaye, cnn.com
Google Illuminati bloodline or
youtube Illuminati bloodlines, dude.
And just like Herman Cain
related to people too,
they're all related according to the shit.
Most of the presidents are all related.
They're all part of the same blood line.
How fucking nutty is. That's
ridiculous. Ridiculous. Riley be true.
If it's true, do we really are the
matrix dude, really? Our Vanilla,
Rowdy Roddy Piper will be totally right.
That movie them or day or whatever day
it was at. It was a fun movie, man.
I haven't seen it, but one of my students,
Dave Callahan was telling me about it.
He said, I need to watch it.
Wow, this is so ridiculous.
Are you finding out more information?
It's just, it's ridiculous.
It's just hard to believe.
Exactly.
But when you see Obama Search Obama,
Dick Cheney,
okay.
Video, uh, blood, uh, cousins,
Obama, cousin Dick Cheney.
And then you'll see them talking about it.
This is what their dos,
this is really weird,
man.
Yeah.
The uh, yeah. Uh, what's all right, I
just, and he's coming over to take a look.
It's just the different
websites or point to that.
I still honestly can't say that. I
don't, I, I don't really know. It's true.
I don't think you should be, uh, just
reading something online and spouting off.
That's true of doing that too many times
in the past and been completely wrong.
No, no, no. I know. I know. That's
why I'm going to, I'm going to say,
I'm going to send you a link Rabia
theory. Why don't you ask Siri? Siri says,
Siri. Yeah. That's, you don't
want to share. See if it,
we'll see what that bitch knows.
Put her, put her at ease. Right now.
I'm going to find the video. I'm going
to call Siri. Okay, here it is. Um,
uh,
I'm going to send you the link.
I could send it to you and you'll be
able to play it. Yeah. Okay. What is it?
Wait a minute. You'll send it
to me. How a t email. No, no,
I don't have that set up like that.
What do you want me to play?
Just the beginning of,
I want you to hear Obama talking about
how he's cousins with Dick Cheney. Oh,
I don't even want to hear that little.
Now he's sick. He says it. I believe it.
He's so, he's some somehow
or another, some distant
cousin with Dick Cheney. Yeah.
But then it gets deeper.
It's almost like someone, uh,
someone dug that out and he asked to
talk about, and he has to admit it,
but it goes deeper than all.
Relate it up. That's what
it's saying, dude. Everybody's related.
Like George Bush is related to Obama.
They're all part of the royal blood line
that goes back to ancient Sumeria. Wow.
Yes. Yes. This is a word doc.
Elliptic shaped the rulers. It's just like
a Hollywood club, right? The promoters,
when they're, when they're new club dies,
just like the ancient scenario died.
When they're new.
They're eighth cousins.
Obama and Dick Cheney or eighth cousins.
Yeah,
and look at type in George W.
Bush cousins press.
Did you hear what Obama said when they
will, they gave them the revelation.
He goes, every family has a
black sheep. Boom son, suck it.
He's fun. He's for sure the most
gangster president of all time.
He said some gangster shit like Matt
Damon said that he was disappointed in him
and then you know,
he does those uh,
president's a press speeches where he does
essentially does stand up and he goes,
hey man,
I saw you last movie right back at Ya.
Like the president said, your last
movie sucked dude. And you know,
it's even crazy crazy is that Brad Pitt
and Angelina Jolie are all in the mix
too. They're all related
to the presidents. What did
you see Jimmy Kimmel doing?
A White House speech or doing standup
at the White House and or wherever the
fuck it was. Some mean nuking which is in
the audience. Obama was in the audience,
whatever the fuck official
name of the gathering was.
He started talking about marijuana
legalization. And then it's real.
People care about weed laws.
It's true.
And that's who said that Jimmy Kimmel.
Oh yeah, I heard about that. Yeah.
Jimmy Kimmel is, it was, you know, it
was a really fascinating moment, man.
He's a brave motherfucker for doing that.
It would end any was,
and he's got damn right. You know, and he,
he did what you're supposed to do if you
get an opportunity to do something like
that where it's going to be on
television. He was respectful, you know,
but he was still funny,
you know,
when he was doing a standup and then
when he had a point about marijuana,
he just, he sits, made the point man
that real people care about these laws.
And he didn't go crazy with it and didn't
go too far with it, but he was, he was,
you know, it's fucking true.
It took roast crazies that,
that marijuana was a conspiracy.
It's still is.
It's still fucking is the most amazing
thing in the 2012 there's people out
there that will list all sorts of negative
effects that can have. Listen, folks,
fucking everything you do can have a
negative effect. If you get crazy with it.
We're drinking coffee here. Coffee
can fucking kill you if you're crazy.
And you one of those dudes who just wants
to drink coffee all day and just get
gacked out of your mind
on Venti Starbucks,
you could have a fucking heart attack.
You could like,
you could stimulate yourself to death.
People die from caffeine overdose.
That's a, that's an actual, you
know, fairly regular occurrence.
I think there's something like 10,000
people die every year from aspirin and
caffeine together combined. Something
along those lines. Either way.
Point is it's,
it's the best site ever of a corrupt
government that this magical plants,
you know, and people's own full can
pull it. Heard you fucking queer.
We're all your magic.
What do you want your weed,
you fork can baby kids vibe without weed.
Those people need weed.
First of all. I'm more than
anybody, right? Yeah, definitely.
And, and second of all,
it's,
he don't understand what this really is.
This is a potential life enhancing
substance that is just naturally growing
around people.
And it's been with us for thousands of
years and we have some sort of a physical
symbionic relationship.
We actually have cannabinoid receptors
in our brain that receive cannabinoids
both from cannabis and from exercise.
Your experience could have annoyance.
That's a confusing. People
don't believe that humans,
and not by the way, by the way, there's
the benefits aren't even psychoactive.
One of the best ways to use
marijuana is to actually eat it,
to eat the fresh leaves, the
eat, the leaves and the plants.
It's incredibly healthy for you.
It has zero psychoactive effect
cause it's not the only one.
You have to smoke it or your staff to
cook it into an edible form and then eat
it. But to just eat marijuana. It
doesn't give you the psychedelic effects.
But what it does do,
it's a really incredibly healthy plant.
It has a fuck load of amino acids,
it contains a lot of protein.
Hemp seeds are really good for
it and they fucking tastes good.
Like I like eat hemp seeds all the time,
like I'll eat them as snacks.
I'll be sitting there watching TV and
I'll have like hemp seed and it's,
it's incredible amounts of protein.
It's really healthy and
clean and it's illegal.
It makes the best paper,
makes the best clothes you could
make fucking plywood out of it.
It's virtually indestructible. It's
amazing. It's lighter than wood. It's,
it grows quicker than would, it's
stronger than wood. It's, it's an amazing,
almost an alien being.
It's almost like something there's,
it's not like it's one of the most
useful plants on earth of aside from the
psychoactive effects of it,
when you add the psychoactive effects,
it's the number one use multiuse
full plant on earth most for sure,
because it actually can change people's
lives and make people feel better.
It actually gives you a good feeling
like the everybody needs that.
That's like one of the most
important things we could ever have.
Something in our life that gives us a
good feeling something or alive that makes
us a little more humble. Something in our
life that makes us a little more aware,
something in your life that makes you
a little more appreciative, you know,
these poor fucks.
Horrified.
Did she feel bad for people that
don't want people to smoke weed? Um,
I understand. You know, I was,
I wasn't into it until I was 28,
so I totally understand where they're
coming from. I just, you know,
I don't want to push anybody
into it or anything, but if, uh,
I'm just going to keep doing what I'm
doing and, and let people know that,
you know, most of the important
stuff that I do, almost all of it,
the important stuff I do,
I'm medicated with, uh,
the sacred plant.
I feel if I taught a class
and I wasn't medicated,
that I would be cheating out my students.
I'm way more passionate.
I'm way more passionate when I teach,
when I'm still in way like doing comedy
and you don't have a little weed in you.
You feel like you're,
you're, you're not giving,
you feel like you're at
85 almost sometimes. No.
I like doing sober shows too,
but I smoked so much weed and my
Mri ever really sober, you know,
because it's adjusted the way I act.
Even when I'm sober like playing music,
not stoned.
I couldn't even imagine that.
And it's when I get in my car
and I got like uh, uh, um,
when I'm, when I'm getting,
when I get in my car I just freshly
baked on my way to Jujitsu. Man.
That's when I'm on fire.
That's when like all my
important decisions and ideas
come together on my way to
Jujitsu cause I'm so happy that I'm going
to show up to a place with a bunch of
my boys there and we're going to practice
strangling each other and whatever
music I got to hear music loud is
how on the way that you to loud man,
you know,
like a latest,
like something I'm just working on or
like a new album I just bought. Um,
like you know lately man cause
Bassnectar up my ass man.
That motherfucker is on
fire. Holy Shit. Yeah,
we're supposed to do a podcast
with him. Yeah. End of May.
Like a memorial day weekend.
He either said Monday,
he's free or that Friday. And so it's up
to you Friday or Monday. So he's down.
He loves you, he loves you. He
just wants to hang out and talk.
I want to hang out and talk to him. He
said, let's just have a conversation.
We don't have to record
this. I'm like, oh man.
So don't deprive people of this cool
conversation that's going to be fun.
He's a fascinating guy. So looking forward
to it. It's, I am too, man. Incredible.
That's why I keep emailing you and
going, dude. He's like asking like, dude,
is this going to happen?
Is this going to happen to,
I can't tell you how weird that is for
me. You know, it's, it's weird, you know,
that, uh, when I kinda got celebrities
want to come on the podcast, I mean it's,
it's, it's a weird thing that people are
trying to do it, but it's amazing though.
I couldn't be happier, man.
This is the most like fulfilled,
like as far as like, uh, like
what I'm putting out. Yeah.
Like the most fulfilled I've
ever felt. Yeah. People. I mean,
like he, he just wants, he doesn't want
to talk about music. He's like, dude,
I just want to get on that.
Just talking about the unit might want
to talk about music too, you know,
whatever. You know, I, I love when
people say that like, you know, um,
I'm going to get a Mac dancing on the
podcast. I really like Mac. Dan's like,
I've been meaning to contact him so he'll
hear about this or reach out to him.
He's a fascinating dude to me. Really
interesting guy. He's a Vegan and he's a,
and he does it for, for,
because of the animal rights,
like the way he feels about pets and
animals and factory farming and, but, um,
what's interesting is he's going to
talk about anything, but I'm amazed
was like, oh dude, can you
imagine how these UFC fighters,
they must be so sick and tired of talking
about fucking fights and especially
after training twice a fucking
day, six days a week. Yeah.
And I just want to say this to
all my 10 planet heads. Uh, I,
for every
interview I do where I'm
just repeating myself,
I know like my hardcore fans are like,
oh,
he's going to use that analogy
again. Oh, that fucking story again.
You know what I mean? Uh, I just
answered the questions they give to me.
I know I could be repetitive,
I apologize.
But you got to understand there's
always new guys just getting into it,
getting into 10 plan and I got to go
back and give the history again. I'd,
I'd that'll talk about the
music. You know, that, you know,
there's a lot of people out there.
I'll, here he goes with the music again.
I'm sorry,
but I'm gonna talk about the music.
No, it's just, I just want to
let people know that because the,
if I overheard someone saying,
dude,
that guy fucking just says
the same shit over and over,
that wouldn't make me feel good. You
know what I mean? But it's, it's,
it's part of the whole thing.
If you're going to,
you've got to realize that every time
you talk it's probably going to be the
first time a fuck load of people hear you.
And if there's an important
thing that you have to get out,
an important part of your philosophy and
important part of how you got to where
you have to say it. Yeah,
unfortunately. Yeah.
Until you become like Marilyn Manson to
become like super dope. Yeah, totally.
Totally. But I'm always gonna. I'm
always gonna pump the music man. Always.
I got to smoke shop and shirt on a smoke
Sherpa servants plan this Saturday for
my birthday. I'm like, yeah, where
is that? It moved, right? Yeah.
Move to dim mak studios, man. It's a
way better place is way better place.
It's in Hollywood.
I'm on 1643 cosmo.
It's a half a block south of Hollywood
boulevard. It's an awesome place.
Dj Aoki, that's his place. It's
called Denmark's name is Dj. Okay.
Yeah, like Shinya. Yup.
She's huge. Really famous Dj.
Huge. I mean a million
followers, that kind of shirts.
They become famous without
me even knowing they exist.
And then I find them when they have
like a 400 million youtube views,
like I'll go and look and look at one of
their videos on youtube, but I'm like,
what this get this has 100 million views.
What the fuck?
How did I miss this? Whizzed right
behind me. Yeah. He's huge man.
He owns that place. Um, uh, it's, it's
going to be my birthday celebration.
My birthday is actually May 15th,
but that's on a Tuesday.
Can't have a party on a Tuesday.
So it,
me and my girlfriend actually
have our birthdays two days apart.
We're going to celebrate it. Dual thing
Saturday night. Everybody's welcome. No,
cover it up right there.
Everyone's welcome. No cover.
You said the two craziest things you
could ever say on the end. Everything's,
everybody's welcome and we'll cover.
No, I want it to be packed. It's just,
it's going to be packed. I want it
to be packed. We go on at 10 o'clock.
So get the early. Um, a three is,
you're going to get a crazy crowd, dude.
I hope so. And if you don't
know what my band sounds like,
you can go on iTunes and just iTunes smoke
serpent. I got two songs up on iTunes.
A Jujitsu is one song and
dropped as another song. Judo,
there's a video for a Jujitsu as well.
You could find that on youtube. Uh,
smoke serpent this Saturday.
My birthday, everyone's well,
we could add that Bj,
Jay,
Jay Expo is this Saturday a day.
That's when Nick Diaz and Braulio
steamer go at it. Um, they,
you could go watch that and just remember
the after party is at Dimock studios
on Saturday. The show.
It's going to be crazy.
You're going to have a bunch of
people with cats on their tee shirts.
Catt squad cat. Beautiful. Beautiful. Um,
also my wrapper, well one of my
rappers is, his name is Capella.
His name is Eric Cruz. He, uh,
he's uh, he's one of my brown belt.
He's awesome and he's an amazing rapper
and he's really good at Jujitsu too,
cause he's, he's one of my best
friends. I love them to death, man.
He actually fights MMA too.
He's fighting May 20th.
It's on a Sunday.
May 20th at the Nokia Center
is a third, uh, amateur fight.
He's undefeated as an amateur. Um,
there's a show called University of Nma.
It's just a bad ass amateur card,
like three or four 10th planet fighters
are fighting and he's one of them.
His name was Eric Eric Cruz.
He wraps or smoke serpent,
May 20th Nokia Center.
Um,
it's on a Sunday so you don't have to
worry about missing Strikeforce like
Strikeforce as the day before. And it's
the debut also on that amateur show.
The first three fights are
going to be combat Jujitsu.
It's a sport that I
started with Turi Alta via,
he runs university of MMA combat Jujitsu.
It's a brand new sport.
It's going to take people really kind of
scared to do it there that really don't
know what to think of it.
But really combat Jujitsu
is, it's right in the middle.
It's in between MMA and, and just
straight grappling. It's in between.
That was a big hole.
It's Jujitsu with punches on the ground.
When you're standing it's just wrestling.
But as soon as one person is on the
ground, you can start punching. So it's,
you can either look at it as,
you know,
if you're looking at it from the MMA
world, it's pussy MMA. Like, well I can,
they're,
they're too scared to strike standing.
You could look at it as Super Tane MMA,
but if you're coming from the,
the Jujitsu side,
it's extreme Jujitsu.
Imagine watching Abu Dhabi and
they allowed punches on the ground.
How brutal and exciting that
would be. You know, it's,
it's all your perspective
and, um, it's gonna, you know,
since we're piggy backing on the
University of MMA show, you know,
it's the first three fights.
We're opening up the show.
We're just getting into it.
Just, we just got it sanctioned.
We're just starting it. We're
just testing it out. Ultimately,
combat Jujitsu doesn't look good
in a cage. It doesn't, it actually,
it looks better like professional
submission league, Rico chip rallies,
old Dutch show. Then that Hixon
Gracie tournament. We're just,
it's like blood sport. Just a flat mat.
Just like Abu Dhabi, a big flat matte.
That's where combat
Jujitsu is going to shine.
It's going to take a while to become
available. The elbow each other.
No elbows or the body. There's basically
amateur MMA rules on the ground.
You could punch to the face,
no elbows to the face.
Wish they would find a way to pad elbows.
You know the real problem with elbows
and my opinion is not them as a blow.
I like elbows there, bad ass, but then
you know, tell that to Paul Horace.
Then you'd have to like,
but
you'd have to pad shins too. It's
really kind of, then it becomes silly,
but what I keep thinking is
that elbows are so pointy.
They're so good at cutting people open.
How about fucking Alan Belcher's
wicked elbows. Now Boucher is
if you didn't see that fight. Sorry,
spoiler alert. Shut this off real quick.
If you DVR this and you
haven't seen it yet,
you got three seconds to one's
Monday. Fuck them. Fuck them dude.
It's on Fox. Watch that Shit
did Alan Belcher. He went,
he played footsies with Paul Harris.
I couldn't even believe I did a little.
Maybe you were what? You had a bad angle
cause you weren't in the beginning.
You look to you from where you were,
where you were watching it.
If you watch it again,
watch a commentary.
It looked like you thought they were
going for lead glocks, but right away,
right from the get go he
pulled in right into the truck.
It was like a profession.
What I meant by,
he's on the ground by Paul
Harris is attempting leg locks.
That's playing footsies in my
opinion. When you're caught
in the truck, that dude,
it doesn't have any leg locks on you.
Well, he did try a few now there's no,
he didn't even roll a couple times for
the only when he started attacking his
legs, that's when he spun out of the
truck and started. When he got away,
that's when he went after the leg locks.
But while in the truck he was lost.
He didn't know what he was doing. He was
just defending. That was no leg locks.
You look so confident.
It was almost weird.
It was almost like he
couldn't believe that. I mean,
I mean Paul Horez like
when he got taken down,
like what does this guy going to do
to get on the ground? He didn't get,
he didn't take him down. Paul Horace took
our shot, took Alan Belcher down. Yes,
he took her Bahara shot,
took Allen Belts Belcher down and then
Alan Belcher laced in and rolled and got
the, because he got the single winter,
his head on the outside, which is,
he couldn't, Alan Belcher could
have took us back at that point,
but he decided to go to the truck
and it was so crazy to watch.
And for people who don't know, it's just
an unbelievably rare position in MMA,
super common around a 10th planet and
Jujitsu, but really rare, in fact,
so rare that only one guy was ever
submitted with a twister in the UFC.
And that is, um, uh,
the Korean Zombie chance on Junge
submitted Leonard Garcia with it.
But that was no battle from the
truck with Koreans, Koreans,
Abi and went from being on Leonard's
back right directly into the twists are,
there was no battle from the
truck that again, like by the way,
the truck for folks who don't know
what the fuck we're talking about,
it's a position where you have one leg
tied up of your opponent with both of
your legs, his back. But you're at a,
at a perpendicular angle and you're,
you have like what's
essentially a lockdown from
underneath of this guy's leg.
So you got his leg completely stiffened
out and you're sort of controlling him
with it. It's a, it's a,
it's a great position that a lot of
people don't sort of capitalize on.
And it was a rare moment on CBS or
excuse me, on Fox and I say CBS,
Oh shit.
Fox going to be mad.
So rare moment is cause I was trying to
correct my earlier mistake about Jake
shields submitting Nick Thompson because
it was on elite Xc, not Strikeforce.
I kept that shit in the back of my head
all this time. Fox. So he's on Fox.
So when when he did it,
when
he went into that position, man, I was
like, I can't even believe, first of all,
couldn't believe he is. Someone
described it best on the underground.
They said it was like a dude wrestling
with an alligator and kicking his ass
like, yeah, what the fuck he's going
to rip your arm off to get to repeal.
It really was like that.
But then all of sudden he was like kicking
the alligators ass craze and then he
escaped the truck after like
a minute he escaped and he,
then he started attacking Alan
Belcher's legs and your, those,
his leg locks are so scary. You're a
commentary or have you heard it yet?
Have you went back? No, no, no. Dude, you
gotta listen to your commentary. You're,
you're like Alan Belcher's mother.
You're so worried about how that,
but I shouldn't tell people.
I've had three knee operations,
so in any ever a guy like Paul Harris is
going for, he'll look, I fucking panic.
I feel it.
I feel that shit go spit out.
You can make it. It was, he can
Rhea steered. It was hilarious.
He was so passionate about it. You were
so worried about, cause Alan Belcher,
a friend of ours, he's been dimensions
a couple of times. And by the way,
you know Eddie and I actually
had a conversation about
this fight before and we
were like, you know, what do you
think's going to happen in that fight?
And like look,
I love watching Paul Horas crushed
boots but I love Alan Belcher too.
I'm just hoping to see a good experience.
I'm so, I'm hoping to see a good fight.
I never would have predicted that it
would have went like that where Alan
Belcher was so comfortable on the
ground with him. Man. He brought it up.
10 Dean lister and Daniel Marae high
level Jujitsu players and especially dean
lister, cause he's always been known
on the west coast is a leg lock mass.
You submitted Cocker Reco,
he won the absolute knob Udag
straight leg locks go man.
Dean was tough to beat. Super Tech
top five talking about world, super,
super technical. So Alan Belcher
being the smart guy that he is,
he brings, you know, he's
fighting Paul hard shit.
You better bring in someone like that.
You better bring in fucking Josh Barnett.
You better bring in Dude's that
that a rip legs off on the daily.
Oh Alan Belcher has a very high degree
of don't give a fuck to Belcher.
Could fight man.
You have to have so much confidence to
just throw yourself at that guy like in a,
in a ground war and and come out of it
all time him and stay in his garden.
Beat the fuck out of him from his world.
That's the first time I ever had
a conversation with Alan Belcher.
He beat the shit out of somebody and
I'd never talked to him before and I'm
pretty sure you know all those.
UFC is eight straight years of UFC is,
I get them all mixed up but I'm pretty
sure it was in London or something like
that. It was at an after party at
the bar. He passed by me and he,
we kind of like caught eyes and
we never talked to each other.
The four and then I, then we, then our
eyes locked and I say decent liquor,
romance like the notebook.
It was like, it was a good,
like an awkward thing in the beginning.
It was because he really didn't say much.
I did all the talking. I
just said, dude, I mean I,
I'd watch fucking fights like a
motherfucker. I work for the show.
I never seen anybody with fire.
He has this fire inside of them is theory.
And that's what I noticed from Alan
like way back that he's so fearless.
He doesn't give a fuck, you know?
And at that point, you know,
he wasn't known as the greatest
striker in the world and he,
and he definitely wasn't known
as the ultimate submission guy.
He was a well rounded guy who,
uh,
was probably best at striking and
man without fearlessness for me,
I just thought, man, if he just got
really good at Hugh Jitsu, fuck,
and then you add that
fearlessness on top of it. Dude,
he fucked up that guy on the
ground and it's so crazy.
It was so crazy to watch.
And His standup is nasty and Duke Roufus
is such a good trainer, man. Duke,
Duke Roufus is so fucking technical.
I've worked out with him a few times now.
And when you work out with a guy and
he sort of explains his philosophy for
teaching this,
why you're doing that,
there's very few guys who could do
it as good as Duke does and he just,
he's just a really good guy too. And all
of his guys like, well, they'll like Alan,
don't like, they're cool guys. You know,
it trickles down from the top fearless.
You know what? I broke down, I
don't know if you've seen this.
I released it early this morning.
I did a, a video breakdowns,
technical breakdown of what exactly what
Alan Belcher went through in the truck.
I really didn't get into the
leg locks much or anything,
but you can go on youtube and just
punch in Eddie Bravo breaks down Alan
Belcher's twist her attempts or whatever.
Um,
if you're interested in knowing exactly
how it went down, I broke it, Dan on man.
So it's out there on youtube. I
just released it today. So anyways,
what about Pat Barry and
Lavar Johnson whole holy Geez,
that was scary, man.
That was, that was scary.
That guy hits fucking hard.
First of all,
I couldn't believe that Pat
Mary not only got him down,
but mountain em and then hopped over
to sign control. I was like, Whoa,
what's going on here man?
I was like,
what if we see Pat Berry fucking spin on
a Samurai or some shit? What did we see?
Pat Barry do the Ninja take us back.
Can you imagine if Pat Barry just got
like wicked good at submitting guys and
the ground? He's a strong mother fucker,
dude. Pat Barry is strong as shit.
When Christian more craft had him
down in his last fight, he that is,
that's a big dude,
that more craft.
He's a big motherfucker and he
had buried down Barry escape,
got back up to his feet, did got
away from a submission escaping up,
back up to his feet. He never
used to be able to do that before,
but he got fucking caught against that
cage with that big Lavar Johnson man,
that guy, it's so hard. He, you know
Joe Joe or Dan said it best. He said,
he was like, oh no. It wasn't. Show deals
with Tony Jr. Tommy Jr said it best.
He's like,
he's like old school Earnie shavers.
Like the way he's throwing these bombs.
I mean he's just a power puncher man.
Yeah, that was, that was ugly to watch,
man. Pat Barry such a nice guy. You know,
it's like I don't he,
it was like a Tommy Morrison beating.
Yeah. Yeah. You want to Google
an awesome boxing match.
Tommy Tommy Morrison versus a ray Mercer.
That's one of the most
brutal beatings ever
to it. Have you seen Tommy Morrison?
Now he has HIV, right? Oh Dude.
You, you haven't seen shit.
You haven't seen Tommy Mars.
What does he really skinny? Oh my God,
dude, you wouldn't even believe it.
First of all, he looks
like, like, he's like,
they just grabbed him from under a bridge,
pulled the needle out of his arm and just
washed him down and put them in front
of a camera. I mean, he couldn't
look any an unhealthy. Wow. And it's,
it's so sad to listen to him talk
because you know, at one point in time,
you know, you go back to like when he was
on rocky dude, he was a movie star. Okay.
This fucking guy was with
Sylvester Stallone in a movie
and he plays Tommi Gunn.
He's out there not to be like,
he's a fucking star of the
movie next two semesters alone.
It's God damn Tommy Nelson.
I all I remember is that movie
was so bad that when they do, uh,
rocky marathons, they always leave
part five out. Did you notice that?
They never get the five.
How quick is he?
Almost like it wasn't how he
did rocky six. He's lucky.
He's out of his fucking mind.
He's got to be out of his fucking mind.
What are you looking for looking for
Tommy Morrison interview and you just have
to say shit. Yeah, it doesn't even,
it doesn't even look real man.
It doesn't even look real. It, you'll,
you'll, it's, it's, it's scary.
Nobody was more nervous than him
fighting.
That was always his,
something he had to overcome
before every one of his fights.
Like they talk about her in an interview
is like the pre fight stuff is we'll,
how nervous will he be and will it have,
how will it affect his cart? He Oh, right.
Yeah.
Shit, right? Yeah. He, that poor
guy, man. He always had a hard time
and amazing left hook
for a white heavy weight.
He was the last great white heavyweight,
not including the European sound.
Call them regular whites.
Those are regular wines.
I'm talking about like a west
goes the clinicals. I don't count
Russian does that doesn't count.
What? Are They Armenian or something?
They're a Lithuanian. No, they're the
Russian. There's strict Gresham. Wow.
Why do I want to say, um, I don't
know why I don't count the Ukrainian.
I might be wrong. I guess
that's why does Fuck Huh? Yeah,
I would say that's why it's fun,
man. That's okay. Okay. Okay.
All right.
American whites and say that the last
great American white heavy weight was
Tommy Morrison, right? Yeah. There
wasn't anybody else. Gerry Cooney,
Gerry Cooney before him and Tex
Cobb beforehand, and that's it.
I remember when I was in high school.
I want to Gerry Cooney to beat Larry
Holmes because he was white cause I
couldn't believe because
this one I was fighting,
I couldn't believe how bad white dudes
would get their asses kicked. Oh,
he's like,
I was always rooting for white guys like
Bobby Chez because you feel sorry for
him. Love Bobby Chez because he was super
intelligent. He was a member of Mensa.
You remember when Bobby chairs just do,
I don't know why Bobby Chez
stopped doing boxing commentary,
but he was my all time favorite.
He was my favorite.
I love it because first of all, he was the
real deal. He's a fucking animal. Bobby.
Bobby Chaz. Whoa. What about Vinny Paz?
The ends, that one. That sound was me.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
he fought Roy Jones jr sound man.
Remember he don't touch it. He went a
whole round without touching Roy Jones Jr.
Yeah. Let me see if this shit
works. I think it should work.
Do you hear that okay?
Yeah,
that this is, I'm going to show, this
is a really recent Tommy Mars. It Shit.
Can you hear that? I get
here. It is. It gonna hurt me.
Tell me the headphones though. It's not
really coming through the headphones,
but should be
okay.
Here we go. Here he is. Look at him
because it was worth
it and then it stopped.
Yeah,
he looks like the Little Kid's father
on a Freddy got fingered the little kid
that always gets fucked up.
His father,
my mother was a stay at home mom
then I was only out of school for a year.
And when I was just thinking
here in high school,
which was a 1988 and my mother wanted me
to fight in the Kansas city gold gloves
exactly the same age. I
graduated in 98 too, you know.
And uh,
once I started getting into that
mindset, kicked here wardrobe,
totally focused on it and,
and you know, the fighting is what I
love, you know, and I dropped the hat.
I mean it's just when I was put
here to do whatever it takes to win,
that's what I'm willing to do.
What the fuck man?
He looks like he's 65. It's incredible.
I feel bad. He's 42 years old.
That dude at one point in time,
first of all,
must have been getting
train loads of pussy.
It must've been just stopping off at
his house. Yeah. He's the first guy.
First guy ever to get
HIV from straight sex.
I mean who knows? I mean the other
dude must just wore his deck out. Yeah,
and then he went crazy and gut like chest
implants. Have you seen that yet? He,
for folks who don't know,
just Google that and take a look at that.
You want to see what's,
what's really
crazy guy got implants in his chest.
This thing is making noise here.
The guy got an implants like like stripper
implants to make his boobs bigger.
That's if that's not a sure sign of
you losing your fucking marbles. Yeah.
Someone needs to pull you aside and go,
dude, what do you, what are you smoking?
What's going on here man? You're gonna
what? You're gonna get a boob job.
You know what I'm saying? He's your man,
dude. He just gained glamor. Her sexy.
Now it's up titties. Tired of doing
bench. It just outside of benching.
Hard to benching,
kept a lot of his other muscles but,
but just our own Jorma tinnies probably
just missed having full Ted's given good
manly. I got really big. You
think girls that there'd be,
some girls are in the fake boobies.
I like fake packs.
I don't think a man is
allowed to pull off fake shit.
That's what girls could wear.
Wigs.
Girls could wear a hair weaves and fake
eyelashes and Vicon have fake teeth.
They're going to have everything as long
as it look good lens. It looks good.
I mean it was my,
I did a bit in my recent special about
how fake tits confused a lot of people
because everyone knows that they're fake.
There's no confusion whatsoever that
they're fake. It's so worst trick ever.
Cause it's a trick that everybody knows
is an incision. There's a bag of water.
They stuffed it inside and stretch the
skin out and then stitched it all up and
we don't care. We'll go here like,
yeah, we can't make some stick out.
Like we're,
we're s that shape is so primitive.
It's so primally satisfying when a girl
has a great body and a girl has nice
tits and they do not have to be
big. You know, I don't, I don't,
it doesn't bother me. I like small tits.
It doesn't, it doesn't bother me at all.
As long as she has a nice body.
Like a girl with a nice ass is like,
it's so much more important than, than
fake boobs. Yeah. When I take a shower,
my girlfriend's hair extensions are all,
I can't in the shower and I don't
give a shit. Like you wouldn't care.
I call it Brittany or to badge in
if you had hair extensions. Oh Man.
And she,
you know,
if like you ever gotten a fight with
the chicks should call you on that show.
How bout some level you're not insecure.
How about your fucking hair extensions?
Huh?
How about celebrities that were two pays
and everyone knows it's to pay and then
I just can't stop. Yeah.
Like Burt Reynolds, like he,
he'll like joke about it.
I don't think he can do anything.
I think Burt Reynolds is at this this
point where it's become like a Joan Rivers
sort of a thing where it's just,
this is off the tracks and into the woods.
You're nuts. It's got to the point
where like, he's crazy. He's,
he's constantly getting in his face,
like pulled back and g's ever see
Kenny Rogers back when he had his,
uh, you got to know and the whole
loop, he was old than the 70.
[inaudible] when the phone, well, he
got a lot of crazy plastic surgery now.
He doesn't even look like himself anymore.
It looks like a totally different
human beings. Yeah, I dunno man.
So that's a weird thing.
You gotta you gotta let it go when
your face starts falling apart,
you just got to take up fishing.
Find yourself a hobby man, you know,
and take it from me. The guy who
had hair transplants, you know,
it was one of the dumbest
things I ever did.
I thought it was going to be able
to fix my hair loss with surgery.
Not even considering the fact that it
leaves this big chunk of meat scar in the
back of your head. You know, they take
care out of here and move it up here.
It's ridiculous, you know,
and it scars you for life.
Like you can never make
that decision go away.
The infomercials are fucking killer.
You know what dude?
There's like, he has three chicks, he's
in a pool, he's got a full head of hair.
You can work for some people.
So for some people it's good if
it was good for me for awhile,
but the problem is like,
I do a joke about it saying that it's
like moving a bunch of really healthy
people into a neighborhood
where everybody's dying.
Cause that's what it's really like.
All the other hair starts falling out too.
Like it's destined. Most of it's
destined to fall out like half. You know?
Most people in my family on my mom's side,
they're like kind of half fish, bald,
like all over here, a little bit bottle
with it. It's going, it's going to go,
it's going to go.
So if you patch up the spots where it's
gone a little bit and then you look,
I'm pretty good for a couple of years and
then the other spots start falling off
and then what are you going do?
Are you going to keep implanting hair?
Their asshole after a while becomes
embarrassing. It becomes stupid. Yeah.
It becomes like a little trap that you've
fos, like forced yourself into. I go,
I go to this trap,
I gotta take care of this gross hair.
Now I gotta figure out how to fucking
make it look like there's more of it than
it is. Yeah. I should be totally bald
by now. You say that man. But you know,
I just don't, I think you're
wrong. I think I missed,
I stopped at Man.
I started,
I was so worried about my hair because
growing up I had long hair and those
backward long hair got you mad
pussy and it was everything to me.
I would have nightmares about
having short hair, you know,
and I was nine 10 so funny.
I'll never forget my aunt my,
cause you used to have nightmares
of having short hair. Yeah.
I used to have nightmares
of what I met Eddie.
He used to wear like a Hindu rap.
He used to,
he used to do Jujitsu would like his,
his hair would be like tied up in
some fucking scuba diving outfit.
Yeah. I, we used to tie it, uh, I used to
tie my hair used to go down to my waist.
I would like double up the ponytail and
then I used to wear just a Bandanna Bro.
Like fucking axl rose.
And then I would put ear guards over
it just to hold a Bandana in place.
People thought I was worried about my
ears. I really wasn't worried about Myers.
I just needed something to hold the
Bandana up. She'd be hair in place. Yeah.
And then some guy down in that when the
Machados we're down in Redondo beach,
some surfer dude goes, Bro, man, you
should just wear a divers hood, man.
I could diverse HUD.
You mean like Jacques Cousteau goes so
you're going with chocolate is still put
on a mask.
You know,
the shit that's all around is that
I ended up going to a surf shop.
This dude told me where I went to
the surf shop, bought a diver side,
I could die a scuba fucking store,
bought a divers hood and I would wear
in the divers would on its own and
grappling cause it did
hold on my shit together.
That would look fucking ridiculous.
But with a big ass your guards
that got the biggest ones do,
they were marooned giant ear guard so
that people really didn't notice that I
was wearing scuba gear and and I competed
with that motherfucker. People always,
people still come up to me to stay cause
dude I remember seeing you at an old
Joe Merera tournament man and use your,
the duties to where the scuba gear.
So it's basically a rash guard helmet
sort of a thing. Yeah. That's Kinda dope.
Yeah.
The, the problem with all the scrapes
and scratches and shit you get,
that's where you could possibly
get ringworm and staff. I like,
I've been wearing tights lately and
that you feel like a dancer out there.
You feel something a little funny about
a man wearing tights but I got over that
shit really quick.
What's wrong with g pants,
man. I like the pants.
I think better protection with the tights.
I don't know.
I think it's skin tight everywhere.
He just liked to show off your mark
and Mugler legs. That's what I like.
I like just walking in with my big Hams.
Let everybody know what the fuck is up.
Yeah man. When and all my uncles
went bald, like in their thirties.
And my aunts knew how much my hair
meant to me and my answered say, Ah,
I'll never forget my aunt patty
goes, oh look, because we're all,
we all lose our hair. Plus we're born
with a ridiculous large, uh, forehand.
Like all my aunts think they're losing
their hair because they have a giant
forehead. So we're born with giant
foreheads and I don't know, my aunt patty,
I was 19 hair longer than a motherfucker.
Oh No. In the height of metal,
the height of metal. Um, my aunt patty
goes, oh look, he's losing his hair. Ah,
you're going to be all sad. Would you go
bald? And I'm like, oh, so right away,
right away. I'm like, fuck.
But that was good because,
because that motivated me to go get
some Rogaine and back then you need a
prescription to get Rhogam. I had to
go to a doctor. The doctor's like,
you're 19 years old, he'd do it
in here. I'm like, you know what,
I'm gonna start early and I just
terrified of losing my hair.
So I've been on Rogaine since I was 19
so you jumped on it way before it would
ever kicked in. Yup. Will you taking
the Propecia and everything? I took,
I took Rogaine from 19 to 30 and when
I was 30 in 2000 that's when they end.
Propecia came on and then I switched
to Propecia from 30 to 40 didn't use
Rogaine at all in my thirties it was
just a pill. Every day I take a pill.
It was beautiful. It keeps the hair on
dude. There's where it works, right?
I should be bald by now. I really should
be. I'm looking, I have there. I have,
cause I've been diligent
about just like vitamins.
I was trying to hold onto
my youth my whole life.
I was holding onto the youth
and, and uh, you know, at, at 40,
I decided to go back to rogue game
because I just thought, you know what,
I don't like taking a pill every
goddamn day. Who Know that I could,
I could easily,
they actually think it provide for me.
It can help prevent prostate cancer. But
who knows what, it doesn't. The other end,
I didn't like taking it
because when I was taking it,
it was a fucking with my libido and I
didn't even realize it was until I got off
of it until I ran out of it.
I'm awesome.
I had these just monster boners all the
time and I was like, what is going on?
And a feel. I boner,
everybody's different, you know,
they say it only affects a
certain percentage of people.
I know other people that are,
they've had the same problem and I know
other people that actually say that it
made him Hornier. Oh, what
the fuck? That's all about
it. But it's uh, you know, it,
it blocks DHT and apparently
DHT is necessary for something,
some brain function, something athletic
function. Something, I dunno. Yeah man.
I Dunno. It's funny though. The
whole situation is funny. The,
there's just clinging to youth, you know,
and it's funny you're open about it.
You knew, you know, talk about
it really openly. Like, Hey man,
I'm just trying to clean the youth.
But for a lot of people that's
like a really shallow thing to say.
Like I know a lot of people who consider
themselves very well educated and they,
they consider to be a pretty astute and
our understanding of how other people
see them.
And so they avoid saying shit like that.
They avoid saying shit like I'm
just trying to hold onto my youth.
They don't want to admit that because
it's a frivolous thing. It's not a,
not a thing for a serious man to consider,
but the reality is nobody
likes it and that nobody,
nobody wants to reality and to
death feels good to look good.
Anybody that says that it doesn't feel
good to look good, they're full of shit.
If it feels good to look good, I'm just
trying to feel good as much as possible.
That's all you want to, you
want your body to work well too.
The difference between you
and a lot of other people's,
you're always using your body for Jujitsu.
So because of that,
your body is like a race car.
I mean,
we've had these conversations before
we talk about lifting. It's like when,
when you concentrate on a rigorous
strength and conditioning program,
you decide what kind of engine
your race car has. You know?
And if you're one of those motherfuckers
like, what's that dude's name?
He used to train at your place to
wrestle. Eric, a really strong guy.
Fuck's his name.
Eric number four in the nation
that got Bradley or Bradley Dude.
I remember doing drills with this guy
and we were doing neon stomach drills and
this motherfucker, I got a pretty good
neon stomach. I can hold some dude's down.
This motherfucker launched me through the
air like, like he had like ridiculous,
like physical strength,
like ridiculous physical strength.
And when you talked about it, he was
like, he, he would never miss his lift.
I remember he was talking about at once.
So I gotta get my lift in.
I don't miss my left. It was all like, I
don't know what the exactly the lift was,
but it was very obviously like a series
of strength and conditioning was like
you're like clean and press or
something like that with a lot of those.
Like you ever see the Randy
coture set that he does? No.
Randy is a fascinating one because Randy
does it all with real lightweights.
He does it with like a a barbell,
a big bar bout with like a
45 not even, not even. Yeah,
like a 25 on each side. Really? Yeah Dude.
He but he doesn't stop. I mean it's, it's,
it's a funnel of exercises,
a fuck load of reps and what he does,
he says what that does is really much
more mimics fighting than full blast bench
presses and full blast squats and
it's more like for muscular endurance.
It's a motherfucker, dude. I
tried it once. It's a mother,
father, full body stuff.
Yeah, a lot of full box of, lot of
lunges, a lot of bent over rows,
all sorts of different shit he does.
It's like a,
there's a whole series of
I'm Randy has them online.
You know what's really made a
difference in my list. Did I?
I love doing squats way more now
than ever because of these shoes.
These are vibrant toe shoes. Eddie,
Eddie Bravo. Where's took dude,
you just put your dirty foot on my mug.
Now I've got a disk. That's very much it.
Yeah, but it's in my house. Someone's
got to drink out of it. Out of my house.
These Vibram shoes are the best.
Don't drink that spot.
We just touched your dirty
feet on it, man. Oh Dude. I
can't believe you did that.
Dammit. Doing squats with what these
things are. It feels so good. Yeah.
I need to take into him. Steve Maxwell
got me into working out barefoot.
I do all my lifts in barefoot now.
Every house.
What does he think about these shoes?
He loves him. Yeah. He likes those. He,
he's a big advocate of flat minimalist
shoes. Yeah, I've got to, um,
there's a box right over there and with a,
another pair of their,
they're not toe shoes, but they're
minimalist shoes. Um, yeah,
I think for lifting weights
and for training, they're
the best. Yeah. The toes.
A lot of people are weird, like they
don't like wearing them. It looks stupid.
It looks silly. But uh, I think if you
could get them and they fit right for me,
I had a hard time getting some of the
toes in, but once I got him in, man,
it's pretty God damn comfortable.
And you really do feel your toes
working as individual units,
which doesn't happen when it's
like one big fixed sneaker. Yeah.
In a big fixed sneaker.
It's like trying to like if you
put sneakers on your hands, okay.
And then try to do bench press with it,
how good would that be?
It wouldn't be so good. You wouldn't
really have that kind of a good control.
Exactly. And you're gripping
the ground with your toes.
Yeah. It's so huge. I love,
I love walking now. Just walking
is awesome. I'm a serious,
maybe I'll get over it in a month or so,
but I really enjoy these shoes.
Sell much, changing the way
I just function every day.
I saw some boot versions. They were like,
uh, like it looked like hobbit feet.
It was on Tim Ferriss, Twitter.
Somebody had tweeted it.
It's like the same company that does it.
What does the company that
makes sure as Vibram? Yeah,
they're vibrams but it's like a boot,
like a tan leather boots like you could
wear and like I guess you'll be allowed
to wear that and go out to eat at a nice
restaurant and he'd be a shoe. Yeah,
they've got to make some cool looking
dressy ones like we were talking about
earlier,
like puts it make for on top of it or
something of diamonds or something like
that. Make up the evil
fake dressy ones. Man,
there's something weird about someone
walking towards you and you could see
their toes moving.
You know?
It's like if for a guy like flip
flops or weird enough, right?
You're out there showing your toes
hanging around, flip flop in with people.
But when you're wearing, it's like you're
out at a nice restaurant and a guy.
I can see your toes move.
There's something about like our idea of
what it is to go out where that doesn't
agree with us. You know,
what are you doing?
You trying to get attention with your
silly shoes. You want the fucker?
Why can't you remember regular shoes?
Like a regular person?
Why are you going to be the one guy
who stands out? You silly bitch.
People talk shit on the shoes like my
girlfriend didn't want like I want her to,
I wanted them for a year and she's,
she would
bring it up to a friend's
and they would laugh at me.
Oh he want to get those shoes. Those
shoes are ridiculous. I'll you know,
and then finally, finally
I told her either I'm going
to get them. Did he brought,
do what you need to get
down with the fanny pack.
That's what you need to get dealt with.
I, I traveled with a fanny pack sign.
I traveled strong feeling. I got
do two little pockets. Oh son,
it's so much better. I put my money, I
got my cell phone, all my bullshit too.
Little zipper pockets, little chapstick
in there. Boom. Schelok log. Boom.
Come on, man. I leave little.
Uh, I have uh, headphones.
I have my little headphones or beats, a
little tiny ones. I keep those in there.
The ear buds. I'm always down to
listen to music if I'm stuck anywhere.
If I'm traveling, I don't go anywhere
without that fucking fanny pack. Yeah,
plane ticket. Oh, where's it go? And
very practical. It is dude. You just,
you gotta. You gotta step up
and claim back. I take it back.
How was it a dude who carry
a man purse for awhile?
I really remember it used to
bring around your CD's everywhere.
You brought him everywhere.
You never wanted to be in a situation
where you wanted to give some anyone you
didn't exactly have one on. Yeah,
always passed now. Fuck cds.
You got mp3s now.
Is it an amazing cds?
Just the solid media is almost useless.
It's on its way out.
Like I go to border books,
you know, and look around.
They always have like a back section where
they sell movies and in cds and Shit.
I look, you know, I think
it's funny, you know,
the CD section just keeps getting
smaller and smaller. You go to best buy,
just getting smaller and smaller.
We're going to be all living in the cloud.
Dude sent me a virtual
bookstore and the future, right,
like a three month thing that you walk
around and he'd just pick out the books.
Well, I mean it sort of is there now if
you have a kindle or if you have a one of
those iPads with the, the I book
application, you just go scroll.
I'll take that book right now. Bang
downloads, images and all guys.
I found out Marilyn Manson came out
with the new album a couple of days ago.
Just, Oh, I just buy it on
my phone instantly. Crazy.
I had my phone on me at all times.
Can you buy it with three g or do you
have to be connected to the Internet?
I buy all my shit on three G.
Really? Yep. So you'd get in,
download the whole album on
three g. Wow. You know those, um,
those cards that they sell you,
those uh,
Internet cards and they have a certain
amount of bandwidth do I downloaded one
movie off iTunes and they sent me a
message and I used up like 50% of my
bandwidth. One movie. How
much bandwidth do I get?
You assholes. There was hardly
any more bandwidth. I mean,
how big is it a movie when you get a
movie on iTunes and never buy movies on
iTunes? How big can it be though? I mean,
I would guess big few gigs. I'm not,
I'm still not sure what a Gig is.
Gigabyte. It's a thousand megabytes.
I know it stands for, I know,
but I don't know how big
that is. Um, a Gig is like,
like if you have a big ass photo of
a very, very high resolution photo,
maybe it can be one Gig,
like a,
a like a good size porno film that
you can save on your hard drive.
It's an Avi file and you could
watch it for like 15 minutes, man,
28 Gig if it's really high rate
a breaking down pouring again.
But it's all depends on the CODEC. So
that's the thing about, uh, there's,
there's a lot of different standards
when it comes to avionics and pigs,
mov files, flash files. There's
a lot of different things.
I mean we live in incredible times and
there's a lot of parallel evolution of
different sort of formats for videos.
You know, it's, it's pretty incredible.
And then blu rays, you know, he can't play
brew Blueway on your laptop, a blu rays.
That shit when it comes to
like high definition, you
know, you watch it, you go,
you got a blueberry player at home.
You ever watch the ads on my playstation?
I think. Yeah, there you go.
Yeah. Isn't that incredible?
I mean how incredible is a playstation?
It comes with a blue ray
player and you watch those.
I mean we'll look real bad ass movies
like Avatar and Blu Ray. Ah, stunning.
You can't tell me that doesn't feel good.
Like that asshole that lives in the caves,
that guy who gave up on money,
you don't get to experience Avatar Douche
bag. You don't get to experience it.
You need money for that. James Cameron
is not going to work for fucking food.
Okay. If a guy's going to
create something like Avatar,
he wants to live in a castle and drive
a private jet, you know, you gotta,
you gotta pay a guy like James Cameron
and make a fucking movie like that and
you're not gonna,
you're not gonna get to see that
while you're eating beans out of a can
underneath a bridge. You think
dictators going to be good? No,
it doesn't look that great.
It doesn't look good and I keep
hearing it's terrible. Oh really? Yeah.
Unfortunately I don't have a huge Ali g
fan. This is how hugely allergy fan I am.
I bought an a different DVD player
because the DVD player that I bought would
play DVDs from the UK because there's
two different regions and apparently like
we used to be cheap DVD players
were all region like a cheap one,
like a really expensive one, but only be,
you could only play American DVDs on it,
but a cheap one for some reason.
Some of them they had like all regions
and it eventually they phased that shit
out. I think, I don't think you can get
all regions anymore. I might be wrong,
but the point is,
I bought a special DVD player just for
European videos so I could watch the
ology show and I got them all off
the Amazon website, the UK, Amazon,
amazon.co. Dot. UK.
They have their own version of
Ama and a bunch of different shit,
like all these allergy episodes that
I never show saw like Ali, Geez movie.
What was that movie allergy in the House
do that movie is fucking brilliant.
You and I remember you and I washed it.
We got banked as fuck and we watch Ali
g in the house and I got this DVD player
specifically to watch Ali g. But
when I watched that, the ad for that,
I mean I could be wrong, but I watched the
ad. I was like, Whoa, what happened here?
Like this looks like a mess.
I see it. There is a chance.
Like maybe he's holding all the good
stuff to cook because Bruno and Borat,
we're fucking brilliant. Brilliant. I've
seen Bruno probably a hundred times more.
Laura was so god damn good. He's so good,
man. He's so hilarious when he's on,
but you know everybody has fuck ups.
I don't know if this is going to be one,
but I keep hearing bad
things. Oh really? Yeah.
I keep hearing they're delaying it and
reshooting things and trying to fix
things. Damn. I hope. I hope I'm wrong,
but it could be also that people like
Freddy got fingered. They don't get it.
You know, like Freddy got fingered.
You and I both agree. It's hilarious.
So crazy or ridiculous movie,
but a lot of people didn't get it.
They didn't like it. They didn't
want to go with it. You know?
It was a trip when we talked about Freddy
got fingered last time I was on the
show. Tom Green. Mike sent
me a tweet. Oh, that's cool.
Like Holy Shit. I worshiped Tom
Green back when he was doing,
when he was doing just the small
time shit on MTV. You ever met him?
I met him once when you did his shall
at his house in the Hollywood hills.
That was fun, man. Does he
still do it though? I don't
know. I don't know. I gotta.
I got gotta call that dude.
I gotta get him on my podcast or go
on his or whatever. I did his too.
He did want to add Kevin Smith's place,
the smog cast place in Hollywood.
He's a great guy. He's going to be out
at the Canyon club zone. Yeah man. Ay
all his early shit. I worshiped Tom Green,
you know, he's a loving standup now.
Really? He's getting into it. He's
a dude. He's a stand up. He's,
he's just stand up all over the
country. All over the world. Wow. Yeah.
I've watched videos of him kicking ass
in Australia. You Dude, he's doing great.
He's doing great. Well he's a funny
guy, man. And he just, you know,
just for a long time just
didn't do standup and then
he just, I remember talking,
I was like, I'm really getting into
this now we're getting an understand up.
Who's really excited about it?
You know,
it was like something new to him
and it was all his, he could like,
he had sort of,
or he was one of the first guys to really
branch out on the Internet and do his
own shit. Yeah. With his show, the
Tom Green showed live on the Internet.
It was really one of the first guys
and then I think he just decided,
you know what,
man?
Why the fuck am I sitting around waiting
for someone to give me a show when I
know I'm funny. I know I'm weird,
but I'm, what am I going to do?
I'm going to wait for someone.
We make something happen.
Let me go make something happen. I love
that. I just loved that he did that.
I respect that so much school, Tom
Green's to put dog shit on a mic and just,
just see how people stupid.
We're stupid.
People were on the street when they see
a camera and a guy come up to him with
the mic,
they are so thrilled about being on TV.
They don't want to believe it's bullshit.
They see the shit right in
front of their face. Literally,
he'll put dog shit on a mic and start
talking to people and interviewing people
and they'll smell it.
They'll look at it and still
continue with the interview,
hoping, just not even thinking
that they're being goofed on.
They don't want to believe that shit.
They want to believe that they're
really on TV and it's real.
You know the crazy shit.
He was an innovator as far as
doing like really ridiculous shit.
He was very original with his,
his whole show.
Fucking that dead Moose on the
side of the highway pulls over.
I swear he was ridiculous and
over and a nice fucking guy, man.
Tom Green is a nice fucking guy.
I always enjoyed being around that guy.
He's just a really good dude to be around.
He's fun.
And then this world of Weirdos that
you meet, you know you can meet some,
some people that are famous that are just
fucking crazy or weird or nuts or too
much or you can't take them or the
two too egocentric or whatever.
It's nice when you meet a guy
like Everlast. You might nice,
nicely meet a guy who could just hang out.
He's just a regular dude man.
Or a guy like Tom Green. It's just
a regular dude, you know? So we're,
we're so lucky being exposed out here
and especially doing like a podcast,
you're exposed to so many
really extraordinary people.
So many interesting people.
We think of all the,
I mean from the fringe to out
from Alex Jones, you know,
fascinating to got to Michael Rupert, you
know, fascinating God. Alex Jones on the,
on this podcast. But we're going
to work it out because there was a,
there was a mistake and I
actually, oh, Alex and apology.
There's a company called bent
pixels and bent pixels is there,
they put ads on people's videos
and Marty, yeah, Marty Cordoba,
who's a good friend of mine and a good
friend of Dana White's and a great guy.
And we were working together this on
videos, but unfortunately
some videos were claimed.
It's not just videos of my standup.
They have like an algorithm and the
algorithm goes and looks for your name.
So when it goes out and
looks for your name,
it doesn't necessarily get
something that you own.
It could be like Joe Rogan
on the Alex Jones show.
All this algorithm grabs that thinking
that there's a copyright claim to be made.
Or You could put an ad on that video.
Well you can't put it down on the video
because it's me and a guest of Alex
Jones show. So of course they release it
and it's a mistake and they, you know,
are trying to correct and apologize for
everything, but it's a sloppy algorithm,
you know, I'm sure they're upset
about it and there it's unfortunate,
but they're not trying to rip anybody off.
And then shortly not trying to
claim copyright from me on stuff.
That's not my stuff. What they're
trying to do is like, you know,
there's a lot of people that
put your standup online.
There's a lot of my videos that are
online and other people's videos as well.
And there's ads on those videos and these,
these videos on other people's sites.
So other people are getting like,
like I've clicked on a link of my own.
That was one of my heckler videos.
And I watched an ad that somebody else
put up on my video and like of me.
And I'm like, that's hilarious. Like this
guy's making money. And I looked down,
it was like thousands
and thousands of views.
I don't have any how many hundred
thousand views, this fucking video guy.
But I'm like, how crazy is that?
This guy, whatever, and add pays you.
I don't know what it pays you,
but this guy's making money from my video.
That's kind of crazy bullshit.
So when Marty confronted me about it or
confirm or offered me rather this and
discussed it with me, I
shouldn't say confronted, cause
that sounds like hostile.
It doesn't confront it presented,
presented the proper word.
When Marty presented it to me, I certainly
did not have any intention of uh,
it, you know, connecting
itself to someone else.
And there's a lot of people
complaining about it,
but most people don't understand
that it's just a mistake.
It's an algorithm and they're not trying
to be sleazy. They'll fix everything.
And I'm sorry,
but uh,
but motherfucker got
bills trying to get paid.
Trying to keep that money rolling in dog.
It's hard to make money off the
Internet, right? Yeah. It's hard.
It's hard to make money off
the Internet. Yeah, their yard.
So that's the thing
everybody's trying to monetize.
Like they try to monetize podcasts.
Like there's ways that people have like
clubs you can join like the VIP program
and you get a free podcast every week and
extra podcast and a tee shirt and this
center of that.
And trying to figure out how you get
someone to spend x amount of money.
You know,
like a lot of dudes like Kevin Smith,
they were asking him for a Ad Free Shit.
Like a lot of people were asking him
for Ad Free Shit. So he decided to make,
he's got like two versions, like his
regular podcast, completely free,
but you've got to listen to a few ads,
you know,
they've got to pay the bills and then he
has a membership offer where you could
get that and then you get the no
adversion pay like five bucks a month or
something like that. Yeah, it's
totally reasonable. You know,
and you'd want to support it
if you really did enjoy it.
It's not as long as it's like five
bucks a month, you know? It's like,
like my comedy special that
I'm going to release online,
that's going to be five bucks and
it has to be five or first of all,
cause Louis C k the first guy to do
it and make this a popular choice.
He charged five bucks. So you can't
charge more than the innovator. You know,
he's completely fair in
the right way to do it.
He did it perfect and you've
got to follow his lead.
You shouldn't charge any more than that.
So I think,
I think there's nothing wrong with what
you know anybody's doing by asking for
some sort of a membership fee to just to,
just to work off some of the bills.
You know,
there's a lot of people that would be
happy to pay five bucks to listen to Adam
Carolla every month. I mean,
it's a part of their daily grind.
I mean for what costs? A couple cups
of coffee a month, you know? I mean,
I don't know how much he charges,
but Adam has some sort of a Ustream thing,
but for a lot of people, man,
they fucking love that show.
Adam Carolla show is super
fucking popular. That's a,
he's a big part of a
lot of people's lives.
This is not wrong as
long as it's reasonable.
The beautiful thing is that it can be
reasonable like five bucks and because of
the Internet it really could benefit the
artists like you, like you know your,
your Jujitsu website, five bucks benefits
you man, it goes right to you. You know?
Whereas me, when I'm selling it five
bucks benefit, it goes right to me.
It's not like the old days where
you had to go through some sort of a
manufacturing company.
He would put the DVD together
for you in a marketing company.
He would put it on the shelves and talk
to where we got Jean at Walmart and you
know, you had to get in and
all these different places.
This was just a couple of years ago,
man, just a couple of years ago,
one of my last DVD deals that I did, I
remember, you know, one of the big things,
I had to go and sit and I had a a meeting
with these dudes that are this big DVD
distribution company and they were
pitching to me how they can get my DVD and
all these different stores all over the
country and this is what's important.
What's important is,
you know,
you can't have anything on the
shelves and can't get onto Walmart.
If you can't get in a Walmart,
you're really doomed.
You're doomed to sell these things.
This is the new reality.
Like how to get into Walmart,
so you had to have something
knows he can't like cab call,
call it like shit talking one on one,
like the name of my message board.
You can never have a a DVD named
that because they wouldn't sell it.
It has to be squeaky clean.
There's just a few years ago. Hmm.
It's fascinating when this is all going,
man.
Yeah. You don't need any of that shit
anymore. I'm, I'm starting to sell,
I'm in the process of
switching manufacturers now.
I'm handling all my merchandise now.
We've got new shirts coming,
new designs and hoodies,
new rash guards knew, uh,
short all that's coming.
It's going to take a little time
because it's really expensive.
But my store on my website
hasn't been running for,
since my website went up. I've
been letting melee, uh, uh,
that fight where handle
all my merchandise. Like,
is this too much for me
to handle it for awhile?
But now I'm going to handle everything
and, and um, you know, take over.
So it's really exciting when we're
talking about this before the podcast,
it's really exciting to be able to
have a concept like what's going on?
It's like a 10th planet heads are
designing shirts and I'm like, Oh shit,
I want that design. I send it over
to my manufacturer. He makes it,
we make it happen. Sell it on the
website. Boom. Just like that.
It's on like donkey Kong. It's crazy. It's
crazy. It's a strange world we live in,
dude. Yeah. So it's like,
like right now is is a bad time
to buy by 10th planet gear.
We're just getting it rolling. You
could still, I'm allowing to sell out
all their stuff. Maili you can go to
10th planet gear.com Malay owned that,
um, until the end of the year they're
allowed to sell everything off and, and,
and while I build up my own merchandise,
um,
it's going to be official 10th
planet brand. It's not like an cause.
It used to be only wants to
learn Jujitsu from your website,
which is more interesting to most people
here. What, how did, how did they do that?
If they want to learn Jujitsu online,
is it possible to just go to a regular
school and like learn all your shit
online and then go to the school and
just, yeah, you could bring a laptop,
bring uh, bring an iPhone. Do you have
an iPhone versions of it? Yup. Yup. Um,
you can watch it on
iPad and all that stuff.
Basically it's most traditional Brazilian
jujitsu schools have like one or two
guys that are into temp planet techniques.
And so you could be that guy,
you could go to a Gracie Baha school
and not jump on my website and for five
bucks extra, you get to learn all this
stuff that they're not teaching to there.
Cause most Gracie Barra schools
don't teach rubber guard.
They don't teach all the stuff
that we saw the Korean Zombie do.
It's a lot of great schools.
There are a lot of them out there.
There's a million of them. You know,
there's a credible lunch I have,
there's only like 30 10 plan in schools.
There's probably 500 Gracie Bajas
not more theirs. They're everywhere.
They're huge. It's incredible. How would
you do to, is taken off man. So it's just,
it's just a testament of what
a fun way it is to exercise.
So I saw this thing man,
and I had to talk to you about it
cause it's completely ridiculous.
Phillip Corso, you know who that dude
is? Yeah. The, uh, the guy who was a,
he was one of the, well he was one
of the people that supposedly was,
was there and saw the um,
the, the, the, the spacecraft.
Wasn't he at Roswell? Yes. He was
one of the actual people. Yes.
His son or someone want to try
to find the, find the actual,
the actual article because
someone in his family,
it was Philip Corso son reveals that
Roswell craft was a time machine.
Quiet like you crazy. Motherfucker
did. Anything's possible though.
I know anything's possible. That's crazy.
I mean it is crazy. It is crazy. Yeah.
But reality is crazy. It is real thing as
possible. Shit. Who knows like the truth,
like the tea. But I love these things
because these, these revelations,
they're always in like some
weird hotel conference room.
There's like a podium and this is
like a bad slide show. This is,
you know, not, not quite fascinating.
And this guy talking about it,
he's talking about how the, it's the,
in the presentation, I'll just read it.
It says the details,
the alleged Roswell craft or talked
about at length a particular interest was
information about the so called
extraterrestrial biological entities,
which contained two brains.
One was organic and thought to control
the beings and the other one was laced
with crystal electronics.
That's still not understood to
this day was thought to connect
the beings with the craft through time.
It is purported that these beings are
essentially artificial intelligence from
our own future and that their crash
caused a bifurcation of our timelines and
altered our history.
The most mind boggling aspect of this
story and the theory that the air force,
et Cetera are operating under is that as
a result of this timeline split and the
subsequent advancement in technology
from reverse engineering that we are the
military are now on a
timeline of technological
evolution that will eventually
create the very same craft and beings
that actually crashed in Roswell in 1947
whoa. That's an insane shit you
imagine. That's incredible. I mean,
it sounds completely ridiculous and I'm
sure this guy's nuts out of his fucking
head. But if he wasn't, just just say,
let's just say two to settle out all the
skeptics and the people that would be
critical of this idea. Imagine if
that is how it works. I mean, we're,
we're working so hard right
now, not we, not yet, not I,
but scientists are to figure out all
kinds of crazy things that are going to
alter the very way we
interact with the universe.
Look what the fuck's going on with
this large Hadron collider. Yeah.
Look at this cork gluon
plasma that they've created
that's like the most dense,
thick,
like it's some insane amount.
Like a sugar cube weighs like 40 billion
pounds or something crazy. I mean,
they're doing some nutty, nutty shit
are working on a time machine right now.
I think they could send photons back
like seconds at a time or something like
that. But they have been
working on it for 20 years.
I mean a time machine is something
that they're actually working on their
scientists working on it. The, you know,
they're going to start with photons
and maybe five minutes in the future,
whatever they know, time travel is
possible. Einstein said it was possible.
I mean, based on the speed
Kurt Godel who came up with it,
I remember reading about it who's
a mathematician, but it needed,
you needed something like an object the
size of the solar system and it had to
be going backwards fucking faster
than the speed of light. It's this,
there's like a lot of weird shit that
happened with the speed of light,
something the transverse its axle.
If you travel out in space at the speed
of light and then like for you know,
uh, uh, a week and then come back at the
speed of life broke, something like that,
that you're going to cut back to a
planet that's like 500 years older,
older. Yeah. Yeah. That is
weird and crazy. Is that, yeah,
that's relative to how fast you're
traveling. Anything. Anything's possible.
It's all nuts, right? Isn't
it? But check this out.
But it's just that I was right though.
We're going to call me a cook,
but I just wanted to play this as really
quick evidence. This is evidence, this,
just listen to it.
There's a lot of genealogical research,
you know, going back, Dick's family,
my family, they said, well, we can
amazing tales of people who went west,
but one of the things I discovered is
that Dick and Barack Obama or eight
cousins,
why is that?
An amazing thing is if you go back
eight generations common ancestor,
these spiritual beings,
that's it. I mean, well there's, that's
when that article we read, right?
Dick Cheney's wife. That bench is probably
crazy. She's living with Dick Cheney.
She must be a devil worshiper.
Could you imagine if dictate he was your
husband? Well, what do you think, honey?
Did I do the right thing? Yeah, whatever.
1 million people dead. Whatever.
We've got a nice house then I'll
fucking bad ass out when it go. Dude,
you provided he provided for your family.
Let's see that kind of like
stick let's Dick Cheney fogger.
Do you think he wears like an old
mask? A her cape, like he's one of the,
the watchmen. Is that what they
were? What the fuck is that?
What are you doing dude?
I was just started trying to apply no
bond and have a conversation by myself.
I was just trying to find out.
You get on that on your laptop sometimes
and ignoring me and I'm left the first
laptop on a fucking island only
for a second to Google something.
That's what I was trying to out trying
to find the Obama interview of him
talking about it. Oh, I don't, I don't
really care if they all are related.
They all suck about that.
They're related, but yeah,
but if they are all related,
fuck, what does that mean?
It means it means that we're living in a,
this is all bullshit.
Maybe we are living in some
sort of a manufactured reality.
I had been thinking that more and more
lately as things get weirder and weirder.
You know,
when that Joseph Kony guy and the guy
who had the campaign against Joseph Kony
and then a few days later he,
they made like fucking insane
amounts of money and they,
the way they had their sponsorship
or their charity rather set up,
it was really fucked up.
Like they got a lot of money out of it
before the money actually got to anybody
that was, you know, overseas, you know,
it was, it was really kind of a scam.
But then the guy went crazy and wound
up masturbating in the street and San
Diego and acting really gay and
it flailing his arms around it,
talking really gay and they arrested him.
He went crazy.
But it's almost like you see
something like that happen.
You see a guy get shamed because
people find out that his, his uh,
his charity was like a little funky,
a little suspicious and then
he winds up blown a gas.
But like as gasket like that publicly,
it almost makes you feel like,
who's writing this? This is, this
is like, this is a work of fiction.
Who's right,
who is,
who's writing the thing where that
wiener guy gets arrested for showing his
wiener, who's writing this? You
know who's writing it? Who's when?
When you see a guy like Mitt Romney and
Mitt Romney talked to that kid who was a
medical marijuana patient who was like,
you gonna arrest me. Am I a criminal?
Like this is the only thing
that allows me to eat well.
I'm not for medical marijuana.
I'm not for it.
And he just walks away from some poor
crippled kid and you're like, really?
You think that this guy has the kind of
compassion that you want as a man who
runs the world? That's a fucking
robot. That's an ideological robot.
That's a guy who's not addressing
a person who is in pain.
A person who's just been dealt a terrible
hand by life and is telling him that
there's a substance that gives me a
very unfortunate person, some relief.
Oh, I'm not for that.
I'm not for your relief.
I'm an Iud of empire and
I can't see the day light.
Did you see that video of Mitt Romney
and Obama agreeing on everything?
It's all spliced together and they
go through every issue, every issue.
I may agree on every issue,
most issues,
most issues like a good like 90% of all
the all the big issues and there's video.
You can find this on you to video
of them going back and forth.
They're talking and they're saying the
exact same thing and not healthcare.
The exact same thing about everything.
It's amazing.
At the end of the day when you realize
how much corporations and big money
influence government and
then once you realize that,
then you will put it together and
you realize this is a shell game.
The corporation's influenced both sides.
They just keep this stupid banter going,
that's a stupid tennis game
or this has got the ball.
Now that guy has got the ball and
this guy's got the ball and they just
alternate between Democrats and
Republicans and it mo money,
Mo problems that Democrats
are there on specifics,
line of problems like sticking their
and chicks miles and all kinds of freaky
Shit to Clinton did and then the
Republicans got their issues too and
everybody's got their own little thing.
It's a back and forth. Well, gay marriage.
I'm not for gay man.
What about abortion?
I think of the six months is a little
with a word of it's rape and they keep
this fucking battle.
Meanwhile,
they just pulling money out
of other spots of the world,
just fucking attacking thing in
the world. It's amazing. I mean if,
if you really look at the actual
game, how it is played, the game of,
of capitalism, the game of, you know,
global imperialist capitalism that we're
experiencing right now live in here in
America and the balls of the
Dick that's fucking the world.
If you really look at it, it really
is an amazing God. That movie.
It feels like someone wrote this shit
down. Yeah. It feels like dark city. Yeah.
As as much as I,
I really am obsessed with just,
I mean I'm not trying to put together a
revolution or an army or anything like
that.
All I'm,
all I'm doing is I'm trying to make
as many people aware as possible.
Let's not make it that easy for them
to fuck us. I'm not going to style it.
You know what asked way to influence them.
This is what I always say.
You're not going to get those
Dick Cheney motherfuckers.
Those guys are broken that he's
been broken since he was a child.
What you're going to get is those kids
in college that are listening to this and
they're realizing, realizing,
you know these guys,
you know they're in their forties or
telling them about life and and they're
telling them about it in a very honest
way and letting them know, listen man,
you are not going to live forever and
the only way you're going to enjoy this
life is if you create
less negative energy.
Then you receive from life.
If you put forth a positive result and
a positive influence and in a positive
reaction to you being on this planet,
that's how you're going
to have a good life.
You are not going to have a good
life. If it's just me, me, me,
[inaudible] taking over the world
fucking over everybody you're going to,
after awhile you don't realize how
much money you have. Once you know,
why would you want $100 million when you
could be happy and comfortable with 10
or 20 and not have to fuck over the
world where they don't even realize it.
They're just caught up in
this fucking crazy game.
You know where a person is
super successful and they
made $100 million fucking
over the world.
They probably could have made 30 or $40
million had done it the right way and
still been just equally as wealthy.
You don't realize $100
million or $50 million,
he's crazy assholes that
want to own everything.
You know what you realize
when you don't have enough.
You can't afford a good dinner.
You can't afford to heat your house.
You can't afford to live in a
nice neighborhood where your,
your kids are safe and they
play in front of your house.
You can't afford to pay for cable,
but once you pay for all
that and you have a nice car,
you have food on your table,
it becomes a matter of what are
you trying to get with that money?
What do you track? Where are you
trying to get your happiness from?
Because if you try to get your
happiness purely through objects,
that shit's ridiculous or purely
through monetary accomplishment.
That's ridiculous. It's a dead
end. It really is a head end.
The way to change the world is to
let kids know this, let them know,
don't get on that path.
You can be a successful
motherfucker and still have ethics.
You can be a successful person and still
be a good guy and do the right thing.
You can protect the country from the cons
of the world without being one of the
cons of the world and that's
where Shit went wrong.
We became cons to protect ourselves from
cunts and we've been doing it from the,
from the fucking get go.
The real problem this country is that
there's a lot of us that aren't like you
or I, and they're the ones who
are representing us in the world.
They're the ones who are
making all these decisions.
They're the ones who are doing all these
fucking crazy backroom deals that make
all kinds of ridiculous shit. That's
horrible for the economy. Legal.
Just so a few people can extract millions
of dollars from the system and it
ain't you and it ain't me man,
and there's something you said to me
once a long time ago and it really stuck
with me and it's a very astute point.
You said,
we were born into a system
that we have no control over.
We were born into it and to try to fix
it is almost impossible and it really is
true. We were born into this thing and
we've got no fucking control over it.
He saved voting it please man.
You really think that Ron Paul
would be losing as badly. He is.
He is in a lot of these places.
It's absolute proof of voter fraud.
When it comes to Ron Paul in
several different districts,
there's been several
different videos on an online.
One of them I believe was in Maine
where they committed voter fraud.
Man there they don't want Ron Paul winning
anything nobody does across the board.
The real reality of our system is that
it's designed to make sure everyone
doesn't have a say. It's not
that everyone has a say. It's an,
everyone has a say in who has
a say about who has a say.
And because of that it's a tiered effect.
They able to control it.
They block it off at certain ends.
You don't really vote for president,
you've over representative the
representative votes for president.
There's all these special interest groups
that are funding these politicians and
money's coming from fucking soap
manufacturers and want to keep pouring a
certain amount of shit every year into
the river and make it okay. You know?
And so it's a mess, man.
It's a fucking mess.
And the way to fix it is not what
these guys that are in place,
it's letting these old
motherfuckers die off and let it in.
The new people come in letting these
people though the guys who own Google,
these young motherfuckers that are smart
and figured shit out and just said,
let's just take over everything. Maps,
email, fucking what's make a browser,
let's make, or an operating system.
Let's make phones. Let's make every,
let's go crazy. Let's just
get nuts. So let's just,
I'll control this motherfucker and
do it with a company that's ethical.
And do it with a company
that's nice to their employees,
do with a company that gives him a big
cafeteria and takes care of everybody.
You know,
it's nice to know that there's good
people out there like anonymous. Yes.
I mean look,
I mean we have a force out there who knows
how strong they really are. You know,
cause I hear from people that,
Oh yeah,
they're shutting down government websites
that the government don't even care
about, you know, but I don't really know.
Yeah, that's, that's what I've heard.
Government cares. The government does
not want you shutting anything down.
The guy that told the guy that
told me that he was actually a, um,
a friend of the comedian,
the Indian comedian,
Peter's Russell Peters computers.
He was a friend of his,
when he did the podcast and he had this,
I don't know who he is or
what his name was, but he was,
that's what he was saying.
He seemed to be, uh,
an expert on the whole anonymous thing.
And he said that they're shutting down
websites that really no one cares about,
but the perception that they have power
is actually giving them the power cause
then people rallied behind them
and, and, and that kind of, right.
So it says it's a good thing that you
know, even though they're shutting down,
like, like you know, an FBI website
that's just like a home page or something,
I'm not sure exactly what they're doing,
but the perception that they are power,
we're actually give them power.
Right. Because if everybody,
everybody in this country decided to look
at the government and look at all the
shady shit that's going on. Un UN,
UN unbiased way like a detective.
If everyone just decided to look at all
the evidence and clear their mind and
have an open mind, man, I think the
power will be shifted back to the people.
I think it's just, it's so
many people like the, the,
the propaganda hours ever really been
in the people. You don't have a strong,
how would I propagandists. Yeah. Just
the fact that that Mitt Romney is,
is as the best candidate that
the Republicans can come up with.
That alone tells you there's some shit.
Well, you first of all, for to be a
representative to be a president. Okay.
We've already established pretty much it.
That's just a figurehead with George Bush.
We sort of establish that he
wasn't really the president.
He was the guy that's in that position
and they've, you know, whatever,
for vote him in whatever.
However he got there,
he got there and then everything behind
the scenes was obviously working without
him.
The Dick Cheney situation,
Dick Cheney was the one who was in the
bunker while after all that nine 11 shit
was going down,
he was the one that was hiding.
That guy was essentially the mastermind
for the fucking global empire that is
the United States.
He moved all the pieces in the place,
made sure a lot of people have profited
and got away with some fucking pretty
insane shit. So since that's the
case, you got to realize, well,
in order to be the figurehead, in
order to be the guy, the main guy,
you can't have a fucked up past.
You can't have like some Herman Cain type
shit where you got a lot of bitches on
the side and you're banging them. And
then you know, national enquirer starts
finding out about shit. You
can't have that anymore. We, we,
there's too much introspective.
We're, or there's too much work.
It's too much investigative work.
They can find out if you did some
shady shit and business in the past,
they could find out, you
know, if you, you know,
you fired one of your employees and she
charged with sexual harassment and then
she's going to tell some
crazy story about, you know,
you whipped it dick out in the
wash room or something. You know,
you can't have it. So it leaves
who it leaves. How many people,
how many people don't have fucking
John David? What's that guy's name?
Don Davidson. Who? The Guy, the guy that
got arrested, I want to say John Davidson,
cause he looks like him. The fucking
presidential candidate who got caught.
He had a a baby with another chick,
like a girl who was a videographer on
his Toral. Yeah. No, it wasn't Santorum.
It was. He's in court right now.
Gingrich. You don't even know politicians.
You don't know anybody do. I know
you'll get grits. Yeah, he's huge. John.
I want to say John Davidson,
but that's not as fucking name.
I know she saw someone on Twitter
will tell me what his name is.
This poor fuck though. He's, he's doomed.
I don't think in our time,
dude,
we're going to ever see anybody that
wants to give the power to the people.
I think we just need a much
more ethical sense of rule,
you know? I don't think given to power
to the people. It's real tricky man.
The reason why this whole system is set
up that way is because way back in the
day,
the founding fathers,
even though they had a great idea
what this country could be and great
expectations, they also knew you can't
just completely give power to the people.
You have to have representatives.
You can't have the mob. Just make,
and people are too easy and
manipulate. Paid 13, 13 bloodlines,
13 original states,
13 stars on the flag.
That's some conspiracy shit.
Like what does the blood,
there's supposedly 13 royal bloodlines.
And when John Edwards, thanks.
Kileo Keel, John Edwards,
the psychic? No, John Edwards.
Love to spangle I r l two.
Yeah.
So 13 blood lines. Is that
what it was? Yeah, there's,
there's a connection between,
uh,
according to the people that have this,
the bloodline mastered all the way
back to ancient Sumer 13 bloodlines.
So 13 states.
It's like they made sure they had someone
from each bloodline and that running
that state so that it, it stays in
the blood. What stays in the family?
How could they cut?
Possibly keep that going all these years
and not have anyone know about it all
over youtube. Yeah. But that
doesn't mean anything. It's,
if it hasn't hit CNN yet talking about
it, you know what I mean? Of course.
It's not,
think about this,
the propaganda and the brainwashing
that goes on TV is so fucking strong.
It's so strong that they can
convince most of the people that, uh,
tower seven fell because of fires that
skyscraper they didn't get hit by plain
yogurt isn't impossible. I mean, I
don't know shit about architecture.
Isn't it possible if they've just
did a shit job of that building
somehow another fire which uniformly
spread through the entire building and
caused like the upper layer to collapse
and then it all simultaneously collapsed.
No Way, man. 1500 architects
and engineers, professionals,
they called bullshit.
You look at it. I wonder, I don't even
need to hear the architects of the engine.
I don't know. I look at that
shit. To me, I'm not that stupid.
The government is fucking,
the government's crooked is fuck
history of being crooked as fuck.
That's a controlled demo.
I don't need it for people who listen to
this and go shut the fuck up. You guys.
What are you talking about?
Well you need to know what was in building
seven cause that's where things get
rid built again. Again, Bill,
most people think only two
towers fell because two planes,
a third tower fell. It.
It not only did it fall,
but it fell at free fall speed,
like a controlled demo.
Those things take weeks to load that shit.
Someone was planning something and all
and tower seven wasn't even next to tower
one and two there was, well
there was four five, six.
We're right under it and those got
hit and had massive fires and got hit.
Not One of those collapsed
but a hundred yards away.
When I was little fires 47 it
wasn't even next to the twin towers.
That one fucking get implodes in itself.
How stupid the afterbody collide.
If you think that if they could and you
know you're looking at a bunch of other
stuff. They didn't put tower seven in
the nine one one commission report,
they'd left tower seven out.
They didn't even explain it
and then people for years
they rallied and like what
happened at tower seven
what happened at tower?
So how can we guys aren't
talking about it? Well.
Then they finally were forced into doing
research on it and they came up with
the crazy idea that fires made a 47
steel skyscraper collapse all at once.
And the only way that shit will collapse
all at once, it's all the columns.
A central columns are blown out at the
same time. How our fire's going to do,
it's impossible. I don't know. It's not,
I'm just playing completely
playing devil's advocate.
If I had a bit on video and, and
it's on video, if it wasn't on video,
if there wasn't on video and people just,
it was just word of mouth.
Like there was a tower seven and it fell,
but no one got it on video,
then it would be, you know,
it'd be like, you know,
you'd have to really look into it and,
and really take the word of all these
witnesses. But we have five camera angles.
We got a good and a
professional professionals
are saying it was a controlled
demo.
I mean anybody can tell it's a controlled,
it certainly looks like a controlled
demo and it does literally fall freeze.
Paul speeds. But what's crazy was
what, what is inside. Like what,
who had there was CIA offices, uh, Enron.
All Enron shit was in there.
Um, uh, secret service,
naval intelligence to me, my guess is
that's where everything was orchestrated.
That was where to fucking imagine.
That was where it was orchestrated it
and they go below that motherfucker up.
No evidence. Can you imagine? Cause he had
to be orchestrated somewhere, somewhere.
Had someone had to orchestrate that shit.
It looks like it had to be tower southern
because why would they completely
destroy it?
Explosions going off everywhere.
There's all these witnesses,
there's tons of them.
Same bombs are going off everywhere.
There's a dude who committed suicide and,
but before he committed suicide, he was,
he was talking about how he put a bomb,
went off in the elevator
and he dragged the guy out.
It's a famous interview like right there,
right when it happened.
And he's talking about how
I just dragged him out, man.
His face was peeling all he had no
skinny, just a bomb. Just went off.
Just blew up the whole elevator man.
And this was right when it happened.
Why would it be bullshit?
He's talking about it.
It is also possible that something could
have blown up inside because of the
fire. Just just to say, I mean, just as
a random, but here's what's crazy, man.
The Larry Silverstein, the guy who
owned building seven or building towers,
all of them, all of them, he, um,
he won an $861 million award from
industrial risk insurers to rebuild on the
side of world tower seven,
because, uh, his, uh,
estimated investment was only 386 million.
So he net a profit of roughly $500
million just on that tower. Just on that,
the third tower that no one talks about
the third tower that no one talks about,
it's not an official government
dot, uh, Nylon Commission report.
They left it out. And even,
even those documentaries,
they try to debunk all the nine one one
shit. They try to debunk everything that,
uh, that, uh, [inaudible], that's what
they call them, that, uh, bring up,
but they won't touch tower seven.
They'll have an,
it was an hour and anything
on national geographic,
any of those documentaries.
I firmly believe the CIA has
their hand in those documentaries.
We know that the CIO has always been
involved in Hollywood and always be that
involved in TV.
Look up Harry Anslinger,
the dude who made weedy
legal in 1937 he was in,
he was the first drugs are,
he was involved after all the
drug stuff that, that he did.
He got involved in governing and
supervising Hollywood to make sure there
weren't any communists in Hollywood
or any pro communist movies.
This is all documented there.
CIA had control of Hollywood and you know,
they have their,
their power in there and I believe this
is like every documentary on that and
the National Geographic Channel that
goes over a nine one one or any kind of
conspiracy theory.
The narrators are just,
they're just making fun of conspiracy
theories there. And conspiracy theorists,
they think this,
I'm like,
what kind of show is it's
so it's so biased and they
never cover Tyler seven and
these shows,
there's a nine one,
one debunking documentary on
National Geographic that uh,
they don't cover tower seven.
They'd cover everything else,
but except tower seven because
they don't have an answer for that.
They can't prove that shit cause
they can't prove it felt, uh,
they can't convince anybody. That 47
story skyscrapers, steels, scriber,
will employ all at once.
All the columns blow on it once from fire,
check out what was there. Here's a, here's
some of the buildings. Tenants ready?
Yeah. US Secret Service.
Yes. The NSA, the CIA,
the IRS, the Bureau of Alcohol,
alcohol, Tobacco and firearms.
The SEC and AI see securities Salomon,
Smith,
Barney, Solomon Smith,
Barney, American Express Bank,
International Standard Charter Bank,
provident financial manager.
It's all like these fucking big giant
banks and government all together.
Just a fucking cunt farm.
The stability of honey,
hive of cunts destroy the
evidence. That's incredible. Right?
Could you imagine how this turns out?
That's really what happened.
And then check this out of it.
It was a controlled demo,
so it must have taken weeks to set up.
So they must like,
you got to investigate the security.
Who's running security or guess who's
the head of security and Tyler seven Marv
Bush. George Bush, his
brother. Come on. Yes, dude.
Google that. Marv Bush security. Yes. Yes.
His brother is in charge
of security at Tower Saben.
Hilarious is that it's pretty cool.
That doesn't fucking make your bullshit
meter. Just fucking go off the Richter,
but come on how it does, but it all
seems so, it's like how do you get,
how do you pass a lie?
How do you get people to believe a lie
and make it so big they can't not believe
it. Make it so people
always say this, how good.
You know how many people who would take
to orchestrate done there would never be
able to get away with it. Yeah. Yes they
do because they control the media yet.
How about, and this is on youtube too.
There's on youtube, they're reporting.
The BBC is reporting.
The tower.
Seven went collapsed and it's still up.
Also because they thought
it was going to collapse.
Apparently there isn't that
kind of fishing. It's like, no.
You know what that says that says they
already had scripted shit ready to go.
They already gave him shit.
I already gave him shit.
Just to play devil's advocate.
It also could be to the firemen had
said there's some dangerous creaking and
noises and they think that this building's
going to fall down and it is possible.
That's our and shit. I ain't maybe
ma'am. I'm not a fucking scientist.
I don't really know. I know. I know.
I know. As a host of the show you,
you want to be, you know, you want to
be neutral, you want to be on the fence,
but you know God damn well that there's,
that's some bullshit that
went down when I went to one.
If you look into it unbiased with open
mind, you look at all the evidence,
just decide to look at all the evidence.
I feel the holy Shit.
I fell about nine one one very similar
to the way I feel about that Phillip
Corso son saying it's a time machine.
Come on Elliot.
It's possible a couple. I don't
know. I don't know man. I don't know.
If I had to gasp. Very
smart. If I had to guess,
I would always say I sniff out
bullshit. Very good. Sniff out bullshit.
Way better than I do, dude. How many
guys have like, you know, over the years,
like dudes and trying to like, uh, go
into business with me or you for whatever.
You instantly eagle that guy's
full of shit and I'm like,
what are you talking about? Your
[inaudible], that guy's full of shit.
Your bullshit meter is strong,
dude.
You got one of those high tech alien
fucking bullshit meters from the finish.
I got a a survival genetic,
your bullshit meter is going
off on the inside on the novel,
the nine one one I would see the problem
with that is that's not where I'm,
where my bullshit meter works best.
My Bill Bullshit,
my bullshit meter other works best
with people. I need to talk to people.
If I talk to people, I could see he was
full of shit. Yeah, I could see who's,
who's hiding something. There's a tick
and insecure aspect to weigh their,
the way they're interacting.
It's not just modesty or social weirdness.
I can see deception.
I can see when someone's full of Shit.
I'm pretty good at that. But this, see,
I don't like fucking with my own head.
So whenever I look at something like this,
I have to factor in all
these different things.
I have to factor in possible incompetence,
the the need and desire to think that
everything's a conspiracy to the point
where, like I said, people
have compete convinced, you
know, other people that I am,
some sort of a government
agent. I've actually read
that, you know, it's hilarious.
It's fucking absolutely
completely ridiculous.
But someone will look for a
conspiracy and everything.
That would be grounds to be,
come on. That would be brilliant.
And you think about it when they're
like, uh, if you were part of the elite,
there's a lot of smart mother fuckers,
I'm sure they're brilliant people.
Part of the elite if you were in charge
of coming up with ways to keep the power
and to take liberties away and to take
the power from the people, like really?
I bet. I'm just guessing. The people at
the top, there are people at the time,
I bet they're really concerned with
keeping their power and however they keep,
they don't want to lose their power.
Nobody wants to lose their power.
They want to keep, so whatever
they gotta do to keep their power,
it's just the human condition.
Anybody that was at the top,
that'd be a lot of motherfuckers,
just regular people.
You put them at the top and they'd
be like, maybe we should fucking,
how do we call them down? Are
you sure that'll work? Okay,
let's spray the fuckers with chem
trails. Okay, let's do that shit.
That's a good idea. That's a really, I'd
be a, in the Illuminati boardroom going,
yeah,
let's spray.
Motherfuckers don't ever see a come
and they think it's his fucking cloud.
Just keep making the lines.
No one believes that shit.
You know what I mean? Yeah.
But we've been caught before
and there's been a treaty,
a UN treaty in 1977 that we
can't spray the people no more.
We can't test airborne bacteria on the
people no more. We have to stop. Fuck it.
Let's just keep doing it. You know what
I mean? And now first it's just, uh, uh,
first it's just,
just regular contracts now.
Like all the GL engineering shit's
coming on now. It's like there's a guy,
there's a guy in a documentary
saying that's just con trails.
It's not barium and aluminum.
But in the future we are going to have
to spray barium in aluminum because
that's going to be the only way to
combat global warming in the future.
We're going to have to do, but that's not
it right now. Like, dude, what the fuck?
They're slowly preppiness for
geoengineering protecting the planet.
You know what I mean?
There's no way.
There's the military jets flying all over
the world making grids right above us
and there's no way they're doing
a right above us. And then I,
you can convince the chem
trails are chemicals and
then it's not just a reaction
between the moisture in the atmosphere
and the turbines and the jet engines that
those are contracts.
Con trails disappear within 2030 seconds.
Are you sure about this stuff?
You really do know.
How was it possible that they can
just get away with this? They can do,
they got away with nine one one they
could do anything they want. Yeah,
but I mean this is what
a regular daily thing,
right as we were saying over the country
and no one talking all over the world
except Japan because they're not
part of NATO. So they don't do it.
There's no camera. Did I get pictures
from all over the world? People,
you'll see me retweet that shit. People,
people who are and and remember guys,
you want me to retweet some camp trails?
It can't be just one line dude,
seven seven send me some alarming shit.
People.
I retweet a picture of one line.
People aren't going to believe that's
going to scare people away. So anyways,
what I'm saying is,
is that for instance,
there's a military base in
Guantanamo Bay in Cuba, Cuba,
supposedly our enemies, they
hate us, we hate them, whatever.
But there's a military
base on that ion of, of,
of Cuba called Guantanamo
Bay and Americans is do
whatever the fuck they want.
They, they, they uh, uh, uh,
their ships come in and out.
No what the Cubans don't
want to fuck with them.
They want to start a war with these mother
fuckers. Well Jack them and every day.
Now this is not a conspiracy theory.
This is on a documentary with one of
the guys in charge, a military officer,
talkies,
so against Cuba talking about and bragging
about how every day they dive bomb
like fighter jets down
into downtown Havana.
They dive bomb low and
just scare him everyday.
And he says this on camera and all proud,
like all about waving the flag.
I'll practice.
We do that every day because when we
decide to attack them they'll never see it
coming.
So that's,
that's an example of classic military
operation like operator operation
Northwoods. There they have a pattern.
They do sheet over. So to me up and we,
and we have, we have,
um, ex military, uh, uh,
air force and marine people
like getting into whether,
uh, getting on the news,
reporting the weather.
There's two separate guys that are on
TV and anytime they look at chem trails
they'll talk about,
well those aren't real clouds.
I don't know what the
military is doing up there,
but they're spraying a thing called chaff.
Chaff is aluminum,
Barium and it's to get a
radar of the whole area.
So that's proven. Whoa, wait
a minute, it's called chat.
They're spraying something in the
air so they can get radar. Yes.
Because of metallic particles,
heart elect.
So if you just spray a whole area with,
and this is what they do in the military.
This is not a conspiracy.
That's how they do it.
In the military they spray aluminum and
Barium to get a radar map and to jam
radars, they jam radars and to
map out locations as well. Um,
how many map manpower locations,
like you could detect the Matarin
were all the metallic particles land,
you know what I mean?
So they do that already.
They've been doing that since the fourth.
They do clouds seat and how do you clouds,
if you put barium in disguise and all
these tests of all these people are going
there,
they're spraying,
all the tests are coming back
with high levels of aluminum,
high levels of Barium.
And then the myth that's,
it's just so happens with the
military sprays, it's called,
they call it chaff in the military.
It's called chaff. And guess what?
There's fucking,
I don't know why they're doing it,
but they're spraying chaff over a lot
of major cities in the United States and
all over the world. All over
England. They're spraying and shop.
And it can be two things. If I was running
the elite and I said, you know what,
spray even make it benign just to throw
them up, just spray, put something in in,
in the, the, the, the, the atmosphere
get, I'm used to all these weird lines.
Don't put any aluminum, don't put any
barium. Cause once they start testing it,
they're gonna, you know, they'll
find out that it's totally benign,
but just get them used to it.
That's what I would do.
I would just get the people used to
it so that when it's time, you know,
if it gets crazy and a revolution comes,
dude,
all we gotta do is just keep doing what
we're doing. They'll never see it coming.
People will start dying, aren't
they? No. One near to though.
Who knows where they're at and I
believe this is what I believe.
I believe that the pilots don't really
even know what the fuck they're doing.
I believe they think they're trying to,
they're they're,
they're claiming that it's
for global warming and it's
to protect the atmosphere.
Now that we're at the stage now
where we're at the stage now,
where they're admitting that that's
what they're going to have to do.
We haven't been doing it.
Who's admitted to do,
there's so much shit on the government
to go, go on my youtube channel,
go on my youtube channel and gone the
playlists chem trails. I got mad dude.
The guy that, you know, what's the
difference between Google and Youtube?
It's all error. You know? It's true. It's
visual shit. You make it. You have to,
you kind of have,
people are talking on video,
you make the decision or
they've brought a shit.
You look at them and then you look
at the evidence, the video evidence.
You know most people thought
Oj was guilty and they didn't.
There was no pictures of her.
That was, there was no video.
Do you know Joey Diaz calls you
chem trails sometimes. Exactly.
How's chem trails doing? Dude? You
know what? I think chem trails.
I think anonymous should be trying to
get to the bottom of why the military is
spraying aluminum and Barium.
It fucks our body of looking to,
it fucks up our immune system.
It fucks up our respiratory system.
I think if there is,
if there's no barium or
aluminum and they're just,
I think they're just getting us used to
it because when shit goes down the good,
the way,
the good look at the way she going now
they're taking away all our liberty.
Liberty's look at all the shit that,
the way they're reacting and battling
occupy Wall Street and all that shit.
They're making it illegal to
protest in front of this and that.
The way that shit's going.
It looks like they're trying
to control the revolution.
What better way to control the revolution
to just spray these motherfuckers?
That's the best way. What
do you got? Another way?
Show me another west the best way.
Get them used to the lines and then
when it went, if they get too crazy,
we'll just spray out.
There'll be so easy to calm them down.
We could put anything in those clouds
and it's in the water. It's in the air,
dude. It's brilliant what they're doing.
Do you know that there's photos of, uh,
of chem trails or what?
You know what looks like chem trails?
The same thing from like the 1940s
apps. They've been doing it, do it.
They've been testing it on,
on,
they've been doing in the military sense
from the forties to the 60s and on over
300 cities. Dude, that's why in
1977 that have put a halt to it.
They had to put a halt to it.
It was ridiculous.
They were doing it for over 20 years
straight the and in, in the military.
That's classic shit.
How do you battle?
How would you fuck up the enemy spray
shit all over him did using chemical
weapons. That's old school. They've
been doing that shit forever.
They didn't have Vietnam
with Agent Orange.
They've been doing it in the Middle East.
They've been doing a world war one
World War II. Just spray motherfuckers.
That's the chemical warfare. That's the
easiest shit. Just fuck them up with the,
you don't have to drop bombs on him.
You don't have to destroy
the buildings or anything.
Just spray whatever you want. Something
that's going to debilitate them slowly.
I mean for people to think
that it's impossible.
It already happened and they
had a stop in in 1977 as a,
that kind of obsessed with dude.
It's, I see it every God damn day.
You're absolutely convinced. I'm
absolutely did. I don't put anything past.
I don't put anything past the government.
I believe there's some
shady shit going on.
Those aren't commissioner
commercial airlines.
How do you even coming out of their
commercial airline? Cause I pay attention
dude.
I've been on the,
I've been on between Burbank and and lax.
I've been on like 10,000 flights.
I know the flight patterns.
I could look up in the sky and know if
that's a commercial airline or have it to
a jet commercial airlines.
I like straight up like rockets and
then come across and they're not,
you've got to, if you pay attention
like you know birdwatchers right?
Like how do you know,
how do they keep this shit quiet?
They do anything they want.
This is above this is they'll
do anything they want did,
you can't stop them think
this is just practice.
It could be practice or that we
can be right in the middle of it.
How much time during the day
do you think about this shit?
Every time I drive and I fucking see the
sky ruined. But what if it wasn't that?
What if it really would try?
Dude,
I hope I'm wrong about chem trails do
cause there's a lot of websites to debunk
it. Well not just one or two but there's
a lot of like scientific science that
really deep well they're,
they're just like,
there's a lot of websites
that debunked nine one one.
All I know is military jets are making
fucking clouds and who knows the exact
reason,
but we have evidence of military people
on a news and weather reports talking
about chat.
They're reporting on the chaff and they're
spraying aluminum and Barium in the s
fund. But I mean to say that all of that
is what you're seeing. And then some,
sometimes you know,
they may have done tests in the past,
but what you're seeing when you
see this criss crossing clouds,
I mean if you talk to a a pilot,
they explain it in that
it's just something when
atmospheric would water in the
atmosphere encounters the jet
engines and it creates these,
it's a contrail depending on how much
water in the atmosphere can actually
create clouds that the numbers that
they give out, they have like uh,
the temperatures like give me the
temperature of what it needs to be.
It needs to be like
30,000 feet in the air.
Like the humidity and the temperature,
they can't,
like what's the difference
between contrast and Kendra?
They can't give you the difference.
What's the difference they have come from,
from commercial Aircrafts? Do you
think they're doing this as a contrast?
The ones from commercial
airlines are contract, but
they look the same. The same.
Sometimes there's photos of him.
Let's show like commercial Aircrafts and
there it looks like or chem trails. No,
no, but, but if you pay
attention and you look at it,
you'll see that it disappears.
It won't last forever.
There's a big difference between,
uh,
the ones that lasts the whole day and
one's a disappear within 30 seconds.
The ones that disappear are
totally not a natural phenomenon.
It's the jet engine with the heat, with
the ice crystals, but it's different.
We already know the military sprays
aluminum and Barium and we know that when
they do that it,
it leaves shit on the weather report.
They have to explain what it is because
of the aluminum, because of the Barium,
the weatherman has to explain that
that's just military aluminum and Barium.
They're explaining that it's already done.
It's not like whether or not they do,
I mean they definitely
know how to make shit rain.
There've been doing it in Abu Dhabi.
They make it ran once a week and they put,
they put chemicals in the sky. Yeah. It's
called cloud seeding clouds sitting up.
I'm sure there's Barium or it's, it's
either burying them or something. Yeah,
that's what they're spraying. And that's
what they do with chaff. It, they do it.
You know, it's this harp. What the fuck
is harp? You don't know what harvest.
I don't know exactly. I know it scared
Jesse Ventura says it's bad, dude. It's,
it's, it's one of those things
where you all I know about harp,
all I know about harp is, um,
look into it, man. It's, it's,
it used to be, it used to be, uh,
a scientific project shooting
something in the atmosphere.
It's like a billion.
It's like a football field filled with
all these electrical coils that make like
a billion. And they can direct a
billion watts into the atmosphere.
They're experimenting with the ionosphere
or whatever the fuck that means.
They're shooting electricity into
the atmosphere and experimenting,
which it, some people think they're
experimenting with whether control and,
and uh, um, you, you love
conspiracy though. No. But now, now,
now,
now it got taken out.
It's not a scientific project now it's
top secret and it's now it's all air
force, military, a top secret. They won't
tell anybody what it is. It does exist.
Punch in harp. It's not a
concern. No, no noise. It's real.
But what they're doing as a
conspiracy. Yeah. Who knows? Uh, it's,
it's fascinating. It's fascinating.
But you fucking love this shit, dude.
I hope. I hope I'm wrong, Dude.
I hope I'm wrong, but Julie,
I know you do you want to have your,
to me,
if someone proved it to
me that I was wrong, Dude,
and I would admit it and I would love
it and I would feel great, I'd be like,
fuck, I don't have to, when you read
the, the sites, the debunk chem trails,
you just don't find their
arguments. In fact, no, no.
It's the same people that think
that at nine one one collapse,
do fired at the same people,
that same mentality they refuse.
It's like a game to them.
They just want to be right.
You look at all the evidence.
We already have evidence.
We have it's military chaff.
We already know that.
They're already talking
about Geo engineering.
They were talking about it in 1996
that they were going to have to suspend
metallic particles in the air.
As Zachariah Sitchin was talking about
this in the 70s that that was going to
happen. I was, you know, he said that's
how the Annunaki, that's how they,
that's how they protected their atmosphere
by so south to get high and talk
about the Annunaki. I mean, I don't
know if the unlucky he was real or not,
but God damn,
would it be fun if they were real,
but it would so suck if they were real.
If we,
if it turned out that we weren't the apex
of the biological life in the universe,
if we're not at the top of the heap,
we're fucked man.
Cause someone's going to treat us the
way we treat everything else. You know?
So if the Annunaki are real,
you should really hope they're not real.
We should hope that we become the Annunaki
should hope that the film, of course,
our junior version as the best version,
the fact that there's a time machine
and we're going to become that in the
future. That seems to me to make more
sense. There's probably, who knows man,
any when it comes to Ufo every day.
Now it's in the science community and
astrophysical we're finding there's,
you get all these, all this
information coming out that there,
there's all of these new
earth's that they're,
they're predicting they're just earth
everywhere and there's life teeming in our
galaxy. Everyone, like
there's on the daily,
they're finding evidence like holy shit,
there's probably a billion fucking
earths in our galaxy or some shit they're
putting out is pretty crazy.
When you think about the possibilities,
possibilities are endless.
They're really can have life seeds from
other planets getting hit by asteroids
and it's all a natural part of
the process. Think about this.
If there's a million earths in
this guy that just say a million,
how many of those herbs are
ahead of us in technology?
I'm sure there's some that are
like not as far as we've come,
but there's a, you know, just the
odds you look at like a scientist,
there's a million right,
that you would say,
let's just say a thousand are
way ahead of us. God dammit,
that's a thousand a thousand race.
There must be a galactic federation there.
There must be,
I think may comment said to be like
a little bit smarter than this.
And then we just blow shit up over and
over again. I think that's what we do.
There was a, you know what,
there's a possibility that, uh,
out of all the earth and all the,
the,
the human like careers
within the front of the line,
like maybe 70% of them don't make it.
You know, like in, in the Roman times,
it was a 50% mortality rate. When you
have a kid, there's a happened, ha ha,
there's 50% chance that it's
going to die in Roman times.
So maybe it's like that. Maybe
there's 50% chance that, you know,
we get to a point and we
just blow ourselves up cause
corruption takes over and
evil just takes them.
And then there's a
small percentage,
maybe it's like 10% 20% of all of these
earth like planets that actually get
past that and we all connect
and we're living like,
you know that when they have
like a category one society's,
you know, level one society
and level two that, you know,
I think a Michio Kaku has done this
like explaining the different levels of,
you know,
societies that can get to a point where
they get away from physical violence,
then they can,
you know,
use a harness the power of the stars
and then space travel and all sorts of
different categories and that we're,
we're like on the verge of becoming
significant. There's, there's,
I personally believe just based on just
basic odds that there is a galactic
federation and maybe we are just,
we don't know about it.
Maybe the elite know about it and
they're communicating with them,
but the people we don't want to
leave. You know, I think our elite,
there are people at the top.
They're not all at the bottom.
There's people at the top.
This is a very real,
I think the very real possibility that
our number one problem is that we're
separated from this idea of how
connected we all to each other because
psychedelics are illegal. That's why this
world in this country that we live in,
this government that we're running to
is so fucked up and corrupt because they
don't deserve to be in the
position they're ad they've
never had a life changing
experience to the point where they
have experienced that other side of of
possible reality that comes
from the psychedelic experience.
You can't get past that.
It's unbelievably humbling and you
should be looking for that in a leader.
You shouldn't want a leader that hasn't
that psychedelic experiences cause
that's a person who hasn't really
faced whatever the fuck that is.
When you strip away culture,
when you strip away language and you
just see truth and love in this humbling
Bayer form,
they'd just like rips you to your
core and makes you sorta rebuild and
restructure who you are as a human being.
A lot of those motherfuckers
have never had that man.
There's a lot of people that
are out there running around,
flapping their gums that have
never really been humbled by life.
They never be really been humbled
by a psychedelic experience,
which is a part of life. It's not just
a choice. I think it's a part of life.
It certainly is a choice. I mean don't
get me wrong, don't do it. If you,
if you don't do drugs and you can't handle
even a drink, you know, don't, don't go,
don't do anything you're not comfortable
with, but it's a part of life man.
That's why it's here. That's why it
works on you. The reason why it works,
he says cause it's here for to work
for you. It's a part of you. You're,
you're part of a giant system.
Get some mushrooms in your head bitch.
Right? Yeah, man, I got to take off.
I gotta I gotta end this to this.
How long did we go? Almost three hours.
Two hours of 57 minutes. How Fun was that?
Did we do enough of it?
Man,
I don't want people passed on and
we did a lot of shit. We did a,
it was a beautiful thing,
man. These conversations are
so far. Um, effortless. Yeah.
Yeah, it was great. I love doing that. Oh,
I'm going to do more of these
one on one conversations.
I think sometimes it's different, you
know, it mixes it up a little bit.
We've got a lot of cool a guest
this week though. I think we're,
I think Chael Sonnen's this week.
I'm not sure.
I got to call is going to be
awesome. When is that? I don't know.
Soon Ronda Rousey. We're going
to, she's going to be sooner.
I ran into her at the UFC looking good
is ever going to face for dice Kat.
Von D is interested.
Is she really?
I would love to have her on
and just talking about art.
She's been on the road
and she didn't have like,
there's some personal turmoil going
on right now, but um, she got,
she wants to volunteer. I love her art
work, man. I love looking at, shoot,
just like a sketch a day. She did.
She did down my grandma on my chest.
It's beautiful too. It's amazing.
All right, that's it folks.
We're going to have a death death squad
show this weekend at the Ice House in
Pasadena on Friday night. It's only
85 seats and they always sell out.
I don't know who was there. It's a
Freddy Lockhart for sure. Me for sure.
Red Band for sure and a bunch of
other talented people in the year. Oh,
Tony Hinchcliffe who's going to host it.
There's a bunch of talented local guys.
And then we do a podcast out of
the ice house called the Ice House.
Chronicles in that podcast is
only available on death squad,
which is a different thing on iTunes.
It's Brian's Brian's whole set up. So, uh,
we will, uh, see you then and tomorrow.
Duncan Trussell is going to
come on and just me and Duncan.
I'm going to sit down and we're going to
talk about the universe and figure out
this whole squad squabble
than he has with Brian.
That's the end of the podcast bitches.
Thanks to the fleshlight.
Thanks to a on it.com go to Joe rogan.net
and click on either link and either
use the code named Rogan for fleshlight
and get 15% off or use it on on it and
get 10% off and the 10% off
is for any and all orders too.
It's not just the first one.
Use The codeine Rogan and
then some other codes online.
Can I then we're almost done here though.
Okay, quick. I'll just real quick,
like I mentioned earlier,
I've got 30 schools worldwide.
If you want to find out if there's
a 10 plan at school near You,
10th planet j j.com click locations.
All of them are up there.
We got Rochester mantra yen.
Perfect.
Beautiful it. Yeah, we
off. Yup. Nice Dude.
That was three fucking hours.
Holy Shit. How do we do that shit?
It seems like.