Hello Freak bitches.
Why do these patterns repeat themselves?
What is it about human beings?
Well,
we like things simple.
We like things simple.
So C and then you often like a simple
explanation is a good explanation unless
it's too simple.
But distinguishing between simple and
too simple is no easy matter.
We like,
we like to know who's our friend and
who's our enemy and we like the feeling
of under and moral superiority and then
learned morals,
which had,
especially when there is no such thing
as earning anyways.
So,
and then,
I mean there's deeper and darker things
that are underneath that.
It's like the human proclivity to pull
down those who have more than you.
It's like these kids on the campuses who
are claiming identity with the
oppressed,
you know,
somewhere like Yale.
It's like how in the world you can speak
of oppression if you happened to be at
Yale is beyond me.
I mean,
first of all,
your North American,
which puts you in the top 1% and then of
North Americans,
you're in the top 1% two in the top 1%
of 1% but yet you,
you want that,
you want to have all the power that goes
along with that and you want to have the
moral superiority that comes from being
a,
uh,
representative of the oppressed.
So that's exactly what you want.
You want all the power and you want all
the victimization at the same time.
Well,
years.
Yale is a great example because Yale was
one of the,
what happened with the Halloween costume
debacle had gail was one of the first
videos that was released that made
people horrified where they couldn't
believe how students were communicating
with professors.
Yeah.
Well do a student who,
who screamed up a storm about,
about that.
Uh,
the male professor who was the husband
of the woman who wrote the Pro Halloween
costume letter,
it turned out she was on the bloody
hiring committee that hired him.
One of the things she screamed was,
who hired you?
It was like,
well,
it turned out it was you because you
were on the committee just a few years
before.
I know.
And they took it like,
yeah,
that was absolutely in the people.
Well that don't know what the hell we're
talking about.
Well explained this debacle because it
really was about questionable Halloween
costumes.
Well,
it was about questioning Halloween
costumes.
Halloween costumes are
part of the whole point of Halloween is
to have questionable costumes,
right?
You play with death for example,
in decay and and horror and,
and it's,
it's a time when the norms with regards
to the expression of things that are
outside of our normal behavior are
suspended so that everybody can can have
a little celebration.
As it turns out.
Well,
you know,
campuses have got all upset about things
like cultural appropriation at Queen's
University in Canada just the other week
they were going after students who were
dressing up as Viet Cong for example,
or Mexicans.
It's like,
I just don't see what the hell's racist
about dressing up like a Mexican.
Mexicans have a traditional traditional
clothing.
What?
There's nothing wrong with Mexicans.
So why is it wrong to dress up like
them?
And if you want to be Puncho via for
Halloween,
what's wrong with that?
A wall will get what you can.
You can regard that as an Omar's just as
much as a denigration.
It's like why is that such a problem?
Right.
But anyways,
it doesn't matter because nothing's too
trivial to be a problem to a social
justice warrior.
And because they don't like to deal with
real problems.
And Yale went after Halloween costs.
So this woman wrote a letter saying,
maybe we should just relax about this
stuff.
And you know,
not don't put restrictions on what
people wear for Halloween,
but let people decide what is and isn't
offensive.
Yes.
And well,
in many Halloween costumes are
offensive.
That's the point.
But her letter was in really reasons.
It was perfectly reasonable.
It was like an,
it was like an adult wrote it.
Yes.
Yeah.
And,
and you know,
all hell broke loose,
all hell.
And she ended up,
she ended up quitting.
And I think he did it.
No,
I don't think,
I don't think he left.
I don't think he left,
but she did.
Seeing him bow down to this woman's
screaming at him,
swearing in his face was so disturbing.
It was so humiliating.
I felt so humiliated for him cause she
was screaming,
this is our home.
What the fuck are you doing?
You're not making a safe home.
The university's not a home.
It's not a safe space.
It's not a secure space.
None of that.
And,
and if,
if it that when they get
a university isn't a home,
that's not what it is.
It's a place to be confronted by,
I would say often horrible ideas.
You want to learn about history,
you think that's going to be safe.
Do you know what human history is like?
It's an endless blood bath with,
you know,
with,
with a certain amount of a hopeful
progress underlying it.
It's,
it's a,
it's a horror show and great literature
is like that.
And,
and,
and biology is terrifying and physics is
terrifying and you want to be safe.
It's stay home.
Stay home with your mom,
stay home with your dad.
Don't come to university if you want to
be safe,
because anything you do outside,
no one of the,
if you,
if you're going,
if the university is going to make you
safe than it ceased to be a university.
So one of the things I tried to do in my
class,
I have this class called maps of
meaning,
which concentrates on atrocity basically
on Soviet atrocity and,
and Nazi atrocity mostly.
And what I tried to do in the class is
to teach my students that had they been
in Nazi Germany in the 1930s,
they would've been Nazis and had they
been offered the opportunity to be in
Auschwitz,
camp guard,
then maybe they would have leapt at it
and maybe they would have been in the
sadistic,
uh,
in the more sadistic proportion of the
Auschwitz camp guard population.
You think that makes you feel safe.
It doesn't make you feel safe to know
that Nazis were humans and you happen to
be one of them.
And so I think that educators that tell
students that they're offering them a
safe space are doing them a profound
disservice.
And you don't,
I'm a clinical psychologist.
Here's one of the things you do to make
people less afraid.
You don't make the world safer.
What you do is you people tell you what
they're afraid of and then you break it
into little bits so that they can go
confront them.
You know?
So maybe they were afraid of going to a
party and you break that down and you
say,
well,
do you know how to introduce yourself?
And he said,
well,
I don't,
I don't really even know how to shake
someone's hand.
And so then you practice having them
shake their hand and introduce
themselves because maybe they weren't
taught by that by their halfway did
parents when they were,
when they were young,
because they were ignored.
And so then you say,
well,
maybe you can go to a party for half an
hour and all you have to do is introduce
yourself to two people and then we'll
call that success.
And you build up their competence and
their confidence one step at a time.
And what happens to the clinical
literature indicates quite clearly is
you don't make people less anxious.
By doing that.
You make them braver.
It's not the same thing.
You don't make the world and its horrors
smaller.
You make the person and their their
their capacity to deal with horror
larger.
You encourage them,
you strengthen them.
That's what you do at a university.
You arm people with arguments,
you,
you hone their intellect,
you help them learn to write so they can
marshal their arguments.
You,
you'll help them learn how to engage in
intellectual combat because that's
better than engaging in real combat.
And you make them,
you make them hard and strong.
You don't mollycoddle them and make them
safe unless you're their enemy,
unless you're trying to devour their
spirit.
And that's what we have in the
universities.
We have,
we have the reign of the depaul mother
who's,
who's answered everything is all just
come a little closer deer and all
protect you from the world.
It's just like Hansel and Gretel,
the,
you know,
the which in the Hansel and Gretel
story.
Well my house is made of gingerbread.
Just come in here and everything will be
fine while she feeds you candy to fatten
you up so she can eat you.
That's the archetype of a modern
university.
[inaudible].