Start recording,
Bam.
So having right now,
but just says off air though,
this is all fair.
Oh,
well you have to refresh that screen.
Anyone else?
Too High.
Alright,
here we go.
We're live.
Bitches.
It's me and Batman.
Batman with me.
So I don't fuck around.
This is a,
some new show.
Everybody with this is.
This is some new bad ass jacket that you
can get that allows you to also be a
robber.
You can be a bank robber and you don't
even have to wear a ski mask and look
suspicious.
You just.
This is like a mask that comes with this
fucking this thing
show everybody.
Show everybody.
How does that
turns into the hood?
It's a hood,
but it's a mask.
So in these hard economic times,
why is this?
Is there another version of that window?
She was the girl that died,
that snored that giant line account.
Really?
I don't really know she died,
but people in the Internet you're
saying,
should I?
Alright,
what's up bitches?
How's everybody doing?
We got two things going on here.
We got this,
uh,
this um,
twitter thing where you can,
um,
if you twitter your questions,
we'll answer your questions for that.
Or if you go to my website,
which is a forums Joe Rogan.net,
people asking you questions.
God dammit.
This one fella?
Yeah,
he apologized.
That's good.
Alright.
What's happened at fuckers?
What's going on?
Can we some questions?
Some good ones.
How many bond here tonight?
We haven't taken anything.
Baguettes.
We've only used a little little pipe
that some of the gaming.
No bond hits bitches.
Bong hits for Jesus Salads.
John's microphone.
Where I see that it's not really,
that doesn't do it.
Somebody does it for him,
why he's doing it,
but they're doing a really good job
getting all the information.
Here's his Christmas dinner was like he
had Charlie Sheen to talk
about.
He had terrorism to talk about how
somehow they connected with each other.
Yeah.
He'll probably have some thing.
Well,
Charlie didn't do anything.
The government doesn't want Charlie out
there and talking about nine slash 11.
I'm half Joey Diaz.
Half Alan knows that that's too high,
ladies and gentlemen,
to to be doing a show.
This is ridiculous.
The weed that they have here in
California is just too goddamn strong.
Ladies.
Gentlemen.
It's medical.
You could just buy it from a fucking
store.
Should is outrageous
and it's train wreck.
That's nice.
That's like one of the best scores you
can get.
I don't like how you guys are looking
down at me.
Makes for uncomfortable.
I wish we're looking eye to eye on the
same level.
I'm going to have to set this up so that
we're looking at eye.
It feels weird looking time.
Yes,
smart monitor.
I can trade you.
You're so nice.
Question,
question,
question.
Let's go to the Rogan board.
We're going to go to two forums,
dot Joe Rogan.to
the official 12 slash 29 ustream ustream
podcast thread where the questions are
not limited to a gay 140 characters.
That shit's ridiculous.
Do you think there will be one world
government in our life or do you think
it will act and and how do you think it
will actually affect us?
I think that's possible.
It's very possible if they can get the
money sorted out between all these
fucking scumbags at Ronnie's world
governments.
Yeah.
They would all agree to one gigantic
system of government.
The problem with one gigantic system of
government it is though,
even though it would be harder for
corruption,
it will be.
It's also harder to keep people in line
because you have to have enemies.
You have to have like,
you know the,
the Turks hate the fucking Iranians hate
the hate the Vac.
If you don't have that conflict,
it's very difficult to keep people in
line,
you know?
And if we were all the United States of
America,
then we started arguing about money.
We started arguing about taxes.
We started,
you know,
if we're all one thing,
it makes it very difficult to do,
but as far as like giant international
banks,
they might already be in cahoots or
close enough to one world government.
I mean there might be a few that are
really pulling the strings and running
things.
But I mean,
yeah,
because the future,
if that government was just the
Internet,
so if we can be wanting to vote,
it was just like going on a message
board in voting like hey,
so we have legal insurance vote now.
That would be critical.
Good.
That'd be like for the people.
But then people would hack it.
Yeah.
No,
it's,
it's all good on paper.
But you know,
anything that you do on the Internet
now,
like two to play poker,
you never know if you're playing poker
against a real dude,
you know,
you could easily be playing poker.
It's a computer,
right?
I mean I don't know what kind of
programs they run,
but it seems to me like at this point in
time people can hack just about anything
they can.
I mean there's,
there's programs like that's the problem
with these drones.
They have.
You heard about this,
those drones can actually hacking into
the drones.
Like the airplanes.
This drones.
I checked the borders and stuff there.
Yeah.
Well they don't just check borders.
They launched missiles.
They have these fucking things,
these drones that shoot these called
Hellfire
missiles and they use them in Pakistan
and all these places where we're not
really supposed to bake and they just
fly in and Jack People.
Well,
the insurgence have figured out how to
hack the code and actually view the
Monitor.
It's,
it's crazy shit,
man.
Speaking of crazy shit.
I really do have to say shit.
We plan this out bad.
So I'm going to take a shit and Brian's
going to answer questions
and that's a $29 program that,
that,
that they use just to hack our videos.
So you ask questions.
I'll be asking questions from here to.
There is a toilet in his office.
What is your opinion?
Uh,
that's good.
In fact,
at twitter,
Joe doesn't make the extract listerine
packages.
It's actually one of the products that's
sold here in California.
When you have a medical marijuana
license,
you can go to a store and they saw the
listerine at the store.
Like it looks like listerine strips a.
So now he doesn't make them himself.
Joe Has not seen avatar yet.
We're the last two people to see Avatar
and we're supposed to see it this week.
It's pretty annoying.
Not being the last one to see it.
Underwear bomber was staged.
Any thoughts they did from the the
airplane stage under coverage?
The government man,
the government.
I think he's just a retard.
Joe just thinks he's a retard.
I think it shows you how fragile our
system is.
Now.
The one guy to do one stupid thing in
the whole world grinds to a halt and
security.
It takes five hours.
Now
you guys probably didn't hear that,
but he thinks it's pretty ridiculous how
one guy did all of that and that's how
bad our security is and now our shit's
all fucked up from that one.
Dig.
Yeah.
Security lines are five hours long,
right?
One guy shows you how fragile this
system knows.
Joel is not.
We're not reading the chat on Ustream.
Joe Is only doing the twitter,
so if you have a message joe answered.
If you put on twitter or Joe Rogan's
website,
which is forums dot Joe Rogan.net.
He's taking a shit right now so he'll be
right back.
It's the coffee.
Sorry,
it's the starbucks coffee.
Um,
let's see.
Let's go back to the.
Alright,
let me go read some messages on chose
website forum style.
Joe Rogan.net.
Joe would be right back.
Let's go.
Uh,
almost 300.
Yeah.
I have the dark vader,
a mark Ecko sweatshirt.
Asa.
But yeah,
that Boba Fett wins.
Pretty sweet.
I have realized though.
It's pretty gay when you're by yourself.
Not with friends,
but these sweatshirts.
There's the Boba Fett.
Is it?
Oh yeah.
You know,
I think Mark Lehman had one of those new
war to the UFC.
Mark Layman is a,
he's a comic book nerd and a,
an a,
a Jujitsu freeing.
Teaches a lot of guys who fight fighting
the world.
Jujitsu.
And he's a,
he's a big video game junkie.
And he had a Boba Fett one on pretty
dope.
Pretty Dope.
Alright.
Questions?
Questions from the twitter world is my
twitter tweet deck.
I couldn't get to refresh it and I think
it's the API thing against.
You may want to close that and use the
ustream one only.
Okay.
I see it's not closed yet.
Just shut off that
right twitter on ustream.
Let's go with the questions here.
Bitches.
What am I back in Ireland.
I'm not going to be back in Ireland
until the UFC back in Ireland.
It's not financially feasible for me to
make those trips without the UFC to the
UK,
but every time I'm there,
if there's a show,
if we're going,
if we're doing a UFC in Ireland for sure
I'll be doing standup comedy there.
They could hear the flesh.
Can you hear me?
Did you want me to take it down?
It was so strong I couldn't resist it.
I knew I had to go.
I didn't want to.
I want to do.
I wanted to be able to just man up and
push through the whole use dream,
but I was like,
I'm going to do a bad job.
Does I'm just be thinking about this
dump I have to take.
So what was,
what were we talking about before I took
off?
Because it was kind of important stuff.
Uh Huh.
I think the one road thing is the last
thing you talked.
Oh,
that was the first question.
The one world government,
our lifetimes,
I don't know man.
I used to,
I had a lot more faith before Obama got
elected.
I'll tell you that I thought that maybe
what we had was a corrupt situation and
you know,
the Bush and Cheney were corrupt in that
if we got somebody else in there,
maybe they could straighten everything
out.
But after Obama got elected,
man it,
it became pretty clear to me that
someone else besides the president
obviously is pulling the strings.
Obama didn't want to send more troops.
Obama didn't want to go to Afghanistan
to bring more people to Afghanistan and
he wanted to pull out a Guantanamo Bay,
close Guantanamo Bay,
don't all that shit,
but it's not.
I don't think he gets to say what the
fuck they do or he was just saying that
kind of shit to get elected.
You know,
the,
the old Bill Hicks,
Joe comes to mind.
You know that American politics is a,
you know,
I like the puppet on the right.
Well,
I find the puppet to the left to be more
to my liking.
Hey,
wait a minute.
There's one guy who's holding both
puppets.
I think it's right.
What are you doing?
Oh,
it's not doing anything.
I'm just.
I know what you're just tracking the
shit you had to hang up on the screen.
Moving shit around.
Fucking psycho.
He's a tweaker but not like the pine.
Mckee has come more to optimize my
internet's.
He's the kind of due to hacks into his
registry to make us internet like one
kbh faster.
You're one of those dudes,
right?
You remember when computers first came
out and uh,
do you ever.
I always had,
I had a friend that said that he could
hack into the library and like get rid
of all the,
do fees and stuff like that.
I always wondered if that was real
for my Lego.
Well,
definitely there were some systems that
you could hack into if you were a
wizard.
You know,
isn't that what nick did a lot of shit
with like phone calls.
Right.
Did like get information from people.
Like it wasn't even that he was this
great hacker was just.
She was kind of like a con man.
Tighter way.
Did you read that?
They just hacked the like a 21 year old
code that a ramp that scrambles or phone
calls on cell phones so now and the
guys,
the hackers put it on the Internet so
anyone could have it.
So now,
I mean of course it's probably not going
to happen to us anytime soon,
but now there's actually people that
have the code to that they can listen to
your phone and listen to your phone
calls.
Holy Shit.
Twenty one year old code,
like a 64 bit code.
I think that's where the
just headed to.
I think that's where I think that's the
future.
The future is there's not going to be
any private information.
I think what we're seeing with like this
tiger
woods thing,
I think we're seeing the future of
things to come.
I mean with him,
it's obviously that he's a celebrity and
it's a.
But the way that everybody is swarming
after this information.
Me Too,
man,
I can't fucking put down and US weekly.
If I see an US weekly at the market and
there's some new tiger woods information
I grabbed that I can't fucking help it.
You know,
will I think eventually there's not
gonna be any secrets.
I think eventually we're going to get to
a point where the way information is
being distributed,
it's changing the way we feel about
information.
I mean it's a weird with celebrities.
It's one thing,
you know,
we're looking at it like,
well these are famous people and it's
like they give up that right once,
once you start,
you know,
putting yourself in the public eye,
you give up that right to privacy.
Well eventually that's going to happen.
Like it's happening with facebook
accounts to like girls are doing stupid
shit in their facebook accounts and he
gets all the internet and they go,
well you know she gave up her right when
she put it on facebook.
It's like that new google goggles where
you can just take a photo of anything
and it figures out what it is and then
search is it for you.
So you can now like go to a,
like a VC,
like a can of pop can take a picture of
it and knows what it is.
Google say,
but you can see it starting to get where
you can.
They're going to do it where you can do
flowers and plants and anything's A.
Pretty soon everything's going to be
google search,
so there is no privacy.
So while I'm here I could,
you know what I mean?
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean eventually I'm sure that shit is
going to make its way into your house.
Well,
it's already in Google goggles came out
on the,
you know what I mean?
I mean you'll be able to search
someone's house,
so yeah,
take a photo and you'll be able to go,
oh,
this guy lives at 97 woodcrest road.
People only have
five years ago.
You put a picture on your facebook,
a Christmas photo that has like your
bookshelf in the background.
Now present day that that's going to
start researching every single book
that's on your shelf and it's gonna put
in a database somewhere and,
and GPS location.
You know what I mean?
So like when you're searching for
something,
you could be like,
oh,
Joe has that book at home.
I think what's happening?
I think what's happening with twitter
and what's happening with facebook and
what's happening with the just the
Internet in general is there's way more
connectivity between all human beings
and a part of that is access to
information so that information is not
going to be lucky.
It is now.
It's not going to be private,
I think.
No,
I think eventually technology will come
to the point where the line will be
absolutely impossible and you will know
everything that everybody else knows and
everyone's going to try to hold back on
it for awhile because people have a lot
of dirty secrets.
They do a lot of creepy shit,
but I think ultimately it's probably
going to be good for everybody.
I do think that that's where we're
headed.
I think we're headed to a point where
everybody has access to all the
information that everybody else has and
not just like go on the Internet and you
search for it.
Not like in the rudimentary way.
We have to actively look for.
I think it's going to be right there.
I think there's going to eventually
come.
There's gonna.
They're gonna.
Eventually get to a point where there's
some sort of technology that's created
that allows human minds interface with
other human minds.
I think that that's definitely where
this was all going.
I mean when there's talk of neural
implants and all these different things,
people think that's all crazy,
but that's.
That's a small step from where we are in
comparison to where we were just a
couple hundred years ago.
I mean a couple hundred years ago,
the fastest mode of transportation was
riding a fucking animal.
Think about that.
You have to write 300 years ago,
the fastest ship on land is to ride an
animal or have an animal pull you behind
something with wheels or slave slaves.
Can't run as fast as some of those guys
can.
No Way.
Not a horse.
This guy's an idiot.
I can't believe I'm doing this,
but I mean think about what a Banya
mental leap between the transference of
information today in 2009 and in 17.
Oh,
nine.
I mean,
think about what we can do right now.
We could send a fucking picture across,
you know,
space is,
send it through the air and then
literally arrives.
I mean if I have a friend in the UK and
I want to send him a picture and a text
message,
I can take the picture,
send it,
and it gets to him just like that.
I mean,
that's fucking incredible.
it literally will get there in seconds.
We don't even.
We can't even fathom how nuts that is
because we do it all the time.
What's coming next is going to make that
seem like riding a horse.
That's what's happening.
That's what I think is happening.
That's what I think is this whole this,
this rush for inflammation and everybody
has this insane desire that human beings
have for the newest,
greatest,
latest technology.
You know,
even when you don't need it,
like people are always trying to pump up
their computers.
The only reason why you need a pumped up
computer really is to play video games
or if you're,
you're crunching a video like,
like he needs stuff like that when he,
when he makes videos just for raw
computing power.
But the average person does is not
crunching video.
You hit a wall.
We've hit a wall and computers in
general,
like they really don't need even like
the fastest computers now.
The programs that video programs aren't
even.
Yeah.
That's why everybody's into those little
notebooks.
You know,
those notebooks are the shit except for
watching like hd videos.
Yeah.
That's kind of sucks.
And you can't,
you can't load a cd into it either.
A DVD,
right?
Yeah.
But that technologies like talking about
the floppy drive right before the floppy
drive left,
you know,
like cds and dvds are out the door.
Even Blu rays have like such a small
shelf life and you think it's ever going
to get to a point where bandwidth will
be so broad and like mobile functions
like laptops and phones,
like those little mobile cards,
it'll be so powerful that it will be
just like your home.
Oh,
it's totally.
It's going to be all of that pretty
soon.
So it'll basically be like,
everything will be broad man.
Do we even know what the fuck that is
doing to human beings?
You know,
like the talking about cell phones
causing radiation and you know,
like when they say it's bad when we say
it's okay.
Well I think,
do you think that it's possible that
that's like altering human beings given
kids autism?
Probably not,
right?
It might be that.
It might be that
it might also be fucking with bees.
There's been speculation that it's been
fucking with bees and there's also been
speculation that at some,
some crazy virus of read that as well.
But there's also been speculation that
Wifi signals and cell phone signals,
they have fucks with b's ability to
transmit.
We did a thing for fear factor in once
with bees on it and it was a fucking
trip because this guy was a beekeeper.
Any,
uh,
you know,
I had all these bs that he brought with
him.
So the stunt was these dudes,
they had to be strapped to this pole.
We strap them to the pole and then we
cover them with bs and they have to
stand there for like five minutes.
Tim Riggins fucked up because every now
and then,
you know,
the bees were argue or something.
They'd sting to dude and it was bad.
I got stung up.
Well while this was all going on and
while this guy's tendencies,
bees and caring for these bees,
a local swarm of bees came in so our
bees and their bees,
we're talking it out and we had a
backup.
Everybody had to get off the set.
We had to close down the set.
We had to close down the stock and
everybody had to move back and the
beekeeper say,
and we've got,
you know,
a local local band of bees is moved in.
I forget what he calls him a hive or I
don't know,
but that's like a no,
I don't know,
whatever.
A local band to bees moved into to sort
it out with these bees.
So our bees and their bees were just
this fucking swarm in the sky.
And they were fighting.
They were just talking like,
so what's up?
What are you guys do?
And I'll work with your doctor,
you know,
working with fear factor.
We've got some dudes are going to cover
them and bees and shit.
They're like working out what was going
on.
And then they resolved their differences
and the local bees went a separate way
and then the,
his be stayed.
Was it like a black cloud?
That's correct.
It was not.
It was a big fucking cloud of bees in
the air.
And the bees were communicating.
Where's your cell phone?
Why weren't you filming back is back in
the day.
He didn't have a [inaudible] no.
Nineteen or whatever role.
We had a press four times to get it as
bad as little Motorola ea 15.
It was one of those.
But um,
so,
uh,
we,
they wonder if that's fucking with bds,
if our cell phone signals and everything
are fucking with beings that autism
thing,
man,
it might be something totally like that.
It also,
you know,
a lot of speculation about autism is the
age of the parents and that the women
are having babies like into their
thirties and forties.
And that increases the risk.
A lot of people talked about that.
That's um,
it's very,
very possible.
Makes Sense,
man.
You know,
when we're just older and smarter and we
look at it now and we say,
well God,
you know,
how stupid would it be to have a kid
when you're 18?
When you're 18,
you're an idiot,
which is absolutely true,
but when you're an 18 year old idiot,
your genetics are much stronger and you
could,
you could have a kid and the kid
probably wouldn't be as fucked up.
I mean,
the reality is even though we're
lengthening our lifetimes with nutrition
and you know,
science and we're figuring out a way to
make people live longer,
people aren't supposed to live much
longer than like 50.
You know,
back in the day if you lived to be 50,
holy Shit,
you pulled off an amazing,
you know,
but not,
not anymore.
Now people
are living to be 110 and you got
Sylvester.
Stallone is 62 years old.
He's flogging,
yoked,
shredded.
You know,
things are getting very strange now.
That's why guys are smart.
They're just knock up 18 year old girls
when they want to get,
you know,
girls would definitely give you the
better genetics.
The real question though is do you,
do you get anything other than,
you know,
like hair,
color,
eye color,
personality,
do you get learned experiences and is it
better off to have a parent with a lot
of experiences?
Are those experiences transfer through
DNA because they didn't use to think it
was.
They used to think that ideas were only
they were native to the person who had
the idea,
but now they're starting to think that
memes can actually be transferred
through genetics and that useless
traits.
Even like racism,
racism can be transferred through
genetics and it kind of makes sense
because there's a lot of things that we
have inside our genetics and our
instincts that are basically ancient
learned things like for like for
instances do named Rupert sheldrake.
Rupert sheldrake is this evolutionary
biologists dude,
and he pointed out that children that
live in New York City,
they don't have dreams about like
muggers or car accidents.
They have nightmares about monsters,
about scary monsters and the reason they
have nightmares about scary monsters is
because back in our heads,
somewhere deep in our DNA,
we remember back when we were like
monkeys when we were these little apes
hanging around and trees and you're
running away from big cats and that,
that shit is always in our head because
that is the number one thing that,
what was that fed off of,
uh,
off chimps and apes is his big cats.
Big Cats are constantly killing monkeys
and chimps and apes.
And that's like when they find like old
human beings,
like,
you know,
the,
evolutionary versions of human beings,
subhuman,
humanoids,
they find all their skeletons,
like a lot of them have like big fucking
cat bites,
big markings.
So that's like,
that's like some memory that we have
ingrained in our,
in our genetics,
you know,
whoever the fuck we are.
It's very possible that if you're 18
years old and you know,
you have,
you fuck a chicken,
she's 18 year both retarded.
You gotTa,
you gotTa have a dumb ass kid,
you know,
I mean that might be,
it might not just be,
you know,
your hair color and your eye color and
how tall you're going to be.
It might be your actual experiences and
your human potential.
Second.
Yeah,
maybe.
yeah.
Maybe if you're a loser,
like if you're a fucking drunk,
if you get hammered and you're fucked up
and your life is in the toilet and you
know,
you bang some chick because you know,
on the rebound and her old boyfriend
used to beat her and you shoot a load in
her.
Maybe a kid would be just like really
fucking dumb and prone to make terrible
mistakes.
You know,
I mean maybe you can get past it,
but maybe his inclination like maybe
maybe we start off
in a certain place in life,
not just based on the economic situation
that our parents are in and you know,
who the people we grow up with and what
our agenda.
Maybe it's maybe it's our,
our,
our position starts out based on what
the parents were thinking and doing when
they fucked and conceived you like maybe
if that's the lowest point in their
life,
you not even because of the way they
raised you,
they can take you away and raise you in
an orphanage somewhere totally
different,
but your potential is limited by the
circumstances in which you were
conceived.
You think that's possible?
Maybe.
I don't think we have any idea.
So I think anything's possible,
you know,
but it's very obvious that there's a
bunch of different types of humans.
There's like super powerful,
super successful,
super smart humans and there's really
fucking dumb people because the
percentage of your brain being used,
you know,
I think people use more brain than other
people and I think it's such a small
percentage,
but even that,
you know,
maybe that's the real way to become a
superhero.
Find out how to use a 100 percent of
your brain.
But it's bullshit.
I have heard that.
That's bullshit that we don't use it.
Yeah.
I mean when they look it up and it shows
the.
Yeah.
But that,
that's not what that part is for.
You know,
I think that that whole,
you know,
human beings only used 10 percent of
their brain.
I think that's a myth.
Well,
they don't know exactly what every part
of the brain is for.
It's like they're still like,
it's like,
you know,
it's like charting out the bottom of the
sea.
There's a lot of shit they still haven't
figured out yet.
Let's see if any,
you motherfuckers are smarter than us
and have answers to all these things
that we're talking about.
It is weird when you see like a human
brain on TV and you're just like,
that's somebody that's a person to
person.
It's crazy.
It doesn't make any sense.
It's nuts.
Just twitter is blowing the fuck up.
Ladies and gentle.
No,
he's about twitter around.
I spoke twitter on twitter,
backslash Joe Rogan.
Oh,
it did
retired
shit.
Fix that.
No.
Who Cares?
You know,
I'm talking about question.
She watched a scanner darkly.
Yeah.
You know what,
man?
A scanner darkly is something that I
bought a long ass time ago.
I got it on DVD and I just have never
gotten around to watching it.
I tried to watch it.
I stopped anti Chris.
Why?
Why did you stop?
I remember it just wasn't that
interesting to hear that shit.
Chris motherfuckers said it wasn't
interesting.
You're recommending it and his.
He saying it's whack.
Canneries.
Canneries is tough.
Action.
Is there ever been a guy that more
universally panned as an actor but more
incredibly successful?
There's no.
I mean he like it.
He,
he blows them off the fucking charts
slipped by every time.
Oh,
here's something that I needed to take
a.
They actually found.
I had a article this month
that there was a roadhouse video game in
the being made a few years ago,
but the company went bankrupt.
Roadhouse video game,
the Patrick swayze.
That's the greatest bad movie ever.
It's right up there with showgirls.
If you haven't seen roadhouse,
I don't know what the fuck is wrong with
you.
If you haven't seen showgirls,
drop this chat and and either download
it or go to the video store and do
something.
You got to watch showgirls.
Showgirls was awesome.
Just a quintessential movie where the
people who are doing the movie where
were just gapped out of their fucking
minds on cocaine and they made a
terrible movie.
That makes no sense and it's so bad that
it's good.
It's perfect.
It's just one of those movies that's
just perfectly crosses over into parody
to the point where you could watch it
over and over and over again.
Right.
I've only seen it twice.
Showgirls was awesome,
but showgirls and roadhouse or both,
basically the same movie,
both movies where it's like they got
people that were just full of themselves
enough and just underestimating the
intelligence of viewers enough and just
hack enough and just,
you know,
they just follow the dumbest formula
lines possible and the difference
between roadhouse and showgirls.
Doe is a roadhouse seems to be raw
stupidity on its own.
Whereas showgirls is the most obvious
cocaine movie of all time because it's
just so dumb.
Like you had to be on coke.
They think that that was a good movie.
Like if you.
If you made that move and you weren't on
coke,
you would watch the dailies.
You'd be like,
what?
The fuck we going,
what are we doing?
What is this moving?
But if you're on call you're like,
yeah,
it's fucking awesome.
Coming into the line.
And what was your,
what's your bit.
I'll tell you escalator,
which one has something to do with like,
would you even be able to see it yet?
Because you know,
the human brain hasn't seen it yet.
Oh No,
it was my theory about,
about how we believe that everything
around us is everything through his.
Right.
And I talk about farts and what I say is
that if someone farted and you didn't
have a nose,
you'd have no idea if something was.
Oh No,
no.
I'm talking about something you used to
say while ago,
something like kind of you were kind of
saying like how cars are.
Would you even be able to see it?
Uh,
uh,
because our brain hasn't seen it yet.
Like the tiger
or something like that.
Would that added on the tiger bit was if
a tiger was running at you,
would you be able to even watch that?
Because I think you bring,
just start
producing cyclist pyramids or something.
They used to have a thing where you
talked about like a,
would they even be able to see it
because their brains never seen it
before.
And so,
um,
I think so man,
that's on my act.
That's um,
I think you're thinking of there's a
part in the movie the secret where those
retards claim that or was it,
what the bleep do we know?
I think it was like looking at,
like they said,
the Indians couldn't recognize the
Bolus,
but if I see it,
it was not my act now,
my,
my actors,
the,
the part about how if we didn't have a
nose and you smell a Fart,
and this is for the people that are
watching this,
this is the idea is that we don't have
any idea if there's more around us all
the time that we can't sense.
And it's very possible that there is.
And what I say is the fourth theory and
the theory is if someone farted and you
couldn't smell it,
you'd have no idea that there's
something around you.
It's totally completely invisible.
But if someone farts you fucking smell
it.
But if you didn't have a nose,
you'd be just sitting in someone's
stench.
How do we not know that there aren't an
infinite amount of things that we just
can't detect and that smell,
even though we can attack this,
it's for biological reasons.
You know,
you smell gas,
you know it's dangerous for you.
You smell fire,
get away.
There's a reason why we have a sense of
smell.
It's good for us,
but what if we didn't?
If we didn't,
it would be an invisible thing and it's
just our imagination that limits the
possibilities of how many other
invisible things there are around us all
the time that we can't detect.
There's all sorts of animals like worms.
You take your hand and he rolled over or
above a where they have no idea they're.
They have no idea.
It's very possible that if that exists
in nature,
that there's also some shit like that
with human beings.
It's very possible that we're constantly
like the idea of dimensions.
Dimensions might be dimensions of
perception.
We just might not have the ability to
perceive all these other things that are
around us all the time.
I mean,
that could be like bad energy,
like you go into a house,
I mean people,
many people have told stories or if you
go into a house where people have been
murdered and they could feel it,
I could feel fucked up energy in the
house.
Like that all might be real shit.
You know,
like we don't have a name for it and
we're not good at detecting it and you
know,
we,
we call it a sense or a feeling that
might be real energy that you're
detecting.
We're just not evolved enough to the
point where we can really tune into it
yet.
Why is it that we like our smuggler and
farts but not somebody else's fired.
My farts are delicious.
Do you think it's just like,
oh no.
Do you think we would enjoy it if we
made herself,
you know,
like if you forced yourself to smell my
heart and enjoy it,
like make yourself into it.
You'd have to be one of those sick dudes
that wax off to Fart porn.
You know,
because there's dudes that do that.
There's dudes,
there's dudes that like that that's
real.
But I've never heard of anybody who
likes their buddies fartsy.
That's weird though.
Crazy.
Meanwhile,
I enjoy my own farm.
I love my phone.
Everybody does.
If you're in your car and you feel a hot
one and a blast,
you when you do this.
He stopped smoking.
When I'm in the shower,
I cut my hand around my ass.
I call it the Donald Duck because it
makes it donald duck noise when you.
And when I fart and it doesn't smell,
I'm always disappointed by far nothing.
It's worse.
Yeah.
But like if somebody else farts like on
a plane and you're like,
oh you mother Fucker,
I can't believe you did that,
then we should love it.
You know?
And it smells the same.
It's not like your farts smell different
than mine.
What?
Well,
with our farts I think we get a little
reward.
Like,
Oh,
you're getting all this bad stuff out of
your body.
But with other people's farts it's like,
oh,
you stinky,
fuck.
You know,
it's not the same reward.
Is there any other smells that do that?
I don't like to smell my shit.
I don't like that.
I tell you that I don't like that when I
take a nasty dump on,
Oh,
get me out of that room.
I don't want to go back in.
Like I would blow my nose or something
like that and go to get some totally
different.
Oh,
what the fuck?
That was my shit.
Yeah.
I don't like it,
but I do.
That's funny man.
You do like if you have ever had to shit
outside Iraq to take a ship in the
woods,
that's the worst because there's no
water.
I think it's just just steamy,
stinky fucking dump on dirt.
Yeah.
The smells horrible.
Nobody ever liked.
It's like sitting there sniffing their,
their pile of Shit and getting all happy
about it.
It makes no sense.
It doesn't make any sense.
It's like what is,
what is the evolutionary reason for that
was the reason.
It's probably like the cure of aids
somewhere in that something that
researchers are going to research on
farts.
Lily,
you think,
okay,
what do you think about all these dudes?
And there's a bunch of scientists online
like um,
uh,
what,
what does that,
there's just one guy that's at the head
of the cause,
uh,
Peter Duesberg and they're all saying
that HIV does not cause aids and that
HIV is a very weak virus and that the
only reason why HIV exists in the
systems of these people that are,
have aids is because their immune system
is so compromised that it can even kill
off HIV.
Well,
I think it's really weird that most of
the people,
it seems like that have aids are drug
users and gaze.
So they're going to have a.
d has something to do with the immune
system,
but then you get fucking,
what's his name?
The basketball player that had fake
aides.
That's the other thing is that people
test negative after a while,
like in the,
they're the Richard he goes into and
then it goes into,
in,
into a dormant stage,
mean magic Johnson has aids and now he's
doing like mattress commercial,
you know,
like crazy.
Why didn't you have a mattress?
Commercials.
He didn't get a lot of money on AIDS
medicine.
Yeah,
I think,
I don't know man,
I guess.
I mean they probably pay him millions of
dollars.
Do any commercial.
He's still got a good name.
How much mattresses though are you going
to sell it as?
Payback?
What have you,
how many?
Like how many more of these basketball
players,
all these dudes who you know are out
there just fucking banging chicks left
and right.
They must be freaking out about this
tiger woods shit.
Who's target?
What?
Shit.
We'll throw a monkey wrench into your
endorsement deals and if you're like a
Michael Jordan type of dude,
like that's where those guys make them
the most,
the bulk of their cash as in
endorsements,
you know,
that's why this is so dangerous to tiger
woods.
It's not the tiger woods can't go out
there and still kick your ass and golf
and say fuck you.
I can do whatever I want.
He can,
but he can't because the endorsements is
where he gets all his cash.
We'll look at letterman.
Same thing.
It's like blown up this year.
Two thousand and nine cents.
No,
it doesn't suck.
It's what I was talking about before.
I think what we're sensing,
what we're seeing in celebrities is
mirrored,
is going to be mirrored as human beings.
We're seeing more access to information.
We're seeing less secrets.
I think it's a trend.
I think it's.
It's a.
it's a trend because I think that's
eventually what the human race is going
to come to.
It's going to come to a point in time
where there was not going to be any
secrets and that's a good thing.
There's going to be full information
disclosed from you to me and everything,
and what it is is the convergence of all
human beings.
That's what's gonna.
That's what's going to start to ignite
the convergence amongst all human
beings.
There's going to be full access to
information.
I know everything in your head.
You know everything in my head.
It's pretty weird,
man.
It's pretty fucking crazy and that's
where it's going.
It's going through technology and this
is what the Internet about is what
twitter is about.
This with this huge stream,
trout is about,
this is what all the shit is about.
It's about a convergence of human beings
like human beings are eventually merging
into one thing.
I mean,
that's the,
the whole ancient line and eastern
mysticism and each eastern religion is,
you know,
that we are all one.
We are,
you know,
we are one consciousness,
like the bill Hicks Joke,
uh,
experiencing itself subjectively.
You know,
that's the,
the,
the Timothy leary ideology,
the ideology of all the,
all the psychedelic heads,
all the people that you know,
they really got into like heavy duty
psychedelic trucks is that it's this one
thing and that we can't recognize that
we're one thing because we have ego and
we have survival and we have all these
things,
but that our technology and the
technology forcing us to evolve that the
access to information that technology
provides eventually will cause human
beings all human beings to converge and
literally be like one consciousness.
If I know all your thoughts,
I know all your information and we have
an access to it,
an interface that's much less crew than
what we have now with typing and with
researching or watching documentaries,
what if it's like an instant access,
a human neuro transplant,
something that allows all of us to link
up our minds together.
That's not that outside of the realm of
possibility.
That to me seems just as likely as the
ability to send a picture through the
Internet on your phone.
That's just.
That's just as fucking crazy that you
can send video through the air and you
could watch a youtube video on your
iphone.
You're like,
what the fuck?
I mean,
it's just coming through the air and you
put the headphones on and it's in stereo
like wax that's going through the
fucking.
Scott is just as likely that human
beings are eventually going to come to
some sort of a,
some sort of a technological invention,
something that we're going to come to
something that allows all human beings
to interface together.
It might be through this thing.
It might be something you put on and
everybody else that has it all links in
together or it might've actually become
something that you put in your body or
it might be something they broadcast
through the fucking air that links
people together.
I can't,
I just can't wait till it gets cheaper
to be able to like upgrade your body
parts.
Like I want to have better items because
I want night vision.
I want to have fucking twitter.
I want.
I knew about that woman that they made
her a new bladder.
Yeah.
They might have a bladder out of her.
They took her on bladder.
They scrape the cells together since the
group.
Yeah,
they grew up.
So
I don't know if the stem cells,
stem cells,
but they,
I know they grew a new bladder for her
and a fucking petri dish and then
install it in their body.
That's crazy.
You know,
a bladder just to kind of a bag for pis.
But that's,
that's going to happen with other shit
too.
Man.
I transplants are crazy too though.
That's amazing.
You like imagine a Jessica.
Uh,
my friends,
uh,
uncle died and they donated their eyes
and how help somebody see that canal
street and they got a letter just to let
you know your,
your uncle's eyes were donated to
so-and-so person who can now see and
they get,
send them a whole letter.
So you can imagine somebody you know
who's dead now,
but their eyeballs are still being used.
That's incredible.
That's like a nightmare.
And that's like a horror movie,
right?
Like,
well,
I heard about.
So her,
I was thinking I was listening to the
art bell show about some lady who
donated her.
Uh,
she,
she got a liver from someone and the
operation and right immediately after
the operation she started having
cravings for what?
Of those duties are you serious?
That's fucked up craving.
She never had before.
And then she found out,
dude,
like really like to eat this certain
type of thing.
First trench.
I wonder if you got a but transplant if
you'd like that person's farts.
If you'd like your own farts still,
if you got somebody else's book,
people might ask the weirdest questions.
Dawkins 20.
Look,
this bill Hicks,
the comedian,
how are they the same guy?
What the fuck kind of question is,
uh,
what,
what does that mean?
That doesn't mean anything.
That's another.
How are they the same guy?
There's one guy,
he's.
How are they?
The same guy.
What Alex Jones is built here because
this is people believe Alex Jones
believes I met Bill Hicks.
I'm friends with Alex Jones.
They're not same guy.
Retarded that these people cannot be
serious.
Just has to be a joke.
It's an Internet meme,
right?
If they're being.
If you guys are being serious about
that,
you guys are fucking retarded.
Yeah.
That's pretty.
So.
Alright,
let's go some questions here.
Magic Johnson's bought the cure for
aids.
Yeah.
Magic Johnson.
Great South Park.
Episode two was more about that.
The cure for years.
No better south park episode than the
one where the,
uh,
the gay dude had a horror off with Paris
shelter up.
I remember watching that going.
How do they get away with this?
You don't pass on circumstances,
but you can pass on the psychic ability
to create them.
Alright.
Christine and they.
Liz,
how do you know that?
Do you really know that?
Are you just saying maybe,
maybe that's what's happening,
but you don't know the psychic ability
to create them.
Have you ever met anybody that says that
they're a channeler or says that they're
savvy?
That isn't a fucking retard.
Have you ever met anyone?
I don't believe any of that.
Every time they do it like fucking scam
artists to me.
I've never met one person that says
they're a psychic or says they can
channel that isn't retarded.
They're all retarded,
but then it's almost like,
do you have to be retarded to be able to
do that?
Like maybe you have to be like,
like some somewhat of a person that can
look like you're.
You're so socially inept.
You're so clueless as to how other
people perceive you,
that you can achieve certain frequencies
that other people can't.
Is that possible?
Anything?
Can I get Alex Jones on opiod?
Anthony?
I don't think so,
man.
I don't think that's a good idea.
I saw a little jimmy little.
Jimmy did the Jesse Ventura.
I don't think we'd like that.
Alex Jones is not the kind of guy you're
supposed to like argue with like that.
You're supposed to enjoy his company and
ask them questions.
And then we started talking about new
world order,
black helicopters,
legend gentleman.
I see them outside of my window every
night you tell me I'm crazy,
but I see black helicopters outside my
window.
So what is going on?
You don't argue with that dude.
You go damn man,
motherfucking black helicopters that's
supposed to do.
And that's supposed to like.
And I think if,
if I was in the room with Jesse Ventura,
I'm certain I would have handled it
different than Jimmy did,
but Jimmy's one of those dudes were Jim
Norton,
fantastic comedian,
funniest guy in radio without a doubt by
far.
He,
he's one of those dudes that when he,
um,
you know,
when he's in the face of someone who's
like a bully,
he doesn't like that shit.
He doesn't stand up to that shit.
Well,
and he feels like that Jesse has this
slow burn in his eyes and the Imo navy
seal and all that shit and that you're
supposed to listen to them because of
that.
And Jim Norton just ain't buying that
and that's why Jimmy just shut them down
and clowned him.
That's just what he does.
He's just,
he's not good at people being bullies.
A respect that
people that meditate have large frontal
lobe cortex is studies.
Show says Pete Shreds.
I wonder.
That's very possible,
right?
It's very possible that it changes the
way your brain works.
I mean,
if you lift weights,
you know it changes the way your
muscles.
Look.
If you,
if you exercise your mind in certain
ways,
if this doesn't make that happen,
Brian is going to smoke marijuana live
right here on ustream.
Thank God it's all legal.
Supposedly.
That's the only thing Obama's done.
He said he would do stuff on after we'd
rediculus alright,
what else?
What else?
Party people.
Let's go to the Rogan board and read
some of the questions that you find
people have.
What is my opinion on freewill?
Your blog talks about how we're all
living through different circumstances,
which is very true,
but it seems.
Do you know what the power of free will,
which kind of sucks.
No.
Know I go,
I start about freewill.
I
think about free will and a couple of
different ways.
I think it's very possible that you know
you are shaping your own destiny and
that you know,
you can,
you know,
choose your path and you can,
go through this life and you know,
and make something of yourself and you
know,
the fact that you did it by yourself and
you have through freewill.
It's all good.
I think that's very possible,
but I think it's all pos.
It's also possible that life itself is a
gigantic mathematical algorithm that all
life itself is like a gigantic
mathematical equation and that it just
doesn't seem like an equation because
we're a part of it,
but like that,
everything,
your personality,
your biology,
your circumstances,
your experiences,
they're all set up in line to put you in
a very specific position to move forward
in a very specific way to interface with
all the other.
Very specific things that are around
you,
all the other very specific people,
very specific events and that the idea
is that what the idea of free will is
sort of a misnomer.
Like you have instincts and you have
experiences that guide you into a
certain way,
like say if you,
uh,
you know,
he drank poison,
you almost died and it was terrible and
he didn't know it was poison.
Well,
you'll be much more careful next time
and you won't drink poison.
The idea that that circumstance that
you've experienced as lead you taught in
a very specific way and that you are
experiences literally are set up as a
part of a mathematical equation and that
it's all to lead this entire human race,
which is really just one organism,
one gigantic super organism to lead this
entire human race into a specific place
for a very specific purpose.
That's possible.
You know,
I don't like the thinking.
when your ego has any control whatsoever
over your mind.
Your ego wants you to think that no,
you know,
I am in control of my own,
my life.
I have done what I've done and I'm proud
of all that I've done because it's my
own accomplishments,
but really it might be you're following
a program.
It really might be.
We're all a part of this gigantic
program that's,
you know,
and that all this,
ego justification,
ego gratification,
sex and love and fun and happiness and
all these things are really just like
numbers and equations and like the
little,
the powerful number that you get from
love forces you to,
you know,
to be in love and have children and to
create more people and to be good to
those people and those people create
more good people and that,
these,
these rewards are all in fact set up as
a part of an equation to move the human
race into one specific place that
everyone is working together all over
the world and we just don't realize it.
We're beings.
Yeah,
we're bs.
I mean like when,
I mean we don't know how bees
communicate.
We don't know what,
what sort of a culture bees have,
but we know that they don't have books.
They can't their past.
They can't study their history.
I mean how conscious,
how aware are they in?
Are they just going through the motions
because that's how they're programmed
and if,
if that's the case,
if that's the case with wolves and bears
and every other animal that sort of goes
through these natural motions to achieve
a specific result,
maybe that's what we're doing.
Maybe we're just doing it and it's way
more complicated because what we're
doing is we're actually changing our
environment.
We're changing the world.
We're creating computers and creating
technology and we're involved.
We're the only animal on the planet
that's involved in this symbiotic
relationship with another life form and
that other life form is technology.
I mean if you don't classify life as
something that has a heartbeat and
something that bleeds,
but if you classify life as something
that evolves and changes and grows and
something that is like inexorably linked
to human beings,
technology is just like a virus.
Technology is just like something,
some sort of a bacteria that's in your
system that you can't get out of.
Well,
you know,
like you have to have a lot of healthy
bacteria in your body all the time and
that that's like you have a symbiotic
relationship with this healthy bacteria
and it keeps you alive.
It actually fights off other bacteria.
I mean,
that's what probiotics are.
That's what acidophilus says.
You're taking in a live culture that
will be your,
your warriors,
and they will fight off bad bacteria.
Well,
it's very possible that that's what
technology is.
The technology is a life force that we
are interfaced with and we are.
We have a symbiotic relationship with
this other thing.
And we needed to keep us alive.
We needed to keep the power on,
you know,
to keep,
to keep us warm in cold climates to,
you know,
to make sure your car gets you to work,
to make sure that the airbag goes off to
save your life and all this shit is
designed to help us.
But in turn we keep it going.
We look at old cars on the side of the
road that have broken down and dead and
those things are just like dead bodies,
you know,
cars that are old that stay alive,
that's just like,
wow,
that's fucking cool.
That's just like seeing an old man at
the gym with big muscles like,
Holy Shit,
you know,
I mean literally like technology and
things that we create,
we are helping those things evolve.
We are helping those things evolve with
our materialism,
with our obsession with technology.
We are trying to always constantly get
the newer,
better cooler shit and in doing that and
then supply that,
we are forcing people to work in that
industry and continue to evolve
technology mean it's very possible that
it's all one fucking big thing.
So that's my opinion on that.
What I get for Christmas.
Your mother's pussy.
Oh,
what's my opinion of.
this is too tripper.
Some people just get way too.
DMT On me.
Stream is the extreme.
Hippies are weird to me.
This dude's question.
This is NPO.
Sharman.
What is your opinion of the non ordinary
reality access DMT and
other NCO substances?
In Theo gins are,
um,
I think the literal translation is
something that connects you to God but a
psychedelic drugs.
Do you feel there is much to learn from
this version of reality?
How can it be applied to ordinary
reality?
That's the real problem with any
psychedelic drugs,
whether you're doing Salvia or doing dmt
or smoking weed.
It's like,
what are you bringing any of that back?
Is it enhancing your life?
Do you think?
Anything enhances your law?
I don't know that question.
To me it seems like he,
he,
he wrote it in the garage with his car
running.
What do you think?
What's my take on Charlie Sheen?
Charlie Sheen is a dude who's friends
with Alex.
Joe like me,
but he's not laughing.
He,
um,
he is a nine slash 11 conspiracy buff.
He's an actor.
He knows every data that you know,
he might have just met.
He's an actor after the tough action
man.
I mean,
I know a couple of actors that are
pretty cool,
but not that many.
Most of them are really annoying.
Somebody said it busted the actors,
like Comedians,
but when.
No punchline,
they always want to talk,
ain't got shit.
They're not giving you anything back.
At least like with Joey Diaz is talking
like you're going to be laughing and
you're going to enjoy it.
You want them to talk,
but after it's just talk,
you know,
actors always have the answers to like
if you're talking to actors,
very rarely does an actor want to admit
that they don't know why something is
this or something.
Is that why,
you know,
they always have opinions,
like really poorly thought out opinions,
whether it's on politics or a war or
anything.
Have you recently,
uh,
an followed somebody on twitter because
they just tweeted too much?
I just unfollowed them.
No,
I hardly ever unfollow someone you all
the time I bought a block.
People if they just have arguments with
me and just sort of boring,
but I followed the dumbest
motherfuckers.
I followed so many dumb people.
I didn't want to tell you what they're
doing.
I don't want to tell you who they are
because some of them,
some of them were just fantastic.
Fantastic.
With their terrible tweet.
I just unfollowed Kevin Smith the other
day because she spent,
he literally spent two hours replying to
every single person that has rode them
and like the last two months,
and you did it because it blogs up your.
It was all him and had no one else.
I'm like,
Oh,
next page.
Are you serious?
She liked him though.
I do like them,
but that's bullshit.
Dude.
Needs to learn how to fucking use
twitter.
Well,
how you're supposed to do if you don't
reply direct messages,
but to all those people,
if you're gonna,
if you're gonna replace all our time.
We don't care what this answer this
question is that if you do,
yeah,
the messages,
the problem with the direct messages
that you kept,
everybody
else can see it in.
One of the cool things about Kevin Smith
is like before following Kevin and you
get to see everybody saw Kevin Smith
responded to you this video type shit.
Then and reply go,
okay,
here's our next person from twitter to
do because it just ruins everything
else.
I hate it.
I met Kevin Smith and he's cool as fuck.
Fuck that.
I'll never unfollow him.
He could put pages of Shit on my twitter
and I will.
I will keep it going to.
I love.
I love the database.
That's just uncalled for.
What do I think of Ben Stein Calling
Ron?
Paul?
Antisemitic.
I don't think about it at all.
It's hilarious.
There's two old queens.
I would love to see Ben Stein.
Ron Paul suck at each of those costs.
I would pay a thousand dollars for that.
But you seemed brutal yet.
No,
I have that on video too.
It's something that watched it and it's.
It's,
it's that whole part with Ron Pawn and
ever since I've seen it,
I always look at him and he looks like
an old queen to me now.
Ever since then.
Yeah.
Just how he handled that.
He hit it like,
I don't know.
Well,
he super religious so it's possible
possibly getting right.
If you're really intelligent and yet
super religious.
I always gotta go,
all right.
What's going on?
What are you doing belong guys?
We don't.
It's weird.
Yeah,
there's something wrong.
Either money or gay.
If you're really intelligent and you're,
you're really buying into,
and this is not saying you know that
there's no god.
It's not saying that there's no this not
something else.
I'm the first one to say that I don't
know.
I have no idea,
but I'm also the first one to say that
you don't know either and anybody that
pays any attention to religion or
follows religion at all and it looks at
the history of religion,
knows that it's a.
it's a disjointed mess and nobody even
knows the origins of all this stuff and
nobody knows how much people altered the
words and what we do know about it is
that the.
Even the Bible itself,
the oldest version of the Bible,
they don't even used the Dead Sea
Scrolls.
That's the oldest version of the Bible
by far.
They don't even.
They don't even use that when you think
that's like the best one,
wouldn't it as like the purest version
of it?
Now we're still busy using the new
testament.
The New Testament was created by
Constantine and a bunch of bishops.
They piled it together and the Old
Testament.
Well,
the Old Testament,
the real,
real version of it was written in
ancient Hebrew and to this day in 2009,
they only know three out of four words
in ancient Hebrew,
that's 20,
25 percent of the words,
they don't know what the fuck it means.
And on top of that letters also double
those numbers back then because there,
there was no numbers.
So the letter a was also like the number
one,
like if you did it that way.
So there was a numerical value to words
that was completely lost when they
translated,
uh,
ancient Hebrew to Latin and then to
Greek.
So like,
like the word love and the word God,
they have the same numerical value.
So we don't even really knowing what the
fuck they were saying.
So No,
I'm not saying that there is no god,
that there's not something else.
But what I'm saying is the follow
current religion as it's practiced and
preached today,
it's ridiculous.
It's ridiculous.
So if Ron Paul's really into that,
come on,
big old queen.
What is doing?
Let's Ron Paul,
big old queen.
Like if he just came out and said he's a
big old queen,
I would still vote for him,
man.
I think he's a bad motherfucker.
I would like to see if somebody's really
tried to get in there and shake up the
system and change the way you know,
the,
the world is run and you know,
keep us out of other countries and to
demolish the irs and get rid of the CIA.
And that'd be fascinating.
Fascinating to see if someone can
actually do that and not get killed.
I don't think that
good if it Kendall.
Yeah.
I got Kendall,
what?
Just wondering.
I just got one of those Sony readers for
Christmas,
um,
when it's cool because Google bought all
these books and so I don't know if you
can do this with a candle or not,
but with this one way you can just go to
google and download all these free books
on it.
And they have your itch issue of Kung Fu
magazine or whatever.
Karate magazine.
Black though.
Oh,
that I was in.
Yeah.
They have that.
And so that's the Sony reader.
You can go and get that.
So you can get any book basically for
free.
Well not any book,
but any other ones.
I'm Google has like a ton of books,
but they're all like old school at a
print books.
I think it has to be out,
man.
I got the kindle and I couldn't get any
hunter s thompson books.
One book that he wrote that was for
sale,
but they didn't have a great shark.
It didn't have to google.com
backslash books and see if they have it
there and he was downloaded.
I don't know if it works on kindle
though.
Probably a kindle reader.
PDF files.
It does,
but when it reads pdf files doesn't let
you enlarge the text,
which was annoying.
Oh,
you can do that on the sign.
Fucking shit.
I got the wrong one.
No,
I don't still better probably.
And our question earlier when we were
talking,
what about kitting poker?
Can these bots on poker sites?
Poker?
Jay who was a John Carlos Alvarado was
on the rubbing board,
says poker sites catch bots with the
program that can see if you click the
same pixel every time you make a move.
Something that's impossible to do by a
human.
Oh,
I guess why you have the program go over
a couple of pixels.
Yeah,
I agree.
Time change the program,
right?
Figured it out already to thing sucks.
How has the shit.
I just thought it was excellent.
Did I really forget everything I learned
during the taekwondo days?
I still remember some type of window
stuff.
Some stuff talking window is effective.
Like you see commonly leaves and a lot
of taekwondo.
He used a lot of turn side kicks in
front lake side kicks and frontline
roundhouse kicks where it doesn't switch
the legs.
That's.
There's a lot of power and that stuff.
It's just,
it's not complete in taekwondo needs
other things.
It needs more time wrestling.
When did you get to and all that stuff,
but it helps.
There's some stuff in it that's
different.
You know,
the,
the style of a like karate that Machida
uses the leaping in and leaping out.
Nobody knew that that would work before.
No,
because no one was ever good at it.
That was good at other stuff as well and
I think that's sort of the same thing
with kindly and window
Du du Du du Du du Du.
These questions all suck.
Twitter suck cock on my website guys.
A bunch of gay ass motherfuckers.
Stupid ass questions.
Um
Oh.
Same questions with the same people.
Circumcised.
Here's a good question.
What'd you get your kids circumcised in
this day and age?
Because most guys in America or cut?
No.
I am not going to.
If I have a boy and his new baby,
we don't know what it is yet.
We'll find out soon and if it's a boy,
I'm going to let them have a big
elephant.
You're discussed and care what?
My baby's Dick looks like.
What the fuck?
He wants a lot of video of it.
No,
no.
I mean I was thinking of that just the
other day.
So funny that this person asked us to.
Dick comes out a certain way of senior
time before knows.
And that covers it like a turtle neck.
Do you.
Have you ever seen porn?
Just felt bad for the poor guy.
A fucking creep Dick?
Yeah.
Bad circumstance.
Have you talked to girls about this?
I don't give a character like,
oh my God.
He had an unsophisticated stick.
It was so disgusting.
That chance to talk to girls that have
sucked uncircumcised dicks and they
don't care.
It's a little different.
Yeah.
Any girl that would care doesn't count.
It's good.
It keep constantly from my boy.
I'm picky.
It doesn't like a uncircumcised Dick.
And what's your why?
Why do you just think it's just
ridiculous.
It's totally unnecessary and it feels
better.
Supposedly we need.
I don't need help coming faster and
faster.
It actually feels better.
It's more sensitive.
It's not whether you come from you.
Actually it's more enjoyment.
Silly,
man.
I'm not getting.
My kids are ridiculous.
This is ridiculous.
I hate and find so weird.
I'm so glad.
I'm just like something.
I think every day I'm like,
thank you dad for.
Oh my God.
I know there's websites out there were
dudes.
Try to regrow their skin.
It's a long process to research them.
Size or Dick,
they stretch it out.
They have like little things.
I get attachment that you clip onto the
tip of your daycare.
It gets more.
They get more infections in,
in,
in like dirt inside there and it's like
if you have a deck,
that's my answer to that.
Clean your fucking Dick.
Look.
How hard is it to wash your Dick?
I hate dirty dip.
People should not have.
I have
no circumcised nerc circumcisions,
but if you're a cleanli personally,
you shouldn't be like my boy bullbait.
He will have an uncircumcised Dick got
down.
Have you ever.
We think we already talked about that.
What have you ever ate out a girl that
had really long,
prissy works?
Yeah,
I like that.
There's one way I could stretch probably
that far.
It was just,
it was like chewing gum
when you always in your mouth.
Do,
do,
do.
See,
this is to.
All these questions are like old.
It's like a hour ago on now.
Hayden.
Funny his twitter,
his twitter is the bomb diggity.
What is it?
The mark,
Hayden that I think he changed it to the
dumb mark gating.
I'm starting to think it's not real.
What do you mean?
Who chose the name of it?
I don't know.
No,
there's someone changed the name of it.
Whoever's doing it.
Then why would they do that?
Man,
we got a thing going on.
Motherfuckers been good on.
Do you think are lifetime microchips has
something to do with dogs where it scan
and send access?
Yeah,
I think that's going to happen.
Yeah.
I think.
I think it's very possible that there's
going to be some sort of a microchip
thing where human beings are going to be
scanned into a database.
The real problem is there's just so many
fucking people.
There's so many goddamn people.
How you do that?
How do you keep track of it?
Who's going to watch it like people used
to say,
Oh man,
what if your phones are bugged?
Who's who's bugging these phones in
workers,
government workers.
How many people they watch him are
there.
Is there one person for every person out
there they just circling on you because
they know you sell pot,
like,
come on man.
How many fucking people are out there
that that could actually be monitoring
people's phones?
Well now they have the technology where
they can just sit there and record every
single phone call and it transcribes it
like dragon speak,
but times 50 technology and it pretty
much looks for keywords like money drug,
you know?
Yeah,
that's.
That makes sense.
I've heard that before.
There's things like video programs,
like what's it called,
Predator or something like that.
They had one,
there was a.
We go through the Internet and search
for like al Qaeda for search for
terrorists,
search for certain specific key words,
peak oil versus science.
You know what man,
I think they're going to figure out some
other shit besides oil.
I think it makes sense.
I think you know,
there's a lot of stuff they could do
with agriculture.
There's a lot of stuff they can do with
hydrogen.
There's a lot of stuff.
It's just we could have come up with
something else.
It's just we got bamboozled into going
the way the oil because it was easy and
cheap and it was already in place and we
stayed with oil,
but I don't.
I don't think society is going to
crumble because we run out of oil.
I think we'll come up with something
just as good.
She heard those meal,
a mini coopers in the cold.
They electric ones in cold weather and
only gets half the power.
How big is that?
That's ridiculous because they're only
good for like 100 miles as it is.
So in cold weather it goes 50 slash 50
miles,
if that makes sense.
Because your batteries more dead in cold
weather piece.
Shit.
Yeah,
but the amount of buying that car,
that's an expensive car imagined.
You know what we top gear.
Did you know that show?
Top gear.
BBC.
Awesome show.
They took one of those Prius's and
electric car and they drove it around a
track with a presence.
A hybrid,
right.
They drove it around the track with an m
three and all the [inaudible] had to do
was keep up with the Prius.
That's all it had to do.
The preschool and went full blast or on
the track and the [inaudible] obviously
much,
much faster car.
All I gotta do is keep up.
The Prius got 13 miles to the gallon and
the [inaudible] got 19,
so when the Prius drives hard,
it's just as much of a piece of shit as
you know,
any other car.
It's like,
it's nonsense.
It's like it's fake being green and it
apparently it's much more toxic to the
environment to create a Prius as to how
it worked is Prius is uh,
only uh,
our electric under 25 miles an hour or
something like that for stop and go
traffic.
It's,
it's,
it's running off battery over that.
Just a normal car.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
And over that as a normal car,
it's terrible.
It's just a small,
shitty,
terrible God damn piece of shit.
Right.
That was bb Jones with the circumcision
question.
It's so weird he asked that because I
was just thinking that.
The good question,
man,
that's a good question.
That's a weird thing with people.
I didn't really worry about what your
kids did.
Did it start?
Well?
I just think everyday how,
how thankful I am.
You're so silly.
If I had your little Dick,
I would cry myself to sleep or somebody
close to this on the board
today about being Indian men and that,
uh,
there's like some,
what is it?
Sixty percent of Indian men?
Um,
I don't know if this is a true
statistic.
Somebody I've been rocked,
posted it.
So tell you what a grant assault.
Sixty percent of Indian men cannot use a
standard condom.
One in five condoms fall off during
intercourse.
So this is from the BBC.
Is it true?
I don't know.
We're going to go to it.
Damn the BBC.
Yeah.
If you go to India,
data fucks and women.
Wow.
It really is.
It's true.
Have more than a thousand men in India
has concluded that condoms are made
according to international sizes are too
large for the majority of Indian men.
That's crazy.
That's sad.
As a magnum user,
I feel for you bitch.
Wow.
Scientists even check their sample check
to see if their sample was
representative of India as a whole in
terms of class religion in urban and
rural dwellers.
So even like the peasants,
you know,
even the slaves in India have a little
dicks,
so sad.
Least the peasants of the like the lower
class America are generally thought to
have the biggest dicks.
Right?
Slaves.
Back in the day when they had slaves,
those guys almost had monster horse
decks.
Yeah.
How many white women do think flux
letters back then?
Ten tons of.
Do you think they did when their
husbands stop fucking right,
snuck in and just got some Alabama black
snake.
How many white women do you think had
babies with slips back then?
I think that had.
There was a lot of dead babies.
Really?
Yeah.
There was a lot of white guys who would
fuck the black slaves.
That was very common and have babies
with their black slaves up.
Fuck.
That must have been.
How weird must that have been to the.
The guy who was the father would fuck
the slave,
have a baby with a slave.
The slave would have his baby and he
would see this half white baby and he
would just leave the half white baby
with the slaves and let them take care
of it like you wouldn't even bring it
into.
Has this kid just because of a race
thing that must be.
That must have been fucking enough.
Talk about like haunting your
conscience.
How Weird is witch trials?
You know,
the old school widths trouser where they
would like way witches or it still goes
on today in Africa and Africa,
they still have a huge problem with
people accusing people of being switched
video where they caught him on fire and
they're just sitting there on five
beating with sticks and kick it.
This is real recent.
There was a,
um,
here,
I'll put it on twitter.
I wrote a blog article about it and it's
one of the worst videos that in Hong
Kong girl snorting yourself to death.
Yeah.
There's the video that you could see
this Hong Kong girl,
she snorts this gigantic line of
Ketamine.
Ketamine is a fucking cat tranquilizer
and a lot of crazy kids are doing this
and she snorted this gigantic line for a
video and then one of dying the videos
available online along with the store,
trying to find the.
Well,
I'll put that article online that I,
um,
that I wrote about.
I think it was called
humanity gone haywire.
I think that was the,
uh,
that was the name of the article,
but it was all about how,
how funny it is that there's this real
problem they have right now.
I don't know when that was from.
There's no search option.
My blog archives are k through that.
It's weird.
I have a search shopping.
This is terrible.
Let's for tell you dude,
look at that.
My fucking website is.
This is way better.
Yeah,
Google is way better for searching then
my own website,
[inaudible] website.
My website is being redesigned right
now.
People.
You've been saying it for eight years.
It has been designed for eight years,
so I'm sure.
Dammit,
let me find out the twitter.
This bitch
guys.
Ah,
ah,
ah.
Here's the battery.
All right.
I put it,
I've just pushed,
put it up on twitter if you bored and
you want to read this thing about
witchcraft,
watch the video.
It's really creepy.
You know,
a funny thing about witchcraft in
America,
like everybody knows about the Salem
witch trials.
Well,
what I read,
um,
the biggest connection they have to what
happened during them,
why everybody thought they were being
possessed and there's witchcraft going
on was that there was a late frost and
that the wheat got frozen and when it
sought out,
apparently when that happens,
when there's a late frost and freezes
and thaws out,
it grows a certain fungus on it.
And this certain fungus is called Ercot
in Ercot has,
it's like really similar or identical
rather chemically to lsd.
So when they would take this bread that
they would make from this wheat that had
grown this fungus on it,
these people would fucking trip their
balls off.
They would have these crazy,
horrifying bad acid trip.
So they literally fund.
They were under a spell,
which totally makes sense and they just
started burning bitches.
And women always want to say that it's
you.
Oh,
you know,
men were,
back then,
you know,
men were,
uh,
the,
the spell that a woman would cast upon
her upon him with her beauty was just to
perplexing and the men couldn't deal
with the fact that women had all those
powers that killed him.
Eh,
come on,
guys have been raping chicks forever.
He tell him,
got to stop back.
Then there's,
this is not that much.
This not that perplexing.
It's guys want to shoot a,
they shoot a load,
you know,
a guy's wants you to load the jerk off.
They don't want to shoot a load anymore,
you know,
they're not going to start burying
people because they want to fuck them.
I don't believe that.
I think it's a much more likely scenario
that this fungus grew on this wheat
because they had already taken soil
samples.
And so they had known from there,
you know,
whatever climatological studies that
they use to figure out how cold it was
during a specific time.
There was a late frost,
there was some evidence that there was a
late frost and then this,
um,
or God was also found somehow or another
during this time period.
So I think it's just speculation,
but it's much more educated speculation
and the idea that the men were under the
spell of these women and they decided to
kill him.
That doesn't make any sense.
I think they probably did the acid from
the wheat and then killed the cons.
That's probably what it was,
you know,
that's why I was a witch trial.
Those were probably the context in the
town.
If I would just,
let's cut these major bitches.
Yeah.
Like these chicks are bad energy.
Like you'd be around.
I'm like,
fucking pitches given me bad vibes,
you know,
because you're all acid now and they
probably just started lighting them on
fire.
I'm like,
fuck it,
let's kill this bitch.
Why are we having are around.
Imagine if that's really.
The witch trials were out.
Maybe like afterwards,
people were so nice.
They killed all the cuts off.
Imagine that.
Is that possible ladies and gentlemen?
Does that make sense?
Little Fuck is calling me during my God
damn podcast,
Tait Fletcher.
No,
my fucking ustream.
Bitch.
How dare you.
All right,
let's go back to the question.
So a gentleman.
Have I ever seen the northern lights in
Iceland?
No,
I've never seen him in purpose.
So.
Awesome.
I've seen some shit online though.
It looks incredible.
It's like the sky becomes like a desktop
screensaver.
I've been seeing way more falling stars
lately.
Like it's almost getting to the point
where it's kind of ridiculous.
Yeah,
it's maybe a deer coming once a week.
Maybe.
I see it at least one.
Could you imagine if we know for me it
does.
It doesn't seem like it's real,
like you said and talk about like
asteroid impacts over the asteroid that
killed the dinosaurs 65 million years
ago or the one that killed you know
everything before that.
The mass extinction before that 250
million years ago,
or the one that ended the Ice Age 10,500
years ago when there's all this
speculation about asteroids,
but the real reality is there are
gigantic,
hundreds of thousands of gigantic rocks
in space that can fuck us up and every
now and then one comes crashing down.
It's happened many,
many,
many times over the history of the life
of the earth.
It's happened so many times and it could
easily happen today.
It could easily happen tomorrow.
You can easily one that comes from
behind the sun and we can't see it until
it's too late and there,
you know,
and just fucks the whole world up.
That's so possible.
We don't like to think it's possible
because it's never happened,
but I always like to see.
I always say it's like an ant hill,
that human life is like an ant hill.
Like if you,
um,
are an aunt and you're living in an ant
hill,
you were probably born in that ant hill
and that hill is all you've ever known.
How long to answer live?
Like a week,
couple of weeks,
something like that,
so say like the sand hill has been
around for six months.
That's been through the generations
after generations,
long dead have made this ant hill and
then you know your toilet away and your
little ant hill and one day some kid is
walking through the field and he sees
that anthill.
It just boom,
boom.
She starts to stomp on it for no fucking
reason,
and then you're ant hills crushed out of
nowhere.
You never thought it was going to
happen.
It's always been fine.
Everything's always been cool.
At the end hill,
if you had a take a gas and you had to
make a gamble,
you would say,
yeah,
this and that was always going to be
here.
It's always been here.
Always will be here.
Bam.
Some kid just stomped the fuck out of
it.
That can happen to people that can
happen to Earth.
Katrina,
how about Detroit?
Really?
Somebody who has a magnifying glass on
it.
Detroit,
I watched Anthony Bordain had a show
about Michigan the other night and he
was there.
They were driving through horrible,
horrible,
terrible.
You ever wants that Anthony Bourdain
show?
Good show.
It makes you hungry.
He goes to the food show.
No reservations.
Fucking shows.
It makes me so hungry.
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo says there's an
asteroid with the possibility of hitting
earth in 20,
29.
Yeah,
there's.
There's a bunch of them out there that
they don't know about.
They come to the problem as the skies
too.
God Damn big.
I mean it's covering everywhere.
Shit's coming from the North Pole and
the South Pole and you never know where
something's coming from.
I mean it could be coming from anywhere
in.
You never know.
There could be something heading our way
that we haven't picked up on could be
behind something.
We don't see it.
Gravity distorts our view of things as
well.
Like if you look at the sun,
you can literally look at it.
Some of the telescope you could see
things behind the sun because of the
distortion and the gravity of the sun
because it's so massive.
I don't understand how that works,
but that apparently is how,
how it works,
and so there's occasionally things that
could be hiding behind something that's
coming straight at us.
We don't even fucking see it until it's
too late,
you know,
there's just not enough human beings out
there monitoring the sky to really
accurately predict,
you know,
oh,
we're,
we are 100 percent clear skies.
Nothing's gonna hit us for the next 200
years.
They don't know that.
They can't say that.
There's always something that comes real
close.
They just barely misses us.
And they go,
Whoa,
Holy Shit.
I was three miles long and it missed us
by 200,000
miles.
That's not much,
you know.
Okay.
Let's go to some questions.
You dirty bitches,
Nabisco in 2012.
So as the antichrist.
Oh No.
So some people think you're set of 2012
movie.
Yes.
Horrendously bad.
Really bad.
Not even worth even a special effects
sucked.
Oh really?
They were there.
I mean,
it was awesome.
Things were happening,
but it didn't look real.
Like the car is,
was a limo and jumping things and
landing fine.
Driving off and it looked a little talk,
computer generated and silly.
It's like every five seconds,
the fucking,
you know,
the car was almost going off the cliff
but barely made it.
You know,
it's like,
come on,
stop.
Stop with your nonsense.
This guy here,
easy dog down below seven says,
yeah,
I believe in God.
How did everything originate?
But how did God start?
Oh,
that's an easy question to answer it.
God.
Um,
were you there?
The real problem is believing in
anything.
You know,
that's,
that's the real problem.
The real problem is believing in
anything.
It's not believing in God.
I believe in God.
The real problems,
believing in anything you don't know.
We don't know.
God created a really good video game and
we're all in it.
That's possible that this is God's
version of the sims and this is on
somebodies phone.
Wait,
we're not even like a good video game.
We're just like a fucking cell phone
video shoot that people play when they
kill time,
waiting in line at the right rear break
break earlier.
It's God.
The real problem with believing in God
is that believing in God just makes
people feel better.
You know,
it's not saying that God doesn't exist.
It's very possible that God exists,
but you you don't have the information
no one does.
You can decide that you have that
information because it empowers you.
You can decide that there's a god
because it makes you feel more
comfortable or makes you feel more.
You know that there's a future to this
world and after you die,
there's something waiting for you and
that gives you confidence and that gives
you that it can empower you,
and that works for a lot of people.
I know a lot of fighters who are very
religious and that that belief in God
that actually empowers them and it can.
It can work that way,
but it really is just a tool.
It's just a psychological tool that
they're using to empower them and it
doesn't necessarily help them.
What helps them is the state of mind
that they put themselves in by believing
in God.
You know,
it's a really kind of a funny thing.
It's a catch 22.
Believing in God can empower you.
The ideas of Christianity are very
empowering ideas,
the ideas that you know,
that you know,
love your man as if he sees you and you
know,
do unto others as if you would have them
do unto yourself and you know,
turn the other cheek and don't be
violent and be helping.
Be Loving and be humble and worship God
and the idea of God.
What God is.
God is life and energy and the whole
universe and that you treat the whole
process as it's one gigantic fantastic
thing and that in,
in,
in going to a religious service and in,
in practicing,
you know any sort of a religion in,
in,
in like sticking to a certain ethic that
what you're doing is committing to
positive energy and if you commit to
that positive energy and then those
positive thoughts and positive way of
thinking,
that's empowering and that really will
help you.
And if you really do believe that you
have a destiny and that God has carved
out this destiny for you,
that's an empowering thing.
That shit,
that shit will absolutely make you
better things you say,
that's evidence of God.
That's evidence that Jesus,
well maybe,
but more likely it's evidence that
you've put yourself in the exact proper
state of mind to achieve things by
thinking positive and having positive
energy and being a loving Christian by
doing all those things.
You've put the good energy out there and
you've given yourself confidence because
you're doing the right thing and you've
given yourself a strong belief in
yourself because you're following the
right path and in doing that,
that's very empowering.
That's how God is real.
That's how religion is real,
but what it what it really all is at the
heart of it is you tuning in to the the
correct frequency of the universe with
the least amount of resistance,
the least amount of Latin amount of
resistance from you.
The least amount of negative thinking,
the least amount of meaning.
Like when I was a kid,
I'd get in arguments all the time with
everybody about anything and really I
was just a knucklehead.
I was just a dumb fuck,
but I didn't realize that by doing that,
by creating all this drama in my life
like I was,
it was just distracting the shit out of
me and it was keeping me from doing
things that I wanted to do.
He was keeping me from being happy and
comfortable and friendly and it was
keeping me from like I was constantly in
a state of causing trouble and causing
drama and creating all these obstacles
in my own life and I didn't realize it
at the time and I always thought of
people that were religious.
Like I just thought,
well there's got to be a lot of power in
that because like I was afraid of a dude
who was a religious who was on one of
the USAA taekwondo teens back when I was
fighting.
There was this dude,
I think his name was Bobby Clayton and I
think that's his name,
but he wasn't the best guy,
but he was crazy religious and that used
to scare the shit out of me.
This dude used to read the Bible every
day and this dude was like super,
super,
super religious and he really believed
that himself and I was,
you know,
not very religious and even though I was
doing really well in these tournaments
and I was,
you know,
beating a lot of really good guys.
There was something about this dude and
his religion that scared me,
like on paper,
he shouldn't have been the scariest guy
to me,
but he was,
for whatever reason,
because this dude was really religious,
so for you know,
that that belief that he had in himself,
that the belief in his faith and his
[inaudible],
all that shit was,
is empowering to him and I recognized
that it was empowering to him that he
was really legit about it.
And then he was his super religious
behavior.
Like he was never.
He never swore he didn't drink,
he was friendly to everyone.
He was like really,
really,
really dedicated and that was,
that made me nervous.
I think religion is empowering.
Brian has been a huge advocate of
scientology ever since he moved to Ohio.
Right.
Tell us about your experiences with
scientology.
They're sluts,
they're easy,
they're real easy to sleep with.
Just have to trick them in a lot of
positive energy and stuff like that.
Yeah,
and you just take their money and they
sleep with you.
That's great.
Do you hear that?
Is the scientology how a thing with
fucking are a lot of fun?
I all it is.
No,
you don't definitely married or anything
and then I don't think so.
Yeah.
When any new religion comes around,
you can be.
I'm not saying he's lying.
I think if I had to pick one religion,
like if you had to do it,
I'd
be Buddhist.
Yeah,
that seems like the one that makes
the most sense.
But the problem with being a Buddhist is
you've got to hang around with a bunch
of fucking.
He's a bunch of people who are
pretending to be Buddhists,
you know?
Yeah.
They always smelly feet.
It looks like it's like the idea of
hippies.
It's all good on paper,
but the real problem with hippies is,
you know,
they don't want to work.
They're fucking lazy and stupid.
A lot of them.
And then,
you know,
it's like the stereotypes of the pot
smoking,
Lazy,
you know,
a Ne'er do wells.
Like that's,
that's like accurate.
And a lot of ways that's the real
problem with hippies.
You know,
what's Buddhist women look like?
I don't think I've ever seen a bit of
school.
I'm doing good.
Vegetarians are really.
Did they have like about heads orange
robes,
gentleman.
I gotta take a shit again so I can't
believe this.
We aid sausage subs this local place
down the street.
They're a little bit too strong,
too powerful.
Five hundred 24 viewers.
I appreciate this and I will be only a
couple minutes,
but Brian will answer questions while
I'm gone.
I'll be gone for a couple minutes.
My bathroom is right down here.
I'll be right back.
All right.
What's the chemicals
or a bod rail you asked what the
chemical structure on Joe's shirt?
On the spike comedy central.
Ask questions.
You can ask questions.
I'll answer them.
What I'm saying.
That's DMT though.
Those sale and no shirts will be for
sale soon.
Uh,
Joe have it on his website.
They're trying to get the website
together to sell.
He's going to have a whole bunch of
different kinds of shirts and clothing I
guess.
So that'll be coming soon.
It's a whole clothing line.
Do you get ever get tired of all these
stupid people asking you about drugs?
I think he just,
you just get tired of stupid people.
They don't care about drugs now.
He doesn't get tenure.
What else?
A lot of the same questions.
Uh,
have you ever heard of Uri Geller?
That's not the point of the same ones.
Psychic psychic.
There you go.
Should I take dmt?
No.
You should not take dmt.
If you're asking joe on a twitter,
if you're a are alien or aliens among
us.
Yes.
They're Asian based.
It all aliens are Asians.
Yeah.
I think all aliens or Asian or some kind
of breed of Asian because they were just
technology than us.
Regular white people were more caveman.
They're more alien.
See,
let's go back to your Rogan and board
forums dot Joe Rogan.net.
There's a whole thread with people
asking questions on there.
Also,
I can.
Can you views you stream over the
iphone?
Yeah,
I believe so.
It's probably only good if you use Wifi.
Yeah.
What's the best place you ever done
standup?
There's no one best place of my favorite
places or Austin,
Texas fireplaces or Austin,
Texas Delphia,
Phoenix,
Arizona,
San Francisco,
New York,
La,
San Francisco to go to new employees,
Columbus,
Ohio.
Uh,
any updates on brock lesnar's health is.
Everyone's asking to take a long time.
He hasn't heard anything new.
It's going to take a long time for them
to sort all that out apparently is a
pretty serious condition that you have
right?
Band,
you seem to be pretty much up on
technology.
What's the single piece of technology or
equipment that would be available to the
public you're most excited about in
2010?
I think a lot of people who know me,
I'm excited for the new apple,
a tablet,
like an oversized iphone because I net,
net books are so popular right now and I
just find that that's just going to be
what's next.
After net books and iphones back just
took another tremendous shit.
Oh,
sorry.
Brian said,
my shit stinks,
which we know what to expect,
man.
Isn't that bad?
Alright,
I'll,
I'll try to enjoy to like it.
All right.
Oh,
that's great.
You're faking it.
Yeah.
I'm thinking it.
Why?
I shouldn't have to fake it.
I shouldn't just act like it's mine.
Yeah.
Why don't you do that?
Okay.
It's mine.
No,
it doesn't work.
It's so stupid.
It should work.
Yeah.
You can trick yourself.
What do we got here?
Uh,
thank you.
Twitter turned out on this page.
Would you see that cloud just blew
through the wrong.
Her refresh
shows your stomach or you burke?
We just added this Italian place down
the street.
Tremendous sausage and pepper sub.
You get to like an east coast sausage
and pepper.
Seven la.
Was it called Cavalry Camera Ready?
Something like that.
Good fellows.
Posters were in there.
Okay.
Questions.
Do you ripe wipe from the front to back
or back to front?
That's a good question.
I never thought about that.
I'm a dude and I'm wiping my ass.
Not Like Regina.
So I guess front to back.
Do you stand up?
Yes.
Yeah,
totally.
Do you know,
were rare.
Most people sit down when they white,
they can't get the job by now.
I don't understand it.
Also.
Uh,
you said you always piece sitting there.
That's kind of how dare you.
I dare you.
I'll tell you something about my toilet
though,
that you probably didn't want to know,
but you probably already know if you
follow me on twitter,
you can.
First of all,
you can't flush those flushable wipes.
That's bullshit.
They say you can flush those things.
Yeah,
they'll disappear,
but they're going to clog up your
fucking toilet.
It was those flushable wipes that you
get.
You got to use just 12.
You've been getting the dis.
The flushable kind of disposable kind.
Yeah,
but they're not,
they're not flushing because I love
first month of using those.
I thought they were all flushable and
then I saw that little picture on the
back.
I'm like,
clogged the shit out of your toilet.
But mine.
Mine got clogged up and they had to come
and fucking clean it out.
Rest you had crossed a lot of money.
But the big thing is that I have fucking
plant growing in my toilet.
Yeah.
You saw that Shit,
right?
It was ridiculous.
It was a gigantic tree that was growing
in my toilet.
They found roots and they pulled it out
and I put it up on twitter.
I think a lot of people have seen it.
I'm sure.
I'll see if I can find it.
I'll throw the link back up.
Maybe something like flicker page.
I mean it was so ridiculous.
I mean it was so ridiculous that I
looked at it and I was like,
how the fuck was that growing inside my
toilet?
But I guess it was the water.
You need to start updating your flicker.
Right?
My photo stream.
I must've had it after.
I know I had it on twit pic.
Right.
Maybe that's where it was.
Yeah.
These are my.
No in Colorado photos.
Yeah.
Something here.
Put it up.
Let me start again.
Twitter.
Twitter is twitter.
Yeah.
Music and hearing now,
why not?
That's against the law.
What is it?
You're streaming music.
If I do this and I have music playing in
the background,
we can't do it.
Could be arrested.
Come on.
Really?
This isn't a topic,
you know,
that's the problem with using all these
different goddamn programs.
Why frog or I don't know what the other
one is or how the other one works so
fucked up when find picture back then
your twitter.
You find it for you guys.
Toilet tree.
I don't even know the fucking photo is.
No,
I have to go to iphone photo and I
apologize this.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is not very entertaining,
isn't it?
You don't even give a fuck.
You don't give a fuck.
When you see the picture though,
the pictures are so ridiculous to.
This goddamn thing was actually grown
inside my toilet bowl.
It seems like it's not going to be worth
the wages.
Google toilet tree,
Joe Rogan.
It'll be out there in zinc.
So yeah,
fairness here.
This motherfucker can mean.
Come on man.
Look at that fucking thing.
That shit's ridiculous.
I've got to show you guys.
This shit is goes.
It looks like.
I'm like,
I was mumbling so it doesn't even look
real.
It looks completely fake.
So now go back to flicker,
upload their shit.
This is,
it's going to be hard for this picture
to live up to the hype of fiddling
through my fucking computer.
Just trying to get this picture of you
guys,
but once you get the picture I think
you'll.
You'll appreciate what the fuck I'm
saying because it's so ridiculous.
This thing was growing in my God damn
toilet.
Weird.
What the fuck?
Where is it?
Explored it.
It's uploading right
soon as it uploads.
I'll take the length.
My Internet is so weak.
Why have you done this yet?
I'm do.
Just make a call.
I'm a procrastinator.
Clearly make a phone call.
That's all you have to do.
I think I will even have a beer.
What?
Sort of six slash one.
So I'll do it tomorrow.
I'm going to do it and gentlemen,
a lot of people
talk about upgrading the Internet.
I'm going to and do it.
I'm going to do it for you guys
because once you do that,
we could have separate cans.
You know,
gonna have two cans,
we got a third cam.
If we need to show something else,
we have a third came.
Just be your desktop.
So instead of having to upload all these
photos,
you could just show what's on your
desktop.
Why would I do that?
It's easier.
That's getting whatever shop.
Okay.
Here's the photo.
All sizes.
Big Size Papi.
Which bathroom is that when you hear
Jesus?
Yeah.
What do you think about the mayweather
pacman situation?
I think they're genius in minus 38.
Really?
How twitter tweet?
Tiny your eye.
Why isn't it just do it for your
parents.
Your mark
tweet?
Because it's a WAC program.
She their twitter programs.
Why doesn't even shrink your urls or
thought that that would be a business?
Yeah,
it's gotten big.
We're getting a tiny url business.
What are you talking about?
Oh,
making people website names.
Really small.
Yeah.
Who the fuck would ever thought there
would be a market for that?
One of the websites,
I can't remember.
I don't think it's tiny url,
but it's one of them like almost got
bought the other day for like a couple
million dollars and that's all it is.
Is that url short shorten.
That's hilarious.
All right.
I put it up your fuckers.
That's another one that was grown.
All right.
Sorry for the long delay.
That was ridiculous.
It wasn't even that interesting but it
is kinda interesting.
I,
I put the picture up.
You can go see the picture.
It's on my twitter.
What's next?
After a weekly Rogan podcast and the
book.
What's the next project?
There are no next projects.
This is about,
it isn't about all.
We're going to do a weekly podcast.
We're doing a show for Sony was going to
be called a l,
F,
m,
a o,
but now we might have to call it
something different.
Yeah,
because I was trying to do it for like
two years and now there's a band called
mail or something like that.
Their clothes will come up with a name
for it,
but it's basically a interviewing
comedians about the creative process.
And,
uh,
we're also enter in the middle of a
coming up with another show that uh,
it's comedy related to I can't talk
about,
but it should be fun.
That and just more shows,
more comedy,
more good stuff.
Is fear factor
returning anytime?
Oh,
it's not.
I know there was a rumor that.
No.
Oh yeah,
there was a rumor for a while they were
going to try to bring fear factor back.
This fear factor when they canceled it
was like,
it was kinda like they could have kept
going if they really want.
That's a show that could come back
easily,
do that shit.
And if you did it without me didn't have
the flavor,
I'm sure it would probably be great if
they did.
It was like Mario Lopez.
No,
you can't pass up on that easy money.
Especially if you're working with all
the same people again and stuff.
I might be willing to
just for my kids just put money away.
What's your movie coming on?
Uh,
October.
Damn.
Should I move to Colorado?
I loved Colorado Man sideshow.
Sit said should I move to it?
I fucking loved it.
I would still be there.
I didn't mind the cold.
I liked the people.
I liked the sky.
I like the way the fucking mountains
looked.
I liked the vibe.
I liked everything about it.
I liked it for me creatively.
I liked living in Colorado,
but when you have a family,
you have children,
you have a wife and it's not as.
It's not as easy as just me being by
myself.
It was,
it was just me by myself.
I'd probably still be there.
I still be on the top of that mountain,
but she was not into it.
It's just too creepy.
When our dog got eaten,
our dog had eaten by mountain line.
That's not like a rumor that actually
happened.
Dog had eaten by mountain lions and uh,
she's bad driving in snow.
She crashed the car,
so it was a couple of different things.
And then she got pregnant and the
pregnancy was the biggest reason why we
had to move out of Colorado.
It was because we were living over 8,000
feet above sea level.
It's really hot.
It's like three.
We are 3000 feet above boulder and it is
really,
really high altitude and when you're
pregnant it's just brutal.
It really,
it's not good for you.
It's unhealthy for you and for the baby.
Colorado is like one of the highest
states in the country that one of the
top states in the country when it comes
to premature births and a lot of it is
because the altitude just.
You don't get enough air up there.
It's just,
it's great for your conditioning,
but it's not,
not so good for from being a pregnant
woman.
So all those factors I had to move out
to Colorado,
but if I could just be somewhere and
live somewhere live in Colorado.
Oh,
in a heartbeat.
If I didn't have to travel,
stay in Colorado and you know,
deal with snow when it comes to your
fucking snowed in.
No big deal.
That's what it's supposed to be like.
A problem with me is I travel all the
time so I would leave my wife and leave
the kids there.
It's not the same by myself.
I'd have no problem with it.
I loved it.
So if you are going to move somewhere
and stay there,
I would say yeah,
Colorado's fucking bad ass.
That's my favorite state.
Do you think there will be a time when
all handheld access will have a pipe in
them?
Like the Tomahawk Tomahawks where there
were a pipe and an ax all in one.
Is that true?
If that's true,
the Indians were bad motherfuckers,
so I think that did just went to a
renaissance festival getting carried
away because I mean if you think about,
if it was a pipe also,
listen,
this is the beauty of the Internet right
now.
We'll google this.
Did Tomahawks have pipes on?
I think there might've been a couple
that did,
but I don't think the majority of it.
I speculate.
Let's find out.
Okay.
I just doesn't seem right.
It seems like it would just make that
the weapon weaker,
having a hole through the middle of it.
Yeah,
that's true.
That's a good point.
Maybe it's enough.
Yeah.
Hype,
Tomahawk.
That's a pipe axes.
The crazy crow trading post.
Show me a pipe backs these pipes
pipe historically accurate pipe axes.
We have spent years researching and
manufacturing the finest line of
throwing Tomahawks pipe,
Tomahawks belt and camp ax is available
today.
Did you even know there was a market for
that kind of Shit?
That's the beautiful thing about the
Internet.
Let's see what this thing looks like.
I don't see the pipe part.
Where's the pipe part?
Hand drill for smoking.
Wow.
Sounds like anytime forge iron had
drilled for smoking.
So basically the pipe is this.
You put some tobacco up in that bitch
right there and you smoke right out of
there
or do you smoke?
You smoke out of there.
Wow.
Nick,
the handle weaker in a weapon.
Weaker definitely would.
Right,
but this seems like it's like really
hard would.
This one's got a metal piece through
that original 1800 to 18.
Twenty five believed to belong to red
cloud.
Wow.
That's pretty dope.
Red Cloud in.
Didn't think it out.
Dude.
I think we should start smoking pipe
from a fucking Tomahawk.
We're going to order one of those.
Come on man.
What'd you the podcast?
We'll smoke out of that.
That's ladies and gentlemen.
What?
Say you on twitter?
I need to order this,
right?
I'm going to order this.
Add to basket.
Listen,
clerk.
That's added to the basket.
All right,
I'm going to check out now.
I'll check it out later because I don't
want you guys to get bummed out at me.
It was boring enough looking for that
toilet tree coming up on two hours.
Which would make this two hours.
You think?
Why are you getting bored anymore?
No,
I just think we to keep it to you have
to do another video.
Someone doesn't think it's fun anymore.
All.
Let's go back.
Four hundred 71.
Motherfuckers in here.
We lost a lot of people for being really
boring.
Madison to I think is just about right.
You want them wanting more?
Not less.
Is that what we want?
Ladies and gentlemen.
Let's see.
Ryan.
He correct two hours.
What is the.
Where's the time on top left?
Where they're getting light is right
over here.
I think after two hours also it doesn't
save maybe or something.
I think as people start hating this bug,
it's got nothing to talk about.
Boring as shit.
So,
so far we've answered questions.
We put photos up on twitter,
we've talked about some heavy subjects.
Would more,
do you need that?
He's in gentlemen.
We're all living in an alien's petri
dish.
Says Dawkins 20 maybe,
you know as possible.
Is time illusion shred for 31.
Wants to know if time's an illusion.
I don't think it's an illusion.
I just don't think time is just one
thing.
You tell that the David Copperfield,
everything's.
I think time is,
you know,
I mean we already know that time changes
when you go fast.
Like if someone's in a super fast
spaceship,
uh,
you know,
and they go at the speed of light,
like time goes by much quicker on earth
and it doesn't in their plane.
So if they come back and they're super
fast spaceship,
you know,
for them it's only been a year.
But for us it could be like 100 years
depending on how far and fast they go.
So time lose in a way that I don't,
I don't,
I don't think it's the way we look at
it.
I don't think it's as cut and dry.
Like,
you know,
this is midnight and this is 1:00.
I think it's,
it's much more dependent upon the state
that the human beings and like the
frequency of the persons in the world
where the person's living,
you know,
that you're,
you're living on earth,
you know,
this dimension,
you know that there's the time varies
throughout other dimensions and you can
access those dimensions.
I mean if they really do come up with
ships that can fly through space at
closest speed of light or something,
they really will be able to go to a
place where they're,
they're literally going forward in time.
They'll have lived one year,
they come back to earth and hundreds of
years have gone by.
That's just nutty shit.
And that's real.
No,
I don't think we understand time enough.
I think Tom is one of those things that
we think we've got a grip I want.
It really is,
but it's probably far more complex and
confusing and variable than we think
I didn't use to get rid of daylight
savings time because I think it's
bullshit that it's fucking pitch black
outside and it's only 6:30.
Yes,
she's absolutely right.
Farmers,
they're all fucking thief's.
What's,
how dare you.
But seriously,
John Mellencamp hater back then it made
sense because everybody was a farmer.
You know,
everything has to do with farmers
nowadays.
Why didn't they just get up earlier to
get it?
I don't get everything.
It makes sense.
I think,
you know,
if you have a regular job,
sometimes it's dark out.
Sometimes it's light out the fucking
earth span.
That's what I love about Arizona.
The Arizona,
they don't change their time.
They're like fuck,
you know,
it's stupid.
What they need to even do it better than
that.
They need to like really fuck it up.
Like I want it to be bright out till
like nine to 10:00
at night.
Don't you think?
That'd be cool.
Yeah.
But then it would be dark
out until like noon here,
but that's fine.
No.
Oh,
that's retarded.
Retarded is that.
It makes no sense.
Most people would rather like to have a
day.
Like most people would rather have
daylight when you get off work and
anything.
I think that's silly.
It's silly.
I spelled twitter long while my link.
I know I did.
I don't think I could fix it though.
I think it's too late.
It is.
It is what it is.
No,
you don't get better.
What do you do that other program
remember?
Oh,
that's right.
That's this little motherfucker right
here.
Check so shit
right in the room.
Yeah.
It's just understanding the whole thing.
Why does it not show?
Because it's like two lines.
You know what I mean?
Like if you hit the right button,
right?
Yeah.
Put a Joe live.
Yay.
High fix that shit.
It didn't change.
Oh good.
Good.
Mm hmm.
Scott is trying to be funny.
Steve whizzy trying to be funny.
Steve was.
He says,
besides Carlos,
when Sia.
Who are your other favorite?
What does make sense being silly?
Goose.
Um,
my favorite comedians though for real.
All right guys.
Well I look forward to seeing like Lucy
Kay,
uh,
Dave attell.
Doug Stan Hope.
Definitely.
Um,
there's a cat williams.
See Him live.
I only seen him on video.
Catlins is on TMZ yesterday.
Just got out of jail or something like
that.
And they,
they,
he got in a fight at a bar and he had a
gun in his pocket.
Ah,
like it.
He's crazy.
That's crazy.
For Real.
I want to meet that dude.
I like his comedy.
I think he's very funny.
Do you ever listen to him on a grand
theft auto?
No.
Good.
Yeah.
He does like the voice.
Well,
no,
they have a comedy club and grand theft
auto.
I like it.
If not telepathy.
What's next for Human Johnny Bananas?
Twenty one wants to know boots for men
if not telepathy.
What?
Snacks for human evolution.
Probably a reversal if not telepathy,
if we gonna I think we're in a race
right now between technology and
retards,
between technology and caveman style
living,
you know,
they're talking about invading Pakistan,
veining,
Yemen and more war and more craziness.
You know,
we're at a,
a crossroads and I think we could either
get hit by a meteor or blow ourselves up
or figure out the next level,
figure out what,
what's going to take human beings from
where we are to the next stage of
existence.
Which is like a real thing.
I mean,
I think we're really going to evolve.
We're really moving towards something
new,
you know,
I think that's what this,
this frantic fucking society we live in
is all about.
I think we're,
we're pushing and moving towards
something all working together towards
something and I think it's going to be
technology driven,
so it's one of those things.
Either that's going to happen,
there's going to be some sort of a
technologically birthed connection that
all people all of a sudden share some
sort of a,
some sort of a convergence of all human
being.
It's either gonna be that or it's going
to be blow ourselves up or a meteor
fucks us up or yellowstone explodes and
we start from scratch.
You know what if,
what if in the future,
the first robot to get pregnant?
Imagine,
imagine you figured out a way to get out
machines so closely tuned into human
beings that you can fuck them and get
them pregnant.
Yeah,
I think that's very possible then don't
you?
Anything's possible at this point.
That's not that crazy.
You know?
I mean,
they can make so many things
artificially.
They figured out a way to make pork in a
laboratory.
The actual,
the meat,
they can take some of the meat from,
from a pig and then making a laboratory.
The problem is it's not really like
mushy because it doesn't exercise at all
and it's not like,
it's not like taught sinew,
but they're trying to figure out a way
to maybe electrically exercise the
muscle.
You could literally like just make
gigantic like rooms full of meat,
you know?
It doesn't even have a life attached to
it.
If they can do that,
if they can do that,
why can't they?
If they can figure out a way to grow
meat,
why can't they figure out a way to make
an artificial human being
that's going to be just like blade
runner though?
They're going to be all sad and shit.
Don't want to kill you.
You know you have to give emotions.
If you don't give them emotions,
then you know they can't relate to
people.
They can't empathize with people and
then just go on mad raping and killing
sprees.
Because if you make artificial people,
if you make them,
when they get the hard ons and shit,
you know,
he has a boner.
Our robots imagine.
I mean if you make the females you make
males to like for like old gay dudes,
you know,
dudes and what you know,
like to have a robot fucked all right,
but gay dudes would want some robot gay.
Do you imagine if they could make a like
a real live like safe.
There was a guy who was your neighbor
who was really creepy and he was fixated
on you and he make a robot that looks
exactly like you and just fuck it all
day long and punch it and tie it up and
shit on its head and there's nothing you
can do about it.
So literally next door to your fucking
house.
This guy's like putting that,
the robot head out the window and waving
to you.
Look,
look,
I'm pissing his mouth and it's like you.
But it's a fake you.
And he's just fucking it up all day.
How disturbing with that be?
There's nothing you can do about it
because you have the papers on this.
It's not a real human sir.
And they chose the papers.
Okay.
I guess it's a robot.
I mean,
if it's a robot,
right?
Look,
if I have a grappling dummy in my,
uh,
in my garage that I use in my practice,
my Jujitsu,
you know,
and you could practice positions on it.
It's like it's a,
it's called the above a dummy to Gracie.
You could buy it from,
uh,
the,
the Gracie Academy in Torrance.
They're,
they,
they're the ones who start selling
another website.
I forget what the website is,
but if you look above a dummy,
it's a dummy that's just designed for
Jujitsu.
And we filmed once playing around.
Remember we're in the yard and in the
garage.
We were beating the shit out of it and
kick it in.
What if that was a real person?
I mean,
it's a dummy that we made,
but what if it's a robot person?
What if there's like a robot person that
you could practice Jujitsu on?
You can rape them.
Who could punch him in the face?
You could just beat the shit out of me.
You could chop his arms off.
He'd be screaming and yelling and the
cops come to go,
look,
it's a fake person.
You ever been there?
The laws would have to probably change
that.
Artificial intelligence is just the
same,
you know,
because then I mean,
yeah,
because I mean a dog isn't as smart as a
human,
but don't.
You're not going to.
You're allowed to chop the dog's legs
off and stuff like a robot that has
artificial intelligence.
It's still going to be considered
artificial intelligence,
I think.
Yeah,
but do you think that they'll treat it
the same way as a human being?
Like the laws?
It'll be like murder,
right?
I think if it's.
If it can think it's going to be
considered life,
but before they figured that out,
there's going to be a couple of years of
masturbating,
extra staffing,
have a direct replica of you and he's
gonna fuck.
It's right in front of your window.
It's going to blow an air heart.
I look out the window.
What the fuck is he doing?
You looked at these fucking your head
and you think about it,
like,
what if that was me?
What if I was the duplicate and the real
me was watching me get raped.
It's weird shit.
That could be real.
That could really be a possibility.
You know?
What I'm surprised is that there's not
technology yet where we can.
I could have a program and type out shit
and make it sound exactly like you.
Like,
you know,
like your voice can do the exact levels.
So like you could prank call with your
mom and stuff like that.
Is there should be that or it shouldn't
be that.
Totally.
Yeah.
Why haven't they figured that out?
It seems easy.
You know,
it's really ridiculous too,
is that you still have to sign things.
You scribble their name.
Yeah.
This is stupid because I write taco
penis.
I don't even care.
They don't look at it and it'll check
your id.
This.
No,
no.
I don't sign my credit cards.
I guess if you could look at my driver's
license,
I scribbled my name on that and it's a
similar level,
but what are these fucking people that
work at the target or they scribble
experts can look at that scribble.
I Dunno.
It's just not the same guy.
Sometimes I write full sentences.
Honest to God.
Yeah.
It's ridiculous.
How is that still around?
Right.
Something with your name and that's
legally binding.
If you write something with your name,
you know what I mean?
Like you know when I got married I had
to get a marriage certificate and had to
write,
scribble and that's it.
That's what ties you up now when you
wrote void.
See,
I wouldn't do that.
I would write.
This is not real and scribble because
then she has a gun head.
If I get a divorce I got.
If you could see I wrote this is not
void on it.
I wonder if that was enough.
Valid.
I don't know.
Maybe.
Maybe you could say it's like shit.
Then I could say,
well we have a.
We have the documents you sign.
Then you can look at and go,
look what I wrote.
Yeah.
It says this is not real.
You know,
been married.
Maybe just sign.
I do not agree to this.
I'm a gun is being held up to my hair
color.
They have my dog hostage.
Robots will have rights after awhile,
so yeah,
that's a guy I watched that will smith
movie ai,
ai,
ai.
So they need to make an ai maybe like
with the kid like sex.
Was it?
I am robot robot.
That was.
That was pretty good moment.
That's a good movie.
Everything was Mac.
Remember all the robots look like Max
does.
Gilbert.
It will have a chance against those
Santos.
This guy's talking about UFC.
This is that.
When you leave you won't talk about UFC
will answer one UFC question.
Yes,
he does.
Gilbert arrivals.
Dangerous.
He's a really good striker,
dangerous motherfucker and he knows
there's a big opportunity for him.
He's going to come charge and guns
blazing.
Don't you think it's stupid when people
ask you is going to win that fight
because obviously it's a fight for a
reason.
Meaning that there's not an obvious
winner of this fight,
so most of the time it's not an obvious
winner,
but most of the time,
I mean there's a lot of the times when
when everybody agrees that a certain guy
going to win,
I mean,
it doesn't mean that you're right,
but in this fight,
this guy doesn't know that much about
this Gilbert Ivo guy probably and
wonders.
I think Gilbert's got a real good chance
he's.
He's dangerous.
If he trains hard,
if he's in real good shape,
he's very,
very dangerous.
He knocks a lot of guys out his out of
Gary Goodrich and pride was one of the
most spectacular knockouts ever.
Head kicked him.
Boom.
One shot,
like 10 seconds of the fight and put
them to sleep.
He's questions that you can ask a dog to
bark once for yes and two for no,
and it had the same percentage of the
outcome of the question in the answer
that,
you know what I mean?
Like if you say,
yeah,
that going to win,
someone's going to win.
Right?
But someone's.
I'll also tell you if someone's good or
not,
you,
you don't know if someone's going to.
Okay.
No more sports questions.
Order it.
I'm going to order that for the time
occupied next broadcast.
Hopefully if they get it too many times
we will have a tomahawk pipe.
I think that's a fucking awesome item.
Like you need another pipe.
I needed tom off [inaudible] like a
motherfucker I bake,
especially since it's a replica of
something from a dude name.
Red Cloud was fanny packs.
They have.
Oh,
they have a sweep and we'll get that.
Somebody that quilt.
Oh,
that's like a shoulder bag.
I don't do shoulder bags.
That's a God damn purse.
Okay.
Fanny pack is fucking manly.
That's a manly shit.
All right.
Let's go to the Rogan board and see
questions.
Yeah.
Why is fanny pack manly?
I'll tell you why.
Fanny packs and mainly because if you're
wearing a fanny pack,
first of all you're saying I don't give
a fuck what you think about how I look.
You know,
you just slapped in this big stupid gay
thing around your waist and you're like,
whatever.
I have two hands free and I'm happy.
I'm not trying to look good for you.
I'm not trying to fuck you.
I'm not trying to get you to be my
friend.
I like having all my shit in a bag then
yeah,
I'm not trying to get laid.
So when people talk about,
oh man hugging,
you wear it for a pug.
That's so gay.
It's a bag that connects to my waist.
This is silly.
The only reason why you don't think it's
good looking because women figures
disgusting and women think it looks gay.
So women have figured out a way to
bully.
Guys did not wearing it by telling us
that looks gay.
Why would you care what kind of a bag?
Another man.
Where's your.
Unless he's wearing a bright pink hello
kitty strap.
It covers up your crotch.
Yeah,
it does cover up my crotch.
It's right there.
So if there's like a micro media that
comes from outer space and could
potentially hit me in the deck,
it's going to hit my cell phone first or
perhaps my wallet.
It's right there.
It's easy for travel.
When I go to the airport,
I unbuckled that thing,
Bang,
put it on my car keys on there.
My cell phones now at fanny packs of the
shit son
got here.
That would be cool if gay people love
the smell farts.
That was didn't Joe Joseph
for awhile.
This fellow says,
when are you going to come to the east
coast of Canada?
I don't like the east coast.
Can't.
No,
I'm just kidding.
We're in Montreal last April.
That was fun.
I'll be back.
I'll definitely be back up there.
All right,
page two.
We're going to the Rogan board right
now.
To answer your questions
thing about Jersey shore.
I don't like Jersey shore watches that
thought I would like it because I knew
too many dudes like that growing up.
To me it's like more annoying and
stupid.
It's fun for a couple seconds.
So you fist pump,
you know,
but after awhile it's just,
it's fake.
Did this is my theory.
I mean talking to my favorite.
No,
I think it kind of like when Hill's
first came
out,
everyone thought that was a real.
Then slowly got to the point where we
figured out it was a fake show that's
film to look real.
I think Jersey shores real way too dumb
to ask.
Did you know half of them are like male
strippers.
I had to audition like they're all in
the entertainment field.
It's called Jersey shore and stood the
hills.
You know,
I bet you anything of that.
Yeah,
I bet you anything sounds and they all
live in this house.
It's really nice.
Like railroad house.
You know what I mean?
That's the real people.
It's really a genius show if you look at
it that way,
but I think in three years we're all
going to be like knowing it's fake.
Like that fight somehow is fake and
everything really.
There wasn't fake when I do punch that
girl to face,
unless that chick is like a,
you know,
stump woman and they fucking practice it
for like 50 years.
You know what I mean?
If they practiced the punch a lot,
you know?
Hm.
I mean you look at movies and you look
at that punch,
it looks real.
If they filmed it like to look fake,
I think they'll do got drunk and punch
that bitch face.
Listen,
someone said what?
I have full blown aids or spend one year
and Mark Hayden's body pick one.
Well I know what full blown aids you can
recover from.
You know,
being in one year and marketing's body
will probably be torture.
David.
I think full blown aids.
If you take your vitamins,
probably be okay in a couple of weeks.
You spend one year in mark cadens body.
Every chicken could possibly fuck,
fuck unaids.
You're not going to get out of these
bonds and mark cadens body.
You don't get aids in marketing.
You don't even understand the question.
No,
I'm saying if you have one year in his
body,
you could just abuse it.
Like fucking get the fuck out of there
in one year.
It's ridiculous.
How dare you.
That's in this.
Let's end this.
Alright,
well a couple more questions.
No,
I need the fuck Outta here.
I got to met.
Some of these questions are really lame,
but it could be that were really high
and they just seem lane.
That's a distinct possibility,
which that's more coffee right now.
Um,
I apologize for the wack ass Internet.
I really am going to fix that.
Should I go 80 and t uverse or should I
go?
Comcast cable.
Charter.
Charter,
Wow.
This guy says,
I think red bands.
Life is fake.
How about that for our children to camp
mistake.
He says,
your life is fake.
I think you said your face is fake in
his face.
His screen names fake.
Like he didn't even have a picture.
This is di.
What would happen?
Well,
it's fake and on.
It was not fun.
Nope.
With this,
this is the laziest rapist ever.
Dave Broomfield@hotmail.com
says,
hey,
Joe Rogan.
Why don't you invite me to come trip
with you and your isolation tank.
How lazy is he?
That's not how you were stalking rape.
Somebody saw him.
It's gonna.
Take.
You gonna have to be a little more
clever than that.
That's ridiculous.
Fuck that guy.
We've got a fake Brett Rogers.
Hey Joe Robbie.
Did you see my last fight?
No.
Fake Brett Rogers.
I didn't.
For Roger's not on twitter.
Isn't gentlemen that's a fake Brett
Rogers.
The railroad rogers is a bad
motherfucker,
but that's not him.
But it was really funny when the fake
Brett Rogers was having an argument with
a real,
a warm machine that was pretty funny.
War machine didn't get it.
Thought it was all really happening.
Brian,
you stopped talking a while ago.
What happened if you've given up on us?
Yeah.
I get to the cutoff point where I'm just
tired of staring at computer.
Well,
I have an accompany in Indian head dress
to go with my Tomahawk pipe.
Says uh,
um,
use 97.
90 four.
Yeah,
that's a very good question.
And I think yes,
I think if we're gonna really get in
touch with the spirit world.
We're going to need full Indian attire.
Anything.
Yeah.
We're going to need the whole thing,
man.
We're going to need feathers and shit.
And the,
you know,
the correct type of.
We'd kind of make sure we only smoke
what the Indian.
Small?
Yeah.
Smaller condoms.
Small.
No,
not those Indians.
American Indians.
That India Indians.
Girl Mosh pit.
I watched her for a couple of seconds,
but it was like one of those terrorists
videos where they cut some dude's head
off after awhile.
I just shut it off.
She,
if any of these questions don't suck.
So,
um,
I think if anything came out of this
somewhere,
someone right now is thinking about
designing a robot where you clone your
neighbor and make a robot out of it and
then fuck them and rape them in front of
somebody.
Somebody is thinking about that.
And I think if this
chat has done anything good for the
world,
it's introduced that idea at that
possibility out there of making a clone
of you.
You're just gonna sack is we're going to
be like 90 years old and they're going
to make the perfect fuck robot,
but we're going to be so old.
We're not going to even care anymore.
I'm telling you that it was.
Yeah,
I guess,
but they'll probably have more problems
than we have now.
You know,
we'll probably look back on these days
and Oh,
remember the simple times they just get
on the Internet and drive to work and
you have to worry about monsters and
aliens and Ufo and fucking know the
Hyena flu.
That's killing everybody lately.
You know,
that's the next one.
Something scary like pig food doesn't
scare you.
Bird flu.
That doesn't scare the fucking Hyena.
Flu is going to scare the shit out of,
you know,
it's a flu that came from hyenas.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
From,
from eating their own young.
They came up with a fucking crazy new
flu and it's an everyone who gets it
dies everywhere.
What beekeepers outfits everywhere.
Cat in California last week got the
first h,
one n,
one reeling people that cat.
Uh,
so maybe it's going to be cats.
We're gonna have to kill our cats or
something like that.
After you have a baby,
cats become just really annoying.
Dogs are knowing,
like shut the fuck up.
But he was the best
babies.
Rural dogs or cats.
My cats started pissing in my office
right after my child was born.
New plans.
Parent little con.
So obvious what you wanted to be a
little bitch.
A couple more questions here.
Let's go to the rug and boards if we've
got a good question there.
Do you ever get mad?
Like in anything?
Actually pushed her off to the point
where urban smash a,
I get that I get upset,
but it has to be pretty fucking a bad
situation.
Me that upset.
I'm pretty rational when it comes to
most things.
I have A.
I mean everyone has the ability to freak
out over something.
It's just whether or not you choose to
let yourself get there.
You know,
just gotTa.
Make sure.
I think the most important thing about
not getting mad as manage your biology,
you got to treat your biology like it's
a bank account.
And if you have,
you know,
if you're in debt,
you know you owe it something.
If you know your overdrafted you,
you owe yourself an expenditure of
energy.
Yeah.
Especially if you have a certain type of
body.
If you have a muscular body,
if you have a person is in engaged in
athletics or whole life,
you have a Bot.
If it's used to exerting a lot of energy
when you owe it to that body,
you have to like you have a debt to pay
and if you don't pay that debt,
you're gonna,
you're gonna have a problem where you're
going to have too much energy that's
stored up and built in,
not blown out and it's going to come out
and unusual ways.
Look in traffic or at work or whatever.
It'll you'll,
you'll start screaming and freaking out
about something he really didn't need to
and really it's all just about managing
your biology,
managing your thoughts.
It's very important to have some
downtime where you can sit alone by
yourself and just think,
that's very,
very important for me.
The isolation tank does that,
like times 100,
that's my favorite,
but sometimes even just sitting on the
couch and just by myself,
just thinking,
you know,
you can call it meditation,
you can call it whatever the fuck you
want.
Just spending time to organize your
thoughts and put your mind in a certain
place.
Put your body in a certain place with
exercise,
with yoga,
with nutrition,
all that Shit's important.
You've got to manage your biology and
when you manage your biology,
it makes managing your mind much,
much easier.
Managing your mind,
managing a biology.
That's the key to not getting upset at
things.
You fucking faggots.
What the best artists created from the
starving artist.
It seems that this is a good question.
It seems the best art is created from
the starving artists being wealthy.
Do you feel it hurts your ability to
create art comedy,
or do you believe that not having to
worry about your financial wellbeing
allows you more time to be creative?
That's a very good question.
I think a lot of times people are much
more ambitious when they're starving.
They have much more energy.
They have much more a dedication towards
something,
but that doesn't mean that you can't
have a lot of dedication towards
something when you become successful.
It all depends on what was your
motivation in the first place.
If your motivation in the first place
was recognition and you know,
adulation and then you become famous and
then you get that,
then you have no motivation to keep
going,
but if your motivation is the actual art
itself is creating new things,
then I think you can be more free as you
become successful because you're in a
position where you don't have to worry
about money anymore,
so you have one less thing to think
about and you're ambitious in the sense
of being creative instead of
concentrating on money.
Your mind is not geared on that.
Your mind is weird on the art.
That's how I like to think that I am and
when I'm at my best,
that is where I'm at.
That's my mind frame.
You know?
That's my my point of references that I
think about the,
the creation of the art itself.
That's when I'm at my best.
If I think about money,
I think about like how much is this
going to pay me and is this worth this?
It's not the same motivation,
so it's.
You don't get the same results.
It's not the same passion to it,
but the passion has got to be real.
It's gotta be my comedy the way in my
head,
my motivation is all about whether or
not people enjoy it.
I don't want to do anything that people
don't enjoy.
I want to make sure that everything that
I'm creating,
I'm creating it so other people get
enjoyment out of it and that's the
reward that you get for that one.
Yeah,
as long as you're concentrating on that,
you do no wrong.
As long as you have the dynamic in the
relationship between you and the
audience,
as long as you respect that,
and as long as your relationship to the
creativity is all based on just
producing more stuff,
that's good that people enjoy as long as
you're doing it for that reason,
I don't think you have to worry about,
you know,
money robbing you of your enthusiasm,
but if you were just in it for the money
and just in it for the adulation,
yeah,
you become successful and then all of a
sudden like,
you're not gonna wanna do it anymore.
You're not going to be.
You're not going to be enthusiastic
about it anymore.
Hyena flew equal super aids.
That's what I'm talking about.
We're planning on doing December 20,
first 2012.
Um,
no.
I'm going to stay.
If it's really what people's.
Are you going to go to the pyramids,
man?
If it's really what some people think it
is,
this convergence is technological
convergence.
We're all human beings will interface
with each other where someone creates a
time machine where some huge
technological breakthrough happens.
If that's,
that's what some people think.
December 20,
first 2012 or whatever that shit's
called Hadron collider and that's about
the time it's gonna.
If that's the case,
then it doesn't matter where you are.
Right?
And they should be amongst friends.
Could done nearby.
Maybe Brian and I will do a ustream
that,
but yeah.
Should we commit to a 24 hour?
Let's commit to.
Right now.
We're going to commit to a huge dream
for December,
December
20,
first 2012,
December 20th,
2012 commit so that as the 21st turns
over,
we'll do it at midnight.
Show at night.
We will start at 8:00
eastern,
so that's 11:00
eastern.
I don't care what time it is in England.
You don't count.
Okay.
That's not December 20.
First 2012.
It's all based on fucking America.
Okay.
Because the Mayans and the Americans
were basically on the same calendar sort
of right now.
Kind of really.
I think a different timeline resource in
teaching eatsa is the same as Miami.
Okay.
It's just a little bit below that.
I'm either way,
December 20th,
2012,
2012.
Brian and I are committing right now to
a use dream.
We're going to do it.
Feel strong about that.
Nothing's going to happen.
Maybe.
Maybe not.
It's going to happen.
That is a possibility.
You know,
I think people let them know that
something's going to happen.
We have a friend that likes to believe
in Ufos and psychics and con chem trails
and anything,
anything wacky.
This,
this dude is just jumps on board.
You know,
and I think it's just as possible that
nothing's going to happen as more
possible.
It is possible to.
Something might happen on the day
because everybody's thinking something's
going to happen on that day,
right.
If it's some dude sitting somewhere with
some bombs that made me think that I
think,
you know,
the idea that we're going to force
something to happen by really
concentrating it as,
you know,
as a point of focus.
This one point.
Yeah.
But that's what everyone thought was
going to happen in 2000.
That is true.
But everybody was waiting for the clocks
to break in.
2,000
was a very specific things falling from
the sky.
Stop working,
man.
I stayed home.
I remember I stayed home.
That was one of the first,
um,
first years where I didn't do a new
year's show.
All right.
I think I probably was worried.
It's so weird is that everyone was
really freaked out about that.
And then we had all this built up stress
because of it.
And then just shortly after nine slash
11,
it's like,
then we finally got the release,
all the stress,
like the world's ending.
I just remember being really stressed
out thinking something was going to
happen.
It seems like right after 9:11.
Alright,
let's quit.
Dr Brain's most easily give up.
Brian doesn't.
It doesn't take vitamins.
Yeah.
Two hours.
Two hours and 20 minutes.
I ate a bag of carrots today.
I have a juicer now.
Oh Man.
Well we've dropped down to 425 years.
But that says to me is at least 100
motherfuckers thought we were boring as
shit.
Yeah.
So I think that how Harry is my.
But from one to 10,
how dare you sir.
How dare you.
Big Too to thug.
Um,
from one to 10 my but three,
three or four.
I really could use shaving and trimming.
I was listening to an old Howard stern
broadcasts where they were fined and he
was fine for talking about shaving is,
but you know,
you don't realize how crazy those
fucking regular radio shows are like
what you can and can't do until you hear
something like that.
But it was inspiring and I was thinking
about Truman,
my own bonaire.
But uh,
it could definitely help.
Solar flares are not in our control.
And that's the thing to worry about,
says wrapped or 94,
wrapped in 94 things that solar flares
are you going to do us in for possible?
Man,
nobody fucking gay.
Make Brian cleaned my room for the next
year.
Stream.
That's just my other desk is covered the
shit I,
it's a desk,
but I really use it as a place to just
leave shit.
I'm a slob and have problems as
adrenaline.
Du Du,
Du,
du Du.
What bullshit resolutions will you say
you will keep and won't know?
I don't make resolutions.
She's not a girl because I'm not a
fucking girl.
All right.
And uh,
if I wanted to fix something about
myself,
I would start.
No,
I wouldn't wait.
I always say I'm going to work out more
this year.
I'm going to talk,
I'll get my shit together.
But for the most part I put out as much
energy as I want to put out.
I focus on things as much,
as much as I can while still enjoying
them,
you know,
always dancing around obsession.
That's very important to me.
Whether it's with comedy or anything
else.
And with games,
with anything in my life,
I always have to dance around becoming
obsessed with things.
So for me it's just just enjoy,
just try to be balanced and try to
consciously,
you know,
just try to have a good time to be
positive when I get obsessed with
things,
whether it's about Jujitsu or comedy or
playing games like pool or video games,
I get crazy about things and I don't
like that feeling.
I don't get obsessed with things.
Brian,
you get obsessed with jerking off that?
No.
Hey,
due to how much porn do you have?
I get obsessed with Internet now for
sure was like I constantly want more
information about everything and it just
branches off more and more and more and
make.
I'll be looking at that why,
what,
how applesauce is made,
but then I need to know about how the
apples are grown,
you know,
and just keeps on going and going and
going.
Yeah.
It wasn't that way when you were a kid,
right?
No,
not at all.
I fucking hated reading and I didn't
want to learn anything.
I just wanted to play video games and
around on the grass.
Funny how different when you get older,
your your id
idea of information changes.
Because when I was a kid,
information always med school and Shit,
you have to learn meant boring.
Meant suck.
Right now.
They were all connected together,
but then when it's no longer a
requirement,
then yeah,
you'd be,
you find out what you're actually
interested in.
You pursue those things.
No,
no,
probably just fucking fall asleep on me.
Believe that shit the fuck.
Alright.
My twitter friends.
I think uh,
we're going to answer one more question.
He's fake snoring like the goddamn three
stooges stuff.
Is that mo?
Are you doing mo?
We got to know her way.
It might've been curling maybe,
right?
Uh,
2000,
2012.
Something very subtle may happen that we
don't realize for awhile.
Good Dude.
Dude,
go smoke your aol discs and get off the
internet.
Something subtle is happening right now.
Recognized for awhile.
That's not what 2012 sources be.
If that's what happens,
then 2012 was bullshit.
One hundred percent bullshit.
If the,
if December 20,
first 2012 rolls around and we just go,
nothing,
I don't feel anything,
I don't feel a thing,
then it's bullshit.
One hundred percent.
It's not like,
Oh man,
no,
there's a change.
You just not going to realize it for
awhile.
No,
it's supposed to be Bam.
It's supposed to be open a door.
Here's a new thing.
You know,
I mean if the Internet turned on,
like if there was a day that the
internet turned on,
we all look back and say,
Whoa,
December 10th,
2019 93.
That's when the Internet turned on in
the world changed forever.
If there was like a recognized date,
first of all,
that would be way more important than
fucking Columbus Day.
How about that?
How about we studied Columbus Day and
that dude never even landed in America,
right?
Who was in the Bahamas or raping and
murdering people and Shit.
You know,
and then Columbus Day,
the Internet day is a way bigger day for
American history than fucking Columbus
Day.
If they came out with an Internet day,
that would be important.
But
December 20,
first 2012 has to be like that Internet
day.
It has to be David.
We look back and go,
wow,
that day some shit started off.
That's the day that changed everything.
That's what,
December 20,
first 2012.
It's got to be the,
all the hype behind it.
If it's not that,
then it's bullshit,
you know,
this whole idea that it's the end of an
age.
So it's becoming a,
a new era.
Maybe,
maybe,
possibly.
But to me that could just as easily
happen tomorrow or being.
Why do we assume that the Mayans were
absolutely correct about that?
Even if they were correcting,
recognizing that human beings go in
cycles,
you know,
that's uh,
that's not,
uh,
an an old idea that you guys is a um,
and I believe Hindu idea.
I think it's Hindu or along the same
lines that there's,
there's like stages that humanity goes
for,
goes through and that these stages of
these cycles,
that they're all repeatable,
they just keep happening.
I can a cycle over and over again,
just like how you breathe in,
you breathe out,
humanity rises and falls.
And right now we're supposed to be in
Kali Yoga and this.
It's also supposed to end the same time
around where the Mayans believe that
this,
this age is going to end and the same
time we're terence Mckenna's,
you know,
timewave zero novelty theory,
which a lot of people think is bullshit.
I don't know if it's bullshit or not,
but there was a guy named terrence
Mckenna that had this crazy mathematical
algorithm designed track time and it was
based off the teaching.
And the idea was that you could apply
this to past events and show that all
human innovation,
that progress in humanity is all like
you could chart it on a graph that it's
all like going along a certain direction
and that eventually was going to reach a
point of what he called ultimate
novelty.
And the idea of ultimate novelty would
be something that we would figure out or
do like create a time machine or
something like that.
That would literally change everything
as we know it.
You know?
And that Ray Kurtzweil calls it the
singularity.
You know that there's a bunch of
different scientists that believe we're
moving towards this convergence,
this one big invention,
and they tie that into the mind thing
that December 20,
first 2012 is exactly the same as the
ending point for ultimate novelty for
timewave zero,
and that Terence Mckenna arrived at that
time.
Completely independent of the Mayan
calendar.
I don't know if it's bullshit.
You don't have really studied at either.
Right?
Did he tell you about this whole thing
and he just programmed this logic around
that date?
It's possible.
It didn't seem like he was a liar
though.
I mean,
he might've been kind of a hippie
and they're.
They're all lies.
They all want the money so they could
buy weed,
fucking patrolling.
Maybe we don't know if it was a.
What we do know is this fucking thing
has been going on for two hours and 30
minutes and that's it.
It's over.
Religious Gentleman.
Brian and I are going to get something
to eat and we're going to sign out.
We're going to try to do this every week
now.
Two hours every week.
Two hours,
two hours and a half,
right?
Two hours is not so good,
but,
or two hours in the half is not so good.
Two hours to perfect by now.
But uh,
we appreciate all 400 and fucking
whatever.
Have you.
We had 500 people at one point in time.
It's like a comedy club and as soon as
we,
uh,
it gets more Internet in here,
we're going to start triple broadcasting
it on both Justin TV
and all the other ones.
I will,
we'll put it on three and St.
so we'll give you different angles to,
to be a fucking Weirdo,
you know?
Can we get better,
bigger heads up a couple of days.
Yes.
My friend Jim Dirksen did know,
did Erik Didriksen Cim?
Didrikson yeah,
we'll,
uh,
we'll definitely get more advanced time.
We just figured it out yesterday.
We're going to do,
and then I put it up and said we're
going to do it in a couple hours,
but um,
what we'll do next time is what we're
eventually going to do is have a
specific time we start at every week.
That sounds like a Wednesday.
Yeah,
Wednesday afternoons.
you're right.
Because even if we go on the road for
comedy,
we don't leave until Thursday usually.
So we'll do,
we'll try to do a Tuesday or a Wednesday
and that's,
we'll do,
we'll do like late afternoon in La,
like 3:00
is perfect somewhere around that line
and we'll do it on a regular basis.
So,
um,
this week I'm at the House of Blues on,
Saturday.
Yeah.
Saturday night.
The house Friday night,
the House of Blues this Friday in Vegas.
That's January first.
There's still tickets available for that
New Year's Eve in melrose at the Improv
in Hollywood on a Thursday night.
It's sold out.
So that's sold out,
but there's still some tickets available
for the house of Blues.
So if you're going to be in Vegas,
um,
Brian's not common unless he wants to,
wants to change his mind.
Vegas on New Year's Day just seems like
that dried puke everywhere.
It's hell it August.
Um,
but,
uh,
New Year's Eve,
like I said,
it's all sold out.
Sorry,
but a new year's day,
January first the house of blues at
Mandalay Bay and it'd be Joey Diaz and
Arash fear far doesn't kill himself for
them.
Hopefully won't.
So,
uh,
thank you very much everybody.
Thanks for tuning into this and,
uh,
we'll see you next week.
We're going to do this every week.
Okay,
bitches.
All right,
thanks.
Stop recording.