So I was looking at this video today of a,
this dude jumping this cliff and
his bike like Jamie was showing.
Uh, this one guy who does this on,
on buildings, he does it like he,
he rides his bike on the
ledges of buildings and shit
and jumps from building to
building and I was watching this other
guy jumped as cliff with his bike,
like literally jumps over one side of
the cliff and lands onto the other.
It's fucking like you're watching the
whole thing. You Go, Jesus Christ,
if he falls, he's daddy's fucking
debt. That shit's totally legal,
right?
It's like we were talking about people
thinking that MMA is barbaric and it
should be illegal. Like where should
be, you'd be allowed to take your risks.
Look at this fucking guy.
This guy's crazy dude.
Look at this shit hopping from
building the building. I mean,
he's riding a bike on the edges of
these buildings. This is fucking insane.
And this guy's got just ridiculous
control with his bicycle. I mean,
should this be legal? I know it seems
like he's doing okay. He was fine.
But if he fucks up like you know about
that Chinese dude that just died? No,
he was a one of those youtube guys
who would take videos of him. Oh,
I heard top of skyscrapers and shit and
he fell. He fell to his death down. Yeah.
Dude,
it looks ugly to look scary.
Like he was trying to call
himself up and he could,
and then you see his hands slip
and you realize that's a wrap son.
Oh 600 feet.
I had a friend who was training to be a
base jumper and there's things you gotta
do. You know, so many regular
skydiving jumps. You gotta,
you gotta master skydiving and
just that before you get into,
and then there's things you have to do.
There's like a less than halfway through,
too many people died in the scene.
Or this person just stepped back and said,
you know what?
Maybe because it's not that uncommon
where these crazy base jumpers die or
almost die, right? Yeah.
There's a lot of videos. There's
one, I saw that it was awful.
This Russian guy jumps off the top of
this building and this parachute doesn't
open up in time and he bounces off the
ground and you, you hear him screaming,
Oh, you just go, how about that
one guys? What do they call that?
They don't call it base jumping, but
they're like flying squirrels. Yeah.
Does that my friend Andy's
the world record holder.
Andy stumps the world record holder.
He flew, what was it, 18 miles?
I think he covered 18 miles. Is
it? It's a flying wing suit. Yeah.
But there's one guy that's super famous
for doing it too and he was supposed to
go through,
you know they go down cans and he went
between two rocks and like his leg,
one of the yeah. And then like fucked
him. He didn't die though, which is crazy.
Well you know the one guy that did
died on the golden gate bridge,
do you ever see that one?
He slammed right into the bridge
while people were watching him.
He was supposed to go between the wires.
Oh,
hit the bridge and she jumped
off the plane. Crazier. Like
he hit it like,
like a bullet.
Nobody jumped off a plane and then when
flying down and try to go through that,
I don't know where it jumped off of.
I don't know if he jumped off of a
plane or jumped off of another bridge.
I don't know what he did,
but when he was trying to do it,
he literally slammed right into the
bridge and it sounds like a crazy car
accident. Like Bang. How long ago
was that? No, a few years back.
This is all short hair. It give
us some volume, Jamie. Yeah,
it wasn't Golden Gate Bridge San
Francisco, which it's horrible dude.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Who's that in that pair of shoes?
It's another guy he was there was,
he was flying with another guy.
Oh my God.
Awesome
dude.
Fuck.
It sounded like there was a bunch of
people they're watching too. We're too,
but this is that should you
will be allowed to do that.
I don't think you should be able to tell
someone they can't do something right
and the why should you
be able to? Why? What if?
Yeah.
What if they just start influencing so
many young kids to do it and there's all
these kids dying all over the place.
Then do you make any legal?
Oh man,
that's a good question.
Well then do you make war legal?
You can't do that,
right? How are we supposed
to eat? Like what sport?
When does it become too dangerous?
I go, what? Like soccer people,
apparently some of them get brain
damage from heading the ball.
Apparently you're not supposed
to head things like that.
And they do it all the time.
At practice.
They start developing a
traumatic brain injuries.
They get CTE from
headbutting a ball to wheat.
So that may be more dangerous
than wrestling. Yup.
You know, but there's no way, I mean,
people talk about trying to make
it illegal because it's barbaric.
There's no way you're going to make
MMA illegal. It's too late for that.
I think so too.
But it's interesting when people
start rallying for more regulation,
for people's behavior. It's voluntary
behavior. You, what's the latest?
Is there some new thing?
No,
just read some article or it was
just something on MMA being barbaric.
And I'm like, it's, yeah, it is.
It's a lot of things are, you know,
we like a lot of things that
are fucking super dangerous and,
but there's something about
like agreed upon violence.
Like you train for six weeks,
he trains for six weeks.
You both get into a cage together and
we all watch it. Screaming monkeys. Oh,
we know that in football. Some guys
get Lou Gehrig's disease, right?
Sure. I mean, Steve Smith
member, the guy from the Raiders,
he was on an HBO special. Uh, I
think it all kinds of brain issues.
Has that happened in MMA? Not
like that. I don't think. Not yet.
But you've got to think of the long
history of football. The football.
You're dealing with guys who played in
the fifties and sixties yeah. Right. Yeah.
This guy was played on the
Raiders like in the early or
Steve Smith I think was,
do you guys like that?
Right.
We have Gary Goodrich fought in
the UFC in 93 or 94 I remember.
He doesn't have Lou Gehrig's.
Nobody's got some serious CTE.
He's been real open about it. Does
a lot of interviews. About it.
It's on bunch of medication he's had
actually the real damage came when he
started doing k one.
Hell yeah. Yeah. Sorry.
Strike kickbox and,
but you know, big can be
surprised though. I mean,
no big daddy was in super fucking
wars. Yeah. Remember he got headcount.
I don't mean by about Gary Goodrich,
I'm mean about everybody.
Like the fact that you don't have,
you have,
you fight for 10 years and you don't come
out with some significant brain damage.
You're fucking lucky.
You're in a solo where your brain
is the target you're trying to fit.
Everyone's trying to figure out ways.
They're lifting weights.
They're doing kettle bells so that
they could hit your brain even harder.
They're learning technique so that
it's perfect so that when it hits your
fucking brain, it just knocks you
the fuck out. You know? It's crazy.
That's the sport that is this board.
So no one should be surprised.
You can't be,
but you can't be surprised like,
you know what was that guy's name?
Tony Conigliaro.
Is that what the guy that
got hit with a baseball?
The Guy got hit with a pitch
when I was in high school.
I think in Boston I was still,
I still like baseball like you know I
found taekwondo because of baseball.
Went to a baseball game and a pass by
the taekwondo studio cause the line for
the ti was a really long to get
on the public transportation.
So he said let's just
go up there and watch.
And so we walked up the stairs and this
Guy John leaves a US national hit light
heavyweight champion was kicking the
back and he was kicking the back so hard.
I was like Holy Shit,
I want to figure out how to do that.
That's a movie right there, dude. I was
walking up to standards on, I heard plump,
Chink,
chink was the chains of the bag just
chink cause he had this hundred and 50
pound bags flying through the air.
Dude.
I came up and I watched him
kick that thing and I was like,
I got to learn how to do
that. Like that. It's crazy.
How the fuck could he do that?
But the guy who was famous
in Boston from when,
I remember when I was in high school,
it was this Guy Tony,
see Tony Conigliaro when he was hit
with a pitch and became like, you know,
uh,
disabled,
he got hit in the head in 1967 I guess.
There it goes.
Revere native was a rising star with
the red sox. So I'm way later than this.
So I must've been just here
and everybody talk about it.
But you know,
that can happen.
Your story about the first time,
you know,
considering how extraordinary
your sidekicks are,
that story is so strong.
It's like where did that shit come from?
It can be from the instruction for sure.
Tell you that,
that story, how crazy that story.
You're going to a baseball game
and you hear these cluck cluck or you,
you end up going to a taekwondo school
because of why w why didn't you go to the
baseball game again while we went to
the baseball game on your way home?
Everybody leaves the Fenway Park. So
the line for the train was fucking huge.
It's everybody's getting on the
t. So we were kids. You know,
it was like just hanging out. I, yeah, I
couldn't drive back then. I was like 14,
almost 50 seats. Taekwondo school.
Yeah, I knew it was there. Cause a,
I'd always looked at martial arts schools
because I wanted to go to one for a
long time, but I looked at him
from the yellow pages. It's like,
who has the biggest ad?
Must be a big ad in the
yellow pages. I was like, oh,
that must be the spot man. That's going
to be the spa. And I was a kid, um,
right next to our neighborhood.
Mcdonald's was a karate studio and man,
I was as poor as poor can be.
I mean we didn't have any money so,
but on Fridays when my mom would get
paid, we'd go to, we'd go to Mcdonald's.
That was our, that was like, we're
celebrating. Thank God it's Friday.
She got $150 check.
She's taking her kids to Mcdonald's
and every time we went to Mcdonald's,
I'd always look over at that karate
studio and just thinking, man,
I wish I was rich.
Jesus.
I just wanted to do karate.
I remember one time,
it was just like a scary studio at in
the end. It looked cool. It was right.
It was in Santa Ana on
Bristol and 17 right there.
It may still be there. I drove by the
other day. Didn't drive by that. That uh,
tell the story about how your
instructor pretended he went to China.
I don't want to bust them out. This is a
very, this podcast is too big for that.
Can I do it without saying his
name? Oh yeah. Don't say as,
I didn't want to say his name.
Don't say his name. You know,
I don't want to bring it. Okay. Hey
man, back in the day. Does the people,
did you know, there's a lot of guys
that got by with some fake martial arts.
They really did.
There was a lot of fake stuff out there
and that's why I think to this day,
like if I hadn't walked up those stairs,
I could have went to some bullshit school.
I took karate for like one lesson or
maybe two at the most before that at Joe
Esposito is karate academy, which is a
really good spot. It was in my city too,
but there was no good public
transportation methods.
It was too hard to get to,
hard to get when you're 1314 yeah,
it was 14 so then a year later is when
I wind up walking up those stairs and
here in that bag going could shrink.
That's a movie right there.
That's a cartoon that he was
training for the world championships.
He was training,
he was a national champion at the time,
so he and he was changing for the
World Cup where he took bronze,
so he was like top of his game. This Guy
John Lee, he taught me a lot of shit too.
He taught me a lot like a black guy,
big tall,
thin black guy who wound up,
he wasn't in a substance abuse problem.
He was a national taekwondo champion.
He was a bad motherfucker. Dude,
he kicked so hard,
but he wasn't the head
instructor at the school.
It was a Korean in Korean dude.
Actual career and an American dude named
Michael O'malley who spent the most
time with me.
He spent the most time with,
who was the main instructor
of the create hunt. Kim,
the Korean guy who was trained, he was
trained about General Che Young Yee,
who's the founder of Taekwondo in Korea.
So he was like one of a very
small elite groups like um,
like Henzel Gracie in a way. Yeah.
But what the differences they,
they emphasized a power style.
Whereas as it got more
and more competitive,
guys realized with that chest protector
on the best style for scoring.
He's like really quick kicks that don't
have as much power but you score and you
win tournaments like that.
And so the,
the game changed and the kicks changed
because like to throw a kick that's hard,
you have to plant yourself and it
does take a little bit more time.
It takes a little bit more time.
So it's better to spend more time
on just getting points. Yeah. The,
in a lot of the taekwondo tournament's
cause those guys were really good and
they knew how to play that game so well.
They were so fast with their legs
but then would just touch you.
They would just stop, stop. And some
guys we kick harder than others,
but the whole hard style of the early
taekwondo was kinda missing in a lot of
their approaches because
they were just trying to win.
And if you really dug in
and tried to kick hard,
a lot of times those
guys without score you,
you know you're dealing with like
really fast, really skillful guys.
But then when you apply that to fighting,
fighting the,
the real problem is like in fighting,
fighting,
you have to land hard shit cause people
are not just going to play taekwondo
with you.
They're going to try to take you down.
They're going to try to kick your legs,
they're going to try
to do a bunch of shits.
All that flippy flip he shit
that flippy flip his shit.
You got to make a hard transition. Whereas
like Moy, Thai guys, Moy Thai guys,
they'd fucking digging roots.
Everything's digging their
fucking drive in, in everything.
Everything they're trying
to blast you with. You know,
they're doing it skillfully.
But there's emphasis on power through the
whole thing. So when they would fight,
if a taekwondo guy fought a Moy Thai
guy and it's happened many times,
taekwondo guys are fucked.
They're fucked.
They just get their legs kicked
out from under this can't last.
The same thing with leg locks in Jujitsu,
it's the same thing as it is.
It's attacking the leg.
Cause when,
when everything is legal and
Jujitsu and everything's legal, man,
legs become like the most important
thing because you don't have to sweep,
you know,
if chokes are the most important thing,
you've got to do a lot
of shit before he could.
You've got to pass this guys first.
You've got to sweep them,
then you got to pass the guard.
Then you got to get us back.
You got to do so much shit before he can
get into his neck. A lot of the times,
most of the times we'd leg locks.
You don't need to do any of that shit.
You just need to jump right on them.
They're right there.
You don't ever need to sweep anybody.
You don't ever need to
pass anybody's guard.
You could just go legs 100% and roll
with a pure Jujitsu guy and wreck them.
You could do that. Yeah. That happens
all the time. The legs, the leg game,
when everything is legal, the
lead game, that's the first fight.
The first fight you have to do,
whether you like it or not,
you have to deal with it.
If you want the neck, okay,
you're gonna have to deal with
this leg war right now cause it,
you can't get to the neck
unless you could deal with that.
You're going to go around the forest,
the leg locks.
Are you going to go fucking
right through? You know, so,
but you take leg locks out of the game,
make them illegal.
Then it becomes a whole different sport.
It's totally different.
So it's exactly what you're talking
about with the power shots and the point
shots. Yeah. It's exactly
what we're talking about.
Words like the style of MMA now is
almost always attacking the legs.
Everybody attacks the legs. Did you see
those Angeles L'oreal? Yeah. Oh yeah.
That was dos.
Anjos is for real.
It is for real.
Striking is better than ever.
Who the fuck ever did that to Robbie
Lawler who just outclassed Robbie Lawler?
Who the fuck did that? Nobody ever did
that. He's drawn. It's Tommy La la.
They're never really at the end.
He kind of showed that his legs were,
were done right at the very end.
I was kind of wobbling fucking animal.
He took it the whole way.
I mean you could see but there's a
guy could just sailing and he was,
he kind of like seals.
He wasn't moving well and he was
definitely more stationary. Yeah,
he was just taken out his leg and it
that, that low leg kick. Isn't it crazy?
I was just talking to somebody crazy that
did more people down the strategize to
use that light to wear down the legs.
You would think in so many fights.
It's never like one of the
main strategies. It's sink.
That low leg kick is changing the game.
I really do remember when Steve Bay
fought Jr and his leg swole up like a
fucking balloon, like almost immediately
Uriah faber, Fahd, Jimmy Rivera,
Jimmy Rivera fucked them up so that more
and more people don't focus on that.
I think they're doing it more and
more now, man. I think, but it's,
it's crazy as it's pretty recent.
I credit it to Benson. Henderson.
Henderson was like the
first guy I ever saw do it.
He started doing it like really
regularly and I was like, hmm.
Like I don't like really high level
guys like world championship liver guys.
Benson Henderson was the first guy to do
it. I was like, oh, I like that. That's a,
it's a fuck. And I talked to
Duke roof is about, he's like,
it's just taking the legs out. No lower
leg kicks. Lower like hitting the shins.
Everybody's, they're attacking the
inside of your leg like in your calf,
your lower calf and the outside.
Devastating in flux.
The nerves up like your legs give out.
You see a re Uriah is fight
with with Jimmy Rivera.
Rivera just constantly chopped at that
leg and your rise leg became like almost
useless.
He can't walk on it.
I was just talking about straight leg
kicks to the Oh, that too. For sure.
Just the regular old kick right above
the knee. Right. Well, you know why?
Here's another thing too, man.
Those Bruce Lee kicks those. Uh,
I'm a bleak kicks that a lot of
guys are using. You know those,
those are fucking legit man.
They blow your knees out.
I mean they slam into your thigh and they
blow your fucking knees out and he did.
A lot of people don't like it.
They think it's nasty, but look,
you're trying to kill each other with your
bones. Pets, getting your naf flowing.
Why that would come up.
When do they're trying to do like flying
knees like those does Honjo that double
flying knees or what do you call those?
A skip needs are flying knee. Yeah,
he goes, he uses that first
need to propel that second meet
Pam. He also gets blended twice.
You have to block that first knee.
You've got to react to that first, Nene.
It helps a second knee get in there. Yeah,
you see that knee coming at you,
you're gonna,
you're gonna react and that second knees
and that should be something that you'd
see way more often.
That should be an,
if you're trying to get in the UFC and
you're not adding as many different
weapons con, you can't add them
all at once. So you take the, the,
the most important ones,
your one two and your leg kick and
maybe a head kick and then you slowly,
obviously you wouldn't, you would
just add them, but you should be,
if you're making a living in
the UFC or that's your goal,
you should be always working on adding a
new strike to the mix and use something
that u mass or something on the,
and this camp, we're going to focus.
You've got to always be so hard to get
really good at one thing while you're
doing everything.
You know,
you got to kind of do focus on the
basics and then do 20 minutes a week or
you're just working on and over
time over time will fly in.
And if you just spend 20 minutes
a week on a new technique,
it's not,
it's going to within six months it's going
to be something that you've mastered.
Maybe a year. If you're consistent with
it, you could just keep doing that.
You can just keep adding
another one at another one.
Especially with all that's
available with striking.
It seems like the days of just going
out there boxing and throwing a leg kick
every now and then, like that's only
going to get you so that that's like,
it's not,
um,
it doesn't seem like it would be the
smart thing to do to not constantly add
weapons like right.
I W I 100% agree with you and I,
I always say like boil it down to the,
what's the best in each genre. And
arguably one of the best striking arts,
if not the best, is Thai boxing. Right?
Moitai and you don't see anybody
just winning Moitai with boxing.
They don't just go over there and just
box. It'll fucking, nobody does that.
They go over there and you you tie box.
Yeah. They kicked each other. They elbow.
They use the clench.
They throw elbows.
They're not trying to like do on Mike
Tyson and there they get their legs
chopped out from under him.
Yeah.
If both guys know how to box the guy
who knows how to box and kick your legs,
it's going to have a big advantage.
Yes. I mean it's just, it's, I don't,
I don't think there's hardly anybody does.
Going over to Thailand and just trying
to box more tie fighters. It's terrible
and there's so much more
to that is what I'm saying.
Turn inside that that if you're
really good at just really good,
it's so good that you're training camp
has to address it and use valuable time
to address and train against that.
You already got 'em off balance.
Like when I was in George Satarah plus
his corner when he fought Dennis Seaver,
that was a part of the training camp.
We had a deal with Dennis
Seavers turning sidekick.
He was laying people out with that
turning side kick. He's done it.
He's still to this day, if he can
still throw it and if he lands it,
you're probably going to get knocked out.
It's probably one of the best,
so that throws,
that draws your opponent's game off.
He's got to constantly worry about that
instead of not having to worry about
that. If, if I, Dennis Cbre
had all the rest of the skills,
but you just deleted that
turn inside sidekick,
then you wouldn't really
have to focus on that much.
You can focus more on yourself and your
game plan and how you're going to impose
your game plan. Like fuck
really what he's, he's doing.
But when you have something real dangerous
like that, like with Edson Barboza,
he's got that turning that that spinning
wheel kick that he's knocked out a few
people with. Right. At least to do first.
We'll check knock out ever in the UFC.
How many does he have? At least two
or three, right? A Capo, I don't know.
He's got the first guy ever in the UFC
also. That has to stoppages by leg kicks.
Yeah,
that's you got to watch.
You got that throws your whole game off
when you got to worry about him throwing
some Grand Slam strike at
Chez kicks are so scary.
He's the fastest kicker I've ever
seen as far as the switch kick it.
Never seen a guy throw a switch.
Kick. Look, it's in Barboza.
It just gets in there so fast. You're
like, what the fuck man? Yeah, yeah.
That he's fighting their Madoff.
Holy Shit.
That's going to be a crazy number 30th
you should just going crazy wanting to
come to that one. Vegas. Come see
that you're alive. It's a tough,
it's a tough one. Tough one. You've got a
family. It's, it's how you can't just go,
hey, I'm going to go to Vegas
with my buddies. You know, it's,
it's a different life. You
know that fight is, I love it.
If I never go to Vegas ever again, I
wouldn't give up. You don't. I don't.
I've been so much that I'm good for the
rest of my life. Seriously. I really am.
I think you'd want to go
back every now and again,
just going to do when you feel that
we're going to do an Ebi in Vegas, uh,
May 5th in Vegas and is it may
fit before the UFC? Uh, no,
it's on a Saturday night. I Dunno if
there's not a UFC on the same day, but um,
yeah. Uh, it's gonna be,
um, we're going to have, uh,
a combat Jujitsu match between
Gordon Ryan and Vinny. Micah last,
Holy Shit. Oh my God, that's crazy. Yeah,
we don't,
we don't normally do super fights and
Ebi Cause I take all the purse money that
we have available in our budget
and we put it towards the winner.
The winner take all in the tournament.
We don't have extra money for
x additional super fights,
but this one we had to figure
out a way to make it happen.
It's going to be nuts to Gordon Ryan
against Vinny Maga last two combat g g g g
two might be the next big thing.
It really could be the next big thing
because it's as far as like preparation,
Jujitsu, preparation for MMA without
kicking, punching and Nina standing up.
It's the best preparation for sure.
There's a bunch of different
ways to look at it. Uh, um,
an MMA purists might say, what the
fuck is this combat Jujitsu? It slaps,
we'll just watch MMA. Like
what's the point? You know,
people can say that easily,
but the way I look at it,
it's,
it's nothing is as good as the
UFC. The UFC, that's the past.
There's nothing better than the UFC,
but there are Jujitsu fanatics that they
just want to see Jujitsu in the UFC.
They're really not that
into a kickboxing match.
If you know junior dos Santos fights Cain
Velasquez and it's a kickboxing match,
great. That'd be an all time great
match to watch. But there's a,
there's a group of Jujitsu fanatics
that they're just, that's right.
They just want to watch the Jujitsu,
but with the strikes and that's the old
in MMA is the only place where you could
watch and a major Jitsu.
It's a totally different style.
When you watch just pure Jujitsu,
that's not, I'm a manage it.
So there's nothing to do with them.
And my teacher,
well I understand is, is if people that
don't do Jujitsu to listen to this,
like what are they talking about?
There's places where you're
gone for a submission,
but someone could easily hit you in
your face and it makes the move kind of
unrealistic.
There's a lot of times had
guys do unrealistic things
and really you could just
be smacking him in the face and they
would have to stop and protect themselves.
When you're doing Jujitsu without strikes,
it's just pure Jujitsu.
You get into a lot of positions that,
uh,
that would be dangerous in if
strikes were allowed. So, uh,
which is fine, you know, Jujitsu, I'd
love submission. Alejandra too. I need to,
and it's just a different thing. It's
just, you need to understand what it is.
I mean, it doesn't mean that you
shouldn't do that move if it's,
that's the most effective
move in though that rule set.
But there's a beautiful place for combat.
Jujitsu
luck is now. We could, we
could watch Jujitsu fanatics.
It's just for Jujitsu freaks.
We could watch MMA,
Jujitsu and it's just pure MMA,
Jujitsu. We don't have to sit there.
The striking because we and Anna Mae,
if the fight gets boring on the ground,
we have standups in combat Jujitsu after
two minute standing we have get down,
we get them down. Just like in
wrestling. Yeah, you get them down.
It's like after two minutes,
no one,
cause if we had a 10
minute or 15 minute combat,
you get to match and they were just
standing in wrestling the whole time.
That matches shit. It's garbage that
match. Nobody wants to see that.
Nobody was just wrestling trying
to wrestle for for 10 minutes.
So after two minutes as horn sounds,
a coin gets tossed and if you lose,
if you won the coin toss,
you get to decide top or
bottom and we start and sit up.
Garlic Butterfly Guard
would double under hooks.
You get top or bottom in that person and
then we start right there and then if
they stand up again, two
minute clock, that's a new
thing to me to get down cloud.
Yeah. When did that start?
Uh, we did that. I like it.
We did that right at the combat digital
worlds about a month ago because that
would ruin the shot. I just, I constantly
am thinking of ways to, to ruin the show.
Like how can I ruin it?
Of course if they just stand up and
wrestle the whole time and that's going to
happen in combat you'd get so they're
not going to pull guard as much as in sub
only people are pulling guard
like all over the place.
It's like people are just tumbling and
then there's no strikes and they're all
over.
They're all read each other's legs and
they're just pulling guard and flipping
and I'll do an all this stuff that
when their strikes, when strikes, boom.
It just, we get into
full garden now. Yeah.
And we get out of the mouth becomes very
important mountain as you could win a
million EBS and never mount a guy.
You know,
you could just be a leg lock
financing. Um, you could um,
uh,
you don't have like full guard
is the Wagner Rocia and um,
uh, Nathan Orchard. Yes. Yes. That
was combat digit two worlds. One,
the winner of the lightweight
bracket was Vagner Rocha.
He beat Nathan Orchard in the finals.
Was he the only guy to stop somebody?
That was the first TKL yes,
he mounted Nathan Orchard and,
and a referee,
Mike Bell Trans Stop the action.
It was a good stoppage to Wagner's
a very accomplished MMA fighter. So,
so again, my point with them
in Jujitsu without strikes,
full guard,
totally unnecessary.
You could win Abu Dhabi 10 years in a
row and never put anybody in your full
guard.
If you never want to play full guard
ever in regular Jujitsu without strikes,
you never have to play full.
You just open up your legs and you're
just get into some z or some kind of
spiraled Delahey eve or whatever. You
never, it's totally optional. You don't,
most people don't even bother
with it. Chrome Gracie, he
does. He loves full guard.
You know, whether their strikes or
not, that's why it's full guard.
And MMA is a very effective because he
always played full guard and his regular
Jujitsu without grappling.
So what happens with Jujitsu as you add
strikes in an NDA match or in a combat,
you get to match. It's the same
thing when strikes are added.
Now full guard becomes
the most important guard.
It was the least important
guard in grappling.
Now it becomes the most important guard.
So if you weren't playing full guard
when you were doing Jujitsu without the
strikes, and now you're doing Jujitsu
with the strikes, guess what? That's,
that's the guard's going to
be the most important one.
When a guy could smack your head. Yeah.
Control posture. Pull guard. Yes. Yeah.
So control posture. And again, in sub
only, you don't ever have to mount ever.
You never have to pass the guard.
But in combat Jujitsu now the mount
becomes super powerful because now you can
mountain strike in sub only a few
mountain. You can't strike. You know, you,
I like mounting and sub all
that, but you don't have to, uh,
you can get cotton leg locks if the guy
has a good mount escape right into leg
locks.
That's what usually happens.
Most leg lock masters are very good at
letting dude's mount them and then they
buck. I'm often right when they
escape, they're already on the legs.
A lot of leg lockers do that and you know,
but when their strikes,
you're going to let a dude mountain
you now, now that he could,
he gets in a strike.
You now it's a big difference.
Now the mount from Jujitsu with no
strikes to Jujitsu would strikes calm Ed
Jujitsu. The mount just turns
into this monster. Well it does,
but what's really interesting
is only allowing slaps.
Think about how much more of
a monster palms darn slapping,
hitting. I tell her, but her
hitting hard. Right. Striking.
What else going to say is you're
not allowing your elbows. No.
Like if you allowed elbows, yeah.
Then it's exactly how. Yeah,
pretty much I refer a lot.
Depends on,
depends on what kind of
garden we're dealing with.
It depends on who's in the guard.
I mean,
but like if you allowed the back to
be taken and you allow the elbows,
would you go to what we've always said,
you said this a long time
ago that if you had elbows,
elbows are allowed to
the back of the head.
They would change the whole back mouth.
You ain't nobody going
for real nick and jobs.
You would just get the back and
just elbow the shit out of there.
The back of their head
and the fights over.
That's what was happening early in
annonay before they outlawed those elbows.
They used to be legal for like a
couple of years. You remember? Um,
the world combat, whatever the fuck it
was where Henzel Gracie fought that guy.
What is his name? The judo guy,
I want to say spiker. Yes. Yes.
Something's spiking.
Spiker judo guy had called him in his
hotel room all through the middle of the
night, fucked with him, and, and he got
so pissed that when he choked the guy out,
he a smashed him in the back of the
head and then stepped on his neck as he
walked off. He took it. He didn't
choke him out. He took his back. Right.
He tapped him with strikes, didn't he?
Or did he choke him? I don't remember.
We smashed him.
I'm not sure how he finished them,
but I do remember him standing up and
stepping on his neck. It's stomped on it.
See if you can find that video. You got
the video of the stoppage is horrific.
But this is the perfect example of how
effective elbows to the back of the head
are once you take the back mount.
So like part of me, I said, yeah,
quick Jan's. I was a
bad mother fucker, dude.
People forget he's still down and throw
down. Fuck yeah. You guys look at that.
Look at this back mount and then boom,
oh yeah. Oh, send any choke.
So he did get the choke,
those fucking shots where those elbows,
that's he's tapping
right there in Hensville.
Keeps holding onto him even after
he checked in with the Geek. Yeah.
And they'll watch it, gets off of
them and steps on his neck. And so
that guy is fucked up. And
that's from those elbows, man.
That position changes radically look
and he's trying to pick them up.
It's Angelo just rolls them over
onto her back. Oh, that is hilarious,
man. That was a big mistake
when an ag, oh, huge mistake.
We're in a g with a guy like Hanzo,
you know,
control thing and you don't have
it and he doesn't ever get on. Why?
Silly idea becomes even more.
It's easier to get rear naked choke
says we're allowing, you know,
you got gotta guys back. He could
palm side of their head. Well,
it's all sorts of the CIATTI. Like if you
have elbows to the body, remember when,
um, rampage stopped chocolate
dealt with l elbows to the body.
People forget about that and pride that
most of the body it got really knows how
to throw an elbow that's nasty. You
know what I mean? Combat Jujitsu,
you're opening up the door, what you're
doing, it's like you're up this door
to letting Jujitsu guys understand like
the where the positions were there.
Be Vulnerable.
Yeah,
but that's going to take the kind of
damage that they would in an MMA fight.
Exactly. Exactly. A great, great pathway.
It's a few things on, on a
few different levels. It's,
it's great for grapplers whether they're
wrestlers or Jujitsu players to get
into if they're aspiring
to be an MMA fighter. Yeah.
Also guys that have done 30 40
fights and they're like, dude,
this is just too brutal
guys coming out of MMA.
It's a great place for them
because generally the, you know,
before combat Jujitsu,
all a MMA fighter had to retire too
if you want her to keep competing in
grappling is like sub
only or the points game.
And if you're not working on
that every day, you know the,
the last 10 years that we're working
on striking most of their time and,
and the purest,
like the pure sub only guy's leg lock
guys and the pure points players,
they're working on that every
day to win those styles, whether,
whether it's to win the points
tournaments or the sub only tournaments,
those that the athletes that
are winning those titles,
they'll work on everyday.
So when an MMA fighter retires,
he's not going to really want to go
into sub bawling. He's like, dude,
I'm just so far behind. They don't want
to do it. But now with combat Jujitsu,
99.9% of the people that flooded me with,
I got a long list of people that
want to be in combat Jujitsu.
They're all MMA fighters,
I'm sure. No walking,
no pure Jujitsu guys. Only
one, only one, only one.
And as Benetti, he's my brown belt from
a 10 plan of San Diego. He's, he was,
he trained with Denny at first,
then he started training with
Gio and boogie down in San Diego.
He's a brown belt. He, he had a combat
Jujitsu match with Wilson Hayes,
combat Jujitsu world,
and Ben at,
he probably has that top two
guards in the world. Wow.
Or the enzyme if you end up in, ended
up in his full guard. It's a wrap.
He does a Hindu low need plays,
rubber guard way different than me.
We have totally different
styles of rubber guard.
It all starts off with either like
a meat hook or a mission control,
but from there everyone's going,
it's so vast now and he does
a leg in guillotine here.
The,
and I've seen it in do low team.
It's the craziest.
There's only like two grabbing.
They were like four guys on the planet
that could do this. It's, it's incredible.
It's like it's a s.
How was he grabbing it?
That's a good question. You know
what I mean? I've never done it.
I know how to do it,
but I've never actually,
I don't have the flexibility for
people think that I'm hilarious.
People think that I'm super flexible.
I'm like, I'm not being flexible. I just,
I'm pretty flexible, but I'm not
that flexible. I just use it a lot.
So it appears that I'm really
flexible because I'm always using it,
but a lot of people can do what I
do in way, in way beyond as well.
And Bennati his
flexibility's insane and he,
he had a single match with them.
Wilson Hayes put him in his guard and
he tapped him with the dead orchard.
You know,
I have a PR problem with people when
it comes to the subject of flexibility
because I feel like there's
this conversation that
people have when it comes to
flexibility.
They say you could only get so flexible.
Like some people just don't take
it. So, but that's not true.
I don't agree with it either.
I think there's, there's,
there's like attention and focus to
stretching and some people just don't want
to give.
What I want to know though is to
get to the contortionists level.
Can anybody get to the contortion style?
Can you train someone to do those crazy?
You know when people like they bend
their back all the way back and they get
into like a scorpion trying
to suck your own Dick
maybe.
Well,
you got to bring up,
I saw a video whatsoever.
I did that.
But you don't want to talking about
working towards your host, can you,
can anybody trained to be a contortionist?
That's what I want to know.
I'd like to see like before and after
type like vlogs but get Joey Diaz on it.
I don't know about being a contortion is,
I don't know that
everyone can go that far,
but all you need to play rubber guard is
to get into full lotus and anybody can
do that unless you have like metal
plates in your hips or something.
Uh,
contortionists are skilled at scratch,
stretching their bodies
in a different shape.
It's mostly due to their spinal
flexibility and strength.
You may think that you need to be born
flexible or double jointed to become a
good, it's, but in fact with
enough practice and stretching,
you can learn basic contortion movements.
I feel like stretching is one of those
things where people just aren't willing
to dig in and really like feel that,
that ah, that like borderline edge
every day. They don't like that feeling.
It hurts. It's uncomfortable. Like certain
stretches, like it's hard to breathe.
Like we knew hamstring stretches. It's
like it's hard to breathe, you know,
but you know, some, I think
that everyone is born flexible,
like at the all babies
can get into full artist.
I just think that some people keep
using it and some people don't.
I always start because people would ask
me why he flexible and I just thought,
I thought it was because, uh, you know,
I was super insecure as
a child and I still am,
but I would put my legs behind my head
to like, you know, like this is my trick.
Right. You know what I mean? So I
thought that's why I'm flexible.
Cause I was always trying to show off
by putting my legs behind my head.
Maybe it is, but when you think about
it, I didn't show off like all the time.
He was at times, but then, but then, um,
my mom came over to the house once and
saw my son biting his own toenails. He,
oh look, just like you when you were a
kid. He's owed. And then I thought, oh,
that's right. I used to trim
my, even like at 10, 11,
12 I used to trim my
toenails with my mouth.
Yeah, he did two. Jamie did I
do a couple of free tow? That's
anymore. But as a kid I did it all the
time. Even with dirt. I would like,
you know when you bite,
you bite the toenail off,
but it has dirt and you could
feel the crunch crunchy.
Yeah. Always. It's my foot.
It's just dirt. That's
true. That's your fun. Yeah.
I've done it with my finger nail. I was
like, why am I so prejudice about my toes?
My feet are clean, but to do the Hindu
low team like Bennati you have to,
I mean when I come back after my surgery,
I'm going to have knee surgery. Um,
I'm going to come, you going to get your
knee surgery with, um, you have a doctor.
Um, we'll talk. We'll talk
about it afterwards. I got
some options for you. Okay.
I do have a doctor's note. Okay,
cool. Doctor Ron in Beverly Hills.
He's a Brazilian jujitsu black
belt. He or Dr. Rob. Is it
fair to go to the right door? Let me see.
Is this the Hindu Lutein? Here it is.
Yeah. It's a check. Check.
Check out what he's doing
around the back of the head.
Yeah. Swing it around. Oh Wow.
See? He goes like right over
his ankle. That's Hindu control.
He just listened and he's got his leg
wrapped over the back of his opponents
head and then he's wrapped his arm around
the ankle area and he's going all the
way around.
The Dude's heading under the chin.
My little t rex arms couldn't do that.
Dude. I don't have enough real estate.
I don't think I could get in there.
I'd have to like really compress it.
Go through it yet.
He's doing it right now.
This is something I think
that people should watch
though. Look at that. This is,
he does it. He's done it twice
and an Ebi. Wow. In one show.
That's crazy.
Watch looking at more.
So we're watching him set this exact
thing up that he was just talking about.
Wow. That's awesome. But yeah,
he's going to fight for the belt at Ebi
Combat Jujitsu Belt that is currently
held by Nick Hahn stain.
He's fighting Ben Eddy at the next Ebi
it at the muscle farm HQ in Burbank.
You hear about that? Yeah, I heard some
muscle farm moved to Burbank. Right.
When did it, why they decided
to do that? The CEO is from La.
He just wanted it here too.
They were in 5,500 feet above
sea level before in a city.
That's a pretty rare thing to have like
to be at a mile like Denver's a very
unusual and that you are at high
altitude but you have a bad ass city.
You know they chose date.
He's fucked up kids,
but it's awesome.
Do the facilities awesome.
Throw a fuck load of money at that stuff.
So far.
They had a fight to win show
there and that was awesome.
That was like maybe three
weeks ago was it was,
it was awesome to places is spectacular.
So we're doing a show there Saturday,
February 17th Ebi,
15 gos in it.
Eddie Cummings is in Eddie companies as
the champion Gos in it. And um, to Eddie,
he came back from a bunch of surgeries.
Didn't he have
some shit go wrong? A bunch of injuries.
Uh, he's been hired a couple of times.
It's normal though. Yeah.
Especially his style. Right.
And you get to think he's constantly
training with all of those Donaher a death
squad leg lock masters are going
after each other every day. Yeah.
Testing their meniscus. Yeah. Yikes. Yeah.
Leg Lock scare the shit out of people.
Hell yeah. Hell yeah. But back to that,
a heartfelt dos Anjos fight.
I just can't believe how good that dude
looks at 170 pounds. He looks like,
like top 10 pound for
pound the world for sure.
Like did the combinations he was
laying on Robbie Lawler. Fuck man,
he looks so goddamn
good. Yeah, it's crazy.
And it think this guy was making one 50
making one 54,
you know,
he still 55 like a small
welterweight though.
He could add some more muscle,
I think.
Cause some of those guys that one 70
monsters like Darren till huge shit.
But he kicked so hard.
I think the kicks are gonna always.
He's always going to be in the game.
Even then, even if the smaller,
he's kicked her so hard,
as fast as shit to men
and it's combinations are
beautiful and he's just super
dedicated. I heartfelt dos Anjos is
very, very disciplined, very driven.
You'll see some of his, a plyometric
workouts that he does. No,
he was with nick curse
on from speed of sport.
I know he's done some work
with other people too,
but he did a lot of it with nick curse
on and uh, nick curse ons from that. Um,
um, the Marinovich camp, you know,
where the, like with Marilyn,
Bj Penn was trained by the Marinovich his,
so he's doing like this kind of shit
like pushing up on all these, uh, bars,
a lot of foot strength drills, a lot
of stuff where they're doing, um, uh,
jumps over hurdles and you know,
those horses,
what are those called?
Hurdles, right? Yeah.
He just does a lot of plant
right there as hardcore. Yeah.
That's working. Your abs,
your work and your feet.
He's lying on his back and he's
kicking up on these things.
It would give you like
the ultimate upkick too,
but the idea is just that you're putting
in these compromising positions off
balance all the time and you're doing
a lot of different plyometric drills.
He doesn't believe too much in like
regular weight lifting type activity.
Everything is like sports specific
plyometric type shit. But what,
what I'm always super impressed
with is his endurance duty.
He fought at a crazy pace and like
the commentated Cormier and Jon Anik,
we're going, man, I wonder if he's
going to burn himself out. You know,
I already knew the result before I watched
it. I got to watch it after the fact.
I didn't watch it live but
watching it I was like, man,
I see why they would think that he might
have burnt himself out cause it's crazy.
The volume, just dig into it.
You're so skillful to men.
It was like he was picking
his shots, you know, he'd go
head, head, body, body, head,
head, body, body, head. It was
all like creative and
constantly attacking it.
Robbie Lawler's just rolling with it.
It's like defensively and authentically.
It's a very impressive scene
because Robbie Lawler's hurt.
He can't move his leg good.
His legs been chopped up,
so he's kind of stationary and dos
Anjos is just moving in for the kill and
throwing bombs on them. And Robbie
Lawler is just raw wound with everything.
He's taken a lot of them in the body,
but he's rolling with everything.
It's hard to hit him clean
and he's right in front of,
in the middle of the fight, in the middle
of exchange. Robbie Lawler smiling. Yeah.
Crazy, right? Yup. Can't
walk like barely can move.
He's get his leg kicked
out from under him.
He's fighting a guy who
was just like a wolverine.
I mean just on him attacking
and Robbie Lawler smiling.
But he did pull out, pull it out of
his ass against Melvin man. Who fucks.
I did. Whoa. Can we see that?
Yeah. He was getting, it was, um,
elite ECC. Oh, was Strikeforce.
He was getting beat down by Melvin
man who and then one shot. Boom.
Yeah. He always had that chance. Right
to the very end. He had that chance. Yup.
Yeah.
The Melvin Manhoef.
One two was at one 85 there was a
bigger Robbie remembering he fought Tim
Kennedy and one any five.
You fought a couple of good guys.
That one 85 he fought Jake shields member
Jake shields tapped him at one 85 oh
boom. Go back a little so
we could see the beginning.
He's getting his leg kick all over it.
Look how much bigger he looks back then
and Melvin moves in for the kill and
Robbie hits him with a fucking,
I mean boom.
And then follows up with a
left hand at stiffened up.
I mean that's like one of the
all time Strikeforce chaos.
Maybe one of the all time MMA chaos
cause he's getting his ass kicked.
He's moving away
and then he steps in
and here it is. Ed, Jim,
Dan,
he's getting his legs kicked out
from under them. Here it is. Bam.
Crazy. And you see Melvin's body
just shut off. Is he still fighting?
Yeah, it's still fuck recently now.
No, he's had a lot of chaos, man.
He's fighting. I think he's fighting
for Bella right now. He's, he's been,
he's been chaotic like quite a
few times where he said, well,
it's one of those guys that never got
into the UFC. No, almost mad at me.
Maybe he could put some wins together and
get back in the UFC and get in the UFC
for the first time. But he's, you
know, I got to think he's like 37 now.
How old is Melvin Manhoef?
It's going to be a,
I dunno man. I got, I,
I think he's gotta be 36 37 41 yeah.
What's his biggest MMA?
Mark Hunt One punch down.
He CalEd Mark Hunt with one punch.
Mark Hunt charged at a mark on,
it was like two 60 net and I don't think
anybody ever stopped mark like that
before.
And Melvin clipped him with
an uppercut coming in. He's
like one 90 maybe. Yeah, maybe,
maybe 200.
So he was at the very least,
he was like 60 pounds
lighter at the very least.
FOC knocked him out with one punch.
Remember when he fought soccer?
Rabo soccer kick soccer.
Robert was one of the Sakharov was most
terrifying losses. Most terrifying.
Melvin fucked him up, dude.
I don't know what happened,
but I don't remember it. Pull that pull
up. Melvin Manhoef versus soccer, rob.
But this was hard for me to
watch because it was soccer.
Robert who had fought Vandelay twice.
He'd been KOD by Vandelay.
He fought a lot of guys and he
had gotten beat up quite a bit.
You were seeing like the demise of,
in my opinion,
one of the most charismatic
guys from that generation.
I didn't know a word that guy said,
never,
never heard him speak English
in like any long sentences,
but I knew he had charisma just by the
way, fought the way he handled himself.
Remember when he wore diapers,
because he's crazy. Oh my God.
Look how big Melvin is. He's
on all the steroids. This is,
they did not give a fuck back then,
man. They let these guys look out.
Jack Dhea is holy Shit.
Melvin Manhoef had one of the scariest
bodies of all time for sure. Right?
Hell yeah. Look at him. I mean, dude,
he's jacked and he was so fucking fast.
You know,
it's just like any old warrior.
He's just had a lot of fights and
you know, this is where he's at now.
But God high, his hands are tied. Robin
never held hands high like that before.
Very dangerous. And Look Melvin just
waiting hands low. Remember that? Yup.
Not Against Melbourne.
Met especially not at this point
in his career and her about soccer.
Rob Is fucking knees, man.
That wasn't just for show.
His knees were basically like fallen apart
on him so he had to like wrap them up
in the most insane mummy like way later
on in his career when people forget
soccer. I would beat Vietor soccer.
I went broke hens those arm.
Remember that dude? I commentated
that fight. That's right.
You worked for pride back
then. Yeah. Look at this shit.
Look at the size of Melvin. He
just looks like a coil. Head kick.
Right hand,
boom. Oh my God. Boom. Passes the guard.
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
This is, this is one of one of
the hardest ones to watch.
Here's the knee needed ahead.
Now he's going to move them to the side
and try with the soccer co right hand
did not stop this fight. Right.
How they not stop this fight.
Boom. Cause it was soccer rob. And
you wanted to give him a chance.
That leg drag to the right hand
is Bam Bam. So I thought it was,
I thought he soccer kicked
him in the head on the ground.
I had erroneous memories. I could have
swore he soccer kicked him in the head.
But really he was kneeing him in the head.
Somebody soccer kicked him in the head.
He had another, I think that's Vander. I
think you might be right. Vandal.
He definitely did it to, to Maura,
right memory held the rope at,
stomped him. Remember that one?
He came out, he dropped him to Maura,
went down. He grabs her. She'll guns.
Stomps his head. It's
rough. It's rough to watch.
I remember Vandelay was mounting Dan
Henderson and then just stood up and tried
to stop on his face. Oh, that's right
away. Yeah, I remember that. Yeah.
I don't know if he landed though.
Cfu Five Vandelay. Kaos Tamara,
did you get it?
Oh,
flagstone
Oh, this is, yeah. No,
that's just Sakharova trying to do that.
That was to veto, right? Yeah. Yeah.
That was that. Vito is a veto. That
was in rough shape though. He, uh,
that was after his, his sister had
gotten kidnapped and murdered, I believe.
Remember Vito was like a shell of himself
for a long time after that. Remember?
I think he was in the UFC at that point.
I don't think so.
You might be right though.
When he fought Sakharova in Japan,
is that what you're talking about when
he ever hate through at turning sidekick
and dropped him? Yeah. I turned
side kicking with the body. Yeah,
right to the body and that
dropped Vitorin he just basically,
but school most of the match. What's
interesting too about soccer, robbers, he,
he had a catch wrestling base,
you know,
like he had some real submission skills
and people didn't know in the beginning,
remember his first fight in the UFC,
he gets dropped by Colin Soviet era.
Refereed,
big John McCarthy stops the fight and
then realize that it was an error because
he had dropped down for a neat, so
they fight again. Remember that? Yeah.
What the fuck? First Time you have to
with in Japan, right dude, it was like,
this is hoc, rob, you need to fight again.
This shit go one more and then
he catches him in that arm bar.
He tapped him with an arm
bar and everybody was like,
what? I Brazilian Jujitsu.
Black belt got tapped.
We didn't even think it was possible.
We didn't think anybody,
some guy who doesn't even have
a black belt is going to tap.
When Mario Sperry got tapped by
egos and Elvia rumor that that was,
we didn't know what to fucking thing.
How can this be?
And that was devastating for me.
How can this be? How can this be?
There it is. Yeah. He reversed.
He reversed the Camorra on him
and took the arm bar. Yeah man.
He got it right there, man. Crazy.
Look how Jack Sakharova was back then.
He was in great shape.
He's such a fucking awesome grappler and
so important to like the history of MMA.
A guy was in some wild fights
and some of them with people,
you had no business being in there
with just the wrong people. Like,
like Vandelay, like that was just
terrible match. How rare that is.
Like there's a lot of bad calls and a
lot of fighters that get fucked from bad
ref calls. They, you can't
ever do the fight over.
You can't do the fight. That was
one of the only times it happened.
Another time too.
It happened when commentated for
too hot to handle and Amsterdam.
I don't know if you remember that.
I do remember back in 2001 it was um,
uh,
Gilbert ival against,
fuck,
I dunno who,
I don't remember who it was,
but Gilbert live on Knox to sky out or,
or standing Tko they stopped the fight
and then the guy's complaining to the ref
like, why didn't you stop it? He's like,
why didn't you stop it? I was fine,
but clearly he wasn't fine. But you gotta
at least, you know, plead your case.
Right.
And make it look like you're fine like I,
why did you stop and why did you stop it
then the rough just said, you know what?
You ready to go get back? We're going to
go again. He put Gilbert in one corner,
the other dude,
and then once that guy he's seen in his
face once he realizes the raft restarted
the fight. He said he sinks
back into the corn goes, oh,
what's going on? But it gets
knocked out again. What do you,
what'd you put on here, Jamie? It was
a kind. It's don fry. Which one? Oh,
Gilbert ival.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well maybe this is another one. No, wait
a minute. Which fight you talking about?
No, the restart. No, no,
no, no, no, no. This was,
that to us was a put Gilbert ival too hot
to handle what happened at Don Friday.
Get poked in the eye or something.
Do you have a cut?
Like why were they checking on them?
I don't remember what happened
earlier in that fight.
I don't even remember what happened
in that time versus don fry. That's,
that sounds awesome.
Do you ever,
when you got a big daddy Goodridge
Kao dawn frier that head kick, big,
uh, Gilbert ival Caleb
big daddy Goodrich. Yeah.
Big Daddy Goodrich k owed Don
Frye with a head kick. This is,
uh, this is Don Frye and Gilbert
Ibel. See if you could find a,
Don Frye are a big daddy Goodrich Kaos.
Don Frye on that car with a beautiful
head kick on that car. Died.
Commentators pride turn of soccer.
Robin Henson. That was a main event,
but also it was Gilbert ival versus a Gary
Goodrich. And that was that one. Yeah.
If you could find a Gary Goodridge
against Gilbert Ival, that's a,
it's a ten second match and it's one
kick. Boom. He clips him, shuts him off.
Here's the Gary Goodrich.
Don Fry one
you hit on when you a leg kicks.
Big Daddy had one of the most brutal
Kaos ever in the history of the UFC two.
And I remember that, um,
from the fireman's carry oh
shit. Against Paula Herrera.
Yup. That was the most brutal knockout
probably in history is one of them.
I mean, come on. That's a beautiful
head kick over the shoulder.
He got one back. Yeah, that one,
that one that happened a against him.
He was out for like five minutes.
It was one of those. And then, uh,
he told me that when he woke up,
he was standing in the ring.
He thought he was in a rave and
Toronto because that's where he's from.
He was,
what if we were all living in parallel
dimensions all around us all the time and
one move left or right.
One dream action
propels you into the next door.
What if he was on death's door
and they'd decided, look, he's,
he's gone from this dimension.
We're going to put them in a nightclub
in Toronto and let his consciousness
right out this experience from here.
And he was with his back.
His sister was always with him. She
was like, um, she was a fitness chick.
She's jacked,
crazy braids.
And he said when he woke up he
thought it was at a rave. Any,
he thought his sister was some chick. He
was mcing on God. That's so crazy. Yeah,
no idea what the sister,
that's so crazy. Yeah. It's um,
that that guy was taken,
he had a long career man
taking a lot of crazy fights.
Okay.
So, uh, do you think Dosantos
can I get a shot at Woodley now?
You would know better than I would. I
don't though. I would think you would.
You don't get one side tubes anymore.
I do. I'd have to ask though.
I feel like I shouldn't ask. I want to
time sometimes I get in some inside info,
but if for the inside Info I get,
I can never talk about anyway.
But this one's a weird one man because a,
he was a lightweight champion, you know,
loses the belt and then has looked insane
as a welterweight and just beats the
former champion like Al Classism.
I think he stands out as the number one
guy in terms of like a guy's getting
another shot at the title,
but Woodley apparently is going to
get some sort of surgery now you need
shoulder surgery, Scott,
like a torn labrum.
So if Tyron Woodley goes out and then they
have to put an interim title fight in,
I would like to see him versus
somebody in an interim title fight.
Like how bout Hofeld Los
Angeles versus Colby Covington.
Hmm.
All the Anti Brazilian hate all, all
the shit that he said. That'd be nice.
Be Crazy.
That would be crazy.
And it would be a big fight, you know,
because of all the Shit Colby talked.
Okay.
You don't,
the only fined for doing like 500 bucks.
We're hitting him in the
head with a boomerang 600,
600 for ratio is probably
like that is so worth it.
You get to hit somebody in the
head with a boomerang on TV. Yeah.
Yeah. You know, the opposite
of a fight like that,
which would be have a lot of hatred is
uh, in Orlando, the UFC in the Lord land.
No. Um, it's going to be Ben Saunders
versus Alan Jobe on. Yeah. Wow.
That's hard. That's a hard,
I'm staying away from that one.
That's going to be a hard one for me too.
And I told them about not to take it,
but the problem is they're on losing
streaks and they can't be chosen and they
did reach out and say, hey man,
we're both 10 planet, you know,
can find the other opponents.
And they said no.
So they both agreed to do it and
I'm staying out of that one. Yeah.
Yeah. You can't corner anybody,
right? Yeah. There you go. On walk.
Actually two friends fighting.
Are you going to go to watch? Um,
no watch on TV.
You know what?
I'm going stay completely out of it.
I was just going to tell you like,
I like being there live,
but I have the most fun when it's us.
When we do fight companions,
we're all here drinking and smoking
weed, talking crazy shit. I been in,
I've been to enough EFCs man. I'm
like, you know, you've been to a lot,
that's for sure. I'd rather watch it on
my phone. I know what you mean. Well,
I don't like watching on my phone,
but I do like watching it at home.
I like watching boxing at
home too, man. You know,
it's like you get all the angles,
you get to hear the commentary.
Roy Jones Jr had some fucking amazing
commentary this weekend on a boxing.
It's so interesting here in sear new guy
like Roy Jones who like points shit out.
He was a, I forget the two dudes
that were fighting. There's a,
there's an Irish guy, there were two,
two guys that I'd never heard of.
I think one of them was Williams,
the other one was oh Sullivan
or something like that.
And I didn't know who they were.
And um,
I was waiting for the main event
and I was watching this dude, um,
and Roy Jones was pointing out all
the shit that he's doing with his jab.
He's like, he's staying right
there after he throws a jab,
he's going to get hit with counters
and then you see poon the counter start
dropping on him. And the guy was
getting hit was the guy who was favored.
He was like,
it's really hot prospect.
And Roy just starts pointing out
all the shit he's doing. He's like,
he's playing tough guy now. He goes, I
don't want to see you play tough guy.
He was, I want to see a boxing. He goes,
you don't want to find who's
the toughest guy is. He goes,
you want to find out who the best boxers.
These guys are just trying
to break each other.
Now he totally called it and you see the
guy who's starting to wilt shots to the
body. It was really interesting
to watch like a world champion,
top of the food chain where the greatest
of all time boxers see some shit that
you're not going to see.
You know,
like he sees vulnerabilities
that you don't see.
Are the Amy high level boxers that are
openly talking about transitioning to
MMA? Do you know? Not that I know of.
I think Andy Jacobs has joked about it,
you know,
the heavyweight champion and
our Joshua Anthony Joshua,
why to call him Anthony Jacobs. Anthony
Joshua was his name, right? Jesus Christ.
Um, you know, clinical used
to be a kickboxer, you know
that it was his brother.
Especially I think his brother was
like a world champion Pka karate style.
Kickboxer but um, no,
none that I know of. Man.
Floyd talked about it apparently date,
this is one thing I can tell you.
Dana told me that Floyd wants to make a
deal in the UFC like legitimately and I
go, did he? I could.
So I texted him, I go,
this Floyd really talking about fighting
MMA. He goes, yeah, he's fucking crazy.
I told him to get killed, but he's
still talking about doing it. Whoa.
For us, a hobby teases GSP versus
Mayweather or McGregor as next fight.
We need a mega fight. Okay, let me
just stop this nonsense right there.
CSP just fought it 185 pounds.
If you fucking really think that Floyd
Mayweather is going to fight GSP kit,
shut the fuck up. Just stop. Just stop it.
Floyd Mayweather is going to be
like a pass. That guy's huge GSP.
So big. You'd have to
be like, like Jones Day.
You'd have to get GSP to die it
down to one 55 and he would be so
depleted and making one 55 Floyd would
light them up like a Christmas tree if
Floyd in light him up like a
Christmas tree anyway. I mean,
they're going to fight in MMA.
He gets smushed 100% there's no way.
Stop the fight. One 85 GSP. No, no,
but they might fight at one 70
if the money was right. If, if,
if Mcgregor won't take it.
I don't know about that man.
That could be a mega mega fine.
That could be a $20 million fight.
Conor might want an extra 20
spent a lot of money on Versace.
He's always wearing furs and shit.
Flying around in private jets.
That shit's pricey,
man.
Is the latest of Mcgregor like
what's going on like today?
Hashtag Bollen that's what's going on.
He's on top of the world,
man. Look that guy. Let him enjoy this.
He's got plenty of time to come back
to fighting. Just have fun, man.
Stare at your watch is take Instagram
pictures of your Dick. Who Cares?
You're the fucking man.
You made $100 million.
You're not even 30 relax,
do whatever the fuck you want.
That no need to force him
to come back and fight.
But if he does come back and fight,
if he,
if he thinks an MMA fight
with GSP is a good idea,
like that's a big guy.
He's very big.
George Saint Pierre is one of
the best fighters of all time.
He's so fucking good at grappling. But
Connor might go fucking now, fuck it.
Give me a couple of months
to put some weight on.
That's not a good fight for them. But if
that's where all the money is, who knows?
I think Tony Ferguson is the fight.
That's the fight I want to see now,
in worse until I see what happens with
Barboza and Neuroma Grumet off. Right?
The problem is if Barboza and near
mcmeadow fight and Durga Medoff smashes
Barboza, he's gotta be next
in line for the title fight,
right? No, you don't think so.
It's not fighting. Tony is the,
oh, but counters out fighting.
Well then he has to vacate, right?
What does it say here? Sodid
rounds tonight. It SGB BG,
Ireland.
He's trained.
I mean, he's definitely not fat. You look
at him there, he's in shape for sure.
I mean, but he might just be working
on his skills. He's got $100 million.
I would not be mad at a world fight if
they decided to like strip him of his
belt and have Tony Versus
Cubby for the undisputed title.
I wouldn't be mad at that.
Yeah, that will probably happen.
I would not be mad at that. I
like that fight. Tony. So fun.
He's so wild to watch, man. You know,
like when he was fighting Kevin Lean,
he's walking towards him when his hands
down and just pot shot him and slowly
wearing, I'm slowly chipping them away
and then the finish him off his back.
Come on man. Sweet. How many
people get finished off their back?
There's a lot of sweet things that, um,
that he came up with, right? They're like,
uh, working, you know,
there's different ways you can get
up off your back with the cage.
Like basic,
whoa walking and stuff like that.
But you can't wall walk on everybody.
Right. It all depends on where
your level of wall walking is.
And how good is your
opponent at countering that?
What did you think when Kevin Lee walked
in with Javier staph infection on his
chest? Did you notice it? I was
like, cool. I hope he's weak.
He forced Tony. He said Tony Has Tony,
did you notice as the staff goes? Yeah,
I was trying to punch it
but with what tone?
The Way Tony got up off the cage when,
when Kevin Lee put them
up against the cage,
he actually can opener Kim from
the bottom and full guard. So yeah,
Tony was head was against the cage
and Kevin Lee's head was right here.
So he basically did like a
Muay Thai clinch, like um,
can open it up right at the bottom so
he couldn't get hit. And then he had,
he had, um, his left foot on the hip and
his right leg was just around us as ribs.
And then at the right time,
Kevin was naturally trying to push,
pull out cause he was holding him in.
He couldn't hit him.
He was safe against the cage and
then Tony put both feet on the hips,
pushed him up, kicked up, and then says,
stood up and was bra. It's like, wow,
we're going to be doing that one.
Yeah, I'm going to be, I mean he,
Kevin Lee couldn't do anything.
He had him exactly where he wanted
them against the cage on his back.
Head pressed against the fence,
but he couldn't do anything cause
Tony did a can opener on no one,
no one does that. I know he's,
he's an interesting guy, man.
That was the first time you ever
did that and it worked crazy. Yeah,
it was perfect.
What did you think,
what do you think about Francis
and Ghana and Alistair Overeem?
How ridiculous was that? Yeah,
I'll fuck is carried out.
How many times is Allister been chaotic?
We,
we did it on a podcast
where you get broke it down.
It was like something like 13 chaos
and MMA and then another three in
kickboxing.
Ooh.
The ones in kickbox and seems so
much more brutal. I don't know.
Not more brutal than that last one.
That last one is just brutal
as anything I've ever seen.
He got launched into another dimension
that I, I'm not a giant kickboxing fan.
I mean really,
I never watched kickboxing.
But if it's on I'll watch it and if it's,
you know,
makes someone else see glory in la
though. That was the shit. Yeah. Yeah.
But I'm not lying. I'm not
following it. You know what I mean?
I don't know who the hell is
winning. No idea. Zero idea.
But when I do watch it, when every
now and then I'll watch a k one.
You do notice that they hit
a lot motherfucking harder.
You the leg kicks into Oh shit man.
Like fuck,
this is some other kind of shit.
I'm not,
you could visibly see it after watching
so much MMA and then go watch them kick
box and you'll see how hard they fucking
kick some serious kicking going on.
Well you see it now with like go con
Saki now the go kart sockies in the EOC.
You know, I like, I was watching
him. So from Turkey, Turkish,
Tyson, he's ridiculous. I mean,
he's a brutal knockout
artists and k one and glory
to see that dude fight in the UFC.
You see these crazy kicks,
you see rediculus power kickboxers
transitioning to MMA. Yeah, but you don't,
you don't see professional
boxers transition down too
hard without the leg kicks
your, it's your whole striking
thing is so different.
You've got to think about
those God damn leg kicks.
I mean some guys are going to be
able to make it. It's not impossible.
All they have to do is be super dedicated
at, but they have to have a motivation.
And right now the motivation and
boxing is, if you get to a high level,
you can be a world champion.
You make a shitload of money and there's
a lot of money at the highest levels of
boxing.
But even at the highest levels of boxing,
like you have to have some name
value. Like they did a, uh,
Gennady Golovkin paper view
and it got like 150,000 buys.
And didn't they say that Ward
Kovalev was like really low as well?
One of the best fights ever.
Ward Kovalev to Andre Ward's stopped.
Andre Kovalev fucking amazing fight.
Sergey Kovalev rather.
And I think it only
got like 160 something,
525,000 pay per view buys.
That's crazy.
So those guys aren't making shitloads
of money for that way or whether it's
crazy. Yeah, it's incredible. Yeah.
But to do your sport like this is what
you've, if you're a really good boxer,
you probably have more of a chance
of making it as a, you know,
a top flight boxer,
then you do have learning all that other
shit while you're already 29 you're
going to learn how to check leg kicks now.
Okay. You've gotta change your stance.
Do you know how to take people down?
You don't. You got to learn that.
You gotta learn how to get taken down.
Okay?
You got to learn how to stand back up.
You got to learn how
to defend submissions.
You gotta learn that executes
submissions by the time.
That means that basically that could
take seven years. It can take forever.
Whereas a a kickboxer so a little
different if you get Mirko Cro cop,
when he fought Vandelay Silva,
he was fighting like one of the top guys
like almost right away because he was
so scary and the feet and
they made some crazy rules.
Remember those crazy rules like you can
only be on the ground for 30 seconds.
I told remember those rules. They had a
crazy rule with Vandelay versus cro cop.
The first one, first Vandelay versus
cro cop was bunch of wacky rules,
man like you, you, you go to the ground,
you can only go to the ground for
like 30 seconds. And if the fight,
if no one wanted the end of the fight,
it was a draw. So it was real weird man.
It's like Cro.
Cop didn't know really how to stop take
downs as well back then and you know,
he's just trying to get off his kicks
and he got off a bunch of kicks but then
they fought again and they fought again
later when cro cop had figured out the
take down defense game and it was one of
the worst Kaos of vandelays career. Cro,
cop fucking climbed them upside the head
with that left Shin. Remember that one?
He'll bit of a giant
Gash on van Billy's head.
So Vandelay goes down like
literally a was the ax murderer.
That was his nickname.
The ax murder literally went down like
he got hit in the head with an axe blood
pouring down his head and was, that was
one of the all time. Great. Mirko Cro,
COP head kick knockouts. Was it Mirko
Cro cop? I'm pretty sure it was.
Who fought that guy in who wore
a wrestling mask? Any Kairos? Yes.
He clipped him on the head and you just
see the blood pouring out of his eye.
The eye socket dude.
Dude.
The eyeopening wasn't that when
he was fighting with shoes on too.
He fought a bunch of those
with wrestling shoes.
Are they led Mirko head kick people
with red wrestling shoes on? Yeah,
I know he fought mark home
with wrestling shoes on.
He had kicked Mark Hunt
with wrestling shoes.
Pete Williams had kicked a Mark Coleman
with wrestling shows. He did. Yes he did.
Yeah. That's crazy. A lot of people
were wrestling shoes back then.
It's an interesting argument.
Like what's worse to getting your eye
a toe in your are are fucking wrestling
shoes. Wrestling shoes are so much better
for traction now. Look at them there.
Boom with fucking tape on his shit.
Nobody took a punch or kick
ever as good as Mark Hunt,
which is why it's even crazier
that Melvin knocked him out.
He'll get that boom right over
the top and Mark Hunt still in it.
Throwing bombs.
What a savage.
So what in Ghana now has got fights?
DPA. What do you think of that?
That's a tough one to call. That's an
interesting fight though, isn't it?
Steve Bill was on your podcast. What did
he say? Oh Wow. He's pretty confident.
It's what he says. But I
would say that too. But uh,
that dude in Ghana is like a
character from a fucking Conan book.
You know, like somebody brought this
up online that like how cone Anne,
when he was young,
they made them push that wheel
and that's how he got so strong.
Frances and Ghana was like
working in like a sand mine.
He was digging sand when he was like a
young guy like that literally might have
had an effect on how fucking
powerful and strong he is.
It really might be like an epic
fantasy novel. Like he's, he's like,
if you were going to go into a lab
and design a perfect heavyweight,
he'd say one,
I'm about 64 to 65 maybe a little heavier.
I was to cut a little bit maybe to 69
cuts down to 65 crazy freak athleticism
fast as shit for heavyweight knock.
Anybody dead with one punch?
Okay.
I feel like you're asking for too much.
Yeah, heavyweights don't move that fast.
They get tired real quick.
Not everyone can knock you out with one
punch from France. He was originally from
Cameroon I think. Is that right? Yeah,
and then France after that did he was,
we get this,
it was grueling and dangerous work.
Spending hour shoveling sand into the
backs of trucks so it could be shipped to
big cities for using construction.
Sometimes we'd stand all
day and water up to Shin,
scooping sand out of the river bed are
the days we spent at the bottom of a
steep quarry where large chunks of earth
often broke free from the high cliffs
and tumbled down onto workers.
Fuck man. It's a movie that's like,
that's like the beginning
of a movie right there.
You want to talk about that Drake song
started around the bottom that way? Hey,
yeah.
I mean, I mean he really started from
the bottom. Yeah. I mean he was there.
He was homeless in France just
like six years ago, five years ago.
Did you know that dude?
He was homeless in story.
Like how did he get into
heaven that he was in?
He was in Africa and he had decided that
he was going to take a trip to Europe
and uh,
he wanted to get away from where
he was and he decides to, uh,
go there. It doesn't exactly know what
he's doing. And somehow or another,
he makes his way into a gym because he
wanted to learn how to box and he made
his way into an MMA gym. And the
coach was like, look, you should,
you should try him in May. Like, you know,
like you could really get good at this.
And he realizes that the guy's a sponge.
Learn Shit ridiculously quick.
You look at him in his first UFC fight
versus now with Curtis blades where it's
the Curtis plates fight and then watch
them. Now. That's only two years ago, man.
So like two years ago and, but
it's improvement. It's insane.
He just knocked out with one punch,
one of the greatest
heavyweight kickboxers ever.
Allister Overeem was a k
one grom Prix champion,
Strikeforce heavyweight champion,
dream heavyweight champion.
You don't get any more experience than
Alistair Overeem fought for the title.
Right. One Punch. First round. Boom.
It is a little late in his career though.
It is. Good point. But still is a,
has anybody got gone the distance
with them or is he knocking everybody?
I know he's, he, he lost one fight. Um,
I think he got lots of decision,
I think like an early fight in his career.
And then,
um, I think Anthony Hamilton,
he submitted him with a Kimora.
He submitted someone with a Komora, I
think it was Hamilton. Is that correct?
Let's see. Anthony Hamilton. Yeah,
he submitted Anthony Hamilton
was with the Camorra.
Kayla Orlowski CalEd Overeem coyote,
the coyote of a bowl. Yom me,
Mia hove, which was a crazy one, man.
He was just dropping bombs on them.
Curtis blades was before that.
He TK owed him doctor stoppage
Lewis and Rick was before that.
That was the first time I ever saw
him and I was like, choose us. But uh,
it looks like decision unanimous against
a dude named Zoom Mana [inaudible],
c I. S. S. E. C s Zumaya
cease. What a great name dude.
He's got his first fight. He won
by Armbar. Yeah, straight armbar.
He's got an arm Crangle choke.
He's got a standing guillotine chokes
admission and he's got one submission in
the UFC by Kimora. He's working
with Vinny Magallanes, you know,
I didn't know that. Yeah. If any
macrolides says he's so fucking strong.
So this is the strongest guy that
rolled with, I did not know that. Yeah,
he's in Vegas now. Yup. He's
at the UFC training institute.
Do they got him over there
like rocky four it's crazy.
Damn performance institute. Yeah,
he's at, he's like literally, I mean,
think about this,
right?
You got a guy who was arguably one of
the best physical specimens we've ever
seen in the heavyweight
division. Like, right? Like it's,
you can't think of someone who's more
impressive than in physically. Right?
Then you have a guy who just
gives up his whole life for this.
Like he just moved from France to Vegas.
Then the UFC puts him in this
fucking state of the art laboratory,
this performance institute where they've
got all kinds of crazy shit in there.
I mean,
they have therapists and food.
They have all these strength and
conditioning coaches. I mean,
they're these guys that are starting
to do their camps down there.
They're going there and they were like,
Holy Shit. Like this place is insane. No,
no.
Wicki was telling me all the different
services they offer and all the different
things they do for the athletes.
For them, it's fucking amazing.
All these top flight coaches
and their training with them,
so you got this amazing facility opens,
right?
He's like one of the first guys there.
He's like,
one of the first guys to do is camps
there, moves from France to Vegas,
brings his coat coach
and he's just trying to smash the
world. Dude. It's like a movie. Yeah.
Homeless homeless guy walks
into a gym six years later,
UFC. Hopefully it doesn't top of
the food chain fight for the title.
Hopefully it doesn't start doing
ecstasy and I started going to raves.
I know, right? You've got to
keep them from getting too
crazy. I mean, because um,
well first of all he's got to get past
DPA and Steve Bay is gonna be the first
real wrestler that he's ever
faced. It's a big deal. You know,
it's whether or not Steve Bay can take
him to the ground. That's a big question.
Curtis blades actually very good wrestler.
Too Steep.
I was going to try to take them down.
Anything I would imagine there's
going to be a lot of everything.
I was gonna I'm gonna imagine that fight.
You're not going to be able to really
dictate entirely where everything takes
place. I don't know too much about
steep hill on the ground. He's,
he's not usually on the ground,
right. He just usually on the ground,
but he's a very good wrestler in college.
Yeah. Yeah. I think, I think he's,
um, 20 plus pounds lighter
though. Like he's about to 40.
Have submission wins on his record.
It's a good question.
I've never seen him win by submission.
I've only seen a win by knockout or
decision. CV can go to a steep A's.
A record. Yeah. I mean,
he's got to know everything.
It's the question is,
does he know,
is he strong enough?
Is as a wrestling good enough to close
the distance? What does he got here?
Any submissions? Tko Keio Keio Tko
tea. It's mostly TK was in chaos,
dude. He is fucked a lot of people up one
submission by leg kicks though. That's,
he doesn't need to got tapped out from
like kicks Stefan Struve beat him.
[inaudible] him. Kiyota yeah. Tko
Dumb. Uh, somewhere in Europe.
I think it was Nottingham,
Nottingham, England. Hey, um,
yeah man.
Beat mark.
Hunt by Tko or Lawsky by TKL for resale,
for doing buy Kale Overeem.
Kao Junior Dosantos.
Tko that's a fucking hell of a
wind streak, right man. Fuck yeah.
He's no joke, man. The Fabio Maldonado
one was scary. Remember that fight? Fabio,
um, took that he was supposed to
be fighting someone else and uh,
Fabio took that fight in Brazil is a
heavyweight. And how did it go down?
I don't remember. Smashed him steep. It
was just way too big. Just way too big.
Just smashed him, knocked him out. Same
Way. Knocked areas. Boom. That's him.
[inaudible] here's her, him and
Maldonado. Yeah, let that go.
This was it mean Stevie right now is in
its prime for sure. But this was, uh,
a good example that, oh, it's
just a lot of his fights.
He's a tough guy, man. He
takes a good shot and he's a
good wrestler. He's strong.
He likes to ground and pound.
Yeah.
He's just going to have to figure out
a way to deal with the extreme physical
advantages that Francis and gone.
Who has one? Is that if I go down,
that is Boston January 20th.
Oh Shit.
Don't come down.
That's also a volt con [inaudible]
and Daniel Cormier on that car too.
That's interesting. Owes Demir is Kale
two really good guys in a row and Meesha,
so Chernoff in one round and then he
just Kale Jimmy Manoa in one round.
That was a,
he hits fucking hard Russian.
I don't think so. It'll say Switzerland.
Yeah. Vulcan sounds like like a,
like a Vulcan. Uh, but that's
an interesting fight too. It,
that's a good fucking card man.
Steve Bay and Francis and Ghana was so
scary. What's the latest of John Jones?
Ooh, I don't know man. I don't think
they've reached any sort of conclusion.
I don't know if, um, they
have some sort of an excuse.
I don't know when the
trial is. I think it's, uh,
it's gotta be some time coming up soon,
but it hasn't been in the news.
See if you can find out when the trial is.
It's going to be interesting to see what,
what they say or what they
think it could be. Hmm.
I tell you the craziest rumor about it,
talking about it on the podcast before,
the craziest rumor was everybody
knows John Likes to party.
I'm not throwing him under the bus.
I mean, he's even joked around,
he said a to d c when DC was talking shit.
He's like,
I beat you after I did cocaine. I
mean, we're just fucking hilarious.
But the craziest rumor was that
they cut Korea teen with cocaine.
It's one of the things they cut cocaine
with and that they use some cheap
Chinese creatine team that was steroid
tainted, which is apparently very common.
Apparently there's a lot of uh,
Korea teens and different things he takes,
they have trace amounts of steroids.
It'll show up in the test because the
same Vat. So they make that shit in,
they make steroids in and
they make everything in.
They're making them in China,
these really shitty bulk places and you'll
occasionally get tainted supplements
happens all the time. Maybe they were
purposely tainted. That could happen too.
We talked about that. The
greatest creotine ever. Yeah.
This should yokes me out.
Yeah, right. Yeah, probably.
Maybe. Is that, that's just the way
to sell steroids. You just sell
creatine. But what's interesting,
it says California State
Athletic Commission, right?
Because it was in California.
So who gets to decide?
California gets to decide.
Is that how it works? Cause it's the
California State Athletic Commission.
So they apparently get to decide
what happens in his future.
Oh, you Sada, you if
found guilty this time,
he faces up to a four year ban.
Holy Shit. What's the minimum now?
I don't know.
I mean it really depends on whether
or not he's got an actual excuse.
If he could get that fucking deal or
to get them some coke and it's got the
steroids in it,
I bet you'd never, the problem is
you would only have a decent excuse.
You wouldn't, you wouldn't have,
you wouldn't be exonerated.
It would still be some sort of a penalty.
Wait a minute.
Did you say they're cutting in China?
That cutting creatine with coke or what?
Steroids? No, using
creatine to cut cocaine.
So if you buy cocaine,
see if you've got a kilo of cocaine
while stretch that shit out, man.
And a quarter. Oh, I got the
thing brow super fucking muscle.
Dick creatine and super muscle did
create team has some steroids in it.
And so when they're cutting this cocaine
with this Korea team that has steroids
in it, he's snorting the coat. This
is he not meaning John Jones a person.
I'm making this up, right? This is, I
don't know what not sure cabin, no, no,
this is the room.
Could be the rumor is that this has been
shown to task positive that he did coke
and it had creating in it and
the creatine had steroids in it.
The rumor is that is what people think
could be a possibility because if John
Likes to party and we
know John Likes to party,
it is entirely possible that he might
have partied and that he might've just had
a little bit of that.
And in that was this creating cause like
if you think about their cottony with
all kinds of different stuff,
right. They cut it with,
I mean I'm not a cocaine doctor, but I
gotta imagine they take some white shit.
It looks like coke and he can make more
coke. Right. That's what the cutting is.
Right. But to cut it with Korea
team, apparently it's comic.
We looked it up. We actually
googled it. Yeah. Damn.
I thought you were saying that he
was taking Korea team and it had,
it was tainted with steroids. That's, no,
that would be better for
him if that was the case.
That will be good because that way you
could take that creatine to Usada and
you'd have to have it on a list of
shit you were taking. He said, look,
it's just says it's Korean team. It's
all I took and they tested. They're like,
oh shit,
this does have steroids in it.
And then they'll go and find another one
that's like from the same that they can
find like the VAT numbers.
I guess they'll find one independently,
hopefully from a store.
And if they test that,
if they find a trace amount of steroids
and that, and that's what God, um,
a dirty bird to means he got off of that.
That's how he got off.
He didn't take any steroids.
Just took some fucking over the counter
normal supplement that wasn't supposed
to have steroids in it. And then, um,
he tested positive, he was stunned.
And you've look at Tim,
he doesn't even lifts weights.
He doesn't even remotely look like a guy.
He's just steroids.
And they tested the stuff that they
found just randomly in the store and that
tested positive. So he only got a short
amount of a suspension. Hmm. Yeah,
it was pretty quick. Like six months
or something like that. But even then,
if you didn't do anything wrong,
why would you get six months?
And so you're saying that the steroids
are in Korea team on accident,
not like they're not doing it on purpose,
right? No. Well, here's the thing.
This is just speculation, right? All
I'm here, I'm hearing a rumor, right?
But the speculation is that these
labs where they make creatine,
they also make a gang of other things,
right?
They'll cook up some steroids for ya or
whatever the fuck the order is, right?
And they're not cleaning those vats out,
right?
So if they're just pouring and other bag,
they pour out the steroids and they pour
a bag creatine in there for the next
batch and they're mixing everything up.
It's entirely possible to trace amounts
of those steroids are getting into that
stuff. When we first started
doing alpha brain, we had um,
some of the early versions tested and
when we got the stuff mixed from a place,
the place didn't do a very good job of
cleaning out their equipment and we had
vitamins in our alpha brain
that weren't in there.
We had some stuff that's
not supposed to be in there.
So when we tested and we
found trace amounts, we had
to switch what we're doing.
We had it changed how we,
how we have the things manufactured.
That's a super common thing when you're
dealing with these overseas laboratories
that are making all your shit together.
So that's one possibility.
Another possibility that
I've said before the,
a lot of people say I'm fucking crazy.
Somebody could have given him something,
somebody could have given him
something to fuck with him.
Somebody could have not liked him.
Somebody could have done that too.
I'm not saying that's what happened,
but I'm saying you have to take into
consideration all the possibilities.
If John is telling the truth and
he's totally stunned by this,
there's a lot of different possibilities
and one of them could easily be
somebody giving it to them.
It also could be that he took steroids.
That's plausible too. I don't know.
If you owned a creating company,
you'd kind of want, you're
creating to be, can you,
you guys are making steroids there too.
Right? Okay, cool. Can we use the same,
that six, that shit. And then
you could always just say,
hey, you know, and I didn't,
I don't know that what's
true. Yeah. You know,
they took a tour with those Dick Pills.
Apparently those gas station Dick Pills,
they have like a generic Viagra in them.
That's why they work so well.
I know that. He's just used to say
that's your honor, your honor. We, they,
we didn't know that they use the
same. That's yeah, they do that.
And they also put steroids
in those things too.
Do you know Brian Red Band was the first
one to call that Jon Jones had take a
dick pills.
That's why he tested positive red ban.
Put it together in his head because he
does coke. He's like, look, you do cookie.
Dick doesn't work, dude.
Your Dick doesn't work.
You take those gas station Dick Pills.
He probably took one of those pills.
He goes, I take those pills and feel
like a fucking animal. He's like,
I feel like I've got steroids in
me. I'm like, really? He goes, yeah,
you get really aggressive. Tick is hard
as a fucking piece of metal. I'm like,
okay, all right. Turned out
who's right. Hmm. That's crazy.
And it was the same thing
with Anderson Silva.
When Anderson Silva tested positive,
it was from some sort of Chinese dick
pill stuff and they found it and they
tested it. Grab that does go look, he's
done it. He doesn't do it all the time,
but he's done it so he knows what it's
like to party and that's what he was
saying. He's like, I know what it's
like. If you're partying and he's like,
your Dick doesn't work. He's
like, he parties, right? Well,
he probably did because he tested
positive for coke. He's like,
you probably does that red band totally
nailed it. Or maybe he was doing ecstasy.
People Take my ag Ron Ecstasy, you
know? Yeah. It could be that too. Yeah.
Look, he's a wild motherfucker and
he likes to party. The question is,
did he actually take a steroid
with the intention to cheat?
That's what we don't know.
He says he didn't.
I wished there was a way that you a
hundred play a hundred percent could tell
someone's lying 100% you're watched that
black mirror episode where everything's
being videotaped with contact lenses.
Yes.
So they just like reviewing everything
they've said. Yeah, that freaked me out.
That's coming.
If we don't have a artificial intelligence
that takes over the world before then
that's common that they're going to be,
you're going to be able to record.
You're going to have some fucking chip
do you put in the back of your head and
it's going to store all the stuff
directly from your nervous system.
You're gonna be able to review it in HD
to the moment.
They can give you eyes that work
better than your eyes and you have an
artificial disc. Right?
Think of that. I saw dude,
he got attacked by a shark
and he had no arm and no legs.
But here he was with a carbon
fiber arm and a carbon fiber leg.
And he's walking around. If you
didn't know, you would never know.
Like from the knee down, he was
missing his leg. And from, uh,
the middle of his bicep area,
he had a fake arm,
may just knocked the fuck out
of people who might kill people.
Just punch holes right through their
chest. You could leg lock them.
Would that be okay with the
California Athletic Commission?
Let someone fight with,
um, a cyborg arm? No.
No chance they'd have to start another
league with Justin amputees with Cyborg
arms. Will you met with that dude? What's
his name? Nick Newell. He used to fight.
He had one arm number. No, he had like a,
he was born with like a stump on one side
and you put a glove on the stump. Yeah.
I think that a man,
there's,
it's entirely possible that
in our lifetime they're
going to have better parts.
For sure. For sure. Then what we have
and once girls start preferring that,
like they only date dids with like
Cyborg legs, you know what I mean?
And they like that machine.
Did it take going to start
chopping off their fucking legs?
The first guy that cuts his
own eyes out for robot eyes.
That's going to be crazy shit. It's
going to happen. Yeah, there's nick.
Yeah.
It's going to be,
is going to be no chance that anybody's
going to want to be normal. Look, yeah,
I'd just rather fade away and get fat and
Cyborg legs and you could run
like 40 miles an hour. Yeah,
you could jump over buildings.
People chop your fucking
legs off shirt cause drink.
Imagine you got some iron man legs.
Like literally you could
jump over a building. Like
first of all,
just stop and think about living
in the year 1500 and someone,
someone somehow or another takes you
to a place and shows you a high abuse,
a motorcycle. He'd be like, what the
fuck is that? Oh this thing is just,
you lie on that. It goes
zero to 60 in less than two
seconds. He just fucking with
you would you would never
believe that could be real.
You could took someone from the 17
hundreds 18 hundreds even the 19 hundreds
like maybe the 1900 and they would
kind of get it cause they had bicycles,
but if you go back like a thousand
years ago and show someone a motorcycle,
they'd be absolutely convinced there's no
way that could exist. It can't be real.
It doesn't make any sense. I think
if you go a thousand years from now,
it's going to be the same
shit with our bodies.
We're going to have ridiculous
capabilities and it'll
look just like a regular
body.
They'll do some sort of like bulletproof
carbon fiber skin that will look just
like regular skin. You'll be able to
jump over the fucking buildings. 100%
this iron fists. Yeah. It was kind
of, I'm just going to lose my hand.
Well you know what bro? My hands been
shrinking. I don't know what it is.
People are just powerful.
Jamie,
with the phone on this last
time you had your phone on.
It's weird.
Yeah. There's gonna be times
where there's no need to like,
like oh you broke your arm. Here's the
good news. The recovery times. Even last,
if we give you a fake arm,
he'd be like, really? Yeah.
What do you want to wait six weeks while
you're fucking arm heals and then your
arm can what? Break again?
We'll give you a fake arm. Wow.
Am I don't know what to do. Get
a fake arm. I love my take arms.
Everyone's going to be just
a robot like Steve Austin.
Remember that $6 million man. Yup. Bionic
legs. Remember the big foot episode?
The best episode ever.
TV shows back then were s
oh my God. Just thinking about
all the TV shows from the 70s
garbage.
Compare that to like a Netflix show.
Compare lack like game of Thrones.
Yeah. Or Black Mirror. That's black.
They did have one shitty episode.
They were just knocking.
It was just like they were hitting,
pitching a shutout.
I've only seen three
episodes. The one where, um,
cause it's all based on what life is
going to be like in 10 years or something.
Like a little bit in the future,
you know,
and that one episode where everyone's
just rating each other all the time.
You know what I'm talking about?
They're just, it's happening now though.
It's called nose dive. Yeah. I get
it. I get into what's happening.
But that was,
that episode is kind of like that.
I mean compared to the other episodes,
like you see the one with
the video game where the guy,
they put a little thing in
the back of his head. Yes.
And he does know when the game's on
and when it's off. It's a tough one.
How about the one where the, the
dude, the dude catches his, his wife,
he figures out that she's cheating on him,
his acting,
whoever that actor is. Yeah.
His Act. That was, that was, uh,
an amazing episode, Matt. Yeah.
Did their intense man there's,
and the writing was so good like to do
with the husband. Hold on a second though.
Social credit APP scene in black mirror
is becoming a reality in China. Whoa.
Yeah. It makes sense. It makes sense.
You're going to have augmented reality
and people are going to have like your
Facebook score hovering over your head.
Like this is Mike. He's a super swell guy.
He's got four and a half stars from
everybody meets. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's kind of like that with
followers. Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Um,
man, it's going to be a weird
world when our kids are our age.
It's going to be a weird,
weird world. Yes. I mean,
I don't even think we could
begin to comprehend it.
I think we'd be totally guessing.
Think there's some shit that's
coming around the corner.
Do you see that NASA,
Tom Delonge thing?
Everybody keeps harassing
me about, um, the, uh,
the video of the Ufo. I here,
I'm here, I'm reading her,
turning up more videos all day long. I'll
be like, not just one. I called him out.
Let's see.
Let me see.
One of them videos is Tom delonge
putting out videos and know his,
his organization is putting out
videos. Have you fos? Yeah. And it's,
I'm a fighter pilot and f a 18,
I believe is chasing this thing and it's
a showing all the details of like the
Lao, the altitude, how fast it's going,
what pitch it's out and all that jazz.
I don't know what that means, what pitches
hat, but they're watching this thing,
they're trying to figure out what it is.
One of the guys is like, it's a drone.
It's got to be some kind of a drone.
They see something and it turns,
it was going very fast.
So basically it's like all the other Ufo,
but it should say no
worries. Yeah, it's blurry.
It's in like a gun sites or like,
you know,
some sort of a infrared site rather.
Um,
so you're looking at it through this
weird infrared video where it doesn't
necessarily look, you know,
it's weird. It's weird. You're
looking at it like, okay,
what am I looking at? I'm
looking at it. A little object.
Do you remember that quote?
It could be a total bullshit quote
from Warner von Braun. He, uh,
that he said right before he died that
beware of the fake alien invasion.
Did he say that in so many words?
I hope he did. I hope he did it.
He did it just to fuck with people.
It's amazing flying around.
There's a whole fleet of,
I'm looking at my asa
gotcha. Oh, going against the
wind. The wind, the hustle.
So they're following it for a
while and then it changes direction
it.
So whatever that is,
whatever that is.
Is Vr fucking super interesting.
And uh,
I heard the now going to shoo fly Travis
Barker to Washington DC to talk to
people and give him some
information as well. No neck.
They're going to fly a Kanye West.
He,
they're going to fly him out and show
him the secret lab for real. No. Oh,
I'm making this up because I think
it's crazy flying Tom delonge. I know.
It might not be fake. It might be
real. It could be looked for it.
Here's the thing about aliens, right? How
often do you think they'd have to visit?
I think they could get it done once
in the 70s and be done with us.
They'd check us out and they'd be
going to look at these crazy ass holes.
This is what we're gonna
do. We're gonna fucking, uh,
we're going to install some cameras
on the moon. These stupid fuckers,
they won't even be able to see it.
We'll just put some big ass cameras to
film them from the distance and let's get
out of here.
These people are crazy like this.
They're going to have nuclear power
with these assholes and they just would
never see them again.
So like if that really is a Ufo,
if it really is from another planet,
rather,
how many times they have to come here,
you don't, I mean, if, if they are real,
how much evidence would
you really see of him?
Would you see it once every 10 years?
How, how often would they come about?
Was it you, maybe someone had a joke that
like, maybe this is like the Tijuana,
the University of outer space.
It really come down here where they're
fucked up and they want to see a show.
Was that part of your yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. That's super old.
It's 2000 early. Two
thousands yeah. I think it's,
I'm not a nonbeliever, that's for fucking
sure. I think it's entirely possible.
Like if, if I looked up in the
sky and an alien ship flew by,
I would never think there's no way that
can't be real. It can't be possible.
I would think. Wow, they
fucking, they visited us.
I mean I'm sure there's something out
there that's smart. I'm sure there is.
It's a matter of what it would look like.
You know?
Would it even be in a physical form
anymore? I mean why do we assume,
we assume that everything has to be in a
physical form. What are you looking at?
Kendrick Lamar says he saw a
Ufo but nobody believes them.
What is that thing in his ear man,
which I think that's fraud and stage year.
It's a stage photo. It's a huge thing
in his ear in ear monitors or Boston,
but they're also the best headphones
you can get those dude that is like some
fucking Borg Shit that it's like he's
already been co opted by technology kind
of stuff. Just for like regular listening,
like seven different speakers in there.
Really bad ass. Yeah. Send me a link son.
I didn't know about the inside of it.
You're in area. That's another good, um,
have good case for a fucking
phone of the headphone Jack. Huh?
Like that's a really annoying to me
that they've decided to eliminate the
headphone jacks from phones. Just lost my
second pair of air pods. You did? Yeah.
It fell out of my pocket. So what are you
talking about? The edge headphone jacks.
Man's cell phones. Now they don't
have a headphone Jack Anymore.
They have this little lightening thing
on the iPhones and the only ones that
have headphone jacks are,
you can get them off of, um,
Samsung Hasum, uh, the new Google
phones, they don't have many more either.
Um, so it's all wireless now. A lot of
wireless. Yeah. Or you have a Dongle,
they have to connect at the bottom and
then it connects to an audio thing at the
bottom of that. So basically they're,
they're adapters still. Yeah. Yeah.
There's adapter still, but you don't
want to carry a fucking adapter around,
you know, but if you want to
listen to really good music,
I find that it's just sounds better
when you have a good headphone.
Just sounds better. It just doesn't sound
as good. I mean those airpods are great.
They're fine, they're good enough. But if
you want to like really hear the music,
like the, the best quality can be. They
say the LG phone is the best for that.
The LG v 30, it actually has something
called a quad deck, uh, like a,
like a little amplifier built into the
um, uh, where the Jack is for the audio.
So they actually have amplified sound.
They said it's supposed to be by
far the best sound for a cell phone.
Like they just decided to like
push that like its own speaker.
Like you don't need headphones.
No,
it's not that you don't need to speak
or you definitely need a speaker,
but the headphone Jack
is like super powered.
It's got some somehow processor in there.
You see that thing?
I'm looking it up and just hearing you
describe it, I'm wondering like why? What,
what they could have that's so cool.
And then like the article I found on the
verge says it's the best audio on the
phone ever. And then quote like it
doesn't, it just doesn't matter.
Like they have some crazy thing
and then it might be awesome,
but it also doesn't matter. Doesn't matter
yet. Yeah. But if it's awesome, if it's,
if you like sound like you like
you're a musician, you like sound.
Wouldn't that be like get in my car.
I have my little ox cable.
I even when you have an ox cable,
see the thing is if you do an ox cable
through the headphone Jack with the Quad
Dac thing,
it'll make us sound better in your car.
Do you remember bass boost on CD players
back in the day? Yeah, everyone had that.
That was the coolest
thing and now it's gone.
But it's just built into all
the headphones, like beats.
It's kind of built into it. Well, do
you remember when people's car stereos,
like the car stereo you would get?
There were always the shittiest
fucking sounding things ever.
And then you have to buy
a stereo afterwards if you
wanted something good edit
equalizers to him. Yeah. Yeah. And then
dealerships like what are we doing?
Why are we letting these people
make money off our fucking cars?
Cause it was like they had,
there was a whole industry that
was spawned so they're like,
why don't we just put our own good merinos
in the fuck are we doing was now like
if you buy like,
like a new car,
like a safety by Cadillac escalades or
something like that. The sound is insane.
I'm getting those things like, God,
it sounds perfect. It's incredible.
Just rings true. The cabin, you know,
I don't know how we got onto that.
Trying to talk about fights. Oh Holly
Holm, Cyborg. We think of that shit.
That's going to be insane.
That's really interesting, right?
Holly's probably the only one
that has a shot against her.
But people forget that cyborgs are
really good strikers. Like people think,
oh Holly is going to outclass or with
her boxing skills and her foot and all
that.
But cyborg striking is she she,
she's like a refreshing aroma
when we tie fighter. She is.
And now here's another thing
to think about cyborgs.
Jujitsu Cyborg is a way better grappler.
She,
people forget how good her grappling
is because of the fact that she went so
many fights by Kale,
but she's competed in grappling.
I know she was a brown
belt just a few years ago.
I don't know if she's
advanced past that now,
but she's the gin on the ground and if
you look at what Holly's weakness in the
Misha Tate fight, I'm sure she's gotten
better since the Misha Tate fight,
but Meesha controlled or on the ground
in one round, I think it was around two,
took her down control there and then
took her down with just a little bit left
in the round in the fifth round and choked
her unconscious. So that ground game,
although I'm sure she got
better at it and she even,
she's got such a good personality
and she says she's such a good sport.
After that she showed a picture of
her with a white belt on training.
She's like trying to get better,
like,
like put a picture on Instagram after
she got choked out and lost her title.
That's she's got some serious character.
Yeah. Some, some strikers they
just don't like training Jiu Jitsu.
They're just not into it.
Yeah.
I don't know if she's into it or not into
it or you know for a while that people
were saying that she just wasn't that
into and there's like a rampage was never
into training. Jujitsu. Yeah.
There's just some guys that
are so confident on their feet.
They think that why will let, would ever
want to learn this stuff on the ground.
Let's just keep it up on our feet.
She's hard to take down.
She works on that for sure.
Holly's heartache down and she likes to
stand and I don't think that fight is
going to end up on the grind.
I don't think cyborgs and I tried to
take Holly down at big cyborgs going go
right at her.
Whew.
So that's the same card is number Grumet
often Barboza this is the December 30th
card and then Jimmy Rivera
and John Linacre. Woo.
That's something that people are
sleeping on. That is a good fucking,
I don't know too much about Jimmy
Rivera to, he's very good. Who,
he'd be very good.
He beat Uriah favor.
He was a one of your eyes last fights.
The second last fight she
cook on Jimmy's record. Um,
but he's only got one loss in his career.
Um,
was he got oh yeah,
he beat Thomas Almeda beat up Thomas
Almeda. It was a really good fight too.
Before that. Uriah Faber, he beats
him. Uri Alcantara beats him.
Pedro Munoz be Tim and he knocked
out Marcus [inaudible] in I think is,
I think that was his debut. Is
that right? Does it say that?
It's just that history? It says
a full history. Yeah. So he uh,
knocked out Marcus and his UFC debut.
He's very good man. Very, very tough.
It's interesting cause he comes from
a chain to, he's from Tiger Shulman's.
Tiger Shulman's is, um, a really
respected name in MMA right now. Um,
they're really good, really
good, real good trainers,
real good fighters coming out of there.
But it's, um, it was always like, uh,
did you, you have chains
out here and the west coast.
Did you guys have like karate chains?
Like you're one gyns Tiger Shulman had
quite a few gyms. East Coast. Yeah,
but a lot of gyms, man, I don't know how
many he's got, but I want to say it's,
it's definitely more than one. And it was
like a known name in the karate world,
you know? And then when MMA
came around, they adapted,
they adapted and they put out some
real good fighters. Remember Louis,
God know the kid, but they were the
green hair. He fought out of there too.
I don't remember him. This is a good
fight. The green hair didn't work well.
You know Carlos condit returning against
Neil Magni. That's very interesting.
But I'll tell you what,
man,
Neil Magni was the first fight where I
realized how God damn good Hofeld dos
Anjos says it. Welterweight window sign
just kicked his legs out from under him,
got him to the ground and smashed them
and submitted them. I was like, Holy Shit.
Some guys, that weight cut is
just too much. And dose on.
Joe said definitely crossed over
into the too much territory.
I mean, in my mind, he's one
of the best right now for sure.
At 170 pounds to so many
good match ups at one 70 men.
So many, not too many fighters go
up in weight and dominate like that.
Not like that.
Not just dominate,
but dominate a former world champion who
just came off of a convincing victory
over Donald Serone.
You know, Robbie's not,
he's not shot by any stretch of the
imagination. It's not what it was.
This was what was most impressive about
of Robbie was in there to the very end.
I mean, he was bobbing and weaving when
he was getting hit with those shots.
He never gave up. He gave it his
all and he wasn't diminished.
He just got out fought. He got out
leg kicked, he got out, worked.
That fucking dude's got some crazy cardio.
I mean Hofeld dose on just
for the barrage that he put.
See if you could find like some highlights
like Hofeld dos Anjos versus Robbie
Lawler highlights.
He was just ripping him to the body
with ridiculous a quantity of strikes.
Carlos condit hasn't fought
in a while. Right? Long time.
How long has it been
Damien Maia choked him out.
I think that was his last fight a couple
of years ago. A couple of years ago.
Pretty sure. Did he get hurt
and have surgery or something?
No, man, I think he was.
I think he needed a break.
Let's put it right in the middle there.
It's not loading up.
God Damn it. Youtube. Get
your shit together anyway.
It doesn't matter. Just as a
lot of, a lot of good talent.
That 170 pound division now.
It's very interesting Darren till I want
to see him get a second fight in the
UFC.
After that cowboy fight,
I was hoping that he was going
to fight Wonderboy Thompson,
but Wonderboy apparently fucked his
hands up in that Jorge Mosfet all fight.
He heard his thumbs, so it's kind
of rest up. Maybe get surgery.
I don't know what's going on here.
Darren till won't rule
out fight with Mike Perry,
but has Wonderboy as
main priority? Hmm. Well,
Mike Perry just lost and a great fight.
But Pons and Tibio um,
Fanta,
a brilliant fight against Peri Peri
is a fucking animal though, man.
That of never stops coming. Do you
see that fight? I did, but not,
I didn't see it consistently. I was like,
just looking over on it. Oh, a good fight.
Mike Perry. He's the guy
who fought Alan, right?
Giovan Giovan was the
first guy to beat him.
Joe Bomb beaten by decision
and then he's on a,
he's been on a win streak since he lost
this fight. And I think he, what did he,
I feel like,
I feel like he won one in between there.
The J Kellenberger fight was
after Alan Jobe on, wasn't it?
I don't remember. He's
dangerous. Very dangerous.
If he catches anybody, knocks him out.
I mean, he just got to catch it clean.
If he catches you clean,
he throws fucking haymakers
super aggressive guy.
Like all dudes with writing
above their eyebrows.
Whenever you get tattooed
above your eyebrow, usually
probably a little reckless.
Probably a little crazy. Yeah.
Yeah. So we'll see here. Yeah.
The Jake Ellenberger Kao was right
after Alan Joe Ban. That was crazy.
The Alex Reyes can win streak he had
before Allen. Yup. Yup. Young. Who? Lynn,
who's a bad motherfucker.
He uh, got him by Tko.
Danny Robert's got him by Kao.
Serious fucking striker man.
That guy throws bombs.
I mean he lost but he lost to a really
good guy and ponds in Libya was fucking
very good and he put that guy in trouble.
But ponds and Libya had an awesome
strategy. Okay. Workload, great cardio.
There was a fight where like both
those guys were like on the edge a lot.
They were both very tired. There was
like some serious back and forth action.
What do you think said what's happening
next for rose? And I'm a Joomla's.
That's a good question. Just bringing
still on cloud nine man rematch with, uh,
maybe, but here's the gun. I don't know
if your honor can make that weight.
I think Joanna is a struggling, real
bad to make that way. When she said,
when she lost no, I mean she gave it
all up to two rows and rows caught her.
But she said she had a real struggle to
make that way and she's thinking maybe
one 25 we better for who knows.
Um,
she fired her a nutrition company though
that was taking care of her people that
were cut and getting her
to cut weight for that.
She said it was her hardest weight cut
when it comes to people that know how to
do that. Boy, there's like,
there's like four or five different
people right now that are like prominent
people. Whose the best
cutting weight? You here?
Two guys consistently.
You hear Dolce and Lockhart.
That's who you hear consistently.
You hear Mike Dolce and George Lockhart.
Don't chase got a little bit more
experience. Who's Delta got right now?
That's a good question. It's got a lot of
people, but he's got a real good record.
You know, you look at his record
for getting guys on wait for fights.
He's got a real good record. You
know, who has the worst record?
Whoever. Calvin has Calvin's lost.
How many times does Calvin missed?
He's missed weight wise. Yeah, but
didn't he make it when he was with dolce?
He made when he was an
adult. A though, right?
I think so.
Yeah. Just needs to be
super regimented. You know,
he's so fucking talented. Calvin is
so god damn talented. Hell yeah. Yes.
That one too that he landed on
our Bisping was like holy shit.
Dedicated with the left hook.
He caught him with a right jab and then
he caught him with a straight left. Oh,
that's snapped his head back. It was
like, but it was, he snaps his punches,
man punches there.
Snap like he's got a very
interesting punching style.
Like he catches guys like at
the very end of his shots. Man.
I mean it's, it's really interesting to
coming from that South Pole position,
paying look at that.
Come on man. Powerful PR.
Fucking super powerful
and a good wrestler too.
That's what a lot of people forget.
One of the reasons why he could strikes
so good as he's so fucking hard to take
down. Remember when he won
against your rival hall?
Yeah. He's been working with Marvin,
my blackbelt Marvin cast down.
He's been doing some serious training
with them. The cerebral [inaudible]. Yeah,
the syllabus. The syllabus is a bad
month. Tries you remember that? Oh,
I know that guy is,
he's got a nasty MNR your role at all.
He's got that like 12 million views
or whatever on flow grappling.
He's not all the time. He's, Marvin is uh,
probably at headquarters. The
hardest trainer. I mean, he,
he's always drilling,
always teach in teaching privates,
drilling his boys.
He's got his own crew.
The break squad came in
about seven guys and man,
that's a training on Sundays doing
doubles on Sundays every day. He, Lou,
that's amazing.
He lives it like that's a girl and
he's hustling to putting out seminars,
training camps. He's got his dark arts,
uh, seminars. When he teaches a class,
it's dark arts just because he's,
you know,
he's got all kinds of game,
but he does specialize in his own.
He's got his own special leg lock
game that no one else is doing it.
It's pretty extraordinary.
And he's the best at it.
And he's teaching and he's got all his,
his crew that he's teaching.
And I've actually implemented
that into the curriculum. We,
we practice his best stuff. I put
it up, I put it right in directly
crazy how Jujitsu has no end.
This is like new waves and new
techniques and new variations and new
improvements and new
defenses and it has no end.
The the amount of ways you can intertwine
and entangle two human beings and in
different angles. It's, it really
is endless. I know there's,
I mean there's so many different
styles of just leg locks,
just leg locks alone as its take
a lifetime to master it so much.
And over the last four
years it's just exploded.
I mean since since Ebi one
when the Danaher debt squad
came in and just started
dominating boom, that's when
the leg lock came, exploded.
It was always around cars
in Abu Dhabi and our dean,
Lester was crushing people with heel hook.
And so as Vinny Michael as they've always
been around, but I think maybe, uh,
people thought, okay, dean lister,
his leg lock and dudes because he's
so strong and so big and Paul Horace,
his leg lock and everybody,
because he's so big and strong,
just ripping legs apart.
Um, you know that,
and I think people looked at that
like maybe it's on a small man sport,
leg locks and even early in MMA,
like big dudes are going for hill.
Cause you know, outside the
look. But when you see guys,
I get e Cummings and you know, he's
not big at all. He cuts down at one 35.
He's the one 45 champ.
But what does he mark around the leg locks
dudes that are 250 pounds a leg lock.
Anybody that's criticism. People are
afraid of him. They're afraid of it.
He's so good at leg locks. People
are fucking, they run from him.
They have such a good system.
The Donna her system. Do
you ever, do you know Donna,
her system?
Do you talk to him about it?
He's very secretive about it
and it's a good mood. You know,
that's part of the reason they're
dominating the sub. Only seen, you know,
they're very secretive. But you know, we,
we take what they do and we added to
the game and we dissect their game.
We dissect a, you know, Marcella Garcia
is gang. We dissect anybody's game. Who's,
who's legit. Donna has got a great
a Instagram page to break it down.
Stuff breaking down his technique. He's
a genius. I mean, look at all his guys.
You got Eddie Cummings,
uh, Gordon, Ryan, um,
Bryan Garey tone and Nicky Ryan and
then the guys from Tristar with,
you're affiliated with them too.
Like Ethan Corellas and Sten I was
messaging just peed a lot of training with
them. Yup. Yup. And I'm all
over Taza. He's awesome.
They got a lot, their crew, they're deep
and they're not just good a leg locks.
They're going to everything. They're
good at passing. Uh, you know,
they're passing people's guards
and Abu Dhabi. Well, look at it.
Look at when George choked
out. Bisping. I mean,
when's the last time you saw a rear naked
choke? That tight. Yeah, that was tight.
Yeah. Right away in a world title fight
the way he slapped it on. And it was like,
you know,
sometimes you,
you'll see like a lot all like hand to
the back of the head type shit that was
just super sunk in and tight.
Yeah. Uh, the, you know, um,
our rival rivalry with them 10
planet and DDS is only be, you know,
it's only because they're so goddamn good,
you know,
and we're trying to catch him
right now and the sub only game,
no doubt they are the best and
we're trying to catch them.
So if we catch him or not, you know,
if we're, if we surpass them or not,
it regardless,
we're going to be as good as we can get.
We're getting better and better every
year. You need someone like that,
that the sport needs someone like that.
To have a team that's that dominant,
it's great for the whole game
because then you realize like, wow,
this is possible and you've got
to take it to the next level.
The elevating everybody's game. And
when Glb Eddie Cummins, that was,
it was so huge for me and for
everybody attempt. It was so huge.
Only because there were so dominant.
Yeah. You know, it's like, you know,
that it was just incredible. So,
um, the, the rivalry we got going,
it's just making us all better
and it's just elevating the game.
It's making us better.
It's making our leg locks better and,
and we're even taking, you know, some of
their passing and their back attacks too.
So who is out of Jujitsu at a high level?
Jujitsu is got like real promise and
MMA right now cause isn't Garrick tonin
about to fight an MMA match?
Gary Tone and who won
Ebi four times I think.
I think. Which is a lot. And
he only has one loss and Ebi,
he's been super dominant.
He's about to fight for one FC.
He signed a contract with
shattery so that's gone down.
I think his first fight maybe
in March, maybe. Well you know,
as long as long,
as long as they bring them along slowly,
no doubt he's gonna make some noise and
crone is still fine for rise and right.
Verizon, he fought for
rise in, in his last fight,
but I don't know what's going on currently
with this contract. I have no idea.
It's been awhile. It's been over
a year maybe since his last fight.
So I don't know.
And when he was on my podcast,
he made it clear that he,
he at at the very least wasn't certain
where he was going to go with MMA.
He talked about how Eh,
the,
the training and the lifestyle
is just not fun. He goes,
I just beat a guy and I'm
like, this isn't, this wasn't
fun. I mean, so he's not,
maybe you need time off,
you know,
cause he's had all the pressure of being
Hixon son and there's so much pressure
that come. Can you imagine
the pressure, you know, he's,
he's fighting a managing now he's fighting
and ADCC you know, all that pressure.
He cannot get stomped.
He gets stomped.
He's got to deal with like how
his dad feels and you know,
that fucks with people's heads.
So there's so much pressure.
So I want to see that kind of
level of Jujitsu. Like when,
like when Brian Ortega fought cubs
warrants, that guy right there,
Brian Ortega, that guy, he probably,
he's right up there with all the best
Jujitsu players in the UFC right now
actually. He's right up there
with Damien Maia right there.
I mean that guy is finishing fights with
Jujitsu consistently and he just took,
you know what, what you would he did in
his last fight with that, um, that uh,
against cub cub Swanson when he,
when he just took just your basic ass
front headlock had an army just takes that
and just closes the show with that.
Now there are many people can do that and
adjusted his hands that he was hanging
on.
He had an RMN faked,
like he was going all neck [inaudible]
and then went back. Cause as he faked it,
loosened up the guillotine.
So I went back bloom and then he,
it was just a little fake.
Oh that's interesting. Yeah.
Oh he faked and went back into
it because the guy on the bottom,
he knows he's kind of arm and Guillotine
and he knows, okay, I'm safe here,
but look, I, there's a little
opening if he switches really quick,
there's a Marcella team there, so you're
always watching it. So when he went,
he adjusted. But he went back and got
in deep with the arm and that's what,
I haven't talked to him
personally about it,
but to me that's what it looked like.
I watched it over and over
that looked like a little fake.
He had had an arm fake the Marcella teen
and went back in and deep and then he
sunk it on the level of squeeze and
clinch that's needed to do to pull that up
on cub Swanson Cub. Swanson
is high leveled. You did.
He's one of the best Jujitsu guys
in the UFC. He's right up the,
his Jujitsu is really,
really good. Really good.
And to to pull that guillotine off
on them and standing the super,
there's so much.
There's,
there's so much technique going on
and when you're almost got that Doris,
was it a dark Fernanda Condo?
Was it a Japanese necktie?
What did he almost got in the
first round to see that again,
he was in some weird position where it
looked like he was trying to seal up a
Doris, but either way he
had, I think it was a,
Darcy had comp Swanson tightened
down quick. You know, like, Whoa,
this guy is closing the show fast.
Those are all so very simple
chokes to learn. The Darce,
the arm and guillotine, the Marcella
teen, um, Japanese Necktie, they're all,
that's the,
that's the easiest part of the
technique is just learning how to do it.
That's the easiest part. The hard part
is mastering it. That's the hard part.
Easy. You could learn a arm and guillotine
in, in, in three minutes. Anybody can,
it's really easy to learn is not,
it's not trigonometry,
but mastering it.
That's what's hard.
Like you would think like why isn't there
more guys like Brian or tag out there?
Just taking little simple,
um,
at front headlocks who had an
arm and then taking it home.
There ain't that many because the
amount of, it's just like, um, uh,
[inaudible] plum clinch,
you know, so easy.
You could learn them when we tie plump
clinch in 30 seconds, really, really easy.
But actually manhandling a
professional fighter with it.
The amount of time that you need
to craft that clench and Polish it,
there's so you actually need physical
time. You have to, you have to,
it's not going to happen on its own.
I remember when Anderson
Grab Rich Franklin and you
could see right away you're
like Whoa, this is a different kind of
Thai clinch. Remember he just yeah, yeah.
Moving them around to every,
yeah.
Every now and then you see a fighter
utilize just the punk clinch and be really
effective with it.
Someone recently I forgot who was using
it and that the UFC last week I forgot,
but uh,
who has it wasn't the Los Angeles was it?
You said it was the Sanyo so that's
right. Yeah, it was him and he comes from,
you know Rafael, Cordelia
is, that's more time.
How much time are you spending developing
that plum clench up. Muy Thai clinch.
If you,
if that is not in your curriculum,
that is not going to be something
that people are going to be fearing.
You actually have to put time into it.
It isn't about learning,
it's about mastering it.
So what's about developing strength
in that one particular image?
Just like the same way.
Like some guys can throw a nasty left
hook to the body cause they just have
ridiculous or is you take the average
athlete and have them throw a left hook.
It's Awkward Punch to throw but
you get a guy like triple g.
He's been doing it so long, that neural
pathway so smooth and car. He just,
he just digs that thing. It's the same
thing with chokes. You see it with Brian.
Same thing with Brian also with his
triangles man. Yes. It's fucking guard.
That needs special time too.
It has has nothing to do with the time
you spent on the front headlock and and
taking that all the way home and closing
the show just from the front headlock.
Nicole Brina did it against
[inaudible] AG, his arm in,
in Abu Dhabi and um,
age.
I wrestled in college Cabrina and wrestle
but at this point he is like a college
wrestler.
Colbert has been wrestling so long he
could wrestle with college wrestlers.
Jay wasn't going to take them down at age
is a college wrestler like the Jit and
he's not going to take co bringing it
down. [inaudible] is like, you know,
a couple of where I'm asked her.
So uh, Cabrina shot in on a,
Jane got a single and then dragged
them but, but he had a single,
a j was hopping on one foot and then he
would drag him down like run the pipe
with it. And Aja such a
professional, he does,
he gets put to the ground
but then pops right back up.
Now we top it on one leg again. He has
a single and then Corina does it again.
Boom. He drags them down and then
a j like a professional Ninja,
he pops up again. How the fuck are
they Jay? Even walking after that,
Gary Tonin about,
I don't know if this really quick,
this is on that front headlock. So
then cold breana he realized, okay,
he sees what's going on. He knows that
he fucking, he still has the single,
still has control that clinch
Cabrina has he, he captured him.
It's not just a regular thing. He captured
them age. They can't pull that leg up.
He can't complete the takedown,
but he ain't pulling the leg out.
That clinch Cabrina is so strong,
right? So then Cabrina does it again.
He dragged them down to the ground and
then before he could pop up, he lets go,
lets go and jumps on a front headlock
and he has a cradle on a front headlock
and then boom, and that's it.
He's not letting go of that.
That's really not that much there. But
you know what? It's a starting point.
The actual real starting point was
that single that clinch on the Sydney.
Submit them. He captured them.
Yeah. Um, he got his back. He's,
he slowly,
he had the front headlock with the cradle
and then he's sprawled on him for a
while, maybe a couple minutes and
then slowly jumped on his back.
He took them out like a real anaconda
and that all those positions,
every step, just a little single
holding a leg on a single.
Most people can't even hold it in and a
guy will limp leg out and start again.
They start fresh and reset.
Most guys get in there and hold
that single for just a little bit.
It's only a little clench, a little
tiny clinches their little second here,
two seconds here,
or there was little risk control,
but when Cabrina gets in there
and clinches on that leg,
he couldn't pull it out and then he
jumped on the front headlock and then he
wasn't going to a lot of dudes,
you put a front headlock on,
most guys you could peel that shit off
and get off my fucking neck easily.
But there's levels like we always say,
we always say that because that's what
it's all about. You have to remind people,
there's levels to every movement
is you just keep getting better.
And then levels to chaining the movements.
That's a different, it's different,
you know, and then boom, you
put another movement. Well, how,
what level are you on this part
that we're going to connect?
That's a whole different level. That's
a whole different part. Another piece,
everything needs to be every
pathway in Jujitsu there.
It can be super long or short,
but man,
there's some pathways that
like for instance, you can um,
capture someone in quarter garden.
That's your first one. I'm like,
this is the path that a normal pattern I,
oh,
I'm trying to do is just capture the guy
and the worst capture his quarter guy.
It's the worst guard.
Africa's anything worse than quarter
guard where you're just controlling his
ankle. There's half guard. You control
the leg, full guard, you're controlling.
His whole body is between your legs.
That's full guard.
Half of that is you only have
control of one of his legs.
And then quarter guard is you're,
you're almost losing that lag.
You got the ankle, that's the worst
guard. Once you lose control of that,
he passenger car. Oh, you have
nothing. You have nothing. So you,
we capture that uh,
ankle.
You're in court guard and then use a
mini stomp. That's a technique, uh,
a series of techniques to get to the
lockdown, which is a form of half guard.
And then from the lockdown,
how are we going to get to full guard?
So it's a little clamp ankle, full
leg. Now I got your full body,
now we're going to attack. And then from
there it's a whole new sport starts.
You got them in full guard.
Now it's all what you did before has
nothing to do with this is a whole new
level. It's like a video game. Now
I've got them in full guard, man.
That took a while, but I finally got
him here and that's the whole strategy,
a strategy in the whole plan.
If anything would've failed
and I didn't get full guard,
then you try to sweep and try to
get on top of them on the bottom.
Use Half Guard suits. Get the dog
dogfight, electric chair, electric stone,
reverse locked down a lot of
stuff. You could do. Butterfly
sweeps over Hook, boom.
I couldn't get full guard, but
look, I swept you. Now I'm on top.
Now we pass the guard, set them up,
put them in the truck from the truck.
It's not working out. Tables back.
Tried to know what you're talking about.
You were trying to say this is a
crazy comprehensive system. There's,
there's a path,
there's all these steps.
[inaudible] nothing's happened
in the truck. Take the back down.
I'm not going to spend
that much time on the back.
I'm going to spider webs well by the web.
That's it.
We're first and goal on the one.
It's not looking good for you.
And there were so many things that had
you had a chain together for that to
happen. All those moves that
sound crazy. You have a chain.
All those moves together to make it
happen. You know? That's, that's um,
that takes a long time. They should
teach that shit in high school.
They really should. What? Jujitsu? They
make kids a lot nicer. I believe so.
I think so. It makes him a
lot more humble, more humble,
but also more realizing that a lot
of the bullshit and insecurity,
you can get that out of your system train.
Yeah. Yeah. A lot of pressure though.
Yadda pressure. Everybody would be
cooler where the chairs are Jujitsu.
It's competition every night. That's,
that's a different kind of pressure self.
You can handle that.
If you can handle,
if your ego can handle the competition
every night, it's Abu Dhabi every night.
If you can handle it and
you go in there like,
I don't care if I get beat by these guys.
I care about the guys that are on the
streets. These guys in this Jujitsu club,
they're all little computer nerds.
I'm not worried about them.
I don't think to be nice to you. I don't
care if they tapped me out one day,
I'm going to be able to do that,
uh,
do what they did to me on someone
that just walked in the door. That's,
that's the attitude you need new.
You need that attitude.
Like people take the tapping when
they go into Jujitsu too seriously.
And there is that,
that's why it's so much fun.
That's why it's a exhilarating
and exciting cause they
don't want you to do that.
Yeah, exactly. And then when you
tap someone out and makes it,
makes it so much better.
The fear of getting tapped or whatever.
Maybe you don't call it fear.
Uh, but I guess you could.
But that in itself makes the tat
feel better. So it's worth it.
You got to have both.
Can't have head and without the hell.
So that's what makes it exciting.
Life itself though. Microcosm. Yeah,
exactly. It's like all the shit that's
going on in the world. It's like,
maybe this is what we're here for.
The pain,
maybe it's opposed to be fucked up and
we're supposed to learn how to survive in
this a fucked up world, you know,
I don't know if we're supposed to,
but we definitely appreciate good
things more when we see bad things. Yes.
Maybe like struggle. Struggle's
real. Yeah. When you think about,
um, like, uh, you know,
getting, uh, let's says,
let's just say you were a
politician or some or a person that,
that were like a truth or whatever, and
then you're thinking about, man would,
if I get, uh, suicided,
you know, no, I'm not,
I'm just saying,
but you brought,
you brought that up many times
about like Hillary Clinton. Yeah.
Do you manage how many people
criticize Hillary Clinton?
Unless you're working for the DNC, you
don't have to worry, but if you like,
but if you're sending some shit to
wikileaks, yeah. People get suicided.
You know what I mean?
But what's,
what's people fight that
the people are fighting the,
the extreme corruption going
on and there's so many layers,
but what's worse getting suicided by
somebody in the DNC as someone ordered a
suicide hit on you or getting eaten by
a great white shark in South Africa.
I, well, how would you rather go
to, has a really matter? There's, I,
it might suck because they might cut you
in half. Yeah, but you're, you're not,
there's not people out there.
You're not going out there
fighting to kill all sharks. Right.
You're not trying to end
sharks, you know? So maybe it's,
maybe we're supposed to be in all this
shit and we're supposed to try to figure
it out. You know, maybe the bad
motivates the good, you know?
I honestly believe that there's gotta be
some opposing forces in this world for
things to get done. It's not that
I necessarily want to see evil,
but I think there's a,
there's definitely some sort of an
equation going on. There's good and bad.
You can look at movies. Movies always
have to have some kind of conflict always.
Otherwise, you're not going to
watch it. It's almost like we,
that's how this all works is there's
going to be evil motherfuckers here and
there's going to be good people.
Like what side do you want to play?
And maybe you're not supposed
to try to fight the evil.
Just try to survive around it. You know,
I gotta pee so bad. We have to end this.
Uh, but uh, tell me when again, as
the next Ebi so people can get it on.
It's on UFC fight pass now. Yup. UFC
fight pass. The next you can watch, uh,
the last, you know, Ebi one through 14.
I'm on the e a UFC fight
pass the next one. Ebi 15,
the featherweights February 17th at
the muscle farm headquarters here in
Burbank. Um, Eddie Cummings, Geo
Martinez and also the combat Jujitsu.
Uh,
the Ebi combat.
You get to bantamweight title
fight between Nick Cohn's dean,
who is a current champion
and Ben Eddy Lo tiene master.
The next fight companion we're
going to do is the 14th of January.
It looks like that looks like
the move 14th of January,
unless another one comes up in between
now and then. Is there any of them,
but that's a good one, right? Yeah,
I think it's just the one on the 30th
of the next fight, so. All right.
Thanks everybody. Thank you. Thank you,
Edna Bravo. Thank you young. Jamie,
how long did we go.