Boom,
and we're live with my pal Vinny shoreman
an eight time world Moy Thai champion.
Liam Harrison.
Ah Fuck.
Fuck.
Yeah,
Dude.
Great to be here.
Great to see a little bit.
Um,
listen man,
I'm a,
I'm a big fan of all combat sports,
but I really believe that if there's
one sport that doesn't get its due,
it's Moitai.
I really don't understand why
it hasn't taken off in America.
I don't get it.
I love boxing.
Boxing's a lot of fun.
I think moy ties twice as fun.
Yeah,
it's twice as odd as well I think,
I mean not fault pro box in and
have an over under Muay Thai fight.
It's definitely a lot harder.
I mean he's getting more mainstream now
along with the MMA because most of the
top of Murphy is,
are doing Muay Thai for the standup,
but it's still not where
it needs to be annoying.
Yeah,
it's weird,
right?
Yeah.
I mean I think what puts a lot
of people off my tie is the uh,
maybe the two minute break and also
the two minute break in between rounds,
traditional music and stuff like that.
People find the arts or take two ready,
which is,
I mean I love it so I
don't see that problem,
but I can see outside
the box for that as well.
So I feel like the two minute break
gives guys more of a chance to recover,
which makes the fights more exciting.
You have more energy and I
don't care about the dance.
The why crew,
that doesn't bother me.
If you got a finite in martial arts
funding me to sit down to where I am.
But once baseball,
baseball is so fucking,
exactly.
It's crazy how boring it is.
A lot shorter than England now
they started to cut out the,
all the traditional stuff.
There's no runway to know why crew
did you get in the ring you face off,
bell goes go straight away.
So trying to cook little aspects of
it out just to make it more media fun,
friendly.
Really.
We should probably explain to people
that don't know what we're talking about
though.
The,
the dance that they do,
it's called the white crew.
Right.
And what's,
what does the headband they put on?
What does the Mong Kong,
that's the Mong Kong and
when you're doing the dance,
the is like to warm up.
Yeah.
This,
there's lots of different rate,
lots of different reasons why these
different counts believe different things
and study mainly to do with bodies and
you see it in the ring and then take in,
uh,
play in respect to your gym.
Yeah.
You'd coaches your parents,
et cetera in Atlanta.
Yeah.
I mean I enjoy doing it.
Eight,
eight tall prepares me mentally
for what's about to happen.
Um,
I've done it nearly all my own roommate
fights only the odd one or two where
I've missed it when that's wanting to
be in because I've been told by the
promoters,
right,
no runway,
I enjoy doing it.
But like Vinny said,
like some people will come watch it.
They just want to see fights.
They don't want to see the
aspect of the sport as well.
They just want to see
people getting torn up.
And in case anybody didn't catch
that through that dance accent,
he just said 108 fights.
That's fucking crazy,
man.
That's a lot of fun.
It is.
For a Westerner,
but a lot of the ties I'm coming across,
they're all 200 300 plus.
I remember last year
I fought a tie and um,
they said all Liam's at a hundred fights.
That is a lot.
What do you think?
And he said,
I'd hundred fights when I was 15 years old
and I was sick down.
Who said that about it?
So a hundred fights and he's,
how's it even possible?
I'm not sure.
It must be every week,
52 weeks a year.
He said live in,
isn't it?
So if they don't eat,
they don't.
If it ends Ireland,
if you don't fight it,
don't eat.
So see ya.
There's nowhere welfare
or anything like that.
So the half the day that I had a former
UFC champion pat Miletich in yesterday
and we were talking about more Thai
and how crazy it is that this one place
Thailand developed this
completely effective style.
Like they changed the way people fight.
I mean they really did.
Yeah.
Did you look at all
the other martial arts,
whether it's karate or
Kung Fu or anything else?
Like they figured it out.
Yeah.
Without doubt.
Um,
but what's happening now is as well the
westerners are starting to catch them up
now.
I mean,
remember the first time
I went to Thailand,
not many people will go in and not many
people knew about fighting that tie
where more a more Western is
now we're going to live there.
The stay in there for
long periods of time.
The getting it down and we,
I can compete with the top level ties now.
Wow.
If all that back in the day or they
might have been like only Ramon Decker,
Danny,
Bill,
obviously John,
we empowered them guys will be running.
But now there's a lot,
a lot,
especially around Europe,
French fighters,
top level British guys.
We've got Daniel McGowan and England.
He's doing it.
I mean we are starting to really compete
with people on top of the top level.
Now is more time,
more popular in Europe
than it is in America?
Yeah,
there's massive shows on
in Europe every weekend.
I mean in America there's like
the main ones laying fight.
Um,
yeah,
we've got like two or three
huge promotions in England now.
Jaco,
there's tiger,
the French,
they have massive shows
on every weekend with top,
top level fighters on,
um,
all over Poland and every,
everywhere he's getting it.
He's getting huge.
I'm a big fan of lion fight,
but it seems to me that there's a lot
of times where these guys come over and
they're fighting someone that really
doesn't belong in there with them and you
get to see like alert Zillow or something
like that that would be absolutely
ridiculous.
Fight against the guy was at 405,
so one of the best Thai champions of
this era and his first ever professional
more to look going back,
ripped off Jaco and everything else.
You know,
you do it in such a way
that the matchmaking Brian
called ridges or matchmaking
our friend if I saw like rarely read,
always,
always competitive,
which I really enjoy.
And you've been doing commentary
for them for how long?
I've been Dean Kamen.
She fall y'all cows
since 2011 I met Stefan.
Yeah.
And,
uh,
when I was working for at showtime
and she asked me to work for them,
I still have some of the old,
it's showtime on my old,
I have a Dvr and my gym that's like
fucking 10 years old and I still have your
voice.
Right?
Yeah.
That's great.
You know what,
as I've,
I was going to say as I've matured,
but after the shenanigans we've got
up to in the past you'd be surprised.
But you know,
it's eight sad,
you know,
y'all cows going from strength
to strength and you know,
and it showtime off shoots like
glory and [inaudible] work far now,
you know,
it's so healthy at the minute.
So healthy kickboxing
and Muay Thai as well.
So high level,
it's just to me,
I mean I've sat down and thought about
this alone by myself for hours on end.
Trying to think like what would
be the way to get more time,
more popular in America.
Cause me as a,
a person who loves combat sports,
I look at my time and I'm like,
this is the pinnacle of striking sports.
It's the most exciting to me.
I liked the clinch.
I liked the elbows.
I love kickboxing.
I Love Glory,
but I feel like there's
something missing with that.
Like just the stuff that you were showing
me today with all the trips and the
sweeps and all that stuff
that's eliminated from glory.
The thing is that gives me it Liam as
well though because he's got such a,
it's got a friend family style,
you know,
he's not particularly a clincher,
but it is crushed bang,
wallop and 150 mile an hour.
And I mean I'm not gonna lie,
I'm his biggest fan.
I mean if he listened
to the common traits,
totally 100% biased and I fucking cash.
You know what I mean?
I've known him since
we 15:00 AM on monarch.
Got flaws,
but he's like,
look how well he's laying down
this mash unit.
But you know for me a AC
style that makes it exciting.
Well the TV thing,
I think it's getting more popular.
Need to pick and choose what
fights you put it on the TV off.
If you just put like a random show on,
we've like free like
fights that are terrible,
but ones,
okay,
you need to,
instead of it being alive,
maybe like pick and
choose some good fights.
Get out there.
Get people talking about Michael Vick.
Wow.
Did you see that?
They see them elbows,
see all that blood,
see them sweeps.
That's what I feel.
Yeah,
that's what I,
that's what I do personally,
but I feel like if a network like Fox
took a chance and had one Saturday night
and they promoted it and then we're going
to show you the most dangerous standup
strikers on the planet earth.
Like you might think that professional
boxers are the most dangerous strikers,
but they literally
wouldn't last two rounds.
They'd get the legs kicked
out from under them.
They'd get kneed in the body
and elbowed in the face.
They'd get cut up and clenched
and thrown to the ground.
It's just a better style of fighting and
a guy like you CV would be a whole lot
of fun.
I'm a big fan of the way you fight,
man.
You've,
you fight like you've got rabies.
It's like,
well,
I've always had that,
that type of style.
But you know what,
sometimes I've probably lost
fires on points because of going,
wanting to go for the kill when
probably I had to change my game plan.
I probably could have won,
but that's just not what I'm about.
I get in there,
people coming to watch me fight and
paying their hard earned money to come and
watch me fight the Onesie,
me smash someone's leg,
don't want to see me knock someone out.
They want to see,
even if it goes the distance and want to
see me pour it all in there and people
are paying their money for that.
So I feel like I've got
a moral obligation to,
to give them that.
I mean,
I can fight technical as well.
I've had lots of fights in the past where
I've just gone in with that game set
and I've won schooled
to top level fighters.
Um,
but I don't like doing that.
I want to get in there and I want to,
I want to,
yeah,
I don't like you doing that either.
I'm not going to be,
you know,
you don't like what he fights technical.
Listen,
we can't do any wrong in my eyes.
You know what I mean?
You can't,
you know,
I mean,
I'll,
Liam Liam's killed a family for nothing.
They must've done something.
But,
um,
no,
I,
I just,
I just think that,
you know,
he style the way that
the show that we work,
I work on regularly.
Y'all come,
I mean to,
to,
to have that level of ease matchmaking.
See in which I was like anything,
if it's done well,
it's beautiful.
It was done badly.
It's not,
it's
one of the reasons why we were talking
about the Gennady Golovkin and Canelo
Alvarez fine.
I mean,
one of the reasons why we're so
looking forward to the fight,
not just because the first fight was so
great because stylistically you look at
the way those two guys fight.
Like how could this be a
bad fight and some possible,
okay.
And now the buffalo and the good of both
change different cam plans and stuff
and he's got everyone thinking again,
oh,
well what?
He's going to happen this time.
There's no change.
Someone's going to get hit and
it's going to be guns blazing.
G,
G.
We've been to haunt him and we were
looking for him over there at big bear.
Yeah,
you guys went stock
side restaurant where he is,
where he came out and said,
what would you like about,
oh look what he has police.
Yes.
And when we was in there,
we were sat there and,
and,
and Liam.
Liam was like across from me and I went,
there's Tom Loeffler and he went,
he was Gtt,
his manager and then we get
an old chairs out and stuff.
Sat in these chairs out for an Ifr.
Here's good arrive,
he's [inaudible],
he's going to be here.
And we were sat that phrase,
it didn't turn out well.
He met Freddy Roach today before
Freddie Roach is a swat guy.
He's a real sweetheart.
And he took us down,
let us watch sparring and
stuff and we were like,
yeah,
he won't even though he's like
stood with his flat half an hour.
We were talking about boxing,
he were like interested in when I
were fighting and stuff like that.
He didn't have to be like,
do you know what I mean?
And I bet he gets people walking in there
all the time like wanting to meet him
and stuff.
But he took time out and talking to
Vince about all different other types of
fights.
Let us watch the some top level fight
a spa and he was like really interested
like absolute legend.
He's very genuine.
I got to interview him back when he was
training George Saint Pierre when George
St Pierre was a under him and he's
just as down to earth as you are.
You are any and you know just regular guy.
Yeah,
he's a good guy man.
I mean to me and men talk about a guy
who's been around the world and seeing it
all that guy,
you know,
training pack Yao and fuck man.
You know what I thought he said
something about I don't have a package.
I was going to train with him for this
fight and he kind of likes and he was so
engaging and endearing about park.
Yeah.
Wasn't he saying,
oh,
pack [inaudible] plays basketball.
Even though he's been with him
16 years and he's just gone.
Oh well if he goes and does
something that's already fans of,
he was like,
oh,
well last basket.
It's just that they don't give a fuck.
He's got money.
He doesn't give a shit.
And you know,
I mean,
his health has been such an
issue over the last few years.
He has trauma related Parkinson's,
which has got to be very interesting
when you're training fighters and you
realize like you're suffering
from fighting yourself.
Yeah,
just me and him that that's med.
My whole trip meeting him and just
seeing are grounded and down to Earth.
He is.
Honestly,
I just couldn't believe it.
Have you gotten a wildcard Jim yet?
Yeah.
That's great.
That's where we
watched them.
What worries them?
George Combos or junior at age 14 at all.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Big Flow from Australia.
Definitely.
It's crazy too.
When you go up to that Jim,
you hear so much about it.
You're like,
yeah,
it's about as big as this room.
Yeah,
it's true.
It's not a big fucking Jim.
He was sweating it all sorts.
Where are we on the way up?
Yeah,
no,
it's,
it's a legendary spot,
you know,
so your in America doing some seminars.
Yeah.
Um,
uh,
fire fury focused seminars.
Vinnie's doing all his um,
NLP mind coaching stuff
for an hour and a half.
And then I take over and do
all the physical aspects,
um,
Moitai all the little tricks and sweep
some of this stuff that I was sewing,
showing you their stuff that I've used
throughout my career to help me get to
where I'm,
where I am in NLP.
Is Neuro linguistic
linguistic programming,
is that what you're doing it,
but it's mainly to language and things.
Tricks that I've picked
up from over the years.
Not all NLP,
a little bit of hypnosis,
hypnotic language,
blah,
blah.
Right.
And it gets them into learning state.
So what I do is I get a prepared
them in a learning state,
give them confidence,
build them up so they can start
to take on what Liam teachers.
So they said double whammy.
Really.
So he teaches some brilliant
techniques as you are aware.
And then I just do my bit to get
them where they have to get to.
Before I met you,
I thought that hypnosis was for idiots.
I thought you'd have to be a dummy.
Am I gay?
Ain't getting me with that shit.
It's him.
He said,
and then when you hit with ties me,
I was like,
wait a minute,
this is real.
Wow.
But it's,
I tried to explain it to me.
Oh to people,
you know.
I'm like,
it's not what you think.
It's not like you don't
know where you are,
you don't know what's going on.
All of a sudden your parents are off.
It's not like that.
It's like you achieve this weird
state of mind that you're aware of it.
Yes I do is guide you to it.
And then the client does it like
whether I do it with year well actors.
We've got an actor friend
called Mike Parr it,
we've,
I've been working with.
He loves it and white and Brown
people it now to help his acting.
He did,
he mentioned me on a
program called this morning,
which is a daytime show in England.
And uh,
he went on in a soap
opera called Emma Dale.
He's normally in a long time and no
need less time because I'm not the your
biggest fan by the way,
say Mike Medis year.
So yeah.
And we have done work with him
and since of going on your show,
which I have to,
I really do appreciate it because my
work's gone from a businesswoman of the
year CEOs and everyone now been,
it's just been,
it's just gotten crazy because they
needed to convince her and he was at so
thanks very much.
Well,
it's legit.
I'll tell you right now.
I mean,
I don't know about other people,
but you know how to do it.
Thank you again.
It,
it gave me some very interesting
understanding about the mind and thought
processes and how it works
and that expression that
you look like to use all the
time.
Hakalau allow,
I think about that.
Explain what that is to people.
I can always,
uh,
increasing your peripheral vision.
Um,
it's correct.
It's increasing your awareness just
by basically cutting off your chest or
chatter that goes on in your mind.
If you see a Liam when he
fights before he fights,
he pushes his gloves together and
Dawson's Zaha cloud is every single time.
What that does when I
am showing you that yet,
I will show you later on if you wish,
is you anchored the gloves.
So you anchor a positive state in the
gloves and you push them together and then
you find Hakalau and
it just gets you in a,
well,
you can explain it.
What's unique about these seminars is
I wanted to do with me is because I've
worked with miss up before and all
this stuff that he's teaching and not,
I know it works myself.
Um,
first time I use Vinny is a,
the story are we all started,
I thought a top level ty called,
I don't want Carl summary
in nickname was [inaudible].
You had like an 8% Kayla ratio and
I went to fight him in Jamaica.
I knew I could be in,
but there are a few aspects that you
think or I would train and it didn't go
right at the time.
Threw him off.
I say,
look,
I'm not a liar.
Really?
Fuck my shit up.
It fucked you up on Michael Jackson died.
Oh yeah.
Massive,
massive fun.
Not about blaming Michael Jackson.
Massive.
Michael Jackson.
Did you ever come out to his fights?
You have no way.
Smooth criminal,
but yes.
I fought this Thai champion in Jamaica.
Like I said,
a few things didn't go right
and he smashed me to pieces.
It was the first time I ever got stopped.
I knew I could beat him.
No,
I'm good at reading fighters.
I knew I could beat him.
So I begged and begged and begged for
the rematch and promote Bri about six,
seven months later,
brought him to England.
Men Arena,
massive show,
big showed the country devacy and
Vinny had spots maybe far in the past,
said you don't ever want
to do a little bit of work.
I know it's fine.
I'm mentally strong and mentally strong
and I don't need to do to build up to
that fight for,
you know what I'm going to train is out
of the August as I've ever done before
anywhere.
But there's no point.
You can never be too prepared
because they'd all been in.
Can we do a little bit?
And um,
we did,
uh,
we did lots of different techniques and
we have like keywords like warrior one
of,
um,
the worry was the main one here.
Bear in mind.
Now,
the reason why I lean was
reluctant to work with me.
It's the first time he met me and
I stole a wheelchair Strunk steel
chapters for everyone.
Fucking Brits.
I was drunk at a show,
at least sound all,
I'm sure these cult Richard
Smith or members or Lisa.
And,
um,
anyway,
so it was a reluctant
because I like to mess about,
you know,
I like to be silly,
et Cetera,
you know.
But he came to me and,
and uh,
we worked together and my take on this
story is I was common sane at the time.
We did great guy called Rob
Cox who lives in San Louis,
who knows everything about weight.
I rub cocktails,
every food,
everyone eats the gut,
the kink simple and it was
calm and sit me meet him.
Now Liam came to me and I wanted
to put a word in that would,
that,
would that keep him strong?
So it was warrior.
Now what was really weird
is I was commentating on it.
You can watch it on Youtube when
I'm compensating on the fight.
He looks me at round four
cause I can see him and
he looks through his coat.
He's trained to Richard Smith and Andy
House and he's caused a news or five time
world champion as well.
So it's in a family and he looks
over at me and he goes warrior.
He looked straight in my eyes.
I do.
I remember doing that either.
They were like the,
the state I was in my,
no Phi in,
it couldn't hurt me.
Bearing in mind our bodily smashed
me a piece in the first fight.
I didn't get her with anything.
I would just be like her
in some totals there.
I was so on point,
I'll make any mess up our school.
Them rarely I'll beat him
pretty convincingly on points.
That's amazing.
And um,
I went to the after party
afterwards I'd bottle of water,
sat down,
passed out,
collapsed ambulance,
came and got me,
took me,
it was bill had a really bad concussion.
Wow.
But did you cause at the state I was in,
in the fight and um,
I didn't feel a thing.
Everything just my eyes
didn't fail and if it were,
we're like,
it's absolutely
so emotionally invested in it as well.
But when he kids,
you know,
on those biggest fan,
when he came over he said,
thank you.
I was like
[inaudible] birthday that day as well.
So there are a lot,
I know we started
and I was so overwhelmed by it,
but look,
I mean it's only one aspect of it.
He's got a fantastic coach in
Richard Smith and Lisa Hall,
Lisa Smith,
Lisa,
you should we call hot Lisa
and all the gangs like Jordan,
bad chair,
you know,
and everyone,
Steve Campbell,
he stone for condition.
He's got so many people around him.
I'm just one little bit,
but it was weird because he went,
he went worrier and I said to him,
do you remember saying you went?
No,
she had that.
I didn't remember.
I'll have to look back at the
video and watch the concussion.
Probably had a lot to do with it.
Maybe I'll look back at the video
and is a left doc in round farm.
I had nearly like,
Ooh,
spins around and turns
the wind up probably.
Yeah.
You know,
it's interesting that that's
catching on mental coaching.
It really is.
And there's a lot of fighters that used
to dismiss it that I know now are using
mental coaches.
I've had conversations with them
before in the past and I was like,
what do you think about
sports psychologist?
When you think about mentors,
I don't need that shit.
And then years later,
oh,
loss or two later their minds in a
weird place and then they decide,
okay,
I need something like
that I think is I think
wouldn't lost in the changing rooms.
I think that in the
locker room as you say,
you know,
one little,
it's like a little tiny bit of anthrax.
It thrown in in a reservoir of poison,
a whole say.
And I think that's what it does.
Men play.
I've seen fires in the dressing room who
I've trained with in the gym and they
have been so strong at
so much power in the gym.
They've been the best ever.
And I've seen him in the changing
rooms and I've seen him start to go out
yourself going to be at of in it.
It's strong in money and I can see,
I'm just trying to deflect change and a
lot of fighters do have that problem and
um,
served by the moment.
Yeah.
That's a common thing with everything,
with any kind of performance,
anything where you're doing something
that's difficult but fighting it has such
dire physical consequences that the
overwhelming anxiety and the pressure just
you,
you see it so many times guys
who were really good fighters,
that they have panic attacks in
the dressing room and they just,
they can't handle the
interviews as well.
It means guess what,
you're uh,
uh,
a diverse mix of clients
that he is everything.
It's what it means to you,
isn't it?
So that your fight against whoever the
artist fight is tie boxes in the world.
Like they keep matching you with and um,
and,
and your job,
are you your interview or are you like
Mikey that the lines that you have to do
while you're showing?
I think it's all relative to you.
You know,
when anxiety's a big scourge,
anytime you have to do anything
difficult comes to that.
But it just doesn't come into play
in anything remotely except war.
It's like war is like
the highest level of it.
And then pass you get below.
That was like probably police
officers and first responders.
And then it's fighters date and it's like
there's nothing like that that walk to
the fucking ring,
you know what I mean?
And you're just thinking
about did I do enough?
Did I sleep enough?
Did I eat right?
You know?
Yeah.
And it's,
and you see it.
I see so many.
I think that's why I've
kind of got into it as well,
you know,
with different things that
I saw so much potential.
She,
I,
you know,
the first time,
well the first times I met him I was
training someone to fight him and I was
like,
right,
listen,
he's only a kid.
So what you've got gotta do,
get in his face and punch him in the face.
Art As often as you can heal suit quit.
How wrong was I?
I wrote 15 who was he?
How old is the other guy?
But at 28 oh Jesus.
Mark has stolen from Liverpool.
Yeah.
You find a fucking 28 year
old when you were 15 right.
I find at 65 kilos now.
My first fight,
we're at 60 kilos when I was 14.
So I've always been big for my age and
then when I got to 15 and just stopped
growing.
Um,
so when I was 14,
I had like a beard and I looked like
a Yeti and also a big in school.
So I'm having a fight older,
a lot older people having
to fight men and um,
so I would like my finger when I 14 when
my first fights without any protection
on how to fight 28 year old.
And um,
I went my first 29 pro fights all and
beaten he wanted until the fought a Thai
champion and um,
I got a bit of an IDN call,
you call it dwell that I realize all I
have to change up my again plenty here
and have to go to Thailand and like
learn how they are doing it different.
What is the difference when you,
when you train in England versus when
you train in Thailand and how they fight?
What is the difference?
Well over that.
Uh,
I stayed there for about 18 months since
island and I just lived in the gym like
the ties did.
So walk up in the morning,
we went running came back pad.
Would it be a clinch?
Not too intense in the morning,
but then the afternoon
session free in the afternoon,
the scorching hot eat free till six.
I mean most classes in England,
no matter what,
an hour,
an hour and a half,
these were free hours.
Intense.
You kicked the second workout of the day.
Yeah.
So you skipped him for half
an hour straight off of that.
Straight on the pads.
Seven,
eight rounds,
straight flat,
straight and aspiring.
Dreadful.
Straight in a clinch him with the ties
and anyone who knows how strong the ties
are.
Clinton as well.
It was absolute torture every single day.
Um,
but I loved it and I don't think without
doing that I would often get to being
able to compete with the
top level ties I have done.
Um,
now the arm,
which Richard as projects progressed,
we,
my gym in England,
I feel like we've got so many top level
fighters now that the wire at that
level,
I feel like I don't have to go over there,
do it anymore.
We've got the stable in bad company
now we've got the knowledge,
you've got the experience and we've
got the and the house in Jordan Watson,
young Joe Craven coming through.
We've got all these strong strong
animals in the gym that am,
we'll probably want to,
well we are,
we have been one at best
engineer for a long time now.
Now do you work out the
same amount of time?
Do you do a morning session and then do
a three hour afternoon session to yeah,
so what I'll do in the morning,
I'll go down and probably to kick pads
with me than my boss Richard and then
maybe a bit of power in
majority than are a run.
So then in the evening I've got
pts all day in between this store.
That's the only different
personal trainer.
Yeah.
I teach as well.
Fuck fulltime.
So I might have five hours a
pts to do in between all this.
It's always exhausting.
Yeah.
Is it,
especially the way you teach?
Yeah.
You get very intense.
Um,
I like to be hands on and
had to get involved and um,
it,
it is tiring.
I just have to make sure,
let me die at some point.
We stopped for that because
if I have a day where I,
where I eat shit and then
I'm exhausted and I'm,
can I get the most out of my second
training session and then I'll get to five
o'clock,
I'll go run again.
I kicked pads again and
that's when Richard,
I'll do like,
so your rent twice in a day.
Some days.
Wow.
Adult run father,
I'll do my five five k's,
but fast.
And the way I see it with Muay Thai,
it's explosive stuff.
So I do my,
I do more hill sprints and more sprints.
Works out to a long distance.
The only time I do my
really long distances,
a funny trauma went down drastically.
But we,
when you fight in five,
three minute rounds,
it's not a long time.
It's like bang,
Bang,
Bang.
So I do more explosive work like hill
sprints from our strength coach and stuff
like that and no plyometric
explosive workouts.
Um,
that's the only thing
that's missing in Thailand,
really the strength and conditioning.
But a lot of gyms out there now are
getting hold of that and change it.
Yep.
Robbie,
Tim and Sharon who's trained,
the Alistair Overeem is over there.
Uh,
but uh,
and bad has been there a few times,
a lot of the Dutch color in Koh Samui
and that they've got a of crossfit place
now.
They've got like a new sort of metaphors.
A lot of them are catching up,
you know,
and,
and you know,
doing it over there as well.
So they kind of catch you up.
I know that Bam Cheer Mackinaw that uh,
well,
cal stock Stradford conditions.
He looks like he does a
lot of it goes opposite.
He's philosophy,
um,
against Johnny Risko
when he lost Johnny risk.
It was amazing that night.
It was just on him,
didn't give him any respite.
How long ago was this?
Um,
about,
I want the last week or last week.
How old's book out now?
Maybe five to the twilight now.
He said let you know I got a chance to
see him fight in La when they had a,
they've had some fights.
They tried to do some pay per view
events and stuff like that out here.
It's just for whatever
reason it never caught on.
Yeah.
We did time in America and uh,
when I'm before undefault twice on it and
that's how I'm able good shows them as
well.
Real good fire to wicked child.
That's where I'm at.
Brown lose our friend who's
looked after us here and um,
Fontana,
California in the house.
Yes.
A double dose.
That's what our seminar is
on Saturday or last one.
And um,
yeah,
it was,
it was a shame because we love it here,
don't we?
We don't want to go.
I wish,
I really wish we could,
I could figure out a way
to get it to catch on.
I just don't understand what's wrong.
Hey.
Like I said,
he's getting there with the,
with the MMA and stuff.
Like I remember the first time I have a
fault man event on a show in England and
I got like paired like this much,
but now I'm a headlining shows and
I'm getting paid like they're now.
So there's a lot of people
are saying going nowhere.
It's going nowhere.
He's bringing that Mike in front of you.
I've watched it like go from there right
to where it is now in my career and
where it's come from is massive.
It's massive gap from where it was
and if it does keep going like this,
it will eventually get there.
But he's just slowly,
slowly,
slowly.
We've always seen much more and more
tight talent come out of England and that
of Europe.
Then we have out of America
for whatever reason,
there's been some standout
fighters in America,
but it's the big shows.
There's like a lot of big shows in Europe
and that just really never been the
case here.
Yeah,
I mean like,
like Jaco is the one now
everyone wants to fight on Jaco.
I'm nothing to do with a promotion.
I'm,
I'm just a young cal fire and I get
people messaging me all the time.
Oh how do I get to vote on your cow?
Who Do,
who do I contact?
And I'm on a,
I mean like hundreds of messages all
the time of people asking like everyone
does it.
That's the show that
everyone wants to be honest.
The biggest outside of the
main stadium ones in Thailand,
the biggest in the world
by by a country mile.
Do they do Internet pay per view?
No they don't.
And um,
I think that's something
they should look at the,
I've said this rage
because I think as as it,
because even even though it's big,
it's small,
if that makes sense.
Even in numbers,
that concert it come to the show.
So I was like 3000 or something like that,
which isn't massive.
Bodies always jump at and I think it's
when you're selling tickets for a show,
he would say,
oh look,
come buy it for like a 5.0 and watch
it instead of wearing the national,
there may have been geo block.
Yeah.
Geo Block cause another infusion do that.
I worked for,
what do you mean that that means that
you can't watch it in your country,
but everyone else
also that people will go to the to see it.
So you buy tickets?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So where does it air in?
Does it air on television?
Like eight,
say the deep.
They bring the,
we do the show and then
they put the fights out and
they kind of feed the fights
are over a youtube.
I think they may put it on their
Facebook page or that the fight.
So I'm not sure.
Every single fight is a war.
Every single fight could headline any
shore we have go around the world.
We,
I've
got some right kids coming through.
I'm a massive funnel or
a boring show is ever,
and even even when Liam's not on it,
which is uh,
you know,
it obviously the highlight for me
because to me mate and he brings,
it brings stone.
It doesn't,
he's a storm.
We've got some new kits coming
through that are just like,
it just mentioned Stuart
Stabler and these gel craven.
And there's these kids
come in through that.
I just watched him take it on his style
and then taken on their own style and
there's some
real dangerous kids coming from now.
I would imagine that with your style,
it's your style.
So physically intensive and
so aggressive that like your,
how well do you monitor your diet?
Um,
I have to do,
we've gone,
I'm close to a fight.
Um,
if at all.
Like I said,
I've got,
I'm going to have no energy
and we'll cut weight.
Yeah.
I used to call it a
lot more than I do now.
I might do about eight pounds now,
but I might start the fight camp
and be on the 10 pounds over.
Not Nothing.
That's nothing.
No,
no,
not long haul.
Um,
my last four or five fights the day
before the way and never been on where it
without getting this song or all blah.
I'm going to go run in the sweat
suit or anything like that.
As I've got older,
I've got wiser.
I usually,
I just realized it was draining you too
much because especially as I got older,
when I were younger,
I could get away with it.
I might be getting sauna and lose like
free fall key or the way in and still get
in there and knock someone
out or stop someone.
But as a,
I had a few mistakes as I got older as
well growing when I'm missed weight and
like met me,
just think,
what am I doing here?
Get on point with it because as
soon as you start to do so flat,
promoters don't want to work with you.
Get a bad rep.
And I'm this,
we're about seven,
eight years ago now and I had done,
I haven't done it since I've met you.
I've been on point with
everything to be honest.
It's down to me.
My misses a lot as well.
She looks after me.
Um,
she,
I,
she goes out and works hard all day,
but whenever I get in from Jim about half,
seven,
eight o'clock,
there's healthy food
there for me and stuff.
Um,
what,
what kind of food do you do?
Specify a lot of people
cut out carbs and stuff.
I'm training so hard and sweating all
day and burning so much calories in the
pts and stuff.
I don't need your car,
my carbs.
That's a big factor.
Like people need to understand that when
they're talking about low carb diets,
it really dependent upon
how much exercise you do.
Yeah.
If you're running twice a day and
you're doing three hour workouts in the
afternoon,
like you're going to
need some carbohydrate.
Yeah,
exactly.
I don't need to call them out.
Um,
even in the last week,
a lot of people who say no,
it's last week fight camp.
Wayne's coming up and he caught my cows.
I'll,
I'll still get up in the morning
and have massive bowl of porridge.
I've still have rice with
my dinner and my fishing,
my salad and stuff like as well.
I don't need to cut it out,
but like I said,
I was down to how much work
I'm doing and stuff like that.
The amount you're burning,
I mean Jesus Christ,
the amount of calories
she must be burning.
Well,
I have my watch on over
there and I think at them,
some of my almost nearly
5,000 or something ridiculous
and a 1000 calorie all
day from betraying and
[inaudible] and stuff like that.
That's insane.
Just think about eating 5,000.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
So with you,
do you limit the amount of
personal training you do?
Because as the fight gets closer,
if I'm not going to fight the pile on
and train once a day just to keep sharp
and keep on top,
top of my game,
um,
I might be,
I do seven or seven hours,
like no problem.
And um,
but as the fight gets closer on cross,
so I'll cook down and cook down and
cooked down because obviously I don't want
my body being tired.
I need a be,
I've got a lot to lose there.
Every time I fight I've
got my mom I can spread.
This is a brand now with these
seminars and stuff as well,
so I need to make sure I'm going
in there as on point as I can be.
So you think about it that way.
You don't think about,
you think about it as like
Europe basically a business.
Yeah,
yeah,
of course.
Yeah.
And um,
I've got a lot so I've got a lot
riding on it every time I fight.
Yeah.
I think that has been for a long,
long time now.
I mean loud,
all the country gets behind me.
There's a lot players out there as well.
They want to see me lose and
they love it when I lose and um,
tell me who they are.
Well there's no getting around that man.
If you're doing well,
there's going to be people that it really,
they just hate themselves.
That's really what it is.
What it is is they see someone who's out
there as exceptional and it makes them
compare their own life to this guy who's
out there smashing everybody with 108
fights and they go,
fuck that guy
kicking the Pudsey of a day.
I got about four or five.
I probably got loads
more than that actually.
But there are four or five comments that
I noticed you said kicking that wrong
far.
Would you click on the profile?
Just have a look at them.
You're all just selfies himself
eating chocolate bar and one of them,
we have a dog.
They're all about 175 kilos
plot of video.
The other day I was holding butts
in Pottsville and valleys out.
I just old boxing paths are that
you're dropping your left hand was like,
all right then.
Thanks [inaudible].
If you ever have a fight,
you're going to get knocked out.
Oh,
if I ever have,
if I as a hundred knife fight,
it's just hilarious.
It's somewhat actually say to
you that are kicking wrong.
Like if anybody,
all my friends out there,
they get flustered by people criticize,
know on social media.
I want to point them to that.
Liam fucking Harrison.
Someone's telling him
he's kicking her are.
That makes me want to cry.
Laughing so hard.
That's how fucking stupid some people are.
But that just shows you that when you
have an open forum where anyone can
comment,
anyone can say something,
you're going to run into a
certain amount of those people.
That was just no getting around it.
Yeah,
I definitely can't look at the comments.
You know,
you can't,
you can't read that shit.
Just get assassinated
for from all corners.
Well,
the thing is,
those people,
they might not even mean
what they're saying.
They just stood there.
It's verbal diarrhea,
they're just black.
They're just angry.
They're upset at the thing is,
no,
I've been,
if I looked at someone's video and I
fought that technique one on point or
anything like that,
I wouldn't have gone and,
right.
Yeah.
I mean,
well of course you,
it gives you the right to go on
and like try to put someone down.
It's putting some dinner.
I mean,
he's just,
he's 12.
This is what I'm going to say is,
hey,
Paul Kane,
of course it was a competitor
or someone like that.
And you know,
if maybe someone's getting
undue accolades and you know,
like to stay ain't shit.
You know?
Or if someone,
you're supposed to know when you're
like 420 pounds sat around just eating
burgers all days.
Ridiculous.
You know what I mean?
They can eat more than you though.
Give a good point.
Maybe,
maybe not.
[inaudible]
man,
I've sit down with some fighters
and you watch them eat and you like,
where the fuck is all that going?
You know?
I mean there's very few things in life
that burn off more cowers and throwing
kicks,
you know,
especially the way you throw them.
And I
like that this the amount of
fucking energy you're generating.
Yeah,
I mean when I'm on the pods and stuff,
every training session I've dropped
100% and especially when I'm on the Puds
pads pad work is fucking awesome to watch.
It's very inspirational.
It's very fun.
Obviously as well with that.
That's just a little clipper
while I'm doing on the pads.
I mean my old pod work,
it just made trap.
Well sometimes it's just me
trying to smash the pods to pcs,
but obviously it's a lot
more technical aspects of it.
Not that's just like a little clip rubber.
I look for what someone's feeling like,
oh,
that was good,
so I'll put it right.
But obviously there's bits
where Richard Stop Him,
him putting me right what I'm doing wrong.
Technique work in the game
plan is to fly out there.
Obviously just little,
little snippets that I just put up
with me doing things wrong apparently.
But that's obviously there's a spar in
all the different technical side to it as
well as that word.
I mean that is like my style,
but I don't fight totally just like that.
Just smash,
smash,
smash.
And you've got to be smart about it.
Especially at the level of fighter.
If I just started
smashing things like her,
I'm just going to walk
on a shot at that level.
It's going to be game over.
Yeah,
there's no way.
Now do you,
in between fights,
do you um,
train with people?
Would that have other styles?
Are different styles,
like maybe some Kyokushin guys or
someone who's doing something different?
I create a lot of,
uh,
[inaudible] is at the minute.
Um,
I've got quite a lot guys
coming to me and we've got,
I've been doing a bit of work.
We might do Casey from the UFC.
He's been treating me a little
bit and he's down in Florida now.
Train in there.
Um,
there's a gym in Leeds where I'm from
called Davy taste like a real hotbed,
some topper MMA or guys out there.
I've got a young kid called
Louis got 17 years old,
seven and o in MMA.
It'd been doing Muay Thai,
but he's going to be an absolute
superstar in MMA and not
his style.
What he's got going on is so good because
he's got the standup and that we were,
we found like a medium to
pull that into the MMA.
So his eyes are on point,
he's movements on point,
but he still finds himself
in the positions to London.
Moitai strikes with all that power.
So generate the power and still be out
of there fast enough and quick enough not
to be,
we're getting taken down and losing
balance and falling all over the place.
Um,
so I watch out for him.
It's going to be,
yeah,
definitely.
Can you just sign with a empty k Mack?
The knife global.
So I'm going to be working with Dave.
Got Boxes,
so I worked with the mind side of that.
So they're getting onto it now,
but they've also gone into MMA side.
He'll sign with them as well till Sunday.
They've signed them too.
They've got boxes.
They've got Billy Joe Saunders who I
know you like Tyson fury and Blah Blah
Blah.
But they've also got an MMA side
run by carrying cattle and um,
yeah,
they've just signed Louis
Louis exceptional more.
The UFC is now coming to Liverpool
and the air until is going to be,
but he doesn't have a fight yet.
Not yet.
I'm hoping it's going to be
[inaudible] they're talking Kamara.
Ooh.
Swan Hill and going
back and forth on tour.
That guy gets no love.
C'Mon what?
[inaudible] seven and o in
the UFC smashes everybody.
Everybody's scared of him.
Nobody calls him out.
I don't think till,
I'm pretty sure til will be scared of him.
He'd love it till one I love.
So yeah,
until it tells there've
been going back and forth.
Definitely what filer and the standup
wise till has a massive advantage.
And then on the ground,
Ooh,
smudge.
You'd have an
advantage.
So it's,
it's a very interesting fight
who sponsor fucking tank too.
That guy's a fucking animal.
They have not seen too much of him,
but that's because
everybody's scared of him.
Get fights.
Well that day you go,
Ooh,
spawn is a fucking stud.
I mean that guy is no joke.
He like,
there's very few people
calling that guy out.
Bit of loving.
Oh yeah.
Tills the one that's calling
them out of there you go.
That he thrives on stuff.
I've known Darren since you were 16 years
old and I'm used to be used to train
together like Moitai bucking.
They used to come over my gym
bag company will be his coach.
He used to work together and then part
of the work came and do bits of him and
he's always had the attitude and I'm
never been scared of anyone always.
I've been like,
yeah,
whatever,
bring it on.
Bring it on.
I believe him this,
there hasn't been a single guy in the UFC
with one fight that's got as much hype
as that guy.
You know,
I'm fight fights.
Cowboys smashes it.
I mean you see what he
did to cowboy and Khalil,
everyone knows the real deal as well.
Special.
It's one of these kids lack.
When I seen him growing up,
it's one of these kids that
you just come to any special,
I mean the city's behind him.
Everyone cause he comes to our gym,
what I trained four corners team,
we,
John Kelly's and barley and all
of them and making Allen and HR.
It comes down as tech.
She's at him but he wasn't
trained but I've changed that.
But he comes and sees
us and he's a great guy.
But his coach,
Collin Heron,
I grew up with kind of,
cause we,
I was checking my TYC all muster scan
and we used to do demos and stuff cause
believe it or not,
I used to be all right.
And uh,
column was always a little bit better.
And since then he's got Karl Benz Carbon.
Jim needs a UFC fighters from Liverpool,
but now he's got this star in
Darren and the whole city is,
it gets,
it gets a bit like give me leads.
They just get swamped
by people.
No,
it was this one,
Darren was fighting more
tired than it became popular.
Yeah.
Well by default more tied than he ever,
you were always like one of the most
naturally talented kids would ever see.
Just Simon oddly that a different coach.
He used to come down to our gym and
he'd have a fight coming up and um,
it would just be wiping the floor.
We worked where everyone,
it didn't even really train
out about their neighbor.
He used to come down to a
young kid in mess around it.
Ron,
Ron Ryan,
the Brailey Alec train was still turn up,
fight and win since then.
So when,
when that natural talent,
he's now got that dedication,
the od.
So someone who has that naturally
talented I'm doing is going to work.
The artist is going to be a foster.
The Ralph Paul forced to be reckoned
with when he stepped in and caught cowboy
with that left elbow,
stepped in and just,
just drove up that elbow and
smash cowboys knows you like,
wow,
that was fast.
Close distance.
Okay,
quick.
Yeah,
we'll call him.
He's trainer.
He was a,
it's a motorcar motor.
Quanta's it Tai Kwon.
Yeah.
He was like Black Bella 11 or
something like that and you know,
he's just calling takes no bullshit.
You know,
Colin just says that's the
way it's a bit like Richard.
That's the way it is.
That's what you gotta do.
That's what you're doing.
And since that,
since Darren's had that
influence in his life,
like Liam said in the LBC,
the story,
but I'm going to Brazil,
it's just uh,
it's just been another level.
What makes a guy naturally talented.
But you take a guy like Darren till like
when you say naturally talent and like
what is about a god like that
that just picks things up quicker.
I don't hoists,
it's hard to explain.
Some people just walk in a bad company
gym and they'll have two free lessons and
they'll just be able to delve that floor,
the movement,
the rhythm and stuff like that.
More like that.
Ever since I remember
when he first started,
I remember his coach saying,
I've got this kid you need.
See,
you need to come and look at him.
South Park should see him kick.
He's only been trained in a few
months and when I saw him I like,
it looks like he's seasoned pro five,
six years of training with our plenty
while out walking Najim at bud company and
they'll come in,
they'll have a few fights and the wow,
so all right this,
but as soon as it gets hard
and the level steps up in the,
realize how hard they have to work
to actually compete at that level,
that's the end of them.
You don't really see him anymore and
it's like the biggest waste of time.
And you've ever see,
we've had plenty law for a ride.
Yeah.
He's not many times.
Not Enough.
No,
not when you get to that level is to a
certain level when you can get yourself
out of jail.
But when the level of steps
up and everyone's working
hard and people who are as
talented as you are working out,
then that's when you're
going to be in trouble.
That's why Darren has gone off and
done what he's done and that's why and
showing what he's all about.
There's this kid,
a class,
my youngest daughter,
she's seven.
She takes a martial arts,
Texas mixed martial arts class and there's
this five year old and it's class and
they're doing drills in their bag and I'm
watching this five-year-old kicked the
bag,
he's got his hands up high,
he's moving like there's I fang
turns the hip over perfect.
Even as switch kick and I'm watching
his five year old and I went over to his
parents and I went,
if I was a strike,
if I was like a us,
a coach that was looking to
recruit a fighter and a young age,
I grabbed that fucking kid.
Like that kid's special.
Like there's something that he figured
out at five at five all the other kids
you're looking at all the
other kids in the class,
they're flailing their
arms all over the place.
I paid attention.
This fucking kid is like this.
His hands are glued right below his eyes.
A Bang,
Bang,
crack,
crack.
Well I five our kids class it,
bud company,
I don't like training upstairs at same
time when they're on cause all the
technique is so good.
It's embarrassing.
Sometimes you look at them all
and you think like from six to 12,
these are amazing.
But like I say,
it's only the ones that really want it
or really willing to put the ab working.
We'll go from the next
level in the next level,
the next level cause a lot drop
off no matter how talented.
Uh,
not a lot of people like having to go to
that place where you need to go to get
to a good level.
Yeah.
He doesn't like people watching him
when he can't do things well either.
Like when he's learning thing,
he likes to go over in the corner
and practice things on his own.
Like very interesting.
And you watch like someone who's just
got like a special inclination towards
something called Shea Williams from uh,
Liverpool and all the blokes
are talking about is eight,
eight.
I'm friends with his dad,
MC eight,
six,
eight.
Everyone's talking about,
hey,
all these guys,
you know,
these big shots,
strong fall under,
let me see,
not a cage for him,
but alien.
Dot.
H eight years of age,
a lovely kid.
But he's just one of these kids that
can do everything that I can balance.
I'll tell you a video on youtube.
We the oven as well then too young.
Uh,
the black American kids boxing coaches,
that kid's amazing to see that
and the coach and what he was in.
But the one I'll do in the park,
he knows Marlin,
most boxing trainers I've
ever seen in my life.
He will,
he's like five years old.
Exactly.
Crate in the hand speed.
Amazing.
Brilliant.
Best Video I've seen.
Absolutely amazing.
Yeah.
That whoever fucks with
that kid in school.
Yeah,
they're in trouble.
That's a big problem.
Maybe it's stopped campus setting
that thing saying you drop your left.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
You're getting hated on by six year olds.
It's um,
I think it's interesting today too as
opposed to in the past that you can watch
videos like that and then you know,
before you'd have to like watch a VHS
tape and sit down and analyze it and pause
it.
Like now you can be at a fucking bus top
on your phone and you could watch world
class fighters instantly,
instantly.
The thing with that is as well though
that with the Internet as well as being at
watch world,
classify it instantly.
Here's a kid,
that's his,
him and his dad,
I guess,
look,
get out fucking technique.
Unbelievable.
It's incredible.
He ducks under,
I mean everything,
blocking punches.
Fucking amazing.
And look at that.
He goes through the body.
That's crazy.
I mean he looks like he's four.
That's a different kid.
That's an even Tinier kid.
Yeah.
Very impressive.
But yeah,
the thing with eating it as well though,
what's starting to happen now though,
a lot in especially in the UK,
people are say,
right?
Um,
we try and match your sure.
Right?
We've got a guy here,
he's had free fights.
Y'All guys,
I'd free fights,
let's match them.
And they go,
oh no,
give me his name.
I need to search him on Youtube.
And he searches Facebook
and hit search this.
So as well as being a blessing,
it's a curse for stuff lab because,
but when I started fighting everyday,
Richard had just gotten me,
I'd walk into gym,
Richard,
go,
you fighting on Saturday,
this might be a Wednesday.
Right.
And I go,
all right,
and then not what I turned upside down.
You have your fight,
but now it's like,
I want to know his name.
He's Jim,
what's his Facebook?
Isn't that a badge of courage too?
To be able to do that?
Like that's something that
people would always admire.
Like a God that would come into
the gym and someone would say,
would you like to fight
this weekend and go,
fuck yeah,
Martini man.
Anytime,
anywhere,
any place.
Yeah,
I mean that that is what you're here for.
Everyone.
I know.
Jim's always been like that.
Well,
if we had an [inaudible] falls down,
Gosh,
from Richard,
we've got a big junior circuit now
with Yaka Yaka and next generation.
How do you feel about that?
About little kids fighting.
They don't fight.
Had concerns.
No head gone.
Time kicks,
body kicks.
Moskal dessert.
Moskal for sure.
I mean some of the kids had got,
we got another kid.
They can't head kick either.
No,
just strictly body.
Some kids from like from Richard's
two sons Finley and forgive Joe.
Right?
Joe Ryan News.
What year would you do let them?
Well,
Joe Ryan,
just 15 he's just fought pro in Thailand
and knocked out and I think an 18 year
old type.
Whoa,
whoa.
He fight pro in Thailand.
He's 13 last week.
Oh my God.
Yeah,
the video on
do what I,
we've been,
but this kid is,
he's special.
He's taller than me.
He's 13 he's taller than me fight,
so about 59 60 kilos.
I've done a lot of work.
We've been one to one as well.
He's dad has done an amazing job with him.
Is that about,
is he on beginning 36 five 36 fights and
he's 13 I think you lost in the f and
the final Rashi.
I gaze a kid that was like 16 and
the weight four kilos heavier.
They got another kid called Riley Smith.
We've got some kid just in of,
sorry.
Sorry.
We got some moving around there.
We've got some right kids
that are coming through.
Jonathan Hogget who's just been on your
couch special and that's 20 years old.
Be a great fire veteran called Keef and
really know what kind of program do you
have for these young kids.
Do you have classes based on age groups?
Do you have classes based on weight
classes or do you just have kids classes?
Well Bud company gym,
the kids classes,
six to 12 year old.
There's about 40 or 50 sometimes
in our kids' classes and um,
there'll be about three or four of the,
the instructors taking it fight is all
I'll be open the ring fight training,
intermediate three in the
middle of is down at the end.
So everyone's got someone
care and reinforce,
forum open and bring through all
the fires are working together,
watching them.
It's just like watching the mini
version of all our fighters upstairs,
east class to watch.
Sometimes I like just going and watching
them all trained in inspiring reach
over and clinch in and helping each other.
And then a lot of them will stay behind
after the class and really not putting
the extra hours in the extra work.
And the is good watching.
Sometimes you'll see someone come
in the gym and they'll walk in,
right,
shy.
And then I look at them again two months
later and I've seen him on the pads.
Got Wow.
Wow.
Bomb.
And he's like looking around going,
yeah,
I see that.
That's what's in the APP.
And see him going through from being
like walking at Jimmy and a shy little
seven,
eight year old boy.
And then the smashing the pads.
And I've in the first fight,
our junior team is so good
because obviously we've got
Richard and Lisa training
him,
but my cousin Andy,
he's also a five time world champion.
He's doing,
pts,
have a lot of them.
Joel ribbons only like 19 years old,
but he's so good with the kids as well.
So they've got a wealth of experience.
And um,
like I said,
they're all just going but,
but bup and the next minute they were
up there fighting and just smashing it.
And I think we've got,
we had 18 fights for our junior
team last week and I think we,
we want someone like 16.
So as to earlier when we
were working out together,
you,
you've never really
considered fighting MMA?
No.
Um,
like I said,
it took me a long time to get where
I am in Moitai and let's be honest,
it was going to stand up in front of me.
[inaudible]
ring.
I'd have to get my ground game song so
good attacking a long time and to be
honest,
I'm really enjoy.
I love Moy Tai.
I love,
I love fighting when we tie and I think
it can only be good at summit that
you're passionate about.
If I got in there and I thought well I'll
do this because there's a lot of money
involved in it,
that wouldn't be,
I wouldn't be where I am.
I find more time cause absolutely love it.
Or your style though
was really interesting.
It would apply very well when I'm
teaching the MMFR as I do Trey.
And I think I've got that good medium
of all the striking needs to be.
And without getting taken down and off,
balancing yourself.
Cause it,
I'm not arrogant enough
to go in there and say,
right Moy Moitai you
need to do this in MMA.
We need to fight,
lack a tie into that.
I'm not arrogant enough.
I know that has to be changes and I think
I do spot that well and it does work
with the fight as a train.
But,
um,
like I said,
I love fighting.
It's,
I,
that's where my eyes and um,
maybe if someone came over it's,
you know,
there's loads of money.
Do you want to?
Maybe yet,
but like it,
um,
I'm a stand fire.
So have you done any wrestling or Jujitsu?
I haven't,
no.
I've always been so
concentrated on Memorial Day.
I fight credit.
I'm always booked out all year.
I don't really get a fart about it
before doing it a bit wavy tea with Donna
Mitchell,
but I'm booked out when fights.
I've got July,
August,
October,
November.
You're already booked.
I'm booked out.
All right.
So I the year that many fights in advance.
Yeah,
very than,
yeah.
Year and a half in advance.
A year and a half.
Wow.
Penciled in so I'm not going to have no
time anywhere cause I need to stay on
top of my own train and just so I'm ready
to go from wound fight to the next and
if you get injured I
obviously I have to pull out.
I got to pull off.
I brought my foot in my last
fight in Paris in December,
brought my foot split machine and a,
I couldn't fight in March.
I went to vote two weeks ago.
Obviously I couldn't do that with
my injuries are part of the sport.
Are you back to kicking things now?
I'm back kicking 100% and I'm back.
As soon as I get back home I'll be
back in camp ready to go in July.
That's impressive.
Three months later you
throwing hard kicks.
Yeah.
Now when you started working with Vinny,
what was,
what was the big difference?
What's the big difference in doing
this mind coaching and like what,
what have you noticed?
Improvement in my awareness,
like the stuff with a Hakalau,
although we're on about
the anchor in it yet.
Get awareness increases.
So when you anchor,
what do you,
what are you thinking when you touch,
when you smash your gloves together
at the beginning of the fight,
I,
I'm sure everyone,
it will be different.
What I'm doing is that when I'm pushing,
mine goes together,
all the stuff we've worked on,
like the high cloud,
the awareness,
everything's all just coming in to man.
The warrior,
he sticks with me.
That word will always stick with me.
After we've worked before,
I'm sure people have worked with him
and got different stuff that they're
anchoring.
Well that's what I'm on cream.
When you say anchoring,
what do you bring it in and
bringing it all back in?
We,
all the stuff that we've worked on,
like when we did the,
I don't know what fight the warrior stuff.
We also had another fight
against Andre Corbin.
I got raw off by everyone in this fight.
You'd been to England twice before.
It knocked out two of our
top guys in the way above me.
So I stepped up him where to fight him
and I went and did a bit of work with any
then.
Then there were a few keywords that
we said then one of them were visible,
visible damage of what were the
of warm hot knife through butter.
A hot knife through butter.
Cause I said hot hot knife through butter,
you guys and your God damn accidents.
Would you learn how to
speak American cheese,
hot knife through butter.
So what pretty good.
It's pretty good.
I'd said to Vinny is I said I don't just
want to beat these guys and everyone
dragging me off.
I said I want to smash him
to absolute smithereens.
He told me the game plan,
he told me the game plan.
He told me what it was going to do
with ruin our,
we're going to win no one,
believe me.
Yeah.
And then I obviously,
because you know,
if you didn't mention it,
I'm his biggest fan and um,
and,
and what we did,
I did a CD for him.
So I said listen to this
CD before he goes to bed.
So I recorded this,
this CD and it was weird because I was,
again,
I was commentating,
thankfully on it was on
the main event wasn't yet.
And I was watching it and it was like
playing a video game cause it's just like
low kick bank.
It was just like and everything that I
and all the thing that I said kind of
kind of cheat in it.
I was like,
it's like a hot knife
through butter anyway.
Bang.
And he just,
I mean if you ever see the absolutely
destroyed cooler and cooler been is,
is a legendary fight from
Bellaruse and it was just,
it went down.
Yeah.
Every time I think that's what we're
coming into my head and the way we vote.
You're going,
it's weird.
It's hard to explain unless you
actually do work with humans.
But yeah,
it worked again.
Perfect.
[inaudible] perfect.
And that one was the game plan
that people didn't believe.
Um,
I said,
what everyone has said,
I'm going to stop him in
three rounds and because he'd,
I will moving up in where and because
he knocked out two of the top fires in
England from that Web or
Michael Dixon first round.
And I think he's stopped
in Runcorn as well.
And um,
I told everyone I'm going to stop him.
He says,
I said,
these legs,
his legs to stretch
from a smashed his leg.
I'm gonna stop him.
A low kicks it will be.
And I said it'd be like a
hot knife through butter.
And I stopped to being round three.
We low kicks.
Now when you were creating this
CD form,
like what was the goal?
What was your objective?
You told me what it was going to do.
So I reaffirmed that.
So we did like a trance thing,
why you go into lead anyone
into an induction and then
just played out the fight
in his mind,
telling him the specifics of what he told
me and how he speaks because you have
to use that language back to them.
If I said,
you know something that's not in their
vocabulary of obviously I'm not saying
you think
smacking.
Well so he's got to add lots of like,
you know what he told me into the,
into the CD.
So it eh,
Eh,
and it went and it works.
I've never done it before.
It was a gamble.
I just thought,
you know what,
when
cause he was like,
you could probably do
that for a lot of people.
Right?
Like different things that
you're trying to work on.
If you could just like listen
to it and like in your,
like in your ear buds
or something like that,
you're doing
awesome.
You know,
I,
I've been,
I have people now,
it worked with me for a year,
like clients that want to work for a year,
they pay me for he end,
they just want to ring
me and talk about stuff.
It's become like a real dark sort
of different than hypnotherapy and,
and just being a therapist in just not,
so it's that sort of way.
But yay is possible.
And look,
I,
the reason why we're doing this
is because number one of the sad,
he's my friend,
but number two,
what we do works.
There's not,
these are tried and tested.
He's eight work signs.
We'll jump in.
I'm his mind coach,
you know,
vice,
he's got a great culture and Richard and
everybody bought what we do works and
people are starting to see the benefits,
the feedback we've got
like San Diego Boxing Club,
you know [inaudible]
and Jesse and all them.
It's been mind blowing isn't it?
Well there's definitely good states of
mind to go into anything that's difficult
and again,
findings,
one of the most difficult things and
then there's bad states of mind and those
states of mind can determine the outcome
and just to have something that you can
get to in your mind that could
put you on the right path.
Like what you were saying,
warrior or hoc allow like are these
anchors aren't doing like these different
things.
Like I feel like these are applicable
for everyday life to exactly that.
This is something that people
could really benefit from.
Like to just to add to instead of just
being like random and wild with your
thoughts and your ideas,
going into something and hoping that
you have a good point of view and a good
perspective instead of that like have
these clear paths that you've already
thought through.
Yeah,
I mean your mind,
you might have Savak class at
nine a set as to no way to go.
We think of it like a ton of time.
I sat know sat nav,
you plug that in that direction and
that's the role is it's going to take you
to,
if you put in the wrong guy,
I look,
say you've touched someone in Illinois
and you're driving around Los Angeles
looking for,
you're not going to find it.
So we have to be specific and what
I do is I try and get my programs.
I do various programs that I do is I have
to get what the client wants and then
once they get their client,
once I put that in,
but then to find out what's getting
in their way through the language,
the kind of language it wrong.
You know,
they say I want this and said,
yeah,
but you're saying none.
And
I love the job.
It's,
it's such a blessing to
be and are not being,
I'll,
you know,
rose tinted glasses and
I absolutely love my job.
I love people like the
people with the feedback.
If I had of getting messages
saying I feel different,
I'm happier.
There's no bad job in the world.
Not at all.
Well,
I mean,
you know better than anybody
that I was a fighter.
The way you think and your mindset that
that affects your training and affects
your outcome.
It affects how you feel
in between trainings.
It's like,
and then absolutely
affects the way you fight.
Yeah.
Cause it does.
I mean,
I reckon like a,
I've mentioned earlier,
I reckon I've lost fights on points
because my mindset's been wrong.
Going into it thinking right,
this is gonna be an absolute Wallace.
And then I've gone in there thinking,
right,
I'm ready for war,
I'm ready for this and I've got alcohol
in it because I've gone in there
thinking that if I in there
may be a bit more relaxed,
sharper on point,
I'd been playing the game but
I wonder adjusted and adjusted.
But then by fault,
you know,
I mean like you just said it happens.
But um,
if you are on point with your mind that
needs to be as strong as your body.
Like I said before,
he can never ever be too well prepared.
That's why I've,
I've gone to Vinay,
I've used him and it has
worked for me in massive,
massive,
massive fights.
Do you meditate at all?
Um,
I do the Wim Hoff method.
Ah,
again,
Vinny,
Vinny and Jordan.
Show me about that.
I remember I saw Jordan doing it one
time before our fight and say no,
what you're doing.
Then it told me where I'm off.
So out of any white wall.
And then I started with a
cold showers every morning,
the breathing and um,
again I've seen massive changes in
that in like my heart rate and that is
absolutely amazing how that works.
He's resting.
Pulse rate was 31 now
Jordan Jordan's with 30.
Mine will say to fuck.
Yeah that one beat.
Yeah.
I went to a women's house luckily.
I know,
cause I worked for infusion and they
did a little bit of a documentary on him
and I went with Mohammed Kamel um,
who I know really well.
Great Guy.
And we went to his house and we went in
the frozen water and all that sort of
stuff.
And then I started following thing and
stuff and a seen him on your show twice.
Um,
he's a slight like a jet
Dyani he's brilliant.
There's something about him,
his,
his perspective,
his and his enthusiasm is not,
it's not just infectious.
It's like it changes you.
Qg He changes the way you think about it.
I want to meet him.
We'll definitely want to.
He's awesome.
He's all set up.
I'll hook that up.
Absolutely love that.
Have you done cryotherapy at all?
I have,
yeah.
A friend in Liverpool dock,
he's got one.
I've,
whenever I've now had a real,
obviously my body gets
real lot of wear and tear.
Holding,
holding pads takes a lot out here,
especially when you've got to train
twice as well on top of that if fucking
forearms,
right?
Yeah.
My back and obviously
from spar in my legs.
A beetle.
Yeah.
Fucking elbows and forearms.
Yeah,
exactly.
I get stiff and after an hour we
could train in adweek or teaching.
I do need that.
So I go over to Liverpool and I jump in
now and I always come out feeling like a
million books all the time.
No,
I love it.
What about a isolation tanks?
Have you done a sensory deprivation tank?
Oh,
I'd never done that.
We've got one here.
We want to try it.
Hell yeah.
How much time do you get?
How much turn off
[inaudible] you think that you
go and as long as you want.
All right.
I have one right over here.
Fucking love it man.
It's amazing.
Since we've come to California,
we've got just feel super aimia mates
from v that might eat Murphy's got him on
CBD oil that's doing all that.
Having all the cool things and
still great with CBD is as Fucking,
I don't have it here.
I left it in my car.
I have this lotion,
CBD lotion.
You put applied topically where you got
like bruises or told me not tried the
great man,
but I got a test.
Yeah,
I got a test done by um,
my sponsors like the took all
the hair follicles out in there,
the tested them all and so they
could test what I should be in,
what food's good for me here.
Fall Hair follicle test.
Yeah,
like the proper sending it off to the lab.
They tested it all and it came back
with that and not blood or I'm not sure.
I have no idea how it works.
But the came back in and said,
right,
this is what you should eat.
Sweet.
You shouldn't be.
If this is in your diet,
tragic now because this is causing
some disruption here and stuff.
It really in what kind of
stuff are they saying causes?
This might be horse shit,
right,
so what about your toenails?
So certain different fruits and stuff.
Flat.
There was saying that rubbery
isn't raspberries and nuts
and stuff were causing
some sort of disruption in my diet that
it'd be better if I took him out and
almonds.
I went to one of those places and
they told me to stop eating Avocados,
like get the fuck there's
along with Avocados.
You guys are quiet.
Avocados.
Oils are great for you.
Best foods you can eat.
I'm like,
what avocado fuck out of here.
I just want to say is we've been
there for a couple of weeks now,
right?
The coolest thing I've seen is how
the fuck did you hit that target?
My mind,
I could not believe it.
The archery target,
that was an amazing,
well it was.
I would do it every day.
You're taught
sheriff 45 yards and to hit that
little small hole like that is not that
difficult.
You just don't have
training session as well.
So you would have had a bit
of a shake or he was sweating,
but I just broke the
record of kicking that pad.
So I was excited.
That's,
we got an a film.
Luckily we were a little concerned.
We had a splice sound from
the other one because uh,
yeah,
we had more than one
recording of it luckily.
But um,
that thing that uh,
Francis and Ghana punched that
almost as hard as I kicked that.
That's how fucking hard that,
oh,
here it is right here it is
Francis Punch that fucking thing.
That was as hard as,
where's one 52?
That's the highest.
That's the highest anybody's
ever registered on that.
Someone to break it.
Some of them.
I mean,
I don't think that many
people are kicking that thing
a bitch,
but um,
yeah,
that archery thing,
man,
I,
it's the same thing as like,
like today when you were
showing me different things,
like,
like you guys showing me just
a little bit of an adjustment,
change the power of that kick.
Just that little extra salt,
body mechanics,
every,
every strike,
every sweep,
everything I teach is
always body mechanics.
And just like that little bit extra.
We'll get this,
this same thing with archery.
With archery,
it's all about posture and form and
you've got to have your elbow up high and
everything has to be perfect and
you're pulling with your back.
I mean,
there's a lot of parallels
between archery and fighting,
but you just,
you just went truth.
Denay well this was the
outro when he just went,
I thought,
shit,
you don't need to fight.
But I do like again,
I do that every day.
I said,
man,
you know,
I shoot arrows every day and I,
that's a 45 yards of my house.
I do 90 yards.
Yeah.
So that's about as far as it shoot
an animal though was 45 yards.
Like maybe it shoots a pig or something
that nobody gives a shit about.
Like,
well shoot it like seven yards.
You lucky you don't have them in England,
man.
We got problems with them here.
What pig problems are,
they're fucking,
they're invasive species.
They're crazy.
And they breed three,
four times a year they'll
have like 10 12 pigs,
a litter climate at the pigs.
Yeah,
fulltime.
Yeah.
Sounds like my life.
Hi,
Beth.
Knife for tomorrow.
Lisa,
by the way,
sweetie,
you got,
um,
if there's,
there's videos of pigs and Texas.
Texas is so bad that they
opened up a highway and a,
the day they opened it,
they built this highway
in the day they opened it.
There was something like
40 car accidents with pigs.
If people were driving by the pigs run
across the road and they're just slamming
them into up there millions of pigs and
Texas millions while they're an invasive
species.
They were brought over here in
California by William Randolph Hearst.
You know that crazy guy that Orson
Welles made that movie Rosebud about.
He's also the reason why
marijuana's illegal over here too.
He made those propaganda articles blaming
marijuana for causing Mexicans and
blacks to rape white women.
It was this crazy propaganda,
but it was also that he didn't have to
switch his factories over to hemp because
they had come out with a new machine
called the decorticator that allowed them
to process hemp fiber.
Hemp,
hemp just makes it way better paper.
And he had all these paper mills and
all these forests that were dedicated to
trees a day they would make paper out of.
And so when they came out
with this decorticator,
you know,
I felt like,
well hemp is the new industry
is like yet the fuck it is.
And so he this crazy asshole
like literally is the
reason why marijuana is so
illegal and demonized,
not just in America but around the world.
And he led a bunch of fucking
wild pigs loose on his,
his,
his gigantic estate.
These fucking things are everywhere,
bro.
This ain't shit.
I mean these,
these look more like fucking
nightclub in leads design.
These are domestic pigs,
bro.
Jamie,
these are not,
these are not wild pig.
Yeah,
it's shut down a freeway in Texas.
Oh,
you know what it is though.
That's like a truck fell over.
Yeah,
they were inside it.
Yeah.
But those are like regular pigs.
Wild pigs would never be
around a person like that.
They would fucking be out of there.
In Bhutan.
Bhutan puts our country called
Bhutan and Yvette that the,
the feed pigs cannabis,
the cannabis probably tastes good,
but he'd make them delicious.
Bacon gets you high as fuck.
Yes.
You get drug tested like Canelo you go.
It's because
you guys don't believe
Canelo with the Clenbuterol.
I've done a logical of look doorway
that Lord to us.
You got to appreciate Canelo as well.
Right?
I mean the canals,
if that motherfucker,
he's a great fire.
Um,
but I just had the Casie Casie
pastor Gigi when this time.
Yeah,
well I think GGD one the first time.
I do definitely.
I think by two or three rounds,
the first fight I think really I think
keeps out first paper view fight.
I'm first,
you know,
big,
big fine.
Or You could tell that he
didn't see me sell fairly tall.
They took him sort of
three or four to get going.
But when,
when he did and then found that steady
pressure and got behind his job.
Yeah,
yeah.
He's brilliant.
And we've seen that little clip that
he said he's going to change something.
It's going to go to the body more.
You think you should?
I think you should have done that in
the first fight when he was up on the
roads.
Can I little really good at
surveys and he's right underneath.
If he had gotten to the
body then I think plus one.
I think there's going to be a lot of that.
And I think there's
gonna be a lot more jabs.
Jab is just so under age like we did
to David Lemieux smashed him a piece is
where each job.
Yeah.
What Abel Sanchez said that when you,
when he turns to the right,
what happened was the referee was,
because he was turning to is ace.
He's left.
So to get away from the right and yet
it was exposing these back and Gigi had
hit in there.
It was worried about getting a point
taken off so the referee would have called
them on that.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah.
He should be on punch.
The referee was as bad as the judge.
Well,
there was one to late but believable.
Sweet Lady.
Very nice lady.
Thank fuck.
Like lassie is like that light muscle man.
She,
she was responsible for some
wacky ass fucking decisions
and no one does anything about it.
What do you have a man boxing once you
did it in a wholly fully feels cold?
She um,
a part of the whole package out.
Uh,
Tim,
the fuck's his name?
Um,
uh,
oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Wasn't she a part of that?
I know she,
I think she was part of the,
I think she's the one that give Canelo a
draw or against Mayweather when he got,
yeah.
Really?
Yeah.
I think she should be fired.
And that was close to the nice lady again.
Very nice lady.
Stevie wonder boiled of Candela.
Dragons,
Mayweather.
I mean he got fucking
schools in that fight.
Masterful.
Yeah.
Big Time.
I'll get along.
They did it.
Not much,
but not much.
That was an interesting,
well,
in his defense,
Mayweather drained him down to
like have done a one foot two.
They calls that.
Do you know that?
They said,
well we'll find you at one 52.
Elena Delle everyone.
Okay.
Cause he said it was going to do,
it won't 54.
And he says,
we don't care what Gil
downsell bone 52 and they went,
thanks.
He just left herself wide
open to doubt themselves.
It could tell he was
seriously sluggish in mix.
Anyone looks all good stuff.
Don't need to be fair.
Joe.
He does man.
He's amazing.
Like what Floyd is able to do,
like his control of distance and his,
his understanding of what you're
going to do next is so incredible.
Like you see him pop jab and then before
the guy even throws the right hand,
he's like the garden and
the right hand passes him.
He pops with a left
hook and he's out there.
He's like,
Bitch,
I knew what you were going to do.
It did that where it mark
had to do it that way.
They popped him.
Then they were gone.
Right buck of him before I even
realized great things with Roberto,
Roberto,
Roberto Guerrero,
because we've got a boxer in
England called Josh Kelly.
It'd be seen him.
Yes,
I have with that guy.
Yeah.
You guys have a lot of
great boxes over there now.
I mean obviously you have the
world champion and Anthony,
Joshua,
he hit the UFC is going
to offer him $500 billion.
That is fine.
And I wonder if that's real.
They wait,
I wonder if it's real Joshua
verse and then garden with them.
So we're going to sleep.
She's Christ.
I,
you know what I mean?
Francis is a great MMA fighter,
but he's been fighting for five years.
He just hits fucking unbelievably hard.
Can't believe that you said he
got under in 2001 20 something.
I think.
Find out what it's playing on.
That's so crazy.
This is what I get with a kick.
You legs,
it carry you around all day.
I'm only hundred behind him.
Well you know,
in his defense he's a hundred pounds
heavier than maybe with just what in the
fuck his hands are so big.
Every time I shake his hands I'm like,
how is that a person?
I mean it's like,
it's like shaking hands with a brick,
like a giant brick.
They're just so big.
I've got a little baby and as
well they probably crush mine.
Yeah,
fucking huge dude,
man.
I mean,
and we were talking before about how his,
uh,
in his background,
he worked as a child in a sand mine,
digging sand just all day digging sand.
Like what a,
what a great workout
that is for your boss.
Go Star is ridiculous.
Or let's say we're almost fucked with
five years ago at UFC title and came real
close if anybody else
other than Steepbanks tpa.
So fucking tough and skilled
and kept away from him.
But well you saw what he did to
Overeem k one Grand Prix champion,
dream champion,
Strikeforce heavyweight champion.
Frances put him into
orbit is Agnelli came off,
he showed his mind were ridiculous
and you could see the way over he was
fighting him tooth.
It's like Yo,
where the fuck up at any moment is
this it 129,161 I got one fifth,
what was it?
One 50 to two that was today though.
The other day I got,
I was super fucking happy with uh,
Taiwan spawn.
What's the former previous record?
One 14.
He's got 1209000100 61 with a punch.
I got one 52 today,
bitch.
But that's what his arms man.
I mean that is,
it's,
it's possible to really overemphasize
how fucking crazy that kind of power is
with your bigger than
my legs ought to have a,
Oh yeah,
no,
don't pick it.
The mind like saint my legs.
Well a guy like that,
I believe Francis is 33 I mean,
imagine if they caught him
when he was 24 you know,
I mean,
imagine that guy.
It's like,
that's what you were saying before.
It's when you get a real champion,
what you're getting is the top genetics,
the tops,
talent,
skill,
mindset and disciplines
and the one in one in it.
That's the main thing.
Because a lot,
a lot of fighters,
a lot of nod fight and they'll go,
oh,
I've seen this again in our gym.
They'll get out,
they'll have one,
but the fight will have been hard.
And I remember saying,
no,
come backward.
I thought,
what a hot fucking fight it's
going to be is meant to be odd.
Yeah.
He's meant to,
you know,
he signed it up for you.
You know what you do.
And then I've never seen him again.
Yeah.
So that they'll kind of it as well.
I mean,
certain amount of,
of real sort of you is to be world
champion pretty much straight away.
Didn't you when you started?
Yeah,
of course.
He was 19 when you went,
you,
first of all.
So it's crazy.
First Time I fought Sanjaya we're 21.
What's going on with Giorgio Petrosyan?
A ace fine and on,
um,
uh,
won championships.
Oh,
he's fighting now.
They've got to stand up now.
Yeah.
Sign like Fabio pinker [inaudible] Cli.
They signed yachts,
yachts and Clyde retirees back again.
Fought last month and he wanted
to him a couple of weeks off
that guy.
Get fucking punch man for south
Florida's we'll call that guy is starches
people.
I remember,
I remember when they
Jordan for him in Thailand.
I went the corner for Jordan and Jordan
came back at the end around two or gum.
She'll die when I went.
Oh,
my teeth are in it.
It's not totally deep.
Wow.
Jordan and real close fight with him.
He is,
was had the first time.
I can't,
no,
I remember Jordan's.
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean it's uh,
it did,
the level of talent these days
is just so fucking amazing.
And one is one FC really huge in Asia,
like how they've got,
and they like UFC level.
Michael Chavela was doing that.
I love that guy.
He's now a fitness slide,
like free different,
they've got the MMA and then they've
got the hybrid or is Moitai in little
gloves in the cage,
like John Wayne Parks,
the take EMT,
and then they've got just a standup
Moitai with eight ounce gloves and I'll
raise it cable under the
cable with the eight ounce gloves.
So they're gonna freeze separate things.
Now there's certain guys that you
just see a silhouette of them.
Even if you didn't see their face,
you would know who it was.
Yeah.
You know,
my favorite that is San Chai.
Like if you saw a silhouette
of him just moving around,
you'd be like,
oh yeah,
fine.
Free Times.
I'm used to in boot in
me all over the place.
What does that like fighting that guy?
You know what it wants
so much power or any,
he's accurate.
If he wants to hit you
straight on the chin,
you will hit your stride on the chin.
She wants to kick you
clean across the ribs.
He'll kick it clean across the ribs.
The first time I fought him,
ironic 21 it,
we're real close fight.
I just showed him a little
bit too much respect.
So again,
like I was saying about the,
I don't want to fight
earlier I was saying,
get me pretty much get me really much.
I could do better than that can do better.
And I honestly believed
going into that fight,
I,
we're going to win.
And in the second fight with absolutely
smashed each of it to smithereens.
I caught him really bad.
I rocked him,
appoint cheese,
he hurt me.
Um,
as well of a punch and wobbled Maya legs.
We absolutely buttered each of her.
I remember in round four,
I won the fourth round and
he went grit in the corner.
I went and sat down and went,
fucking hell.
I'm gonna wind here.
I'm going to win by the
time around five and up.
And again,
I'll call her back in skin.
I blinked and he'd
kicked me about 16 times.
And how the fuck did he do that?
I ended up round to my coach and my
coach went cause he's sunshine and a
champion for nothing.
It's his eyes and stuff
like that second fight.
Even though I lost days,
one of my favorites because to be able
to push the greatest of all time well or
at least of the last 25 years into that
deep water and they are really proud of
that and it [inaudible]
our best moments in spot.
And even said afterwards
said that one of my,
one of my toughest fights.
But we're good.
We're good friends now and stuff and um,
I'll probably go over to Thailand
and train with him at some point.
What amazes me about him is his movement.
He's very unusual and the way he moves
around a light on his feet again and out
and switch the stances constantly and
is very creative with his approaches.
Like he does all sorts of weird shit.
Like there's one fight,
it's on his um,
San Chai,
Thailand.
Um,
Instagram.
He,
he's got a guy up against the ropes and
he steps hard to the right and throws a
left high cabinet texted me that off.
It's like straight up in the air.
But if you watch what
he does first like this,
if you watch what I do is first I think
he sets it up by kicking the leg and,
and bringing me over one over it.
But you see the master of Arts to Florida.
I remember the first time I fought him,
he jumped in the air and I looked up
and I got kicked in the leg and I'd fall
the fuck with other dot.
Don't look at him.
And he had it.
But I mean like got kicked and
I'm thinking how did they do that?
And then when I watched
it back I realized,
and yeah,
some of the stuff that he does,
no one else can do that.
He's so creative
and that's what you get with these
guys as well as sees everything
that they've said.
Same sorts that he's a
Llama Chenko Muay Thai.
Right.
Definitely.
The way he even,
he hits pads are different.
Like the way you hit paths,
what he's,
he's just tapping,
he pop pop,
but he's not hitting it
and now over the last,
but you don't want to
get hit by any of it.
But he's like constantly moving
when he wants to it hard as well.
Like kind of like I said a few
times easily clean on chin.
And I remember thinking fucking hell,
I want expecting that.
Yeah.
Where it's like working the pads,
like when you see the way he throws kicks,
like he's not,
he's not like,
and he could probably
do that shit all day,
just so loose and flexible,
but,
but he's a fucking tremendous fighter man.
And he stayed,
must be faced 7.8 now and he's still,
is he 38 met 37 38
that's why it's amazing.
Yeah.
And he's still wiping the floor with
most of the incredible people who fight.
I mean,
and just constant movement and attack his,
his pressure and his,
the volume of strikes that he throws.
I mean,
he's a fucking unbelievable fighter man.
Yeah,
definitely a pro.
The best of out out
over the last 20 years.
I mean even did one fight
in the stadiums in Thailand.
Two on one and in this one,
one one,
and this was this,
we're only about five,
six years ago.
Pet Boone.
True.
So I get now,
so essentially we're ranking
board punchy with number two.
So I got no problem number three.
And these weren't like
less fight as an AME.
He farm two on one.
How the fuck did he do that?
Sag it down.
Got It.
Not a pit bull jewel got him for the
first two rounds fault and he went out and
we just try to wear him down and
clinch him for the last three rounds.
Saget dodgem team fresh Sanjoy one.
Wow.
Paul pet plan.
She's a clincher.
The [inaudible] tried to wear him down.
That is fucking insane.
Oh there we go.
So he fought one guy for two rounds
and then the second guy for him fresh.
Yeah.
Unbelievable man.
That is unbelievable.
The size difference as well.
The last mile is bigger
than him that he's like,
well he's always fighting bigger guys.
Right?
He got to do a giveaway in the stadiums
with the other bet in works out there.
No one had been a bet of.
Sunshine comes in at one three five and
pat Boone trail comes in at one 45 no
one's going to bet because they
know essentially is going to win.
But of sunshine comes in at one fair and
pet boot shoe comes in at one 44 then
he's even any up a little bit.
Then the gamblers,
we'll all get on it and he's going to,
that's what's also interesting
about Thailand is that the gambling,
it's such a giant part of the sport
influences it so big and it influences the
scarring in the decisions
and stuff like that.
But what about like guys fixing fights
you whereby [inaudible] you're worried
about fighters,
froing fights,
but then they'll get thrown
out steady in the world.
Be a of fight,
but can they do hear about that a lot?
Y'all swear about people dropping stuff
in people's drinks to try and just like
give them a little of bunny
so when they're gamblers,
yeah,
that happens a lot to me.
Got Pies.
And when he fought Sros
in Chelsea and said to me,
whether it's true or not,
don't know.
So don't quote me on it.
But the,
he told me that when he fought none,
Nathan Pauper mock,
he said they gave,
they gave him a drink and he said he
was dizzy and that because they will not
fight.
I think the ad about a million bucks
side but so it's about 20 grand side bet
their gym and this gym.
So you do it,
do Arabic stuff happening like that.
Wow.
That sucks.
That's a wild ass fucking place.
Thailand,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I'm sure.
Yeah.
I love it.
I love,
I love going to the foods that,
you know,
especially coastal maybe when I go,
yeah I love Thai food.
Beautiful coast from HP to fall.
But you know,
you know bank cops,
beautiful thing.
I scratch too much time in Bangkok.
I lived there for like
18 months to two years.
So yeah.
So whenever I go now I prefer to go to
the island so I can train and then relax.
Cause when I went,
I was just living in the gym
all the time and I couldn't,
I don't think I could do that anymore.
Now it's for to now could
go silk sheets baby.
Yeah,
I can train odd.
And then I come in.
You had the,
I'm fingers.
I were locked in a room in the gym with
nothing but a fun blowing hot air on me.
No Air Con.
Oh,
it ties it all at foster sleep snoring.
And I'm just there sweating me at off
and having two hours sleep a night and I
couldn't do that anymore.
Now I don't know.
I like,
I go to the island,
I can still train just as art.
There's some great coaches.
I still barren can go to the beach,
you can relax.
And it's like [inaudible]
is that where you go?
Uh,
[inaudible] it's um,
that is put out a safe place to go to.
Yeah.
You know,
you know,
silence safe everywhere you go.
They used to like seeing junkin
not that I ever drink over that
stumbling down the road for rangs.
We'd like,
lady,
please wait.
And
you hear horror stories or stories about,
uh,
Thailand in the media and stuff like that.
There's horror stories everywhere you go.
Yeah.
I've all the time I spent there.
I've never seen that one
too odd up and really,
no,
never.
That's amazing.
Even obviously it does happen,
but it happens everywhere.
John Wayne,
parts of the same thing.
So it goes over there.
Is that everyone's lovely.
Yeah.
Yes.
And he has happened to where I'd been
serious jam and spent time with him.
He's another one that if
you saw his silhouette,
you'd absolutely,
no,
it was him.
Cause he's so,
he's got such an odd style of movement.
You know,
like there's a video of him go
to John Wayne,
pars Instagram.
Well he's changed his style a lot now
because obviously when he lived in
Thailand,
he act to fight the thigh where
[inaudible] but like since he's back in
Australia now and you can adapt to it
all that because he's such a good puncher
as well.
They can fight both ways.
I'm sure if we ever fought in time
in which you don't need to anymore,
he's done all that.
But if he did,
I'm sure we know to go get this.
Like the way he moves,
it's a hundred percent John Wayne par.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
I mean it's very fascinating.
Like you,
if you watched him,
you would know for sure.
If you didn't see as if
just saw the silhouette,
you're like,
oh yeah,
it's chatwing parks.
Definitely.
He's got some engine,
any fighting or getting
to weekend training,
like fucking savage
knocking people out as well.
And one of the nicest guys you ever
want to meet just couldn't be nicer.
Yeah,
his wife's nice and and kit.
Have you seen his son
Jesse doing flips and Chet?
Yeah.
And His dad was a killer.
We made me and a fault on the same show
in August last year and now she come
over,
she beat a British girl and she's,
she thought this my training in my garage
and just watching him kick the bag,
I was like,
holy fuck.
That guy kicked him.
Right.
He comes down a lot of weight as well.
Wp.
Yeah.
I think I've seen him before in him like
85 kilos and then like two free week
later,
boom.
72.5 shredded,
big fan of Australia.
I'm a big fan of Australia.
They're just nice people now.
The base never been.
It's fucking great.
Everything can kill you though.
Don't leave to the s shock spider snake,
Sasquatch.
Every that begins with s
in Australia will kill you.
Yeah,
and I don't like any of
them things and crocodiles,
some season tickets.
Fine.
It's a crazy fucking place.
But you know,
that's a,
they're pretty close to Thailand,
right?
Six hour flight.
It's a slow,
it's on it.
It's like that Spain,
isn't it?
I mean,
when you know,
and they go get John Cargo
and package holidays.
He goes to Spain.
Thailand's the DAS.
Bain.
Rarely.
Is that what you guys do?
You go to Spain.
What are you going to Spain?
Yeah.
I mean,
y'all can love me.
[inaudible] me and my wife got me.
I'll call you up and be Oka Majorca.
I got ob for with all my friends were,
that'd be for,
oh,
a Beazer easy.
You guys say it,
but it's a z.
How's it a thug?
Semite Chavon it's say a band.
Yeah,
and I dunno.
A beaver is a weird one.
I've heard people say that.
I'm like,
where are you talking to beat that down.
That's as a Beazer what did you just say?
I'm too old to go to a bay for now.
Just below.
You know,
that's a spinning thing,
right?
Like they use they,
there's a lot of thug,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
No.
Yeah,
true.
probably.
He's so good.
Fighters from Spain as well.
Fuck yeah.
Well Europe is always had
like ridiculous Moitai talent.
The French are outside time and
I think it's probably France.
Then England was that guy
that went to a John Mark.
What is his name that got Bosky?
Yes,
he would grab fire rock when
it came into the MMA champion,
a bright man and he was that
drunk and fucked him all up.
It was up night drinking at a bar,
like went to a club,
was drinking,
came and smelled like shit.
Had a fucking like a glass with him of
alcohol like and then put on the pads
like go put on the gloves and
beat the shit out of here.
We're dropping them all at everything,
but you want him around?
I think you're going to rank number one
at Raj and I'm gonna instead him when he
were fighting until you were like top,
top level and he's promoting,
I'll put it on that.
Real good shows.
Really good shells.
Yes.
Crazy thing about him is he
doesn't look like anything.
No,
he never looked in
great shape or anything,
but when he fought pick up fucks people
like that.
Then he thought he could catch the legs
and sweep the ties and put you asleep
when he John Wayne puppy even
though didn't he standing on.
What will great about Skrebowski though?
It used to fight from one 40 up to one
six five it will no wear close for him.
When you said there's a fire at
one six five you want to do it,
you go.
Yeah,
and then he'd go fight installed.
You've got fight two weeks,
one 41 route.
I've got the work done voice.
So yeah,
that's why you were so,
so good.
Now you see a lot of a traditional
karate style in a MMA now where a lot of
these guys are learning how to fight a
different way and throws people off with
like front leg sidekicks,
wider stance.
Is that hopping is it wouldn't
have boy who fights like yes,
but you don't see that in more tie.
We'll talk about tension,
tension.
The kid from Japan,
the new kid,
he was really in the south part of,
I love how you say his last name,
not so not so Carla.
Yeah,
fucking amazing.
He meets these two actually these Haman,
Zachary and the and the,
they won't let him fight the same way.
It's was just wanting the k one.
Thank you.
60 kilos or something.
He's gone on.
We showed a video of Taco
respiring the other day.
[inaudible] horrible.
Yeah,
it's horrible.
But you know,
tension came from originally from karate.
He's doing karate as a kid.
And the thing is,
he's been knocking out ties as well
because he's unpredictable and you don't
know what's going so fast as well.
If you can get that balance
and in Muay Thai he,
he's going to be a bit difficult.
But for care one,
yeah,
yeah.
But he see so many different kids.
He's Moroccan kids coming from
infusion at the minute that I just,
you know,
I'm like,
wow,
he's amazing.
He's in that.
He's just lazy kitchens.
Only 18,
right?
Maybe 19.
Now we have a CSA.
We have a fire called uh,
uh,
I really,
from,
from Holland and he's spot and you're
like kid you see in the 18 year old Tyson,
Tyson [inaudible] and just
knocking blocks spark in them.
It's just like there's some
dangerous boys about it.
I'm so glad I'm old.
I am so glad.
The old fella,
it's a,
it is amazing how our combat sports,
just like any other sport,
they just,
the new talent just learns from the old
ways and they get better and better.
I mean,
it's just there.
There's better talent today and evolving
and evolving all the time in MMA in
particular because it's
such a recent sport.
I mean Emma amazed really only been around
like popular since the 1993 somewhere
around there.
So if you look at like
1993 MMA versus thousand 18
so it's like fucking the
light years difference,
but Moitai it's more incremental.
Right.
And it's not,
it's better but not as much better.
No,
that the westerners are,
they're coming.
Oh so much quicker out there now.
Yeah,
I just think it's the opportunities
that it again fro and now with like the
likes of Y'all called the likes of,
you know,
all the promotions,
the upbringing.
I'm free.
I know we've just got some really
good like Daniel McGowan and his last
performance Efr and he's east
going to go and live in patching.
Dino is sponsored by them.
He was absolutely superb.
We've got some,
I'm very proud of our country
when it comes to my tie.
I'm very,
very proud of it because
I've been in the days where,
even before Liam,
I've been up 34 years,
I've been involved in it.
And just seeing ties come over and
beat the shit out of people like that.
Oh fuck.
And the game grew up.
I love it.
The likes of this one here
in the likes of other people,
uh,
have given us a better chance.
You know,
so it's the fights.
Some all competitive and ties are starting
to train the train folium like they
trained for him.
Like I know that my life
pat trains solidly for him
when he fought him on that.
Yeah.
It never did.
It never train trains one week for a fact.
The,
you were telling me before,
I've trained two months for
this health trend to mumps.
Where'd you find him?
On what car lion fight.
It was the line of Fire Arb.
You won't be in my points on that.
Yeah.
Oh,
I saw that fight.
Yeah,
that was fun.
It was good fight sweeping him.
Yeah,
that was good.
Fine.
One judge.
Give it fucking 50,
46 to him.
Really?
Yeah.
It was at the late bird.
So lion fight hasn't had
a fight in a long time.
I'm a,
I haven't heard anything that they
didn't used to be with access TV,
but then I don't think they are anymore
that working with the MTG P it's run by
a Karen catalogs with the the one the
empty.
Yeah.
Did they have an American outlets?
I actually don't know.
So fuck,
they need something in America.
So what big one as well
at one point they were,
you know like access TV is mark
Cuban's network and it's a,
they've got a lot of great fights on it.
It's they,
they've always had like a real good
strong Moitai and combat sports elder
Jacada.
Yeah.
And while they have,
um,
pat millages is doing commentary
for MMA this weekend with that,
but it's just they're missing the,
you know,
the wide distribution of like a fox or
fs one or things that have gotten the UFC
so popular.
Yeah,
they've got,
um,
they've got to standout fighters as well.
Really,
I think the need mohs timeout fight is
they get their fight is like on big show.
The broaden that they've got.
Kevin Ross,
obviously the shielding as well,
but he's more MMA in k one and Anjan
topic and they are like the two that
everyone says about the
normally tie in America,
right.
Ross topic there,
the tour to come straight up,
but still Schilling is a,
they're all fighting Beltour now toxic.
That's jumping,
which is great.
It's great.
I'm a big fan of Bela Tarr kickboxing,
but again,
it's kickboxing and stumbled on top.
I prefer to work Kevin Fight.
Moitai could he cook?
He likes to go on a wall,
so it's exciting to watch him do that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Won't let you say it limits what?
A Muay Thai fighter.
Yes.
An English girl called [inaudible]
Barlow is Enfusion champion as well,
and she's a lion fight.
Muy Thai champion.
She's that.
She's won 10 world titles.
He is at 140 fights and she
fighting since she was four.
What?
Yeah,
yeah.
The,
She's from DSRC issue in a train
by that man Barlow of clip clipper,
her offering quality.
Have you seen it when she kicked
and she kicked 10 times girl,
nine times in a row go Bam,
Bam,
Bam.
Right,
right,
right.
What is her name?
Mri in particular.
Barlow.
Spell that.
Uh,
um,
MRI is a I.
M a n like Iman.
Marlo.
Yeah.
I'm on Barlow for left door
shifts your battery if you
see her when she sees me.
But uh,
yeah,
she's a great fighter and you know,
in,
uh,
where's your accent?
You guys,
is this Liverpool?
I live in Liverpool,
but I'm originally from Manchester.
So what does the difference to
your accent and Olivia Talk?
Very posh compared to deliver it.
You tasteless.
Scousers talk like that.
He talked like,
wait,
it's her luck.
My wife,
my wife Lisa scale.
So yeah.
Is this the one?
Yeah,
it's not the fire.
Um,
that's serious.
I think.
Keeps Marina's waiver.
The bow head kick to the
body and then to the head.
Damn.
Fuck.
Yeah.
That's the thing about legs,
man.
I mean,
every woman that weighs 130 pounds is
carrying 130 pounds around all day with
their legs.
Try walking around in your hands all day.
Yeah.
Women can knock you the fuck out.
Then when she wished she had one 15.
Yeah,
she's only small.
She sounds really nice.
He's like,
oh no.
Dot though for a girl
to have 100 plus fights.
He's,
it's ridiculous really
when you think about it.
But she's still smashing
it and she's doing,
she is,
she's one about 95,
96%.
Yeah.
She asked you,
how old are you now,
Liam?
30 too.
So you're still in your prime right now?
I would think so.
Again.
I mean,
um,
my last 10 fights,
I've probably one eight.
Um,
the two losses have been on
points one to Fabio pinker,
top level operator,
um,
and another one in front of a
French boy rub off on points.
But all my fights in between that,
I've even knocked him out.
I'll stop them.
And I've,
I feel when I'm trading,
I don't want to fight and
I feel like I'm in prime.
I feel like I'm stronger than ever.
I feel like I'm faster than ever and
sharp or whenever I've still got the
hunger.
Um,
I'm still really wanting
to fight all the time.
We saw all I'm concentrating on
as well as training overs as well.
But my sole intention is still,
I've still got goals.
That's the thing.
Like I know I've had a
lot of fights and stuff,
but I've still got goals that I
want to achieve and I want to do.
And I'm like what are the,
um,
well I want to WBC title in 2015 and um,
you can see I've got a metal plate in me.
I'm there,
I brought my hand and they didn't even
give me a chance to strip me of the belt
straight away.
It didn't give me chance to say,
right,
we're a few months defense.
We can defend it then just stripped me
of it and now other people have won it
and stuff.
So I want to win that belt buck.
And I've let
in your hand,
they just stripped you.
You had to just took it off my hair.
Why they do that?
I don't know.
I think they wanted the French
boy why we went to defend against,
to fight for it.
Cause it was in front.
So they'll let him fight for
it and he won it and stuff.
But now I think the title is vacant.
Oh well something.
I think the champions moved away.
It's become vacant again.
I probably shouldn't be saying this,
but I am fighting for it later
on in the year against a real,
real strong fire as well.
Um,
I,
I don't think he's been released.
I'm not last say,
I don't think he's going to be probably
one of biggest vice Britain seen in a
long time.
So obviously I've got that
looking forward to in July,
massive,
massive.
I'm defending my UK number one spot.
I've been looking
forward to this for ages.
I've been number one in new care for
about 13 years and that was a lot of talk
about a Guy Charlie p as
number two in the rankings.
Climbed his way up.
I had some big wins and he shot,
he's got the old country divided.
It's not fee south.
I'm from Leeds,
which is up north.
He's from London,
which is down south.
He's got the country divided.
Um,
he's R and d shops.
I'm really looking forward to that.
That's a bit of a grudge match.
Yeah,
you could say it not dark
and going on a little bit.
A little bit.
I'm fucking useless.
It shits well.
I like it.
Throw an insole out there.
They just don't even make no sense.
And I got,
what the fuck am,
I just don't know.
I just look a complete idiot.
Funny marry you.
They're good at that shit or you.
Yay.
Connor's got a gift.
You know Conor McGregor
good at it as well.
Leo?
I mentioned earlier.
He's good at he's,
I have no fucking useless.
So as keep my mouth shut.
So where's the best way that
most people can watch you fight?
Like a lot of these fights,
you're going to have to watch
him after the fact in America,
right?
Um,
yeah.
Most of them do come straight on
youtube or some of the cow puts them on.
They put them on their youtube channels.
And is it just your cow?
Why?
Oh K K A.
Oh yeah.
I mean that's,
that's the one that Liam
fights on this a lot.
I comment.
Say on them a lot,
which are very privileged to do.
But yeah,
living this other outlets you'd be
typing laymen in Youtube will have it.
They can watch him.
I love the way you commentate cause you
always say something and you say isn't
he?
He's winning.
Isn't he beautiful?
Like that's an English thing man.
You like you like you say something but
then you also want everybody to agree
with you I think.
I think it's kind of a,
I'm quarter Welsh and the whilst do
that so maybe that's a DNA thing.
It all the time I say,
Oh you good in one way you're
[inaudible] all the time.
I've got that one.
Just did.
We knew out loud why.
Notice that when I was in England.
Just having conversations with people
that that's like a speech pattern that
people do it where I
learn something everyday.
I first heard you when you were doing,
it's showtime when
you're doing commentary.
I remember hearing that,
like this guy always does that.
And he says that after some of the,
some of the things,
I mean there was,
there was one fight where
Mohammed CML and a Ma sub,
I'm Ronnie and I got fucking bananas
and looking back at it now I'm thinking,
but they loved it and so do yours.
We liked who was screaming like pitch
squeaky voice.
It makes the fight exciting
then Kabil so I spend that
much time in Holland anyway.
But uh,
yeah,
so thanks for that.
A real pioneers right when it comes
to like expanding into more Thai and
kickboxing.
Wow.
How did that happen?
Like the Dutch,
it was a pure Kachin base originally,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
you've got to thank people like Johan Vos,
um,
Tom Herink,
and uh,
young Plas,
Vuss trained,
uh,
Ivan hyppolite enesto host a Shakuri Kid,
dad batter from the beginning,
prs,
et cetera.
And,
and they,
the pioneers and then what now they've
got so many good gyms coming through and
so many kids that they had,
it's like the fight,
like you stole something from them.
They just blitzkrieg each other.
And the Thai version of
the ties in Thailand.
Moroccans,
they're like NK one there.
That version,
the soul out to beat.
I know Liam Liam loves
Moitai and you know,
I try and talk to Leah about
kickbox and he just gets annoyed.
But um,
it's true though.
It like,
it just points out you
don't watch kickboxing.
I will.
If it had been,
he says,
watch this fight is amazing.
I watch it.
I won't go out.
I'm aware to watch it.
I don't know.
I just thought this dog
isn't that interesting.
He likes what he likes and that's it.
You know,
that's how there's a big
thing with a lot of Americans,
you know,
when it comes to like,
I've tried to show American fight fans
Moitai even like good buddies of mine.
Like,
how the fuck can you not like this?
Yeah.
It's what people like.
And he's like,
I used to like watch boxing,
but now I've been watching,
uh,
like movement specialists,
you know,
I've been doing all
that movement and stuff.
I've started doing it and especially
I trained with a guy called dom met and
now and he's a student of Edo puts up
and I like watching that and Simon
self just sat there watching man in men
swinging it around and rings for,
you know what that's called?
It's called mental pause ball.
Certain staff what?
That's definitely definitely true.
I worked with done not long buck and
some of the stuff he does is amazing from
way Tyler,
obviously you hip flexor and stuff
that are working all the time.
Some of the like the different
stuff that we're doing always.
I get really tight run.
We have some stuff on.
I'm kicking all the time and not,
some of the stuff that he showed me
and we worked with were unbelievable.
I felt so much looser
and we love that guy.
Yeah.
Have you ever done any yoga?
No.
I did a hot yoga once and I nearly died,
so I'll do that one again.
I should do it to be fair,
but I think now that I've found done and
all the different stuff that he showed
me,
I think,
no blah blah.
It can replace any,
any sort of yoga I shouldn't be doing
because this stuff is is amazing.
I think you would be a good compliment
to your style cause their stylists.
Fuck yeah,
you're so tense and powerful that I would
think that like maybe that will open
you up a little bit of
that stuff that Dan does.
Does he like,
he's opening using
different joints and stuff.
Putting me in positions that I'm not
used to and three Farah is is odd,
but after you've done it and you,
after you've done the workout and stuff,
he's join.
Yeah.
You just feel loose and he feel amazing.
It's brilliant.
It really,
very good
sell every Wednesday morning
and I don't want to go,
I'll fucking tell you the truth.
I'm driving down that
it's an hour away from me.
I'm thinking fuck this and
then I get there and it's just,
it's just a very,
very special.
How illegal is weed in England?
I'm not in sweat.
Me.
Listen Bro,
take two solid hits and
then go to yoga class.
It's on solid hit from behind in run
back on myself or I'm telling you,
it's not for me to see American wheat
get ahold of some of this California shit
orbit serious two hits and
then go to a yoga class.
It's like you're on a journey.
You're like,
you get out of their hour and a half late,
it's perfect cause an hour
and a half into the sweating,
the pots worn off and you're like,
you come back down.
We'll put in the middle of it.
You feel like the world's going to end
any second now and in the middle of the
class,
like there's no way this
could be sustainable.
There's no way I'm not going to survive.
Did the whole way you just think about
everything that's going on up in Tracy.
Again,
I'm a Joe will like a house on fire.
My Dad,
not me.
I can't do it.
Don't agree with me.
I love it for Yoga.
Small.
My favorite things ever take
two hits and go to yoga class.
When you stone,
you can't not be on stone quick.
He just like,
Oh shit.
Tomorrow.
No,
there's nowhere enough.
Quick.
Yeah.
Caffeine helps a little bit.
Coffee.
I remember Jordan give
me a drop of cannabis,
I will be fine.
I like melted into we for for about six
hours in a conch move and I'm thinking
I'm dead.
I'm Sam,
I'm doing it.
Yeah.
This time,
last time I was a a high at someone,
I add some cannabis oil and I was sat
there watching TV and then I was like
fucking hell of those mine.
And then they got the remote control
from the TV and this guy was getting a
little older and I turned
him over and I went,
Huh.
To me fucking self.
And then I knew for not,
it's not for you to as well.
It's just one of those
things like anything else,
you've got to ease into it.
You know what,
I don't understand what you're saying.
Yeah.
I'd like that for just relaxation,
reflection,
you know?
Yeah.
I think it's also great for like
pain management and like just,
you know,
after you're done training,
everything's sore.
Your shoulders,
your elbows.
Well my mom and dad,
they both love it,
but I've just never been able to me.
And what I tried to drag before and I
nearly had the fucking paranoid Taco.
Yeah.
Cause he had to go hide to dig a little.
Yes.
But those are those type of guy
that I'm all on north India.
I mean,
so yeah,
I'm sure every aspect of your approach
where you approach Moitai that could be a
real fucking child in
Potsdam as all in Potsdam.
Never.
Diana said,
right.
Just just bang.
Not just that,
just,
okay.
Just Bang.
Get that.
So you're trying to like get
him to settle down and he yeah,
no,
no.
Where near the level of his
coach are just old parts in the,
in the,
in the way the icon.
I'm more of a boxing holding pads for
boxing because he's no way he's evil paths
for Jordan Watson and
I am not holding paths.
I'm not very experienced in that.
Again,
I'm an old man and I'm not
old in Potsdam and John
and get twice as out as me as well.
He's kicks up solutely redeem it probably
breaks straight through that machine
out there.
Yeah,
it's an absolute nightmare
holding parts for him,
I'm sure.
Yeah.
I've seen him fight.
I saw him fight Georgio too.
Got caught with that critic.
Look,
it was a fatal mistake that
[inaudible] has got such good eyesight.
The East,
just
before it got off,
50 years ago,
this kid,
my box of fighting and we went in and
we heard about this kid geology patrol.
She was like,
right,
whatever.
Yes,
he's on beat and Blah,
blah,
blah.
Fuck off,
fuck off.
They just trying to scare you.
Don't worry.
My box went out.
He was a great fighter himself.
Rick Barn,
a lovely kid,
got his own gym and a fall block by Bam.
Slip,
got cough drops,
body shot,
and then he got up again.
Body shot,
leg kick,
banged,
and he'd come back and he said,
I call it unethical to them that I said,
you fucking couldn't.
I'll tell you what the
most of this kid special,
impressive thing about him as well.
Here's the watch the videos at ventings
to send men and it looks all right.
I commentated with anyone's live on him
and I just saw the subtle stuff that he
does.
Book cloth on the little slips,
the little step off himself.
Softball and I just said to Vinny,
I'd like took the microphone.
This is fucking unreal.
Just a sort of stuff,
which is what makes it a
level above anyone else.
He's the grass k one fighter of all
time and I mean he puts what he does.
He's in a gate.
She,
it negates your rhythm so that when the
Dutch fight they don't fight mainly in
combination.
The Firefox fast hands,
fast kicks.
They find him straight away,
but he negates that first
shot and then he'd step off so
he puts that right Paul,
you fight southpaw.
Yeah,
that's right.
Right palm out.
He throws a lot of teeth,
kicks off the right front leg is strong
as well as he's deceptively strong as
Armenian.
He's not actually
Italian is his real name.
Gleevec is real.
He called him George Arbitration,
but his real name's Gleevec.
They changed it because it's
more palatable for the Italians,
but he's a,
yeah,
he's a very,
very special individual.
So technical.
Yeah.
In a really interesting
guy to watch him train too.
Yeah.
I love,
I love watching them on pallets.
Not Nothing's done override or anything.
It's all just done.
Perfect.
Every shot the perfect.
Yeah.
I mean again,
like everybody's got their own style.
So that's one of the beautiful things
about [inaudible] is that like the,
the art is very straight forward.
You have your eight weapons but it's
like how you apply those is all based on
creativity,
your own personal preferences to the
grip thing about like when you watch the
top ties in Thailand,
you love,
I'm a technician but then you'll have
a big clincher and the might be getting
the floor with them outside the clinic,
but as soon as they grumbled and they
stopped buying in big needs in and stuff,
he's going to make the fight a
lot more interest in its end.
The technician's job to
keep him off the team,
to move to score your cakes.
And that's what the great
thing about mortality.
What I'm saying,
that's why I love it so much.
Well that's why I think it's the best
striking style is because it incorporates
so much grappling.
There's so much sweeps and clinch and
knee work and controlling the back of the
neck and you know,
this is just,
it's so effective.
It's to take that out.
Like when I watch a boxing
match and they're like break,
I'm like,
why break?
And yeah,
we'll go back and watch
Jack Johnson place.
You ever watch old Jack Johnson fights?
I've never seen
the shit out of everybody in clinch skill
where you see that was a heavy weight
from England knee.
He used to,
he used the clinch.
I was saying it's been working with Liam
and doing the seminars that we've been
doing.
I've been doing it a long time
and I'm watching him and I'm gone.
No,
I didn't know.
And it's been brilliant for me to fall
in love with [inaudible] again because
you'll see what he doesn't it.
I don't know that I thought,
well,
there's so much to boxing,
right?
I mean,
when you see a guy like a Floyd
Mayweather or a real technician like Loma
Chanko,
just use so much to learn now.
Leg Kicks,
knees,
head kicks,
elbows clench,
all this other stuff.
And more tie is almost never ending.
I say all the time,
I've been trading for 20
years and I learn every day.
Every day.
I will learn just summit new,
whether it's from someone
in the gym or be inspiring,
whether it's from a cork,
Richard Barrett from a youtube video
or watching a fight in Thailand.
Some I'm still learning every single day,
and I remember my trainer from Thailand,
Jay,
when I will live in there,
he was saying,
I'm 50 years old.
I've been doing this for years.
He said,
I learn every day as well.
That's never right.
Yeah.
He's never ending.
That's why I'm in love with it so much.
Jujitsu is very similar,
I could imagine.
Yeah.
I can imagine MMA being exactly the same,
but the rest of them,
the Jujitsu,
it's one of those things that
on the outside you don't see it.
The closer you get to it,
the more you real.
I was like,
wow,
this thing is like never ending.
Yeah.
You know what?
I'll be honest,
I've not met anyone that
had rarely disliking it.
They're all pretty decent,
aren't they nice people and it
did not fuck out of each of them.
The light jazz.
Talk about a character developer.
I mean what develops your
character more than combat sports?
You find out who the fuck you are.
Yeah,
exactly.
And that's what we'll come back to.
What I was saying earlier,
you find out who you are.
Some people think folk lists at that me
over people said fuck yeah let's do that
again.
That you know what I mean?
Yeah.
And that's that all the best fighters
are all the most best people you're going
to meet as well.
I think like look it up.
Much of a gentleman petroleum is.
Yeah it is.
Absolutely.
You know what was funny about the fight
with Jordan Potosi in a very similar
characters that are very,
very nice people.
I mean Jordan is an absolute,
you won't think Jordan was a
fire even though when I met him,
super sweetheart,
lovely guy.
But you know,
and then you then at the end of the fight
with Giorgio Petrosyan Joshi and runs
over,
but he's had on him because he helps him.
Cause I think like a truck,
like,
and I think he understood that it was a
fight once it's over the bells ring in.
I said to him,
cause I messaged Giorgio patrol,
she said,
you,
you know,
punched another one of my friends will
have a congratulations but don't hit
another one of my friends I love me to
deal with as if he's fucking scared like
it matters.
And um,
he said,
oh no,
he kicked hard.
He kicked really hard.
It kicked very,
very hard.
So he was still respectful,
you know.
And he's a good guy.
Well listen,
let's wrap this up.
Liam,
thank you so much for being here.
Thank you very much my honor.
And thank you for training with me too.
That was an odd problem.
That was awesome for me man.
And uh,
people could find you on Twitter
at Liam underscore bad code.
Get my on my Instagram.
That gets updated on a,
and I see Twitter,
I'm on Instagram,
my Instagram,
all my training clips,
everything.
I put up posts on the Alma
fights on my seminars,
Amil comedy stuff that
we're doing with Vinay.
We'll all be thrown onto there.
And Vinny Shoreman,
you're on Instagram as well with a y,
Vinnie and Vinn Wash Orman and Vinny,
sheldon.com domain.
We'll see what happens day.
Awesome.
Cheers,
man.
Thank you very much.