And we're live.
So literally this morning
I had this thought,
um,
I thought about it a bit yesterday and
this morning I thought of it and I was
like,
why don't you just do it?
I said,
I need to do like some sort of a,
an MMA recap show cause there's always
so much shit that's happening then I miss
a lot of it.
I don't get a chance
to talk to a lot of it.
I love doing it with Brendan.
He's my favorite because we get so silly
and because he loves MMA as much as I
do know,
I could talk to him forever about it.
So I'm sure I'll do some of those.
Definitely in the future with him.
Uh,
he's really good at
breaking down fights to men.
He has a,
he's got a skeptical eye for
things and he has a great,
obviously it was a high level
professional heavyweight fighter,
but he also has a real good understanding
of where someone is at various stages
of their career.
I think that's big because fighters have
like these peaks and valleys and you
never know where they're at.
You know,
like fighting is a hard,
hard business and the idea that you could
stay at like a super high level for a
long period of time,
that just doesn't seem to be the case.
It seems like everybody's body starts
giving out after a certain period of time,
after a certain amount of
time cage fighting your body,
just giving out unless you're a guy
like GSP that takes all this time off,
which I think was brilliant.
Now in retrospect,
he knew what we all didn't know.
He really was in fucking amazing shape.
He really was fighting,
I don't say amazing cardio shape cause
that's one legit criticism that Brendan
had is that he looked like he was getting
tired and it was pretty early in the
fight.
The guy was off for four years and he's
stepping right in fighting Bisbing who's
the middleweight champion?
That is not easy.
It's very hard.
Bisbing keeps a fast pace.
He's got amazing cardio.
He's tough as shit.
Like there was a tall order like
to see him come back like that.
But he,
I think he recognized that
grind was too heavy on him,
but he wasn't done yet.
You know,
he was only 32 I think when he retired.
32 is that right?
Somewhere in that range comes back at 36.
I'm like,
wow,
you know,
what are the odds?
He's actually going to be better
than he was before or look good.
He looked fucking amazing.
He looked like a bigger,
better version of the,
the welterweight champion.
George St Pierre was weird.
It was weird to see.
I mean,
I don't want to say that I doubted them
because I did not doubt him because I'm
very open minded and I have
a deep respect for George.
I think he's amazing.
He's just a great person.
A great example of an,
in my opinion like how a
champion should carry himself.
Like George has always been like one
of my favorite examples because you see
them and you liked that
guy is like well spoken,
he's friendly,
he's genuine.
And he's super open
minded in terms of like,
okay,
uh,
his to listen
to coaches and formulate a good game
plan and always be trying out new stuff.
Like he spent a lot of time working with
those guys and a Hendo Gracie's that
Donna hurt death squad.
There was a lot of images of them training
together if he's training with like
Gary Tonin and some of
these fucking animals.
I mean,
John Danaher is a wizard and he's,
he's done just this amazing job with Eddie
Cummins and these kids that he has in
New York that has these,
these leg lock masters.
I mean,
it says Gordon Ryan,
they're just animals.
He's guys are killing people.
And for George to be in
the mix with those guys,
like he's,
he's getting down with some
serious fucking strangle experts.
Okay.
So for just knowing that he's training
with those guys because Eddie Cummins has
been killing tournament's.
Gary.
Tony has been killing her.
They've all,
Ryan's been killing tournament's
that all those kids,
Nikki Ryan,
his brother too,
they're all animals.
So these got,
like,
Donna has this great group of really
savage Jujitsu players and George has
diving into that mix.
Comes to la,
he's doing boxing with Freddie Roach.
You know,
it was one of the best
boxing coaches in the world.
Many packy I was trainer.
So he's like getting down with
like real boxing trainers.
He's getting down with real jujitsu
coaches and he never stopped.
He never stopped,
which is just amazing.
It's amazing that you can
just jump right back in.
Dominick Cruz send me a text
message right after it was over.
He said,
I told you ring rust is bullshit.
And unfortunately Dominic
just broke his arm.
I don't know the specifics of it,
but that's a,
that's a huge bummer.
He's uh,
he's gotta be chomping at the
bit now to get back in there.
Now that Tj just knocked out Cody
Garbrandt he must be chomping,
chomping at the bit.
Um,
so a few of the fights that went down
really recently this past weekend,
Pedis and pour.
Yay.
Holy Shit.
What a good fight that was.
That was crazy.
That's a crazy fight.
And Dustin poray at a 155 pounds,
it seems like a different person.
He just so much healthier at
one 55 and he looked awesome.
The Joe Duffy fight too.
And this,
this fight was a big,
big wind farm though.
Former champion in pedes guy who
was a champion of strike force too.
I mean,
shit,
that's,
it's a big win.
You know,
Anthony Pettis is a tough loss.
It seemed like he had
broken a rib or something.
Like there was something going on.
Like when he got mounted,
he had a tap,
you know,
that's uh,
that's very unfortunate.
But pet is just look really good.
In his last fight,
who did Pettis fight?
He fought and beat in his last fight.
Did he fight Gilbert Melendez?
Jim Miller.
That's right.
Who did Gilbert Melendez.
Right.
You know what I just watched the
other day I rewatched Gilbert.
Oh,
Gilbert fought.
Who has it?
The kicked his legs.
God dammit.
Can't believe I'm forgetting this.
Jeremy Stevens.
That's what,
sorry,
Jeremy.
Jesus Christ.
There was like one of Jeremy's team is,
is fine,
finest performances.
I forgot who did it does too many fights.
I have to erase my brain data.
I got to race him.
Dan Severn footage from the 90s.
I just,
I have to,
I can't though out of respect,
but I have just a too many fights
floating around my fucking head.
That fight was a good fight though,
cause that was the pedes employee.
A fight is a fight between two guys
that are like legit top 10 contenders.
Like either one of them with a couple
of good wins could be fighting for the
title and maybe for portrayed that was
enough to get him in there and fight for
the title.
But it's like you gotta
just a shark pool there.
Tony Ferguson is the interim champ.
Who knows what the fuck is going to
happen now with Connor because Connor was
involved in some sort of an
altercation with referee Mark Goddard,
where he jumped into the cage while
the fight had not been called yet.
Apparently this is mark
Goddard's interpretation of it.
And I think Connors Connors,
uh,
he made an apology and I think what he
was basically saying was that he was
angry that the referee
had not stopped the fight.
First he thought the referee had stopped
the fight and then he was angry that he
had not because he gets
like really concerned when
someone's taken a beating too
much and he felt like this guy really
was out of it and taking a beating.
I think where the confusion was,
and I hope I'm not fucking this up,
we'll check the confusion was I think
that Mark Goddard was saying essentially
that he had not known whether
or not the bell had gone off.
He knows he knew the bell was close,
but he did not know
whether it had gone off.
It was too loud in there
for him to hear it.
And he was concerned.
I believe that it went off.
And so that's when he stepped in
because he thought the round was over.
He was not necessarily
calling the fight yet.
Then when Conor McGregor jumped in,
since he hadn't already called the fight,
he was in a bad situation cause the fight,
technically speaking was still going on.
I hope I'm not fucking this up.
Did I fuck that up?
He made a statement on Facebook.
Yes.
And by the way,
I felt the way he wrote
this statement was really,
it was,
it was not just like very professional.
It was,
it was very,
I'm poised.
I was very impressed with it.
I don't want to read the whole thing,
but he essentially says the first round
is progressing and then so when the guy,
when the guy got hurt,
he said he connected a Charlie ward
connected with the left hand that slumped
John Redmond to his knees.
And at this exact point I could not,
and had not made my determination that
John was either out of the contest or not
in the petition position to
intelligently defend himself.
The Punch and the action that followed
resulted in a surge of crowd noise.
One that was so significant.
I had already made my determination that
I could not audibly hear the bell sound
for the end of the round.
I had made my decision to step in with
the belief that the bell had indeed been
sounded,
which in actual fact it had not,
this is a critical fact to
the ensuing proceedings.
So apparently there was a massive amount
of confusion because of the noise.
And so it looked like it looked like a
very reasonable stop exceeding and find
the video footage to me.
Cause there's a bunch of video of the
brawl itself and all the craziness that
that happened with it.
But it definitely seemed like if they,
if I remember correctly,
I've seen it,
but I,
last time I saw it was
a couple of days ago,
it looked like a really
reasonable stoppage,
like a smart stoppage,
I guess see it and you go,
yeah,
that guy is,
he's getting hurt,
they should stop this.
And then I think Connor just
assumed when he stepped in,
which you would,
especially with staff fucking loud,
you assume there's no bell
and Mark Audit steps in.
See Conard runs in and he
tackles him to the ground.
And then,
but there's already cornermen in there.
And so these guys are hugging and Mark
Goddard is trying to get control of the
octagon.
And so Connor comes at him,
it pushes him and he's yelling at them
this,
this is a just a terrible scene.
Terrible scene.
You know,
and I'm sure Connor,
if you could take it back,
we'd take it back because I'm sure he,
you know,
realize that this is a disaster.
And he even apologized.
You know,
you can't,
you can't do that.
You can't run in.
You gotta be sure that the
referee stopped the fight.
And you know,
I mean,
they have to have control of the octagon,
otherwise anything can happen,
right?
Anybody can get it in at any time.
Not just a friend,
but somebody wants to hurt you.
So they don't know what I mean.
Obviously they knew that Conner was
probably coming in to congratulate his
friend,
but they,
you can't make them give up the rules.
Like the rules are in place for very
good reasons to protect the athletes.
People get super emotional about fights
and there's many times I would believe
that if they weren't like very,
very stringent in how they
allow the athletes to behave,
like have really stringent set of rules.
If they didn't do that,
those guys would fight a lot.
I mean there'll be a lot of chaos.
People would climb into the ring
and beat the shit out of each other.
We've obviously had a few incidents
where corners argued with each other,
but relatively speaking,
when you think about how
many fights take place,
it's a very small number and it's one
of the reasons why is because we have
pretty clear rules like you have to
listen to the referee at all times.
It's,
it's real simple like this.
There's a time where the cage is shot in
the referees in there and that guy has
control of that until you bring somebody
in and he has to have control over it.
If he calls the fight,
then he does.
He calls time and then he
brings the doctors in or
whatever he wants to do or he
stops the fight.
That is entirely this
guy entirely be his call.
And I see the Connor thought it was
over and it was probably like completely
caught in the moment and he just
fucking happy for his friend.
He dives on his friend there,
they're celebrating,
he's thinking that there's going to be a
bunch of people in there any second now
because the fights over,
he's thinking they're gonna open it up
and Bruce buffer is going to step in.
But no would have been Bruce
buffer is another organization.
But you know what I'm saying,
whoever their of Bruce buffer is.
But then somewhere along the line he
realized the fight hadn't been stopped.
And then I think he got very upset.
He said because he has seen people take
unnecessary punishment and he felt like
that guy was done and he felt like to
not stop the fight right then would be a
terrible thing.
And I totally see his point of view.
That makes sense too.
That makes sense to just,
you can't,
you can't push officials.
You can't jump in when you're
not supposed to be there.
So mistakes were made,
but,
um,
I don't know what you do
about something like that.
I Dunno how you,
I dunno,
like fifth standard
punishments for Shit like that.
But it'd be a shame if that instance took,
uh,
a Conor fight away from the fans.
I'm not saying he shouldn't be punished.
I would just say if he was punished,
it would be a shame.
I mean,
I guess you have to set a precedent.
I don't know how that works.
You ever shove an official Jamie?
No,
I've definitely yelled at him.
but I mean,
playing basketball,
right.
Fighters.
You can talk to an official,
right?
Yeah,
man,
they're real strict about that.
Like when people do,
they get very upset and you definitely
can't put your hands on them.
You know,
Roy Roy Nelson just was pissed off
once it a late stoppage and he,
uh,
he kicked a big John McCarthy in the butt,
but it was like the most gentle kick ever.
I mean,
he didn't kick him like
he was trying to hurt him,
you know,
he like touched his foot on his butt.
I mean it was nothing and big John said
it was nothing but he shouldn't have
touched him.
It's all it is.
It's just there's rules and you get crazy.
And it was the same thing.
In fact a big Roy was pissed that he um,
he let them take so much punishment.
Something similar happened
this year in the NBA.
The Steph curry is one of the top players.
He's known for throwing his
mouthpiece when he gets pissed.
He always takes his mouthpiece out a
lot when just one play is not an action.
So he does well for whatever reason,
something happened in
the NBA finals last year,
he turned around and tried to throw it a
at like the the scores table and it hit
a fan.
That's so nasty.
It's definitely really gross.
I mean it's just like a UFC
fighter throwing it into the crowd.
Like some nasty mouthpiece.
I nobody wants that.
Some fighters,
oh no,
this is,
some people would dive for
a UFC fighters mouthpiece,
but if he's throwing it at a referee
that's like spitting in his face.
Boy,
he bounced off the ground and hit
him I think is to what happened here.
Oh,
like he didn't,
I don't know if he even
meant to throw it at them,
but either way he shouldn't be thrown
his mouthpiece and he's pissed.
It's sort of like,
but he didn't get suspended,
which a lot of people were
saying like what do you think?
Early in the year you should have at
least got a three or four game suspension,
not just a $50,000 fine,
which is a 10th of what he
makes that day probably.
I don't think anything would happen to
you if you're a fighter and you three
your mouthpiece at the
ground in front of a referee.
I think cause the rev,
the UFC is so violent that
that would be taken as like,
oh come on,
throw the mouthpiece on the ground.
But I think in basketball it's
probably a pretty big deal.
Right?
Definitely different.
I mean you can't,
your spit your gum,
Adam can't spit at people.
Man.
Wow,
that's different.
I mean we are taking
off your head bailing,
you're spinning at people.
You're just throwing it with your hand,
that things all slobbery and shit.
You know what the fuck you doing?
So gross.
Anyway,
I all the hands and sweat
and blood and everything.
Just going around the court.
Is it a satisfying know to take out
your mouthpiece filled with spit and hit
someone in the face with it as
it is to spit in their face?
Never done either,
to be honest with you,
but I don't know it in the face thing.
It's a dangerous move.
Haka Big Louis.
Yeah cause you gotta be close.
Real close.
It's a bit,
it's like,
uh,
it's like I'm ready for violence move.
You spit in someone's face like Ooh,
that's not just an insult.
It's like the only way to respond to that
insult is like something more intense.
It's like there's always like a moment
when someone spits in someone's face
with,
is this like terrifying moment
of anything could happen here?
Like how does this go?
Does this swing left the swing?
Right.
How does this go?
But in MMA,
like that happens,
I mean you're,
you're involved in these
violent altercations.
If someone just through their
mouth piece of the ground,
like you barely even notice it,
you know,
you couldn't do it at a referee.
Like obviously it a referee,
they would warn you or
something like that could,
maybe I'm wrong.
Could you throw a shadow
punch or shadow kick and buck.
I was never going to hit him.
I wasn't even close,
but like,
no,
no.
That's threatening.
You know,
if you,
if you fee like fake kicked,
even if you were five
foot away from someone,
you're kind of threatening.
You're at the very least,
you're doing something
that's totally unnecessary.
Like why,
why would you do that?
You're doing that to elicit some
sort of response from the referee.
You're trying to get them scared,
trying to get them to realize that
he's in the cage with a trained killer.
You know?
I mean,
seriously,
if you're in the cage
and Frances and Ghana,
who's mad at you?
Direct three.
Ah,
what a fucking terrifying
position you'd be that guy.
He's a smasher.
He's just a super athletes at Emory
happened in the history of MMA,
like in a big fight in a cage or that
a fighter's gotten pissed and taking us
from,
I've seen it happen in boxing I think
enough few times just doesn't happen often
obviously.
But I think UFC fighters credit,
I don't think anyone has ever
taken a swing at a referee.
I don't think that's ever happened.
I don't think so.
Okay,
well that's good.
Yeah.
I think that like
if you,
if you stop and think about how many
fights there are and how few even like bad
situations or are in between fighters,
I like to think that even
though it's a super intense
endeavored to do be fist
fighting another person,
male or female,
like for the most part they're like
really friendly people that do it for the
most part.
They're very,
you know,
they're,
they're accomplished there and they
don't have any time for bullshit.
But lately there's been this trend and
I think it's because Conor McGregor has
been so successful with it of shit
talking to like the nth degree,
like who can be the biggest shit talker?
And Colby.
Covington is just going for it,
baby.
He's fucking going for it.
And I got to tell you,
I don't know how I feel because part
of me thinks it's entertaining as fuck.
When I read some of the shit that he says
and I see some of the shitty says like
he is just going for it,
but it's working.
See,
here's the thing,
and this is one of the
things that he said.
Got To understand like a
lot of this is your true,
just trying to get your name out there
and you try to do something that makes a
splash.
Even if it's a band splash,
even it's like pissing off
the entire country of Brazil.
He's making a splash,
you know?
And I could see the point that
like you shouldn't do it that way.
I get it.
I get people saying that.
What I don't get is people saying
that they're not paying attention.
I'm paying attention.
I'm not encouraging it.
I'm just being an,
I'm a analyzing it from
an outside perspective.
As a person who's a huge fan of
the way Conor McGregor talks,
shit,
I enjoy it.
I fucking enjoy it when Jeremy Stevens
says something to when he goes,
who the fuck is that guy?
He's um,
he's a magic man with that shit.
I think he's amazing.
His fucking timing,
the things he says,
he's a character,
he's a fucking character
and he fucks people up.
There's no denying that.
You know,
Conor McGregor is a beast and I
think probably not even in his prime.
I mean,
I think his athletic prime
might be a couple of years away.
I mean he,
who the fuck knows what
that guy can accomplish?
But one thing that's clear is that he's
changed the landscape when it comes to
shit talking.
Like now everybody wants
to be a shit talker now.
Shit talking.
It's like it's mandatory for the Gig.
You know,
shit talking is become
some thing that like,
it's like an art form in and of itself.
[inaudible] some guys
are just going for it.
So Colby apparently got into it with
Fabrizio Verdon because one thing about
Brazilians,
if you talk some shit about Brazil,
they will get really mad at you.
They're very proud.
They're very nationalistic.
They'd love Brazil.
And I don't know if that was
what the argument was about,
but for breezy over doom hit Kobi
Covey to with a fucking boomerang.
See,
the problem with that is I don't
think for BC was trying to kill him.
Right.
But the problem with that is
that's a weapon like that.
It literally is what it is.
Like it seems like it's
goofy because it's,
uh,
something that we have when we're kids,
you know,
it never really works.
I can give you ever got a
boomerang to come back to you.
Like,
come on man.
You can't just stay in the same spot
and get that boomerang to come back to.
Is Anybody ever done that?
Can you really do that?
For sure.
I've seen it happen for sure.
You got to do it up in
the air or something,
the way you throw it.
Yeah.
They could just go right back to you.
See if you can find a video of someone
to actually getting a boomerang to go
right back to the same
spot where he stands.
They do that you can
do with the Frisbee to,
I seem like I do it with crazy frisbee.
So like they invented it so they
can kill things with it though.
They invented like
throw at birds and shit.
So this is a real weapon.
Like you're literally,
you literally hitting the guy
in the head with a weapon.
I mean,
I'm not,
I'm not looking at this guy
that's Australia is fuck,
what's he got to say?
And the boomerang.
We'll come back and then we
just demonstrate for you.
That's,
that goes English.
How you see it.
Boom.
Raise was straight out.
Oh,
I fuck dog.
Which is it?
All right.
He got Ya.
He got shot.
I believe someone probably can,
but the point is,
it's a weapon.
So it's like co Colby got hit with a
weapon for dude hit him in the head with a
piece of wood and apparently he
punched him in the phase two.
According to Colby Covington,
this guy looks like he'd be
really good at a boomerang.
Let me see it.
Come back.
Oh Shit.
Look at that.
That's fucking crazy.
Oh,
flew away.
All right.
Yeah.
I mean,
is this bullshit too?
It comes back to the
vicinity that you're in.
Sorta like a,
I mean,
I don't know.
Like even if you send a falcon nine on
and off and come right back to the same
gps spot that you left it,
let it go from,
but pretty,
pretty close.
Yeah.
How does that work?
Falcons who just didn't know what to do.
I have no idea on that.
So this dude is like a boomerang expert.
Look at them just whipping that boomerang.
How long would you have to practice
to get that good at a boomerang?
That is what?
A weird fucking weapon.
And he couldn't catch it.
You couldn't catch it.
But what a weird thing.
Yeah.
You know that someone
figured out how to do that.
Like how smart were those?
God Damn people.
Like how many different
shape today come up with a w.
Okay.
If you had to guess,
how long do you think the
boomerangs been around?
Thousands of years.
Abi.
I would say
it's gotta be one of those accidents
someone figured out and was like,
Whoa,
look at that and just throw it right.
Hey comes back,
look at that.
It comes back.
Yeah.
But do you think that like there's a
conventional academic view of like when it
was invented,
it must be right.
So you could find that.
I just heard that there's this,
the one,
one of the most popular VR
games or VR experiences,
I think I it to,
you probably done it called tilt brush,
that virtual painting experience I just
saw yesterday a tweet that said it was
started as a,
the guy who made it start out
to make a three d chess game.
But a bug was found that one of the
pieces was dragging a light behind it or
whatever.
And he's like,
oh look at that.
And now he made the most popular VR thing.
There was based off of a bug that so
similar to someone could just throw on a
stick and be like,
hey look.
I said,
hey,
this is what comes back to you.
What could we use this for?
Right.
SORTA like how they invented Viagra
cause we were trying to come up with some
blood pressure medication or some shit.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
Like hey,
hey,
I want to knows when no one knows for
sure how the returning boomerang was
invented.
Mm.
Anywhere cold.
We got hit in the head with one.
I don't know how that works,
man.
That seems like a salt.
I mean that's like,
I know he wasn't trying to kill him.
If you watch the video,
let's see if we could watch the video.
Boom.
Right.
25 to 30 to 50,000 years ago.
Wow,
that's a big gap.
Yeah.
They're like,
um,
I dunno.
Threw a bag of like he just
bought it or something.
I think someone might've,
yeah,
he might have bought or someone
gave it to him or something.
They give you boomerangs down there,
but he's got it in the bag
and he just fucking whips it.
He hits him in the like side of the head.
He hits him in the shoulder and the head
and Colby still talking shit to him.
Did they give out boomerangs
like blaze and Hawaii?
Is that probably show up.
They give you one.
Yeah.
Colby.
Like when he hit him with it,
he's like,
whoa.
Yeah,
this is crazy.
That just happened today,
right?
I think so.
I just found out about it like right
after the last podcast was over
cray and they talking
crazy shit to each other.
We don't have to broadcast,
they shed talking.
I find it rude and vulgar.
It's weird man.
It's like some people like it,
some people like the trash talking,
but to these two guys are obviously in
different weight classes so they're never
going to fight.
But some people like this like tough guy
conflict that fighters have with each
other and some people hate it.
There's some people that think that
some people are martial artists,
you know,
and they think that this
is all like offensive,
that you should conduct
yourself like a martial artist.
And some people have
said that and you know,
a lot of people like agree with it and
think that this is the better path for
this sport for all of us.
But there's no denying the
entertainment value of being a shithead.
It's entertaining.
You know,
I don't want people to fight,
but I am entertained.
Often when they do,
I think we'd all be better
off if they didn't fight.
But there's something about like,
John Jones going,
I beat you after I did cocaine.
Like there's something about that that,
yeah,
it's not like,
it doesn't feel like the embodiment of
the true spirit of what we would think of
as martial arts being a
vehicle for developing your
human potential and the path
of the Warrior Samurai and the noble poet.
You know,
we have all these like quiet Chang
Caine views of what martial arts are.
But one thing that martial arts are,
is a psychological warfare as well.
It's undeniable that it has a big
impact and who you're fighting,
you can get emotional.
If a guy fucks with your head too much,
you can get to a point where you're
at a character and you take chances.
You shouldn't take your nervous beyond
like your ability to control because
you're so worried about losing it.
This person that they have this
big emotional investment with,
that's real.
I mean that's one of the things that me
and molten Musashi used when he was a
sword fighter in,
um,
the book of five rings.
He would talk about all the
different games that he would play.
I people have documented it like
when Musashi would have these duels,
he would show up like hours late and let
this poor fuck just freak out worrying
about a sword fight that he was going
to have the guys sitting there for hours
and hours.
Then finally Musashi would show up and
the guy would be like a nervous wreck and
he would just fuck them up and kill him.
And he,
he had all these tactics that he
used and that was just one of them.
So psychological warfare is something
that's always been a part of the martial
arts,
but some people feel like the most
noble path for both warriors is just be
respectful and just have no,
no emotions on the line
with this in terms of like,
uh,
a hate for each other.
Instead just respect each other
like warriors and go after it.
And there's been some amazing fights
or guys took on that mentality.
That's uh,
you know,
that's an,
it's an interesting,
it's an interesting thing,
the way people express themselves when
they're doing what I think is like the
most difficult athletic endeavor,
the way people get their
express themselves.
Do you decide,
just put on a show or do you
decide to be the stoic warrior,
you know,
who doesn't talk much and
takes care of business?
It's interesting,
man.
I go,
we were talking about steep bade.
Me,
Oh church before the podcast,
I was going back and
forth and Steve based,
he pays a fireman,
he's the heavyweight champion of
the world and he's also a fireman.
He's the baddest man on the planet.
He's the UFC heavyweight
champion of the world.
He's smashing people
and he's also a fireman.
You know,
like that guy doesn't get enough love.
Like that's the,
that's the heavyweight
champion of the world to,
it's what a what a weird
position that guys in,
you know and couldn't be nicer but you
got to think what if he was like a crazy
shit talker would have steep Emile chick
was like Colby Covington just talking
mad shit.
You know,
instead Steve Bay shows up to knock people
out and he looks like he's in in line
to like take the bus to get to work.
Like he barely looks
like he's about to fight.
He has like the most stoic relaxed
expression before he fucks people up much
like fate or did.
He's got his own sort of version of that.
I goes,
one of the more amazing things about fate
or his career was like he would be in
the middle of a firefight,
just a full on fire fight and he
never let his expression shift.
You never saw fade are like gritting his
teeth and making a mean face fade or it
didn't waste any energy.
Maybe if you made one or two
main faces in his career,
I might've missed it,
but most of the time he would be in the
middle of these fucking horrific wars
and pride with like just dead face,
you know?
I mean he in hindsight,
especially since Keynes
been injured so many times,
he in hindsight I think has
to be recognized right next
to Fabrizio over doom as
the two greatest heavyweights of all time,
which Cain Velasquez is right
in there in that mix too.
And if he wasn't injured so much,
I would think Kane is probably the
most difficult one for all of them.
He just was when he fought for doom,
not making any excuses for him,
but I think he really didn't have
enough of an opportunity to adapt to the
Mexico City altitude.
It's like extreme altitude and
for Dune did a very wise thing.
He got up there way early and he lived
up there even higher than Mexico City.
He lived up,
he set up his training
camp like way in advance,
so he totally acclimated.
So for the first time it Keynes career,
somebody had a cardio advantage over him,
which was crazy.
And then on top of that for BC over doing,
it was just the nastiest submission
artists in the history of the sport.
He tapped out fade or million enco he
tapped out Minotauro Nogueira any topped
out.
Cain Velasquez,
those three guys have to be
considered top three all time.
So top three or five all
time guys made a Taros tap.
Three of them,
excuse me,
for for breezy.
Over doing was tap.
Three of them made a Tarald
tapped a bunch of them too.
You know mandatorial when
he tapped Mark Coleman,
that was gigantic for Jujitsu to show
that a guy could tap somebody off of his
back that was a UFC heavyweight champion
and still a murderer like mark the
hammer Coleman watch them in a Toro.
Tap Him was giant,
but it just got to think of how good
for doom is for doom tapped minute Toro,
he tapped cane,
any tapped fader or so for Colby to
talk shit to him like cheeses too.
I want to see the rematch
between for doom and Steve Bay.
I hope they can make that.
If for doom wins his fight,
he decided to take this
fight on short notice,
fairly short notice for mark,
Mark Teen Marchine.
How'd he say it?
Marching Tibora who's a very promising
young guy and he was supposed to be
fighting Mark Hunt,
which is going to be a crazy
strikers match I would imagine.
But I'm Mark Hunt got
pulled from the card.
There's some concern about something
that he said in an interview and he said
that the UFC is uh,
they wanted to remove him because
of his lawsuit in the UFC was like,
look,
we,
we've already paid you one point $6
million since the lawsuit was filed.
Like you've,
you've fought for us and made
a lot of money since then.
Like we're not trying to stop you.
I believe that's what they said.
Pretty sure.
I don't want to,
I don't want to misquote that.
But the point is like,
uh,
they decided for whatever the reason was
to remove Mark Hunt from the car and,
and Fabrizio moved right into it.
And it was right after he just submitted
Walt Harris so for resale is still in
the mix and like having that quick
win like that over Harris got a nice
submission,
beautiful armbar transition from the back.
It was just nasty.
His,
his just so high level on the ground.
I don't think people
understand or appreciate it.
He could do that to almost anybody.
That thing is like his level of Jujitsu.
He,
he was a legitimate world
champion in Jujitsu.
He won Ahboo Dhabi.
I mean for breezy over doom
is just a straight up killer.
His Jujitsu is at such a high level still
like most of the heavyweights they get
on the ground with him are going to be
in deep fucking water is just the level
of Jujitsu that he has is so high.
They're like the average MMA practitioner,
you know the at a,
at a high level has a really good level
of Jujitsu but Fabricio Verducci is the
guy that taps those guys.
Like that's how good he is.
He,
if he gets anybody that's anywhere near
his size on the ground that's competing
in the heavyweight division,
there is a huge likelihood that he
has a massive Jujitsu advantage.
And until you've rolled with a guy
who has a massive Jujitsu advantage,
you don't realize like how
big the difference between
like him being 5% better
than you.
Him being 10% better hidden
being 15% for ratios,
probably 20 to 30% better than anybody
else in the division when it goes to the
ground.
So it's even if you're good and strong
and you're athletic and you're quick,
he puts the smush on you,
you stay smushed,
man.
I give the Brandon verify.
It's a great example of that.
Brandon Vera was a bad
motherfucker and he's,
he's good at the ground.
He knows how to fight,
he knows how to submit.
He knows how to kickbox.
He was on fire at the time,
but Fabricio put the smooshed down on him.
He got on top of that mount
was just inescapable and
he started smashing him for
Bricio,
super underrated Jujitsu.
I think even though people know it's his
strong suit and they know how bad ass
he is when you watch like
the shit that he can do,
there's not a whole lot of guys
that are like that as a heavyweight.
There's not a whole lot of guys that
have that kind of guard is on a whole lot
of guys that are just so dangerous from
everywhere and his striking has got
really good too.
You've got to think.
He knocked out Mark
Hunt with a flying knee,
you know,
and that's how he won the title.
He's a beast for received
for doom is a fucking beast.
He just got super emotional when he
fought Steve Bay in Brazil and just really
charged at him.
Almost uncharacteristically aggressive
and steep page is set it up and just
dropped a bomb on him and knocked him out.
But Steve Bay could do
that to any living human,
any living human that chases steep Emile
chick around like that and Steve Bay
can just stop and cork went
on you as you're moving in.
The only one I think you might be able
to take something like that was like a
prime time Mark Hunt like primetime Mark
Hunt had like the greatest job of all
time.
Cro.
COP head kicked him full on,
left high kick to the head and Mark
Hunt like barely wobbled a little.
He was like wobbled a little
like it might've went down to one knee
for a second and bounced back up like
that would smash people.
Most people got hit with that Cro.
Cop left high kick and it was night night,
but there's a video of it.
I'm pretty sure cro cop was wearing shoes.
I think he was wearing shoes
when he had kicked him.
He's wearing shoes.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
They let Mirko Cro,
cop Kitkak kickbox which shoes
on pride didn't give a fuck.
Look,
see that he's throwing kicks with that.
Boom.
Hits him in the head.
Look what happens.
A little wobble.
That's it.
That's insane.
You have to know how insane that is.
Folks who don't know.
I mean,
that is crazy.
Mirko Cro.
Cop puts everybody to sleep.
He didn't even make Mark Hunt sleepy
that prime time.
Mark Han had the most
ridiculous job all time,
the most ridiculous,
ridiculous ability to take a shot,
I should say,
of all time,
because it wasn't just his jaw anywhere.
He just could take a shot.
Just insanely,
insanely tough for base
over doom owed him.
So you have to realize you we're talking
about a straight up killer now and he's
40.
It's interesting.
He says,
uh,
he says he feels great
though with guys like that.
You almost wish they
could get him on some TRT.
You almost wish it was legal.
Like the only they could
administer it monitor levels.
Because if for Breeshia
over doom could do TRT,
if we get out like TRT
Vitor tight physique
member that does the,
those were the glory years of chaos.
The TRT RTV tour years have
you get a TRT ver doom.
Holy Shit Son.
I mean,
God damn,
that would be insane.
I wonder.
Uh,
yeah,
there's tr TV tour and there's regular
retort with the cross on his head.
And then there's the first v tour,
which was,
uh,
probably like some other Shit v tour.
Yeah.
Crazy.
But that his prime man,
like when he knocked out Luke Rockhold
or when he knocked out Michael Bisbing or
Dan Henderson in one round,
he was just terrifying.
He was just something different.
Just smashing people in a way that like,
was kind of stunning.
Like wow,
if he tourists never been better,
he just understood more because
he was older and experienced.
And then when they let them take tests,
his body was performing.
Look,
a young guy's body.
So he has this young guy's body,
but this old guy's brain and he just has
incredible confidence from all his wars
and he's been in there with so many
just assassins and survived and lost and
won.
You know what I mean?
Vittores it's been around forever.
So to see him on the TRT makes you go,
God Damn Monster,
I'm doing cheer team,
man.
You're not supposed to say that.
But here's one way that a company
like Bella tour or one of these other
organizations could get ahead
is if they allowed that.
I don't know how they do that.
I don't know if that has to be a
state athletic commission thing,
but if there was a way
where Bella tour decided,
listen,
let's be honest here,
fighters would be much healthier.
Be able to get through
their training camp better,
feel more physically strong
if we just allow them to do
just a little bit of TRT.
Well the,
we'll monitor it.
We'll make sure everybody's okay.
Extend the career of a
lot of the older guys.
What's up with that?
A heavyweight Grand Prix.
They just announced a big tournament.
Yeah,
they're doing some big crazy tournament.
Ryan Bader is going to
fight as a heavyweight.
Came Mo's going to fight as a
heavyweight big countries in it.
Mitre own fade or rampage.
Chael Sonnen's in it.
Yeah.
It's going to go like for a year
or that they really don't know.
I don't know what the schedule is.
Um,
I just saw the announcement for it the
other day and I saw some pictures and I
was like,
Oh shit.
Yeah.
Interesting.
Huh?
It Trios.
I like,
um,
Ryan Bader as a heavyweight.
That could be interesting.
Ryan Bader,
we're not having to cut any weight.
Maybe even putting a little
weight on fast as fuck man.
That might be his weight class.
Who knows?
You know,
and Ryan Bader is the,
he's the bell tore champ now some
I get cut off in the back there.
Who was that?
What happened?
The picture cut someone off.
Isn't that Frank Mir?
I think that the pictures,
Frank Mir,
how dare they cut Frank Mir
off you sons of bitches.
You sons of bitches have some respects
that frankly on the left have some
fucking respect.
Whoever edited that Shit's
going to ask if you,
have you heard any,
I haven't heard his name come up
yet to know that it's Kyle Snyder.
He's a wrestler from Ohio state.
He won the gold medal and the Rio
Olympics and he's really young.
He's only 20 when he wanted and he just
won the 2017 Gold Bento for heavyweight.
Uh,
it could be to Russian and I guess he's,
I've seen his name pop up a little bit,
but I haven't heard any of them thing
about him training with a particular team.
I think he's done at Ohio state now.
He went back to back like
doesn't want to fight MMA.
So I was just googling it.
That's why I was asking
if you heard anything.
It said that he wants to fight in
the UFC and do the 2020 Olympics.
Whew.
You'd have to be matched up carefully.
You know the thing
about the 2020 Olympics,
like,
man,
I got to think that would
take up all your time.
How would you have time to like
kickbox and learn submissions?
I don't know.
I mean he's a bad ass wrestler obviously.
It's,
I don't know.
I don't know what he doesn't
know or what he needed needs to.
Well,
I think everything escalates,
right?
Everybody gets better.
I mean there's,
there's outliers in every generation
like Michael Jordan type characters.
But I think in every
sport people get better.
And it must be the case in wrestling too,
right?
It's gotta be,
I would imagine,
I don't know enough.
I only wrestled for one year in high
school and I quite honestly don't know
enough about modern.
Right.
But I could always call,
call me up and he would school me on it.
But I think like if you look at the level,
like he's a great example.
Look at the level of technical wrestling
knowledge that [inaudible] has in
relationship to maybe some of the earlier
days wrestlers you're talking about a
completely different level.
Like one of the reasons why core has
been so successful is how technical he is
as a wrestler.
How good he is.
I cause his wrestling's [inaudible] like
him Yoel Romero is probably number one
like Yoel Romero meddled in pretty much
every international match that he was
ever in.
Every international major
tournament that he was ever.
And he medalled the Romero was like
one of the scariest wrestlers it's ever
done.
MMA for sure.
There's no doubt about it.
I mean,
he was the freak of freaks.
He beat Cael Sanderson twice.
And who's one of the
greatest wrestlers ever?
I mean,
you all were marrow,
so fuck Rick.
Did he,
did he ever fight in UFC or anything?
I remember hearing him
when I was growing up.
Cael Sanderson.
Yeah.
I don't believe you ever fought MMA.
Could pull,
pull that up.
Find out if that's true.
There was a fake MMA fight.
I found out that,
um,
uh,
the Russian experiment did God damn it.
Why can't I remember his name?
I don't see anything.
It just says he's a
coaching after he wrestled.
Yeah,
it probably did.
Probably decided not to.
What the fuck's that dude's name?
The giant guy.
The experiment.
I can't believe his name is slipping my,
the giant Russian dude.
I believe.
I can't remember I said Carrie Berona.
No,
the one.
I'm always talking about.
What,
how,
what,
how does that happen?
Where does an idea go
and just vanish?
Why is it saying sleep experiment?
No,
the Russian experiment.
Uh,
he's the guy who lost a
rule on Gardner Gardner.
Jesus Christ.
I can't believe.
I can't remember his name.
This is so embarrassing.
I got God that was pull up.
Look him up.
No,
those guys.
Huh?
No,
the guy right about what?
The group,
the red singlet.
Keep going.
Keep it right.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
That's him.
Go to the webpage.
Alexander Karelin.
Thank you Jesus Christ.
How can I not,
I was coming up with some
weird fake Russian names.
We smoked pot before we did this.
I'm sorry.
Sometimes is not good for your memory.
There's a perfect example
because Carolyn is a guy.
I've been a fan of his forever.
He's just one of the scariest
human beings that's ever lived.
Uh,
I don't even know what my point was.
What was my point about Carolyn?
Why would we be bringing him up?
Oh,
we had a fake fight.
He had an MMA fight.
Everybody was always like,
wow,
if that guy only fought MMA,
it would be fucking amazing.
And then he had like
a pro wrestling match.
I don't believe I W W it's not my,
I'd seen it was like a fixed fight.
I'm thinking it was like a
pro wrestling type situation.
And,
uh,
it just look weird to watch.
But at the time,
I think before Rulon
Gardner had beaten him.
He had one like,
who knows how many
fucking matches in a row.
If you such a terrifying person,
he would scoop guys up by their waist and
they would try to flatten out on their
stomach to try to avoid being
thrown the received video.
Whoa.
Did we blow out what happened?
There we go.
Yeah.
All right.
We're back.
We had some issue,
I don't know what the fuck happened,
but we were talking about,
uh,
Josie Aldo versus Max Holloway to dose,
which is only happening because
Frankie Edgar apparently got injured.
I do not know what the injury was.
Do you know what the injury was?
And James,
did you disclose it?
Stepping up?
I thought it was a bunch of people
that we're talking shit online.
I was watching,
uh,
one of his,
Instagram pictures or the video that
he made a bunch of people calling him a
bitch for pulling out of the fight.
Like these fucking kids like it
of all the people to call a bitch.
Frankie Edgar is one of the biggest
studs it's ever fought in MMA.
That guy's an animal.
He's,
I mean he's like one of the most durable,
tough and like mentally
strong guys in the sport.
So when someone calls him a bitch,
it's,
it's actually hilarious.
It's like you read that,
you're like,
that is one of the craziest fucking
things anybody could ever say.
You called Frankie Edgar a bitch
like that doesn't even make it.
That's preposterous.
That's like saying Joey Diaz
is a hot chick or something.
Just what he's saying,
it doesn't even make any sense.
Like if Frankie Edgar is a pitch,
do you know what kind of
benchmark you ha you have set?
Like you have to be more of a man
than Frankie Edgar or you're a bitch.
That is crazy.
We're all going to be bitches.
We will all fail.
You're going to look at a nation of
bitches if that's what you're setting your
bitch benchmark,
you're calling yourself a bitch.
For sure.
Because I guarantee you if Frankie Edgar's
pulling out of a fight for an injury,
you would have pulled out quicker.
So you're more of a bitch than him.
You'd have to be.
There's no way you're less
of a bitch or anything.
Anything remotely close to him.
When you're talking about a guy who's
a former UFC lightweight champion in a
weight class that he barely
even cut any weight for,
that was,
he would walk around at one
55 and he won the title.
He beat Bj Penn like
get the fuck outta here.
More than once.
Big Cubs wants to me.
Frankie Edgar is a fucking monster.
He's an animal.
He's the wrong guy to be calling a bitch.
She can't.
It just,
it just shows you how
ridiculous people are online.
WHO's Joe Nobel?
You'll get it,
bro.
He's a bitch for pulling out.
I guarantee you that's not true.
I guarantee you if he
pulled out of that fight,
it's because he's fucking injured.
Period.
End of discussion.
He's not a bitch.
He's not afraid of anybody.
And that's not taking anything away
from Max Holloway Cause who's fucking
awesome?
Max Holloway's a savage.
He's a killer.
Straight up killer and not
even close to his prime.
Max Holloway is a long
way away from his prime.
He's way better now than he was
when he first got into the UFC.
He's continued to get
better with every fight.
Now he's the champion and
he just stopped all though.
And then when they offered him the
rematch because Frankie Edgar got injured,
they offered all do the rematch.
So although took it now it's going to
be Max Holloway versus all though too,
which is still a huge
fucking fight and all those,
when he although got accepted,
Max Holloway wrote on his Instagram,
it is what it is like no big deal.
Well what are we going to do?
Like what you're about to fight the
greatest featherweight of all time for the
second time.
And he's like,
it is what it is.
Like that's how bad ass he is.
He just figured if I fucked you up once,
I'm gonna fuck you up again.
Like in his mind,
this is not a good fight.
Which is hilarious.
That's,
that's what a beast Max
Holloway is that he's facing.
Joe's a Aldo and he's like,
it is what it is.
It's not what I was looking for.
Yeah,
it is what it is.
What a beast.
Max Holloway is a killer.
He's a fucking killer.
That kid,
he's a killer.
It is what it is.
You're fighting Josie,
although he's coming to get you because
you knocked him out to win the belt.
He has a chance at revenge and he's like,
it is what it is.
He's an animal man.
A fucking kid is the real deal.
What's so exciting to him about him
and said he's not even close to done.
You know,
he has massive potential and he could
easily move up to one 55 if he wanted to.
Like if they could,
if if say
Max Holloway wins this fight spectacularly
and then starts talking about your
shit about Conor McGregor
and then moves up to one 55 I think Max
Holloway can easily compete at one 55 if
you wanted to do some
sort of unification bout.
I think that,
I'm not a unification bow,
but you know a champion
versus champion bout.
I think for sure Max Holloway could,
could be competitive at one 55 and Max
Holloway's only lost in his career and
was to Connor as the only
loss he has on his record.
That's what a Badass he is.
And he was the only guy
that went to decision.
Frankie Edgar release a statement
after UFC two 18 withdrawal Max.
I'll see you down the road.
Well,
what's the statement?
It's got a facial surgery
to repair a facial injury.
It says it's a minor setback.
Oh,
start trading in about six weeks.
I wonder what it is.
Oh,
maybe it's a phase problem,
bro.
It might be.
I'm just saying
facial surgery can meet a lot of things.
You know,
it can mean a,
you got something wrong with your jaw,
a which is not good.
You could mean you got something
wrong or your cheek bone,
which is not good.
It could mean you got something
wrong with your orbital,
which is not good or it
can mean something to that.
I don't understand.
So if he's not concerned about it,
maybe it's something I don't understand.
Maybe it's not a broken something.
Maybe like something was like detached
or something need to be stitched back on.
Yikes.
I think about all the elbows,
people who've taken all the shit that
gets displaced all over your face.
Like John Wayne par.
I sort of documented all the
stitches that he's ever taken.
Multiple time world Moitai champion.
Just a fucking straight up savage from
Australia and John Wayne par was still
fighting.
It's fighting for Bell Tor now.
It's one of the bell torque on
the Beltour kickboxing roster,
but he's had,
oh God,
he's going to be pissed
at me for not remembering,
but I think he's had more
than 300 stitches in his face.
He's such an animal.
He's like documented them too.
I think they did some thing where chose
John Wayne par and it shows all the
places and they put stitches on all the
places where he's had actual stitches.
They like,
you know,
doctor demand.
Yeah,
and the pictures just straight crazy.
You're like,
you are in a business
that's shreds your face.
Yeah,
that's it right there.
That's all the different places in
his body where he's been stitched up,
which is just incredible.
I mean,
you look at his face,
it's like a mask of stitches,
but he looks normal.
When you meet him,
they did a great job stitching them up.
I mean,
it definitely looks like a
guy you wouldn't fuck with,
you know,
and you want to fuck with a dude
who a scars all over his face.
Probably not a good move,
but couldn't be a nicer guy.
That was a fight that he had,
whereas cornermen took that big cut on
the side of his head and started making
mouth many things with it and talking,
Hey Martin,
dear ms Mr. Caught,
that's how morose these guys get.
But um,
you know,
he's,
he's still after it and that guys,
you know,
I mean it comes to like the amount
of facial damage that he's received
and delivered,
delivered a lot of it too.
Shitload of it.
Yeah.
Oh No.
Who's that?
Ron Stallings for?
Suffers nasty cut eyebrows hanging off.
That's the choir boy.
He's a very good fighter.
That sucks.
Yeah,
there was a real bad
one with Marvin Eastman.
Vito Belfort hit Marvin
Eastman with a flying knee,
not a flying knee,
but like jumped into it jump knee and
just smashed him in the forehead and cut
his eyebrow open terribly.
It was like this really long cut.
I was like,
oh my God.
Yeah.
That one.
Pull that up.
Yeah.
That is a enormous cut.
I mean literally,
I mean four inches long,
maybe third eyebrow.
Yeah,
like a,
a huge third eyebrow going off his eyebrow
and you see all the meat in there and
everything and they have to
stitch all that together.
I mean,
I don't know what happens with
the muscles underneath it.
Shit.
That one was bad.
What was that one?
Is that it?
Marvin Eastman.
Oh my God.
That's the other,
the last tangle was even worse.
Go to that one right next to that one.
Yeah.
Look at that.
When you see it from that angle.
Ooh.
It literally looks like he
got attacked by a machete.
Like someone stuck a machete in his head.
Yeah,
those are nasty.
I don't know how we got to that
and then how we got on that.
We're talking about damage,
you know,
I dunno if we said enough about the,
the Goddard Mcgregor thing,
but it's,
it's always,
this is very disappointing.
I wish he hadn't had done it,
but I get,
I get where he,
I get how he thought the fight was over.
I get why when he thought
the fight wasn't over,
he was furious.
I get all of it.
It's just very uncomfortable.
Uh,
and I think Goddard could not
have handled himself better.
That guy is a fucking man.
I love the way you handle it.
I wrote love the way he wrote about it,
the way he wrote about was like
so clear and so concise and uh,
it's the way he wrote
about how taking control,
like his job inside the cage
when he was trying to do,
makes you realize what a
great referee he really is.
Like how he's taking everything into
consideration and following the rules even
in the middle of chaos.
But you gotta do,
you gotta do,
it's fucking tough job.
That is one of the toughest jobs in sports
to be a referee in a professional MMA
fight.
It's one of the toughest jobs in sports.
There's so much craziness going on and
it's so dangerous if someone loses the
moment between someone getting hit and k
out and being okay that to taking five,
six,
seven,
eight unanswered blows and not being
okay that there is a difference.
There's a big difference
in a great referee is very,
very important and it's so subjective.
It's so hard to decide when a guy's done.
And how do you know and do you take
into consideration how tough the guy is.
Cause like Frankie Edgar can survive
past the lands of doom where most people
drown in their own fear.
He survives past that and
comes back and can win.
There's guys like him and then there's
some guys at once they get hit and once
they get hurt,
they're just,
they,
their ability to recover is not the same.
And I don't know what it is.
I don't know if it's just
the person who recovered,
didn't fight someone who hits hard enough
or in the correct places to do enough
damage where they couldn't return
or if they're so damn tough,
it doesn't matter who hits
them or where they hit him,
they figured out a way to make it back.
It's who knows?
There's a lot of arguments on both sides,
but man,
you got to take into
consideration like if,
if you're watching,
say a Frankie Edgar Gray
Maynard fight and you go,
oh my God,
this could be stopped at any moment.
It can be stopped,
but it wasn't stopped and Frankie came
back to when he had a draw in one fight,
one in the second fight and the
second fight where he won by knockout.
It was arguably even crazier because
gray Maynard was fucking him up in the
first round.
Again,
like gray Maynard was a beast and he was
huge for one 55 but Frankie Edgar got
through that storm.
Some guys wouldn't have in some referees
would have stopped that fight and I
don't know who's right.
That's,
I want to be really honest about this.
I have no idea who's right.
I don't know what the right move is.
I don't know if the right move is to let
a guy fight and let them recover and,
and,
and give him every chance
he can to win that fight.
Even if it makes him
take unnecessary damage.
Give him the benefit of the doubt or err
on the side of caution and safety and
different fighters would
have a different opinion.
Um,
you know,
there's,
there was this archaic idea for a long
time that is pretty much since been
abandoned,
but the idea was that
if you tap from strikes,
you're a bitch.
It was a real thing.
You know,
that people would stick.
And George Saint Pierre his face because
he tapped with strikes to Matt Serra.
Matt Serra was just blasted him
and he was on top blaspheming.
Him and George knew he was going out.
So he just,
he had a tap.
Matt Serra was a Kol artists too.
He could hit fucking hard.
Um,
but when you tap to strikes,
if you,
you know,
if you know that you're
not going to recover,
I think it's a smart move.
I think we have the wrong
way of looking at it.
If we denigrate P I know,
I know they do it just to talk shit.
I know it's a,
I don't,
you know,
you're testing someone's courage but I
think between fighters there should be a
difference between the shit talking that
fighter's engage in and then the way
that other people analyze
the actual sport itself.
Because I think if you analyze
the actual sport itself,
you can't see anything wrong with tapping.
It strikes if you're a,
you're a pundit,
you're a sideline or you're an MMA fan,
your eye,
in my opinion,
if you really trust you guys' judgment
as a champion and as a high level fighter
like George Saint Pierre,
as you can't be upset if the taps,
the strikes,
it's cause he's getting fucked up and
he knows it like the you want to you and
Jay check,
she said she didn't tap the strikes.
She said she was moving her hand around.
It looked like a tab to me.
She was getting smashed,
though she might not have
even known she was tapping.
She might've been in a a memory short
out circuit or she's getting blasted,
blasted,
blasted.
So if she even remembers tapping,
who knows?
She's getting cracked,
man.
I mean she got clipped with that left hand
and then rose gets on top of her and
starts dropping haymakers on her,
which was boom,
boom,
boom.
And you see her reach over and tap right
as a referee gets in and rescues her.
And she might not have meant it.
She might've been just,
you got to realize when you're
getting smashed in the face like that,
everything is chaos.
It's fireworks and sparks.
And every situation is different.
In one situation,
you might have a guy who was fully aware
of what's happening and knows exactly
what he's doing.
He's getting bombed on,
but he can get through it.
Versus a person who gets hit
and from the very first shot,
they don't know what
the fuck is happening.
They're just on Queer Street.
They're gonna fail.
They don't know where they are.
They're like,
whoa.
And you can't see it from the outside.
The only person who knows is the person
that's getting and you only person who
knows their ability to recover.
Now how much is that his psychological,
how much that is their fighting spirit,
how much of it is physiological guesswork?
No one knows.
It's a combination of all
those things for sure.
100% cause you can't just
have the physical and you
can't just have the mental.
If you have the mental and someone
has the physical way better than you,
you have to have all of it.
It's a big,
there's a,
the,
the idea that any person
could be an MMA champ,
it's like Ooh,
I don't know cause everyone that's a
champ is fucking super ups exceptional.
If it's not just physically,
it's physically and mentally
like it's not an easy game.
It's a crazy fucking sport.
And who knows if you want a chapped,
it looked like she tapped.
Who knows if she realized
what was going on,
you know?
Did you see that thing about that football
player that was diagnosed with CTE
for the first time while he was alive?
We sort of glossed over it.
When we were talking to Dan Carlin,
this is the first time a living football
player has been diagnosed with CTE
and ask what it was,
but it says there unnamed.
Mm.
Yeah.
I wouldn't want people to know,
I guess man,
they're saying that even
high school kids have it,
but high school kids who
play a lot bang heads a lot.
You're going to get it like that is,
that is so hard to deal with.
You think about how many
people play football,
how many people box,
how many people fight,
how many people are going
to walk out of that thing?
Does God's Ville
and how many people are going to be
really clever like mighty mouse and avoid
the damage and just have a
technical understanding of
like where to be and we're
not to be what's coming next,
how to,
how to keep somebody's thinking,
how to overload their,
their,
their mind with possibilities.
You know,
it's like you've got two different styles.
You've got that style.
I think these super technical upper
echelon of MMA where he's like get super
aggressive and picks up his pace towards
the end of the fights and wind up
finishing guys just had a just
excellence like that crazy um,
suplex to arm bar thing that he did
on um,
ray a goddamn it.
What's his name?
Ray Borg.
The taz Mexican devil.
I fucked that up all the time.
And when I do the Wayans I
call him the Tasmanian Devil.
It just comes into my mouth like an idiot.
But Ray Borg who's a very good fighter
and very tough and fast man when mighty
mouse just put it on him,
it was like you're watching an artist,
you're watching someone who's just clearly
head and shoulders technically above
anyone in this division.
That's why this fight
that Tj is asking for,
it gets really interesting.
Tj Dillashaw versus mouse is going to be
one of the greatest fights of all time.
If they could pull it off,
they actually wind up making that fight.
Holy Shit.
Will I be excited?
I'll be so excited.
Cause I think this would be the first
time in a long time where mighty mouse has
been challenged.
I mean you've got challenged by Ian.
Ian Mccall had him in a really bad spot.
Um,
he certainly been challenged
by other fighters.
You know,
he certainly like fought fighters early
in his career where he had like really
good fights with them.
Joseph Benevidez but at
the stage that he's at now,
he's like,
he's so fucking,
he sell advanced that I think it takes
someone like a Tj Dillashaw like a real
super confident world champion killer to
give him the fight that we need to see.
Cause if Tj really can make one 25 and
he says he really can make one 25 then
holy shit.
What a fight that is.
Ooh,
that's a good fight because TJ
will have a giant power advantage.
Right?
I mean Tj is knocked out
Hanan Barao Tj is knocked out.
Cody Garbrandt in his last fight,
TJ avoided all,
all the chaos that John
Linacre brings into the cage.
Tj avoided all that.
He shut him down.
Like TJ right now is operating at a
real high world championship level.
And the only fight that he lost,
he lost to Dominick Cruz by
the narrowest of margins.
Some people don't even feel
like you lost that fight.
The,
there was an argument that if you look
at the damaging blows that he landed more
damaging blows to Dominic picture it.
Particularly if you
factor in the leg kicks.
So it's a,
it's arguable that that
was it at the very worst,
a draw that was a such
a close fight to call.
That's arguable.
Or you could argue the Dominic one too.
But the point is he's a lid git
world championship caliber fighter.
Like TJ is a fucking killer.
He's a killer.
What he did to Hennen borrows insane.
And then what he just did to Cody
coming off the deck and Kale and Cody
Garbrandt like that.
That's fucking insane too.
He's in rare form.
So him versus mighty mouse is the fight.
That's the fight where you go,
Holy Shit.
Which one of these guys is arguably
the best fighter in the world?
Cause right now we
think it's mighty mouse.
But that's that thing
always moves up and down.
Like who's the best fighter in who?
You know that it always moves around.
Like when Jon Jones wins and
knocks out Daniel Cormier,
you go,
damn,
you almost want to give it to John.
Like he's easy in a deeper shark pond.
You know there's more killers.
He's fighting Cormier who's just as good
as they get after beating rumble after
holding the title and John Kay,
awesome.
You got cop hand.
You almost have to give it the John.
But then John test positive.
So you're like what the fuck man.
So here's the heat.
It's John
and DJ,
right?
Demetrius is probably my ideas.
Number one cause and John is in the
situation where he's probably going to get
suspended or something.
But then you got probably Tj,
if not George Saint Pierre GSP
moved up on the official list.
Did you go to number one?
Number two
Oh of course.
That's interesting that you give them
that with one fight against Michael Best
Bang.
That just shows you how bad ass you
have to be to step in and fight Michael
Bisping after Michael Bisbing
knocks out Luke Rockhold,
after he had beaten Anderson Silva defends
his title against Dan Henderson and
he just jumped in there and beat him and
then jumped to number two and the pound
for pound rankings.
Like,
welcome back,
man.
It's crazy.
So what do you think about all that stuff?
They're having all this,
uh,
these conversations about who's ranking
the fighters and that the organization
shouldn't be able to rank the fighters.
Like do it,
shouldn't be able to make the matches.
It's done technically right
now through a writer's right,
but mostly writers is it,
I think are,
you can see who the writers are,
right?
Who writers are voting panelists.
I'm sorry,
but they're all people from,
let's see.
Yeah.
But at the end of the day,
logs and whatnot,
do you have see decides what
they're going to do right now?
At the end of the day,
they go,
yeah,
you guys are cute.
Listen,
George Saint Pierre is going to fight.
Michael Bisping shut the fuck up.
It's going to compare it to a,
just something that came out this week,
the way the college football at friends,
they're big playoff as they have a
panel that takes into account all of the
official rankings that are done,
a couple of computer rankings.
But then at the end of the thing,
it's still the seven or eight people
are going to decide that this team is
ranked over this team and it
really comes down to money.
Dick matchups they want to see
and what they can sell in ads,
but they don't officially say that.
It just creates more posts
that like why did they do this?
We don't understand it.
And they won't say it was that Kinda,
yeah,
well it's the UFC has the ability to
do whatever it wants and they're in a
situation and this,
here's the argument for it.
During the situation where they just
bought this organization for $4 billion
that need to make money,
motherfucker.
So think going to have Tyron
Woodley fight Nate Diaz.
Like,
Hey,
I was going to do some paper
review numbers and it will,
that's an interesting fight.
I like to see it.
I'd like to see,
uh,
I'd like to see how Nate
deals with the biggest,
fastest welterweight in the division,
the biggest knockout artists
welterweight in the division.
I mean there's no doubt about it.
Tyron Woodley is a tank.
He's a tank who throws missiles your way.
Boom,
boom.
And he's gotten very tactical.
People got mad at him for
those two Wonderboy fights.
But I,
I suggest that they don't truly
appreciate what those fights represented.
They represented extreme
consequences for any mistake.
You're fighting a guy who's like one of
the best counter strikers on the planet
earth in Wonderboy.
He's one of the sneakiest slippery
just strikers in the sport.
He moves like a world champion karate guy
who also has takedown defense and he's
got a ton of experience in MMA
now and he just fights weird.
He throws front leg
roundhouse kicks to your face,
he jumps in and hits you with shots you
don't see common cause he like has that
blitz karate style that he employs
sometimes very difficult to hit.
His hands are always down low and Tyron
managed to not just beat him and they
were boring fights.
I'm not going to lie to you.
They were boring fights,
but they weren't boring to
me while they were happening.
It was boring in terms of the overall
result because it was a five round
decision.
We're not a lot of exchanges took place,
but it wasn't boring
when I was watching it.
And this is why it's because
now that you know that what,
how it ended,
you'll just sit through the fight and go,
oh my God,
this is boring.
But when you don't know
what is going to happen,
they don't know either.
And they're making these decisions and
they're so evenly matched that they're
canceling each other out.
And Tyron is doing a very smart thing
by not engaging and he's not doing too
much because if he does too much at leaves
these openings and he doesn't want to
even remotely risk that,
he's going to put himself in a position
where he gets open and wonderboard
catches him.
So he makes Wonderboy do all the leading.
And then when the bombs get
dropped on both occasions,
Tyron Woodley was the
one that hurt Wonderboy,
which is crazy when you
think that Wonderboy is one
of the best kick boxers it's
ever fought in MMA.
He had some insane kickboxing record.
I want to quote it out
of the top of my head.
I think it was 57 and [inaudible]
57 [inaudible] as a kickboxer.
He's,
this is a guy that George Saint Pierre
said was the best striker that he's ever
sparred with.
That's how God damned good Wonderboy is.
He's,
he's,
he's another level striker and those
two fights between Tyron Woodley and
Wonderboy,
essentially we're striking
exchanges for the most part,
except for the first fight,
the first fight.
Tyron did get him in a gay teen for awhile
and it looked like he was burning his
arms out.
Like you couldn't believe that
wonder boy you got out of it.
But the point is that in the points,
in the moments of the fight,
we're one fighter was in trouble.
It was always wonderful and that's
enough in my eyes to give tiring the
decisions for sure.
Just the just that if we want
to look at what is a fight,
I think the current
system of like 10 points,
nine points,
it's too flawed.
It's a,
we adopted this from boxing we that we
should have a way more comprehensive
system and I think it should be a system
that's probably over a hundred points
or up to a hundred points rather that you
have points for significant moments in
the fight.
Like maybe significant moments when
someone gets dipped that accounts for a
certain amount of points,
significant moments where a person almost
get submitted and figures out how to
power out that accounts for
a certain amount of points.
Do they power out and wind up reversing
the position cause that should be worth
a certain amount of points.
You know there should be
an accumulative effect.
It shouldn't be just
like you want or you won.
She'd be like,
how do you know who won?
Like can we look at the stats?
Can we look at the numbers and then can
we look at it from an expert point of
view?
Cause every punch does not have the
same impact at other punches do.
Every kick does not have the
same impact that of the kicks do.
And every submission doesn't have
the same probability of succeeding.
So if you're watching
all these things happen,
you need real world class
experts to assess what's
happening at any stage of the
fight.
Like you should.
The only people should ever judge a fight.
Our guys like bat Hume who
used to judge for pride,
guys like Duke Roufus like
worldclass guys for Rasa Hobby.
We could,
you could get that level of martial
artists to judge fights and I think you'd
have the opportunity to create a totally
new system that's not boxing base.
Cause the 10 point must
system is just so flawed.
Have a new system and just only have
high level worldclass martial artists and
nothing less do all the judging cause
they don't understand what the differences
between someone just taking somebody
down and someone taking someone down and
threatening them.
Someone who's on the bottom was winning
with elbows or was threatening with
submissions.
Maybe they don't understand how
close these submissions are.
Some people don't know what a triangle
is locked up until it's a fucking tap.
You know,
there's,
if you've never sparked a day in your
life and you watch someone who's tapping
someone with a wrist lock,
you're not going to know
what the fuck is happening.
You're just not most likely unless
you're a real efficient auto that's just
never physically practiced it.
Most of the people that are referees,
unfortunately,
or I should say judges,
there's a lot of them,
I don't want to say most of them.
A lot of them are real martial artists,
100% but there's quite a few that were
sort of grandfathered in from boxing and
they don't necessarily
know a whole lot about MMA.
Now,
this is not representative
of the vast majority,
but I see them every now and then and
some of them were very nice people and I
say,
Hi Mike,
how you doing?
I mean,
we're just talking disagreements on
things and maybe different levels of
appreciation for what's happening,
but some we get every now and then you
get a decision where everybody looks at.
Everybody was,
what in the fuck does that
just say like everybody,
you,
me,
everybody look over at Tony.
I look over at Jon Anik,
he'll look over at me.
I look over at Daniel Columbia.
He'll look over at me and were like,
what the fuck?
That shouldn't happen.
That shouldn't happen when all the experts
are in agreement that this is a bad
decision.
Now we're not talking about
like debatable moments.
Like there's fights where
you look at it and go,
man,
I could see the argument
for this guy winning.
And then the other guy could say,
well I see the argument for that
guy winning and I'll be like,
damn,
you got a point.
You know like Brendan and I
will do that all the time.
He'll,
he'll make an argument for why he thinks
that Conor won the second fight easy.
And I'll make an argument and like,
I don't know man.
I don't know about all that.
I mean we're not using the same system
back then when someone got dropped,
it's not an eight a ten eight thing.
Right.
It's not like they don't give away
ten eight rounds as quickly back then.
I'm pretty sure that was the old
rules wasn't not God damn it.
I should know that.
Anyway,
point being,
um,
some people think Nate could have got
to draw on that fight and I'm like,
maybe,
maybe it wasn't far enough away.
We couldn't see that it was
one of those where like Bob,
maybe this has been a bunch of fights
like that and I could see the argument for
Conor winning 100%.
He hit him quicker,
faster,
harder one the first rounds bigger,
you know.
But man,
I don't know.
We're adding points if you just doing
this ten nine thing that occasionally 10,
eight,
but now most of the states are adopting
the full new MMA regulations and as they
do that we're going to get a much better,
we're going to have a much better uh,
range of rounds.
Like what would around scores
as which is a good step.
It's a good step in the right direction.
I just think it is an incredibly critical
part of the sport is who judges the
decisions.
And that again is not to disparage
anybody who's currently doing it,
but I think it is a position that should
be held in the highest of esteem right
up there with referee.
I think this position is,
is,
uh,
it's crucial for the
future of the fighters.
It's crucial for the legitimacy of the
sport itself because when bad decisions
happen,
people get angry and they question
whether or not the sport is legitimate.
And that's dangerous to the
respect that the athletes face.
Like,
here's a perfect example.
Canelo Alvarez versus Gennady
Golovkin everybody was a boxing fan,
knows Gennady Golovkin won that fight
and last year a huge Canelo fan and you
just,
you're just absorbed in Canelo.
You love him.
If you watch that fight,
Golovkin seem to control way more
of the fight that Canelo did.
It didn't mean a Canela didn't win rounds
didn't mean Canelo didn't land good
shots,
but he lost he,
it seemed to me that he lost
and they didn't give it to him.
Golovkin didn't get the decision.
It was a draw and people
were watching it going,
what the fuck?
And that's what Brendon called in advance.
Brenden's shop called it in advance.
He's like,
and let's go Lufkin wins by knockout.
He's never women in decision.
And I go,
you really think so?
He's like,
fuck yeah,
he nailed it.
He totally nailed it.
When,
when they read the draw,
I put my hands on my face like
Macaulay Culkin home alone.
I Wa oh,
you fucked him.
Who fucking not Eagle Love Kid.
Oh,
you got 'em.
What do you think of the,
when they did the instant replay at,
I think it was the first
time at the UFC in New York.
I didn't know Walt Harris fight.
Yeah,
it's a good move ma'am.
They keep doing that or is that
only a one time kind of thing?
I don't know.
They should keep doing it.
No,
it wasn't Walt Harris,
right.
Wolf.
Which fight was it?
They said they did it
because of the massage.
Aussie Weidman fight.
Right.
And then they used it.
I guess it got used though
during those two fights,
right?
Yeah.
It was Juan Harris fighting
and it was the other fight.
Um,
uh,
it was Demir.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So I came into play and was used properly,
probably,
right?
Yes.
It was.
Well,
the wall Harris things.
Very unfortunate.
And he had kicked that dude.
Um,
but the other one a owes
Demir got knocked out by,
who was the gentleman?
Austin.
Tamir was fighting.
Uh,
don't try to remember.
Look it up.
I was like,
I was there.
I can kind of remember.
I remember him like being pissed
that he thought he'd knocked a loss.
Then you came in and told him
that he didn't actually lose.
Is that the duty?
Fobts a beast.
Um,
this is a weird time.
We're at time for the sport man.
Like a,
this is like a transitionary period,
I feel like.
And uh,
Connor is such a gigantic star that
he's almost eclipsed the sport.
Who Was it?
It wasn't,
it wasn't.
No.
Oh.
Volkov owes Demir is the
guy who's going to fight.
Yeah,
he's going to fight.
I'm
like,
that's hilarious.
Just pull up the last card.
Yeah.
17.
It's not Alexi Oli nick.
Actually that sounds right.
Is it Curtis blades defeated
Lexi Olin name Curtis blades.
Beat the shit out of him.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's right.
Curtis blades is a really
interesting prospect,
is a big,
big kid,
is super athletic,
and he threw a,
an illegal kick,
but it literally just touched the ear.
That was the god Beer Walt here.
That was the illegal kick and that
that was God be Your Walt Harris.
Yeah.
The other one was a doctor stoppage.
Right.
But wasn't there something
that happened in that fight?
There was also a controversial,
I think he was beating him
up and then there was a,
I can't remember how it stuck.
I think it was who did God be a fight?
He fought Walt Harris.
He got head kicked.
Correct.
Right.
And God beer got the win on this.
But then when Curtis blades,
he accidentally kicked him in the
ear or you just touched his ear.
Referee stopped the fight after blades
delivered in an illegal kick to down the
opponent.
Yeah.
Doctor called in to check to see that
that kick barely touched his ear like he
was already done.
Yay.
Right?
Yeah,
he was hurting really bad.
Curtis was putting a beating on him and
when he went down Curtis through this
wild kick and just touched,
I mean literally touched his ear,
it did not hit him,
but the referee saw the contact and then
went to the instant replay to make sure
that it was okay.
But as soon as the referee
saw the instant replays,
like,
okay,
clearly he's okay.
But the doctors looked at
him and they asked him like,
dude,
this guy's fucked up like this.
This fights over.
And I think he said that it was over.
He said he couldn't continue.
I was bringing that up to begin with.
Could do you know how the
instant replay worked?
It was like,
did they all just get into a huddle and
watch the video or is there someone,
I can imagine the referee probably right.
Watches it and they probably
watch it with like Mark Ratner,
one of the officials,
you know,
and they,
they look at it and make a,
an informed decision,
you know,
and I don't know what the
parameters are that are,
no,
don't who gets the call.
But I would imagine it's a group.
I would imagine there's very
little disagreement when
someone's looking at film
like that cause they're not biased.
They don't,
I mean these guys,
if you have John McCarthy and herb dean,
they're looking at film,
I guarantee you they're going to
agree and what it is and it's uh,
there's a lot of dispute
dispute about that kind of shit.
You know,
it's,
it's really important to have those guys
that are like completely on top of the
rules.
Like there was one fight where,
uh,
Tim means fought cowboy Olivera
and he hit him while he was down.
Do you remember that?
And we were trying to figure out whether
or not it was legal and I believe it
was Dan Merkley,
Yada.
And we even got mark Ratner on the air
and Mark Ratner thought it was illegal
knee cause he was down on one
knee with one foot and no hands.
He's like under the new rules
that would be legal and big.
John McCarthy says,
no,
it's not.
If anything from your feet other than
the soles of your feet are down on the
ground,
you're still a down to Poland.
And I was like,
oh.
So he had explained it to me after the
fight because everybody was called it
three points of contact,
but Olivera literally did not
have a foot on the ground.
He just had his knee,
his foot was up in the air and his
other foot was touching the ground.
And he got kneed in the face
and we got kneed in the face.
They said it was an illegal nay.
And we were like,
how is that the case?
Cause there's,
there's only two points of contact.
There's the knee and the foot.
Like you're not talking about Nia foot.
And the hand is just
two points of contact.
But apparently it can't be
anything other than the ball.
Your feets.
But it could be is you have the both
balls of your feet down on the ground,
but you have one hand down
that's three points of contact.
And under the new rules that would
be legal under the old rules.
If you touch the ground at all,
it's illegal.
Super confusing.
Right.
So in that one,
it was really important to have a,
a referee like big John Waite.
And right there.
Yeah.
See he smashes him like see how he's got,
yeah.
The need means more than one.
Right.
That's what they're going with.
Well I think when it landed that right
foot was elevated and was off the ground,
then something similar happened.
Where did the guy delivering that needs
like lifted him up off the ground.
Yeah.
Get them off the ground yet.
Yes.
Yeah guys have done that to lift him
up off the ground and slammed ease into
their body because they were
touching with their hands.
You can do that.
That's legal.
It is a weird a rule.
It's a rule that we're
going to have to figure out
what makes sense because the knees
to the head to a down deponent.
I feel like that almost makes sense
because that is a real legitimate move.
And if someone can do that to you,
why is that different?
Is it too easy?
Like why is that different than being
able to elbow someone in the face when
they're on the ground?
Cause it hits harder?
Is that what it is?
Okay,
so it's better.
So I can't use it because it's better.
So you can just elbow me
all day long in the face,
but you can't name me in the head
and put me out on my miseries.
I don't know who's right or who's wrong,
but it's an effective
martial arts technique and
they've eliminated supposedly
for the safety of the fighters.
But you got to figure out like
what's legal and what's not legal.
Like here's another thing,
and this is a fascinating fight that
just took place between Matt Brown and
Diego Sanchez.
Crazy wild fight.
As long as it lasted.
Matt Brown lands this fucking beautiful
Elbulli palms him away and just boom,
drops this beautiful elbow on him.
I mean it was just picture
perfect and Diego goes limp,
like a sniper.
Just shot him from the
sixth floor depository.
I mean it was perfect.
It's like the perfect Kao.
But Diego was complaining that
it was the back of the head.
But here's the thing,
nobody gives a shit if it's the back
of the head of your standing up.
Watch this,
boom.
Look how it goes.
Limp.
I mean that is Diego Sanchez is a fucking
warrior dude for him to go limp like
that.
Look at this.
Boom.
Totally on the back of the head,
but that's okay.
When you're standing up,
that's,
it's weird if you punch something
in the back of the head,
like when Matt Serra Fought George,
I'm pretty sure some of those
shots he blasted him with,
he hit him in the back of the head.
It might've even been the first one
because if you're swinging sometimes and
your hand goes around like your hand
hits the back of the head all the time.
Head kicks,
head kicks hit the back
of the head all the time.
I give you neck kicked.
Somebody.
Like if you go over,
like say if someone's standing
with her left shoulder to you,
have you go over that left shoulder
and dropped down with that kick,
that neck kick shit that a lot of
time it goes in the back of the head.
That's a lot of times where it's landing.
It's coming around.
You're coming over the short.
You're literally slamming your he foot
the instep right into the back of that
dude's head and that's a hard fucking
impact from a leg happens all the time.
It's totally illegal.
It's weird because if
you get on the ground,
they'll go watch the back of the head,
watch the back of the head
like even from the mountain.
I mean even for the guard,
rather.
If you're in someone's garden,
you're punched him.
Watch the back of the head.
Everybody's watching the back of the head.
How about protect the back of your head?
No one says,
watch your eyes.
What?
Don't hit the eyes.
You don't say it on hit eyes.
Be The back of the heads off limits.
It seems like a good spot to hit.
Like what do we do it and I mean,
well it's so dangerous.
It's everything is dangerous.
This is fighting.
This is MMA.
Look,
it's we shouldn't,
you know what works the best if you can
elbow someone in the back of the head
sometimes.
How can we can't do it all the time.
I'm not saying that anybody
should change that result.
The result was perfect.
Matt Brown by Kale.
I'm not saying that.
What I'm saying is open it up.
Let guys do whatever they want to do
and no gloves.
I'm tired of saying this.
Take the gloves away.
No raps,
no hand wraps.
That would save a lot.
You would not be able to get
away with nearly as much.
Everybody would look like
John Wayne par though.
You'd be all cut up.
But I just think it's more realistic.
It's just so weird to me.
He put pads on your knuckles,
but you're allowed to elbow
someone in the eyeball.
Oh,
you're protecting your hands.
that seems like cheating.
You should be like,
if you only hit someone
with your hands so hard,
that should be how hard you can hit them.
Shouldn't be able to
fucking put them in a cast.
I mean that's what you're doing.
You put them in like a
soft leather covered cast.
That's what that Margarita fight was.
You know when Margarita got busted with
Shane Mosley when they found a cement
and his gloves,
I took it too far.
But that's what it is.
You're,
you're,
you making it so you
can hit someone harder.
It hurts almost as much.
It doesn't have the sharpness to it that
someone has when they hit you with bare
knuckle.
Bare knuckle has like a sharpness,
but the amount of power that someone
can generate just w with no regards to
their own safety is more,
they can swing drop bombs on you.
That
copy cause of that picture.
They saw it and I do not know.
Did they see it there?
You could see it there.
I mean it's hard to tell what
that is and that's what that,
that's what that other picture
was sort of alluding to.
Can you make that bigger?
That's far as it'll zoom.
I think it's hard to tell what that is.
That could just be the
gauze that's all wet.
I mean it's after the fight
it looks like a crack.
I guess that's what they're
trying to say is like low.
Really.
I mean,
I don't know that Gosh
shouldn't crack like that.
Right.
I should rip
Yo.
Imagine if that's the case.
What if it really did
turn into like hard shit?
Like real plaster.
Whoa.
I don't know how they found it.
Yeah.
I mean how did he get caught?
I don't know either.
I think they uh,
someone from,
cause that's how you catch sugar.
Shane Mosley's team watched him,
watched him wrap his hands.
I think you're allowed to rap,
watch your opponent,
wrap their hands.
And he noticed something in the
wraps and had it pulled out.
So then everybody decided that that's
what he had been doing his whole career,
which is why he had been smashing people
cause he had been smashing a lot of
people.
He just had more power.
More pop is loaded.
Gloves.
Prior to the 2009 sugar,
Shane Mosley,
Antonio Margarita fight Mosley's trainer
Nasim Richardson was in the Margarito
dressing room so he could
observe Margarito his hands
getting wrapped prior to
putting on boxing gloves.
As Margarita is trainers,
we're wrapping their fighter's hands.
Richardson noticed what appeared to be
a plaster of Paris powder on the wraps.
Don Tom.
Ah,
the plaster of Paris hardens when it
comes into contact with moisture and any
fighter will sweat during
the course of a fight.
Oh Shit.
As soon as Richardson saw the substance,
he accused Margarito of
fighting with loaded gloves.
Margarito his hands or rewrapped and
Mosley hammered Margarito he did too.
He beat the shit out of him that day.
I bet that dude felt guilty.
No one that you were going to try to
fight a world champion like sugar Shane,
but you try to change up.
Yeah,
that's not good.
But I think that bare
knuckle would be different.
I think it would be better
for submissions for sure.
Way Easier to secure.
Chokes your hand slip behind things way
easier when there's no gloves and it'd
be way harder to hit somebody.
You,
you would have a really hard time if
someone duct and you hit the top of their
forehead,
you can easily break your hand.
Like people break their hands
all the time and that way.
Um,
what else did I want to talk about?
I think that might be it,
dude.
We covered it all.
Although Max Holloway,
we covered that a little bit.
I want to see if,
although still can compete at a world
class level and improve because you know
that he can compete at
a world class level.
You've seen the last few
fights that he's had.
He's still,
I mean other than the fight that he had
with Connor were Connor starched him.
Did he fight Frankie Edgar
right after he fought Conor?
I believe he did.
I believe that's who
we won the title from.
Is that who it was?
Yeah.
And he uh,
outboxed him,
you know,
he fought a guy in Max Holloway
that's at the top of his game,
top of his game for now and
with more height to come.
But I mean,
he's just peaking.
He's ramping it up right now.
Max is a fucking beast.
So it's interesting to see whether or
not all though can recover and he doesn't
have a full camp for this fight either.
You know,
he had to take this fight on,
um,
I want to say four weeks notice.
See if that's true.
I don't want to lie,
but
I think Max Holloway is one of the
best up and coming fighters for sure.
In the world,
a world champion.
When I say up and coming,
I mean up becoming in like the
pound for pound sort of a way.
I mean he's just greatness
written all over him.
If he just keeps up at this
pace and he's got the attitude,
he's got the skills,
he's a straight killer.
But you can't look past
and old warrior like Aldo.
Not saying that he is,
I bet he's not.
But um,
everybody else can't look past it either.
Although still fucking super dangerous.
He's going to be real motivated in a wind
by all though would be to [inaudible]
John,
I can't tick at this stage of the game.
If although could bounce back the way
he bounced back from the Mcgregor fight,
an outbox Frankie,
if he could bounce back in some way,
figuring out what he did wrong in
that first fight and solve the puzzle.
Whoa,
that's big.
That's a big fight.
And the other fight we talked about,
um,
Tyron Woodley and Nate Diaz
does the other one.
That's crazy.
Five days ago I found that it says he
was supposed to fight Ricardo Lamas,
uh,
two weeks later.
And now he's been bumped up to this.
So it was only five days
ago they made that fight.
Whoa.
And so he only has two weeks then.
Yeah.
So yeah,
November 11th she's confirmed
auto replace Frankie Edgar.
So I guess that was
when they announced it.
Jesus Christ.
That's crazy.
Well,
I hope he's training a lot.
I hope he's in great shape.
I hope to weight cut isn't too
much either because he's a big guy.
At least he was for awhile.
He leaned out quite a bit because I
think he was having a really hard time
making that cut from like well into
like he looks like he's about one 70
something and they would cut down
to one 45 and real hard for him.
He would suffer in the last round,
the fights like uh,
if he didn't smoke guys early on,
sometimes he faded towards the end
like he did with Ricardo Lamas.
Like the end of the fight,
moss was on top of him.
Like he had done enough to win for sure.
But at the end he was fading.
He's getting tired.
And I think a big part of that was
probably just getting the water sock data.
You know those guys,
they tortured themselves,
man.
The card for this weekend,
Dun,
Dun Dun Duh
for doom and to bore is interesting.
I like that Tim Means and below Mohamad.
That's a serious fight.
Some good fights on that card.
All right,
and that is when Saturday,
yeah,
Saturday night.
Saturday night in Australia.
Oh Shit.
Oh Australia.
I'll be in,
I'm going to be in Phoenix.
I'm going to be in Phoenix,
Arizona.
I'm going to get to see a Mike Goldberg.
I haven't seen Mike and Forever.
He's killing it in Beltour man.
I like the fact that Bella tour exists.
You know,
I love the UFC.
The UFC is my home.
I'm not doing commentary for anybody ever.
The UFC is like family to me,
but I think competition is important.
I think it's important for everything.
I think the systems competing
with each other make some greater.
I think the more opportunities that
young fighters have to perform and fight,
the more you're going to see higher and
higher level of ability and performance
level fighting knowledge.
You just,
there's more,
competition is a higher level for the UFC.
It's higher level for Bella tour,
everybody is going to accelerate.
This is a growing thing right now and as
long as you're not competing with each
other on the same night long,
they don't do anything dumb and
that fights in the same night.
I think they compliment each other.
I really do.
I think there's some fighters
that will do better in Beltour.
that prefer to be in the UFC.
It's all good man.
It's all good.
You know the UFC has way
more worldclass fighters,
but bell tours got some
tough motherfucker,
some real legit worldclass
fighters to now and their,
their rosters growing like Rory
Macdonald's is one of the best fucking
welterweights on the planet
and he's over there now.
I hope we get him back.
I really do.
I love commentating his fights.
Lorens Larkin's over there now.
A llamas.
Like there's a,
there's a bunch of guys,
Diego,
Lima,
um,
I think,
uh,
Lima is,
or Douglas Lema is one of the best
fucking Walton weights on the planet for
sure.
His brother Diego,
I think it's still fighting for the UFC,
but there's a bunch of
town over there now.
Like real legit talent.
It's good.
It's good for everybody.
It's good for the sport,
gives people opportunities,
makes people raise their
games up for the athletes.
The more Michael Chandler's are out there,
the boogie man in the woods,
Michael Chandler is a boogie
man and 155 pound division.
He's terrifying for everybody.
It doesn't matter what organization
you fight for that guys,
straight up killer.
So this like,
there's enough really dangerous worldclass
fighters over there in Beltour for it
to be excitingly
competitive for everybody.
I think it's good.
And I liked the gold.
He's got a Gig because I love him.
Uh,
so I think that's it.
I think we did more than an hour.
We're going to call it the hour,
but I'm blabber mouth motherfucker
and I can't stop talking.
Um,
I don't feel the need to
apologize for anything I said.
I don't think I fucked
up and offending anybody.
If I did,
I'm going to blame it on the weed.
Anything to add young Jamie?
Nope.
I think that was a good first episode one.
I think we'll do this more often.
Okay.
I'm not,
I'm not guaranteeing every week,
but we'll keep it close.
All right.
Bye.