It's authentic.
That's sweet.
Yeah.
I'm just now getting over the hurricane
of Shannon Briggs.
It came through this with a storm of.
Let's go champ.
He's a maniac.
He is a maniac.
So,
uh,
I'm glad we can get you in here today
because,
uh,
explained to everybody.
First of all,
people don't know Chris produced and
what'd you direct it and produce it in a
bigger,
stronger,
faster and prescription thugs and
prescription thugs,
which is particularly important because
a lot of it was about the prescription
industry and the,
the how many people get hooked and
you've had experience with it.
I,
we,
we've all known people in the last.
People that have had problems with
prescription pills,
but you want her to come in and talk
about Kratom
sure.
Yeah.
You know,
a while back when I was actually hooked
on pills,
I was looking for a way to get off of
how it's searched the internet every day
on a way to get clean and sober.
And I came across this thing called
Kratom and I said,
are they sell it at these head shops and
different things.
And,
you know,
back then I wasn't really familiar with
the head shop singing or anything like
that.
So I actually,
um,
I never found it.
I never went out and sought it out.
And then,
um,
after going through Rehab,
I had heard about it a couple more times
from some people I've heard about people
taking it to get off of opiates.
It's a plant,
it's a,
it's a 100 percent natural plant comes
from,
um,
you know,
Thailand,
Indonesia,
Malaysia,
that's where they grow it.
It's been used for like 2000 years.
I'm basically,
it works sort of like an opioid,
but it's not a drug,
it's just a plant,
you know,
and it has these properties that have
helped people bridge the gap when they
get off of opiates so they don't have
withdrawals.
What it also does is help relieve pain
and it also helps with anxiety.
It helps with,
uh,
you know,
elevates your mood and it does all these
great things.
But the government now wants to make it
a schedule one drug.
But so you're saying it's not a drug
though?
Well,
you know,
that's,
I guess it's semantics.
It's like,
how do you classify something that's
been around for 2000 years?
No one's ever done any studies on it
being a drug and no one's ever done any
studies on it.
Well,
there's been some,
there's been actually a lot of studies
on it being a supplement,
but they aren't like these FDA approved
double blind placebo studies that
they're requiring for it to be on the
market as a normal supplement.
But it,
um,
does it,
uh,
has psychoactive properties.
Well,
it'll,
it'll elevate your mood.
So would just talk about Alpha brain are
some nootropics.
It'll work like that and it will elevate
your mood.
I mean,
I don't know where the real distinction
is between high and elevation of mood or
were,
you know,
what the difference is really there,
but it doesn't make you feel like.
It's not like I smoked pot.
It's more like I had a good cup of
coffee,
you know,
I'm fired up back in the day when it
used to take pre workout supplements.
Caffeine and ephedrine kind of feels
like that.
I just feel like fired up and ready to
go and I don't feel pain.
That's interesting to create them,
gets you fired up.
I would've never,
I would've thought it would've melted
you out.
I have zero experience or that you have
some here now and you could drive in
this stuff is
that they tell you not to operate heavy,
heavy machinery and things like that.
But I've never had a problem with it.
I actually take it to drive.
So you know,
tomorrow I'm leaving for Thanksgiving.
I had to drive six hours.
So that's your ass.
I'm taking Kratom before I get in the
car to go because it actually helps me
focus.
It relieves the pain.
Wow.
That's,
that sounds crazy.
So it,
it,
it mimics the effects of opioids,
right?
Opiates.
But it also elevates you.
Well sure.
So like if you don't know if you've ever
taken oxycotton or a vicodin or any of
those things like that.
A lot of times when people take that,
they feel like,
you know,
they're indestructible.
I took violin and I think it was viking
in once when I had my first knee surgery
in [inaudible] 93.
I fucking hated it.
I took,
I took it literally one time and I guess
for me,
you know,
I guess it's different for everybody.
I think it was vodka didn't,
it might've been percosets,
but whatever the doctor gave me for
pain,
I took the pills.
I was like,
oh my God,
I feel so fucking stupid.
I'm like,
I'd rather be in pain that field as
dumb.
Sure.
I think a lot of times,
like what happened with me is I came out
of anesthesia from a surgery and I was
all doped up on the drugs and I didn't
even know it,
so it just kinda like,
just kept going,
you know what I mean?
Like I never,
I never stopped getting high from the
time I was in the hospital for like six
years.
So,
um,
for me it was like,
you know,
opiates were real big problem.
They were ruining my life.
They were destroying me.
Now that I got sober a two and a half
years ago and I started taking Kratom I
feel great.
Like everything in my entire career is
going skyrocketing,
things are going great.
I relationship,
my girlfriend's great,
just everything's been been good so I
can't really see the badness.
So when they decided to make this a
schedule,
one drug,
we decided to make a documentary about
it and show the world what it,
what it really is.
That seems really bizarre that you would
have a problem with drugs and then this
would help you.
Like I would think that if you have a
problem with drugs you would want to
stay away from anything that's sketchy.
Sure.
But a big part of addiction you got to
remember is that we relapse relapse if
you can have something.
It actually helps with alcohol
withdrawals and alcohol cravings.
So if we have something that will help
me to not crave those things or even
think about them and also not feel pain.
Like why should I have to be in pain?
Like there's no,
you know,
no.
You in pain right now?
Not right now because I took them before
I came here,
but I would normally be in a lot of
arthritic pain.
Okay.
Just and you have arthritis just
naturally,
right?
Double.
Yeah.
Double hip replacement surgery.
I need both of my knees done,
my shoulder shot,
you know,
kinda everything.
I'm kind of pretty beat up and so for me
it just works.
You know,
my brother who was also a power lifter,
he takes it as well before he trains and
he really loves it too.
It takes it before he lifts weights.
Yeah.
Wow.
And he's trying to bench 600 pounds so
he's not like,
it's not like he's using a little bit of
weight.
He's your brother's a gorilla and he's
pushing it.
That's,
that's so strange to me.
And this is all like,
I'm glad we didn't talk before this
podcast because I had a thought in my
head of what this stuff is.
And you changing it right now.
I,
you think it was.
Well,
I felt like it was probably just a good
way that people could relieve pain
naturally,
but I felt like if someone was going to
describe it to me,
I thought they were going to tell me
about an opiate type of effect.
That it just mellows you out,
but it doesn't,
it doesn't hurt you.
There are different strains of it.
There's a strain called Bali,
which is supposed to be good for anxiety
and kind of calm you down.
There's a strand called green melee,
which is like sort of get.
That's the one that is a good pre
workout,
but they're all kind of the same thing.
You know,
they all have the same alkaloids.
Kratom has 27 alkaloids.
So when you look at it,
it actually has alkaloids that worked
like opiate stay attached to opiate
receptors,
but not in the same way.
If you look at oxycotton when it
attaches,
they went opiate receptor.
I mean it's like,
you know,
it's stuck in there.
It's like screwed in basically if you
think about like a screw and opiate
recite screwed in there so tight that
you could never just pull it out,
you'd have to unscrew.
So with um,
with,
with the Kratom though,
it kind of like balance,
it Kinda like drifts around the top of
that opiate receptor.
It doesn't,
it doesn't attach it nearly as hard.
They say that opiates attach a thousand
times greater to the opiate receptor
than anything found in nature and
Kratom's found in nature.
Oh Wow.
But what about heroin?
Like the actual poppy seed is found in
nature,
right?
So,
and they have to do stuff to it to make
it,
you know,
heroin.
They have to do stuff with a coca leaves
to make cocaine.
They have to,
you know,
it's like marijuana and Kratom are
probably the two most similar things.
And when I went to,
uh,
interview,
Senator Mark Pocan last week about a,
he was the one that wrote a letter to
the government.
He wants to keep Kratom legal.
He thinks that,
you know,
it should be allowed for everyone.
And I said to him,
what do you think about marijuana?
And he was like,
I just think it should all be legal.
And it was the first time I was ever in
the presence of somebody that works for
the government saying that they think
that weed and Kratom and all this stuff
should be illegal.
And it's because he had a good head on
his shoulders about the problems that
people face every day.
You know,
it's not black and white.
Like I live in this gray area.
I don't,
I'm in a lot of pain.
But I don't want to take opiates and I
shouldn't have to take opiates.
So where's the pressure coming from to
turn this stuff into a schedule one drug
if there's no.
If there's no negative response by the
body,
you're not having people die of
overdoses.
Is there an ld 50 rate on this stuff?
Well,
if you look at,
you know where,
where is the ld 50 explained.
Probably explained to people lethal dose
at 50 percent.
Meaning if you take 50 rats and you give
them a pound of this shit,
50 of them are 25 die at a certain show.
We've heard about,
you know,
there's been no deaths from marijuana,
right?
Freedom is the same thing.
No,
no deaths.
There have been zero deaths and there,
there have actually been 15 deaths that
have been brought to the FDA and the dea
is attention.
Those 15 that's.
I actually went and interviewed one of
the.
One of the mothers.
The kid was on three psych meds.
He was withdrawn.
He was
honored withdrawing from three different
psych meds.
I have a black box warning that says,
warning,
if you're a teenager,
you might commit suicide basically,
and this kid committed suicide.
He didn't die from a Kratom overdose.
He died from committing suicide and his
mother wants to blame Kratom.
She doesn't think that the,
uh,
the psych meds had anything to do with
it.
And I don't want to say that Kratom had
nothing to do with it.
We don't really know.
And what I really call for with Kratom
is just more research,
like I want people to put in the money
to do the research to make sure that
this is safe and let's see if we can
solve this opiod epidemic.
Let's see if we can crack down,
you know,
basically lower the amount of opiate
prescriptions we have in this country.
I just read an article the other day.
One in seven people in America are going
to be affected with addiction problems.
Wow,
that's crazy.
One in seven.
That means somebody in your family,
that's,
that's insane.
Somebody in your family will be affected
by it and that's 10 percent.
Yeah,
that's weird.
That's weird,
right?
And not everybody is.
It's not that everybody gets addicted
that are affected by addiction.
My girlfriend was really affected by
addiction because when she met me,
I was taking drugs and drinking every
day.
And um,
that's a,
that's a big effect on,
especially on women.
It's tough.
It's tough thing to handle.
Now I can understand this woman whose
son died being to understand her remorse
and looking to point the blame at
someone.
And a lot of times people are reluctant
to point the blame towards something
that a doctor prescribed and they'll
automatically say,
well,
it probably wasn't that.
It was probably this other thing that's
not regulated.
You know what she said to me?
She said,
Chris,
I'm going to pray for you because I know
you're taking Kratom and I'm going to
pray for you that you're okay.
And I was like,
you know,
lady,
you don't need to pray for me.
Like I've been taking it for a year,
you know?
And I think that people just get it
wrong and I feel bad for her.
I feel bad for her.
And the fact that,
um,
that she can't just realize that,
you know,
she can't look at the research and see,
because when I went and interviewed her,
she said,
well,
I'm not even sure if Kratom killed them
and this is after a gigantic,
you know,
uh,
they,
they mount this gigantic media coverage
of this story,
right?
Like this was all over and now and now,
like two years later after the damage
has been done,
she's kind of coming back and say,
well,
I don't know if it was Kratom,
you know,
she already did the damage like that.
These are,
these deaths are the reason why the dea
wants to ban it.
Well,
the dea though is going on.
What kind of effort?
I mean,
when they do a scientific analysis of
creative and they break it down,
they find they don't find anything toxic
in it.
Do they know?
Well,
I talked to Melvin Patterson,
he's the spokesman for the,
for the dea.
And when I talked to Melvin Patterson,
what he told me is that they lean on the
FDA a lot for these kinds of decisions.
Right?
So they go to the FDA and they asked the
FDA,
can you give us an eight point?
It's like some sort of a thing that they
have in place.
It's like an eight point inspection to
make sure that this drug is not
dangerous,
you know,
and if it is dangerous,
it's deemed dangerous,
they'll take it off the market based on
the FDA's research.
So the dea had asked the FDA for that
eight point inspection,
the FDA never went ahead and did it.
So the DEA got upset and said,
well,
we're gonna abandon any way because
we're waiting on you guys.
And then there was a big uproar.
There was 100,000 people signed a
petition partly due to to you tweeting
about it and things like that.
It was a Guy Andrew Turner,
he tweeted you.
He was an Iraq war vet.
And um,
you should see his video.
He can't even speak without Kratom.
He cannot talk normal without Kratom.
He speaks with all these ticks and
twitches in his face due to they think
maybe ptsd and some other problems that
had affected him.
And now he takes Kratom.
And those twitches all go away.
He did a video on youtube that was kind
of amazing.
He stopped taking it for six days and
you can see all these twitches are
evidence and then he goes back on the
Kratom and they all disappeared.
Wow.
So who's pressuring the dea to turn this
stuff into a schedule one drug.
And why schedule one?
There is a,
there's a couple of patents that are on
the alkaloids that are in the plant.
So I think that big Pharma would be the
first place to look.
They have a couple patents.
They want to basically take this,
you know,
I think it's actually,
I,
I don't,
I don't look at it as being that bad,
but why make,
why make the organic kratom illegal in
order to turn this into a more powerful
drug?
They think that they can extract some of
these alkaloids,
right?
There's two alkaloids,
metallothionein,
and the other one is like seven hydroxy
metallothionein.
It's too technical for anybody to really
care about,
but there's two alkaloids that they
really care about that help with opiate
withdrawals and help with pain.
And those are the two,
and actually just want to ban the two
alkaloids,
but you can't do that because it's in
the plant.
So you have to ban the whole plant.
And to me,
you know,
you said it the best.
He said making something else illegal.
It's like archaic.
It doesn't make any sense.
What are you going to do to the people?
You know,
five states just legalized marijuana.
Now you're going to throw people in jail
for Kratom.
It doesn't make sense.
Well,
I'm worried about this new
administration when it comes to men may
various reasons,
but I'm worried about them when it comes
to being compromised by big Pharma.
I really am.
You know,
it's just a such a business oriented
administration and he's bringing all
these old dudes over there right out of
the TV show.
The strain,
like the vampire dudes that are hanging
out with the Nazis.
Like I'm looking at all these people
like Mike Pence and all these old dudes.
He's bringing in with these archaic
ideas.
They're all against gay marriage.
I mean,
it's ridiculous.
You know,
I was hoping that maybe trump would
bring in some people that would be
opposite of his thinking and you know,
it just hasn't happened.
So he was a Democrat for a long time.
I mean Donald Trump was always a
democrat.
I mean him running as a Republican is
kind of odd if you look at this history,
but he's going all in with a lot of
these people in.
Some of them are deeply opposed to
marijuana legalization federally and
know that stuff is very counterintuitive
and counter progressive and the
marijuana legalization,
we've been reading a lot about that and
it's going to be what a lot of people
think might be a mess because we're
making it recreational opens it up to
Marlborough and all these other
companies that make tobacco products to
now start selling cannabis and a turn it
into what we already have.
Bullshit.
Well,
I'm not opposed to them making it
commercial because I feel like the more
people do it,
the better we're all going to be sure.
I really,
I really believe that.
I mean,
people say,
Oh,
your upload who'd brew,
but I really think it's a it.
I think,
I mean you can call it a drug,
but whatever it is,
it is a component of life that makes
people calmer,
makes people happier.
It makes people more sensitive.
I just think it's better for people.
I was 100 percent against it ever since
I was in college.
Like I had just thought like a
marijuana.
Wow,
that's.
So,
that's the worst thing,
you know,
and,
and steroids.
I thought marijuana,
steroids were the,
were the devil and come to find out it's
all the drugs that the doctors actually
prescribe us that are the devil that we
need to look out for.
You know,
they're not necessarily to say the
devil.
They help a lot of people,
but we have to be very careful about
what we're putting in our bodies that
our doctors give us.
We can't just say,
well,
the doctor said it's fine and just take
it.
And that's how I got addicted to
opiates.
And a lot of people want to say,
I'll get it on instagram all the time.
Well Bro,
it's your fault,
man.
It's all your fault and they know
nothing about addiction.
It's not my fault.
It's not anybody's fault.
These things happen because it's a
progressive,
you know,
these drugs were designed to make you
addicted,
so to say,
it's my fault.
It's kind of ridiculous because the drug
was actually designed so people get
hooked on it.
Yeah,
you just didn't outrun it.
That's all it is.
I did not run it.
Yeah,
I mean that's really what it is.
It's like some people out run it and you
get away from it.
You should have been stronger brew.
All right.
How many people have to get fucking
addicted before you recognize that it's
a problem instead of the giant problem
in this country?
We lose a person to addiction every 19
minutes in this country.
Accidental overdoses.
I think I've said that several times on
your show and it's just,
you can't say it enough.
You know,
we have this giant opiod epidemic and we
have something here,
you know,
in,
in our film,
we're just,
we're starting to make a documentary
about this and in the film,
you know,
we show a guy who has a,
not a,
not a huge habit,
but six vicodin a day habit and he cuts
that down to zero using Kratom and we
watched that,
you know,
that process because I feel like that's
important to show that like,
Hey,
you can actually do this now if we have
people that are really,
really addicted to heroin and really,
really addicted to these other drugs,
they might need something like suboxone.
And then Kratom,
you know,
like we don't really,
we don't really know.
You know,
my friend Kelly done,
who owns the company,
uh,
urban ice that we were just,
we were just talking to,
he actually bought a farm up in
Washington and it's his intent if people
don't have money to go to rehab or do
whatever they can come up and visit him,
you know,
and get Kratom he's actually a licensed
therapists and all that stuff like that.
So like,
I feel like it's sort of this,
this grassroots movement to um,
to try to get people to even try Kratom.
That's what I've been trying to do is
get people like,
hey,
this,
just try it.
Like you said with marijuana.
The more people that try it,
the better off we'll be.
And I really feel that with Kratom to
making me want to try it now.
What is the name up Kratom plant?
Like what does the plant look like?
It's a plant.
It kind of looks like,
I don't know,
like a poison ivy plant.
I'm sure he can maybe pull one up,
you know,
but it basically just looks like just
like any other plant,
shiny green leaves.
And I don't think I even heard about it
until maybe a couple of years ago and I
didn't know how to pronounce it until a
month ago while people say Kratom
Kratom,
tomato,
whatever.
I didn't.
I mean I've rarely heard of.
I think someone gave me some after a
show,
one day I'm more wrong,
you know,
what that looks like or it goes,
it kind of happens a lot.
Like somebody will say,
hey here,
try this,
and I,
I never trust that either,
but for me what happened to me is very
interesting.
I have a lot of friends in this,
you know,
in this world of fitness and whatever.
And so I just ended up talking to a lot
of people that try a lot of different
things.
So after I got done with the opiates,
I was on Dr drew show and he said,
well you should try advil and tylenol
and combination that's going to be
better than an opiate for your pain,
for your chronic pain.
So I said,
okay.
I started trying that.
Then I get a phone call from my friend
who's lives in England who tells me he
just had a kidney transplant because of
all the insights he was taken.
So now he doesn't.
Nonsteroidal antiinflammatories which
are advil.
Sure.
Yeah.
Advil and tylenol.
So that.
So he had a kidney transplant.
I just thought,
you know,
I didn't think that that was going to
necessarily happen to me,
but I was taking like 10 advil a day,
you know,
that could happen.
Then how many will your friend tig?
And he said about 20 and he was in new
Bain addict before that,
so he doesn't know if it's a new Bain.
Right.
Blah,
blah blah.
Right.
So you're getting all these problems.
I just thought like,
well look,
taking 10 advil and tylenol a day
because I was taking them in
combination.
That just can't be good for your
campaign.
So my friend Kelly hit me up.
He's like,
hey man,
you should try this plant.
It might help you.
And what was your first experience with.
My first experience was um,
so my friend Kelly was a very serious
about this and he wants to help a lot of
people.
He said I'll fly to Sacramento.
I was living up by my brother at the
time.
So he flew out to Sacramento to see me.
He gave me some Kratom.
He went to his hotel.
I went to my house.
I had just been filming with my brother
for like five hours straight.
And my arthritis was like,
at its worst point,
like the worst it could possibly be.
Is that from standing?
Standing up?
Yeah.
Just get beat up,
you know,
and I'm also standing on concrete floors
and gyms and stuff like that,
so I was just like,
beat up.
I took the Kratom and then he came over
later that day to talk to me and I said,
dude,
you're not going to believe it,
but I'm in.
No,
I don't feel any pain right now.
No pain.
And it took a good two or three months
for me to really get into it because
like I might tell you now and you might
go home and try this,
right?
Right.
Anybody say,
yeah,
Chris,
whatever the fuck like that,
that doesn't work,
but then for some reason you'll go back
to it and then he'd go back to it and go
back to it and all of a sudden like it's
a miracle.
You.
I don't know what.
That's how.
That's how it was for me.
I'm not saying that's how it's gonna be
for everyone.
Well,
I'm not in any pain,
so if I took it,
it was just to get fucked up.
Well,
elevate your mood to elevate my mood.
I'm pretty happy right now.
I don't want to get more elevated.
I'll do something silly.
Yeah,
you might.
You never know,
but also helps with that lowers your
blood pressure.
It helps with anxiety,
blah,
blah.
Right.
So you can look at it for several health
band,
but it doesn't get you to a point where
you can't drive or you don't know how to
type.
I should probably get responsible and
say it hasn't gotten me to that point.
Hasn't gotten you to that,
but I have.
I have taken too much of it.
Oh,
okay.
Give me one of them packets and tell me
like how much you're supposed to take.
Well,
if it's all gonna be relative,
right?
You would take one of these.
What do you weight?
One Ninety,
200?
Yeah,
somewhere in the range of 200,
so 200.
So I take six of them that I worked up
to six of them pills.
Yeah.
I would say this is a packet of pills.
Sure.
Now now crate,
I'm a lot of times it's taken in a
powder form but it tastes disgusting so
I can't handle the powder so I just take
the capsules.
Yeah,
somebody gave me an a powder form and
I'm just like,
heroin.
You don't want to hear something really
interesting.
I,
I was supposed to speak at an AA meeting
the other day and um,
I got a phone call from,
from somebody at the AA.
If I took some right now.
How much should I take?
I take two.
Okay.
But you know,
like,
um,
I was supposed to speak at an AA meeting
and I got a phone call from a good
friend of mine and she said,
well,
I'm confused now because I'm not sure if
you're sober.
Oh,
because you're taking Kratom I'm taking
Kratom and it affects your mind.
So now I need to worry that you're
fucking up.
They're worried that I'm fucking up and
it,
you know what,
it actually hurt me.
Like it hurt.
It hurt to hear that from somebody that
like helped me get sober.
It really hurt my feelings.
Like,
I don't mean to sound like a pussy,
but like hurt my feelings to hear like,
Hey,
you're not sober from people.
I really looked up to him and I can
understand their worry.
I totally understand.
There I,
it's so confused.
It sounds like you're doing a heroin
substitute.
Sure.
Natural heroin substance and it's been
called,
you know,
herbal heroin.
So I can,
I can see their concern.
So is that maybe the same sort of
concern that led the dea to take a close
look at this?
Because I mean if you look at it,
I mean everyone wants to worry that the
dea is in bed with big Pharma and it's
all about business and they're really
here to screw over the American people.
Keep these legal,
natural things away from us.
But I had the same sort of reservations.
Man.
I didn't know until you came in here
today.
I didn't know that you could operate
cars on it and it doesn't fuck with you
and that you take it before a drive.
Like I would've never imagined that I,
I do want to stay in the area,
but I don't want to be here and be
irresponsible.
I don't think every.
I don't want to say,
oh,
everybody should take credit.
I mean everybody,
you know,
but I feel like I feel like I know that
it's safe enough to try.
For example,
I know it's safe enough for anybody to,
to try.
So I've seen it.
I've seen any in thousands of people
that are,
that are using it.
I get emails everyday from people that
take Kratom because we're doing a
documentary and you know as well,
you know,
when I feel that media has the power to
change your world,
I feel like what you do,
what I do,
we actually have a voice and we have a
power that can change people's minds.
My film bigger,
stronger,
faster,
completely changed people's minds on
steroids.
It did,
it changed my mind.
It gave me a view into it that I'd never
before and that.
And then there was a.
was it an hbo real sports did a whole
thing on steroids.
Real sports.
Yeah.
Sports.
And they were essentially saying,
where's the body's like?
Everyone's talking about people dying
from steroid overdoses.
No,
it's not what's happening?
They're dying from pain pills.
I didn't get to tell you how I turned
around on marijuana.
Oh,
the Joe Rogan experience listening to
the show,
you know,
that's why I said media is important.
I feel like it's.
We can change the world.
We can change things.
I was dead set against it,
thought it was for losers.
I'm like,
oh,
Joe Rogan smokes pot.
Maybe it's not so bad.
So I started doing the research.
I'm not saying I just jumped in and
started doing it,
but I've done the research and I know
enough that it's.
That it's safe.
You know,
we know it's 100 percent safe.
I mean,
you could definitely take too much of
it.
Just like you were saying,
you could take too much kratom.
You can get too fucking high and freak
out.
That's true.
But if just get a little bit high,
you're gonna be all right.
Ma.
Marijuana and Kratom or both.
They're both miracle plants.
They're both plants that are put here.
I,
you know,
if you believe in God,
I believe that,
you know,
these things were put here on the planet
for us to use,
to heal ourselves,
to feel better.
There's nothing wrong with feeling
better.
I think we have a big aversion in this
country to people being able to feel
better.
Like anything,
you know,
I don't know,
taking Kratom I'll.
It makes you feel better.
Like why is that a crime?
It shouldn't be fine.
And she'd be,
you know,
we have alcohol on the market that makes
people feel better.
We have cigarettes and tobacco and that
makes people feel better and they get a
little buzz from it or whatever.
Why not Kratom like what's the big deal?
Yeah.
We have a reluctance to indulgence in
some ways,
right?
Like we're worried about indulging in
something,
something pleasurable,
like it's bad for you.
Well,
people say,
oh,
Kratom,
I heard that makes you high.
And I'm like,
well first of all,
what would it be wrong?
What would be so bad with that?
That's a good feeling for a lot of
people.
I don't,
I don't see that that's so bad to have a
little bit of euphoria,
you know,
now being high on cocaine or crack or
whatever.
That's a completely different story.
We're not talking about that.
We're just talking about like a little
elevation in your mood.
Yeah.
There's a big difference between being
high and being impaired short,
right?
I think we,
we put those two together and they're
always in the same category for some
strange reason and they don't
necessarily have to be like a nice cup
of coffee gets you high.
Yeah,
I made it.
Look,
I drink a cup of coffee in the morning
and I start slap my hands together and I
want to start doing shit.
You know,
if I drank that little caveman coffee,
sure I'd be bouncing off the walls
because that's so strong and it's.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with it.
I love it.
I think it should be legal and I think
that you know of Kratom is in the same
league as coffee and starbucks is the
biggest business in our country.
Like why?
Why is it so bad?
So since the people like people that are
sober and then are helping you with
that,
they have concerns about it and there's
a lot of people that are going to.
It seems like this is a drug or a plant
I should say,
that just does not have enough.
There's not enough data,
there's not enough research,
not enough research.
And that's what we want to do.
We would like,
you know,
look,
every time there's been an epidemic in
this country,
we had a polio outbreak,
right?
And our president was affected by it.
So what did we do?
We decided,
you know what?
No more polio.
Let's fix the problem.
I don't see why the government doesn't
say,
look,
we're losing a person every 19 minutes.
This is way more serious than polio.
Why are we not putting funding into
researching things like Kratom?
There's other things that are like
Kratom to why aren't we researching
these things?
There's another plant called Aka Uma and
other plant called soursop.
There's several plants that are,
that are like Kratom and do they do
similar things?
Why can't we study those to stop the
deaths,
to like slow it down,
you know,
to,
to make a dent and the deaths from opiod
addiction.
There's no reason why the government
can't fund that.
Now.
What are these other plants,
Aka Uma and what was the other one?
One's called Aka Uma and one's called
soursop.
And the reason why even know about those
is because what happens as soon as
something gets banned,
you look for the next thing,
right?
Oh Wow.
So you're a step ahead.
I don't even know what those things do,
but I know we like as soon as,
uh,
Kratom was band,
we were on the Internet looking for
like,
well,
what else is like it because I don't
want to have to deal without it.
Well,
I think it was you that tweeted
something and um,
I might retweet it or just read it,
but you tweeted something about someone
getting arrested,
like some big drug bust where they
busted him for Creighton,
which wasn't even illegal.
Yeah,
that's that,
that's a weird thing.
That was a guy I think,
um,
maybe because that,
that,
that guy's neighbor has had it out for
them,
they sorta like had it out for them and
they saw these big green bags of what
they thought was drugs at his house and
the cops went to write it and they're
like,
well,
we're not sure what this is,
so we're going to have to arrest you.
Oh God.
You know what I mean?
It took causes like a pretty,
pretty weird problem.
You know,
the thing was when they made it illegal,
I had two giant boxes of Kratom sitting
in my garage and all I could think about
was like,
okay,
the cops are going to come here and
they're going to bust me because they
know I'm doing a documentary about it.
I'm going to be,
you know,
the mark man.
But I decided that like no matter what
happened,
I was going to keep those boxes in my
garage and I wasn't gonna worry about it
because I figured like,
what are they going to come arrest me?
You know,
how stupid that would look because
that's all going into the documentary.
So I don't really have a fear that other
people have because I feel like I put
everything on camera and put everything
out there.
So I feel like.
But uh,
but other people,
it is serious,
like the um,
the vet I was talking about,
he can't live without Kratom.
What are we going to do?
Take it away from him.
What are we going to do in the meantime?
You know,
if we,
if we ban it,
what are we going to do?
What are we going to do with that guy?
Yeah.
Like where's she going to go back on
opiates to the VA hospital.
Like it's fuck what a weird situation.
So we really need you.
Chris Documentary is actually important.
Yeah,
it's very,
very important.
It's very important because it's not
just about Kratom is about how the Dea
and the FDA protect the interest of our
federal government and they keep the
money all in the pool to themselves and
they don't want anybody else in.
And I feel like it's just greed.
It's total greed.
It's not.
Has nothing to do with it being
dangerous.
Well,
we're definitely more aware of that kind
of and those kinds of compromises where
these companies compromise various
branches of the government for their own
personal interest.
And this Kratom is a perfect example of
that because so many people including me
know almost nothing about it.
This is a weird one.
You know,
this is one where they almost got in
like before people could understand
what,
what exactly it was,
which is rare in 2016.
There's something like that available.
They've never had anything like this.
The Dea has never seen a reply like
this.
There was 100,000 people that signed a
petition,
but one thing that I need to get out
there to everybody,
one,
the one way we can keep this legal and
keep other things legal as well is
everybody needs to go to a website that
the dea is set up.
It's called Kratom comments.org.
So just Kra tlm comments.org.
You can go there and you can leave,
you know,
up to 5,000 word message.
You know about Kratom and it doesn't
have to be from somebody who takes it.
Like you could just be like,
hey,
I think this should,
I watched it,
this podcast and I,
I really feel this needs to be
researched more and you know,
whatever,
whatever you feel needs to be said.
You can just say it here.
So you know,
like I went on and I left a comment
about why I use it and what I like about
it and I feel like everybody that does
needs to do that or they're not doing
their job.
And what does that put that back up
again?
Jamie,
please.
It says December 20,
first December,
first deadline.
Submit your comments now what is the
deadline?
Well,
that's why.
That's why I was a pain in the ass and
kept texting you because I was like,
dude,
can we get on before this deadline?
Well,
it's very important that people know
that there's a deadline for these
comments and it's in a couple days.
It's December first and if you make a
comment by December first,
the dea has to read it like they have to
look at it.
So even if you write a bunch of
Jibberish they have to read it,
which is kind of funny now.
But don't,
don't do that though folks.
They'll go,
he's on Kratom and Kenny can't spell.
No,
but I'm saying they have to.
They have to look at all of them.
So if we can get 10,000 comments,
I think there's maybe half that right
now.
And your show is so powerful.
If we can get 10,000 comments then this
is going to stay legal.
Wow.
So it was supposed to be scheduled one.
They had a plan to make a schedule one a
while ago.
Very interesting.
The dea only has one option.
The only.
The DEA has an emergency scheduling.
So there was a drug called [inaudible].
Have you ever heard of flocker?
No.
Jamie can you look up Flocka Fla kkr
because you have to see this.
Flocka was a drug in Florida where
everybody was going crazy.
They were like smashing shit and like
they were like smashing through their
car windows and jumping on cars and they
were like zombies and that got banned
like immediately and nobody.
There was no,
like there was nobody that stuck up know
produce killer drug.
Yeah.
Well that was something.
So you made him crazy.
Yeah.
Anyway.
Well you see like what some of these
people do like paypal,
God that goes on there on Flakka is that
real?
But see what happens is,
I don't know,
I don't know.
It's a synthetic drug,
so I think Kratom gets lumped in with
these synthetic drugs like spice and
Flocka that are like,
watch this guy jumps into the back of
the car.
Oh my God.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
See,
like what the fuck this is someone on
Flocka.
Holy Shit.
Can you imagine that's like that.
That's like that movie it goes flying
off the car back into the car.
It's amazing.
Whoa.
What the fuck?
Why am I not getting this guy smashing?
You know?
Oh my God,
that's like the most entertaining video
I've ever seen.
So even if it's not real,
I love it,
but I think it was a drug that they were
selling in head shops down in Florida
and it got banned within like,
I dunno,
a couple months of it being always
fucking Florida guys always handled
Florida.
The gateway to demonic possession.
I was saying that seems like that's like
I am legend.
Like they'll fucking crazy things from
the will smith movie monsters.
Yeah.
So this guy jumped on this guy's hood
and he's trying to shake them off.
Is that what happened?
What I'm saying is that when we sell
things,
you know,
things that they sell in,
in head shops like old spice members,
spice was a synthetic marijuana.
And the problem with it is that,
um,
a lot of times they're unregulated.
Like nobody know that spice just came on
the market.
There was no regulation.
They were selling in head shops.
They were getting away for like,
I think everybody puts this stuff on the
market to get away with it.
But when Kratom was put it on the
market,
it wasn't put on the market to get away
with it.
You know,
it,
it's been in like,
the problem is like there's a,
there's a law in America called the act.
Have you heard of that?
It's a to Shay is basically the dietary
supplement health something act,
right?
I forget.
But basically what it does is anything
that was on the market before 1994 gets
grandfathered in and is illegal
supplement.
So like even if they didn't do the
research on it or whatever before 1994.
And that's something that Orrin hatch
put in place to kind of keep the
supplement industry,
you know,
it helped to supplement companies.
It doesn't help us as a consumer because
we don't know what we're getting because
there's no regulation.
But um,
but I feel like that,
you know,
that the Shea Act says if there was a
supplement on the market before 1994,
um,
that it needs to stay legal and flow and
Kratom has been sold in Florida.
They've been selling it for 30 years.
You know,
they've been selling it before 1994.
So I'm actually just trying,
I'm,
I'm actually went to the freedom of
Information Act and summons the records
we saw in the records for importation of
Kratom.
Now if we can prove that Kratom's been
imported to the United States before
1994,
we have a pretty solid case to say,
you know,
look,
this gets grandfathered in just like
everything else.
Wow.
So we grandfathered in as a nutritional
supplement.
I don't know.
I mean it's,
I'm sure they're gonna make it harder
than that,
you know,
I'm sure like if we have the proof,
but I'm just going at at full blast,
you know,
I feel like if you go out something with
everything you got and he,
and you look down every avenue,
you're going to find something.
You know,
it's kind of like a,
I feel like a lawyer right now.
Wow.
What a strange predicament.
But it's very unusual that there's
something that's this well loved by the
people that are taking it.
But so little is known about it by most
people,
including me.
I have to say something that's very
important.
The people that are against Kratom are
just against the fact that they don't
know a lot about it there.
There's very few people that are like
really dead set against it.
There's a congresswoman down in Florida
who's dead set against it because they
want to boost their election.
They want,
they want people to vote for them,
so they say,
oh,
we took this off the street.
We saved your children,
and like she doesn't really know nothing
about Kratom like to make it illegal.
What has she said about it?
Does she?
She said,
she told me,
this is great.
You didn't interview her.
I interviewed her down in Florida and
she told me that,
you know,
look,
when you talk to a mother who,
whose baby was born addicted to Kratom,
she's like,
that's going to change you.
And I said,
can you get me that mother's name,
address and phone numbers so we can
contact her a?
Yeah,
yeah,
sure.
We'll get around to it.
They've never produced that.
We've asked them for aiming.
There really was a mother who was
addicted to them.
We've asked three or four times and we
haven't gotten it however,
however I did an interview,
a girl in Washington dc who said that
her baby was born,
she was born,
her baby was born addicted to opiates
and that was a terrible,
terrible thing that she had to go
through and um,
and now she takes Kratom and she's fine
and she's not going to relapse and
she'll be fine and her daughter ended up
being fine and stuff like that.
So what I'm saying is like these opiates
or what people will be born addicted to
Kratom,
you know,
they're looking down the wrong.
They're looking down the wrong rabbit
hole,
you know,
like,
you know.
So does Kratom have any potential
addictive side effects?
Is that we don't know.
It's hard to tell.
You know,
I,
I can give you.
How often do you take it?
I take it usually every day,
but I can give you some anecdotal
evidence that I went to Thailand for two
weeks a couple months ago and I had been
taking Kratom for four months straight.
Then I had a two week in Thailand.
We were actually shooting a kickboxer
movie and after,
uh,
after I got back from Thailand,
I wasn't,
I wasn't Jonesing for Kratom like I,
I didn't take it for two weeks because
it's illegal there.
So there was a reason it is illegal
there.
Yeah.
Like the last,
like I've never been to Thailand and
last thing I want to do is show up to
Thailand and end up in Thai prison.
Yeah.
That doesn't sound fun now.
It doesn't sound fun at all.
So I was like,
you know,
I was like maybe maybe they don't even
take this seriously there and maybe it's
bullshit,
but I'm not bringing it.
But it is illegal over there.
Uh,
yeah,
it's illegal in Thailand,
you know,
why it's illegal in Thailand.
This is like,
it's really interesting because we
looked at,
this is what they call it.
It's like a kind of a tie,
a tie name.
But the reason why it's illegal in
Thailand is because it was cutting into
the opium profits.
Oh Jesus.
So what happens is people probably
exactly the same pressure over here.
Exactly.
So hills just happened in the forties,
1942 or three.
They a ban Kratom and they wanted it.
They basically kept it illegal because
it was cutting into the money.
The people,
people were taking it instead of opium
instead of heroin.
Wow.
And that's the same thing that's gonna
happen in this country,
but it's going to be different in this
country.
It's going to solve a problem.
You know,
is,
is opium legal and Thailand,
I don't think it's illegal,
but like I think even,
you know,
it's like they just try to get it gay
Kratom Kratom out so that nobody was
taking it.
Oh,
I understand.
So the people that were profiting off of
freedoms more illegal than opium,
if that makes sense.
That's hilarious.
Wow.
What a weird rabbit hole this is.
Yeah.
The whole,
you know,
to me the whole thing is interesting
because I completely get the other side.
I don't want anybody taking something
that's unsafe.
I don't want to market something that's
unsafe,
but I don't make a dime from selling
Kratom.
Like,
that's not right.
You're not selling it.
That's not where my income comes from.
And I'm not going to sell it,
so it's like,
it's not something where I'm like,
hey man,
I can make billions of dollars off this.
Let me just go.
Not only that,
if anybody would have a an interest in
not promoting something that's
addictive,
it would be a guy like you as an
intimate knowledge of what it's like to
be addictive and under the spell.
Sure.
I think addiction needs to be looked at
in a certain way though,
where you look at addiction and you go
like,
okay,
I'm addicted to coffee.
It's no big deal.
You know,
like what is that going to?
What is,
what's the problem?
What's the problem being like people are
addicted to coffee.
What's right.
There really is no problem.
Addicted to coffee,
addicted to sugar will lead to problems
down the road.
But not a problem today.
Addicted to cigarettes,
lead to problems down the road,
but not a problem today.
You know?
So we don't really know.
There's not any long term studies to
show that Kratom is good in the long
term.
There's not any interest studies,
but we can go by the evidence that we do
have,
you know,
and they've done a lot of studies in
mice and all the studies and in mice,
like none of the mice die,
you know,
they're not the.
And,
and the number one opiate addiction
study they did was at a university of
all,
it's all miss whatever that Mississippi.
So Ole Miss,
um,
Christopher mccurdy,
he's a guy that are doing the research
and he really feels that this could be
the savior for the opiod epidemic.
He feels that they need to make it
stronger.
He feels they need to extract it,
make it stronger and that would be used
for the opiate epidemic.
So that's why I said I think there is
potential for it to be studied as both a
dietary supplement and as a drug,
because if you can,
if you can make something out of Kratom
that's gonna help a lot of people,
you know,
it's like,
what's the big.
I don't really see it as a big problem
if,
if it could be both.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Like let them make their money and
whatever,
but keep it legal for us.
So in doing your documentary,
what have you,
what have you learned about the push to
try to make it illegal?
And when,
when did it all start?
It all started I think,
um,
shoot.
When did it start?
Started?
Like over the summer.
I actually started doing the documentary
a little bit before it.
I was like,
well maybe if people she should know
about this,
maybe this is something.
So you were doing it just to let people
know about it.
And then along the way it started to be
threatened.
He was weird.
It was like I started doing it going
like,
is this going to be a movie or is this
more like an infomercial?
Like what is,
what is this going to be,
you know,
like I don't,
I don't want it to be like an
infomercial because I'm not selling it
and making money off of it.
I want it to be something that's very
honest about what product does.
And so to me,
the ban and the controversy is the best
thing that could ever happen because now
people know about it and they're aware
as long as it doesn't get banned,
we're okay.
You have a knack for that.
You know,
we think about it like in prescription
thugs,
you're making this documentary on pill
addiction and then you get hurt during
the middle of it,
started taking pills and become addicted
to pills during the middle of a
documentary on pill addiction.
How many there are blessed or cursed?
I don't know.
I don't know what that is.
You know,
you.
You might fucking manifested or
something,
man.
I hope not because actually the next
documentary is about cancer.
Oh,
well the reason I'm doing that,
the reason I do all my documentaries is
because,
like I said,
we have the power to change the way
people think and we have the power to
open up people's minds about things that
they might not know about well and also
explore things.
You're very good at exploring things in
a very objective way,
in a very honest way.
And I think that that's so important in
today's day and age because it's so hard
to know where,
why a person's promoting something in
one way or not promoting something in
another way.
It's like,
what is the interest behind it?
What's the motivation behind it?
Sure.
So to know that there's a guy like you
who's doing this stuff,
just completely honest and open and raw
like that.
It's very,
very important.
Well thank you.
I really appreciate it.
Like number one,
be being respected by somebody like you.
I just means so much to me because,
you know,
all my life I'll ever wanted to do is
like,
I always wanted to prove myself.
I always thought I had to prove myself
as a kid.
Like Oh,
I did this or that,
but I feel like these movies just kind
of automatically do that for me.
I think you've been like automatically
validating like everything I've tried to
do my whole life,
you know,
I wanted to be a big feature film maker
and make Arnold Schwarzenegger movies
and that couldn't be the.
That's the furthest thing from my mind
right now is to make movies that are big
action movies that are mindless.
I want to make big,
you know,
big documentaries that are smart.
Well,
it's interesting as life goes on and you
know,
you change and evolve and you know,
your motivations changed.
But I,
I recommend your movies still.
A lot of people,
man,
particularly the prescription thugs
because of this.
So many issues that have come up over
the last,
you know,
it seems like the last couple of decades
in this country are just unprecedented
numbers of people that are addicted to
pills.
It's crazy.
There's a couple of million people
walking around completely checked out
and I feel like,
uh,
it,
it definitely needs to be.
I,
I still,
I can't wrap my mind around why the
government hasn't stepped in and said we
have to fight this opioid epidemic.
I think they're getting paid off.
Why isn't the government putting,
making the companies that make
oxycontin?
Like for example,
purdue Pharma,
purdue,
Pharma admitted like we got all these
people addicted.
We lied to doctors,
they admitted it and they got fined.
But the fine was only like a little tiny
percent of what they made you get fined
200 million,
or even if you get fined a billion
dollars,
he made $8,000,000,000.
Who Cares?
You don't even feel it because you're
going to make another billion next year.
And after that actually call it the
price of doing business.
They build into those fines into,
you know,
into the product.
So they know,
hey,
we're probably going to get fined on
this for 400 million.
Let's just build it into the cost of the
drug.
I mean,
it's,
it's an insane system that we have here
for products that are supposed to help
people.
Well,
it's also this disingenuous thing that
politicians do with it.
Pretend they're looking out for the
people,
but yet,
how are you,
how come you haven't heard a single
politician in decades?
Say a word about cigarettes?
Obama got into office,
he was smoking cigarettes,
got in,
which is just,
that's half a million people just in
this country die prematurely every year
because of that.
And I think,
uh,
you know,
if we look at tobacco and we look at the
problems with tobacco,
what's the big problems with it?
They put all these chemicals in the
tobacco and if they could just pan that.
Let me,
I don't think actual natural tobacco is
that bad for you?
Well,
how many people are dying from cigars?
Not a lot.
Not,
not that I know.
I mean maybe it's abuse.
Maybe if you get crazy with it,
but that's kinda like wine and the wine
is great.
But if you drink wine like four or five
bottles a day,
you're going to kill your liver.
Yeah.
It's just like so many things like
things like that,
like wine and wine feels like kind of
like Kratom has this sort of self
limiting thing.
Like wine.
You could drink too much of it,
but if it feels so shitty and it's like
Kratom is kind of the same way.
Like as you take too much of it,
you'll just feel so crappy that year.
You're going to know never to do that
again.
Where does it do?
How does it make you feel?
Crappy,
because you said yes too much,
just stomach aches,
nausea,
um,
you know,
and when I say so I guess I should,
I should mentioned that.
What I actually took,
I don't even know if it was Kratom when
I took was a product and I'll never do
this again.
It was,
it was like some extract as somebody
gave me and I tried it and that's what
made me sick.
So it could have been way stronger than
regular Kratom.
There could have been something else in
it,
but that's sort of,
that was my first like,
okay,
be smart about this.
Look at the,
look at the packaging and a lot,
a lot.
A big problem with Kratom is most of the
cranium that's on the market.
This is the only company in the entire
country or world that packages credit.
I'm like a dietary supplement.
Every other supplement,
if you look on the back,
it'll say right here,
not for human consumption.
That's problem.
Can they.
Can people buy this right now?
Yeah.
They could buy it.
Yeah,
for now.
Sure.
Yeah.
In this company is from Vegas so that
they do a lot of business in Vegas to
actually in health food stores in Vegas.
Explain it to people so they could get
an.
Obviously you nor I have any stake in
this at all.
This is called urban ice urban ice
organics.
They have a website.
Yeah.
They have a website,
I believe it's urban ice organics.com or
urbanites.com.
I'm not even sure if they tell you the
truth,
but um,
any,
any like head shop should have Kratom
um,
they saw a lot of this in Vegas.
So in Vegas it's all over.
Um,
but you know what the other thing we
talked about,
it's like why are they making illegal?
The Guy who owns this company made a lot
of money off of it and I'm sure you
know,
millions and millions of dollars.
So like when you make millions and
millions of dollars,
people want to know like,
hey dude,
you didn't go through the process.
And I think we are.
Kelly and I were just talking like what
the process to make something a,
you know,
dietary supplement is a long arduous
process and I feel like Kratom may need
to go through that process because like
we don't have enough information on it
and it hadn't been studied.
It's sort of something that slipped
through the cracks.
Like nobody really knew about it.
It wasn't that popular and it's been
around for 2000 years and no one ever
decided to say,
hey,
this is a dietary supplement.
Wow.
Now these other ones that you were
talking about,
the other ones when you were saying if
this gets illegal,
there's,
there's similar name those again,
what does it against?
Our esop I think is one of them and Aka
Yuma,
which is like,
I don't think it's Japanese or
something,
but Aka Uma and soursop.
I've never tried them.
I don't know.
I've just read about them,
but they have a similar effect.
Allegedly.
That's what it says.
Yeah.
That's what they say.
But there haven't been as popular so
maybe,
you know,
like,
I feel like they're not as popular
because it probably not as good or
strong,
but I don't know man.
So what do we have isolated?
Like what is the pressure to try to get
it illegal?
Yeah,
we,
we've kept trying to isolate,
you know,
and we've talked to the people that are
against it and their congress people
that are against it are grieving parents
that are against it.
Um,
we,
you know,
like nobody in big Pharma is going to
come out and say,
hey,
we're going to make this a drug and
screw all you.
Like,
they're not going to really say that.
So it's really when you get into
Washington,
like we were just in Washington for a
week and everything so shady and
underhanded in my mind,
like all these people are,
are working together.
They're all in cahoots,
you know,
like everything's in everything seemed
to be like,
I don't know,
just the,
the congressman that I talked to mark
Pocan from Wisconsin,
a marijuana and create them or both
illegal there and he's kind of fighting
for it to be legal.
And like I said,
he's one of the only congress people I
met that was willing to go to bat for
these kinds of things.
And I think we need more congress people
like that,
that are looking out for the citizens.
So there are state laws against it.
Uh,
there's six states,
I believe that I've Ban Kratom.
I think they're Wisconsin's one of them.
Uh,
Tennessee,
Alabama,
and I'll remember the rest of them,
but there's a couple of states where
it's band.
And what do they cite when they say
that?
It's deaths,
deaths and danger and kids taking it,
you know,
everything's about protecting the
children and saving the children.
But you know,
none of the people in the Kratom
Industry,
I've never said like,
hey,
let's age restrict this,
let's make it,
you know,
21 and over 18 and over are 25 and
older.
It doesn't,
you know,
whatever,
whatever they want to do.
Like no one's even the FDA has never
even come and taught like it's
impossible and this is the big problem.
It's impossible to talk to the FDA or
dea.
I just spoke to the,
the spokesman for the dea last week,
Melvin Patterson and I said,
hey Mr Patterson,
I would really like to come down and do
an interview with you.
He's like,
Oh yeah,
sorry we don't do that and I want to say
about you work for me.
Like you know,
we pay,
we pay their salaries.
I know people here that will done.
But like I think there just needs to be
more transparency 100 percent in the dea
and the FDA.
You can't find out the FDA's like
scientology.
Like you can't find out anything about
it.
Like when you try to do research on and
try to find out,
you know,
who's doing what or whatever,
there's not a whole lot of transparency
and that's why documentary film makers
like me have to use like the freedom of
freedom of Information Act where if we
request something from the government,
you know,
they have to give it to us and that's
something that really helps us.
So this is a,
we were talking about what a rabbit hole
this is,
but this is a weird rabbit hole for you
to have started this out as something
like,
you're,
you're finding this plant to be
beneficial.
You see all these people that are
benefiting from it and you're like,
hey,
this is a great subject.
I want to let the world know about it.
And then as you're doing it,
it's theirs.
You start feeling this dark push for it
to be scheduled one and,
and just start making illegal.
What's that journey been like?
I'm weird.
You know,
I think I'm scary a little bit because
uh,
he started this thing and I thought it
was just going to go down to two.
I mean,
I thought they were going to maybe make
it illegal and then you know,
maybe we have nothing.
You know what,
once you make something a schedule one
drug,
it's impossible.
Ask The people matter.
The marijuana people,
it's impossible to take it off the
schedule one,
it's,
it can happen but it's really hard.
So I think that the idea is not to get
it there in the first place,
whether it was talking about the dea
removing marijuana from schedule one
this summer and they backed out of it.
They were just.
I just read some more about that today.
That's still kind of up in the air,
Huh?
Well they got close to it and they said
they were going to reconsider it and
apparently a lot of people were very
helpful.
They thought this is gonna be at
scheduled ones.
Ridiculous.
No medicinal value.
I mean they've shown marijuana to cure
some forms of cancer to say there's no
medicinal value for it is completely
ridiculous.
We need to start dumping our money into
researching these plants because like
how like look,
you have these Pharma companies and I
don't know if you've seen this shell on
discovery where they show you how they
come up with new drugs.
They basically take like there's a
machine and it's like this fucking robot
and it takes like every fucking
substance in the world and combines it
until like it makes millions and
millions of different,
different kinds of fucking like things,
you know,
different kinds of drugs and then they
start testing it on like every different
disease to see if it works.
So it's like it's like shooting in the
dark.
It's like they have no,
like they're like there's a machine that
will just make a drug and then they
figure out if it works on something
rather than like we already know that
Kratom works for this,
this and this and we already know that
marijuana works for this,
this and this.
Why not put the money into studying that
rather than the shooting in the dark,
making some weird combination.
Have you seen that?
That.
No,
I haven't seen it at all.
I have to find that sounds almost like
that.
That sounds like a.
they're like,
you know,
the like they use those algorithms to
try to work the stock market.
That's something similar.
It just throwing numbers up.
Yeah.
Well there's a lot of them to come out
real bad.
I mean,
I know a dude who had a stroke,
a young guy from Vioxx.
That stuff.
Yeah.
You probably know about that.
Arthritis,
arthritis medication.
Yeah.
I know the guy in his thirties.
Who the Fuck Australian.
That stuff.
Yeah.
See,
that's this.
They pulled it off the market.
Yeah.
They pulled that off the market.
I think there was 55,000 deaths from
Vioxx and Kratom zero.
Oh,
weird marijuana.
How many strange.
Yeah,
man.
That's A.
There's a business in selling people
pills.
You know,
living in a twisted world we live in.
People are going to keep that from
somebody who's in pain is ridiculous.
Well,
I'm hoping that as time goes on,
we're slowly starting to understand that
it is impossible for your doctor to know
all the ramifications and repercussions.
Sure.
Involved in any.
Any drug.
Yup.
And there's just no way.
I was just on the show,
the doctors with a doctor whose son was
taking Kratom,
he found his son was a drug addict and
he kind of found out about it.
And then his son said,
dad,
I'm going to get off all the heroin.
I'm going to start taking Kratom.
And he said his son has been on Kratom
now for,
I don't know,
like six months.
He's been sober.
He had been happier than he's ever been
and this doctor is 100 percent down with
it.
And he was on the show,
the doctors with me and he was arguing
with,
you know,
there's a guy from a.
what's that show intervention.
One of the dudes from intervention was
on the doctors with us arguing like,
yeah,
people get addicted to Kratom all the
time.
It's like,
dude,
you're a marketing guy.
Like these people in Rehab,
like you gotta understand.
The reason why if you Google Kratom
rehabs come up is because rehabs have
marketing teams,
they're trying to get as many people
into the doors as they can.
So they tell you Kratom's bad and they
put it on their website.
Narcan on is a big a rehab center.
They're owned by scientologists and
they're all over the Kratom thing saying
like,
Hey,
are you addicted to Kratom?
Call us,
you know,
and it's just like,
I feel like the people that get addicted
to it,
like I,
I went to Rehab,
I've been in rehab that with people that
were there for marijuana and you want to
just be like,
dude,
what the fuck are you doing here?
Like number celebrity rehab.
Yeah.
But,
but people do have a problem with it,
so it's okay.
Like you can go to rehab for anything.
So going for Kratom is no different than
going for like depression or some
gambling.
You have to go to rehab for gamble.
So I don't,
I don't know why they're marketing it to
people.
I think it's kind of sadistic in a way.
Like they're looking for people that are
on Kratom,
you know that to,
you know,
if.
I Dunno,
I mean I don't know why they.
Well they don't have any personal
experience with it.
Maybe they're not as nefarious as we
think it is.
Maybe they just ignorant.
Sure.
And the and the good rehabs aren't doing
that.
I should say,
like when I went cliffside Malibu,
they don't have a Kratom thing on their
website because there are legitimate
rehab center.
I was talking about celebrity rehab.
I remember when Eric Roberts was on.
It was hilarious.
Everybody else has shaken throwing up
and sweating.
Eric Roberts sitting there with a
newspaper or a cup of Costco,
get slippers on.
He was just in there for pot.
Yeah.
Like there's no,
there was no withdrawal.
There was nothing happened.
You know,
they go with what does it feel like?
He's like,
I feel fine.
I just,
I just don't have weed.
Well the problem with when you tell
somebody that they have a problem,
they start thinking,
fuck,
I have a problem.
If you ever had a cop behind you and you
never did anything.
No.
But you're like looking at both hands on
the wheel and yeah.
You feel like it has my license.
My license is good.
I pay my insurance,
I have a gun.
There's a gun in his.
Why am I afraid of
fucking freaking out?
Am I speeding?
Not going the speed limit,
but meanwhile there's something.
If someone tells you,
Hey,
you've got a problem,
you might not think you have a problem,
but you got a problem.
Like fucking got a problem.
What's my problem?
Your problem is Kratom,
or your problem is sex,
or your problem is whatever the fuck it
is.
Exercise.
You're addicted to exercise.
If someone could tell you have a
problem,
and then most of us are at least a
little insecure,
almost everybody I know is at least a
little insecure and as soon as someone
accuses you of something,
you all,
you start considering the possibility
there,
right?
Yeah.
And then sometimes you try to hide it
more.
Yes.
That's,
that's my,
my,
you know,
as an addict,
I was like,
okay,
well,
not now they're onto me.
I better really,
really hide this.
I had a conversation one day with my
dad.
I'll never forget it.
My Dad is like the nicest person in the
world.
You've seen him in the movies and one
day,
um,
I was out of money.
I'm in my forties and I'm out of money.
That's ridiculous.
That's stupid.
You know what I mean?
Because I was.
But I was a drug addict so my dad said
to me,
I don't know what's wrong with you,
but I think you're a drug addict or an
alcoholic or something,
but there's no reason why a guy in there
40 years old,
she'd be out of money.
And I'm like,
you know what man,
he's right.
And that was that conversation that it
was about three months before I went to
Rehab.
But like that was the conversation.
It was that conference.
It was,
it was my dad being disappointed in me.
It was like that conversation that
really sort of shook me to the ground.
Like somebody telling me I had a
problem.
It kind of shook me to the core because
he yelled at me when he said it.
He never yelled at me.
Wow.
Well sometimes that's all you need is
one person's opinion.
Who you really love.
Yeah.
Boot and the asked from dad.
And you go shit.
And my dad's been through everything.
You know,
he's had cancer.
He's add his half of the intestine
pulled out,
he's had all these issues and they're
not due to drugs or alcohol.
So it makes me feel even more guilty
because like my issues are just due to
something I'm doing.
Right,
right.
Well,
except arthritis.
Yeah.
But I'm feeling it now.
I don't know what it's doing,
but something's going on.
Got a boner now.
Does that happen?
Probably warning.
No shit man.
I wish.
Um,
no.
Just uh,
I feel good.
Um,
it doesn't,
it's not.
I'm not negatively affected me in any
way.
I don't feel slow or anything like that.
That's what I was assuming it was.
I mean,
literally today,
one of the things that I wanted to do
before I'm talking to you about this,
I wanted to do no research because I
literally wanted to just go in with my
ignorance so that I can question you
from ignorance.
And interestingly enough,
if you try to do research,
it's kind of a,
it's kind of biased right off the bat
from Google.
Like when you,
like I said,
when you search Kratom,
a lot of times what comes up are the
rehab centers that are paying to be
or let's try it right now.
And then if you type in Kratom band,
you'll get more of a across the board,
up and down,
you know,
I'm going to try it with being because
I've been using windows so let's see if
they have the same thing
mark and I don't know.
Big is not bad man.
I don't,
I don't have any problems with bang.
Okay.
Kratom read on Amazon Dot Com.
See they try to sell you it.
Oh,
trying to sell it.
Yeah.
Kratom red.
Okay.
Drug Abuse.
Kratom affects.
Okay.
Narcan,
not,
I did not know narcan on is owned by
scientology,
but I have a,
my buddy Anthony Roberts,
he was like,
uh,
when I was doing bigger,
stronger,
faster,
it was like this dude that would always
hit me up online about stuff.
And he kind of knew everything.
So I hired him to work on this movie as
a,
as a researcher and a writer and he's
been.
He's been teaching me a lot about how to
find stuff,
you know,
let's,
let's see what the Narcan on people have
to say about it.
Effects of drugs.
So it's [inaudible] dot org.
The effects of drug abuse.
It says Kratom is a relatively new drug
to the US and Europe and has been used
for many years in Southeast Asia as an
anti dye or real medicine.
Hey,
doesn't really,
you know,
I've heard that.
Yeah.
A lot of people.
So you get diarrhea,
you take Kratom a painkiller and a
recreational drug.
Kratom is the popular name for a tree
and the drug comes from its leaves.
The drug may be bought in leaf form,
but in this country is more likely pur
purchased as a capsule with a powdered
leaf material or chopped up in the form
of a leaf that can be used for a tea
over smoking.
Yeah.
This says t on it that people make
actual 10 make tea out of it.
Tastes like shit.
I think it tastes terrible.
It's pretty,
um,
pretty bitter.
You know,
it says the effects of Kratom come on
rather quickly and last between five and
seven hours,
although high doses can last longer.
It's heavily promoted as illegal,
undetectable safe drug that can be used
to come off stronger drugs.
It is not illegal the United States,
but the breakdown products of Kratom can
be detected in some drug tests.
Is that true?
Like for people that work at ups or
something?
I haven't seen that happen now.
I don't.
I don't think that's true.
They might be scaring you.
Yeah,
probably trying to get you to join.
I don't think it will show up on a drug
test.
It's not an opiate.
It's not the same,
you know,
same ingredients.
It says the breakdown products of Kratom
can be detected with some drug dose.
Hmm.
Maybe,
maybe some drug tests that are looking
at.
Well,
there,
there is a specific drug test that looks
for it,
you know,
that goes,
that will go in and look,
you know,
look forward just Kratom and that's what
they,
that's what they use when somebody
commits suicide or whatever it makes
like,
oh,
is there,
is there Kratom in their,
in their system or whatever,
you know,
and there's 15 deaths from Kratom at 14
to 15 deaths are all polypharmacy,
which means we've taken several
different things,
but most of the time it's like
polypharmacy.
It's like,
oh,
they were taking Xanax,
Vicodin and Kratom and you're like,
why would you blame it on the Kratom it
seems like the least,
the,
uh,
you know,
agregious of all of them,
if it's only in combination with other
pharmaceuticals,
that sounds crazy.
I mean,
that's like marijuana,
like,
you know,
it's like,
who knows,
who knows how many people have died on
marijuana and other drugs.
It's funny that you bring up Thailand
because they're using Thailand as an
example here.
More than 13,000 people were arrested
for Kratom related crimes in Thailand.
That's just because it's illegal in
Thailand.
The leader of the opiod industry,
they conveniently ignore that,
so the drug is abused for it's abused
for its sedative or stimulating effects,
not used.
It says abused.
Will say.
The thing is I.
I don't think that like taking a normal,
you know,
I think if I took,
50 pills a day,
that'll be abusing it.
I maybe take six pills a day,
maybe at the most 10.
Then you're even the term pill is a
weird word because what you did
basically taking this powder plants.
Yeah.
Well the,
the term drug is a weird word.
If you went back and read that statement
that you just read and substituted the
word plant,
it wouldn't sound bad at all.
The plant comes as a powder.
The plant is this,
the plant does that.
It wouldn't sound bad,
but when you use the word drug of course
sit in a corner.
Well,
drugs such a weird word because it
covers too many different effects.
You know,
covers stimulants,
depressants.
So here's what it says,
a person using this drug may expect or
may not expect or want the following
undesirable effects of Kratom edginess,
nervousness,
vomiting can be severe,
prolonged nausea,
it can be severe,
prolonged sweating,
itching,
constipation,
delusions,
lithology,
respiratory depression,
tremors,
aggressive or combative behavior,
psychotic episodes,
hallucinations and paranoia.
There's a big thing you just mentioned
that respiratory depression and has not
been shown with Kratom.
And that's,
and that's what kills people with oxy.
What about hallucinations to people who
say on them?
I've never met one psychotic episodes,
never met one aggressive or combative
behavior.
Um,
Nah,
never,
never really experienced that.
The only thing I can say that I have
experienced are like people that feel
better and are in better moods.
Here's an interesting one.
Addiction affects me include number one,
loss of sexual desire.
People like,
fuck this drug last actually prolong you
during sex.
Oh Shit.
Prolong you.
So like make it harder to finish
basically darkening of the skin or face.
What do you want to be black.
That's why that's an effect.
That's negative effect.
Well,
you know,
you know where that comes from.
Darkening of the face and the skin comes
from.
I'm in Thailand.
When they did the study in 1975,
they were researching a migrant like the
workers,
the workers out in the fields.
So the research these workers out in the
fields that were,
that were true in the Kratom leaves St.
Oh,
they're turning brown because they're
out in the fear on the fucking Sun.
So like these people are turning brown.
Oh my God,
that's so stupid.
And that's listed as a side effect.
Melanin.
Well,
and then you'll,
then you'll have people like
congresspeople and,
and other people that are fighting
against this.
Try to use that as a fact.
Here's where it gets really weird.
Withdrawal effects of them are very
similar to those of opiate,
like heroin or prescription painkillers.
Let's hear those.
Here's the withdrawal effects.
Diarrhea.
I thought it was anti-diarrhea.
Make up your fucking mind.
Um,
muscle pain.
I thought it's good for pain.
Yeah,
that's great.
Right?
Okay.
Muscle tremors or,
or jerking.
You were saying the,
the,
uh,
vet
all his muscle jerking and twitching
goes away.
They're seeing that.
That's a side effect.
Riff,
restlessness and sleeplessness.
Does it help you?
Uh,
you know,
I haven't,
no,
I haven't like really stayed up all
night on it,
but,
you know,
I let you know,
there's adverse effects to everything
that we could possibly ingest.
So it's more like let's take a big group
of these adverse effects and see which
ones occur more often,
you know,
when people.
And it really,
it really hasn't been shown across the
board to do all these things to
everybody,
you know.
So like there was one guy that was on
Kratom for three years and they said
he's got to be addicted to Kratom.
We're going to study him and we're going
to see what happens when we take them
off credit,
you know,
when he gets off Kratom.
So he gets off Kratom and you know,
what happened to him,
what he had a runny nose.
Whoa.
Asked Gary.
That was the only.
The only,
the only thing that he complained about
was like a runny nose here in large font
it says narcan can help the person who
is addicted to Kratom in large words and
then it goes back.
Why have you drunk has different
effects?
Oh Man.
The route back to sobriety is much the
same from person to person.
Recovery.
Recovery must include release relief
from incessant cravings and you're the
beginnings of Rehab.
You know,
you know what we said about,
we were talking actually heard your
podcast and you brought me up on a,
on another,
you know,
on another one of your podcasts and we
were talking about time.
The amount of time it takes to get sober
and I still,
I still believe that,
right?
I still believe like it takes time and I
still be short,
but the thing that we have to talk about
is like,
you don't just take this and get off of
opiates,
you take this and you go to Aa meetings
and you go to,
you know,
whatever,
whatever works,
counseling,
go to counseling.
You go to a therapist and go talk to
them.
You talk to them about why you couldn't
get off the drugs and you tell them
you've taken us and you say,
Hey,
let's see if we can.
If we can solve this problem,
you know,
but it's,
let's not be stupid about it.
Like I went to the doctor and I got one
when I,
when I was addicted to opiates and I
was,
I would drive around my car crying.
I'd be crying saying,
I just want help,
you know,
my brother was dying from this.
I knew he was going to die from it.
I knew it.
So I was driving around.
I would cry and be like,
I need,
I need rehab.
I need help.
I don't know what to do.
Every Rehab I called was like $4,000,
$6,000,
and I didn't have the money.
At the time I was a drug addict,
you know,
I was broke.
If I,
if I had known about something like this
back then,
it would have completely changed the
person I am now.
I would have,
I wouldn't have lost five or six years,
you know?
Wow.
That's fucking crazy.
It's just crazy.
It's so.
It's so weird when you're a grown adult
and all of a sudden you find out about
something that's been around for
thousands of years.
It's been helping people,
you know,
like I,
I try to pay attention to how the fuck
did this one for me being like the guy
who did bigger,
stronger,
faster,
always talking about supplements,
everything.
I missed it too.
Wow.
You know,
I know.
I know about every supplement on the
market.
I know everything
on it makes every supplement that's out
there.
I look at them,
I want to see what they do,
you know,
and um,
I missed it.
It's the,
that is really fascinating.
It's just really,
really fascinating.
So now we're in this state where the dea
held off it scheduled one distinction
right there.
We're going to designate it as a
schedule one and the dea isn't,
I think this big monster and everybody
thinks everybody's like,
oh,
the dea and the dea.
I believe from what I've gathered from
this whole situation is a data.
They're not happy about what happened.
They,
they,
they didn't know.
They weren't aware that this many people
use Kratom and are happy about it.
I think that they really didn't know.
I don't think it's like,
I don't think it's as dvs as people
think like,
I don't think it was a big,
you know,
and,
and now it definitely could be something
that is pushed by big Pharma,
but I feel like the way that the dea has
reacted so far has been,
you know,
pretty normal.
Pretty reasonable.
Yeah.
Reasonable.
Like,
it's been like,
like,
Hey,
okay,
I'm sorry,
let's open up a website and take some
comments.
Well,
I really hope people listen to this.
Get to it,
give it to give the address that one
more time.
It's credit kratom comments.org Kratom
Comments Dot Org,
k r a t o m comments.org.
And so December first,
once December first rolls around,
which is right around the corner,
what happens if they get a bunch of
notes and I mean they have to get
10,000,
is that what it.
Don't have to get any certain number,
but I think if they get $10,000,
like that's the number we were at.
Everybody.
That's where you were aiming for,
was aiming for,
you know,
like,
what's great is um,
I've actually become friends,
a lot of people in this Kratom community
and it's not the kind of people that you
would think like,
you know,
I feel like,
um,
when I went to the march in Washington
DC,
I didn't know what kind of people I was
going to meet,
you know,
but I bet you know,
mothers and grandmothers and you know,
like all these people that were like,
they were like my mom,
you know,
and I wasn't expecting that.
I was expecting to meet a bunch of
people.
Like what's up dude?
And that Kinda that Kinda saying like,
yeah man,
the government sucks.
Let's keep this legal tower seven bro.
Look into it.
It was,
it was vets,
you know,
veterans that fought overseas for us and
have risked a lot for us.
It was a mothers and grandmothers and
people like that more than it was of
these,
a devious characters that they think are
using Kratom wow.
So this is,
this is a really important issue.
And when,
when is your documentary going to come
out?
We're hoping to documentary will come
out early next year.
So just a matter of how fast we can get
it together.
So we're almost done shooting.
Okay.
So now it's just the editing process.
And then also are you going to wait
around to see what happens after
December first?
Yeah.
We'll,
we'll wait around.
We're going to start editing.
We're starting editing right now.
So basically,
you know,
if things happen,
for example,
Bernie Sanders is one of the guys who
signed the Kratom letter.
I want to talk to him,
I'd love to.
He.
He's kind of an amazing guy to me.
I would love to pick his brain about
this and see what he thinks.
So it's impossible now these people
down,
but you never know when you might get
five minutes with Bernie at a rally
somewhere,
you know.
So we're going to continue to try to get
those,
those bigger names that we wanted to
get.
I think they're important.
Orrin Hatch's involved in this.
Orrin Hatch is a senator from Utah
that's been very involved in the dietary
supplements for a long,
long time.
So,
uh,
we,
we'd like to get his opinion on it and
you know,
but like,
it's kind of crazy.
I would hope that the dea and the FDA
would listen to this interview and like
sit with us and do an interview.
I got one.
Yeah.
I would love to like,
just let them speak their mind.
I don't do interviews where I go in,
in an ambush.
People,
I let them speak their mind.
No,
you don't at all.
Um,
I,
I think I took it probably an hour ago,
right?
How long?
I take it 15 minutes into the show.
It's A.
Yeah,
I mean,
I guess I'd have like a mild,
very mild stimulant sort of effect that
I feel.
But uh,
it's,
it's nothing,
nothing to be concerned with.
You're not dying know it doesn't me.
You know what I mean?
It doesn't really like I've taken some
stuff before I,
I was in Colorado this weekend and I
took a lot of edibles.
Whoa.
Who?
Those fucking people aren't screwing
around,
man.
They're going deep in Colorado.
Man.
I heard you are a special.
Talking about edibles.
That was amazing.
So was pretty sensitive to them too,
right?
I guess.
I Dunno man.
I'm more sensitive than Joey Diaz.
Joey Diaz that like,
I'm on that level.
Like 300 milligrams.
Yeah.
That's cool.
That's what you take.
Oh,
I,
I don't even do it because they just
have.
I'd have to take too much of it.
Well,
one time I did a podcast with Sam Harris
recently and I have this spray that is a
thousand milligrams,
like I guess it's a thousand milligrams
and the whole bottle,
but it's like,
I don't know.
I don't know exactly how to spray.
This is the more mild version.
This one's 175 milligrams,
which think it's like 20 milligrams of
pump or 10 milligram between 10 and 20
milligrams of pumped depending on how
strong the stuff that makes sense.
This is jumbo.
Jumbo makes a bunch of great stuff.
All organic.
They used to get data dispensary.
I'll hook you up.
But the uh,
hey you want me to do is take this one
the spray.
Enjoy.
Don't get crazy.
You know what's weird?
I don't know,
I don't like to smoke pot.
I like,
I like this stuff better because I'm
just so used to taking things like that.
So.
And I also feel like I don't want to get
back into the hole.
My girlfriend would flip out if I
started smoking pot,
but to use some like edible stuff and
play around with this and see if it
works for pain and stuff like that to me
is something that's very,
very viable.
Yeah.
Isn't that funny?
Where people worry about like smoking is
like,
oh,
he's smoking drugs,
but if you're spraying breath spray
under your tongue,
it's like,
Eh,
he's just relieving pain,
you know,
I just think we need to open our minds
to a lot of these substances that are
out there that can help us,
you know,
it's great to say don't take anything
that's not the world that we live in
now.
Right?
Well CBDS,
CBDS are great because they're not
psychoactive at all.
And uh,
I.
Shannon Briggs was just in earlier so
that it's helped him tremendously.
CBD.
That's pot that'll know that fucked up,
so you carry care,
but you know,
the,
the difference being the editable
version of marijuana has a very
different psychoactive effect too.
That's why a lot of people think they're
getting spiked.
Like they'll eat a pot cookie and
they'll think,
oh my god,
somebody put an acid in this because
it's really psychedelic and the way it's
processed by the body,
your liver produces this metabolite
called 11 hydroxy metabolite and it's
just way more powerful than thc.
You the only comedian that I've seen
bring science into that fall into that
pit.
That was amazing.
You know,
just to kiss your ass a little bit.
That entire special is at the top of the
game.
Oh,
thanks bill.
Thanks.
I'm hustling.
That's great.
So,
uh,
I wanted to get you.
I don't have a whole lot of time,
so I wanted to get you in here today and
get it done.
But um,
what else?
Um,
can you tell people about this and what
else can be done?
I think that people need to go to Kratom
comments that org leave a comment,
uh,
people can,
you know,
they can call the dea,
they can ask for Melvin Patterson,
he's the spokesman.
They can leave a message with him.
I think this Kratom comments.org though
is going to be the most effective and
also like people need to seek it out and
people can hit me up on facebook or
instagram.
I'm,
I'm pretty readily available so if
people have questions and want to,
you know,
hit me up then just hit me up.
I mean I'm a big,
strong,
fast on social media and I will answer
your questions as much as I can.
Like I'm not,
I don't hide from people,
you know.
No you don't.
And when the documentaries out,
can you come back in and I'll watch it
and we'll talk about it and will and
hopefully we'll have some good news
about it.
And.
All right folks,
I'm.
Hi,
I'm Kratom right now and it doesn't do
anything.
My brother wants to get back in here
with you too.
Okay.
I love that.
Smelly.
Yeah.
Can I mentioned something about him?
Yeah,
for sure.
He's got a big sale going on for a the
black Friday.
If you enter the Code Rogan,
it's 20 percent opposite for his
slingshot.
How much you bench?
Dot Net is his website for slingshot
slingshot products.
I had to plug them.
Okay,
beautiful.
Will shout out to mark.
All right,
well thank you Chris.
Really,
really appreciate it.
And do you have a name for this
documentary right now?
We're calling it a leaf of faith,
a leap of faith.
I like it.
So if you have a new name,
we'll have to go like that.
I think I did that name.
It's cool.
Let's go with a leaf of faith.
Beautiful.
Thanks Chris.
Why are you so much?
I appreciate it.