All right gentlemen,
we're live with a freshly fed uriah
faber.
No more dieting.
No more way.
Cutting.
Is this his mic on?
There we go.
Now it is.
Yeah.
Just pull that sucker up to you and cody
motherfucking God brand finally made it.
Yeah.
Here.
Gentlemen,
what's happening?
Just chilling out a nice little beach
run and I jumped in the ocean.
Cody kept the shoes on and all that good
stuff.
You still got a mouthful.
Those green belly bars,
don't tuck it in.
Your mouth would get squirreled away.
These teeth or specialty that have like
pockets in your.
I need to floss twice a day.
This guy was making fun of me.
He's like,
Bro,
you've been brushing your teeth 1:20
minutes,
20 minutes straight,
brushing his teeth.
I brushed,
my teeth,
came,
you know,
walked out and I was like,
man,
he's still brushing his teeth.
Made me have second guessed that,
brush my teeth long enough to have to do
it again.
I'm lazy.
I got braces or anything.
So I've got like all these natural
little gaps.
It's like I'm like a squirrel food gets
stored up in there.
I got to get it out.
I understand.
How does it feel to not have to worry
about.
We were talking about this for the
podcast,
not have to worry about weight cutting
anymore to be able to eat healthy.
Not,
not banged up anymore.
Man.
It's been really,
really nice and always kind of
envisioned after even wrestling in
college,
like having a break and then you know,
went 14 years longer fighting people.
But I mean it is really nice to be able
to.
I mean,
you go train.
I trained what I want to but I don't do
this stuff.
I don't want to.
I,
I get in and do the grappling rounds and
whatnot,
but I just feel so much better here.
You look healthy but you made out of
retirement.
Perfect.
You know what I mean?
Like you had a long career but you
didn't get too banged up.
Like you just end.
You pick the right time.
You went out with a win with a quality
opponent,
like ride off into the sunset.
I know man.
I don't know.
I was a little luck.
A little bit of it just felt right
though,
you know what I mean?
The last fight we went out to what,
5 million people on Big Fox.
It was the first fight in my hometown in
the new arena that's like the heart and
like revived our town.
You know,
we had cody fight for the belt,
like coming right up and,
and uh,
you know,
it was just perfect man.
It was time to good.
Good.
You know,
it's nice.
It's nice to see someone do it the right
way and I hope other guys coming up can,
can learn from you in that regard.
Well,
what are the things I thought about was
first and foremost,
like I'd been rocked more than in the
last two and a half years of my practice
and live fights that I had in my entire
career,
which is,
you know,
a lot of different factors.
Probably how many times you're rolling
the dice,
you know,
you get hit in the head a bunch of
different times.
Things are loosening up a little bit.
You get a little bit older.
Guys are getting better.
I got cody Garbrandt and the Jim and
Chad Mendez is,
and,
and you know,
Lance Palmer,
these guys hit heavy so,
you know,
I was just like,
that's one factor.
And then I lost two fights in a row for
the first time in my career ever,
even though it was a decision to dominic
and the decision to uh,
what's his name,
uh,
and go riviera riviere Jimmy Riviera and
it was like kind of lackluster losses.
But nonetheless it was like,
yeah,
just like,
you know what,
I'm not going,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna.
Call this one and a good time.
Smart.
Very smart man.
And I really do hope more guys learn and
pay attention to how you did it and do
it the right way because like,
how do you guys feel about like,
uh,
you know,
you seem like a lot of these guys are
going over to Bella tour and I think
Bella towards science,
really good fighters,
you know like Rory Macdonald,
Lorenz Larkin and they got,
I mean gay garden saucy.
They got some great talent over there,
but they also have guys that are,
you know,
late forties,
fifties still banging stuff.
Yeah.
Freak show stuff for me.
We always talk about this.
I tell her,
I said if I start getting fucked up and
they're knocked out,
like I'm going to keep fighting,
like make sure that you pull me away
from my leg,
be the HMI that says,
Hey,
sits me down.
Like,
Hey,
let's do a different career path.
You know,
if Allie say that,
you know,
that's one thing I always say,
we're fighters,
we're always going to fight through it
and obviously a lot of different reasons
you know,
financially or sometimes it's just hard
to walk away.
What do you do in the next chapter of
your life?
People don't set that up,
you know?
Luckily I'm fortunate I have a lot of
good people around me so you know,
I'll have different avenues to go and I
always tell them,
hey,
if I start getting fucked up in their,
stop me telling me it was important to
understand that the kind of intensity
and focus that's required to be a great
fighter,
you could do anything.
You just apply.
Just figuring out what that next thing
is going to be in go out at the same way
you went out your championship career.
Yeah.
I always tell these guys,
you know,
we do talks before and after practice
and it's like a feather in the cap
mentality.
Like every we've got guys in there that
won't see the UFC daylight.
I mean they'll never step foot in the
octagon,
but they get a little bit of pride.
Whether it was one day it was 10 years
or whatever of being a part of that team
and that's something they add to their
life.
They take on them with the next thing.
Somebody just comes in for a week.
Some guys are going to be,
you know,
make it to the big show.
Some guys are going to be world
champions,
some guy's going to be hall of Famers,
you know,
and,
and that's,
that's whatever your journey is,
that's a proud thing.
You can put a feather in the cap and
move on to whatever you're doing next.
But,
but it's,
it's a bigger picture and it's like
journey's never over.
It's just always changing.
Oh,
for God,
like Lance Palmer,
who's a real world class guy,
but he's fighting in,
what do they call it now?
It's not world series of fighting
anymore.
They have a new name for it.
Right?
What is it?
They changed the name real pro fighters
or something like that.
Yeah,
but the problem is nobody's watching a
few.
Very few people are watching,
but he's a real world class professional
fighter.
Like you see when just engaging came
over to the UFC,
you realize like,
Hey,
this fucking kid is world class and he's
been fighting in an organization that no
one's watching.
Right.
Well,
I mean,
the hard part about that is like you
said,
you got a gate and you got to Lance
Palmer,
they're still fighting tough ass dudes
there.
So
it's the same level of competition
sometimes,
sometimes even even worse when they get
all the Russians over in belt or like
those Russians are tough,
you know,
so like freelance,
we just have to exit them at the right
opportunity.
He asked to get on a little winning
streak and be at the right time in his,
in his,
in his contract and be able to jump out
and go to the big show.
But uh,
it's hard because he's fighting these
tough guys.
Like the last guy,
he lost it,
he broke his hand the first round and
then he's fighting a tough guy and it's
like,
oh,
he lost in this show.
He lost against a world class dude.
And he's a world class fighter.
So,
you know,
it's,
it's hopefully just something where he
can make that transition over.
How do you guys
feel about a win lose?
Like pay days?
Like one thing that bothers me about mma
is that mma,
if you win,
you get a certain amount and if you
lose,
you get less.
I feel like contractual.
I think I feel like you should have a
contractual amount that you get paid and
I feel like when you're leaving it up to
the judges sometimes and the judges,
I mean both of you guys have been
involved in least teammates getting
terrible calls tall and you've seen it
and you go,
what in the fuck?
You know,
like look,
even in boxing,
the conor Mcgregor Floyd Mayweather
fight.
Two of those judges had connor only
winning one round.
Yeah.
How?
They're crazy.
I was looking around at those judges to.
They're very familiar.
Some of them were a mma.
Make a judges also,
right?
There's a lot of them that did that.
They started with boxing and then they
learned a little bit about Emma man and
he came over and sort of judging mma,
but there's a lot of them that literally
don't know what they're judging or know
very little about it.
And your career could be.
You mean you could,
you might have 100 and 100,
so $100,000
swing on someone who doesn't know Jack
Shit.
Right?
Oh,
that's terrible.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
I guess for me as a fighter,
I look at it like it's rewarding,
you know,
but then the opposite scale of it,
you can be on that losing call and
horrible call the rep,
screw Ya,
but I don't know,
for me it's.
And they still appear like it's pure
thing to do,
so you got to go in there and fight for
two checks is more your training.
You come out with two checks you lose.
It's for me,
I honestly,
and I always remember getting a check
afterwards and especially when I first
started,
I was like,
oh yeah,
I got paid for this.
Like literally,
like it had nothing to do with the money
at all.
And then you got that check and then
you're like,
oh man.
So if you're doing it for the right
reasons,
it should be.
Yeah,
just get your set amount.
I think that is to warrant against the
guys that are doing it for the wrong
reasons.
I think it was a good motivation at
first or when they're trying to build
it,
but now it's not.
We're not building it anymore.
Now it's a world class professional
sport and I remember Uriah when you were
fighting in the cage,
right?
I remember the first time I saw you
fight.
I think you're fighting 55 to.
Yeah,
I had to start.
I mean there was no weight class for me
at that time.
Yeah.
Now I remember talking.
I remember I was all pumped because
Rogan knew who I was because he followed
all the underground shit.
I was super self aware of like how,
how much my notoriety was and like the
bigger show because I,
you know,
Youtube,
I started looking on there and be like,
I only have like 1500 people watching my
shit.
I can here and then kid Yamamoto has
like $250,000.
I'm like,
fuck no.
But yeah.
Well I was frightened.
I mean I fought Tyson.
My first loss was against Tyson Griffin
and cannot die casino and in the parking
lot.
And I hit him just like need him inside.
Tripped him and the head dive into the
steel pole and just gashed my head open
like eight seconds into the fight and
I'm just pouring down blood.
I remember that they didn't have padding
on the pole,
well they supposed to do it,
but that the crew was running out of
time,
so they didn't even take the time to put
the padding on the bottom level.
They just put the clear like fake
leather on the top of it.
And I'm just fucking gushing blood.
I think we talked about this last time I
was at her show.
I think we do a man for real.
That was a terrible way to pave the way.
Fuck that.
You know,
like I said,
a lot of guys can learn from you and I
think it's good man.
What's it like,
you know,
training in his gym and like when did
you come here?
You came there like three years ago for
about going on four,
going on four now.
It's four years.
I came out,
I was off an injury.
I had um,
symptoms of Vertigo from mild
concussions and I broke my hand,
my pro debut,
so I had like a whole year layoff and
always reach out to Uriah.
Lance was out there,
so I knew lance,
you know,
wrestling,
him and his brother throughout,
you know,
arresting careers,
um,
is,
it always came and wanted me to come out
there and finally hit favorite when I
was 18 about,
hey,
I'm going to come out and take the gym
out,
see if it's good date.
He had to hit me back.
It wasn't till like four years later I
was able to make the trip out there and
said out of the year off,
I was like,
dude,
I'm not wasting any more time.
I know I'm good.
I want to see how good I am with some of
the best in the world.
I made all those killers out there.
They had Tj,
Chad favor,
Joe,
Danny.
I mean we had.
Chris was on,
Holdsworth was on,
you know,
getting,
you just won the ultimate fighter.
That's a bad dude right there.
Houses head doing uncrown champ,
Bro.
I'm telling you.
UNCROWN chat.
He's doing okay.
I think he's just,
it made him look at things a lot
different and he's like,
he's like a gem in the gym.
He's a coach for us.
And just like everybody just soaks up,
but he's got
and he's eager to just going to stick
with coaching now.
Or is he thinking about an option?
How old is Chris?
He's 27.
Still Young.
Very young.
And he's been off for what,
two years now?
Almost longer.
Uh,
was that when Tj,
when the bill was his last plate,
they find the same card.
So.
And so he was dealing with some
concussion issues?
Yeah,
a lot of guys.
I mean,
remember Tj grant was gonna fight,
Benson Henderson for the title started
getting some concussion issues.
I Holdsworth would have it
where I'd look at him in one,
one of his eyes would be all black and
one would have like a little skinny.in
the middle.
And I'd be like,
dude,
what's going on?
And he'd be like,
but like hosers is like Weirdo,
you know,
master Tang always used to say,
hey,
you know,
tj champion,
uh,
you know,
80 percent holdsworth champion 100
percent.
He was like,
he would never come to our,
our,
our team gatherings.
He wouldn't go to the river,
he would do anything.
He was just all about training,
like almost like a problem,
you know,
but that's what happened to Bj Penn,
Bj Penn when the,
when the Bjj world championship,
the first American to do it and like you
get an obsession and he was just vision,
vision,
vision had this obsession to be the
best.
He was knocking guys out on accident and
practice high kicks and knees,
you know,
with knee pads on,
like just because he was,
he's good all the way around.
But his Jujitsu,
is that right?
Top.
Yeah.
Super good.
And I remember coming out there and uh,
with all those guys know,
like a year,
a year layoff and I'll say,
man,
I want to see how you know how good I
am.
So I went out there and mix well with
good with the guys and had a fight lined
up.
Like I have a fight in two weeks.
I went out there for a week,
a favorite came in the last day that I
was there and like matching me,
like put me through the gauntlet with
all these team Alpha male guys.
Uh,
it was wrestling day.
So I was going with these guys and we
walked off the mat and he's like,
he's like staring me up and down,
look at my tattoos like that.
He's like,
what do you want to do?
I'm like,
well,
the fight in the UFC and be world champ.
And he's like,
alright.
when can you come back out?
I'm like,
I'll be back out next week.
I'm sure $100,000
guys been in there and said the same
shit to him.
So I was like,
I'll be back out.
Came out,
you know,
the week after we shook handshake,
he said,
all right man,
he's like,
get to five and Oh,
and we'll get you get you to the UFC.
And I just,
every fight I was saving up.
I fight.
We came out there for a week that it
can't knock them out.
Flew back suitcase was staying at the
firehouse.
It was like 12 people in their twenties,
Jap,
you know,
Japan,
Canada,
all over.
I mean it was just,
man,
you have a weird setup,
right?
Like do you still have that block inside
block of houses?
That's,
that's how our team got built and that
was like I bought a house in the,
in the the time of the market where
anybody can buy a house,
like stated income loan and I didn't.
I'm like,
I'm going to buy a house pre 2008 before
the crash,
before the crash it was 2005 or $2,000.
Yeah,
four or five and I had no job,
no income really.
I was coaching wrestling camps and I was
getting like $7,000,
but you could do it.
My,
my Egypt one buddy was doing loans and
he's like,
I get you alone.
I'm like,
really?
Is it?
Yeah.
Say it didn't come do this,
do that work history because you're
coaching now and you went to school as a
teacher.
It's a two year,
like all these different things.
I didn't know that that's the reason our
whole economy crashed,
but I was able to get a fuck hidden.
But worked with you alone?
Yeah,
worked for me.
I never defaulted.
I just moved all sorts of buddies in.
I started,
I mean on that house a block and that
block of houses we had probably probably
45 people that went through their
childhood there.
Tj lived there.
Uh,
Justin buckles live their master tongue
live there.
Fabio Prado or coach lived there,
like we had four or five houses at this
point.
We've been selling them off,
so we all hopefully now the sports at a
place where we can be in a nicer
neighborhood.
So we're all trying to get in the same
neighborhood in east sac,
the fabulous 40.
So a nice neighborhood.
That's the new.
That's a new block.
Yeah,
an interesting spot because you guys
like surrounded by it's kind of country
in a lot of way,
you know,
this is like the river.
It's beautiful.
I love outdoors activities.
Tahoes close.
Sandra.
Yeah,
our way.
you guys.
It's a good spot.
It's a good sentence.
Actually located spot and I mean I
always say,
and I think cody,
like rough as cody's background was,
he had a core,
like a town that like rewarded him for
being a champion athlete from football,
from wrestling,
from boxing,
etc.
And there's a heart to it.
ThAt's why I feel like cody,
such a good person in general,
like when you,
when you get cody,
like,
you know,
dealing with people and individuals
walking on the street,
he's like a gentleman and like has,
has a heart for the kid,
you know,
is kids that have disabilities,
these kinds of things that comes from
that small town where there's,
there's accountability,
you know what I mean?
It's like,
you know,
you're a good part of the community,
that's it.
So I Think sacramento has a big city,
big enough city,
but a small enough town feel for that.
Which you lose some other places.
Yeah,
definitely have all the little mom and
pop shops.
We go to like a big team,
alpha male fans.
We have a discount.
It's like almost like a friday night
lights,
football town,
kind of like,
oh,
we're the fighters out of there.
So we get the hookah.
We get,
you know,
It's,
it's nice and everyone's super nice with
us.
So we moved the gym.
The old gym was a downtown,
so I moved it to over by the stadium in
the state of the art facility.
It's great.
So we've got to drive through phab
forties.
So where I live,
I drafted the five bad forties.
That's who's who make it,
you know,
the nicest houses.
So it's always nice to drive through
that neighborhood.
I got,
I'm going to buy a house here and then
go to the gym.
So it's,
it's nice,
a nice little change up this year we've
had.
Yeah.
So you're right.
Now you're prepping to fight tj to
defend your title for the first time.
First of all,
what does it feel like to be ufc
motherfucking bantamweight champion of
the world?
Man,
it's awesome.
I'll have so fast.
yeah,
it's awesome.
You know,
now it's about what you do with a belt.
We were just speaking about this on our,
on our run.
Yeah.
He started taking off when I started
talking about this at fired up.
I hate to run neighbor,
like he's like wants to these runs.
He's always after the practice to do
these like shitty ass,
like sprints on treadmills and like,
dude,
this is not fun,
like wants to do this at 10 minutes,
scratch,
like just on.
And I'm like,
he's a bit of shit that people don't
want to do.
I'm like,
I don't want to do this.
I'd rather,
I just hate writing movie was.
And he was like,
all right,
do you think that running?
Like,
I've had a conversation with a friend of
mine about this with conor mcgregor,
conor doesn't run.
And he was like,
I really feel like every athlete that's
doing something that requires real
endurance,
like boxing or mma or something like
that should run that.
Like the act of moving your body,
like forcing your body,
like your legs propelling your body and
constantly working your lungs builds you
like the kind of lung stamina and
strength that you can't get from
anything else.
Um,
so this,
that's a good question and it's all
different because I mean we,
me and cody had a discussion and I'm
like,
this title fight.
I'm like,
cody,
look dude,
I know you don't like to do them.
I want you to do these fucking runs.
I'll get on a treadmill and do like a 10
minute or put it on 10 and run for five
minutes straight and then I'll and then
I'll put it on 12 is a little incline
and do like 40 seconds on,
20 seconds off and I had to do it with
me once.
He was like,
bro.
He goes,
look,
I've always,
I've done this kind of thing.
I don't really like to run.
It's not part of my regimen.
I guarantee I'm gonna be in great shape.
And he went in there and he fought
dominick cruz and I mean,
so you can't really argue with that,
but in my opinion I think it's a great
way to get yourself uncomfortable.
You can run easier,
you can run hard to simulate the feeling
where your lungs are going to blow up
in,
your head's going to pop in your fucking
teeth hurt.
like I like to be able to do that with,
with running.
But you can get the same thing at a hard
goal in wrestling or jujitsu go if
you're pushing the pace or a boxing go.
If you can simulate that type of like
energy and expenditure.
But you're forced to do it when you're
running really,
really fast until you.
Until you stop.
There's no coasting,
right?
Yeah.
But it's funny.
I asked dan henderson,
I asked dan harrison his good buddy.
I'm like,
when I first started fighting,
you know I was trained with randy
couture and dan henderson.
They would come out to sacramento and do
little camps and stuff and I ask a.
I asked dan or dan henderson's buddy.
I'm like,
bro,
how many days a week this dan and run
and this is 2006.
And he's like,
dan hasn't ran and 12 years.
And that motherfuckers is savage.
Dude,
he's a savage.
He is a savage.
Yeah,
mike.
He's a mentally toughest dude ever.
My uncle was all like old school
trainer,
so we'd like pad work,
bag,
work,
run shadow box,
you know,
and,
and spar.
We get.
When I was younger he would get us 50
rounds of work.
It's like you get 50 rounds,
you're ready for a fight.
We'd always spar 50 rounds of boxing
rounds when you're younger.
50 rounds and rounds fight before the
fight.
So it could be five rounds,
10 times.
Is that what you mean?
Yeah,
throughout the four or five weekends to
your fight,
you know,
fight every.
Sometimes we live in the tri tristate
area.
So I would fight and I had a bunch of
books I'd fight in Ohio on friday,
saturday and Pennsylvania,
West Virginia on sunday.
So I had three fights and we can't do
that anymore,
but we lived in the tristate so we
always had these regional books,
you know,
and if I,
I got this book,
you only have five fights,
you know,
this guy's,
has 100 so box amateur boxing was almost
like am dressing.
they're always,
you know,
competing like that.
But he never really forced us to run.
We always spark,
you know,
that's when you really fight would
happen.
So I'm just composing that.
He always told me growing up,
he's like,
fighting doesn't make you a better
runner or running doesn't make you a
better fighter,
so I just always tell it to favorite.
Every time he wants you to do those damn
runs he's running doesn't make you a
better fighter.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of different schools of
thought on it and some people think that
you have to run like long distance.
Just enable your body to dig deep in
those late rounds when you're getting
tired that you'll have more endurance.
That way
it doesn't hurt.
That's true,
but the whole thought process behind one
person's theory.
This is why I can't stand coaches that I
think it's the only way you know what
always learn.
Of course you always want input from
other people and you have things at
work,
but like even my,
my,
my manager back in the day,
he always used to worry about Chad
mendez,
his training because like Chad mendez,
lance palmer,
those are two guys that had been
training since they were five years old
on a regimen,
like their dads pushing them,
making them go to this and making them
do that and so they're.
They're like little vacations they got
were like the most they needed that they
needed to go,
go hunting or go fishing and get the
break.
For me,
I was always.
My dad,
we'd.
He dropped the trailer off.
We'd have a,
a motor home.
He dropped it off at a pawn.
He'd go to work and we'd fish all day.
Knew no one was having me wrestle or do
anything.
I didn't start till I was in the eighth
grade,
so I've always been on like a,
like trying to catch up kind of deal and
like a chat and lance are like,
get your homework done.
You train your butt off,
you do a regimen and then you take your
little break and then you'd take your
breaks,
you know,
and it doesn't matter.
It's just about what you,
what you're processing as your method
that you believe in.
As long as you really believe in it.
That's the most important thing.
The belief system is bigger than
anything else.
It's gotta be,
there's gotta be different methods for
different fighting styles too.
I mean some people move around more like
dominic and some people are more,
more stationary and you know,
rely more on power.
I mean there's got gotta be different
routines that would be more effect and
it's kind of about finding whatever
works best for you.
Right.
Exactly.
For me,
I like sprints on like a very explosive
fighter,
but also I have endurance.
She was like,
I did the vo two testing.
It's actually I tested as a cross
country runner.
I hate running on the results,
you know,
so,
but I'm,
well I feel like I'm,
I do better at spreading then long
distance,
but it's crazy.
Like what,
you have to be in shape for going,
you know,
to fight for the cage.
Like you have to be a great wrestling
conditioning,
boxing conditions.
Those are all different conditioning.
It's like a boxer comes in and wrestles.
he's toasting a minute if that.
sometimes wrestlers they same thing.
They go in there,
their box color just to composure,
you know,
that's what made with herbs.
I would.
Connor said right after mayweather.
He said shots were nothing.
He didn't,
you know,
it was just the composure.
Allen's logged
in.
He's just so efficient to any new.
The connor was going to fade because
connor was relying so much on
explosiveness and tense and so
and they didn't have enough time to
prepare.
I thought,
I thought connor did a good job of
staying nice and flow and everything.
But here's,
here's the truth.
It's like if I were to take a pretty
good high school wrestler or like a even
like a really good high school wrestler
and put them against an olympic gold
medalist,
like,
like a high high level high school
wrestler versus an olympic gold
medalist.
I mean,
there's going to be a difference,
but when,
when the fatigue cracks a little bit,
it starts happening a little bit.
one guy's gonna keep composure
completely and the other guy going to
have a little bit of a of an opening in
the other guy will be able to to to,
to isolate that and I think that's what
happened with the fight and I figured
that would happen.
I just didn't think that connor would do
that well,
the whole fight until it happened,
you know,
he was doing awesome.
It makes me wonder like,
how would he have done if he had six
months to prepare,
how good would he have done if he got in
good shape?
I mean it might've been able to make it
to the twelfth round.
I think either way the more loose floyd
got,
the more he was going to start landing
shots.
He's just a far better boxer.
He's especially.
I don't think it was.
I don't think it would be.
It's about getting in shape necessarily
because connor had to be in amazing
shape.
He's already a world champion.
Then he's got this big opportunity.
That's what I always tell the guys also,
it doesn't matter what kind of shape
you're in.
Being a cheap only means you can do more
until you get tired.
I think the better shape you're in.
He would've kept doing more,
do more,
and if he wasn't able to finish him,
you know what I mean?
Because floyd was lettIng him do more.
I mean it wasn't letting him,
he was wasn't letting him necessarily,
but it was taken rounds on for sure.
Letting connor blow out to manager.
So it's,
it's like the better shape you're in,
the more you're going to output until
you get tired,
but if you're trying to fucking win,
you're going to be,
you know,
you're going to be putting it out,
putting it out,
putting out.
I think he would have been able to do
more until he got tired.
But the fatigue would set in.
Yeah,
there was.
We had this in our wrestling room,
a board saying,
I said,
fatigue makes cowards of us all know.
I read that.
I was like,
I had this.
I was in the same restroom since I was
five years old.
All the way until,
you know,
sophomore year,
junior year I was done wrestling,
but I always read that I was like,
man fatigue,
you know,
I was like,
I don't even know if it was,
but I knew what a coward was.
So it was like I knew they didn't go
right.
So I would literally go so hard.
I know how to wrestle really.
I would just would go,
go,
go and just keep scrambling out of
things.
And that's how I always dress well.
And my brother was like the same exact
way.
It was a grinder,
old school wrestler and I had him
pushing me.
So it was always that fatigue,
fatigue makes cowards of us all.
So when you get tired you're always
going to get tired in the fight.
Like I didn't know,
I've never been to the fourth round.
Been in the third one.
So you know,
with,
with cruz had all these questions like,
oh,
how is it going to be as composures can
they go,
you know,
keep that power and speed up the fifth
round.
Shit.
I didn't know how I prepared for that
and believe that's the thing,
it just believing I was tired,
but I was having so much fun in there.
You juSt kind of pushed through that
when you're tIred.
And that's the thing when fatigue sets
in,
some people can either wilt from it or
you know,
propel them to like,
when I get tired I feel like I biked
down while I'm more iSo index.
I'm tired.
I know that mistakes happen when you're
tired.
So he has,
when he's got to stay on it more to
concentrate more on keeping your
technique clean and making sure that
you,
uh,
well,
it's an interesting thing when you're
fighting a guy like dominic crew too
because he's so awkward.
Like,
you,
you're,
you're preparing for someone who moves
in such a way.
I mean,
you're right.
you knew better than anybody.
You fought them several times.
So he was so weird.
You know,
he does move weird,
like the second time I fought him,
uh,
I feel like it did a good job of,
of like letting him move and then when
he'd landed,
hit him.
And so the one thing I went back and I
watched that fight and I'm like,
you know,
you're always looking at excuses of why,
why did I lose this fight or not?
And I think little things count,
and I talked to cody about this in his,
in his fight with,
uh,
with don was let's make sure the eyes
are on you when there's no action
happening because dominic has always
doing this weird.
It's like peacocking,
he's moving and doing these little
movements and weird shit.
And so when,
when nothing's happening,
who you're looking at,
you're looking at the weirdo,
you know what I'm saying this,
he said yeah.
So then it's like,
he is weird,
but it's not like,
oh,
it's a different kind of weird.
What was it like doing the ultimate
fighter opposite tj,
like knowing that you guys were
eventually going to fight and knowing
that you guys used to be teammates.
Honestly,
it Wasn't bad.
Like for the first two,
three weeks,
it was fine.
We were cordial,
like,
you know,
it was what it was.
And,
uh,
until he started going to like the media
and like would say that I'm different on
and off camera.
I was like,
dude,
like tj,
we were just like being cordial and
cool,
like getting through the weigh ins and
doing that whole process.
Honestly.
It's,
it's a lot,
you know?
Right.
I'm still trying to train and fight,
but it was opportunity.
I love to do it.
I love the guys a team.
Um,
had my coaches out there,
my aliquot out in vegas.
It was a good time.
We had a good time with the team and we
were fine until,
like I said,
he would go to the media and like talk
shit.
Sal was different like about choking one
when he was talking shit.
And he stepped towards me.
So I was like,
so you're saying that.
And so we cornered,
I cornered him,
uh,
and the,
and the and the,
and the.
Yeah.
And that with no cameras like tj,
I was like man,
what's going on?
Why are you talking shit?
And the media saying that I'm different
on and off camera.
Like I wouldn't beat Your ass you right
now.
Cause there's no camera.
he's like,
you think that?
And he's like,
no,
I don't think you would whoop my ass
right now if I grabbed his ass up again
when I throw it and slam against any
like squared up with me.
And I was like,
all right,
we're gonna throw down like cool with
just me and him.
We'll throw it down and that's it.
No cameras around and maybe will subside
some of the shit because I was getting
pissed.
He was being with me,
you know,
right there.
How many people were there when you guys
almost fun?
No,
it was him.
I was there and just got out the shower,
the shower,
have a picture of it.
So if I sit there like it is tough but
as just confused on.
And I was like dude we're,
we're cool.
Cordial with each other.
And then you go on in the media.
That's when I started.
I was like man,
I was just kinda like fed up with the
whole thing.
But now it's like so long drawn out for
the fight.
I'm just like,
if you take all that away,
him leaving team alpha male,
um,
all the variables and he's breaking down
against fighter verse spider.
This is a fucking fight that I like,
thankful for,
you know what I mean?
I'm finally getting to fight these
opponents that are,
they're worthy opponents that can go out
there and show,
showcase my skill against,
you know,
so it wasn't a horrible and being around
the guy until he would go and talk,
show in the media and I was just like a
pod bouncing man,
what is,
what is going on?
How did you guys resolve it when you
were alone in the locker room?
Dude,
everybody came with literally broke it
up.
Did that happen?
Well,
that happened and then he like put his
fist up and I was like,
all right,
here we go.
I was,
I was just gonna throw some fire.
Adam,
we're going to fight like,
all right,
cool.
He's going to fight me.
And then uh,
he put his hands down and he was like,
look how you're acting bro.
And I was like,
oh,
like he went from straight ready to
fight and then to that.
So I was like,
whatever it is what it is,
I'll just like do quit talking shit on
the media.
Like right here,
you cAn say it to me.
like I don't know why we don't have a
con.
You know,
we can talk about it in a couple of
times.
We've had off camera talks with me and
him about the whole joe daddy stevenson
fight.
I was like,
look bro,
I understand you're trying to get your
guy back on,
but joe should not fight.
He took so much damage in that fight and
he's fighting in six days.
I'm tWenty five years old and I would
not fight in five or six days after.
I just felt like that he was concussed.
He was hurt and teachers like a man,
like I can't tell them not to fight.
I'm like,
you have to tell them like you're a
coach.
You can't call his wife or his coach or
you have to sit and do it.
We can have.
I don't want my teammates fighting each
other,
but dude,
that's going to be bad.
I said he's going to get knocked out and
be hurt,
you know,
and teachers like,
don't,
don't get that in his head coding.
I'm like joe and we were doing in front
of joe.
I'm like,
joe,
look,
I love your pioneer.
Like you're,
you're alleging that sport.
You don't need to go out here and get
$10,000
and for whatever it was they were
getting,
getting into that fight to go in there
and have serious brain damage.
He's fighting.
Hydro hydro has I think eight knockouts,
vicious knockouts.
He throws his hands.
I knew it was a bad matchup,
you know,
it was,
that was an ego thing,
tj.
One and his whole team,
because he was,
he kicked your ass on the team.
You know,
we didn't,
we didn't silently pick the best match
ups or you know,
it was in there trying to do what we
could with those guys.
You know,
it was,
it was tough.
You know,
it's like teaching an old dog new
tricks.
It was just,
it was hard.
It was honestly hard.
It's got to be weird coaching people in
a short period oF time like that to me.
You really need veterans.
Right?
So it was,
it was.
We had no,
I didn't do any of my research on them,
like how they did outside of the ufc
career,
you know,
I remember I'm in the ufc,
I'm like,
okay,
you know,
this guys,
he can fight eddie gordon.
So these massive,
let's go with him.
You know,
how we just didn't know like how they
did outside of it,
you know.
So I would have just assumed that like
as a coach,
if you get anybody and you're working
with for six weeks,
you would start thinking,
oh,
if I had six months exactly rid of this.
Yeah.
What I noticed when I coached against
don,
we had a,
we had three months.
Oh that's right.
Because you guys did.
There was the crazy alive.
The only life season.
What was that like?
How's your life?
that was vegas been all these guys.
They,
I was,
I was staying under wraps.
But uh,
you know,
we had the whole crew out there.
It was all my coaches were just the
young guys coming up to try and get them
exposure and everything,
so I had tj and lance and you know,
all the,
all the guys were my coaches.
They're running a muck in vegas.
It was
various three connor season.
That was when I came out.
That was.
I was ready to leave vegas.
Like I couldn't wait to leave vegas
after that.
It was just.
Yeah,
same as cody is what my coaches remember
for the bigger.
Yeah,
it seems
send me that like vegas to live in vegas
is kind of like living near a nuclear
reactor.
Like you may be able to do it for a
couple days,
but after awhile the radiation is going
to get you one wrong decision from a
whole change of life.
Yeah.
All of a sudden you won't have seen
daytime for,
for a couple.
This also in my,
my feelings on it is that your round,
like maybe it's just me being sensitive,
but I think you're around people that
make shitty decisions allowed to around
a lot of that in vegas because you're
around a lot of compulsive gamblers.
Just a vibe of the city,
like there's great shit in the city,
there's a lot of successful people,
you know,
dana and the fertittas and there's a lot
of people that are making great money
and doing well in business,
but then there's a whole like underbelly
to the city that's compulsive gamblers,
have a ship and a bunch of other stuff,
compulsive,
all sorts of stuff.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But uh,
I think the.
It'S funny,
like you go to la,
this is mostly talking about like,
you know,
people have that are trying to get into
the entertainment industry or whatever.
It's like la is like a social climate.
If you take the crappy part of the
social scene,
it's people trying to socially climbing,
oh,
if you do for work,
what a car is kind of,
what can I get out of this person and
try to play the game and have success in
vegas has just sold out.
Like,
all right,
I'm going to go get a bunch of fucking
money stripping this cocktail,
Whatever it is.
Yeah,
whatever the deal is or whatever it is.
So it's like la social climb,
vegas sold out.
Well it just doesn't seem like a vegas
has a,
like
there's a lot of transient people and
there's a lot of people that are there
just for the casinos.
Whereas like any other city,
if you live in chicago for instance,
it's a town,
you know,
it's a real city.
People been there for generation after
generations,
a lot of different businesses,
a lot of variety to it.
In vegas you got the hub which is all
the casinos and then you got the
surrounding areas that are just sort of
feeding off of the casinos.
It's weird.
It's a weird gig.
Weird.
Great.
Great for short,
short times.
Yeah.
The one thing I would say it was cool
while you're there is,
I mean sacramento's not necessarily a
destination spot.
So while I was living there and people
knew that we were living there,
I would get hit up like every couple of
days with somebody that was coming to
vegas.
So there's always like,
you get to rehash,
like see all sorts of people that you,
uh,
you know,
would like to see that are,
that are popping into vegas.
All of a sudden it's like damn
everybody's hitting you up.
Like it's like,
you know,
it's kinda like a little reunion place,
we go there all the time
now.
As far as your new place,
like what did you do differently when
you guys moved to the new spot?
Like how did you set it up?
The old spot for a long time,
right?
yeah.
You got to check out the place.
He'll love.
I saw it online.
It looks amazing.
So basically we just made it bigger and
better and tried to cover all the things
that we do as mixed martial artists
within one roof.
So we have crossfit,
we have yoga,
we have a trx,
we have,
you know,
conditioning classes that are,
mma base.
We have introduction to stuff.
And then we have the mma side,
which is a traditional moitai are,
are pros happen,
work out of there.
We have our own little locker room for
the,
for the pros and we have like,
like nice finishes.
There's a cafe there,
there's an outdoor area,
there's like,
you know,
bathrooms and showers and that's
amazing.
The other place was just,
it was 8,500
square feet,
which is still pretty big at the time.
It was just cutting edge and it was like
one shower,
one toilet and it was 13 years of
building the team and the place stunk.
That's a good recipe for staff and
shower.
First time I ever got staff was when I
went out to team alpha male.
It was right before my ufc debut.
Literally like remember that two weekS
to three weeks beforehand?
No,
I got the call like,
you're going to fight in three weeks.
I'm like,
yeah.
Did you get on antibiotics?
Antibiotics?
Yeah.
I remember it was like,
why are you taking it on?
I'm like,
dude,
I got staff and like in my leg,
like couldn't walk.
It was horrible.
First time I had it.
And was it from not showering right
after you trained or just have staff all
over again?
Body habit,
your nose and everything else.
I think immune system down and then cut,
you know,
do you guys fuck with defense soap?
Yep.
That's,
that stuff is this shit guy.
Seiko jakks is awesome.
This boy,
great guy.
Great guy.
So,
and that,
that product is fucking amazing.
He has a bunch of different things like
solve for scratches.
This ointment,
this tea tree oil and eucalyptus and
stuff like that.
Yeah.
But you could stay on that stuff on a
regular.
you will 99 percent
of that shit.
They getting that sleep,
getting sleep and eating right.
And,
and,
and you know,
shout out.
What kind of diet are you on cody?
Like how do you,
uh,
how do you organize your nutrition?
Actually spoke with aubrey a couple of
weeks ago.
We did like opposite and submit
standpoint from onnit.
You gave me a whole protocol.
W wait,
you know,
for this camp,
daytime,
nighttime stuff really matter.
I can eat whatever I want.
I have a super high.
It's hard for me honestly to gain
weight.
Like I'm hovering around 1:47
after workout,
put so high,
so high and I don't,
not never been a big year.
Like I never liked to be full.
Like I don't like that because I don't
know.
So I just,
I usually do some meal preps.
I messed with some meal prep companies.
Um,
my wife's a great cook so she usually I
eat a lot of salmon.
I love salmon or bison.
Um,
so I keep it at the end.
George lockhart,
I worked with him so he,
he scraped the whole diet.
Here's my card,
here's the proteins and then we get to
the fight week and I'm literally 12
pounds over and I start doing his diet
and water loading and I don't run,
I don't have to,
I just do my workouts regularly.
Like I would for a,
you know,
just to keep sharp for the week,
lose the weight.
I mean it's the best.
I feel the greatest,
you know,
I used to always cut weight within,
like cut a lot way and then get up and
feel sluggish.
Like with with george and the diet that
he's given me an asa with,
with the onnit products,
I've for two months I had been on the
honor products and I feel so much like
just better,
better with them like joint wise,
like I had such defense.
I got a,
like I said,
abra gave me a whole thing that this
krill oil pills,
all that stuff,
giant men official is so important for
people and so many people don't take it,
but it's just for joint mobility and
joint health and just reduction of
inflammation.
Also it's fuel for your brain.
It's great for building your muscles,
like fish oils.
Just one of the primary supplements I
think people should take.
My mom used to have us take spoons of
that,
not the pills.
She would actually have fIsh oil and I
have that stuff.
I get it.
Crossings,
I get it in a jar,
two tablespoons of it,
but they have it.
They you put like lemon flavor in it and
different things,
but it always tastes like shit.
Shit.
Tastes like shit.
Not true.
Not good.
Yeah.
So you just essentially eating healthy,
you know,
you don't have like any specific diet
you follow?
No,
I mean I,
I stick to the,
you know,
the lean stuff,
get sushi,
salmon.
I always do that.
Um,
we have a bunch of good little healthy
spots around town too.
We got a.
Actually I'll send you out some juice or
liquid.
Ology juice.
It'S fresh juice.
We have two spots that are like right by
the gym.
They have like super healthy foods.
Yeah,
it's like a health bar.
So you guys have almost like a whole
fitness location there.
It's not just a gym.
Right.
You know,
and how many,
how many members you have now?
We're like 1400 members.
What's the name of the
place again?
Your ifa?
Results meant fitness.
That's it.
Yeah.
Because I know you were thinking about
doing something with the ufc gym at one
time,
right?
We have one,
we have one out there,
one of those 35 minutes away as well.
That's in rocklin,
which is about 35 minutes away and I've
got a partner there who is a gym guy.
He has crunch gyms and he's in tight
with mastrov and the guys that ufc gym
and so he Primarily runs that and
there's no contact in that,
in that place.
You know,
you can't do sparring and things like
that.
So.
Oh really know any of the ufc gyms.
So when they have like,
oh,
so you could strangle each other.
You can't kick or punch Egypt.
So when they have like kickboxing
classes,
do they tap each other at least?
No.
They the bag work and no drills.
I mean,
you're not going to learn if you don't
do something.
They do.
They do some jobs they don't do any
like,
no,
they don't have like one,
one person hold mitts and one person
hold,
but he could do privates and stuff like
that.
IS it just like a liability thing?
I would imagine.
Probably worried.
Yeah.
Well at least they can do jujitsu and
jujitsu and you learn great technIque.
It's a great idea too to have a gym
that's based around the ufc where people
were fans can go and learn that kind of
stuff and get a great workout.
Just see what they should have.
Bob arum said today,
so we have a boxIng as an enemy and it's
the ufc.
The ufc is the enemy of boxing.
He's still a little dummy.
Fuck bob.
Tell me.
Well you just,
you just got six point 5 million pay per
view buys from mayweather versus
macgregor and a bus match.
So you tell me how the ufc is the enemy.
You silly
few out dude made.
Made,
made boxing cool again.
Definitely.
I guarantee you it bumped up canelo
alvarez and triple tops.
Watch the 24 slash seven while.
Yeah,
me too.
Boy.
I don't know.
Look,
nautica lufkin is a motherfucker dude,
but canelo alvarez get gets better all
the time.
See a younger guy,
you know,
he looked fucking sensational against
amir khan.
He's looked sensational.
It gets everybody except floyd floyd.
JusT floyd got them to drain himself.
Go all the way down to 1:50
1:52
or something and cut down that far.
Yeah,
he cut down way low and they just look
sluggish.
And floyd is the best boxer,
pretty much ever that he is boxed him up
game plan and stick to the game and just
look beautiful.
Did triple g's interviews are hilarious.
Like traditional,
like russian,
you know,
it sounds like.
Exactly.
Max max.
I hear it for big drama show.
Yeah,
exactly.
Of course.
I think it would be a good fight for the
fans.
That's what I'm here for.
more chose christ.
Yes.
My friends,
mexicans love triple g fights.
Like fucking julio.
Cesar chavez.
Man.
He's a savage.
He's a fucking animal.
Body puncher and ripping shots.
Well if is going to get it,
cody.
Man,
I think honestly canelo.
I don't know,
I just think,
you know,
a,
a triple g is a beast.
I think
you like to know.
Why do you like to know on this?
I just like his,
his,
his um,
his pressure is body punches,
you know,
is the,
how he flows.
He throws a lot of hooks on it.
Like I'm a big hook guy.
so like any,
like Mike Tyson,
I used to watch all my stuff hooks and
canelo does too.
Um,
he throwS some creative stuff to die.
So I did that.
I started doing a move off of watching
canelo.
He throws like a fake hook to an upper
cut.
So it's like this and it goes like that
because the guy who covered here and it
comes right up the middle.
I mean my didn't look as good as his.
I didn't punch against scotty jorgensen
when I find it looked like I was just
winding my,
my,
my arm up like this.
But it's like,
well,
but he has a bunch of little tricky,
subtle things he does.
I like canelo.
He also his ring generalship like that's
huge for me.
Like I caught you can knock people out
fast or have good combos,
but the way that you take the octagon or
the ring and stock them and then impose
your will on him.
His,
his presence in there.
He knows where he's at all the time.
Yeah.
What's interesting to me about this
fight is this is the first time that
he's fought a guy who's world class that
is a brutal power puncher like him who's
bigger than him,
who's going to come towards him,
you know?
Whereas he fought floyd for.
It was a smaller guy,
but just way craftier and slicker with
the style and you know,
it was an interesting fight,
but ultimately it wasn't like the most
exciting fight because floyd just kinda
outboxed him.
I think this is going to be a bang of my
fight.
I.
Yeah,
I think you're going to come towards
each other and it's gonna get crazy for,
for real.
This is like the highest stakes fight in
boxing because you have two murderers
punchers in their prime.
Gennady golovkin undefeated.
The only person canelo last two is
floyd.
That was only last.
Yeah.
This is the only last and it's been
decisions to use.
15 professional,
young,
50.
Phenomenal.
I mean,
just such a good fight.
I cannot wait for this fight all amped
up.
That's what I was with.
Oscar tweeted about,
you know,
he's all about it.
I as they,
dude,
we're still gonna.
Watch you.
This is why they're all fools.
If,
if oscar just said,
this is great for boxing,
this is great for everybody,
then everybody would have been fine.
Instead these guys create enemies.
Know and say,
this is a disgrace.
This is a fixed five numbers.
They're saying,
floyd,
if fixed the fight and you know,
they're still saying some crazy shit.
I aSked her is losing his mind.
Dana dana is like,
is he doing blow and cross dressing data
is a savage.
He's,
he'll call them and they'll come outside
of my picks about like some,
you know,
if I posted about them or something like
that.
He just kills people.
He don't,
he does not give a fuck.
It's so funny.
He's hilarious.
That's what happens when you have a half
a billion dollars.
You don't give a fuck I guess.
Well he didn't give a fuck in the
beginning,
which is why he was perfect for the ufc
picture.
He went right before he,
uh,
right after he did the whole deal where
they sold and everything he was on like,
and he was on some show.
And he was just slouched over,
look like a like a pile of crap,
and I took a picture of it and I sent it
to him.
I said,
bro,
why don't you sit like you have $400,
million dollars in the thing or at least
investments of some fucking fitness shit
or something.
I sent him a picture just all slumped
over like this.
I think he's super stressed.
I think he's better now.
I think that time was like a crazy ass
time.
Could you imagine you're about to get
involved in a $4,000,000,000
deal.
And then how about afterwards all the
shit starts falling apart.
Rhonda gets murked.
Connor decides to go to boxing,
you know,
the,
the sports fallen off in a lot of the
pay per view buys jon jones test
positive again.
Like what's up?
Like so much.
I mean he was on his way to being a next
gigantic superstar.
Right?
I mean if you take away his,
his time off,
right?
The time off where you get busted before
he had to take a whole year off because
of the dick pills,
all this different stuff.
That time off from the car accident take
all the time off and john keeps winning
and you got a goddamn gigantic
superstar.
The likes of like anybody that's ever
been in the ufc,
maybe even right up there with connor
means you don't know.
Even even.
I mean all the negative stuff that's
happened in John Jones,
people are still booming dc and cheered
him.
He has some great pr going that I don't
think it's that at all.
I don't think it's.
I don't think theY have the brain.
I don't think anybody alive has the
brains to organize public response.
I think public people tweet to pe.
They love john becauSe what john is,
first of all,
he's a ruthless killer inside the
octagon and then he's like,
he fucks up,
but he's still a bad motherfucker.
Like he.
He was getting booed and everything and
then he took the time off and then by
the time he came back,
people were back out to the side.
It's like,
you know,
he glued.
When was he getting booed there?
He's getting booed a like before he got
suspended the time before.
Really?
Yeah.
When he tested positive for coke,
I can't remember.
I'm getting booed and if but if he was,
it was nothing like dc dc winds fights
and gets booed.
Crazy.
You kNow what I mean?
He beats rumbling.
He gets booed.
People get mad at them.
They got mad at him when he beat
rumbled.
Member were blowing them like,
what are you blowing?
The guy just fucking choked out.
Rumble johnson like how we kill it for
the second time.
How are you doing?
I don't get it,
but you can't.
The public.
Yeah.
You can't contribute fickle.
Just decide.
Exactly.
They decide who they love and they
decide who they hate to tell you what
though?
John's speech after he beat dc was
beautiful.
That was great.
It was.
It was great,
but it was followed up by a steroid
tests.
That's why it's so sad.
I've been looking.
I'm hoping just like everybody else.
There was some sort of a fuck up and
then we figured out that someThing
happened.
Something was wrong.
Well,
I haven't really followed it too much.
I don't really know the good.
It's not good.
Well,
he tested positive for something that
only shows up in urine tests.
And so they did a urine test after the
way ends.
He tested positive for this stuff and
then they did a blood test and you know,
he's his campus saying,
oh,
it's not in the blood test.
Well they don't test for it in the blood
tests.
That's why they do a urine test and a
blood test.
It's a two different tests like d ball,
like the main tee ball team,
toronto ball or something like that.
At some it's a weird substance that not
a lot of people take.
So um,
um,
apparently chael sonnen was talking
about it that if he's taken that like,
this is real old school steroid took a
short acting short,
short half life.
Steroids
just me out,
man.
It's sad.
I,
I just don't think I've been.
What's,
what are you proving?
That's my whole thing.
Well,
he must have felt like you needed some
sort of an edge.
If he took it.
He took it or,
or the real problem is,
or was he taking stuff the whole time?
Did he get involved with those power
lifter dudes and start taking shit
because remember he's got fucking suit.
Her dad was just massive.
yeah.
I mean he literally was going to
heavyweight.
He looks huge.
I mean,
I don't want to speculate at all really.
Yeah,
I know.
But uh,
but you were involved in the sport in
the early days when there was no
testing,
they just look at you.
Yeah,
I mean when you were,
when you were first finding like Kenya
cage,
was there any drug testing?
No,
nothing.
Not at all.
There wasn't any type of anything.
I mean it was illegal in California,
so the,
the only reason we were fighting on
indian reservations because everything
was illegal.
Isn't that crazy that native americans
do whatever the fuck they want because
we screwed them so bad.
But it's not a way.
I mean,
it's happened so many generations ago.
It's kind oF weird that it's still
around,
but they have like this sort of.
They have a nation inside a nation.
So it's very odd little situation
over in the u,
s we talk about the holocaust and what
happened over there and over in like
Germany,
they talk about what we did,
the indians.
Well you know what we did at the indian,
we were here when it comes to like
genocide.
You know what the biggest genocide was?
Disease.
Yeah.
Ninety percent of them were killed by
smallpox and all sorts of bugs that they
just had no resistance from.
That's right when they first met the
europeans and it had nothing to do with
like a planned attack on them.
People were just dying off like crazy.
That's what happened.
That's right.
Terrific.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
but it's a thank god they have casinos.
So I've got a bUnch oF buddies that are
native and so they have like different
things in one tribe.
Like you had things you Could,
you could choose one group up in
northern coast,
took their fishing rights so they can
fish with nets and like put bombs in the
water and.
But they didn't take the,
the casino fucked up.
they did fuck all the fish.
Casino money.
They they slang that smoked salmon.
It's good.
It is good,
but it's not like the casino money.
You buy a lot of smoke sound foxwoods
cash.
Exactly.
Yeah.
There was um,
a,
a place in alberta where,
uh,
I've been hunting up there and the
natives,
they call them first nation people up
there.
They're allowed to basically hunt
anyway.
They want these spotlights and shoot
animals at night.
They shoot as many as they were their
rights,
right?
Yeah.
That's part of the deal.
They fish casino,
he got free moose have free.
They're just allowed to use all sorts
of,
you know,
what other people would think of is
unethical techniques.
Do you have any hunting trips coming up?
Yeah.
Mom going to Utah soon.
Alcon a couple of weeks.
We're excited.
You eat mostly.
I know Chad does that,
but tries to eat mostly food that he's
killed themselves as much as I can.
Ninety nine percent of the food I eat is
wild game other than vegetables.
Yeah.
Shit.
well,
if you could shoot an elk,
like either those ell kids that are.
How back?
That's 400 pounds of meat.
I give a lot of it to my friends who
don't hunt,
you know,
just like elk.
But uh,
that's,
that's enough meat for a year and then I
usually shoot a deer to a year.
Yeah.
And that's what trips me out about
people that are so against hunting.
I mean,
I'm not a big hunter,
but uh,
like the things that happened,
like on the farm is where they're like,
you know,
have animals,
is cajun and try to feed him getting
fat.
I mean,
that's some nasty stuff and this is way
more humane and a healthier way to eat.
Right.
It's definitely healthier way to eat and
it's definitely way more humane.
people love to point the finger.
90 seven percent of the people in this
country meet either that or they're
pescatarian and they eat,
but you know,
that there's maybe three percent of the
people in this country that are vegans
and that's a,
that's a small number.
But you know,
they,
they get very vocal about it and the
best way for them to like,
they can find a person,
like say if you hunt,
you hold a picture of a deer that you
shot,
they found you,
you're you.
So the urine individually.
Whereas like if you have a steak,
like that steak was raised by a rancher,
it's on a ranch.
Who's the guy who shot at,
who knows,
but you got it.
A supermarket.
Here it is,
is too many.
Too many people down the line.
It's not.
You can't point to one person.
But if I see uriah faber or holding up a
doc that he shot like,
well that's you,
you,
you killed that dog.
Get the vegan cat lady after you.
Again.
It's true.
That's true.
That's a true bit,
man.
That's the true bit.
This,
this bunch of.
It's a community of people that think
it's a good idea to feed their cat vegan
food.
Yeah.
There's a whole move to feed cats,
vegan food,
and the cats can take it.
They go blind and have heart attacks and
shit.
Yes,
yes.
Yeah.
Cats are supposed to eat something
called taurine that only exists in
animal food and like in an animal
protein,
cats are what's called an obligate
carnivore,
which means they can't eat anything
else.
It's like a dog.
Dogs can eat carrots and a bunch of
other shit like dogs eat things.
You can eat.
Dogs can eat some grains and potatoes
and stuff like that.
It's fine for them.
They mostly eat meat,
like dogs are mostly carnivores,
but they can mix their diet up a little
bit and still be okay.
Not cats.
You,
you fucking start feeding cats beats and
vegetables and shit like that.
They bit.
This chick came after you.
I'll show you.
I don't want to do the because it's on
my next netflix special,
but it's like someone got mad at me
because I posted a picture of some meat
on instagram.
It's based on the total truth
store and it was one of the vegan cat
ladies.
Yeah.
Just fucking pitch.
So I don't want to ruin it for the
adult,
but it's just the community of people
that that feed their cats vegan food,
they are fucking completely there.
They're like next level,
crazy,
like if you talk vegans are crazy.
They're like,
well,
we're taking the shit to the next level.
It's like there's levels to everything.
You know,
like this,
like you were talking about your gym.
There's guys that are just tough guys.
They don't really want to fight these
guys who will want to fight and the
fight in the amateurs and then there's
cody garbrandt.
She's the cody garbrandt,
have a vegan,
vegan activists level of crazy.
I went to his,
he was a month or so ago,
man,
I would like to come on.
It was great.
That was the first guy I went live.
I sat down.
It was,
it was great.
I was laughing my ass off.
Sacramento's fun,
man.
They came out.
It was a good time.
I always love performing there.
Ever since.
Back in the little comedy club there,
the punchline,
sacramento,
it's great spot.
It's a great little spot.
I went up there.
Craig robinson was in town and he's my
buddy.
He's a good dude and he pulled me up on
stage that have me do something.
Fucking shit it up the place.
Pretty bad.
Craig bring his music up there,
but it saved me a little bit because
he's brought me all right.
I wouldn't bring my boy up,
blah blah.
And I got up there on stage and then,
uh,
and so I'm like,
my manager kind of like gave me a heads
up,
like craig might pull you up there.
So I had like,
like,
all right,
well I just told the story that the
chick that knocked on my door and came
and shit all over them.
I did that,
but I had craig do sound effects for it.
So I was like,
hey man,
I'll do this,
but you gotta give me a sound effects.
He was on her sing,
like,
then she took a massive shit and he's
you know,
doing it on the,
on the key word.
This was like new year's,
right?
SoMeone broke in your house.
It was just a saturday night.
I mean,
this was on new year's.
I'm more known for,
uh,
for this lady shitting in my head,
my bed,
my bedroom or my bath.
And then fucking most things I've done
in my life for myself.
Well,
you told a story somewhere.
I took a video of it on snapchat and I'm
like,
dude,
this is still open.
Yeah,
it's probably up.
Well,
tmz,
tmz did it and did a story on it and
they did an interview and they showed my
whole thing and I actually like got a
picture of the cic opened the door and
there's like a canoe of shit between her
legs and she's sitting in vomit and shit
half in the toilet,
half on the floor in my brand new house.
I just spent a whole year building it,
me and my dad and she just tries
to get in your house.
What happened was the store the door,
like an idiot.
So.
Okay.
So I'm sitting there with my buddy
virgil and his girlfriend.
It's like 1:00
on a saturday,
we're just kicking it bs and yeah,
it's like a side piece you.
He doesn't put that in there.
No,
come on.
So then I hear a little knock,
I thought and I'm like,
someone knock on the door and then it
goes away and I hear again and I'm like,
I think somebody is knocking.
So I go in and literally I opened the
door like this and I got this plump like
24 year old fucking drunk as shit woman,
like leaning against the door,
like looking at me and I opened the door
and she just walks in and I'm like,
can I help you?
And she's got a little boiler.
Is that her in the background now?
That's my buddy.
virgil's ex girlfriend.
Oh dude,
this is great.
This is kind of strange.
Just send the case walks in your house
and then it goes into the bass.
You walks in my house and I'm like,
can I help you?
Most thing I've ever seen him already.
So she was passed out in shit and piss
your bathrooms.
So.
So I opened the door and she stumbles in
like all chubby and,
and like a boiler hanging out fucking
ambulance,
firetruck,
swat team to come get this chick out of
my toilet.
And so she walks in and walks,
dress,
I'm not going to help you.
And she just keeps on walking.
I'm like,
excuse me?
And she like walks the end of my house
and just locks herself in the bathroom.
Is that her right there?
Uh,
yeah.
Just sitting on the stoop.
This is after she wiped up.
Yeah.
oh jesus.
She didn't wipe up.
That's the christ itself.
Jesus christ.
She missed everything.
It's weird that she knew exactly where
that bathroom is at.
I've just sat them bath.
It was not there.
The heroes.
Had she ever been over your house for a
party or something?
No.
So she just was in the neighborhood.
So I live on a corner and there's maybe
there's maybe like it comes to truth
locked down.
There's a bar called,
uh,
called uh,
cheaters,
I think she was drunk from that walk in
and had it really take a shit.
There's a bar called cheaters.
Yeah.
Because it's kind of like the ashley
madison and bars go there to hook.
Yeah,
of course.
Of course.
Yeah.
I really wouldn't go there.
So anyways,
if you go to that bar,
look like you know what's going on.
Oh,
it's an old ass like bar in east sac,
which is like the nice little
neighborhood.
And it's like a shitty dive bar,
so I don't know what it's all about.
The dude's name is cheater.
It's probably cheaters bar man.
About cheating and cheating.
Names.
Cheater.
They're cheaters theaters now.
Maybe it's cheaters.
It's on 34th.
And folsom.
Is there a posture fee after the are no
cheaters.
Okay.
Yeah,
look at that.
It looks angry.
Fuck up.
So this is right doWn the street from
your house that,
that,
that bathroom was not there before I got
the house.
I added that on,
poured a slab and built back and
everything else.
And so I don't know how the hell she,
she dead ended in the end of the house
and just took a left.
so she just got lucky.
I found the bathroom shit all over the
place.
Did you ever contact her afterwards?
Did you ever lie?
No.
She ever contact you and say,
hey,
I'm sorry.
Shit all over your house.
Like she's got to know that it was on
tmz and all these different websites.
I think she reached out.
Think again,
we cut that one off.
Girl gets into a 12 step program.
You will be one of the first people she
apologized to say I gotta make it right
with all the people that are wrong in
the past.
If she's,
she's someone in the neighborhood and I
don't know,
but the truth is like she went into that
bathroom,
like she was just drawn,
like how could she,
could she have known
if you know my house.
That's what I'm saying.
I always ask them too much.
This guy,
mexican guy that was working for me and
he had an issue.
He,
he would do the lacquer on all my
cabinets and everything and so he took
like an extra month and he would get in
there and I go into the house.
It was being built and he'd be passed
out on the,
on the floor.
He'd just get high as fuck and like pass
out.
MY theory was maybe he,
when he was,
he was like,
stay the night at the house,
the house under construction.
Maybe He was having this chubby check
come over or something
semester I man passing off to a mexican.
It's just not how you doing.
Let's change the subject that's move on
from the phantom shitter,
like team alpha male in sacramento.
You guys are like one of the real super
camps in the world.
Like there's like a handful of super
camp says country,
right?
There's like a tt,
you know,
there's a duke roufus,
there's for us,
uh,
hobbies,
camp,
tristar,
aka there's a bunch of super camps.
Do you try to pay attention to how other
guys are running their stuff and try to
figure out what,
what they're incorporating as far as
like strength and conditioning,
you know,
rehab places like physical,
physical therapy,
things on those lInes
a little bit.
You know,
we have a reputation for whenever we go
somewhere and going into the gyms and
trying to get it rolling,
you know,
testing yourself against other people.
Like,
like kind of an open door policy at our
place too.
Like if somebody wants to come in they
can come in and check it out.
So we've gotten a lot of throughout the
years a lot of feedback and done her own
stuff.
But I'm always trying to but not
necessarily like.
And we kind of have our own recipe like
we ever things that work out regimen and
a lifestyle.
it's like set set programs throughout
the day and you can kind of make shift
your own depending on what your coaches
think you need to do and what you feel
and needed to do because there's,
there's,
you know,
two,
three practices.
You could hIt a day if you wanted to.
And then there's individual workouts and
they go,
you know,
some guys do the cryo therapy and then
they,
they've been doing that suction therapy
and they've been doing that.
The cup stuff,
cupping.
I don't,
I'm like,
I'm like old school,
like I don't really believe in.
I'm not like looking for all these
little secret things to do but have
never done those things.
Help.
Something's got to help.
A little like cryo helps.
Do you do that at all?
I've done it a couple times.
You're not like,
it's not a thing that I'm adamant about
that I think is good,
which I would've liked to do more of
throughout my career is the hyperbaric
chambers that after the aldo fight,
right with your leg,
with after the aldo fight,
after the Mike Brown fight,
like you broke your hand,
broke my hand and had surgery.
Like,
I mean I would use that just as regular
bit.
And then tj dillashaw actually got one
and had it at his house in his garage
brewing like in sacramento.
He and he had like a certified,
him and his wife got certified to do it
and,
and he would just like chilling that
thing.
Oh,
so what does the hyperbaric chamber
dude,
it's like oxygen rich environment,
right?
Yeah.
So it's high oxygen rich environment.
So it basically like it can,
like,
it does like the same thing that red
blood cells to do like transport things
to,
to your body fat and help you heal
faster.
So like there's high altitude which
helps you get acclimated and,
and,
and make more blood cells yourself.
And this is just like helping pass
things through.
It's like a hyper oxygenated
environment.
What do you,
what do you feel like it did for you?
It healed me faster,
so that's the first that I never.
I never been like a big strength and
conditioning guy even in,
in,
in wrestling,
in college because I was always cutting
weight so I felt like,
like,
you know,
I've always been really strong for my
size.
It wasn't one of my tHings that I needed
to work on necessarily.
I was working on technique or working on
this or fluidity or whatever.
So I started.
When I broke my hands,
I started doing a heavy lifting regimen.
I used to not like to do lifts,
like squats and stuff like that because
I would get so sore I couldn't do all
the shit I like to do like wrestle and
run and things like that.
So I was going to heal my hand while I
was doing these heavy workouts with my
trainer.
Kept asking me like,
am I sore?
And I was like,
no,
I'm not sore.
We finally put it together because of
the hyperbaric chamber.
Like I was like hyper healing.
It was like,
like I would do a hard,
hard workout and never get sore because
I would go into the oxygen chamber.
My schedule just worked out.
I was going in there quick.
Huh?
That's interesting.
Is there any downside to doing it?
No,
there's no.
Well the downside is it's expensive and
that's the same reason why insurance
didn't,
didn't
pass it to,
to be insured.
So like there was a session and it can
be as much as 200 bucks and I a session
for an hour.
And how many sessions were you doing?
I would get it to where I was doing,
you know,
like four sessions a week.
Dammit.
Insurance wasn't paying for this know.
Ufc would pay for it.
Oh,
that's nice.
Yeah.
That's so like,
is this something they have set up at
the.
You have the new ufc performance center?
I think they have a,
all that stuff there and I know the
underground treadmills,
the high altitude a building.
I've used their pet a couple of times.
I'm just,
we have a very fortunate with russ back
in sacramento,
eldorado hills that he does all that.
I use hyperbaric chamber as well.
I had the whole whole last year.
You know what?
Sometimes you kick someone wrong angles
messed up for two,
three days.
I would go on there that day and
literally you could put weight on it and
move around and be fine.
What they use it for his brain trauma.
It helps heal your brain.
Like they'll play your ons and yeah,
it's the same thing that they do for the
bends.
When somebody goes and does deep sea and
they.
They feel like deep sea diving,
they have to put them in a hyperbaric
chamber to like acclimate them to like
heal them from coming up too fast.
I mean there's like a real science
behind it.
It's no.
I've heard about people using it for
breaks,
bone breaks and having some really quick
recovery.
I've just never experienced it.
You should do it.
I feel like why would.
I would imagine it'd be just a good
thing to do all the time,
but I wonder if there's any negative
effects.
I don't think there is,
I mean,
you know,
they're,
they're doing it for autistic kids,
for people with lyme disease.
Lyme disease is a big one.
She uses.
that stuff's scary.
Yeah.
There's so many fucking people that have
that and don't even know you're tired
all the time and broken down.
They don't understand that their immune
system is devastated by ticks.
Yeah.
There's a thing called the rocky
mountain tick,
rocky mountain flee or something like
that.
I think it's rocky mount,
but uh,
there's a um.
Oh no,
that's not it.
It's the lone star tick.
There's a disease that people are
getting that makes you allergic to red
meat.
Huh?
And then getting it from ticks.
That's a trip.
You take a tick bite and you don't
realize anything even happened and you
go to eat meat,
like you cheeseburger,
something to get really sick.
Your immune system gets devastated.
There it is.
The lone star tick injects alpha gal
into the bloodstream and then the immune
system releases immunoglobulin e
antibodies to fight this foreign sugar.
After this reaction,
the future intake of mammal meet with
the same alpha gal will result in an
allergy reaction because meat has,
it's like alpha go lactose.
They're saying alpha gal as short.
But I forget what it actually is.
I forgot the actual.
Uh,
so does It.
Does it say there?
Yeah.
Galactose.
Alpha one.
Three.
Galactose.
So that's the shit that lives in later.
Tigers
shit bro.
You do a podcast every day,
three hours ago and learn something,
but it's been around for shit.
But that's fucked up,
right.
Chad mendez.
Got that?
Uh,
he'd be devastated that man.
Make sure you got that stuff on.
You just can't see chaz vegan.
Well,
you can eat fish.
It's mammal proteins.
You start eating crocodiles.
Crocodiles only.
Yeah.
So the hyperbaric chambers is a good
one.
I've been doing the,
uh,
the,
the salt.
What's the thing you've been doing?
Float to do that a long time.
And they finally got one right next to
our,
uh,
we own the island,
a little vibe.
Health bar in sacramento,
the liquid and the juice fiber and they
have the right next door.
They have that hyper,
a float center float center,
so I've done that.
So amazing in it.
It's cool.
I mean the only problem is I have to
have a quiet mind enabled to go to get
the most out of it.
Like if I'm stressing about something,
I go in there.
I just like.
I mean I ended up like just thinking the
whole time,
whatever.
I have to be at a right place to go in
there.
I think yeah,
maybe it's a personality thing.
Like do you.
I mean I like it when I can relax,
but like if I have like a lot going on
my mind,
I can't just shut it down and then I'm
stuck in this like a lingus thinking and
I can't and I'm like,
I gotta get out of here and go take care
of this,
take care of that,
but what I want,
I'm able to chill.
I love it.
I know cody uses it a lot.
I use it a lot.
I one time I had a close call,
like a astral projection.
I don't know if it was crazy.
I went in there.
Basically it's,
I was explained to the guy that owned it
at the time because I quit going.
I was like,
one time it happened,
I feel like grim reaper came over top of
me.
No shit.
It was like trying to push me down and
drown me,
but I was like sleeping and like a deep
trance.
Like I'd always felt like my body would
vibrate and you're like kept coming.
I will come back to like the wake,
such an sleep deep trance.
I come back up and I'd finally calm
myself back down,
relaxed and would drift off into the
float and they bone would come like just
the whole time I could feel that hot
coils on my back with my face,
you know,
because it's still,
you're just above water around your
head.
LIke three times.
I finally got up and I was like,
god,
I really felt like something was trying
to do.
Someone's trying.
I don't know what I was going on and
anxiety or something crazy,
crazy.
Wow.
Stop some crazy visions in their last
time I was in there.
I just kept the.
It has the blue light in there and I got
the music going and I was just spinning,
lIke bouncing off this.
I was just staying busy.
I could chill.
I'm not good at relaxing these days when
he would say,
I would think you'd be better at
relaxing now.
Now that you're retired from fighting.
Oh no way man.
I have to.
I'll have to like if jujitsu is going on
and I'm like,
I'll have to like stop and be like,
look guys,
we're having a meeting right now.
I go,
let's cover this over like jujitsu
started 20 minutes ago.
I need to get that workout in.
Otherwise I'm like,
you know,
you create yourself a regimen throughout
your life of working out a couple times
a day and that's what you do.
And then you go in and try to have
meetings all day and,
and like this and put this fire out and
get on this call.
And it's like I was doing that together
with being a full time athlete.
So finding the balance has been the key
for me.
Well for you there,
there probably Is like a requirement
that your body has to like blow out
stage two
and that and that's another thing with
the diet.
Like he was asking about his diet,
like I had been like an overeater,
he doesn't like stuff stuff and he was
calling me,
you know,
making fun of me for eating all the
time.
I'm like just constantly eating and
whatnot because I'm used to doing that.
You burn so many calories in the day.
Now I have to like be mindful of not
like overeating because I'm not putting
out the same thing.
otherwise I feel like crap.
You don't want your fat tire and you're.
Yeah,
I mean I'm not worried about getting fat
necessarily.
It's more of just like feeling like,
shit,
this guy's coatings the best instigator
ever.
Whatever.
I'll do it.
He tries to,
he tries the like accentuated like,
like if he knows that I'm like man,
I'm a little thick and then they'll wait
like a day and they'd be like,
man,
fabian looking a little bigger.
Just always trying to make
about 13 percent.
Do you hAve a jujitsu match with paul?
Yeah,
right?
Yes.
That's it.
And you went to a decision with him,
man,
that's checked six overtime.
That's gigantic.
That guy is fucking legit,
man.
He's pretty good for garlic.
You didn't specialize in that and
specialized in mma,
you know,
and coming from a wrestling background,
obviously you have a grappling
background and you were great at
submissions in your mma career.
But to take on a guy that's like,
that accomplished as a grappler,
that's gigantic.
Yeah,
it was cool.
I mean I always tell these guys and I
actually believe it and that's what I
said about connor too,
like you have to in our sport,
you have to be able to go with a world
champion,
jujitsu player,
world champion wrestler,
a world champion judo player,
a world champion boxer and be able to
hold your own,
you know?
And that's,
that's the difference with our sport and
that's why it's so impressive.
And so that's what I was saying for
these guys and I didn't even for that,
for that.
I was going to train real hard to take
it real serious.
But then I got this the rampage movie
role with in the rocks new movie,
so I went and spent 10 days in atlanta
and then I had told Chad before that I
would do this charity,
a fishing ship with these,
you know,
the injured vets.
And so we did that for three days and I
went in there looking like a chubby.
There's a picture of me.
I look so freaking chubby in that,
in that thing.
And didn't even train,
but I was like,
you know,
I,
I go,
I take a lot of pride in my grappling
ability.
I feel like,
you know,
I'm one of the best grapplers in the
sport.
So it was good to go in there and do
that.
Well,
you know that.
And Chad beating Jeff Glover,
tapping him.
Yeah,
that's fucking crazy.
It just shows you the level of grappling
that you guys have at your gym.
I've,
I've gone,
like Jeff Glover and I,
when I first started training,
it makes more storage because I'm from
santa barbara with him.
And bill would.
You're from santa barbara?
Yeah.
I was born in santa anna,
beLla vista.
And we have a house in santa barbara.
Yeah.
I love it up there.
Oh bro,
you got to come stay at my house.
I mean we rent it out right now.
Barbara.
I'm renting it out.
It's rented out to a family from Sweden.
But.
Oh,
come into play.
I'll hook you up dude.
It's bad.
You just bring your family up there.
It's like santa barbara is awesome.
Yeah.
So there's one of the best spots really
is one of the best bots.
So what you're saying about Jeff Glover,
you knew hIm from paragon.
So jay,
I've trained with jeffrey years,
so the paragon used to be like the size
two of these tables,
like in a little room and so I would go
down and walk down from my uncle's house
and go down to paragon when those guys
were just starting and and me and jeff
who trained together for years and,
and bill to bill when he.
Every time they build the grill,
every time I come in there he'd want to
go straight,
straight wrestling.
Like hey,
can we do some take downs?
Because he was trying to work on that
part of his game,
but like I've,
I've shamed with sabrina,
I've shamed with hobson,
maura.
I've trained with glover.
Like when whenever I see somebody that
they can whoop me in jujitsu,
I'm going with that guy.
I had hobson come stay at my house.
I go and train with code green all the
time.
I had a glover.
I'd always hit him up and go with them.
So I've been going with this top level
guys my whole career.
That's huge though.
That's shining accomplishment for you
and even bigger for chat.
Tap glover and it's you to see this guy,
man.
That's what I'm saying.
I always give you shit.
I've said it like two or three times
when I'm like,
I'm like,
let's roll.
And you're like,
yeah,
you just want her to try to fucking,
you know,
put it on me and this and that.
And I'm like,
no,
because you always worried about me and
other people's guards.
I said this the other day.
I'm like,
whenever I read about you and your other
people,
like cards,
like in a fight,
I'm commenting,
I'm talking about your coMmentary.
When have I ever been worried about you
and someone's card debt?
What's his name?
Michael mcdonald.
He's like,
you're right,
michael.
Mcdonald's got a really good close
bottom.
Say that because if I'm looking at a
fight,
I'm looking at what?
What's the possibilities here?
Absolutely.
I'm just fucking with you.
It does have a good good team from his
back when you fucked him up.
He has some good.
He has some good triangles.
He's got.
He's got good game,
but it was a big win for you.
That was a big fight.
That was a good fight.
Wild.
Yeah.
That fight.
I mean he was knocking everyone out and
yeah,
he's a weird one man.
Like it stopped because you look at his
body,
you think or how is this car or heavy
puncher and then he just,
he hits hard fuckers.
Oh,
you believe it.
It's a weird thing.
Cody's like that.
Look at him.
All skinny and dopey.
Hit hard.
I've been given this guy shipped in the
last few days because it black guy,
he got a black guy,
he got elva advised by somebody that was
like covering up,
kinda scared and then he box with my
little Joseph Morales who's been with me
since he's nine.
He's A 25 pounder,
just had his,
his debut in the ufc and I'm like,
man,
po po got you with that black guy.
And he's like,
no,
It was,
it was an elbow.
And I'm like,
nah man.
It was.
I was getting so busy.
He's like,
you're going to make it real hard day
for joseph next time I
having a bunch of people around you that
fuck with you like that is actually
probably good for you when you get into
a situation with a guy like say dominick
cruz talks a lot of shit like you're so
used to it.
Like that was one of the interesting
things about that fight.
You could tell.
You're so used to shit talking.
It didn't bother you at all.
They get charged you up?
Yeah,
because he was getting fired up.
Man.
Dom doesn't act like that.
I like the way he was acting like our
times that we ran into each other.
I remember about the ms dot aki fight.
He was talking so much shit about me
being fatherless and like crazy.
I'm like,
really?
You could tell her you sat around and
tried to research is how he's going to
talk to you.
I'll do that.
My father was in prison or whatever it
might do.
That's right for you.
It doesn't matter.
So we go through the.
I'm getting ready to film to walk in the
fight.
Ms dot garcia at two.
Oh,
to catch fucking dumb at the corner of
my eye.
Like look and look,
look away.
And I was like,
okay,
I'm going to say something to him now.
We caught up to him and he's like,
what's up man?
I was like,
yo,
what's up mami?
As a you're going to talk shit on a tea.
Talk shit on the media about the stupid.
Even saying like,
I'm going to beat it.
I'm going to not be ms out faster than
you did and I'll beat your ass next.
And then I was like,
look,
I don't slam slamming on the concrete
now like biz being and who,
uh,
daniel camaro was right there.
And he's like,
oh hey,
like,
look back.
And like,
he's like,
yeah,
you do have daddy issues,
like said like the off the wall shit.
Like,
like,
sorry,
no,
he's not about it,
but he's a great fighter,
don't get me wrong.
But when it's in that kind of situation
he's not.
I knew he was flight then you knew what
the,
that he wasn't about the fighter like
any in his,
in his interview with me.
And he didn't want a bra with you.
Exactly.
He's,
he's not a fighter.
He's an athlete and he's good at.
He's at what he does.
But I knew that he was a different level
mentality one.
But that's a weird statement.
Like the people I've heard people say
that before.
I,
like he's an athlete,
he's not a fighter,
but if he's fighting,
he's a fighter.
Like,
so what's the difference?
Yeah,
I think.
I think dominic actually showed like,
I think he got to brave with cody.
There's a couple times where he's like,
all right,
I'm going to get in there and show them
I can hit hard and it got them in
trouble in that fight.
I think he's a fighter.
I,
I know what he's talking about with
athletes that are,
that are more athletes and less of a
fighter.
Like people say that a lot about george
st pierre.
Yes.
Like I don't know if george st pierre
loves a good nasty like knock down drag
out.
I know tj dillashaw like loves can't.
He likes to get punched in the face and
putting fuel back.
Cody garbrandt will stand there and like
if he gets punished,
he'll marsh guys down with his face down
and like tell him to hit him again.
There's those kind of people that love a
fucking,
like a grinding fight whether he's going
to do it all the time or not,
but like they have an affinity for it.
Like they enjoy it and then some people
that are like playing a sport consider
themselves tough and don't,
don't like that kind of.
Yeah.
It's interesting.
Rumble said that about himself.
Rumble johnson said,
I'm an athlete.
He goes,
I'm not a fighter.
I'm just really at it.
I thought it was crazy.
Yeah,
you chewing over there,
so what's going on?
You guys too.
And tobacco.
Can you drinking?
You're spitting and just had a louis
man.
Oh shoot.
I don't have any vices.
I thought you were getting into that
now.
Fuck
that.
That fight leading up with dominic was
everyone thought I was,
you know,
the emotional one or the way that he was
acting.
I was like,
man,
this is going to be easy.
Fight for me.
Right?
Because it was out of out of not like
dominic do that while you were a big
threat.
That's probably what it was.
Right.
I gave dominic cra credit because I know
that dom knew that was going to be a
hard fight.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
He said it.
I said,
hey bro,
thanks for giving,
for choosing the harder route in and
talking up the fact that cody cody's the
next guy because he went for the
toughest fight coders until he knew that
yeah,
he came to the fight,
you know,
I know he got here.
He got busted,
he was leaking.
I mean it's,
I was completely gassed and he was still
fighting,
like come on,
you know,
talking,
but all the way up to that,
to that point where I had kicked them
and split them open and uh,
he was talking shit back to me.
It was funny.
I was like,
he's like,
well,
you little bitch.
I didn't hurt.
Like I was laughing,
like,
oh,
don't lie,
don't lie to me.
I know that haven't got,
you know.
So it was fun.
Lego was figuring them out but still
like talking shit to each other and then
going in and it was great because I'm
like,
this is the guy that I pictured fighting
since I was a teenager,
you know,
and got prepared for him.
He's,
you know,
you said once he hit that he stopped.
So exactly.
Once we're.
He was,
every time I'd hit him or he,
I hit him with a good shot or he thought
he'd get me with one good.
We'd go back and forth until I had
kicked him and my knee hit him.
And then he came back up and I saw him
like,
he a great poker face.
Man,
he's tough.
He knows how to,
you know,
when he's hurting,
he keeps it going.
But his eyes,
he looked at the button like I saw his
pupils go really big and I was,
hey don,
you having fun yet?
And he didn't answer back.
I was a great thing like that.
The third round it was,
I knew that I was okay,
if I just keep doing what I'm doing,
I'm going to win this fight,
you know,
end up catching them or you know,
it's my fight as long as I don't get
caught with something because he throws
looping punches and kicks and he's very
unorthodox.
But I knew right then after that he was
like,
oh shit,
this is an interesting fight coming up
for you to be fucking tj after training
with them for so long and all the bad
blood that you guys have.
Tj leaving the team and going to train
with duane.
Not so much about the team.
There's a lot of confusion about what,
what,
what went down.
And it's,
it's fun for people because tj trained
with you guys for a long time.
Here's,
if I send you a text,
I'll say the four minute video of him
explaining exactly what happened,
which is know you don't have to do that,
but you tell me from your point of view.
So tj left the team,
like said,
hey look,
I first off it was,
it was a timed on ultimate fighter with
connor with,
with the company.
He came from that because he was there
and that's when we were defending them.
That's why I'm kind of like took it to
because he's like,
I'm all about loyalty and like we don't
do that shit.
I never really liked dwayne,
especially when he left because he was a
guy
and like it was always about money and
weird things,
et cetera,
et cetera.
He left and that was fine.
That was his deal.
Tj was going to try to have them come
back in and train at our gym for his
fight.
And dwayne refused to do it and I'd had
a talk with teaching.
He's like,
it was crying and like,
you know,
that,
that dwayne just wanting to focus on his
own gym and this and that,
and he's like,
you know,
whatever.
And so he's like,
I'm going to spend some time there and
spend some time here,
et cetera.
Like that's fine.
So tj,
when he got there,
got some exposure for muscle farm and
muscle farm
was they help people out here.
Duane ludwig's,
a former kickboxing champion who was an
mma fighter who fought in the ufc and
then went on to be a coach for a year
for a year and three of us.
No,
no,
he coaches now a lie,
right?
With his own gym.
But for you guys,
he was your striking coach for a little
bit,
for a year and three months and he
worked with a bunch of fighters and he
had a very special relationship with tj,
right.
Then he moved out to denver and he moved
out to denver to fight is I want to
start his own thing.
And then muscle farm,
which has a big gym in denver.
They invited tj to come train there.
So to fill in the blanks when people
that don't know the story that aren't
maybe big time fans.
So then,
so yeah.
So then he,
he basically said that he wanted to,
that he wanted to,
uh,
he was doing his camps there for about a
year and a half,
but he'd spent a little time there,
a little time here.
Most of the time he lived in sacramento
most time there we go.
Work with dwayne.
No problem with it.
I cornered with dwayne even after he
left with,
uh,
with you guys and stuff like that wasn't
an issue.
So then I heard dwayne actually text me
and was like,
dwayne said something like,
well,
I mean there's a whole side of the
dwayne thing,
which is hilarious.
That was him getting weird like a year
after he left,
like acting like he was there.
He tried to sue me for a figment of his
imagination of some money that wasn't
even there.
And like this whole thing he had like
his one of his students write this
thing.
So there is something where he said that
I'd like,
I can't even remember,
like something like I didn't give them a
discretionary bonus,
it was supposed to be given or something
like that and so there was like some,
some like intermingling is about that
whatever.
So dwayne texts me and says,
and I said,
dude,
I never said I had to set the record
straight on.
Dwayne and dwayne texts me and says,
hey,
I'm not the one trying to steal your
team in your fighters.
I know there's a team out here in denver
being built but I'm not a part of that.
And I was like,
are you talking about?
And then,
and I had talked to him and someone else
said that,
hey,
I heard that matt brown and tj dillashaw
are getting paid to be on this team.
And so I come in and I was like,
hey,
I,
we were talking about some team things
and teachers and practice.
I go,
I get the weirdest thing.
Dwayne texts me this and this other guy
said this.
I said,
are you going to like,
are you getting paid to go?
Would be starting a new or something and
it was,
cody was there and lance was there and
always there and tj like lies straight
to us about,
about the whole thing.
He's like,
he's like,
no man.
I know they offered me but I'm not,
I'm not,
I'm with you guys.
He's like this and that.
And I was like,
okay,
whatever.
Then time goes on and we have an actual
sit down and talk.
We'd go eat sometimes and everything in
tj,
Chad mendez,
uh,
my buddy phil,
we all go and eat and tj just tells me
like,
hey man,
uh,
my next camp I'm going to go out to
denver,
which he'd already been going out to
denver has been like a year and a half
since twin.
It'd be gone.
It wasn't like he like gone and
whatever.
And he's like,
but muscle farm offered me like some,
some real good money to like be part of
their team.
He was like,
so I'm basically,
I'm no longer going to be representing
team alpha male.
I like,
I'm going to do my camp out there and
I'm gonna you know,
they're going to announce me and we're
talking about.
He told me at the time it was I think
4,500
bucks a month,
a month and they were going to rent them
a house and I go and I was like,
okay.
And Chad was sitting right there and he
just sit there and go.
I go,
well shoot man.
It was nice having you on the team.
And he's like,
why are you getting upset?
I go,
I'm not upset.
I'm just saying like,
like,
you're off the team then.
And he's like,
well yeah,
but he's like,
but I,
I have a house here.
I'm still want to come back and like
come in and spar and when I'm in town in
the off season or whatever.
And I'm like,
for real weird to you guys for real
weird.
And then I said,
I said,
well,
I said so that.
So he was no longer going to be on our
team who's gonna be on a different team
and.
But then he wanted to come in.
At the time I'm ranked number three in
the world,
cody and him are going at it and
practice.
It's anybody's given day,
you know,
we can look at the footage if you guys
have the footage,
you know,
but uh,
and then holds verse seven and no,
and,
and had just won the ultimate fighter.
And so tj is basically saying is leading
the team.
I go,
bro tj,
I said,
I said you can,
you know,
you're welcome to the team,
but like if you're,
if you're no longer on the team,
like you know,
what,
what does that mean?
He's like,
well,
I mean it's just a good opportunity man.
They like,
they don't have to pay.
They pay me to train and,
and like you know,
it's,
they're starting a team and everything's
going to be under one roof and I go,
all right,
cool.
That's anybody ever done that where it
worked?
I don't know.
They're always tried that but,
but here's the thing.
So then after that it was like,
he's like,
who's going to leave in two weeks?
And so me and teach me and cody are
sitting in there and like we hadn't said
anything.
I told fabio,
art instructor,
uh,
our jujitsu instructor,
what was happening and he told someone
in Brazil is the brazilian in Brazil.
He leaked it out that tj was changing
camps and there was all this drama and,
and this and that.
And then,
um,
I said,
look,
tj.
So he,
he was coming in and teach you is never
the best teammate.
He would like try to hurt people.
He's a very competitive guy and he has a
temper and like trying her people how
she shot him.
She always,
we always use it in the bell boxing.
He nia,
he's like,
I just need him to the bottom.
Like,
yeah,
we're boxing sparring easy to the body
of the box.
Did asked.
There's no secret about tj is we talked
about it when he was still on the team
also that he had to be like reeled in a
little bit.
Right.
He's just,
he's just got a temper.
Just want to call them killer shaw.
Yeah.
Killa sha dilla shank like all that kind
of stuff.
I mean,
it was,
that was his thing,
you know,
that's just super competitive.
Aggressive guy and cheap shots.
Yes.
Super competitiveness.
Like I'm competitive.
I don't want to lose.
Someone takes me,
you know,
I'm fighting tooth and nail not to get
taken down or get that extra win that
round it just at the end of the bell
knees.
You know what I mean?
That's why chris is out,
you know what I mean?
Need him in the back of the head.
I mean chris holdsworth,
that's where the injuries.
I mean I don't want to.
Chris doesn't want us to really talk to
them about that number that we're
talking about.
Cheap shot and that's what I mean.
He doesn't care if we talk about it.
I mean,
I guess truth.
That's what happened.
What,
what,
how did it go?
I'm not saying I remember distinctively
duane used to come up with chris and be
like,
hey,
like grasshopper.
He's like,
we have a.
Tj is fight and he'd take it easy,
take it easy on him.
And chris is a killer.
It's a killer.
Fucking him up everybody.
I mean,
christmas was the animal and I guess
chris choked him out and tj got out and
talking to him in the back of the head
when he's down in the man who was down
on the mat and the spying,
but it needs to the back of the head.
That's what.
Why,
I mean just dirty shit like I've been a
couple times.
I told chris let him up,
was submitted them,
let them off and then teach them in the
back of my head.
I don't know if that's exactly how it
was.
I remember seeing the whole thing.
I don't really want to get into this
because it's christmas gig,
man.
Yeah,
that's fine.
But we've already gotten into already
got into it,
but yeah.
So let's talk about tj being the chief
charles.
That's what literally killed chris's
career.
No,
majority of obviously concussions.
Yeah.
We're real good friends with chris and
they live together though.
They lived together.
He went through and his.
That's why his last fight was he had to
fight with concussion because he,
you know,
he was scheduled to fight happens.
This is why he's just like that.
And you know,
we've all,
you know,
it's one of the things that when I first
came out there,
I was never really close with tj.
I was out there,
I was doing well with the guys and a
couple of the guys told me like,
man,
tj can't wait to spar you.
This is when he was coming off as rafi,
I'll send cell loss.
I was like,
cool,
like fuck it,
I can't wait to spar with him either.
He's better and it's going to be a good
round,
you know.
And I was pretty worn like,
hey,
tj does some cheap shit.
Just,
you know,
keep it going.
And,
and others video,
I think I have some,
uh,
one of the kids that was a boxing and he
sent it to me months ago.
Tj,
like,
keep shutting me out in the bell.
I was like,
tell tj.
I said,
look,
motherfucker,
you cheap shot me again.
We're taking the gloves off.
We're going in the street and fighting.
Yeah,
I down because of that.
Yeah.
I just don't ever like that.
Especially the teammates.
You don't do that shit.
Like,
hey you,
you,
you get me,
but don't cheap shot me at the end of
the bell.
And then as soon as
you're hitting someone after the chief,
you're like,
oh dude,
I'm sorry,
like,
you know what you're doing.
So anyway.
So anyways,
that being said,
we knew that was part of tjx thing but
now he's not longer part of our team and
he's also getting paid to go somewhere
else.
He's no longer contributing in any way
and he wants to come in and come in and
spar our guys and like,
like get.
He basically wanted to be on our team
benefit of our team without being a part
of the team anymore and getting paid to
be somewhere else,
which I would have been finding it.
Talk to me about like,
hey,
I'm going to work something out where I
go get paid and do this,
whatever.
But then I'm like okay.
So that whole week he's in there and
he's sitting there watching me and cody
in practice and I don't care.
I mean tj is a competitive.
He's always looking for edge that whole
week prior to telling us that he was
leaving,
he kept getting like,
hey,
there's a getting some proprietary
series in this series.
There's a single a guard says I used to
get them with and he's like,
have me and martin kampmann show him all
this stuff.
We were working on,
hey,
can you show me this?
Show me that like the week before.
And then so he goes,
I go,
tj,
look man,
this is getting awkward and practice.
I said,
look,
we can.
I had them over at my house and I said,
look,
we can build a friendship however we
want to do it.
I said,
but this is getting awkward and like you
being in practice and he no longer being
on the team and everything else.
Like you know,
let's finish out this this last couple
of days and then,
you know,
you'd be on your team.
We can be friends on,
on the outside,
we can work on that as a,
as a deal,
whatever.
And he's like you.
He wanted to come in and train with our
team's still,
you know,
as not as not part of the team.
Right.
And then I was like,
but you're welcome to stay on our team
obviously if you want and continue to do
your camps and whatnot.
And he is just like,
like out.
So at that point it became him taking
this opportunity,
going to denver,
being with dwayne,
getting paid to do the muscle farm
thing.
And then the whole thing with connor
happened on the tv show before this,
before any of this happened,
conor mcgregor started calling him in a
coma.
Snake a snake because me and connor had
one conversation.
We were sitting there and he goes,
he goes,
man,
congratulations on tj defending his belt
because he was still on her team is last
title defense.
And I go,
thanks.
He goes,
but what's up with dwayne saying that no
one on your team wants to be champions.
That's weird.
I said,
oh,
he's just bitter because you know,
he's trying to get everyone to go out to
his camp and he's just being a hater and
this and that.
And he goes,
he took that little bit of,
of,
of drama between me and dwayne,
like dwayne saying that no one on our
team wanted to be your champions,
including cody,
who sent him a text,
a tweet that said,
hey,
keep my name out of your mouth and
you're like a jealous girlfriend or
whatever.
And he said he took that one little
thing and then next time you saw tj he
goes,
oh,
there's a snake in the grass.
And just built it in this big thing.
So that means either how well he is so
good at seeing people.
Right.
So that took like what really happened,
which is tj got to go somewhere else.
Me saying,
all right,
fine,
if you're going to do that,
it's cool.
But like,
you know,
if you're on that team,
you're on that team.
And then then connor turned the public
around on him because it came out later
after the thing.
And so then tiji became the victim and
then he.
And now tj is new stories that I,
I,
I got mad that he was trained with duane
ludwig and I kicked him off the team.
Well,
you know,
tj now has a snake as his logo.
I know on the ultimate fighter he
brought in snakes,
you know what I mean?
He just,
he's at home with it,
you know,
he's cool with it.
So it's all good.
I don't weird rewinding back a little
bit like if you want to be friends,
let's be friends,
but don't,
don't,
don't lie back to it.
I remember going to Canada,
the whole was during the ultimate
fighter sticking up for,
for tj because tj was st [inaudible]
basically,
you know,
like inviting them to fight and,
and teachers.
Uh,
yeah,
you know,
like nonchalantly,
whatever about it.
But it wasn't defending himself.
Like I'm not a,
it's someone calling me a steak in the
grass and say I was like this loyal to
my teammates and shit.
We're fighting and that's why I stick up
for tj is tj is literally,
I'm like we're partying in vegas,
we're having a good time.
Like for the first time kind of a heart
to heart with them.
With tj.
Yeah.
And he's like,
so he's telling me this shit.
Like he said,
dude,
I'm with you guys.
Like I'm not leaving.
Fuck that.
Like I'm with you guys.
So I'm like,
this is not even that.
I'm not that close with tj,
but he just powered through the
champion.
He's,
you know,
even the champion,
you get taken care of and people you
know,
to defend them.
So connor was doing that.
He's like,
what do you guys want to do it?
It was talking about t j.
So I was like,
man,
I'll do something bad like you're asking
for a fight.
We'll fight and broken to the pushing
match and it was going out to the
outside because that's tj saying that we
were,
there he is with us.
I'm like,
dude,
you're not going to talk about my team
and how does it feel now knowing that
you're going to defend against tj with
all this weird drama,
all this bullshit for me.
I don't ever get wrapped up into it.
It might look like that with this show,
and this is my life's been like this so
I can live and prosper and folks on when
it's time to focus and die,
it's like flipping a switch.
Like I can be doing the dumbest shit
like you're fighting.
Dominick cruz were in the back just
doing dumb shit.
Like I might warm it up.
I'm just.
I'm just flipping.
The switch was like that since a little
kid like wrestling football.
Just when the lights shine,
I shine the brightest.
I always feel like,
and now a tj,
I don't respect him as a person and it
doesn't mean I don't respect him as a
fighter.
The guy skillful,
he's mean as fuck and he's going to
bring a fight.
That's going to be what I.
I love the challenge with tj.
It's gonna be a challenge.
I know him like the back of my hand,
my coaches know him,
like the back of my hand.
We were able to dissect dominick cruz
for me,
you know,
through all of their experiences.
This is a guy,
they build it up that was there longer
than I've been.
You know,
I went out there at to know I had 10
fights now with,
with the team alpha male,
now 11,
now 11.
Oh,
world champion through the,
you know,
obviously I was scared before I got
there.
We blended together that the recipe for
success,
I listened to follow lead with favor and
a lot of other guys on the team and so
we know t jan always going to do.
I know what I have to be prepared for,
so I'm excited for it.
Like all those drama bullshit a
whatever,
like it's been,
it's gone on too long,
like I'm just ready to focus on this
fight and go in there and do what I have
to do to get this winning against.
You have a good mindset.
I mean think that is.
It's a gigantic part of what makes
someone successful in the sport.
It's being able to do that.
Like you said,
having the confidence that you're going
to shine the brightest when the lights
are on and having this mindset like
you're appreciating the fact that tj is
mean and skillful hawkins is going to
give you a great challenge.
Yeah.
It's like a couch or something like you.
What do you think tj is doing?
He's sitting on the couch,
so you're getting up,
going to do the extra work and you know,
tj is a workhorse.
Like that for me makes me motivated.
I need these guys to keep me motivated.
Like dominic,
you know,
he was,
I watched the embeddeds of him.
He was running alone,
you know,
like a sob story on christmas.
Like I just got to do this.
I like it.
I'm sitting there,
you know,
we're having a party.
Enjoy this shit.
Like I'm about to fight my first title.
You know,
I've never had this time again in my
life.
I'll never fight for my first world
title.
Now it's a fight.
I'm finally getting to defend my title.
Who cares?
A lot of.
We were talking about this,
a lot of people when the title,
but what the fuck do they do with it
right now it's about creating that
legacy.
And now I have tj who's man,
he's a bad motherfucker.
He was ranked in the pound for pound
before and the top 10.
He's a killer.
So that's a.
I'm going to catapult my career with him
and I know that I'm going to do to do
with him,
you know,
I like said I've been with wanting to
know when I was green as I was just
boxing,
wrestling,
athletic,
loved to fight.
Now I blended and found my own style and
just finally I'm getting really um,
composed in there where I can let my
shirt and my skill show off it and it's,
I'm fighting hire people.
So like my skill level rides.
I've always just liked that.
Now what is this video supposedly of you
knocking him out?
Oh yeah,
yup.
true.
True.
Yeah.
How come you guys didn't release it?
I don't.
First off,
I don't stop my video.
I have seen it.
It's just,
it was on justin's gopro and do this.
I literally that I felt bad not bad for
it because it was just whatever.
Tj came followed me around the gym,
wherever I'd go put my gym bag way.
Like,
hey man,
like I slipped dude.
I'm like,
okay.
Like literally,
like he was off his rocker about it.
I'm like,
super competitive.
How did it go down?
What happened?
I've ever had them throw in,
uh,
you know,
doing his little footwork and then he
did the jump down and does the uppercut
and I just throw overhand,
right?
Boom.
Now that I'm out and he got up and it
was literally fighting easton right
before the eastern flanks.
I remember the date,
he didn't go out cold,
like flat out.
He just got dropped off and came back.
He came back,
he was on s stanky leg,
like walker and he's gonna come on.
That fucker hit me.
I'm like,
just like,
like paul,
my gi about like,
he was saying that after you dropped
him.
Yeah.
He's,
he's a fucking nut.
I love it.
So I mean he's got a fucking now wasn't
a knock out as much as it was.
You just dropped him.
Yeah,
I dropped them to his.
I mean,
he,
his legs it,
I got back up and started saying,
come on motherfucker.
So he was conscious.
Right.
And he knew that he was staggering bro.
He looked like John Dotson had him on
skates again.
Is that honestly,
that's what I was like,
oh,
okay.
And he was like,
I'm not going to hit him.
You're fighting in two weeks out.
It wasn't like that,
but literally he had to say he fell
forward and he slipped.
I'm like,
do it doesn't matter.
Like I'm not going to stay anyone know?
And then I was showing danny how I like
steal because he likes overran rates
high like throw my head off the lane and
bring the right hand this and that book
was,
comes over and say,
dude,
he goes.
And it was on,
it was christmas day or something,
sparring film.
His own film was all inspiring.
He's watched you knocked tj and I was
like,
oh yeah.
I was like,
oh wait.
He's like,
oh,
I have it on my gopro.
I'm like,
oh,
that's cool.
And then nothing ever came about it.
And then tj was saying that he used to
make me cry and practice.
No,
I have cried and practice for
[inaudible].
This motherfucker jumped me on my head
before the almay to fight.
I was like super mad about it.
Favorite comes in,
has the camera crew,
the pierce labs and like we're going
hard and like don't show my head.
I'm like,
oh,
I get mad.
I'm like,
well,
you know,
I'm like trying not to get hurt before
the fight.
So like I've never cried.
Teetering there made me cry.
So I was like,
please be talking about making me cry.
Like,
oh man,
if I cried when you get dumped on your
head,
did you get concussed or something?
Or you get hurt more like sound like a
fair.
He's out.
He cried out saying favorite comes in
and just go ma,
I barely remember this.
I think it was happening.
First off,
here's the thing,
cody is a dangerous,
dangerous motherfucker if you're not on
your,
even if he's not trying to,
you get in fucking rocked or hurt or
whatever.
So I have to be on,
on a game with him.
Even if you go on light,
you know,
unless he's going to go light,
but light doesn't work when the guys
accurate and strong and everything else.
So we had to go.
So it was just like a,
like a wizard hip heist.
Lots me do that last year on my head
because you were coming after me.
He was like,
so I know now when there's a camera crew
fall in favor.
It's not light.
It's fucking to fight.
So I love that.
That's where that came from about the
video and like coming out like we have
the video,
you can get knocked out,
tj.
You didn't make it.
He was saying he made us beat us all up
like with the dominic sit down.
Dwayne was maybe saying that or
something.
He said,
oh god,
you beat your teammates.
And he's like,
yeah,
I actually for a matter of fact haven't
beaten them up.
I'm like,
I don't fall most of this stuff.
What are your.
What's your thoughts on sparring?
Like do you think that you should be
sparring hard or do you think you should
be sparring technical and pull back on
shots or do you think you should have a
little bit of both?
I think a little bit of both.
I think beginning of camp you get your,
your,
your rounds into where you're feeling
comfortable and then later on I can't be
your technique,
you know,
your,
your combos that you're working kind of
like flight simulation,
but get those rounds in because you're
not wanting to beat your body up closer
to the fight.
I want to feel fresh at the fight and I,
that's how I've always used.
I literally get 50 rounds of sparring,
start tapering off towards the end of
the end of the fight camp as it called
unboxing.
Really camp.
Do try to spar with only people that you
know,
so you didn't know that you can trust
them.
So you
know,
like especially obviously there's tj
fights,
a giant fight,
huge fight and it's going to be huge.
Not just for the division but for the
sport.
I mean all the major fans are going to
be paying attention to this fight.
Yeah,
definitely.
I'm safe with it now.
Like we were talking about,
I have all these fights log in.
Not even just all the street fights,
all the boxing matches,
the sparring work.
I don't need to spar as much,
but I need to.
We were respiring 10 rounds for the cruz
fight,
10 straight fives,
you know,
eight to 10 each week.
I'm like,
buckles is kinda,
you know,
it worked,
you know what I mean?
But we were doing smaller glove,
more mma based,
you know,
big gloves.
I mean me techniques thrown out the
window,
you know,
people just sprawl and brawl kind of
shit.
Like I liked small glove,
you know,
you're still pepper in the shots hitting
them,
but you're working the whole gang
takedowns submissions.
Right.
So I liked that.
And also fight simulations.
I like fight like having my uncle come
out,
pad holder,
justin's the other pat order for you
know.
And then danny j favor have Like four
different buyers rely on you as like a
fight there on next.
You know,
you're hitting pads and you get tackled
from behind.
You have to work up,
you know,
things like that.
It's safe,
you're not.
And that's typically what I like to do.
Yeah,
there is,
there is nothing like,
you know,
like,
like we talked about running,
sprinting,
blowing out the lungs,
etc.
There's nothing like actual,
like intense sparring to simulate what
it feels like in a fight though and it's
familiar as you get with it.
It still feels horrible when it happens.
Like I've been,
I've always been known as the
conditioning guy,
like I can condition and and like never
get tired,
etc.
Etc.
In fights,
you get tired.
It's about the poker face,
it's about being familiar with it.
It's about like you know these things
be.
Yeah,
being comfortable with that,
being comfortable with it.
So you have to get there sometimes and
it's just being smart about it.
yeah.
Cowboy doesn't spar anymore really?
Yeah.
Cowboys essentially does mostly drills
and pad work and simulations and stuff
like that and if he does sparkling,
these bars super light because he was
realizing that he was beating himself up
too much and training and coming into
fights like already kind of a little
soft soft but
hurt them for a week and that's what he
loved to do.
Fucking treadmill,
bike workouts and sparring pad work.
Nothing really else interested with
jesse.
Just love sparring,
doing all that.
So yeah,
he,
he's sparred hard though.
I mean he was jackson.
I heard he's a,
he's like a killer knocking dudes
allegation like a,
like a,
like a nasty
luck in sparring.
Sparring partner probably.
Maybe that's one of the reasons why I
stopped doing it.
Probably maybe all that stuff just.
I mean,
look,
you can't always be the hammer if you're
having those kind of a rock 'em sock,
'em robots barring sessions,
you're going to get tagged for sure.
Right?
Absolutely.
For me,
I like getting in those.
We just had saturday sparring with a lot
of it.
Yeah.
We had a killer's row of sparring going
on this last weekend,
10 round.
You've got to get those in.
Sometimes
it's,
he knows for me,
like I'd been out of it for a little
bit,
like just knowing that it's a couple
weeks,
knock the rest off,
you know,
that's why it feels good,
but you feel good about it.
Like your mom,
like we're going to go in here and fight
and fight the tj and I bring.
It's going to be.
I hope it's a phone booth,
you know,
I hope it,
standard trade.
Let's,
let's see.
I don't know how he's gonna you know,
because he knows my skills and knows
that I have,
you know,
lilly have gotten so much better since
then.
I was still getting the better of him
and I'm not saying this to toot my own
horn or whatever.
It's the gym.
But you're as competitive as he isn't
competitive.
I am.
You're not going to give an edge in
practice.
I don't give them an edge of practice.
Favorite takes me down.
We're going again.
You know,
it was vice versa.
I'd take favorite down like oh it's
overtime we go 40 minutes after.
Sometimes it's like this guy's one of
the hardest guys a break because he's
just obviously too dumb to know he tired
or stopped going.
Like someone like we were just talking
about that and now he's retired.
So he comes in like these guys are like,
fresh off is all fresh,
but it comes in like,
this guy's retired like fuck favorite
man,
this guy is breaking these younger dudes
that are killers themselves because he
just has that mentality.
It's a different breed.
And that's what I'm like.
I said tj,
he's that breed.
He is at that point,
you know,
he's an alpha male guy.
And fortunately for me,
I feel like you could ever reckoned in
style or do you feel like he's crossed
the line into some weird sort of area?
Right.
Did so much defending of that guy
because of,
you know,
whatever his thing is here and this and
that.
And I have a lot of great friends that
are newer.
I mean like cody's newer in my life,
but we've got a bond.
I've got friends that I've had since I
was like kindergarten and before
kindergarten and drawing up together,
you know,
in my community in like I've got great
groups of friends.
So it's like,
I mean I can reconcile whatever just
stopped lying about what actually
happened to save your face is like I'd
never kicked the guy off of a team or
anything and then he gets a one
opportunity on national television to
say something about me.
That's my only qualm with the guy.
I didn't like dwayne because of the
things that he had done.
But tj and I will always work
because work is that people making the
weirdest things about running a jam and
running a camp is a,
you kind of have to manage,
you have to be like a psychologist.
Personality did.
A lot of fighters are prima donnas and
you do not just a trainer,
not just a teammate but you also a
psychologist and some sort of a
counseling
be glue.
Which and when I,
I honestly,
I'm just learning this more and more
when I stepped out of the,
the area too much.
It's like,
I mean I have to come back in and put
out fires and bring everyone back
together.
And that's,
I would say that's one of my skills is,
is getting along with people and making
things mesh and in finding a culture and
building like a healthy environment and
that can get tweaked so easily.
It's crazy.
It's cancer.
Yeah.
And now jUstin buchholz is your main
trainer now,
right?
He's like,
yeah,
we.
Well,
we've gone to now is we have,
we have like a whole staff of main
trainers because we have so many fires.
I mean we just had sage northcutt yeah,
year rodriguez and Sarah Mcmahon or in
the gym right now.
and,
and uh,
you know,
rick glen is about to go and he's a new
guy to the team and we've got,
you know,
darren elkins,
so we have different guys.
Like danny castillo is a head coach,
chris holders,
the head coach,
coach joey rodriguez as a head coach.
Danny castillo is a head coach.
We have fabio prado who's a coach,
a dustin bari,
and those guys have been with us for 14
years,
13 years.
And I'm,
I'm in a lead position as a coach.
I run,
I run practices and oversee things and
coordinate things.
So it's a,
it's a big co op and different people
have different coaches that are like
their main gig and you know,
different
is still fairly young too.
Right.
Hold justin.
So 34.
Yeah,
he's 35 I think.
Is he completely done competing?
That's a great question.
You never know with,
with the fight game,
you know what I mean?
It only takes a yes to be back in the
fight game.
But yeah,
sometimes guys when they coach they also
feel like they're getting better because
they understand things more.
You see that a lot with jujitsu
competitors or at times coaching makes
them a better fighter.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
I don't know if they'll,
if they'll come back,
but I mean what we've got is a great co
op and it's always a struggle to keep
things because there's going to be
cliques,
there's going to be the potheads and the
nerds and the fucking
jocks and like,
you know,
whatever can dope.
Are you enjoying it still all these
years in the game?
Did it.
You know what I,
you know what it is.
It was awesome.
I went to Mexico city and I miss chad's
wedding to go and chad's my boy.
I love chatting,
love abby,
his wife,
and it was,
I know I miss a great time,
but I got to go corner.
Joseph miralis,
who's been with me since he isn't,
he's the oldest member of our team.
Wow.
He's been with us the longest and he's,
he's nine years old when he started with
us,
that's crazy.
And he,
you know,
like danny castillo is,
it was me and danny castillo and our
coach joey in his corner and danny was
getting all teared up like we all got
teared up right before the fight,
like we brought it in and everyone's
kinda crying and everything.
And like joseph,
I mean,
he's been through his struggles.
I went when he was going through a hard
time,
I took him to the front row of a,
you know,
the ufc and,
and just,
you know,
putting right there and let them
visualize.
and so that's,
that's the stuff I enjoy
now.
Uh,
you guys had your ear and camp?
Huh?
What else?
What a crazy animal house right now.
He's all by himself and big old house.
What a crazy style.
That guy's couch,
dude,
he's telling is a really talented guy.
Weird style to ryan like that.
Taekwondo based.
Yeah.
Kicking and wild shit.
Like when he hit bj penn with a
threesixty roundhouse kick to the face.
Like go.
Okay.
Yeah,
he's crazy.
it's crazy.
Yeah.
That's a good range.
Even said that he's hands,
you know,
I'm not so good with the range and like
knowing like my kicks,
I'm real accurate with his kicks and he
says I kick harder and stuff.
I think that he feels like he's more
accurate with this ass kicks
and he is with his hands
quinces if he's not doing it with
someone who's also a great kicker,
you know,
because he's able to operate in a range
where he's pretty effective and most
people aren't.
Yeah.
So he's a long kIcker too.
Has been staying.
He's been staying at my house the last
like week and it's,
I'm getting to know him a lot.
I mean,
what a cool dude.
I mean that guy is very smart,
very smart.
Is like well put together.
He's,
I got to hear a little bit about like
the townies from chihuahua in Mexico and
like it's a pretty,
pretty scary place and in kind of his
journey as a,
as a young kid is one of the top karate
guys in Mexico,
so he's been a competItor for a long
time.
Used to have a coach that used to like
hit him with a stick.
So they left that place and the guy
called him back and was like,
can you please come back and I won't hit
you with it?
Yeah.
What he was like seven and eight.
Well,
jesus christ,
he's been,
uh,
he's been in a combat sport
for awhile.
Yeah,
I think that frankie edgar fight was a
very tough fight for him,
but a good fight as far as a learning
experience and a lot of people had said
that.
And I was one of the ones that said it,
like we'll see what happens when he
fights a great wrestler.
Right.
That's going to be the real issue with
him because he's got all this wild
kicking stuff,
but that stuff doesn't work if somebody
grabs a hold of you.
Right.
And if somebody.
Frank frank.
Yeah.
Frank at a different level of guys.
He's a great mixing it together.
So yeah,
a year hIs wrestling because I got to
wrestle in the other.
He actually post a little video of us
wrestling,
but his wrestling is good.
It's just like connor connor's wrestling
or boxing is really good.
It's just not floyd mayweather.
Good.
Right in the later rounds,
you know,
so like,
yeah,
years made a lot of gains he wouldn't
share with izzy,
izzy,
Israel martinez who put him through like
uh,
you know,
he's a great coach.
Israel.
Very good.
And he uh,
he put them through a,
like a whole year of wrestling.
So his wrestling is top notch,
but it's not,
you know,
it needs to get to another break,
jaeger level when you're a little bit
fatigued and you make a small mistake
and the guy can capitalize,
but it's getting there.
No.
Yeah,
It's uh,
it's interesting.
You see so many different approaches and
his approach is very unique and it's one
of the things that's exciting about him
is that he's got that crazy wild kicking
style.
Yeah.
Throw everything.
A torpedo kicks all kinds of shit.
Yeah.
that's the guy I to mix up with because
you don't see too many of those guys,
but once you run into him,
right?
Yeah.
You better get it right.
Fine.
It's good to watch him and feeling we're
trying,
you know,
he,
he got a win over feely,
but like he felt like,
ah man,
I was in that fight.
He just got caught.
He got popped in the orbital and then
got like couldn't see and get switch
kick to the dome.
And so fuel is like,
man,
it's fun to watch these guys come full
circle,
like,
like b be feeling now they're chaining
together in,
in working together a little bit.
And then darren elkins lost to Chad and
darren elkins came to see us and and
he's been on like a six by eight win
streak.
That guy's frigging jam
dude on
back to it because one of the craziest
moments have ever seen the guy getting
his ass kicked for every fucking second
of the first couple rounds and they
finally gets a hold of them,
damn.
Beats them down and chaos and then just
screams like all like a demon covered in
blood.
I was sitting there,
I left during the second round.
I was like,
man,
I can't watch this.
Like I don't like watch my friends.
Then.
Especially when it's shit like that
happens.
I'm like,
I walked out,
the next thing you know,
the place goes nuts and I see elkins
knocked him out.
I was like,
cool.
I like it.
That kid,
you got to honestly stop elkins.
You have to knock them off.
Yeah,
for sure.
I mean,
tough elkins is the,
the like the pillar of consistency.
He's always in the.
He's always at every practice listens to
every coach.
He'd going hard.
We have these two and brothers that come
in there.
They're from chechnya.
They're really talented guys.
I'm actually going to go corner to the
guys over in Ukraine,
but uh,
there are super skilled fighters but
don't have that drive and like we have
here and so they keep popping him,
boom,
boom.
And then d and then they keep tryIng to
call time out and they catch him with a
couple of things in elkins chased now
they go,
oh you are,
you're not taking the time.
l oh,
grabs the guy.
Why did they try to take time?
Because they get tired of that shit.
Don't be pop,
pop.
Just flap his head.
I'll fly back,
boom.
Hit them there and kick him in the leg.
And he's lIke,
he's like,
he got,
catches him with something and like
grabs like time,
timeouts that man.
He's like,
oh fuck that motherfucker no time now
because it's a grinder
great against dennis bermudez.
That's a big win,
a big win and he looks smooth and that's
fine.
He didn't take as much damage,
the names of damage for a reason because
he gets somebody to also like the way
his.
He's moving looks better ways.
Kicking and punching his combinations.
He looks like he's got less extra steps.
It's like this all smoothness and his
transitions in his movement.
That's what I've been working on in.
Go ahead and I think a lot of that has
to do with obviously working the
footwork,
like these guys,
some of these guys that are straight
wrestlers and then like,
all right,
we're going to wrestle and throw punches
and try to take you down.
But your footwork is the core of
everything.
Yeah,
you can have throw good hands,
but if your feet are out of position or
getting taken down,
you know you're.
You're not gonna land power punches.
So the footwork,
I,
I religiously work on footwork daily.
Like this will work.
That's dominant.
I mean that is his entire thing is his
ability to move.
It's just so unusual as footwork.
So we're.
That's one of the things where you went
toe for toe for toe to toe with them
when you're,
your footwork was equally as good as his
is not better and you were landing
harder.
Combination
for us to master tang was all about
footwork and biomechanics and he's back
in Thailand now and then that's been
passed on to our next generation of
coaches from.
He moved back.
He did move back after 11 years.
Why did he decide to back to silent?
Became
a monk for a day.
It came up for a day because because his
parents had died,
if you don't go and live in the
monastery for within a year and a half
after he hadn't seen his son in 11 years
since sentras for.
And he,
I mean he spent all his time facetiming
with his family and he wasn't
necessarily allowed back in the.
He went and he went back,
he stuck back.
He wasn't allowed pack.
How come?
Illegal.
Oh,
oh.
So he couldn't come back to America if
you went back to Thailand?
Yeah.
so when he was gone,
he was gone because he overstayed a
visa.
So he,
uh,
yeah.
So that's one universal.
When you saw tj dillashaw my corner in
Canada,
that's because master tom couldn't go to
Canada and tj knew everything.
Every single thing that,
that,
that mastered tongue,
like knew all his,
his stuff,
get a hold mitts,
but he was all about that now.
Which,
see,
that's what's great about having all
these coaches like justin buckles,
he knows,
he knows master tongs style.
He knows my style.
He knows,
uh,
every coach you've ever had In their
dwayne style.
He knows,
you know,
anybody.
Dimitri [inaudible],
dimitri made dominic style.
Anybody that's been in here,
he knows bob,
bob's my uncle bob's style.
And so you get a guy like darren elkins,
it needs to work on that striking and we
put them with justin buckles and you
know,
with the cumulative part of the team,
it works wonders and then you get a guy
like,
yeah,
a year who comes in with this striking
background and now we've got all these
different attributes or like a sage
northcutt who's with us right now that
guys,
hey,
let's take a moment to acknowledge sage.
NortHcutt is the nicest guy in the
planet.
Yeah,
definitely.
Like the nicest dude on the planet.
I got into the ufc too quick,
just like a little bit,
but it doesn't matter.
I super talented and was looking really
good in some small organizations,
but really didn't have a complete game
yet.
I'm going to tell you,
he learns really,
really fast.
I always mess.
I was a mess with cody.
I was getting this kind of like,
man,
sage lillian's a lot faster than you.
It's not really the case.
I just like to fuck with this guy.
But a dozen st mark's sister.
That's her karate competitor.
GotcHa.
Yep.
She just shook her first fight and she
lost.
Uh,
but she,
she,
she asked some potential too.
That's interesting.
So he's a,
he's a fun case,
you know,
because he's got that weIrd karate style
super fast too though.
I mean you would know it but he's got a
little mean streak and he's,
he's,
he's got all the knowledge like
everybody because he's nice.
Everybody wants to help the guy and he
is so nice.
It was just like,
oh thank you.
Like just like learn from whoever tells
them,
you know,
calls me,
mr.
Favre.
Mr.
Favor now when you guys do a camp,
lIke say you training for tj,
who organizes your camp?
Like how do you organize your strength
and conditioning routine?
How do you organize,
like what are you going to do that day
or
do you do a base on how you feel like
who is,
who is the coordinator?
Myself,
basically I kinda,
yeah,
that's what we do.
Like favorite always would preach about.
It's a lifestyle change.
Like if you need to do this much work
you needed to do wrestling,
get get guys on the team and wrestle.
So I'll figure out what I need to do.
Especially for this fight with tj.
I know the specific work that I need,
combos,
what he throws,
what he likes to do,
it vice versa.
So I get with all my coaches like,
hey,
I would like to have this much work with
chris personally as much work with
motion and movement with favor pad work.
I'm uncle come out and do pad work as
well.
and then I get with my strength
conditioning coach from going three
times a week,
usually one heavy day to like movement,
foot work,
you know,
Greece in the body.
Uh,
so It's just always like usually on that
sunday and we're like,
hey,
we lay it out,
lay it out,
lay it out.
So will you lay out the whole week of
events?
So like when you have a heavy day,
say if you ever like a rock 'em sock 'em
robots day the next day.
Do you like to do like a yoga stretch
out,
do movement,
hit pads?
Like how do,
how do you work?
Okay.
I usually go sunday is kind of like a,
uh,
what do you call it?
Like a shakeout kind of active rest.
We're moving to that felt wherever.
yeah.
Yeah.
So I don't feel like garbage on monday.
Monday we hit it hard and usually
morning practice or pad works in the
afternoon.
Then jujitsu,
so it's usually three on mondays and
tuesdays I usually just wrestle and
maybe do some pad work because I like to
kind of be rested for sparring,
sparring.
So a lot of swearIng on wednesday.
And then I'll usually do a strength
conditioning workout after sparring.
And on thursdays usually when I like no
Impact day,
I usually kind of like,
it's wrestling.
Sometimes I'll go in there and just
wrestle.
If I feel good,
I'll drill.
I won't go live and then I'll do like
yoga or more.
My hyperbaric chambers have to go.
I had to go towards the end of the week
after the sparring because friday's a
intimate practice.
so it's like everything.
It's you're doing sparring and they are
doing the grappling.
So is this trial and error that's led
you to this schedule that gives you like
the thought to take thursday light and
then go hard on friday?
Monday.
HArd sunday light?
Yeah.
This is what has worked for me since I
said like I came out here.
Literally I was in,
I was doing my own strength conditioning
before I came out to team alpha male and
I was hitting pads is my uncle and I go
in and inspire.
I wouldn't even,
it may,
I would do boxing would take downs.
That's all we do because a lot of the
boxers I was with russell or you know
what I mean?
So they would do,
we would just do the boxing.
So we need do the boxes didn't want
kicked.
Right.
So we're just doing that.
I get my work and I was working with pos
battle for a lot of these boxers and
cleveland and pittsburgh and I finally
came out here and these guys had it
like,
man,
a system,
a system like wrestling system.
That's what I do so well beCause they do
the drilling.
You start out with this,
we're going to go wrestling and then
we're going to go in the clinch back to
strikes fit into like,
hey,
it's goes from this structure.
Yeah.
So I didn't,
I never knew knew any of that.
Like first time I really change your
jitsu was out here,
like learning it and like blended
together.
I always said I was a good athlete,
a good wrestler,
good fight.
A good boxer by I my own news style here
with like going and doing really the
first year that I was here I was just
training like for like,
yeah,
he actually told me,
he's like,
bro,
this is like a little,
you know,
we had to tone it back a little bit.
Which like I said,
we have.
The team was built on overtraining.
It was like I didn't take a vacation for
seven years when I started fighting.
I mean I never took vacations growing up
either.
We didn't have money.
It wasn't like something that we did,
so I'm not like used to like,
oh,
we're taking a vacation,
but like seven years I didn't take a
vacation.
And so it was like this grind,
grind,
and everybody's kind of keeping up and
we've,
we've shifted and gotten smarter and
have more input and etc.
Etc.
But the bottom line for me is this,
we have a lot of advisors,
right?
And I like it.
Sage northcutts a great example.
He can,
he'll,
he'll listen to whoever's talking to him
and like people want to talk to them all
the time and tell him what to do.
Right?
So like there's advise,
there's an advisory,
like we say,
hey,
this is the coaches and I think that you
need to do this and we need to do that.
But you have to be,
especially at a high level like this,
you have to be a thermometer for your
own,
for your own stuff as well.
So we have set practices throughout the
day,
but if you're feeling way too beat up,
you know,
because we're not worried about guys not
showing up to practice because they're
lazy.
We have the best athletes in the world,
the rIght mentality.
We trusted the mentality and the and the
purposes they're in.
Right?
So if you're feeling too much,
you got to let us know and we'll take a
little back and do it there.
And so this is kind of what we found
for,
for him as well.
No,
when you're scheduling everything
yourself,
like there's two schools of thought on
that.
There's one school of thought that says
someone should be overseeing everything
for you.
So you're not
telling you what to do.
Scheduling is one thing,
but what's your scheduling?
Scheduling something with a coach.
He's got a strength and conditioning and
a physical therapists that are making.
Taking that part of his thing.
He's got,
you know,
us as head coaches over looking saying
hey,
we need to make sure that you're getting
your,
you know,
this end.
But there's coaches every single time
for that.
It's not like you're just on your own
doing your course.
Right.
Some people do do it that way.
Some people like to do everything on
their own,
which is interesting.
Some people would just like to be told
what to do.
Just you're going to do this.
Exactly.
Yeah,
but that.
That goes away.
Which ones somebody fucks you up.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Like my,
my australian positionIng coaches,
pt coaches with my mma coach,
they're all in like coordinates like,
okay,
we went heavy with this.
We should ease back this,
maybe do this many rounds.
So,
but that's just started doing that.
I think for the cruise by the first time
we were a heart rate monitor and try to
track where my heart rate was at.
Was getting up high in the 80
[inaudible] trying to bring it back
down.
That's the first time I ever done that
because what you what?
So like when you're doing that,
are you doing that for strength and
conditioning?
Are you doing that?
Holding paths,
like how you that that was literally we
would throw for a 90 seconds.
We would throw.
We do it for six rounds.
I would throw the same combo.
We had three or four different combos
that we'd throw for 90 seconds and just
keep the input up,
blah,
blah.
Ba ba ba bump ba bump,
four or five punch cabo with affairs,
with the kick or wherever the heart
rate's,
get checked and then you wait until it
gets down to what before you go again.
And then I think You would have 1:40
or something.
I was going to down I think lower than
that one.
Ads.
So we do that time.
Have you've given yourself in recovery
times in between?
In between rounds.
I,
I like to do 45 seconds because you
think middle thing for 45 seconds I got
another 15 seconds of you know,
recovering well usually you feel good at
30,
like I'm good.
I got 30 more seconds to to put it the
45 and like in the fight you're like,
well because that that meant it goes
fast as hell,
right?
Next thing you know,
you're talking to your coaches,
you got your bell rung,
get stitched her,
your eyes fixed,
and they back up there.
So it's like 45 seconds.
Let's keep going because that here you
are,
you're 25,
right?
Twenty six,
2016 champion of the world.
When you look at your future,
you look at your,
like your potential future in the sport.
I mean you could be a gigantic fucking
superstar.
You have the world is your oyster,
right?
Like how do you,
how do you plan on,
do you,
do you have like this sort of a master
plan for your career?
You know,
what my goal is so long to be the world
champion and I grind and towards the
head that go,
I got that goal and I accomplished that.
And then it was boom,
right into the ultimate fighter boom
injury boomed,
fight postponed.
So I was like,
I haven't been able to really,
really sat down because it's like,
well,
you know,
when you're in training,
you're focused on something.
For me,
I'm a creature of habit.
I like routine.
Um,
so we have just recently now sat down
and like we've said about it,
you know,
everyone can win the championship,
everyone can be a world title to what
you do at the title.
Now I've set these goals to build my
legacy,
you know,
to start going on and who knows,
who knows what can happen in a year or
so because I didn't think I was going to
be injured,
you know,
I never thought I'd be out this long,
that this is the most tiny time of my
life because I couldn't do something
that I love to do.
And been in pain.
Injured.
How long have you been injured?
For many years.
It's been since junior year I started
having back problems from football and
yeah.
So ball on and off.
Yeah.
Fucking football.
Fuck.
So what apple says all the time,
all the time.
That damn foosball.
And so I've,
I've dealt it but progressive.
It was the henry is fight was the fight
that I almost pulled out of that fight
was the first five report besides
obviously tj had to postpone it.
Um,
I couldn't walk,
but sean shelby a gathered window maddix
and our story and that he wanted to
walk,
so I just told them and my back was
really bad.
Then I'm,
so that's when it really started to come
on.
And then I didn't fight for after the
henry fight and flight for nine months,
10 months.
And then I got the usi kept booking me.
I fought augusta mendez was supposed to
fight,
um,
other brazilian linacre.
He got sick the week of the fight
replacement and then fight hand in
almeda and then it was ms dot
[inaudible].
Then it was crew.
So I didn't have time to be like really?
I just dealt with the pain,
like there was times where I would take
two weeks off of like really training,
doing anything or it would switch side
and my left side or my right side.
So I always go south.
Paul until that side started messing up.
I switched back to orthodox.
Like it was a lot of like sometimes
working around working around it
[inaudible] I had to because I get my
money right for that regina king
procedure.
And how did that go?
You know,
what,
it felt good.
I feLt like It took the,
you know,
inflammation inflammation away so it
stopped like locking up and sitting the
shop,
you know,
the shocks down my leg.
Um,
but still I was,
I've been doing rehab since and I've
been doing rehab one day,
wednesday and friday and obviously on
tuesday,
thursday do lifting.
So I've been doing rehab and getting to
because I feel like a better athlete,
I'm moving more.
But still it's like from being
constantly wrestling,
sansar,
boxing stance,
being like that now I really pride
myself open and it's the muscles around
it are still,
you know,
I just had a little scare a couple weeks
ago.
We're good,
you know,
we're moving on from that.
I feel way better.
My back backfields way stronger.
Um,
I wasn't aBle to fight July 8th,
like there's no way.
Uh,
we try to get optimistic about it.
Going to Germany and thinking that was
going to heal miracle miracle,
miracle shots.
And maybe would have been if you took
more time off or time off thing.
It's like you're a pro athlete,
so like you're not just having these
procedures and then taking a long time
to recover,
you're having these procedures and then
trying to get back to training and
pretty quick literally like,
you know,
I had that fight so it was literally
seven weeks out from when I had the
first stem.
So,
and then I take a month off,
take four weeks off and then two weeks
of trying to solve leaves me with a week
and a half to train for my title fight.
Like you guys understand that it's
insane and that doesn't even make sense.
So you are a October 7th is the fight,
right?
November fourth,
November 4th.
Madison square.
Oh,
that's right.
why the fuck that?
I think.
Okay.
That makes that stuff.
That makes it hard,
I guess.
I mean I got hit by a couple of news
outlets.
I was fighting october.
I'm like,
yeah,
that's the vegas vegas card.
Who's on that card?
Who is Kevin Lee?
I think that sort of ferguson.
Kevin lee for the interim.
One hundred 55 pound title.
Yeah.
That whole interim thing is so crazy
right?
They Just sort of randomly decide when
they're going to have that title,
how they do that.
I remember dominick cruz had it for a
long time and they let him keep it for a
long time and there's some guys they
just like,
all right,
you're done.
That's what I was with the whole thing
that I said,
I'm not rushing back.
If you guys want to make an interim
title or take the title from me,
that's fine.
I'm 25 years.
I'm going to.
I'm going to get the title back.
I got it here.
I'm going to get it back if that's where
it happened.
So I didn't want anyone to sit,
you know,
tj wanted to go down fighting dj because
that was my thing.
I texted john and dan [inaudible] I can
make 25.
That was my whole game plan was to fight
tj July 8th and I got her pull out and
it was going to fight
dj a massive.
So regarding.
So I was always in my mind was going to
fight in november,
massive square garden.
It just a different opponent.
Well somebody's gotta fight dj.
I was kinda bummed out that demetrius
decided not to fight tj our video.
I'd never even knew that was an option
just to be like,
I'm not going to fight.
Well,
he said,
and I guess his mindset is that he's one
fight away from breaking the record of
the most title defenses ever.
And if tj being down,
being able to beat up anyone in the
world and your weight.
Yes.
Which is the important thing to think
about there.
Yes it is,
but if he lost a tj and tj didn't make
the weight,
it would fuck them up.
Like if tj decided not to,
if he couldn't make the weight.
It's a lot of ifs.
There's a lot of assets a lot.
So he wanted tj to fight one time I
would make sure you can make the and
then fight them.
I guess it makes sense,
but the other thought processes your,
the pound for pound best fighter on the
planet.
You should be fighting the best fight
that you can get and that's a really
good fight.
It's like no one's floyd didn't make
sure economy gregory could make the
weight.
No,
they just booked the fight and the light
on them as a professional,
and jon jones wouldn't fight shale
though.
That's because he hated shale though.
That was part of part of it.
It was like,
fuck this guy.
This guy might have a possibility of
beating me.
He goes,
no,
I'll,
I'll do this through a real camp.
And he goes,
I'm not going to come in here and take
this on short notice.
I don't know man.
I mean he took the osp fight on short
notice and it wasn't his best fight.
You know,
he sort of prides himself on having a
long game plan and that's his mentality
to man,
this whole thing is so depressing with
john.
Apparently we're gonna find out soon
what's going to happen with the b
sample,
you know,
but if the b sample test positive as
well,
he's kind of doomed.
This is doing what,
what would be three or four years,
four years.
Let that belief.
I mean obviously I'm not the fucking
athletic commissioner.
You saw it or whoever calls it out,
but I think the first one was what?
Well,
the first one was an out of competent.
No,
the first one was a tainted supplement
and they gave him a year.
Right?
Didn't it give me a year for the dick
pills.
So was it really dick pills?
So it was the other test to the pills
blockers.
They put those in these estrogen.
In these messages.
Gas station dick pills.
Yeah,
because they make you excited.
They block your estrogen,
fill you up with.
I mean look,
they could put whatever the fuck they
want in those things is trying to get
your dick hard.
Not.
They're not thInking that a world class
world champion professional athletes
taken me of 11 gets he's a maniac.
But don't you think though,
I mean this is what I've always said,
that world class fighters,
like professional fighters are not like
any other athlete because they're
fucking reckless.
They're wild motherfuckers like cowboy
like you.
Like a lot of guys,
they are impulsive,
reckless risk taking people.
Oh,
you know,
I don't know.
I mean,
I guess I guess disciplined for sure.
I mean a professional cali kid,
you know,
you're,
you're definitely different.
But there's a lot of different guys in
the sport,
you know,
that have,
different personalities,
but a lot of fighters,
it's a big percentage that are wild.
And john's fucking wild.
Like if you want to get a wild
motherfucker like john who opens up his
fight at 23 years old fighting shogun
for the world title with a flying knee
against shogun.
I mean that's how I opened the fight.
That's,
that's a wild impulsive dude.
He just go,
feels it and goes with it.
Flow state.
Yeah.
And feels like pop them gas station dick
pills,
just like,
let's just do these red lining that all
the time.
There's no like,
well,
I mean he had all the excuses,
you know,
the cocaine was just partying.
The dick pills.
That's more of the same.
now this one though is a different
thing.
This is an actual.
He's not saying anything.
No one's saying no,
no official statement.
Talk to my lawyer.
Yeah.
I mean they're saying they didn't do
anything,
you know,
that would Be the most fucked up thing
in the world if somebody slipped some
shit into your water.
You know,
just to get you to test positive,
but you got to watch everything you
fucking eat.
I mean,
you always have to think.
People definitely do double cross
people.
Definitely in this world,
there's somebody who would absolutely
put something tainted in your food.
All they have to do is sprinkle a little
bit,
a little bit of it in a dish of food.
You wouldn't even notice it.
I made you really think that's what
happened.
I don't think anything.
I don't know anything.
I wonder.
I mean that's true though.
I mean they're so fucking evil people
out there.
That's one thing I've learned is getting
older is like just being a nice guy.
You assume everyone's nice and good and
it's like there's some creepy negative
people out there
there.
Man.
It's beautiful when you find nice people
because of that though,
it balances it out.
So when you know people that you can
trust that really are your brother,
that's like,
that makes it all the more it'll give.
Everybody was cool.
You wouldn't necessarily appreciate cool
people as much.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
I mean that'd be good
everywhere.
Whereas all the dishes get mad.
I need an enemy.
That is.
Have you ever fought somebody that you
really liked?
I thought a bunch of guys.
Who'd you fight that you really liked?
Your.
I liked?
Uh,
charlie valencia.
Brian bowls.
I like scotty jorgensen.
I liked eddie wineland.
You're friends with those guys.
Michael mcdonald.
I was friends with all this guy's weird,
right?
I could say probably one who ms dot
gawky just because he didn't speak
english,
but honestly I was like,
man,
he's like,
but cody from the get go.
He goes,
hey man,
I know you're cool to your opponents.
Everything.
BUt I like,
I like intensity.
I like if I,
like people say that he's got a temper
everything and he's like,
yeah,
it's,
he's fighting this guy.
He's getting that mentality.
That's part of what he liked.
My thing is I will either you whip your
ass,
whip my ass.
I'm always going To show you respect
after like,
hey,
you know,
it's good.
I remembered that when I got signed,
I fought marcus image and
I don't like shaking my opponent's hand
before the fight.
I never liked that.
I never liked glove touching any of that
in markets.
We,
I saw him a couple times in the hotel.
He's like,
what's up man?
Like,
I got it.
Cool man.
Good to see you saturday.
You know what I mean?
And I taught them before weigh ins.
I was like,
hey,
you know,
go on stage.
Like,
hey,
I don't want to shake your hand out
there.
Don't make me look like a dick.
Like if I go to shit,
you know,
it's cool.
It's cool.
Yeah,
right on w w I said I got respect for
you.
I promise show and I'm like walking
away.
I'm like all right.
Any like shook his hand out there.
And I was like in my mind like it was.
Oh.
So I shook it again.
And recalling back to buckle's was like,
he got me again with the handshake.
I didn't even realize exactly.
It puts us on to come up and be like,
hey,
I don't want to shake your hand,
let's fight.
But how about the throat bridge against
tourists and against no love man,
because he wears that thing where that's
our goal.
So what are you doing?
You're the video game.
The,
um,
the post fight press conference.
Uh,
I had a lot of respect for dominick
cruz.
The way you handled that.
He just,
he didn't know excuses,
like took it like a man.
So he was a Better man.
He beat me.
I got no excuses.
there's nothing I could say.
Yeah,
for sure.
No,
definitely we've had our differences and
still might not.
He still has me blocked on instagram and
twitter,
but man,
top sheet on my wife's a photo and then
blocked me.
I'm like,
this motherfucker that shit up.
you blocked me.
Like trying to be cool to do an
interview in it.
Don was trying to needle cody cody's
like this.
I didn't even know what was going on,
what was happening.
I was doing the fox for the ultimate
fighter.
It was obviously karen.
Brian asked about me grabbing teacher by
his throat.
Like,
yeah,
he goes anD me and dominic got into a
altercation at wayne's at two.
OH seven.
I come out.
I'm just waiting.
I had my hands full with all the
paperwork bullshit they give us.
And george gave me all these waters and
refuel stuff,
so I come out of the door and I crossed
paths with dava quite didn't know,
didn't even register with him,
but I might prefer you.
I catch something and I kinD of like
turned back around and He was like,
had these sunglasses on,
like these big chicken sunglasses.
Yeah.
Split up news like kicked out of you
skinny little motherfucker.
And I was like,
oh.
I was like,
dude,
we're fighting tomorrow man.
I was like,
so good.
I was just laughing,
like really?
Like he wants to do it now.
The first time we saw each other a day
before we were in this split room,
this,
this much or we're talking shit to each
other on a camera.
I'm like,
well we can't do like sit down and
obviously like that he has Jeremy
Stevens in there and I'm like man he got
in.
Steve's a good little boy,
like talking,
like just riding off of dom's hype or
off is off don.
LIke he brought in a self proclaimed
savage and Jeremy Stevens like to
counterbalance that I was portraying to
be a savage.
That's what he kept saying.
I'm like,
like I was like,
I'll come over back.
Both of you guys right now,
took my earpiece off.
I ran through the securIty and then he
was saying I was throwing shit.
It just the whole buildup.
So we finally saw each.
I was like,
man,
it was,
I got beat your ass tomorrow.
Like walk it off like I to just hide it.
and I see Jeremy Stevens,
ray,
he's all puffed up.
He's like,
you're too small little dude.
give me one of your teammates.
And I was like,
I dropped all my shit and get ready to
hit.
I'm like,
man,
I'll leave.
My manager comes out of nowhere,
swoops jeremy up.
But he grabbed me like he like scratched
my neck,
had a big scratch on it from his nails a
little bit now.
And like,
so it was that.
And then,
uh,
that whole car.
So he gets on skype or not skype.
Fox sports is about to do an interview
Interview about the situation of tough.
Karen brian asked that and he goes,
he said,
come.
He's like,
hey,
just a little dick.
You know,
he just,
you know,
whatever,
you can respect him for what he did and
he,
because he knows that I always said that
he knew what he had to do in that media
for people not to hate him.
You know,
look how connor and raley sometimes they
will change a little bit after he lost
he,
he took us home a pine,
a respect them for that.
But I knew deep down that wasn't turmoil
in their exact.
It has to be a dance all over his ass.
You know what I mean?
He's a great fighter.
I embarrassed him,
you know,
saturDay really go.
Oh.
So I come on and I'm split.
Coolest.
Cool.
I respect Him.
Like,
hey,
hat's off.
Get a tough,
tough dude.
We talked after.
I was like,
yeah,
that guy's tough.
Like I'll been pictured in this and
would come on and say hey,
you're getting joined with dominic.
And I'm like,
oh cool.
Like that's cool.
Like,
like it has to be brief that we're
professionals.
Like okay.
So iT goes on about things like,
yeah.
Have you ever been choked up at wayans?
And if so,
what would you do?
And I'm like,
really thinking about this.
I'm like,
well,
you know,
hopefully that will be professional
enough to keep my composure and know
that I'm going to whip this dude's ass
tomorrow.
And then he was like,
huh?
Like just being a smart ass.
And he was like,
oh,
he'S sick.
So he didn't mean to tell me you never
been choked up.
And that dawned on me,
I was like,
oh,
are you talking about when you brought
your self proclaimed hype man in and
scratch my,
my neck with his little bitch now?
and he's like,
no,
no.
I was like,
hey dominic.
I said,
what happened in the fight?
I danced around you and beat your ass
and made you look like a fool.
I said,
sit behind a desk and shut up.
And then it was like this that go on
skype.
Just as old as a private conversation.
Private conversations goes black screen,
the producers come on,
we're like,
we're sorry how dominic was acting like,
I don't mind coming on here and doing
this shit,
but I.
The first thing I said,
hey dominic,
how are you?
And I was like,
oh,
just waiting for dominic's and say hi.
And he started off.
He goes,
I don't get to say hi to you,
I'm talking to you in a couple of
minutes.
and I was like,
oh god,
what the fuck you guys are probably
going to fight again if tom stays in the
game.
So we had to redo the whole sItuation
and he just sitting there like,
you know,
because I was like,
man,
that's cool.
So that's why I wanted the rematch with
them.
so honestly tj should thank don for not
taking the rematch and finally getting
his shot.
So that's why after the fight.
So tj tom Doing these days,
you know,
I know he has plantar fasciitis,
got some serious issues with his feet
because he came back real quick after
the knee surgery anD maybe pushed it a
little too hard.
That's a,
that's a tough one.
I mean tHat's why his feet were all
taped up.
He's doing a lot of commentary on.
Yeah,
I'm probably getting decent manager that
I talked to his coach.
They're going to try to get,
you know,
we didn't win,
it was scheduled,
but he was trying to fight on the same
cart or around about.
So it keeps in the transition.
Who do you think would be a good fight
for him to fight for?
Dominic?
It's a good question.
WIthout a riviera.
Very good fight.
But I think doesn't he?
Doesn't jimmy have a fight?
He just beat the dude that you knocked
out.
Oh,
he alomeda he'd be,
he'd be out.
Dropped him a couple times.
That was.
Yeah,
it was a very good fight.
That's already beat it.
I made it,
but I feel like he has another fight
lined up.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe it was.
I'm thinking of um,
you know,
the day Before the fight,
like hype before the fight is always so
interesting to see how people react,
see where their head's at.
Like when connor came out with a heart
on against floyd.
What is,
what is he doing?
Is he fucking wearing a rubber band
around his ticket balls just to get it
hard?
Or is he playing with himself before he
gets out there?
a couple shakes before he gets on his
fucking dick was half hard,
but he's standing there hard and that's
just what it looks like when it's limp,
but it literally looked like it was half
hard when he's standing there at the
wind.
Like a siren.
The hill.
I've seen a couple of the guys,
I think mcgill dixit way and a couple
other guys that had that same thing.
I think it's like an involuntary thing
that happens when you're like hungry or
something.
I dunno.
I'll tell you what.
Get survival.
We have to go.
We haD to get real creative on the
physical anthropology of why you get a
hard out when you're about to get into
confrontation.
Maybe you're going to fight over a
female out the nature and I can maybe.
It was just such a weird problem when
stinks.
Confrontation to connor screaming,
yelling at him or for just standing
there literally like not a worry in the
world.
It was interesting how floyd handled it.
Yeah.
He didn't have a worry in the world.
We're seeing that.
I see composed because you know,
you're so composed 50 and oh man,
15.
Oh,
you know,
I'd said that he was the only guy that
ever reached that and break that record,
but apparently there was some other guy
that had fought and I'm like a really
light weight that made 51 zero.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That I didn't even know.
I thought they were talking about rocky
marciano.
I was taught that that was the record
for the child is it?
Wasn't he like up there before he got
defeated too?
Good question.
But he didn't retire with question one
was like six years.
RicArdo lopez?
Yeah.
He was a.
What wait was.
He doesn't say light flyweight yeah.
What?
What is that?
What is light flyweight?
Minimum waiting.
Jesus minimum.
Wait,
what the fuck is minimum way.
But ricardo lopez a.
Maybe he,
I believe he retired at 51 and.
Oh.
Oh,
he retired somewhere around that range.
Does it say one girl?
Yeah.
Oh,
we had to draw 50.
One wins,
zero losses and one draw.
The one draws the.
It's so funny.
People about that shit.
It's so
weird.
That's one thing about mma fighters as
opposed to boxers.
Boxer who was always undefeated record.
That was like,
that's such a big selling point in the.
In the.
Yeah,
anD I guess it makes sense though
because I mean you're trying to make a
case that nolan could,
you know,
there's something intriguing about
somebody that can,
that no one could ever beat this person,
but the difference between mma and
boxing and mma,
you're tested way more on the way up to
the title and you're fighting world
class fighters pretty quickly soon as
you start getting to zero.
Whereas in boxing you're taking care of
your record,
gets pad and you're slowly worked up to
a world class fighter.
If you have a good manager,
maybe 15 to 20 fights and you're trying
to maybe start fighting some.
OkAy.
People,
you know,
especially with you.
And again,
do you think that that's the way to do
it now?
No.
With those guys know,
because a lot of those boxers have had
three,
400 amateur fights.
Not like they don't need groomed into.
That may be to get out of the shoe
shining amateur style,
but switching notes,
a headgear getting taken away.
It's more,
you know,
it's,
it's set up and the point system,
how it's changing with the olympics,
you know,
taken into headgear off and how they're
changing all that.
So they're coming more professional,
setting stuff up,
not that,
you know,
pitter patter shit to shine,
that that's how it's been.
But I don't think they need to be,
be like that.
But I think in boxing is a huge records.
Like,
oh,
he's 37.
Oh it's 28 knockout we're gig.
I mean I guess the difference with,
with,
with ufc is use has always had a
reputation of putting the best fighters
against the best fighters,
which I think has gone away a little
bit.
I mean they still make sure you get
testeD.
Do you think it's gone away?
I don't think it's going away.
I think when they try to do is have even
matchups because there's like,
like a uh,
ricci and uh,
and,
and what's his name?
Who's fighting alvarez for example?
They just want to see that fight.
I mean,
they're both very tough guys.
It can be a champion and and her just
teaching,
but they want to see matches,
but they do that all the way down.
Like tHey're not gonna,
they're not trying to set up mismatches.
They're,
they're trying to get it more evenly
matched,
but that doesn't mean that there aren't
guys that they could set up with
mismatches within the,
within the
god get a tune up fight.
We're in boxing.
It's a big deal.
Or boxing guys get tuned up fights and
you even call them a tune up fight.
He's getting a tune up fight before the
big match.
Yeah.
You know,
and they go in there and they fight a
guy that's not expected to win and then
they get sent off for the next fight but
at tunes theM up,
get some sharp and then they have the
world championship fight.
When that happens to get into the ufc a
lot though,
a lot for me,
I have over half of my professional
fights are in the ufc.
I signed a five and no,
and you know,
so I have my plates or been in the ufc
against,
you know,
ufc obviously you can say the primary
organization with
spiders,
it's not even close,
but it's getting close now.
You know,
wHen you look at what bellah tor is
doing right now,
it's,
ufc is always going to be the top of the
food chain.
It's always like the premier
organization as far as the public knows.
But as far as the quality of talent,
bella tour,
at least finally as Roy Mcdonald,
you know,
they finally have all the that are
growing.
They are as well.
Yeah,
you're right.
But I mean getting um,
you know,
gay harden,
blue,
saucy,
worldclass guys,
we're like legitimately with pay.
Yeah.
I mean rory has a victory over tyron
woodley and a victory of a daemon maya.
So he had a victory over the one and
nuMber two guys,
it's interesting you just mentioned roy
can go back to what we're talking about
with training rory.
I mean that's a guy who,
he's a strange character and like I
wonder what goes on is what's his
motivation for fighting?
And what started him,
et cetera,
but I saw him do a,
uh,
an interview about his training.
He's like,
I'm like,
I talked about coaches making you do
shit just in.
You're just like,
do whatever the coach says.
He was like,
look,
I've been doing with all the coaches
say,
he's like,
I'm gonna.
I keep getting hurt.
I keep doing this.
And now he goes,
I'm going to take things into my own
hands a little bit more.
You know,
he's the guy that did that,
but he's,
he's having a lot of friggen success
too.
He looked like a fucking world killer.
And he'd be paul daley.
He looked perfectly savage to.
Yes.
That's gonna be an interesting fight.
Paul daley and lorenz larkin.
Oh yeah.
Explosive style.
Supercycle kicks.
Yeah.
I'll just.
How this longer than use.
Nope.
Nolan's lorenz larkin just fought
douglas lema for the title.
We lost a five round decision.
Very close fight.
Very good fight.
Douglas slam is another one.
That guy is world class.
I mean,
he is.
He's right up there with anybody in the
world at one 70,
in my opinion.
He's been around for awhile too.
Yeah.
You know what pisses me off is ben
aspirins still fighting over in one fc
like jesus christ I,
I am the number one district of his
retirement fight.
That's.
It drives me crazy.
Should've been the ufc a long time ago.
I always wanted to see that
pissed off.
Dana and his style is weird,
right?
The style is weird.
That's one thing,
but pissing off dana was ultimately the
end of it all.
I mean,
he was talking some serious shit.
Yeah,
that's too bad.
That's too bad.
Really bad.
I will have it mixed up with this guy
and fuck you.
I would have loved to see that guy fight
the best in the world in the ufc,
you know,
and we'll never know.
Now.
It's really unfortunate.
He made some decent money over there and
I hope you did.
I hope we did.
He's just a fucking phenomenal grappler,
man.
Here's a perfect example.
That guy destroyed larkin on the ground
or it's not locking lima destroyed him
on the ground and destroyed core cuff on
the ground just to be manhandled.
Those dudes got a.
Of those guys was ragdoll and fools.
Just throwing them around like that.
An orthodox weird wrestling style.
I wouldn't have wanted to see him fight
the best guys.
Yeah.
You know who had been a.
He would have been a terrible matchup
for is george st pierre was.
George always
saw he starts hitting his nice little
shots,
but he always ends up getting the nice
tape now.
But how was he going to do in grappling
against?
Asked her.
That would've been a good one.
I saw and I always wanted to see too.
Well,
you know that got him in trouble with
johny hendricks.
Right.
But johnny hunters is a different Johnny
Hendricks back then.
Yeah,
sure.
Interesting.
You saw this trip and changing lives,
bro.
I sit that I.
That's,
that's one of the thing that makes me
want to get back into it is now that you
saw it as an.
I still have you saw to test me just in
case there's an opportunity that pops up
because yeah,
they,
they pop in all the time.
60 a buck 60 right now.
What do you book?
60.
Do you think you could get done look up
anyone in the world?
Absolutely.
That's my guy.
He'll come in and he does practices with
us and shit will always give them a hard
time like,
oh,
he's still got it.
you still gotta?
Yeah,
he's retired.
Are you kind of retired?
Mostly.
Mostly retired.
I'm retired.
I,
I'm,
I'm definitely retired,
but I'm not a first off.
I love the fight.
That's the hard thing about retiring is
it takes so much time,
energy and there's so much to learn that
I'm definitely a better fighter when I
retired than I than I was when I was in
my prime.
Meaning as far as skillset goes,
but like there's a lot of skill guys out
there and it's just like a focus thing
and a motivation thing like.
So you wish there were,
you saw it.
It was there the entire career.
Oh god.
Are you kidding me?
Hell,
you ever feel any temptation when you
knew that so many guys were using shade?
I had,
I had a couple week.
We'll sit down and try to talk me into
it before they tried to talk you into
just like,
hey,
you know,
like everybody's doing it but this and
that,
blah,
blah.
I forget What the.
Somebody had talked about it and I had a
coach a long time ago that was like,
hey everybody.
And I'm like,
no,
I don't think so.
I,
I take a lot of pride in the fact that I
had in my career and I didn't.
I'm like oblivious.
I'm like,
like,
you knoW,
like when you're not In the circle,
you're definitely not in the circle.
Yeah.
They don't tell you,
tell you.
They don't want to tell you,
you know,
everything else.
So I,
I think a lot of pride in the fact that.
And I,
and I teach to my guys and that's one of
the conversations I've had with cody.
I'm like,
bro,
you know,
we don't need any of that shit.
Dude.
That's all mental.
It's a mental thing.
The problem is that the differences when
you have someone that strong mentally
that is like a scientist on himself and
also has all the attributes,
then it matters,
right?
When you get a guy in math class fighter
and then on top of that they take some
shit and then yeah,
they have the mentality,
right?
If everybody's doing it mentalities,
which allows like champions to do it as
well.
Right.
This champion never did it.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Beautiful.
I mean,
all right,
let's wrap this bitch up.
Good luck man.
Can't wait to see you.
Madison square garden.
That's November 4th,
november forward.
That's a big fucking.
Does a historic venue,
man,
as going to be amazing.
Fireworks.
I have favorites.
Ultimate fitness,
sacramento,
California.
You arrive favor on twitter and
instagram and cody,
uh,
you're,
you're on twitter and instagram and all
that shit too.
Thank you gentlemen is a lot of fun.
Alright,
I'll see you guys.