Okay,
boom. And we're live. What's up
brother? How are you man, Joe Rogan.
I am so happy to be here. I'm
so happy to see you. Fuck,
you've gone through a journey.
Oh Man.
Since the last time I seen him yesterday
was one year from your heart transplant
anniversary. Exactly.
Wow. One year. And Joe,
if I told you it was easy,
I'd be lying. But man,
it was so worth the journey
and they ain't even funny.
What does it feel like right now? Like
have another person's heart in your body.
What does that feel like?
Well,
a lot of times it feels like I actually
did die and this is just a dream my hand
right now. Yup. Wow. This,
this is, I think there's,
this would be my heaven. You look
great. You're still jacked. No,
not losing any weight. Oh yeah,
yeah, yeah. But I mean, you still,
you still jacked. He's still
got muscles. Uh, you know, it's,
it's such a,
a fall from where I was, you know, I
really appreciate it though, but I, I,
you know, I look at myself, man,
it's just, uh, you know, fragmented.
What I used to be, but you
know, still here. That's
what's so important to me, man.
Well,
the ridiculous thing you were doing,
you're making videos of your working out
like getting ready and after your heart
attack,
heart operation,
this you have a heart transplant and
you're running in a parking lot and you
trip and fall. I'm like,
Jesus man, slow down.
You just decided that you were just going
to start pushing from the beginning.
Well,
uh,
actually my brain was
ready but my body wasn't.
Did they warn you about doing that?
Did they say it was okay?
You can tell me that they gave me
permission to walk and you know me,
I'm like walk shit.
I can run
my mind so that I could. Right. What
does it feel like though? Like when you,
like what is the difference between
the way your heart feels now?
It's night and day.
You know,
before I got the transplant
it had got really bad,
really bad. I had a Frat line
two more times, uh, you know,
before the actual transplant and it was,
I couldn't go through one another frat.
Right. I mean, that would've been it.
But the difference now, I mean, it feels,
I only say flatline, like
your heart stops. Yes. Yes.
And what did they do to
start it back up again? Okay.
After had this last heart attack,
um, they asked me to see Mr freshly,
do you want to us to put in
a pacemaker? And I, you know,
I thought about it a lot because my
brother and my older brother at Walt had a
pacemaker installed before he passed away.
And his pacemaker was actually
going off, uh, when he,
when he died. So I'm like, man, I
didn't really do any good for him.
So I was like going back and forth
and then this, it's sounding voice,
say Diego and get it. And so I told him
he had put it in and pacemaker saved me.
Wow. So it went flat like she,
her heart gave up. And then the p,
what is the pacemaker do exactly?
It's like a defibrillator, you know,
I think they had the paddles to give
you an electric shock, you know, that's,
that's what the pacemaker does.
Just give you a little inside, uh,
inside, and it's connected directly
to your heart, that sucker flat lines.
It gives you a jolt. Wow.
Yeah. Did you feel it?
No. No. I was, I was
dead until you're dead.
You don't feel nothing. So
you'd blocked out to Oh, uh,
it's not, uh, a blackout or,
uh, uh, like those offerings.
You're sleeping.
Death is totally different.
Totally different.
And you,
I knew that I was dead
before I died before at flat.
Right. It was just me and my wife at home
and I was talking to her just like I'm
talking to you. And the next
thing, all the lights went out.
It was like a one of
those old fashioned TVs.
I don't know if you're old enough to
remember these black and white TVs. Yeah,
yeah. That's exactly how it
was. Just sort of Chinese pop,
tiny pinprick of light and you know that,
that's it.
Wow. It's no, you know, you
absolutely know that this is it.
And it's not, you know, this is the
irreversible and you're, you're, you know,
that it's, this is death and this,
you're not just those in our,
you know, did you have a near
death experience? I everything.
Um,
the only thing you have to,
I don't think I had time to
say was I had timely, uh,
call my wife's name. But I mean,
when they say things rush, you know,
everything's like, this is
the, this is it. You know,
you're not going to be able to do this
anymore. You're not going to get it.
This is it.
The final finalization of
everything hits you like the,
you know, this is it, you
know, this is the final thing.
This is your last moment on earth
and you know it. And I'm like,
what do you do B, you know, I can do
with say my wife's name. And that was it.
That was it. So the, the pacemaker
kicks in and then you route.
Yeah. And it was, so that's a
damn good description. I mean,
it was like a,
I thought I felt like that
I had been asleep for hours.
It was the best,
most peaceful,
restful time of my entire life.
Wow.
And in just a short moment,
it felt like I had been asleep for eight
hours, so rested so well rested. So,
and my wife told me,
and I was just a short period of time,
but it felt like I'd been asleep for
eight hours. So this happened twice? Yes.
The second time was in
the hospital. Oh Wow.
So they tell you, okay, Mr.
Fletcher, we have a heart for you.
Yeah,
they call me like two 40 in the morning.
So that you have to get in there right
now. Is that how it felt was? No,
I had hours, uh, before I had
to actually be at the hospital.
I said the be it the hospital thing,
like six or seven, they had more. Yeah.
And then you think an whoa boy.
Uh,
I was happy and sad when I got the car.
I was happy for myself,
um,
because I didn't think I could
go through another flat line,
but I was sad for the
donor and dawn's Fam. Yeah.
I knew somebody had to pass away
in order for me to get that hard.
So I felt real bad about that.
So they put it in you,
you wake up,
what does that feel like?
Um,
it felt like, uh, um, being born again,
a rebirth. I never
tried. Never go at life.
Wow. Yeah. I get it. Never started
another chance they had it,
my said ain't over.
Wow.
So from this,
so they have to open you up,
do that chest spreader thing and uh,
and what is all that like?
Well, are you, of course that
you were out, but when you
wake up and you look down,
you're covered with stitches,
right? I mean, it must be
a giant scar, right? They,
it's, they are so good now
to go get it. You know,
I have a scar, but considering that
it's my second time being split open,
you know, the first time, uh, and Oh
five, when they put a metal valve in,
I've flattened. I during that
operates in three times on, you know,
on the table during the,
the operation itself. Uh,
so me and flat line, you got a five
flat lines. I think I'm at my limit man.
Um, I seen the scars.
They had to take a pace,
the pacemaker out, they took
the metal valve out of it. Well,
they took the old heart, had the metal
fab and he took the old hard out.
They put in a new heart and uh,
it's just me and it's unbelievably this
before a shower would kill me if I took
a shower, I'd be done for the
rest of the day. A shower. Yeah.
Shout we kill me for the rest of the
day and I had to seat in the shower,
you know, uh, how would, how
would a shower kill you? Oh Man.
It was that amount of physical activity
and you know, uh, how, you know,
people take taking a shower for granted,
but that amount of physical
activity would kill me.
I'd be white out just for washing your
sheets. Yes. For the rest of the day,
man. It was. So you were hanging by a
smell? Yeah, definitely. Definitely.
It was, you know, Kim, you know,
and my wife was opening jars for me,
you know,
here I am,
former big spreads world
champion and I got my wife.
Hey baby cause you open these jelly
jar for me. Wow. Yeah it's a humbling,
humbling. Very big time. Big Time.
How long did you have to stay in the
hospital for? Um, we were in the hospital,
not very long. I mean we got out of
uh, we went straight to intensive care.
They keep you there for like three days,
but I think I was probably
released to within two weeks total.
Wow. And then are you using a
walker? Are you walking fine?
Like I wouldn't say I was walking fine
but I was walking just walking slowly.
Oh, big time. Big Time. Slowly. Yeah,
I was crawling along. Yeah. Wow.
And how long did it take to,
for you to get to where you're at?
And like now?
Like now I'd have no idea that you had
a heart transplant and really well I
appreciate it. No. When I saw you, me,
you look very happy. Oh, I am happy.
You look like you're growing.
I am extremely happy just to be alive
when you come that close to dying.
I mean every day is just the blessing,
man.
If people are having ain't doing CT,
I'm blessed man.
I'm sorry I got no complaints.
Oh yes. No complaints whatsoever.
I'm through. I seen, I want to hug
them. Joe. I'm so happy to see.
I'm so happy to see you man. I'm
alive. Wow. Cause we, you know,
last time we talked about me needing a
transplant and I needed the transplant,
it now back.
I had it,
the first six months were rough.
Yeah.
The first six months after it was uh,
the jelly jar oatmealy jelly jars,
just not being able to do,
you know, normal things. The first
thing I tried to do was walk.
So they had me walk around, I guess
a city block. I mean, city plot.
Joe. When I first tried to
walk around a city buck,
I'd have to stop probably 1213 times and
take a seat and get up and try to walk.
And it was, it was killing
me, man. My, my, you know, my,
my wife would slow down and he slowed
down and walk with me and us too.
It was such a struggle and I'm like,
you know what,
I don't give a damn how long it take me.
I'm going to make you mad and I'm
going to make it says keep, keep going.
And what kind of activity are
you able to do now? A year later,
I am a lifting again, but very
lightly I am able to do, you know,
the machines and stuff from the 10.
Uh,
I think I've been able to do
that for the last two months.
So when you say it lightly, is this by
doctor's orders? Oh yeah. The doctor.
I can't do anything. You know,
without them approving it first. Yeah.
Except the run in the parking
lot. Didn't even approve. Yeah.
Well mine was like, go ahead,
you can do it. My body was like,
leave me out this month. Yeah. So what,
what holds you back in terms
of like lifting weights?
Like why do you have to go light?
And my strength is just nowhere near what
it used to be. The strength of steel,
you know, I can tell that, uh, you know,
I have a long way to go, but, you know,
just to be able to do anything.
So I guess I kinda need
to do and I do what I can.
That's what I tell people all the
time, man. If you can't, uh, you know,
do what you want to do, at least get
in there and do what you can do. Yeah.
It's better than doing
nothing. Yeah. Yeah.
So now did they have you on medications
to make sure that the heart doesn't get
rejected by your body?
Most definitely in an,
and people out there who've
had transplants, I know
that they were like, oh man.
Yeah. I take about 21
different medications everyday.
Yup. 21 different medica and when
the side effects of the stuff,
they used to be worst,
but now, you know, my uh,
fetus swollen pretty much every day.
Um,
something in the medical kind of kicks
my arthritis. I have arthritis too,
so it kind of kicks in and told her
stiff, you know, pretty much every day.
But when I compare the side effects
to the work took possibly after him,
which is death and the
side effects ain't shit,
I'll take them now when you have
to take this medication forever,
uh, it gets less, less and less.
When I go back this month back up to
Palo Alto where they did the transplant,
um, they're going to take off about
four or five different medications.
So I'm a year out now. They last
and then the further you get out,
the less medication and thinking events,
we'll get down to two or three,
but you'll always have to
take some oh yeah, definitely.
And it's just because your body doesn't
understand why it has someone's heart in
it. Um, for a while they had
that in the beginning, right?
I'm taking 21 now. It's
because, you know, uh,
to keep the chances that rejection
down why it's your check today,
then understand that it wasn't the
one that she was born with. Right.
As a foreign, you know, foreign heart.
And I really want to talk to you about
that heart. What I know about it. Um,
it's a woman's heart,
right? Yeah. So, you know,
you know already I was going to drop a
bomb on, you know, the following. Yeah.
Very good. Yeah. Yeah. I won.
But I tell you that, that threw me
for a loop. Yeah. And I was, you know,
I'm always talking about how strong
my faith is and you know, I'm
faith, faith, faith, faith man,
the Super Man of faith. Uh,
I could have so much faith to
Matt and can't phase me. You know,
I went into the operation,
hey,
I see you guys in the other side
of this because you know, I got,
I know I'm going to be here. I
got so much faith that, you know,
I'm going to get through this
so I'm going to see you guys.
But when the doctor came in and told me
that I had a woman's heart that sock the
shit out of my face because I had done
steady, you know, I looked, you know,
steady on this,
the,
the survival rate of male to female.
And it wasn't good.
The stage that I had read wasn't good.
When they do a female to me, I'm sorry,
female to Male, the term it's not good.
And I was like, everything I had
read said it's not a good thing.
The doctor comes in and says,
Yep, you've got a woman's heart.
And she wasn't that much
younger than you are
that, that you know, side.
Yeah. Tested my faith big time.
How did she die? I have no
idea. I have no idea. But,
um,
the thing I have feelings,
I haven't talked to the family.
I would love to.
I don't know anything about it,
but I have these feelings and I really
would like to know if what I'm feeling is
right. You know, I want, I really
want to meet the family and let them,
let them know that I'm out here doing
everything I can to raise donor awareness.
And if their mother or their wife or
their sister or their aunt didn't die in
vain.
And then I'm doing my absolute best
to carry on and let people know that,
you know,
she was a donor and that it's so
utterly important for people to donate,
give the gift of life. What are these
feelings? I have feelings that, uh,
for some reason I can see that I feel
like she was an oriental lady and I,
I, you know, I don't know why,
but I really have feelings like that
and I feel like I can see this woman,
I'm telling her husband,
you know,
I'll see when we get home from work and
making plans with their kids for the
weekend and have no idea
if this is right or not.
But I just had those feelings.
But they are recurring. Yes.
And did you like it? Do you
remember it like a memory? It's, um,
it's like I get to look into her,
you know,
her existence, her, her life,
and I have no,
I could be totally wrong.
She kept me a Jamaican
lady. Right. I have no idea.
Or if I'm in the ballpark or not.
I just have this feeling.
I just have a feeling. Wow.
Do you have any unusual cravings
or anything like food or, uh,
I don't think, uh, no.
I don't think I haven't.
I do talk to her and I feel like that,
uh, you know, when, when like when
I was walking around and I'm trying,
I'm trying to make it around that.
I would often ask her for help
to help me make it around me.
Wow. Yeah. Well I talked to
her a lot. Wow. Come on lady.
I need to have a name for it.
I just kind of the lady,
come on lady. I need jail.
Wow. Wow. That's crazy.
You're superman from
captain has a lady's heart.
Now when you say that,
that it's not,
the results aren't good for lady
hearts in Male bodies. Yeah.
Did you say that to the doctor
and the doctor is so, um,
it's so funny.
I don't even know if the doctor
suppose because it was this one doctor.
He would come in and young guy
and he would come in every day.
How are you doing Mr. Fletcher? And
I will say I'm blessed. I don't care.
When I woke up from the transplant,
I consider every second
after that a blessing.
It's borrowed time and I wasn't supposed
to be here, so I, I, my answer is always,
I'm blessed so he can meet you. How are
you doing? I'm blessed him. But he said,
you know what, you're going to
change that and I ain't to no doc.
It's nothing you can say.
It's going to make me change my answer.
I'm going to always be blessed
no matter what you say. He said,
you think you're doing really good, don't
you and I were hair. Yeah. I think I'm,
I'm, I'm alive. Yeah.
I think I'm doing good.
I walked around this a hospital corridor.
I think I'm doing really good.
He said,
you're not,
you're doing about what you're supposed
to be doing and you have a woman's heart
and it's too small for you.
And she was almost your age.
Fuck,
it's too small.
He told me that the heart
was too small and uh,
the lady was,
I was 58 or nine and 59 cause
that'd be 60 on June the eighth.
So, uh, he says it's too small and
you're not, you know, you're not
doing anything extraordinary.
You just do an average and
she's your age. I'm like, man,
fuck for the rest of the day I was fucked.
I was fucking mind,
man. I was, you know, God, why
didn't you do this? The League?
Why did you kill me? Oh, well I'm
and sorry. And old woman it dad,
why can you give me an
age? Well, I'm the why God,
I was questioning why did you
do this to me? Did you ask him?
Hey, what did you say? You mean the
doctor or guide the doctor? Uh, I didn't,
I need to ask the doctor that my doctor
did come in and I deal. Do you know,
I'm sorry. I did ask the doctor.
I asked her, I said, dad, why,
why could you now I am, dude. I had tears
in my eyes because this was, you know,
I'm like, fuck, I got another
heart, but I ain't gonna last long.
I'm going to be out here.
So it was, you know,
it was fucking with me and the
doctor, um, acid dye of why,
I mean, why, and she looked me in the
eyeballs doing, she said, Mr Frichy,
we didn't want you to die. It's just
that sample. We didn't want you to die.
That was what was available. That was what
was available. It was a healthy heart.
And I need one bad deal now. Well,
that heart grow to match your body.
It already has really,
it is the proper size that it's,
it did. Yes. And the doctor
that told me it was too small.
It was the one who told me that he
had grown to the proper sides. Wow.
Why does it grow? Because it recognized
it was in a bigger body. Ah, Joe, I,
you're on. That's on the physical. Uh, if
you look at it physically and probably a,
you know,
on with a rational mind
that would probably be it
realized that it had to adapt
to a larger,
but I'm going to give him a little
credit the car because it's just me man.
So cause he came back too fast.
I mean it was like a week later and said
it's already decided that she would be
a week later, a week after week
later before I left the hospital.
He was telling me that it's
already sizes should be Jesus.
And I said see dark.
I told you I'm blessed man.
I that doesn't make any sense.
I know. What did he say?
Did the doctor say it doesn't make
any sense to the normal thing?
I have no idea why. I have no idea
if it's a normal thing or not.
But you know, I mean me I'm giving
credit. I'm going wild. Another miracle.
Thank God
I didn't say that question guy and I,
my answer was what did I,
I got back was what simple.
He said that if I gave you or a
18 year old Olympic athletes harp,
CT and you recovered,
was doing well,
then people are going to say that.
That's why we got an 18 year old Olympic
gold medal is hard and you're able to
recover and stuff because of this,
but if I take a old lady's heart,
there's two small and that not,
you're not supposed to be able to come
back and do these things with this heart,
then they're going to have to
give me a little credit. He said,
I have a habit of taking
the least of the least,
the lowest of the low and making
something out of it and I see anywhere.
Let me shut the fuck up.
You're absolutely, it
wouldn't be that impressive,
right? It wouldn't be a miracle if I
eat if it was this wonderful heart,
but because I'm God,
I'm going to take this heart and give
it to you and he's going to still do all
those things, so shit up Ct.
I said, okay, that's good.
Now when you're exercising now eight,
you're just,
are you pushing or you just get into a
point where you just feel a little tired
and your back off?
Joe Rogan,
I can't help but push my say no.
That's why I'm asking like, you know,
I give, I gave her, I gave
everything that guy. Yeah,
I can't help.
It doesn't matter if you feel weird when
your heart starts beating heavy. Um,
or should I say her start her heart,
her heart starts beating them pretty
fast and you know, I don't feel weird.
I feel like,
uh,
it's something I've done my whole life
and I'm just glad to be back able to do,
you know, some of what I used to
do. It's just a feel good. You know,
I still talk to her though.
Come on. Wait, I'm sure.
I'm sure we get through this sadly.
And now you feel it building up like
you feel like every month or so you get
stronger? Um, definitely.
Yeah, definitely.
I feel that the longer that gets any
long as that, that the heart is in need,
the more it feels like, you know,
it's, that's where it should be in my,
my body adapts.
And how long does a heart transplant
usually survive in a person?
Well,
um,
I think the the longest at this
point it's close to 40 years.
40. Wow. Yeah. Yeah. I
don't want 40 years. That's,
I don't want to be a hundred man.
You don't know why not?
I want to, I, you know, I never expected,
I said on June the eighth,
I'll be 60.
I never expected to make it to 40,
so go really, really? Yeah. I never,
I never expected I expected
to die young. So, um,
I'm way past where I thought
I would make it anyway.
So it's why'd you think you're going
to die that young? Oh Man, I never had,
I want it to be, I was, I was my,
and I want it to be the sky rocket man.
Brilliant.
Like to shoot way up. They Ms.
Guy be a brilliant burst. And Dan,
I thought they would be the perfect
ending. Just go for it. Go for it.
Go for it.
Go for it and explode
it dead motherfucker. Yeah.
But he, he was, you know,
he was something else when he
was alive and happy with that.
That's what you thought. [inaudible]
hell yeah, definitely. Wow. Yeah.
Now you've got to settle in for 41 years.
I don't even want to be for her
to be alive right now and
every day is a blessing. Yeah.
So why is it 40 years of blessing? It
would be a blessing, but I, man, you know,
I would be, uh, I didn't
want to be around where,
uh, um, I don't want to be a
burden on anybody and, uh, I think,
yeah, a hundred man. Yo, somebody else
got to take care of you, wipe your ass.
You know,
you got to wear diapers and shit.
And I don't know if I w I w I wouldn't
want to be around to be a burden on
somebody. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. I know what you mean.
But right now you're not a burden. I
hope not. No. I think my might disagree.
But you're moving around, man. I
mean, like I said, if I didn't know,
I would have no idea.
Well, I appreciate that.
And even though I know you must
have lost some muscle, he's still,
if I just met you, I'd be like,
this is a Jack Dude. Yeah.
He's still hanging on the size of
your arms, man. There's still huge,
I don't think so. What they
used to be. That's why.
Yeah. Yeah. I don't, I
don't see him. You see it?
That's kind of stuff don't even
matter that much anymore. Right.
I'm sure you have a new lease on life. Oh
yeah. Big Time. What matters to you now?
Uh, the, the really important
things are of course my family,
uh, and spreading, um,
donor awareness is so important because
so many people die just waiting to get a
heart, you know, on the list of 20,
I think 21 people a day pass away,
just waiting, trying to
get in. I was so fortunate,
so blessed to be able to get on that.
I want to try to make sure
that other people get one too.
So if whatever I can do
to try to raise awareness,
what is the problem? Like people putting
on that they'll donate their organs.
You could do it online. Now the only
drivers, like in California, you can't,
I don't know about other states, but
in California you can do it all online,
you know,
and,
and through the DMV and get your
diet on your driver's license.
And I want to be a donor and I mean, you
can't take the stuff, which, you know,
wait,
no,
you people get paranoid too.
I've heard people say,
I'm worried about doing that because
what if they don't resuscitate me because
they need someone to get a
heart or a liver or something.
I'm like, I don't know,
man. I really don't think
that's what doctors are there.
No, no, it's, it's, uh, I had, uh,
I, Eh, younger, you know,
when I first got my driver,
I was 16 years old and asks you to even
want to be a donor. I'm like, no. Oh,
I'm taking everything that God
gave me with me. I ain't even know.
I know, right. I ain't doing
nothing. But you know, uh,
time brings about a change,
man. You get a little older,
a little more wisdom and,
uh,
and if I can get something
to somebody else can use,
definitely most definitely take it.
Yeah.
My mother and all nine of her brothers
and sisters all passed away from heart.
Well, so it's just something that's
in your family. Oh yeah. It's,
my older brother walked passed away just
a couple of years ago from congestive
heart failure and other complications.
So heart problems run big time in the
Fletcher family. That's a crazy one.
Right. That does run in families.
Yep. Yeah. It is crazy. Yeah.
But it's reality.
Yeah.
So now, um, do you, what kind
of diet do they have you on?
Uh, I very clean man. Um, I guess, uh, um,
I had my, uh, my kids crack up. I
tell, I said I'm a Presbyterian,
but actually, uh, there's Pescatarian,
I face a face,
you know,
and blessed stubbles and um,
it's no bullshit,
no bullshit, no time for bullshit. No time
for bullshit. It's exactly right, man.
Cause time, coffee time is precious.
Do I used to, but the caffeine, uh,
and my doctors don't like we mad the
caffeine. Yeah, I would imagine. Yeah.
So, um, rest must be very
important for you to yeah.
God I get putting any of it. Yeah, it is.
What other things they make sure that
you do. Um, the Diet has to be on point,
have to take my medication. Uh,
they didn't want me, um, to,
uh, you know, do too much
strenuous activities.
Um, they had limited me. I, I wouldn't,
I was not able to travel out
of the country until yesterday.
Um, so yeah. So at one year anniversary,
that's when they give you the green light.
Yep. Man, I can go all over.
What did they say when they saw you
running the parking lot and fall down?
All my doctors and um,
you know,
they all said,
uh,
CT what we think except one except one,
my cardiologist. And he
said, you know what, CT,
I'm not going to wreck. She's
like, everybody else did. Uh,
you already know that they
shouldn't have done that. But man,
I am so proud of you.
He said,
you have inspired me to
start working out again.
That was doctor Salaam. Doctors Slam
him if he's listening. Thank you.
He was the only one
that didn't condemn me.
How far out where it was that
the surgery when you fell down?
Three months
get so crazy.
I felt like I could do
to my mind was like, oh,
well that's that mentality that you have.
You know?
I would imagine it's very
hard to adjust. Uh, yeah,
it's big time. I mean,
from being a village,
it will be the same for you.
So you're an active guy kicking
the shit out of the bags and stuff.
Old Lightman foot over there and then
even maybe you think and not be able to
raise your leg. Yeah. Or throw a punch.
Man. I'll be walking around in
the grocery store. I'm like,
man with my wife and I'm like, man, I hope
nobody fucks with me. Oh, right, right,
right. Yeah. How's he feeling
if somebody, you thinking, man,
if somebody fucks with you can't even
punch him. Yeah. He can't do anything.
You can't do nothing.
You'd be helpless.
That's man that it's hard to
little old ladies have to do.
It's hard on my pants and my fuck with me.
I'm just going to get beat.
I got no defense.
That's a terrible thing.
That's a terrible thing. But
awfully humbling. Yeah. Tam.
Then you reel, he realized, you know,
just how your whole life you
live for strength. You know,
I've been a strong man my whole life
and then all of a sudden all of that is
taken away and you're just,
you know,
fucking invalid man.
You're just weak is shit.
It's very hard mentally to deal with.
But you're past that now.
Yes.
Now you're just in what wa how would you
categorize like how you feel right now?
Um, I categorize my, my, uh,
emotional feelings as being
probably better than ever.
Really? Yes. Uh,
as I see things in such a different light,
uh,
after coming that close to dying,
the things that I thought were
important just don't even matter.
Like what I used to, I give
you one example. You know,
people I used to tell him,
okay,
you asked me about this last time I was
on the show. And I tell people, they say,
well, it's about to steroids and
steroids, how CTU. He takes years.
And I tell him the same thing that I've
been saying for fucking 25 years and
magazine articles and
stuff. I tried them. Yes,
I tried them when I was
young and didn't work for me.
I stopped taking [inaudible] with nobody.
Nobody.
Lot of people don't believe they didn't
believe that. And they'll tell me, oh,
you're full of shit. Ct your line.
And I had an out of that and Joe,
that used to bother the fuck out of me.
People flying.
I'd be arguing with people online and say,
fuck,
I take a Goddamn drug tests anytime, 24
hours a day, you could test me. I fucking,
I tell you what, I gave you 10,000
bucks. If I fail your drug test,
all you gotta do is get off fucking social
media. Nobody ever took that burden.
But, but uh, I don't give a fuck if people
say I take steroids now. I don't care.
Who Cares? Right. Okay. Now it's
a fucking compliment. Do you a,
you don't still go back and forth and
argue with people online? Oh No, no,
not anymore. I sure it
did. I, Oh shit. I would,
I would jump on him in a
minute. Shake my head like, why?
Oh man, Joe, because that was my
mentality. A attacker attack back.
He hit me, I'm gonna hit you back, man.
Try to hit your heart of escalates
all the APPS. Oh yeah. Well, you know,
I do the all caps. Can you talk to me
about, you're yelling, you're yelling, CP,
but I can't have seat so I make it
all caps so I can read what I'm,
what I'm trying. Right, right. Or you get
one. I said, can you actually hear that?
Can you actually hear
that through those words?
You're fucking loud. It's, you
got spidey sense, man. Got, so
one of the most humbling
things about getting older
is the vision going. Oh yeah.
I've known it like from when I was like
42 I started to notice it and by the
time I was 46 I was like God damn.
And I think I need glasses cause I would
just try to like read the computer and
I'd be doing this when my,
I was like bawling my eyes squinting and
trying to look at it sideways and try
to see what the fuck I was raised.
So weird thing. It's like, oh boy,
my ability to see the world
is fading. It happens. Yeah,
it was to the best of this. But it's
a warning sign like, hey man, this is,
you know, this is a
finite existence. Yeah.
Oh get some shit done. Right. Yeah man.
Right now don't wait.
It's going to be waiting time.
It sets or precious
commodity billionaires.
You cannot buy one sec.
One second of life.
Yeah. Can't do it. Nope.
It's whole pricing.
Anything that you're thinking about
doing and you've been putting off,
my advice is to get the step
and get the to her next year.
Right now. Get after it. Don't put
it off any longer. Get it done.
So do you feel like you're
like CT Fletcher 2.0
definitely that I'm a new dude.
I knew dude wouldn't do attitude.
Yeah. Yep. Big Time. No.
Well you won't be arguing October the
guys. I used to argue it online. Hey,
I love you man.
You can hate me all you want to.
I love to see I ain't got time
for hate and racism or big.
I ain't got time for none of that.
It's all full of shit. I said,
it's so much bullshit and just a waste
of time and they ain't even finding,
I'm like, look, if the end,
the transplant experience
enhanced my view.
I've always said we were
all saying I need the bar.
My mom taught me to love
everybody, but look, they took,
I have no idea the nationality
or race of the donor,
it don't matter.
I hope you're right. If you're
right, it's an Asian woman.
I think that would be fantastic
and you could feel that,
that you would know that
and he could feel it.
Man. Wouldn't that be something
be amazing. I got to find out.
How can you find out? I, I don't,
I have no idea. I want that.
Hopefully they're listening
to the Joe Rogan podcast.
Why don't you give him some details?
Like when,
what day did it happen and what,
like where did the,
did they tell you where the donor came
from? No part of the country. Nope.
I know that their heart was
flown in and I actually,
you know,
my,
my wife baby crazy is that it's something
that took a heart out of someone's
body and they put it on ice and
we actually see as video the ice,
just a lead going into the room and
then the ice just come follow him right
afterwards. God, that's so crazy.
It is crazy. It's, I mean it's,
when I was a kid, uh, it would be
like doctor Frankenstein. Yeah. Yeah.
They didn't start doing it to 68 and I
was born in 59 so you know why they did
heart transplants and see
68. Yeah, my wife's, yeah,
lactic 60 a week doing a
long time. But, uh, when I,
like I said when I was a
kid would have been like,
Dr. Franks time you told me something
like that was possible. I would say,
Oh hell no. You're crazy. You're just
making it up. It's science fiction,
but it most,
it most certainly is possible.
Well, do you think they're going to
be able to grow your own heart? Yeah.
They're working on that right now. Growing
your own heart with stem cells and,
and you know it's going to
happen, which is just crazy. Yeah.
It is going to happen.
I have no doubt. Yeah.
They've already grew a woman's bladder.
The woman had bladder cancer and
they grew her a new bladder. Wow.
Replaced her bladder. Yep. So the
hearts coming. Yeah. It's coming, man.
Yeah. They're already working
on a, I think they're three d.
See if you could find a Jamie,
they're three d printing a human heart
and they think that they're going to be
able to get to a point where they
have a working model of a human heart,
like wow. And, and put
your heart in your body.
A freshie new one,
which is just so crazy.
That is crazy.
And how about for people who are
amputees and things along those lines
with your own limb
actually grow you a limb.
Isn't that something?
Here it is.
The first three d printed heart
made up of living human cells.
Like who knows? Yeah. Yeah, man. It's,
thank God there's people smarter than us.
Old Good.
That is a heart made by universities.
Uh, Tel Aviv University.
Wow.
Heart.
The size of a rabbit marks the first
time an entire heart has been three d
printed.
So that's a tiny one right now.
But complete with living cells, blood
vessels, ventricles and chambers intact.
Crazy, incredible. Mini heart can
contract, but it can't yet pump out blood.
So they're working on all those
different variables, I guess. But man,
in that incredible,
look at that three d printing machine,
like three d printing machines freaked
me the fuck out. Like their, hey,
that's the future. They're gonna be
able to make things. Yeah. Look at that.
Look how that works. If you folks who
haven't seen this, uh, this is, uh,
what the future is on cnet.com.
You can Google it and just watch the
video of them actually creating this.
It is unbelievably fascinating.
So did you look at the heart
before they put it in you?
She has to see it. No, no, no. I was
out. Yeah. It was out by that time.
Yeah. Wow. You don't look
at it and say, wake up,
lights come back on. Yup. And uh, doctors,
their wives, they're doctors.
Damn my wife's there.
And uh, it was uh, you a
new day and I was like, Eh,
I wa I kind of wanted to, I kind of
wanted to say, Eh, I told you so.
Yeah. That was a hot, that's hilarious.
Do so I told you so.
It was a funny thing to say.
Would you come back from a heart
transplant on me because you would be a,
you would be surprised
at how funny though,
if you did say that it was so many.
Uh,
I got so many people and it
was overwhelming support,
but I got quite a few,
well too many for me, uh,
messages with Dns and I hope you don't
make it. I hope you die and your,
I wish to be dead already know
stuff like that. Do you feel,
I'm sorry for those people now?
Oh yeah, most definitely now.
Now I do, you know, be angry
before [inaudible] I was like,
oh, choke the shit out of
him. But you know, now,
I mean you gotta beat.
Um, what, what is your,
your existence must be pretty
pitiful for you to, you know,
feel that much hate for somebody that
you don't even know. Never. Yeah,
I just can't stand Joe Rogan.
I hate him.
I've never met him.
I never sit down.
There's no happy people that are
doing that now. It's so transparent.
You gotta be pretty, you know, probably
believably miserable, miserable,
miserable. I'm a file of Joe Rogan
just so I can talk shit about them.
I don't care.
I wish Joe Rogan was off the air,
but I'm following every word he said
because I don't want to miss nothing to
Joe Rogan has to say, but I hate them.
Yeah. Makes no sense, man.
Well, it doesn't make sense,
but a lot of people don't make sense.
That's true.
People live their lives and just very
counterproductive ways and they feel like
as long as they've got something,
they're excited about that,
that they're doing something,
even if it's excited about
hating you for no reason.
I don't get it. Time is too precious
to waste on hate. It's just foolish.
It's a foolish way to exist. Yeah.
I can take, they can take, uh,
livers and hearts and different organs
from any nascent malty and switch them
around. Were any changeable
till we were interchangeable?
All one thing.
Yes.
The only thing that separates us is the
climate that we came from. That's it.
That's it. And it's so it,
it, it makes racism. So s
anything stupid.
Tribalism is stupid.
The conservative versus liberal. That's
southern versus northern. That stupid.
It's too Asian versus black.
Pakistani. Stupid Dude. So stupid. It's,
we're all in a tangible dude.
That right there shows you
that, you know, we're all one,
we wouldn't be interchangeable now.
Couldn't make we
just this outer shit.
It's on top.
This epidermis, the skin,
this stuff that, you know,
uh,
the Pfizers and it's what makes us
interesting or foolish about it.
It's like,
yeah,
what's fascinating to me is that human
beings came from every single spot on the
earth and then one time they originated
in Africa and spread out all over the
planogramming adapted to
each individual environment.
When you meet someone from
Ireland, they're white, like paper.
That shit's just because there's no
sun. Exactly. Their body developed.
It's like a, a solar panel
for vitamin D. They're like,
we've got to figure out how to get
fucking vitamin D, this black skinny,
cut the fucking sun out here.
We don't need this melanin cause we're
not protecting ourselves from the sun
anymore.
So they turned white
but did the same exact thing.
They can take that guy from in the guy
from Africa and this guy needs a part.
Hey, let me just switch it up
with me. This gentleman here,
Graham Hancock was on my podcast last
week and he's a brilliant, brilliant guy,
but he studies ancient civilizations
and people and one of the things that
they're studying now is,
um,
the various civilizations that we didn't
even know existed that existed in South
America.
Like huge,
multimillion size of population
civilizations in the Amazon,
like 20 million people living in
the Amazon at one point in time.
And they think they were wiped out by
Spanish explorers and European explorers
that came over game smallpox,
like the way they wiped out
90% of the native Americans.
They think the same thing happened
down there in the Amazon. It just,
they had huge cities down there that
European settlers had reported on.
They were just wiped out.
But the point is that we were,
we were everywhere and it's all one thing.
It's all human.
It is human race.
That's it man.
And the funny thing about white people
that are racist is that especially like
I have a neanderthal DNA
that's more primitive than
homosapien DNA and it's only
in white people. Like, it's kind
of funny that way. You know,
cause white white racists,
like they have to deal with the fact
that the only white people carry that in
the end are tall shit.
No,
I don't think that they would find that
a bad thing right at the end to talk to
you. Ain't no, I think they'd
be hell. Yeah. Oh right. Yeah.
Well they weren't smart enough to
stick around for whatever reason.
I don't even know why.
You know,
they don't know if we outbred them or we
interbred with them or if we wiped them
out. They don't even know. They're also
finding new humans that there's a human,
they found in Russia called a Dennis,
I think it's called Dennis
Olan is that he's had,
and they just found more
bones of them in Tibet.
So they know that these Russian people,
that was a totally distinct subspecies
of human travel travel to Tibet.
Yeah. And neanderthals lived
for half a million years,
so they were around way longer than we've,
uh,
we've only been around I
think for a couple hundred
thousand years. Homo, yeah. So
they were around longer than us.
Like by a factor of like somewhere
around 300,000 years. Yeah.
All over the world, man. Just
what a crazy animal we are.
We just travel everywhere and find
a spot and adapt. That's right.
We make it stay in a community so he
could help each other and live off each
other and adapt.
And unfortunately that's where all
of tribalism comes from to that,
that we have this tight knit group and
everybody else, fuck everybody else.
It's US versus them. And
that's inside of us. You know,
wouldn't it? Wouldn't
it be great? And, and,
and this is why I don't
think that it's wrong.
If you're a attacking guy,
I don't think it's wrong to be
very proud of being Italian. I,
and if you're a Polish guy,
I don't think it's, uh,
wrong to be very proud of being posed.
Why can't I be proud?
Or why can't you be proud of
being whatever race you are?
You can be proud of that.
But there's that mean that I have to
hate another guy because he's not,
no. The racing game, you can be
proud of what you are and not hate.
Another guy for being different
than what you are. How?
How about we give daddy tried?
Well, I think the feeling that you
got from the second chance on life,
this beautiful feeling of appreciation
and celebration of, of this existence,
that's what we need to try to
foster in people. Try to like,
let people know this is, this
is a temporary thing, man.
If you're lucky, like we were talking
about a hundred years. If you're lucky,
you get to a hundred years. I'm 51 I'm
halfway there, right? If I'm lucky,
if everything works out perfect and
it probably isn't, let's be honest.
Beat the shit out of my body.
Right?
So it's probably not going to
make it want to make it to be,
obviously it was what's
up. I do because I, I'm a,
I'm a science nerd. I'm, I'm,
I'm fascinated by all these three
d printed hearts and all this shit.
I want to see what the fuck they can do.
I really think,
and talking to guys like David Sinclair
and all these anti aging specialist,
I think they're on the verge of being
able to reverse aging that they're
treating aging like it's a disease.
It's a disease at the cellular
level instead of accepting
it and that like, wow,
you get older, hey, you're
going to have to accept,
you can't do as much by is not
going to work as well. Why?
Maybe that's not the case.
Maybe if they can correct certain
things about the human body,
maybe they can correct that and I think
it's very likely that in the future,
I don't think that's an
insurmountable is a situation.
I think they're gonna be able to correct.
What happens to your body when it ages,
the deterioration that's
caused by the aging process.
Your body produces less hormones, your
body starts to slow down, all timers,
all these different things.
I think they're going to be able
to correct those things. Wow.
The problem with that is then what?
We're going to live forever.
You gotta be happy living forever. Like
what if when you die, it's amazing.
What if when you died,
there really is a heaven.
You really,
we really do go to some spectacular
dimension filled with love and peace and
happiness. And there's no
emotions like we think about here.
There's no fear. There's not none
of the things that hold people back.
None of the anxiety and the angst
is just consciousness and love.
And then you're wasting your time here.
Just trying to stay alive,
taking pills to live to be a million
boy. You open up big ass can
of worms, right fit. Well,
I will tell you, um, Joe,
without a shadow of a doubt.
None whatsoever.
Death is not the end. You don't
think so? I know, I know too.
How do you know, cause I've been
dead, right? Yes, I've been there.
What about that experience
cemented in your head?
Um, when I, like I said,
it was the most peaceful.
Um,
and, and I, I don't feel like it
was the most peace, most restful,
most I was, I woke up laughing. I was,
yeah. Yeah. Ma, I was
overjoyed. You woke up,
laugh.
I was over to it.
You remember anything about what happened
when you blacked out a street at the
time? Extremely peaceful. Extreme.
I didn't have a worry.
Extremely true.
And I was not sad at all.
You know,
I was overjoyed, very
happy, very peaceful,
and it erased any fear
that I might have had.
And I, and, and any fear of dying is gone.
I don't feel that at all.
It so I made that.
Maybe that's why I didn't want to
live to be a hundred, cause I mean,
I wouldn't mind visiting that place again,
man.
It was so much peace so much and
it wasn't like, you know, um,
this is, you know, I'm just in the ground.
I'm a and I'm not a plant, uh, just
dirt,
you know,
I know that I'm in a very
comfortable place and,
and you know, I wouldn't mind
visiting again. I wouldn't mind.
So I'll definitely, I hold no fear
it. And so when I say that it's,
it's definitely not the end. You're,
I believe that your soul, you know,
so people have a different name
for consciousness of whatever.
It's definitely eternal and it has.
How else could you have these
feelings or emotions or you know,
they had that,
that sort of comfort,
the feeling of comfort and being in
the right place if something didn't
continue. Cause my life, my wife was gone.
The essence of life, my, my bindings,
you know, God, it was gone
flat line dead with him.
I told my doctor that died. He said, no,
actually it's called some kind of Paul's
or some shit like that. And I'm saying,
look, if I, if the pause lasted
doc, I wouldn't be talking to him.
So I call it a pause. Like, Oh,
well during that Paul's,
I was dead. So, uh,
it's, it was a wonderful feeling to,
well I think with a guy like you,
so physical and you've been
so physical your whole life,
the big fears to not be able to take
care of yourself or move like that's what
we're talking about when you
talk about being a hundred,
like having someone wipe your
ass and take care of you.
Like that's the big fear is not death.
Death is just peaceful. It's the end.
But the, the big fear is the
deterioration of the physical body to them
point where it's just
painful, everything's painful
and you can't go anywhere.
You can't count on
yourself. Yeah. It's uh,
it's very peaceful,
but I definitely don't think it's
the end I made just the beginning.
Yeah. Yep. And that's a,
it's an overwhelming feeling.
Like I had,
I was able to peek over into the other
side and that is definitely assurance
that it's not the ends and that there
is something else on the other side.
I have that assurance is able to
pick it, just peek into it. Well,
I think we all have this feeling that
we are something other than our body.
Most definitely.
I mean,
I,
I have that feeling like I feel like
there's like a little ball of energy in
there that moves this thing around,
but that's what it feels like.
And it always feels like
that. Yeah. That's what I,
I've always rejected the label atheist.
Like people say, are you religious?
I'm like, I was, when I was a little kid,
I had to go to Catholic school and I,
you know, I did all that jazz, but my
parents when I grew up were hippies.
After that,
my mom split up from my dad.
My mom shacked up with
my stepfather who was a,
he's a hippie and there was no,
no church after that.
But I'm not an atheist. I'm
not, I don't know. Like I,
I don't believe anybody that says they
know what life is or what life means or
what happens when you die.
I want to hear your opinions.
I want to hear your thoughts,
but you don't know.
And anybody that says they know
what happens when they die.
I know what happens when I die. It'll be
black and, and cold. And that is the end.
And just like there was nothing before,
there'll be nothing at the end. And like,
you don't know that. Yeah, you're
just saying that there is no god.
How do you say that? How do
you say that? Well, one day,
what have you stand in front of
God or, uh, in, in God's presence.
And some nonphysical form. And then
you're, you're weeping and, and your,
your arrogance and s say,
stating that there's no higher power.
Like it might be the, the
universe might be God. I mean,
we don't know anything.
We are strange little monkey people
living on this fucking planet,
making things that alter our
environment and moving around,
drive and fly and talking to each other,
talking shit. But at the end of the day,
you're only aware of what you've
experienced and when you don't know,
that's like when people have had,
I've,
I've talked to several friends at
vet near death experiences. Um,
a very good friend of mine,
she,
she was in a car accident and she had a
very similar thing where she said it was
so peaceful. Yeah. She
said, you know, they got,
I think they got rear ended and like
really bagged up and when it felt like she
was gonna die,
she felt so peaceful.
It's so true. Yeah. We got
a lot of people get, uh,
have come that close to dying. Uh, are a
lot of them are gonna say the same thing,
that they have no fear of death anymore.
It's the raised and uh,
you, you put two, you also have
the feminine back. You know,
that this existence on earth,
you when your physical body,
it's definitely not the end.
And the way she describes it
as exactly the way you do.
She's my manager and you know,
I talk to her all the time.
The way she describes things is
essentially exactly how you did that.
It's just so peaceful. Just
felt, just felt peaceful. Yeah.
But Mac, uh, you know, like
black people who don't believe
in back there. Uh, by the way,
let me, and let me say I'm
not religious either. Yeah.
I was raised super religious in
a super religious home by a us,
a pentacostal a heaven or hell brimstone
and fire and brimstone preacher and
they do the tongues. Oh
yes. Oh, that's hilarious.
Shower and uh, speaking in
tongues, everything, everything.
Everything was a sin all summer
where everybody, oh, dancing.
Dancing was listening to rock
and roll music. Yeah. Oh yeah.
Everything was us.
So I think that's really what drove
me away from being a religious person.
I'm definitely not,
I always say I'm a man of faith.
I have a tremendous amount of faith,
but faith and religion are two different
things. A lot of people confuse them.
Yeah. They, they talk about
him as being the same,
but they are definitely not a
religious man makes and you know,
a set of rules. It makes it, okay,
we're going to be this and if
you want to be this religion,
then you're gonna have to go by these
rules. And it's, it's, it's all man made,
but faith is not me and me.
And so I'm a tremendous man of faith,
but not religion.
Yeah. Some would say that like
you're a spiritual person.
That's like a thing that gets thrown
around today. Like I'm not religious,
but I'm spiritual. People say that
a lot. Like what does that mean?
No one really knows.
It's a strange sort of definition,
but I feel what you're saying that
there's something more to this.
There's something more to this than just
tissue and bone and blood moving on.
This rock that's traveling through
the universe. There's something more,
there's something, there's
something, there's some,
and maybe it's just something more for us,
but the beauty of friendship
and love and family,
like those things are intense,
beautiful emotional experiences that I,
I don't,
I don't know. They seem to
transcend just regular life itself.
They seem to have a, there is a higher
power to them, a higher beauty to them.
I think that's one of the things that
we'd like when we see people doing
something really great. We
love seeing people accomplish
things cause we, we love,
we liked seeing people succeed. We like
seeing people like that have doubts and,
and,
and something almost insurmountable and
incredibly difficult in front of them.
And then they,
they overcome and it gives us all hope
and it gives us all like this inspiration
that's feeling. We're connected in
some sort of very, very strange way.
But I think you could just chalk it
up. Oh, that's just comradery needed.
That because of evolution. That's how
we stayed alive. Like maybe, maybe,
but maybe there's something else.
Maybe the whatever this
consciousness is that's totally not,
no one has ever defined consciousness.
And there's certain people that think
that it occurs only in the brain and the
neurons and the synapses and it might war.
That might just be an antenna.
I mean consciousness might very well be,
you are using your physical tissue
to tune in to whatever this,
this thing that we share is this
life force that we all seem to share.
And when you win this, I think like
looking in someone's eyes, man,
like when,
when you know someone's like there for
you and you know you're there for them,
like that comradery, that intense
camaraderie, this, he's just like that,
that the expression,
the windows to the soul,
that the eyes are the windows to the soul.
It really does seem like that. Right?
Like you see people, you
see them, you know, like the
Avatar Lady said, I see you.
Yeah. Yeah you can. It's I'm
looking at, they didn't to look in this
in my anxieties. You can tell a lot.
You can tell if they're bullshit.
Yes, they're full of shit or not.
Or if they feel weird about something
you can secure and maybe they feel like
maybe this isn't a smart thing or maybe,
maybe,
maybe I should've done better by you.
Yeah. Maybe fucked you over. Yeah.
You can tell that. And I, uh,
I, I, I told her first,
first time I had the, uh, uh,
open heart surgery and flatlined
three times during that surgery.
I also had an experience,
um,
that also strengthens my belief in there
being something after the body dies,
I gazing or whatever you
want to call it. Uh, okay.
I see.
I was able to see my mother who had
passed away the year before and uh,
you know, I say I see my
mother, I'd add, see her face.
I heard a voice and I knew it was
her and she was pleading to a,
I say, God, a lot of people
may say, you know what,
whatever they look up to and I
ain't got no problem with that.
I don't think that, uh, because
people don't believe exactly like,
I believe that they're doom
and they're going to hell.
Although that was the way I was raised,
or if you don't believe like this, I mean,
all Catholics, when,
when I'm coaching my dad,
all Catholics were just lost.
They're not gonna make it because they
don't believe they believe the wrong shit.
Ain't no fuck that.
Don't bleed right shit there.
So of course they're not going to
make it about Jews. I'll go right.
If you don't believe,
like this is fucked up,
just lost man fucked off
man. Oh, you'll get it.
Specially you're especially lost and
that they, you know, but that's how they,
that's how they felt. That's how I was
talking to yesterday. And that just,
you know, I don't believe that you
can't, you got this, uh, my dad was,
some people they found, my dad
thought that he could walk on water,
he could do no wrong, and it's the
same guy that you knew. So, you know,
break my nose and send me to the
fucking emergency room kicking my ass.
And my mom was a slave and that
was perfectly fine with him. And,
and also this was the guy who
was fucking women in the church.
But you don't believe like,
I believe you're going to hell.
Yeah. People have a remarkable ability
to be hypocrites. Yeah. There's soup.
And I seen that so much
from super religious people.
They didn't just turn me off from
being a religious person. Well,
I think a lot of what it is is control.
People want to control the people.
They want to be able to tell people
what to do and when to do it.
And it gives them some power in
their own life by doing so. Yeah,
man, I that just a, you
know, it destroyed my, uh,
um, faith and just super, you know,
people that are in church every Sunday,
every Tuesday.
We went to church three
times a week for three times,
three times every Tuesday,
every Friday.
And every Sunday in church and churches.
I mean,
during the watts riots, I'm a
little kid. We went to church.
Wow. Yeah. The guy that soldiers
are national guard on the streets.
They pulled my dad over and a little kid
in the back seat. What are you going, uh,
I'm going to church and I'm like, fuck
these guys, this tanks on the street.
This guy's got fucking MCS 16
and asked him and my dad's like,
we're going to church. I'm like,
fuck, could you leave us at home?
We leave. I want to be at home looking
at fucking Heco with Japanese cartoons,
man. I don't want to fucking be it.
Got Man. We went to church, man.
So he was super dedicated,
you know, to, you know,
pardon was super dedicated to what
he believed. And then, um, you know,
it'd be go over the sisters Sally's
house to give her consultation and I'm
looking in the room,
her bedroom doors open as my dad would
just fucking [inaudible] sister Sally's
in her slip and shit.
And I guess me and my brother was there
to be as a scape goat or you know,
he's, excuse my mom, you know,
if I take them and you know,
nothing could be going on wrong, right?
Like I still remember that shit. Fuck.
What kind of castle tasting is he doing?
All right.
I think right now we're experiencing
some of the most insidious aspects of a,
of religion in the people attacking
people while they're worshiping Muslims
attacking Christians and
Christians attacking Muslims.
And it's like in synagogues and
Christians attacking Jews. I mean it's,
the whole thing is so insane.
While they're worshiping,
it is insane.
This sign of how fucked up things are
right now that this is something that's
happening on a regular basis now
in the name of religion.
I mean doesn't,
I mean what kind of religion
would you know say this is okay?
I mean, aren't we supposed to
love thy neighbor as thyself?
I mean the,
the Christ church one you could not,
it's hard to even say that
that was about religion.
There's more about bigotry and
racism and anything. Right.
And then the response to that is what
you're seeing in Sri Lanka and you know,
people blowing people up and in
churches and synagogues and it's just,
it's insane. It's a, it's just, we've,
we've reached this very critical moment
in our society and just civilization in
general where people are attacking
people for things that they believe in,
which is one of the most insane things
to attack people on and not attack people
because they're aggressive because
they're coming towards you.
They're trying to take away your, your
resources or harm your family. No, no, no.
They believe the wrong.
Yeah. Which one? The Kelo. Yeah. They
don't believe like hundreds of them
since Saturday. I mean, it doesn't
have to know how to fix it.
I thought the overriding principle
of most every religion is love.
Yeah.
I posted to be low.
I thought all of them taught me love.
Isn't that the overriding
principle of religion?
Your religion?
Doesn't it teach you to love people?
If you're really to teach you to hate
people to go out and kill people,
then something's fucked.
Yeah. Yeah. It's supposed to
be reinforcing this idea of,
of community, of we're all together
working towards a goal that's wrong.
Yeah. It's, uh, I mean it's
some, I mean, there's so many,
right? There's so many issues
with, uh, with poverty, with crime,
with all these different things
in this world today. But the,
the religion issue and the hatred,
hatred of other people's
Religions has gotta be one of the,
one of the strangest aspects of
our community or our cultures.
It's so crazy, man. I, man, I,
I just want to do everything that
I possibly can possibly can do.
And I, you know, I'm just a little
guy from Compton. Nobody knows me.
Nobody knew who the fuck is CP fucker
ain't nobody but whatever I can possibly
do to try to bring people together,
man,
let it just come together and
lobby that I had, it's this thing,
we're all the same under the bar. That's
my equivalent of trying to, you know,
bring people in. A weightlifting says
a similar thing from all the same.
We're all brothers and sisters on the
maths. Sadly. That's exactly what it is.
That's,
that's a thing sometimes you know, when
someone has like this common struggle,
like, like you find out a lot about
someone when you lift with them, right?
When you know that they can do 10 and
they can start pitching out at seven like,
come on Bro, steer your spirit. Come on.
I mean that's,
that's similar in,
I mean marathon runners have
that sort of camaraderie,
that feeling like what if someone can
can actually complete marathons and then
ultra marathons.
If you have the girl doesn't know it,
no one gives a fuck of your Chinese
or black or a girl or a boy,
you're a bad motherfucker or you are not.
If you are not,
you should work towards becoming one.
Yeah. I mean that's MMA, right? Yeah.
That's martial arts in general.
I mean it's all about a vehicle for
developing your human potential.
I've always said that one of the best
ways to stop bullying and stop all this,
I mean it sounds counterproductive
and counterintuitive,
but that's stop bullying. Teach
kids how to fight. They won't fuck.
They won't do that man. I mean and the the
ones who are the strongest, they won't,
they won't have this need to
impose on people. They don't.
That doesn't exist in Jujitsu
the way it exists in, in,
in kids because kids are insecure and
they have this weapon being bigger or
being mean or, or being more
aggressive and scaring kids. And they,
they see someone intimidated and they
can't help himself because they don't have
any guidance. They don't have, they don't.
No one's taught them the proper way to
behave and think and then no one's taught
them the consequences of that shitty
behavior and thinking they just get away
with it. They do it and they don't think
that it's hurting anybody or they don't,
they don't care. They don't feel it
yet, but just numb to it. They're not,
they're not, they haven't been taught.
No, there have not been taught this is,
this is the way that I can stand out.
Yeah.
And a lot of it is because
like they need a real cause.
They need a real,
something real to work towards
instead of like looking for conflict.
And some fucking kid is looking at
you at the bus stop, weird. Look for,
find real conflict,
find something that you could really
work towards and you'll feel better about
yourself and you'll feel better about
the way you communicate other people.
It's one of the reasons why a
lot of people talk about Jujitsu,
like it's a religion.
And in some ways I think it kind of is
because you learn not in the bad ways,
but in the good way is that you learn
this sense of community through struggle.
Right. I think the same thing could
be said for weightlifters too.
There's a bond you guys,
man, and it's, it translates,
it's sold.
Maybe MMA guys that you know,
have come through the Amtrak train,
uh,
worked out and it's so relatable.
Good weightlifting her of
the fighting world. Uh,
except for not getting busted upside
the head when you're in the gym.
But that struggle though. Yeah. This truck
I saw when you trained Tyron Woodley.
Oh Man. Sort of struggle. Yeah. Yeah.
And He's another dude that
looks like he's on steroids,
but he's not answering me.
Just,
he got that fucking beautiful roll of
the dice and Jane had a girl the dice.
That's exactly right. And by the
way, Tyrone, if you're listening,
you would have not been back.
And I worked like for you to come back
to do the type of fighting that he does
though. You can't really lift
the way you had them left
all the time. No, no, no, no,
no, no. Uh, no.
It would just be a incorporates most most
fires just choose a weight lifting as
a tool. Yeah. And just when they come,
they want to test themselves when they
come and train with me this time I just
want to see and what I do, I can
take, it can take you to nine,
you know, motherfucking side
no matter what. No matter what.
And knows.
Those guys do really well because it's
so much mental chore involved in it,
you know? And, and they,
they're the mind to tough.
Even make guys minds are tougher.
Nick. They do real well. No,
you don't get tougher. It just, you just
got off. You just get different, you know,
I mean, like I said about
ultra marathon runners or any,
anybody who does anything that's
extremely grueling and brutal. You don't,
you don't get taught for you just to
find a different different path. Exactly.
That's sort of tough and
it always leaks through.
The mine they passed always leaks through
the mind, man, that whole expression,
that idle hands are the devil's
play things. That's so true.
That's so goddamn true.
People need, they need,
sometimes they need a cause and
you just struggle. They need,
they need something hard.
They need something difficult to define
themselves through. If they don't,
they just,
they get scattered and insecure and crazy.
But through that struggle you, you
gained confidence and character. You,
you know who you are. I'm like, no man.
You could pull off a workout
with CT Fletcher at the
end of that fucking workout
and you sitting there on that bench
drinking water. I know. Who the fuck
did it? People need to know that they
did it. Yeah. Need that they need,
I did it. You need, I did it all the time.
You need, I did it like five days a week.
It's true. If I take a couple
of days off, I feel like, man,
I gotta go do something. I
don't feel bad. Yeah. Too Bad.
I still won't do the shit in the
had to kick I show. Yeah, man.
Right now it's slow.
They cover a little more.
The good thing is, the best
way to learn is slow. Oh,
well I'm ready to tackle the
real slow. Yeah. The people,
the real problem with strong people is
that they want to put their strength into
it, you know, and you know, you want to
like really just fucking drunk. Yeah.
It's a hard for strong dudes to learn
how to kick properly. It really is.
It's a perfect time for Peter Marino.
Take tickets.
They put so much grunt into everything.
Oftentimes they're not pivoting,
so they put too much pressure on their
leg. They want to pop in their knee. Yeah.
I mean there's a lot, a lot
of shit kicking man. Sick. God
chill.
He's got some of the meetings kicks
I have ever seen from anybody.
I'm like, I didn't know you could kick
it. Fuck it. It's a funny thing. Um,
there's a guy named John Dawn her
who's a Jujitsu genius and uh,
he came to me once and it turned out he
actually knew, but he was playing it off.
Like he didn't know.
He was telling me that he wanted George
St Pierre who is the champion of the
time.
I know of my,
they wanted him to get some coaching
on his, a spinning back kick.
There was like a, he's a, he thinks
the fundamentals are a little bit off.
Do you know anybody? And I was like,
alright, this is gonna sound crazy.
I know I'm a comedian and a no,
I'm just a commentator, but I,
I have a really good spinning back.
I'm like,
I could show you how to do it and I
can show you as good as any human being
that's ever lived. I'm like, I could show
you how to do that. That was my shit.
I mean, but when I was
a kid, man, I, you know,
it's hard for me to even talk about it
now because it seems like a different
life,
like a different person for from the time
I was 15 till I was 21 I was obsessed.
I trained all day, every day.
I mean, that's what I did.
I basically lived there and so that's
why I developed all that opp station.
They say it's a bad word. I don't
think so. No. The find my life.
It's about life, you know? I
mean, I've had a good life.
I've had a good life through obsession
now coined that phrase. I'm
also at a good rifle. Shit.
I'm careful with that shit.
Like a bad dog.
I keep that motherfucker on a leash and
I keep it away from the wrong people.
Got some good savings. You have
to be careful. Like Jamie knows,
we've been having problems
with his goddamn quake game.
We play play this video games,
first person shooter called quake,
and I have a real problem. I
get obsessed with things. Well,
I want to play all day long.
I want to play fucking eight,
10 hours a day. I can't,
I don't allow myself to,
but that's the same thing.
It's the same thing that got me
into martial when I was a kid.
I have a fucked up brain,
but it's fucked up in a good it.
As long as I know how to guide it,
as long as the,
the managers in the building and the
manager is me right now going, hey,
settle the fuck down. All right. You
got shit to do. You've got a family.
Got Stuff to do.
You can't just go run off
and decide you're going to
be a professional this or a
professional dad because that's
what my brain wants to do.
My brain wants to find something
and go with what's this thing? Okay,
what's the be the best in the world?
We're going to be the best in the
world test. This is what this is.
Every day you're gonna wake up and didn't
know, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
I got pay taxes.
You got shit.
I fucking love it too because
you are not alone now.
There's a bunch of us,
a whole lot of them were in the UFC.
Yeah. It's a whole lot of mouth.
Their jobs running crazy going crazy.
Like tapping the things on the desk just
can't wait to get at to what the fuck
they want to do when they get off work.
Ain't that something fucking 28
years at the post office man.
I hate thinking about,
you know, go do what I really yeah. Yeah.
It's a lot of people out there listening
that have that same feeling. Oh Man.
Punching the clock every day
and they fucking hate it.
You know, you're not alone.
Not alone years. I hated it whenever
I had a job, whatever job I had,
I fucking hated that.
And I had a bunch of part time bullshit
jobs cause I wouldn't take a real job on
because I was so scared that if I had
like a real nine to five and then started
getting a career and then have a family
got married, they trapped, dropped.
I was in, that was me. I was definitely
trapping and kids at home and had to eat.
So yeah, nothing you got to, I mean,
and then you take that time when you get
off and that's your obsession time then.
Yeah. I mean there's a lot of people
that live that life, you know,
and but I've always tell people is
before you have all those other things,
a mortgage and family and
all that other stuff, damn.
To funnel that energy into you to
what you like. You could live up
wonderful existence and charmed
life if you could do what I mean.
Whatever it is.
What do you like making knives are fucking
painting whatever the fuck you like
to do. If that's your thing and you
think about it all the time, God damn,
you got to find a way to do that.
That is your call.
Most definitely excellent
advice from Joe Rogan. He's so,
so right. And before you
get, you know the wife,
the kids because then you
trap. Yeah. But the minds,
everyone's mind is so different.
You know,
there's some people that they don't have
that obsessed mine. Their mind is like,
they're, they're better
off like, you know,
running a country store somewhere.
Just being real friendly to people
that come in and being a baker,
making good food for folks. That's their
thing. That's their calling and that,
you know, that's perfectly
fine. It's the people, you know,
people that annoy the fuck out of me.
I love you.
What's your annoy the fuck out
of me is people that have no,
no drive whatsoever.
I'm just happy not doing shit.
I always wonder about that.
I was,
I was wondering like what if I
got them when they were little?
What if I got ahold of them
when they were little and,
and just introduced them to
exciting things and rewarded
them when they did well
and high five them and hugged them.
You know what I mean?
Like it could possibly change
reinforcement of,
of positive goals and reinforcement
of positive experiences.
I think there's some people that just,
they never got any of that and everything
was just work and just drudgery and
they'd rather just lay around because
that is the alternative to work and
drudgery.
Wow.
Um,
I gave a a speech and I'm talking about
obsession session and being driven and
all those, and you know, one
of the questions Africans,
because the guy was asking
me, so, uh, what if you know,
what if you don't want to do anything,
you don't have any goals or upsetting,
uh,
could you tell me how to get one?
And I was like,
fuck,
how do I tell this motherfucker his,
you know,
he won. He Won. He said he won. He
Won. I want to find the goal was him,
but I don't know you, I
don't know. I don't know.
This the first time I ever met you
and you're asking me how to give you,
uh, an obsession or, or
make him give you an idea.
I only thing I can tell you is fine.
Something.
Do you have anything that you'd love?
Is there anything that you love?
Anything that you'd like to do,
then you know,
start the head start if you it.
If the person looks back at you and
says, no, not rarely, then I'm like,
fuck,
this dude is irking the fuck
you mean you don't have any fucking thing.
I know some people that have nothing.
Yeah.
Some people it is nothing and there's
nothing. Absolutely. And that, you know,
I you, I love you guys, but um,
he bugged the fuck out of me.
But just,
you don't have a calls or go or
nothing that really excites you,
that you really want to make a difference.
You just,
you're happy being blind,
frayed and fucking every image.
I just want to be a Kog man.
I just want to be a fucking car.
World needs cogs. Do you think that some
people are like, here's, here's a thought.
Like not everybody but could be
a fucking psychopath right now.
Not everybody can be obsessed by things.
The world will be too insane and regular
stuff would never get done. Right.
You and I aren't getting
regular shit done, you know?
But how about being the
best fucking cock bear is
best fucking cod varies man. I'm going
to support the fuck guy to Joe road.
Oh Man, I don't know what people, I don't,
I would like to add,
I think one day we're going to probably
be able to experience this through
technology.
I would like to know how people think
like go well I would like to know like
what is going on in someone's head
when they experience like some,
sometimes things will happen to you
in life and you're just in the worst
possible state of mind when it happens
and sometimes it's the best possible
state of mind and sometimes when
it's the best possible state of mind,
something that should be like
catastrophic, like Eh, it'll be all right.
You don't like the person who
did it to you. Like, look man,
I know he didn't mean to do. It's all
right, don't worry about it. Take it easy.
And then you just drop it and
you like feel good about it.
And then other times like fuck that guy,
I'm going to fucking kill that guy.
And it's all like, it's all in
white. How were you wired that day?
Like what, what's, how
are you coming into it?
You coming into this with a lot of stress,
you've got a lot of other bullshit
piling up in your life or you coming into
this fresh off a heart transplant where
you feel love for the world and you and
you have like a new found enlightenment
where you realize that this is all
bullshit, all this nonsense and
fighting and arguing for nothing.
Like why, why you do you enjoy, relax.
I appreciate
mad or just think that's serious
passion for your existence
and what you enjoy,
what you truly love and your friends
and Camaraderie and fellowship.
That's what it's all about.
Yeah. And I think, uh, you know,
they got a whole field,
the psychologist and psychiatrist who
that's their field and some of the worst,
uh,
some of the most mentally challenged
people I've ever met were psychiatrist.
I'm like, what though? Have
a theory about that. Yeah,
I have a theory about that.
I've theory about that.
That's very similar in my
theory about cops. You know,
I have a deep respect for
cops. Neat too. And uh,
I think it's insanely difficult job.
Just same my same feeling
I have for soldiers.
Like you cannot expect someone to
just do that with no guidance and no,
no. You have to have an
appreciation for this trust.
They go through every time
a cop pull somebody over,
this might be the last
moment of their life.
Every time they come to that window and
it's tinted and they don't know who the
fuck is in there and what kind
of warrant that guy might have.
They don't have any idea.
And we've all seen videos online and cops
getting shot and people getting killed.
It fucking happens. And everyone
they're dealing with is lying to them.
Everyone they're dealing with is,
if you're a psychiatrist,
every day you're dealing with
people who are fucked every day.
Everyone's fucked up.
Everyone's and some,
some of their fucked up is nonsense and
you just want to grab them and shake
them by the call and get your
fucking shit together. Man,
the fuck is wrong with you. Come on.
You know there's something wrong.
Stop doing what you're doing stupid.
But you can't even say that,
so you have to go. So Mike, um,
uh, you know, uh, you're, you're,
you're still getting tied up by that
woman and she still kicks in the balls
because he should,
the people are into like every day
you showing up and everyone's nuts.
Everyone you work with, you know,
I'm very fortunate. I show up here,
I get to talk to nice people like you.
I hang out with great people like
Jamie and every, everyone's fun here.
It's all nice. My experiences on a
daily basis are very mostly positive.
I go to the comedy store, hanging out
with comedians. Did you do to, hang on?
What'd you do to guys?
It's fun experiences or good experiences.
Psychiatrists are just dealing
with crazy vox all day long.
That's the chosen foggy gap to deal
with next. Yeah. When I was, um,
when I was briefly
college,
one of the things that I was concentrating
on with psychology because I was
trying to find out what can,
I knew there was times when I fought and
I was very confident and I knew there
was times that I felt that it was a
nervous wreck. And I was like, why?
What is that, that feeling of nerves?
Were you scared? It's very compromising.
If it fucks my performance.
Oh, more guy. Yeah. I mean,
look, you, you might get hit,
you might lose it. This could happen.
But to dwell on that, it's crippling.
Like you gotta be able to
accept those consequences,
but you also have to not dwell,
save to be zen.
And so I was reading a lot of
psychology books and philosophy books,
a lot of Samurai books.
And um,
but one thing I realized that in
talking to people that were like,
psychologists are psychology majors.
Like you're dealing with
fucked up people all the time,
especially psychiatrists.
Oh, fuck up people.
And then they're prescribing
them drug right there.
You're going to get out of here,
take this.
Yes, we're getting numb. Crazy man.
He was crazy. Very nice
guy, but was great.
I think you get crazy.
I think you get crazy dealing with all
those people all the time too, man. Yeah.
I mean,
if your day is blocked off,
you have your secretary and then
you've got patients all day long.
They're out of their fucking,
yeah.
Yeah. Very good point. It's
a terrible diet, you know.
But you know, I don't know if
you knew, but I used to, um,
do tournaments, fighting a
karate style, right? Yeah. Yeah.
And the reason the,
what discouraged me or made me know that
I didn't want to be a Friday was just
what you described,
anxiety. Oh yeah. It would,
it was paralyzing. It was
paralyzing. Yeah. I mean,
I'd be frozen with it. It's,
it's so crazy that I'm going to,
last term,
I was an ed Parker's a international
variety tangling ships in Long Beach,
California.
And I knew they'd fight
until my feet worse stuck.
And I was a taekwondo black belt,
but my feet were frozen to the fucking
man. I couldn't lift them like an ace.
Wait a thousand pounds each. Me and I
was so paranoid because all these people,
it was always people around.
And I was so afraid that I was going
to do something to embarrass myself.
And I'm like, oh my God, everybody's
looking and then you know, I'll sit,
but the Max is going on at the same time.
But it felt like everybody was
looking at me and I'm like, man,
they got to watch them through something.
My technique's going to
be wrong or it's got,
I'm just going to fuck up
in front end of the, the,
the fear was paralyzing him. Like,
you know, I can't fucking do this.
I'm not cut out to be a fighter man. I
just can't, the press just kicked my,
I think to overcome. Oh, that's
hard to sort your way through it.
And it's what's really hard for a lot
of fighters has come back from a loss.
They get beat up and smashed and then
then they have to come back and figure out
a way through, you know, and um,
that's a devastating loss of quotes,
you see, isn't yet but devastating.
No Raymond Daniels is,
oh, of course they go.
Did you see his fight this past weekend?
Do you see that 720 degree punch?
So go to Bellatore they
find that clip man. Aye.
Well we won't be able to show
it. Right. I can show you guys.
Just show us for folks who don't know.
Well,
one of the reasons I brought up Raymond,
Danielle says Raymond Daniels. Oh,
he's a belt or kickboxing champion.
Now he lost in devastating fashion to
Nikki Holt skin who's a another world
champion. And uh, also to Joseph
Valtellina who's another world champion.
So when he was making the transition from
karate champion to kickboxing champion,
he had some stumbling. Yeah, it made,
it didn't, didn't go 100% smooth,
but that guy's got an iron will
man,
um,
stunt coordinators and
move. Yes. Watch this.
Look at Ray Mactan.
Raymond Daniels.
Wow. That's fucking, it's fucking crazy.
He went for a three 60 roundhouse kick.
Dude wasn't there and then he continued
to spend further and boom. I mean,
that is insane. That is
such an incident. The land,
a punch at the end of that.
I mean is so bananas and he
landed a spinning back kick
to the body right before
bed too. Yeah. I mean he did a thing,
find the thing he did in um, in, in glory.
He did a jumping sidekicks, spinning back
kick combination where he touched him.
He touched him with the front leg and
then spun in the air and spinning back
kick areas right here.
Yeah.
I mean this is fucking crazy.
He watched watch how he does
let, let this go. Here it goes.
Watch he touches up.
Oh, Ooh. Shit. And World
Class kickboxer like,
that's what I'm saying.
I mean the movie or looking at
his highlights to come up with,
you know,
fight free dude.
If there's stuff that they don't even
do in the movies in a real fight. Yeah.
Yeah. He's hard to handle. He,
he uh,
a pep talk or speaks into a group
of fighters. He was in the group.
They came out and then I got it.
I got to meet. I was like, man,
I don't know all his fan. A fan boy. Big
Time. All right. Again, I'm saying like,
damn mother fucker.
I love watching those guys and like
guys like Michael Venom and Paige was
another one who has those karate skills,
but then they're learning all the skills
of MMA and then you see, look man,
if you don't know that karate style,
and he knows MMA,
like you're kind of fucked because they
didn't do shit. That's like outlandish,
you know, venom page Landis Shit.
It's ridiculous. And he's,
he's so long too. And his,
his timing and movement
is so unpredictable and he
could sprint at you and you
don't even know all of a
sudden, Bang. He's punching
him in the face. You saw that,
that knockout when he knocked out cyborg
and caved his head in with that knee
cave the man's head.
And I've seen thousands of fights.
I never saw a man get his head caved in,
ever hard to lead his phone.
Look at that.
Look at his skull. His,
his head is pushed in.
I mean that was six
that the video above it.
Does that show the actual
knockout? No, that's not it.
But look how he fights to
hands down. I mean, that is
the scene writhing in agony.
Like that.
I remember his fight with, uh, it
was one of the best MMA fights.
Every real muscular guy.
He's real muscular. Cyborg.
Cyborg had a fight with
this. I never, oh, he's,
he's kind of on the down hill now,
but at one time he was like
the Mike Tyson of MMA we built,
I know, you know what I'm talking about.
You that was a man whose yes. Yeah,
I knew you knew what you see.
Cyborg.
Yeah. It's a mother fucker, man. Ooh.
He's another one man. Yeah. Came
from that. Uh, he's, he comes from,
um,
Mike's gym in Holland,
which is a famous kickboxing
gym for savages. Just,
just wore the young, a
young man. What's up?
I can see. Oh, there it is. Woo.
And Melvin is built like a fucking,
he was another one.
Unbelievable power and speed
when he was in his prime,
but he's not the same anymore.
You're right.
Wars. But man, that dude was super
and he always wore those gladiator
jokes too. Here's a piece of my,
one of my favorites,
but that showed you how tough Cyborg was.
That was a war that was in cage warriors.
I think that was the name.
That was the war. Yeah. Yeah. I'm in.
I've had the privilege watching
so many great fighters fight.
It's interesting to watch all of
the different styles and all that,
but the thing that they all have,
all the great ones,
they have this unstoppable belief in
themselves. Even if they lose, they just,
they learn, they lose, they learn
to come back. They get better.
Favorite interviews was
hoists Gracie and man, uh,
his mentality, he says, you know,
I make no plans for after the fright.
Yeah. Of these guys guys.
Fucking, they're ready to die.
He's not saying I hate.
See, I see guys, man.
I'm talking about the after party and
meet me over here. Say, no, no, no.
I am prepared to die in
hell. Yeah. Shit up Joe.
Because I was prepared to die
on the weightlifting platform.
The doc says, Hey, if you go see
tea, you're able to have kicked,
burst right there on stage you dying
for, and all those people. Good.
That's the way I was.
If you want to,
if you want real greatness,
you have to be able to give it all away,
but to find somebody else does that crazy.
I was like me,
I thought I was the only one.
Did you see the middleweight championship
fight between Calvin gas Lum and a
Israel at a Sonia a style bender?
Did you see that fight? Of course,
right before the fifth round.
It means a close fight and style.
Bender came out and just
destroyed in the fifth round,
but right before that he said,
I'm ready to die. He says
he's looking at him. He goes, I'm
ready to die. I heard that man.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
That was one of those believeable moment.
I love Kevin Calvin.
He's a beast. He was a great, he was
also at the top is speaks to that.
Gave him rd coat. Kevin was
there and saying, young guy, man,
and he's still a young guy and he
really should be finding one's heaven.
Honestly. You mean he's, yeah, I mean
he fought at one seven and he just,
he likes to eat. You know
how hard, I really don't.
Guy and Kevin, if you listen, I
love you man. Kelvin's a beast.
He's not even near his full potential yet.
Style bender is either
young guy, stop vendors better now than
he was in his first fight in the UFC,
which was only about 16 months ago.
He's better now.
He's trouble for anybody man. But he's
in his house and he, that guy has some,
he's probably the most technical
striker that's ever fought in the UFC.
So tactical. But um, okay.
Let me ask you about this.
I heard a rumor of him
and John Jones. No, no,
each other.
Oh yeah.
John was talking shit about him
and he was talking shit about John,
you know that maybe they'll fight.
John is way bigger. John's a big man.
Yes.
Yeah.
And he's bad motherfucker man.
I mean maybe one day they
could fight. But John, I
think John's futures in heavyweight.
I really do.
I think John is going to clean out the
light heavyweight division and then move
up and I think he's probably going to
try to catch DC before DC steps out
because DC is going to fight
against deep Amy. Oh chick,
they're going to have a rematch.
And then I think DC versus John Jones is
probably what? Yeah, heavy heavyweight.
I think John, what's go up there and
take that heavyweight title, you know,
but I think DC has a better
chance against him at heavyweight.
I don't think DC liked cutting weight
and I don't think it's good for his
performance or his durability
or anything. You know, I think,
I mean judging by his
fights with Derek Lewis,
who's a fucking huge guy
and knocking out Steve,
a mule chick who's nobody's ever
been able to do it like that before,
the way DC did it mean DC says that
heavyweight, he's just way more powerful,
hits harder, takes a punch better,
you know? I mean, he's not tall guy,
he's the only five 11 but he's
as wide as this fucking table.
DC's a tank of a man,
his wrestling of booties for now.
But that's why as John so God damn
impressive at John took him down.
John went right at them with
wrestling. It's like, motherfucker,
I'm going to take you down and scare you.
My favorite
food is if he's not the greatest of
all time, he's in a conversation.
He's in a conversation that's like me.
My opinion is that mighty mouse
Johnson's the greatest of all time,
but the caveat is that mighty mouse never
really fought the Caribou caliber of
competition that John jumped it.
Jon Jones first fight in
the UFC at for a title.
He's fighting Mauricio Shogun
[inaudible] who is a legend.
That's John's first fight.
John Opens up with a flying knee.
It's a legend, you know, chokes. Liotta
Machida, completely unconscious. You know,
chokes out rampage. Chokes out.
He's just just smashed everybody.
John smashed everybody. He's only
lost one time. That's a bullshit loss.
Loss of disqualification. The fight that
he was dominated. Yeah. He's afraid, man.
He's a real free.
It most definitely is my favorite,
especially since he told him he
listens to my eggs before I fight.
I always listen to your, I am
the one speech Ct. Hell yes.
He's something special for definitely yes
he is something special and I think um,
you know he's had some troubles in his
life and troubles but I think he's got
that shit behind him. I really
do. And I think he's, you know,
he hasn't had a near death experience but
I think he's had so many you like near
career experiences that
he appreciates it now.
And I also think to be that good,
you got to be fucking crazy and I think
Jon Jones is fucking crazy and he's just
getting his crazy online.
He's just getting his crazy and order
like keep my crazy and under wraps.
Just keep my crazy together.
Going to be that good.
You got to be a wild motherfucker.
Oh you gotta be wild if that's,
that's what he is.
He's smart too though.
He's got like the perfect combination
of things like smart and wild and
physically talented like and then, and
then long, long as for the weight class,
he's very strong toes lifting man.
I get time tones into
the belly of the beast.
Maybe after the fight with Tiago Santos
still have some time off, but he, uh,
it's interesting,
his coaches thought that his
powerlifting was a bad idea for him.
Apparently not coaches.
They think that he got really into
that before the OSP fight. Man,
we had a big stretch of time often in
the OSP fight. He didn't look as good,
but I credit that to Osp.
I just think that OSP fought real hard
fight and he's a real big strong guy and
he's fucking dangerous and I think
improves a piece.
I think that it's just one of those
things where stylistically, you know,
[inaudible] fought a really
good fight and I mean,
opens had a broken arm for I think the
last round that round with a fucking
shattered arm.
Never let anybody know then say a Goddamn
word about his forearms snapped for me.
Tell some base to do that.
It's the hardest game in the world.
Next to being a cop or a
firefighter or a soldier.
MMA fighters the hardest came in
the world. Yeah, I totally agree.
Um,
gratitude brought up soldiers because
I'm a [inaudible] through myself and I,
you know, I have a lot
to have a, um, PTSD.
I was hoping that during the conversation
we could get a PTSD in there some kind
of way because my [inaudible]
bad, uh, suffered from PTSD big time.
He went in the Korean
War and eight, 16, uh,
he got a guy, yeah, he had
a guy, a signed form, uh,
and said he was his
dad and he was able to,
to get in for a while like
that. And that was, uh, uh,
I,
that was,
I give him a pass on a lot of the
crazy shit he did because of that.
Right. You know, he never sit down and
had a conversation with me about it.
I never talked to my dad for
more than five minutes at a time,
you know,
and when I talked to him growing up,
never be more than five minutes at a time.
And in our whole life,
my whole life, you know, he died
when he was 86 and I'm 50 something.
I was 57,
eight,
somewhere around there before we had
maybe 10 minute conversation that was just
apologizing to him for,
you know, hating him. Yeah.
We talked about this,
but he had the kid,
when they call it a shell shot back then.
So I explained to me it was an
explanation for a lot of his, uh,
um, over the top behavior. I can't
imagine myself at 16 being, you know,
gun fires in dead dead guys all around
me. I know I would have been, uh,
uh, I'll mental mess also.
So I gave him a lot of, uh,
and it's such a problem now PTSD with
soldiers now they have the 21 pushups for
21 veterans who kill themselves
every day, uh, from Ptsd.
So it's a big cause for
me. I want to, you know,
do everything I can do you try to bring,
and we're in this for the,
my fellow veterans out there
that are suffering from that too.
So I'm with you guys.
I'm with the Vicks. Yeah.
So what we were talking about before to
ask someone to be able to get through
that.
Yeah, it's an, it's incredible ass. I want
to ask you your opinion about something.
So do you think a police
chief or F F up guy can be,
do you think a guy can possibly rise to
police chief without ever having been an
officer himself?
It doesn't seem like it should be.
Okay.
Do you think a guy can be a fire chief
without ever having been a fire man
himself?
Doesn't seem like you should be.
Do you think a guy can be the commander
in chief of our armed forces without
ever having been a soldier himself?
Doesn't seem like you should.
Thank you Joe.
I think it's way too easy to be
commander in chief. Like how many,
how many people would, if that was like
a prerequisite you had to serve like uh,
like in the Israeli army, if you're in
the Israeli army, everyone has to serve.
There's a certain amount of time everyone
has to put in the South Korean army.
Same thing you have to serve.
You know,
a chance on John who's a top level UFC
fighter took two years off his career
because that was the requirement with the
South Korean army. They had him serve.
Um,
I think that if you are going to be able
to tell people where they go and that
they have the risk of their life on a
campaign that many people might think is
fruitless or even worse,
many people might think it's
financially motivated and not necessary.
And you're asking some someone's son to
go over there and die for that preach.
Yes, you, you should have
some understanding about what
you're saying. You should,
you should have served.
I think it's possible for you
to have a good understanding,
a grasp of what you're asking.
If you haven't experienced it yourself.
But now let's go back and
look at all the presidents.
How many of them serve Barack
Obama never served. George W.
Bush didn't serve, but George Herbert
Walker Bush served and you know,
he's actually shot down in World War
II, right? Um, Clinton never served.
Nixon ever served. I
mean you, you got to go.
Got It.
And I,
and I think that none of them have been
able to be commander in chief of the
armed forces. That's just my
feeling. If you didn't serve,
you said they got plenty of
generals that could feel that spot.
Yeah. I think that they
should change whatever they
need to change whatever wall,
whatever it is to change that to commander
and chief of the armed forces has to
be, has to be us, have been a soldier.
They have a lot of five star generals.
A lot of guys at the top that
have been in the military.
Did that know what they're uh,
experience.
Let them be the commander
in chief of the army.
These are the 12 presidents who did
not serve in the military. So wait,
wait a minute. That Nixon did. Nixon
served commander naval reserve.
It says Oh, neighbor was okay. Um,
but Clinton didn't know FDR,
Hoover Coolidge hardy.
Interesting. But um,
George W w Bush didn't serve.
Did he think he was a reserve for a
small period of time or something? Oh,
that's right. Yeah. There were
some shenanigans for, they
got, they got them out of,
I think Trump had like eight deferments,
like feet,
her phone sprayers.
How do you get bone spurs,
but never working out ever. How did that
happen? He's kind of funny though, man.
The,
the not working out thing.
He thinks his body's like a battery and
then thinks like if you, you work out,
you use up your, your juice. Ooh, that is,
you've got a finite number of
heartbeats or something like that.
Is that what he said? Yeah. There's
other people that believe that too.
I've looked it up too.
But they do believe that that's the case.
But here's the thing, when you train
you, it lowers your heart rate.
That's what we didn't understand.
Like Michael Bisping as a 34 beats
per minute resting heart rate. Yeah.
Most fat fucks out there have
like 78 80 you know that they're,
they're wasting mirror. I'd like
to run this super low. Yeah.
And then when you take him speed,
right pills,
he's just described me as a fat fuck.
It was like 78 eight no, no, no, no,
no, no. You ain't a fat fuck.
You know what I'm saying?
But if even if that is true,
I mean there's no real evidence
that that's what it is. True.
I think, um, yeah,
I think anybody that is going to tell
people they have to fight for our country
should have had to fight most or at
least should have had to serve, serve.
You don't have to necessarily
have had military.
I mean it's not your fault if
you didn't see actually. Right,
right. Yeah, I agree with
that. You know, amount of calm,
you don't have to be a combat death,
but it is being have been willing
that when do you were cold
yes. To accept the call
and step up and you know,
we cause by doing that you're saying and
when I signed this piece of paper that
I don't know if there's going to be
conflict, there's going to be a war not,
but I'm signing up. If
there is, I'm available.
I'm here man. And so we're always hoping
for the best, right. With presidents.
But it always disappoints us like, no,
no one, no one's been the most amazing.
No one has ever like the one person,
when you look back and go, man,
that mother fucker nailed everything.
They got it right.
They got it right with whistle blowers.
They got it right with human rights.
They got it right with freedom of speech.
They got it right with everything.
You've got it right with
military intervention,
they got it right with regime change wars,
they got it right with everything they
did do. Didn't do anything wrong and man,
everybody should be like them.
Like a lot of goofy people look back
to like Ronald Reagan like this,
an old Ronald Reagan.
He was our guy like just that's just cause
it's a long time ago and you remember
sucks. I remember, I remember when
people fucking hated Ronald Reagan. Man,
I remember when they were trying to
get him out of office like that wasn't,
that one didn't work either. No one. No
one's good at the job. They're going to.
Boy, you got to get a lot of
comments on man. It's true though.
It's an impossible job to please.
Everybody is always an impossible.
It's impossible thing. No, I don't
know anybody who, not everybody,
but the idea that one person is going
to oversee every branch of government,
the military, the economy, social issues,
censorship,
big tech problems with the environment.
Like what the fuck are you crazy?
How could one person do all that?
It's not possible.
It's not possible and do a
wonderful job at it all too.
Right?
I mean I,
I don't understand how
it's even humanly possible.
I don't think a human,
I think that job should be,
there should be a council of wise people
decide things and we should be able to
decide whether or not they're
wise. You know what I mean?
There should be, I guess,
I guess that's what the
Lex and in Congress,
that's supposedly what that I guess,
yes, that's what it's supposed to be.
It's also like it's too easy to vote.
I mean it's too easy to just say, ah,
that guy, that guy. You should
be able to tell me why that guy.
Like what's your reasoning?
Does it make sense?
Did you think this through you just like,
that guy's a republican.
I'm a Republican. Fuck it. Is that what
you're doing? Like what are you doing?
Like you,
you'd making these choices and you know,
you throw on your mark on this piece of
paper and that could affect the way the
world swings. Like what's the thought
process behind it? So easy people.
So they have to explain that.
I don't because I don't think that,
I think the right to vote should not be
anything that's infringed upon in any
way,
shape or form.
But it would be a lot better if people
knew what the fuck they were voting on.
It would help. It would help if
they had a real understanding of it,
but people don't have the time. That's
the other problem. Then you know,
we're talking about people slaving away
all day. If someone's working all day,
eight hours a day,
how much time do they really
have to research foreign
policy and which time they
have to research what's going wrong
with the economy, sub, you know,
sub prime interest rate loans and all
that shit. Oh, how much time do people,
they're concerned about what's going on
in their family and they're trying to
get laid. And the triangle and they
want to get to the game and uh,
they got tickets already.
Fucking the vendors are
out there three hours long.
I stayed awake. I haven't seen it yet.
I stayed awake. I heard it's great.
Good enough to keep me awake. That's,
that's, uh, at saying something from the,
I go to sleep off with time from the heart
transplant or you sleep beer now? No,
no. I went to sleep all the time
before Doris get comfortable.
Fucking it's over, man. Yeah.
Well that's the thing too,
when people train a already fucking with.
Yeah.
If you train a lot though,
you're always ready to take a nap because
your body is always like recovering.
I'm out. Oh, proud.
Or overtraining is bullshit. You think,
look for trainings. Bullshit. Oh,
I know you don't.
I think I picked to think that it's not
bullshit and overtrained is very real.
Don't you try it? Yes, I do. And who
you would say that you know what?
Rhabdomyolysis is a no, I
have no idea. When you're
overtraining, you're literally,
your muscles start breaking
down to pollute your kidneys.
People die from it. Wow.
That was a big ass long words.
And if you're looking at dictionary,
it'll say boasts,
no dry pick it. Beers under resting
under recuperation. That's true.
But a overtraining. Nah. If you get
enough rest and enough recuperation,
I think overtraining spools.
Right.
But if you have to work out hard and
then you have to work out again the next
day and you work out hard the next day,
that's a, that's robbed on my locis Piss.
When you get robbed though, you're pissed
comes out looking like ice tea. Yeah.
I don't mean the rapper.
You're more than a rapper though, right?
It's hard to say. He's a rapper. Actor.
Yeah. He's a cool dude. Yeah. I mean
he has body count. That's a metal band.
So there's that too. Yeah. Yeah.
Right. Acts Peaks. Cool. Um, but yeah,
it looks like diet coke would say that.
This looks like it's fucked up. Yeah.
That's, um, that's what
happens in that train. Every,
I'm worked fucking eight
hours a day, eight, 10,
12 hours a day for the post office.
Went to the gym,
put in another four to six hours
for fucking 25 years in my pissed.
Never looked like that.
Yeah.
I think that's more endurance athletes
and uh, particularly crossfit.
A lot of crossfit people
get robbed at Oh yeah.
Cause a competing gets other people
and they get real wrapped up in it.
I got to ask, Jason could leap about this
good friend of mine, see if he's pissed.
Every look like root beer.
That's a real, real issue for crossfitters
and like ultra endurance athletes.
Yeah. Yeah. He's one of the
top crossfitters guy. Yeah.
He's like world champion
two or three times.
Those guys are ridiculously ridiculous.
Lee Fitting to add him in the,
in mind to him and I put them through
my training. It was one of the,
he did the shit like yeah, he's
fucking that guy. Crossfit. Neat.
And you know, wait with this would kind
of laugh it cross fingers and ah, that's,
that's, you know, you know
girly shit man. It's bullish.
Cross fitness bullshit.
But that motherfucker is in
extremely good shape. Yeah.
Crossfitting is definitely not,
definitely not bullshit.
You know, it's very hard. Yup. What
those guys do is very, very, very,
very hard. Yeah. The real question is
whether or not it's good for your body.
And that's where,
um,
that's where I'm not qualified to judge,
but there's a lot of people that are
professional strength and conditioning
coaches to frown upon it because they
think that those kind of movements like
power lifting movements like clean
press, that kind of shit. Again,
that should not be done for the
maximum amount of repetitions.
I think that should be done for
power then you should, you know,
you should holy step your maximum or 85%
of your maximum for x amount of times
and that's it. But what they're
trying to do is just, you know,
if Mike does 10 I want to do 12 Mike
does 12, I want to do 15 you know,
and they,
they think that there's like Steve
Maxwell who's a pretty famous strength
conditioning coach, he frowns upon
it and he just thinks it's just,
those movements are not
designed for endurance.
Those movements are designed for power.
He thinks ultimately it's
detrimental for your body.
And that if you want to have a long career
in fitness and constantly be able to
work out like deep into your 50s and 60s,
he just thinks it's very
detrimental for your body. Again,
I'm not the guy to tell, right,
that's true or not true either.
I need to get one of those
top level crossfit guys.
I know I've gone back and
forth with rich Froning.
Is that how you see a chance again online,
but I'd never got him on.
Oh yeah.
What were we talking to him again?
I'm sure Jason would die to
be going on here, but um,
he is exceptionally fit and,
you know,
the long term, I don't know, cause
he's still a pretty young guy.
But, uh, I,
I have a real bad habit of,
I'm looking at the people that,
uh, say those things about, uh, you know,
athletes like that.
I always look at them
and act as a bad habit.
I can't help him.
All the people that give all the advice,
the weightlifting advice online,
I always,
and look at their pace and
Seattle fuck pay, look at sauce.
The overwhelming majority of uh,
Instagram coaches are fat fucks.
Yup, it is. I had a fuck.
Can you give advice and look like dead?
Exactly right. How can you, I tell
people all the time, how can I,
I can't tell you or anybody how to,
to get through anything if I never
been through anything myself.
I can't tell you how to
overcome an obstacle if I
never overcame me any fucking
thing. Right. And I can't tell you how to
be in shape. If I look like a fat fuck,
I just can't do it. And I have a bad
habit of looking at that person in, in,
you know,
examining them first.
If you're going to give me this kind
of advice, then I have to, you know,
I got to look at your page, Joe. I
never seen them pictures and shit.
You been posting me now if I want to
know, that's why I'm asking. Joe wrote me,
show me how to kick cause I seen this
motherfucker kick and he kicks like fuck
fucking you man. I'm like, I want
to learn how to kick from dead guy.
I want to see somebody kicking through
walls and shit and just rules that if you
have not seen room kick look it up.
That is one kicking ass
ob to kick his ass though.
Yeah, I think you, you
got a good point about uh,
the people that criticize like some
people criticize people that work too hard
because they don't want to work that
hard and like you don't need to work that
hard. Yeah. Yeah. I don't trust
trainers that look like shit. Oh fuck.
Gang of them. Some of them are pretty
popular and I seen him, I'm like,
what kind of body is that fucking car?
Yeah.
They gotta be great.
Talkers got to be great. Oh,
they must have good degrees
and physiology and this. Nah,
they must man, let me, I look at them.
They look doughy like with
their Chin looks like,
okay. How might they know Claire?
Too Skinny. I came out first you,
I'm talking to talking
shit about them guys.
I couldn't get a job
as a personal trainer.
I had all these fucking world championship
certificates and sit and make told me
you're not certified by this.
Not 35 Friday, we can't use it,
and I'm like, fuck,
you're a personal trainer.
And this guy looked like he had
never seen the inside of here.
We even drove by a fucking Jew and
he's a fucking, if you're the head
personal trainer here, I'm like, oh,
I wonder if someone could
be a good trainer without
ever really working out hard
themselves.
Isn't that sounds similar to someone
saying that someone shouldn't be the
commander in chief without Howard?
Yeah.
If I'm going to work out, I want to work
out with someone who's built like you.
I want to work out with someone
who's built like, oh, this one,
the fuckers lift some weights.
They understand what it takes to get big.
I know what it takes to get strong. It's,
it's like I'm not just in theory. Yeah.
It's like we do hire a boxing coach.
They never been in a box. It just
never been in the ring because never,
I hasn't seen lies. I couldn't
do, I couldn't buy some piece of,
the interesting thing is some trainers
are just really good martial artists and
they never have competed.
I don't understand how that works though.
It doesn't make sense to me. And then
they would say that you know, their,
their skills in teaching things
just not in fighting itself.
But I think some of the best,
best fighters are the best coaches
are there have been fighters,
some of the best. Yeah, I totally agree.
Cause they know what the
fighters going through and that,
that's part of it was not just the skill,
you know,
the techniques that the kicks the point.
It's not just that they know
everything because they been there.
They know what you know, they know
everything from the ring walk to what,
what it's like when it gets hard. Brian,
when you're down on your cards. Yes.
They know that that's
a very fair and no and,
and a guy that never been through that,
it'd be lost in that situation. We'll know
what the fuck to tell you. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean I think that's what
most things in life, right? Yeah.
So I was going to give you
advice on something they
better have some actual real
world experience.
Yeah, I think so. I think it's a
necessity. But what the fuck do I know?
Lot Ma'am just came from
Compton. Well, I ain't a kid,
but I'm just a scroll guy from county.
Yeah.
But a lot of good stuff comes out of
Compton. Had Dr Dre came from Compton.
A lot of good stuff comes out of pressure.
Yeah, for sure. Compton's pressure.
It is definitely pressure.
Things come out of it as well. Oh yeah.
You know what I mean? It's not ideal,
but damn. If he can make it
through. Oh Man. I said crazy thing.
Like you don't want your children to
suffer, but the people who do suffer,
God damn, they come through
with some incredible character.
It's a conundrum, right?
Wow. Yes. It's such a,
I think that, you know,
people telling me it showed,
people tell him I get letters and
a DM and stuff from people from Oh,
the planet and so many different races.
There's rush and uh, Ethiopian, um,
people from Sri lock everywhere.
Hey CT,
it was something about your store.
If it was a childhood,
um, your health problems, uh,
how you went through that and overcame,
gave me inspiration to
go through my problems.
That is the best feeling in the world,
Joe.
And when I hear that I'm like everything
I had to go through or everything I
went through, I, I didn't volunteer
to die. I read her or April,
but it wasn't my choice.
If I had a choice,
I had been perfectly fucking hills but,
but going through it,
if it can help that guy in Sri Lanka,
they came rushing to guy and to guy and I,
if it can help them
then it was so worth it.
It ain't even funny.
Do I do it all over again tomorrow?
Just because this guy says that it
helped me get through some inspiration.
Inspiration is very, very valuable.
Very valuable and really hard to,
I mean it's hard to quantify if you
unexplained inspiration to someone who's
never experienced it.
But like someone else doing something
good makes you feel like you can do
something good.
It seems like it shouldn't be.
It shouldn't have anything to do
with you. But it does. It does.
I have my first one. We had
a, we go to do these expos,
these expos and stuff and people
come and something. Wait in line,
two or three hours to shake my hand.
And I think that's so crazy to hoe.
I mean,
who the fuck am I?
Who am I?
I'm I fuck I am nobody.
I'm nobody.
I ain't done nothing. Well,
stop and think about this.
Many of your videos have like more
than a million views. Yeah. So that's,
you're not nobody. It's crazy.
But that's not nobody. Everybody.
Somebody, right? I mean
that's an old saying.
The reality is you have reached out with
your videos and touched and if you saw
a million people in front of you,
you'd freak the fuck out. Right?
Well that's more than that.
You've touched many more than that
is millions and millions of people.
It is absolutely crazy to me
too. I just can't, but I don't.
Cause the first, first year there I
get on on Youtube, I go, hey, look,
I don't give a fuck if you listened
to me and not who would listen to
me. I listened to it, like
turned me to fuck off.
I don't give a fuck if people in and
I'm carrying a fucking million people
looking at this. And I'm like, man, I,
it's just, it's just so crazy. So cause I,
and like I said, I consider myself the
least at least, and Lewis and Lewis,
the bottom of the barrel and I'm just,
you know, people, people will say, oh,
CT or you're, uh, the
greatest year, King Year, uh,
I went, oh man, ain't none of
that stuff. I'm nothing. Yeah,
I'm absolutely not friend.
Well, that's not true either.
What you are as an exceptional person.
The thing about exceptional people
is there a self critical. And the,
one of the reasons why you got to
be so good at what you chose to
be obsessed by is that you,
you worked hard to constantly improve.
So when you're constantly
working hard to improve,
you're not thinking I'm the best.
I'm the best healer. God Damn,
I got to go to work. I got to get this
in. I gotta get this done. And so when,
when people tell you you're great,
you're like, what are you, I'm working.
I'm over here working, trying
to get better. Great man.
That's inspiring to people though.
The thing about what
inspiration does to people,
it's almost like a type
of intangible fuel. Oh,
it's can change lives.
So
come to me in, in the line,
they kind of tell me, uh, uh,
grown me.
He starts crying rope.
He's down on his knees and might
want to stay away from that guy.
This guy is crying.
He would get down on his
knees and tell him, oh,
see changed my life.
You kept me from committing suicide.
I've heard that story that I,
because of me,
they didn't take their own life
at least a hundred times. Yeah.
Joe Rogan,
what I have gone through just to say if
these people are the same that I saved
their life because I didn't
give up because I didn't
give in because I kept the
faith and kept going. I was going to
do that anyway, Joe, that's just right.
But it takes their life for them to tell
me something like that. I'm like, fuck I,
she had all over again
tomorrow. Well, you know,
it's like what we were saying earlier
about people that don't have anything that
they're inspired by.
And S I was saying I could maybe I wish
I w I saw them when they were young.
Like maybe if you got ahold
of them when they were young,
you could teach them the
value of expressing themselves
and competing or doing
something where you get positive feedback
from your effort and I think that some
people, they just, they don't,
they don't ever get that.
And so when someone gets that
from someone like you, when they,
they get that,
that fuel,
that intangible fuel that you get when
you get inspired by somebody, they,
it's so emotional because it's a really
is like you gave them a gift and that
gift we model ourselves after
other successful people.
We do it all the time either. Hopefully
if everything goes great, you Molly,
self hockey parents or you
model yourself after your uncle,
your brothers and sisters or
whoever it is that's around you,
that seems to be exceptional and that
that fuels people, it helps people.
It means a lot to people.
Sometimes people don't have that,
so they've got to look inward.
They got, uh, you know,
it's like that old Whitney
Houston Song. Um, you know,
everybody's searching for a hero song
that was like on the Mohammed Ali,
a life story that was, uh, that
was, that was the song that they,
the original version
of that song was on a,
it was like a Docu drama
on Muhammad Ali's life,
but that sometimes you don't find someone
for a long time and then when you do,
it changes your whole life.
You find someone,
maybe it's just a youtube video and
it's you saying it's still your mother
fucking set and it's you just pushing
people and telling people to go get after
it. And people see that and all of a
sudden it's like they get goosebumps.
Their hearts starts racing.
It's like you gave them a drug,
like you gave them fuel and then
then they want to change their life.
Then they want to watch you tomorrow
and then they want to watch you when
they're at lunch break.
They don't want you,
they're taking a shit in other
watch you on the phone. But that's,
that's fuel and you literally can change
a person's life through that because we
need each other.
I mean this is,
it's one more piece of evidence that we
need each other and then we have this
sort of very strange,
loose,
fitted community of all
human beings together.
And when someone like you does something
that's exceptional and says something
that's exceptional and has
these inspirational words,
it can change a person's whole life,
changed their whole path,
change who they are.
I've gotten so many messages from people
that say I lost 130 pounds. You know,
I did this, I got off sugar. I'm, I'm,
I'm, I'm, I'm fucking running every day.
I hit the gym five days a week.
Now I'm, I'm a different person.
I'm drinking water. I'm exercise that
I take vitamins, I'm eating healthy,
we've got more juice,
I got more energy.
My whole life is different now
as it happens all the time. Yeah,
but how does that make
you feel too obligated,
you know? No, I didn't know exactly what
to me. You like, you have to keep going.
You can't feel,
you can't cause man,
you got all these people
looking up to you.
Yeah. I don't want that. I definitely
don't want anybody looking up to me.
But I do like people being inspired and
if people get inspired by me, I'm happy.
But uh,
you know,
they with Joe gave looking up to
you and you can't help it. Man.
You can't help it think I
don't want it. I mean, I don't,
I always say it all the time.
Yeah. I'm nobody. I'm going
way. Don't look at me, man.
I'm looking at, I talk about a higher
power and look at the higher power. Man.
Don't look at me. We fucking
need each other. We all need
each other. We really do.
There's something beautiful
about that though. The only Kiki,
he can't just go it alone. You
really do need each other. And like,
if you accomplish everything
you ever want to accomplish,
but nobody's there for with you.
Nobody cares. Nobody likes you,
don't mean shit. It's useless. Absolutely.
Love is the most important thing. And
that sounds so cliche, but without love,
it's all useless. Yeah. It's all useless.
There's no personal satisfaction and
accomplishments. If nobody loves you,
you're not going to enjoy it.
Yeah. At least your family. Yeah.
Yeah.
[inaudible] everybody. And the more
you can spread positive energy,
the more people will love you, the more
you'll have that community of love,
you know?
And that's,
it's just like I tell you to, I
never expected even, you know,
Leah Passporty I people,
I always think about,
um, I'm the little kid that used to, um,
hide in the closet when I hear my dad's
keys rattling the door or a police car
pulled up behind the cause that
they're trying to hide. I didn't want,
I didn't want him to see me. I didn't
want to just, I'm that kid, dude.
I'm so hmm. And my dad would
always tell me that, you know,
you're never going to be nothing. You're
never going to do this. You never go.
And so I'm that kid. So it still
fucks with you owe it to come from no,
it, I'm reminded of it. I,
I think about that when people
tell me all your grades or You,
no man, I'm, I come from, I'm you man.
I, I wash dishes, I cut grass, I pump gas.
Um, those people, you know,
I bused tables as a kid.
I watched it.
I did all those things.
The people that are saying that I'm great.
I'm my own man. I'm you. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm you. I'm not, I'm at
anything other than you.
That's so important.
Yeah.
Here though. Yeah, they are you. But
that they can be someone like you to,
if they put in the kind of time
and effort that you put in,
that's the real message.
The real messages. We all
started from nowhere. I mean,
we all had bullshit jobs
where you felt like losers,
but through time and effort,
you build a stronger human. You build a
stronger body, you build a stronger mind,
you build complements and we'll,
and momentum and then you
look back and you go, hey man,
I'm not washing tables anymore. You
know, I'm not a, I'm not washing dishes.
I'm not cutting lawns
and not digging ditches.
I'm a different person now,
but I used to be
and are these desire not to be there
for a mattress? That's, that's what the,
that's the hardest.
Yeah.
All right.
Just to get out of that Rut when you ain't
got shit and there's nothing going on.
To have faith then is so difficult
to have faith when you're successful.
It's like, yeah, this is a bit,
she'd been successful for a while.
Once she got faith, just keep doing
what you're doing is absolutely right.
It's like you already got up the hill.
Now you're just coasting. You know,
you're just rolling down the hill.
Everything's great and it's easy,
smooth sailing. The hard part
is getting up that fucking hill.
Especially if you've got
a dad you're hiding from,
especially if you feel
like you're a loser.
You never really had anything in your
life that you could look back on and say,
hey, I was really good at that. You know,
and that's a lot of people
out there listening to this.
There's so many people that are in that.
That's that starting point,
like the people that come up to you and
say, what do I don't know what to do?
What should I do? How do I do
it? How do I get going? Well,
you're going to have to figure it out.
One foot in front of the other.
You're going to have to find a thing and
keep working at it and get better at it.
That's one of the things that I
liked so much about martial arts.
They let anybody in anybody in,
and then from that,
from learning how to do that, you get
better and then you realize, damn,
I didn't get better at anything because
it's so the first time I ever did you
did sue. I remember just being
manhandled. So bad going, man,
I'll never be good at this. This is
terrible. I'm fucking awful at this.
And this is,
I had already been a black
belt in taekwondo and
already kickboxer did a bunch
of shit and I was like, I can't believe
I'm starting from scratch again.
But that at least I knew then that I
already done that before I'd already
started from scratch. So like I had some
experience and started from scratch.
I'm like, Oh, I have to do is just
put in the time and the effort.
Yeah, the desire to get better data.
That's for everybody. Just find a thing.
Everything.
And if you find a thing like
a particularly martial arts,
because you get belts and ranks and
then you could see how you're doing with
opponents,
especially Jujitsu.
I liked that when the bolt's cause
you're not getting hit, you know?
I think there's so many people that
in the, especially if you go to a,
a bad gym in the early days,
people going to tune, tune you up.
I'm going to beat you up.
Yep. Yeah. You can get some little
damage. It'd be scourge a lot.
Yeah. But if you could just find a
thing and work hard at that thing,
you'll realize through that thing that
you can get good at anything with time
and effort.
Don't have anything on hand. I
mean, you pick the thing. Yeah.
Great. What getting calls to you,
whatever. Whatever calls to you.
Yep. They'd be desired to
change to, to, to not, uh,
to change those circumstances, whatever
they might be. Yeah. As long as you have,
you have to have that desire,
the will to change their circumstances.
That's actually start right there man.
We are how bleak it makes scene.
But if you have the will
to be sired to change it,
they are just starting point.
Since you started doing these
videos on youtube to now,
how much of a difference
has it made in the, the,
the types of people that come to your
gym and then the numbers of people that
come in,
um,
that I have Joe Rogan's phone number.
I have Terry crews phone number. I
have doctor Trey's phone number. Yeah.
Saw you, you took a lot of pictures of
Dr Dre man. Even high with them a lot.
Dr Dre. I know, hey, you guys
look at the news and he's,
he might see, hey, it don't say
anything bad about Dr in front of me.
We haven't got an incredible
individual and credible Dr Dre,
I call them trade. Now. Trade
is an incredible individual.
His heart is huge.
Huge too.
I can't take it out cause it took,
not too,
but that he's an incredible individual.
Was jacked at one point
in time, right? Yeah.
You still looks great.
He told me he's in very
good shape right now.
He's a lot of cardio eats really
well. Matter of fact, uh, he,
he's got this trail he wants me to,
he challenged me to turn it out hiking
up a hill and I'm not ready for it too.
But Dr Dre, if you miss me, I'm
gonna make it up at fucking trail.
I might have to roll down, but I'm going
to back. You know, he's in great shape,
but he's a great human being.
He's a, a very good human being.
That's awesome to hear.
I love hearing just down to Earth.
So he shifted his training from
like just a really big goal.
Yeah. He's all at the comedy store one
night and he looked like the rock. Yeah,
exactly. You know, he's,
he's more a, you know,
health oriented and cardio
and he wants to, uh,
he said his goal was to
get down to 200 pounds, uh,
of just lean low body fat percentage
muscle. What does he weigh now?
Uh, two 10 I think he said, and were with
me and him saying around the same way.
And my goal is also to get down to
200 pounds. I want to be 200 pounds,
which I haven't been in a long time,
but I want to be 200 pounds. Well,
there's pictures of you
when you were power lifting.
Three 25 25. Oh my God. I man,
wow man. I ain't gonna call
this motherfucker in the world.
So you are as wide as a building
now house God damn three.
So you were 115 pounds
heavier than you are now.
So, so you see why I feel like I'm
scared of within that 15 pounds state.
You know, I feel like a skeleton
now. Compare it to did man,
but just stop and thinking
about 115 one pound stakes.
Just slap, slap, slap, slap, slap, slap,
slap, slap, slap, slap, all that big.
I just a lot of me
shoulders and I did care.
I pay out, almost pass out, tied my shoes,
get out of breath, walking to the
front fucking door. I'm like, Oh fuck.
See overweightness are at your door again.
Oh fuck.
You were saying you had a terrible
diet back then. Oh it was horrible day.
You are looking at you.
Yeah. Yeah. That's my it
shit.
That ain't all fat man.
You look gigantic as a fat fuck and
I'm trying to get like the other guy,
I don't know if that lean
lean CPU on the other side.
How much did you weigh in the other side?
On the other side I was probably about
two 20 I want to get down to 200 pounds.
That's the goal by sixties be 200 pounds.
Jesus crossing the size of your arm,
so crazy fucking arm.
That is so preposterous.
And the TRICEP,
the line
between the tricep and the Bicep,
that is,
that's what me, me and I think
through my a lid on. Yeah.
I don't think so. Stop lying.
I picked, they helped me. Yeah,
I don't think so. You look
pretty young there too. Yeah,
I was actually a 50,
50 more tonight to in that picture.
Yeah. Wow. Go back to that again.
That's 50 with no steroids.
That's ridiculous. Well, a natural, uh,
um, and uh, uh, professional, uh,
the natural professor
who would be freezing.
So I won the over 50 category and mile.
Well,
that's how I got my pro card
is a bodybuilder. But, uh, I,
it looks a little at what daddy me,
big difference. We were talking about
people that come to your gym nomad,
I mean flock to you now. Um, I flack,
I don't know if that's kind of cool though
because you,
you have sort of,
you've taken on this role as a guru.
I mean,
that's one of the things that a lot of
people have gotten from your videos and
these, I mean there's
motivation from, you know,
a lot of people can give you motivation
and some of that motivation seems stale
and then there's some people that give
you motivation like, wow, that's alive.
That shit's alive. Your
motivation is live. It's real.
You could tell it's not scripted.
Yeah. Tell me what you see. I put her
in the heart. Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
Everything is right off
the top of the head, man. I
think, uh, when a guru, right,
that's an every tighter I think
I'm definitely not worthy.
I maybe, you know, people
say, oh, he's an old g old.
It's more closer to I've
been around long enough.
Well, you're also like people turn
because of the fact you've been around,
you've done so much, the people
will turn to you and say, hey you,
this is a person with real
life experience. You, you
really have done things.
You had done some stuff.
When you start talking about pushing,
he started talking about pushing yourself.
People understand this is
coming from life experience.
This is real and that's a different,
that's why it's if resonates with people,
it resonates with people
because it's authentic.
Man. That's, that's a high
compliment. I appreciate it.
Thanks it death.
Both staff leaves.
There's a lot of people out there
listening to this, that know you,
that are not in their head right now.
And appreciation and understanding.
They know what we're saying. They
know that when you, when you,
you fire me the fuck up dude.
Those videos I get fired
up high praise right there.
It's not just me man.
It's a lot of other people.
But that must have led a lot
of people to come to gym. Yeah.
I get people from a and I go,
I guarantee that I'm going to be there
on Wednesday nights because people come
all the time expecting me to be
at the gym 24 hours a day. Right.
Where is the gym? It's in
Signal Hill, California and
uh, it's iron addicts, right?
Iron addicts, GM, Signal
Hill, California. And uh,
there's a rumor that we're going to be
opening up another one here pretty soon.
A, we haven't decided yet.
I'm over here side, you know,
that's, that's a possibility. He
will need a hardcore gym out here.
That is a possibility. Uh, uh,
an area where people can afford the
membership. That's what we were thinking,
man. You know, cause we're where
I'm at now too. I tell you,
I could make a lot more money,
but I, you know, first responders,
firemen, policemen, uh,
all vets, paramedics,
they trained at the gym for free. Could
feel I don't turn to him. Nothing. Man,
that's amazing.
It's the least I could do.
I think it's at least I can
think is beautiful. And so yeah,
I could make more money,
but that's something that I
choose to do. Good for you.
Yeah.
But yeah,
we're thinking about opening up another
one in the area where people got some
money. When you do, man, let
me know and I'll get that
bat signal up in the sky. Oh,
hey, definitely. Definitely Joe Rogan
podcast. What? You had one of my,
it's on. Yeah, man. Thank you.
I really appreciate that.
Oh my pleasure brother.
I was so fucking excited when I see
that somebody, somebody seen it first.
One of my kids see first cause there
all the time on social media. Hey Dad,
look at you. I'm like,
Oh fuck. That's cool.
I was happy for you to see that your
posters hanging up in the air to a broken
screw up my poster hanging up
in his brain. That's cool man.
That is so,
so you're there every Wednesday,
every Wednesday night and that's
when the gym is pretty packed.
And Wednesday nights we do
a live workout and people,
you take people through this workout,
all you have,
if they come on Wednesday
nights, I've trained people,
you know, I don't, I it it,
it's on Wednesday nights to
absolutely free. I'll see.
That's another reason make them, I have
people come over on Wednesday nights,
they train for absolutely free.
All you gotta do is sign the waiver.
So if you get fucked up, it's on you.
You don't try to sue me in that light.
But if you come on Wednesday night and
sign, the waiver is absolutely free.
That's amazing. Yeah. I yell and
scream at him. He'll let me see.
He called me motherfucking people.
It's so funny because my motherfucking,
I'm like,
I've been calling people a motherfucker
since the fifth grade for him.
For nothing, man. He
wasn't that weird. Yeah.
And now they want me to call
him mother fucker. You know,
I'm on the Cameo Cameo and on
the cameo they can for 25 bucks.
I cussed him out.
Oh,
that's how it became your
app and it costs 25 bucks.
I cut some out and I'm like, damn, I used
to cuss me out for nothing. That's how
I took about 10 a day. Really?
Yeah. Wow. Some out man.
I wish my, uh, you know, wished me
happy fucking birthday. See Dean,
I was happy birthday or whatever the
fuck they want. Right. Five bucks, man.
That's very reasonable. Yeah.
Yeah. Used to be more and, and uh,
as an African and make it cheap and
so more people can afford to do it.
I don't mind. I might cuss him out. I
would, I would say he got a heart of gold.
But you have a new heart. Yeah. So
you've got a new heart. A goal there,
but you really do, man, the way you
look at things is, it's very cool.
It's very cool the way you let first
responders and firefighters and veterans
work out for free and the Wednesday
night working out for free and all that.
Your heart is in the right place.
Your mind's in the right place. I try.
I tried to go. It is, man.
It is so like the
environment around the gym.
How much did it change once you
started putting up those videos? Oh,
uh, it's, it's a type of gym.
My type of jam that um,
if you're don't,
uh, you know, I got to say is
we got number two behind goals.
Dam as a favorite
hardcore gang in America.
Iron addicts get behind
Gold's gym, man. Holy Shit.
You can't beat Gold's gym
because she might be number one.
Always going to vote for
Gold's gym number one.
But that can be incredible. That's an
honor, man. That's what I'm saying.
I think you won. That was a super,
I feel like you got first place.
He can't really defeat Gold's gym.
People come in, you know, from,
from a Lithuanian CT, and then we
came, we were in, in town on vacation.
One place we wanted to go was your gym.
Wow.
I love that kind of stuff. It's
amazing. It is so gratifying. You know?
It might, but it's, it's
not a planet fitness.
It's a hardcore, I love
the way it looks. Yeah.
It looks like it's just like a fucking
tornado ransom. But if you don't
look like they've been, everybody's
been lifting. Yeah. That's what I like.
Fuck out of here with that.
But see the x [inaudible] the,
if you had that kind of mentality,
then you'll love it. Yeah. You know,
there's some people going like, ah,
I don't know. It's not my
cup of tea. Then you won't.
Thank goodness there's enough people like
us. And my daughter's like, could you,
could you just put recovered this one
big track got ride of like the stuff
that's coming out and I look at it
and I'm going, fuck, this is perfect.
And my daughter's like, no. Put your
got like a Patina. Yeah, I like it too,
man. I like seeing shit that's chipped
up a little bit. Banged up. Asked me.
Especially if you, you're going
to go put yourself through hell.
You like cars too. Yeah. I love
cars. I noticed that you love cars.
I love cars. You got a
corvette to yeah. 65. I know,
man. It's fucking bad ass
too. But you didn't know that.
I'm a car nut too. I do know your
car. Not We talked about it. We did.
Yeah. What do you have? Oh,
I have a four core vets for,
I know you were a corvette
man. Damn. I have a 65,
a 72 or 74 and 71 I got,
I see threes.
That's
wow. Damn you are good on that. You
speak about, yeah, that's yours too.
Oh, that one's nice. Black
with the side pipes. As for 27,
we tried card. Right. That's a beautiful
one we have here. Is that sent me to that.
So that's all generation three,
right? Yeah. Yeah. My, my uh,
my neighbors hate that fucker is loud.
I bags that years.
Amazing. Those, those
are gorgeous cars, man.
Compared to what you can. But you know, I
like them. I love them. I love Corvettes.
I liked the new ones too.
I like all of them. Yeah.
You got something else besides the
corvette too? I heard about it,
but I haven't seen, I seen the
corvette. But what else? Um,
I have a 69 Nova that they're
building right now. I did sucked.
I think I did. And, and you, you,
everything's like super new. I know. It's,
yeah.
I don't like old shit.
Fucked up suspensions. We can't go around
corners. I'm not interested in dying.
Not like that. Oh yeah. I
like what they call resto.
That's the electric
yours. Oh No, no. I, I,
well the yellow one I got from a guy
who's a plastic surgeon and that was like
his bottom of the line car,
but he did everything to it.
It's got the suspension and everything
and it makes a big difference. You know,
I could try that thing anywhere. But the,
uh, the black room for 27 try and Carb,
it's old school, old school all
the way and the brakes. No, no,
it's got disc brakes. Yeah. That's where
you got to draw the line. Yeah. Yeah.
Got It. Here. I've got to be able
to stop. Got to be able to stop it.
That fucker is, and actually I
like, I like shit like that. I,
I wouldn't mind the restroom. I, but
I, I like the, I like, Oh shit man.
I just, I like old houses. I like
old cars. I collect old bikes.
Yeah. Just old shit. I just,
shit man. I do too. Yeah.
I think this character told things.
Yup.
It's like either you like it or you don't
like some people just like everything
new and modern and shining.
Like when I started making money,
I started buying older cars.
I like older shit.
You just have a different feel to them.
Totally. Totally. Totally. Totally.
I have a, uh, yeah. Yeah. Just your trade.
His truck, man. What did you get this?
I got that, uh, probably six months ago.
See,
I liked it motherfucker at all.
All the Patina on that crew cab
or for freaks, the wine crew cab.
Find those creek and it came from
the factory or crew cab man. Wow.
That truck looks like me
bashed in windows and shit.
Scars. Beautiful. I love it. I love you.
Drive that around that motherfucker.
You know what? I'm waiting there.
I am going to get the Party work done
on that mother fucker because it's got
some holes in it. Oh it's pretty beat up.
Yeah, it's pretty. I got to get the buddy.
We're good to go. There's something to
that. When you look at those old cars,
you realize that they don't make
anything like this anymore. No Man.
The style,
uh,
they really put a lot into
style 50s and sixties, man.
But it just doesn't seem same. He didn't
say look good like a new corvette,
like a 2019 corvette. It's a beautiful
car. But you look at that old truck,
it does not have what that truck has.
Its like it,
it'll put a smile on your
face just driving it, man.
One of my biggest joys is it
sitting behind the wheel of that,
those old cars, man, it just makes me,
I feel like a young mother fucking,
when I'm sitting there like a kid.
Yeah. Like it's a toy. Oh, like a ride.
Like you driving around in a
ride. It is, yeah. It's so much.
You pull up to a stoplight, some other
fucking glue in the car next to him.
The guy's giving you a thumbs up,
man.
I be cheesing from ear
to ear when that happens.
And you don't even have to drive those
fast. No. Yeah. Even that corvette,
you don't have to. Every once in a while
it's fun, you know, break them loose.
It's a little fun to break them loose,
but you know,
you don't have to drive for me.
Well, for a power lifter though,
it's almost like mandatory for you to
have some sort of a muscle car. Yeah,
I can't. So it's like, it
goes with the territory.
It doesn't like a big block
engine. There's you, oh,
somebody got a video of you
driving by. Yeah. That's hilarious.
I like you get recognized a lot,
you know more than I, you know, I'm,
I'm still shocked but it,
I go to the store,
I was walking down the street
the other day and it got, hey CT,
you know what? I was yelling and
screaming from the car and I'm like, man,
how do you even know what the fuck I am?
Because I figure if you're not a weight
lifter and you don't look at Youtube,
then I know that's a lot of
people. Yeah. Well you know,
even know who the fuck I was.
I was, I still shocked by,
but I get recognized more than that,
you know, or did I thought I would.
This CT Fletcher 2.0 that this life
that you're living right now. Yes.
What? What is, what is different in
like what you're trying to accomplish?
Oh Man. The first one, you
know, it was me, me, me, me,
me and this 2.0 guy is so much more
concerned about other people and doing
something to help somebody
else is almost more important.
Veno know my,
my initial videos you see as well,
you may not know right now,
but you will, you know,
I'm going to do this and what this
guy, fuck that guy. I'm, I'm king.
I'm the beast album. The bad. It's one.
I'm the baddest man on the
planet and you know, as I,
and now I consider myself this new guys
so insignificant that it's not even
funny me and just a CT for us.
It feel weird to just completely shifted
your consciousness like that. It,
it,
it s a little weird at times.
It feels a little weird.
Like you're not even you. Uh,
but so much it's me and I know it's me,
but I feel so much better,
so much better, man.
He was, what happened when, when
the focus on me, you know, um,
this, this new version, it's news. It's,
I feel so much better than I'm
trying to bring people together.
I'm telling like, I have a, my mission,
my purpose is so much greater.
I'm trying to do some good old
[inaudible] Fletcher. That's my mom.
That's the lady who kept me from
being completely retarded as a kid.
I the oldest reflect your
heart foundation. You know,
I'm tried to a nonprofit organization
named my mom and it's to people because
our transplant is a very,
I mean, lot of people,
if it wasn't for the
army, for what? For me,
being a veteran is no way I
could afford a transplant.
It's $1 million for seizure and
handle fucking million dollars show.
It's so, but there's other,
even if you have insurance,
there's other things that comes up,
you know,
say that the head of the family has to
have a transplant, a heart transplant.
He's out. Ah, okay. His medical bills
are taken care of it, but what about,
how's his wife gonna pay the mortgage?
How she's going to buy gas?
I just going to feed the kids.
I started the Osb Fletcher
Heart Foundation to help people,
uh,
with that to help the mom who still at
home was still has to pay the bills and
stuff because insurance doesn't cover
everything to help the people that don't,
you know, I haven't, I haven't had even
had my first event or anything like that.
I just paid the lawyer for, uh, to
get the name and stuff as a kid,
but I won't have to start.
You got to start somewhere and that
started had the visit of my hand.
I'm going to do something for my mom. So
her memory, you know, go on. You know,
even after I'm dead and gone,
those referred to heart foundation will
still be around and we'll do something
to honor her because that woman, you
know, everything I am is because of her.
So I wanted to do something to honor her.
I just got all these things I want
to do to help my veterans and PTSD.
Uh, I could, I got so many goals
and stuff to live for a man.
I don't know what to do and I don't know
how much time I got to do it. I can,
you know, walk out of here and
dropped dead. I don't know.
But I'm going to be got danced with her.
I'm not going to waste one second Evan.
I'm going to be trying,
I'm on the Joe Rogan show and I'm talking
to Joe Rogan podcasts and I'm talking
about it right now. So I'm doing something
about it. Joe, what is donor weirdness?
Beautiful to see your,
your transformation man.
It's beautiful to see this evolution view
as a person and it's beautiful to see
the, you got through this, you know,
terrible scare but came
out a better person.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
It's something else that we were on the
last time we were talking to and I said,
yeah,
they tell me I need a heart transplant,
a heart transplant. Oh my
God, Dude. Are you scared?
Like no drop, mad, scared. But it's
uh, it's something else, man. It is.
It's crazy to see you a year
later. Now you have it. Yup.
And you're just as different human
man. And I back on the tour, Bro.
Hey, thank you man. Thank you.
Thank you so much for being you.
It was so many people come up
to me and tell me that you know,
I found out about you from the Joe
Rogan podcast, Joe Rogan packets.
That's how I know who, even who
you are. So this opportunity,
the opportunity came the last time
open up so many more doors, man.
And so to be back on here, I
can't thank you enough, man.
This is fantastic.
It's my pleasure.
And for people that are listening that
have never heard you before are watching.
You got to go watch his videos.
This is the reason why you
got on the first place.
I got so inspired by your shit
and seen you online with these,
these videos and just shows your passion
and your motivation and now to see you,
this new person on top of that still
have the passion. But now you're,
there's like this,
you like this new enlightened CT Fletcher.
It's beautiful to see Matt and yourself.
People are going to be able to get good
laugh or that you are man, you like,
I could tell the moment I saw you today.
It's like you've got a different energy
about you. It's really interesting.
Oh Man. I was so happy to see
you. I'm so happy to see you too.
I'm so happy to see this new
lease on life you have. Oh my God.
I was just very happy to see and look.
I'm my own for, I want to
just, I'm alive. You're alive.
Yeah. And getting better
every day. Gave him better.
He's talking shit and stronger every day.
Well, how'd he get ahold of you on
social media? What is your interest,
Graham?
[inaudible] dot com go
there and search on youtube,
everything.
Signal Hill,
the iron addicts gym. And then when you
do open up a new one, please let me know.
Absolutely.
Let everybody know where and we'll get
there for the grand opening and below
that motherfucker up.
Hey Dr Dre, if you're listening,
I want to their man, Dr Dre.
He's gonna run that hill. Yeah.
Oh, I'm glad. Primacy. Dr Jay.
I'm going to make it up at here. I believe
it. Thank you brother. I appreciate you,
man. Really appreciate
you. I really appreciate CT
Fletcher, Ladies and gentlemen.
Yeah,
I have no idea.
Hmm.