Go to the Jersey shore.
Three,
two.
Great.
Tom,
Papa will be at the Jersey shore this
weekend.
Do you ever get do gigs?
Downloading flip flops.
Had a metal detector.
Do you know anybody's ever scored with a
metal detector?
No,
I mean scored like,
found like a bottle cap.
Civil war belt buckle or some shit and
never,
never.
I used,
I had one when I was a kid.
I used to go to the Jersey shore.
It was orange and I would get
sure
and no heat,
no air?
No a earphones or anything.
I would just walk out on the beach with
it.
Never found anything.
What's the earphones?
Did they tell you?
Like when the frequency is different?
Does that sound?
Yeah.
You just go and it's just like the
frequency of the beeps?
Yeah,
it's like hot hotter,
hotter,
hotter and hotter.
Burning hot.
You're there.
How do those things work?
I have never looked into metal
detectors.
I don't know.
But you know like if you take that to
like the Appalachian trail or like you
know where the civil war went down and
that kind of stuff like that.
You'd find stuff.
Oh,
I guarantee Ya.
Yeah.
I guarantee you see what is the most
sophisticated current.
Oh,
I just.
I just looked this up just a couple of
weeks ago.
$2,000,000 worth of Viking Golden.
God.
Oh,
who's laughing now?
It's 2 million pounds.
What does that 4 million.
It's 20 bucks.
Is that $4 million?
A double.
It's like do I at least one and a half
to two times?
Yes.
I'm like,
Jesus Christ Viking treasure hoard.
What does he got in that photo?
That's what it looks like.
Oh,
that's his metal detector.
You looked at metal detector to.
Looks like assault duct taped together
and shit.
It's like he's been using it a long time
and this dude found millions of dollars
in viking fines.
That's pretty great.
I found nothing.
I found like a bottle cap and it's
exciting when you hear.
It's like dee dee dee dee dee dee lived
it all this shitty found.
Look at that vase.
Look at that ring.
That's cool.
That's like the hobbit ring.
Wow.
Tenth Century Gold Ring.
Oh my God.
Is that cool?
That was one 10th century Golden Rain.
It's pretty great and he wore that.
You guys got to walk in the right
places.
I'm in the Jersey shore,
you know what I mean?
There wasn't.
My Dad lives in Florida on the treasure
coast,
they call it,
which is like the Atlantic,
Mid Atlantic or mid halfway up and down
in Florida.
So like every time it's hurricanes too.
People are always out on the beach
looking for stuff because shit gets
to treasure.
Chests are train wrecks,
like in the Bermuda Triangle.
So I like the pirate treasure gets wiped
up onto the beach.
There's something about finding that
the,
like if you went to a museum and you saw
a ring from the ninth century,
the 10th century,
whatever it is,
you'd probably be like,
wow,
that's incredible.
That's right.
But if you fucking founded in the dirt
and you picked it up and it may be
likely,
I mean there's,
there's at
least a possibility.
The last person that touched it was the
person that died there.
Huge,
huge possibility.
Huge.
I mean,
that's.
how great would that.
The feeling would have been amazing fun.
Find a fossil.
You ever find a fossil when you were a
kid walking around?
Not really a felon.
Arrowhead though.
That's important to you.
Excited is.
It was in Nevada.
Bowhunting.
I found an arrowhead and I lost it.
Oh,
that's terrible.
Think you're actually supposed to leave
them there.
So it's probably Karma for them.
Like leaving here.
This is a trail.
Anyways,
gonna find it.
This is stupid.
Like if you want me to bring it to me,
his hair or something,
that's one thing.
But just say,
just leave it there for.
Yeah,
someone else is going to become taken.
No one's going to leave it there.
Story of my brother in law who uses
metal detector and his,
his uh,
friends married couple I think newly
married when hiking in the grand tetons
and she lost her ring.
She lost her engagement ring and uh,
he was going out there like in a month
from then and he went out and he took
his metal detector here and he hiked
along the same trail and he comes back
to New Jersey and his buddies in the bar
and he just sits down next to him at the
bar and touches the ring on the,
on the bar.
Holy Shit.
I found it wholly shaking.
Yeah.
Wow.
What are the odds of all the steps she
could have taken?
Yeah.
The places she could have gone.
I mean they probably told her what trail
that he took or whatever.
Just the whole trail.
Yeah,
exactly.
Someone telling you I lost my wedding
ring on this trip somewhere.
Go find it.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Greg?
On the great move is not calling and
saying,
Holy Shit.
I found it.
Just showing up at your local bar and
think that's pretty gangster.
Yeah,
it's pretty bad,
but it's like the state of the art
consumer model,
metal detector.
Maybe I should have a metal detector.
Dude,
come on here and talk to me and go,
what the fuck they do.
That would be cool because I guess it's
gotta be exciting.
Right?
Especially like places like the beach.
We're stuff washes up.
Yeah.
Do you have to wear sandals when you do
it?
You have must.
Right?
But you must have a certain body odor to
like have like a mill do.
Dewy,
bittery.
Sort of a salary.
Milky smelled like a little like ham.
The Garrett.
Is this supposed to be the shit?
Oh yeah.
Look how popped up.
Pretty high.
That goes on your forearm,
right?
That weight.
So for 340 bucks you could find out the
back of your 2 million pounds worth of
Viking stuff.
Look at that thing and it's cheap.
Is that the best one?
See if there's some sensitivity.
Lack of a metal detector role model.
Who was the way it comes to the
waterproof?
Well,
ever since I went pro comes with a lot
of stuff's changed.
Golden Sixty four.
Jesus Christ.
Oh you went pro.
I went pro,
you know,
uh,
after the Viking gold thing,
right?
Like obviously I'm blessed.
So uh,
oh totally,
totally.
But what does that mean to you?
You have a sponsor,
yo bro.
Oh Man.
Make money off of a finding a river.
You take it underwater.
Whoa,
that's deep.
That's actually pretty bad ass.
You know what though?
It's not all that bad ass.
There's something about,
there's something Corny,
like even even the best ones,
it's still like,
it's definitely like it's in the fanny
pack realm.
Yeah,
I endorsed,
but it's like,
what?
What are you doing here?
Exactly where you're given up by this
one,
$799.
Eight thousand thousand,
8,000 extra night in there.
Go.
There you go.
Gold Nugget.
Metal detector.
A mind lab to easy go up into the go up
in northern California where all the
gold mines were.
That'd be cool.
Yeah.
That's a move,
right?
Yeah.
So how does that fucking thing work?
Because that works different than only
picks up gold.
Set it on gold.
Yeah.
This other one had like on the top of
the meter it has specific for gold iron.
It gives you different readings and then
this thing is called a pinpoint or
whatever that is.
I'm only interested in gold.
See,
I guarantee you this is one of those
things that there's a fucking rabbit
hole and you start with this,
and next thing you know,
you're kidding.
Minor magazine in the mail,
you're subscribing to these websites
where people go on these,
these,
uh,
metal detector.
Your wife comes into your but Dan and
you have a miner's helmet with a light
on it.
Aren't you coming to bed
late?
A minute,
honey,
for real.
Like,
what?
Then you find out about a treasure
somewhere and you go,
oh,
I can find it.
Oh yeah,
that's pretty hard to find.
Well,
have you ever seen those documentaries
on those guys that are professional
shipwreck hunters?
No.
Dude is.
There's real crazy money in that real.
And if they know we're a viking ship
went down or Roman ship went down,
they know where they're pretty sure that
there's some gold.
There has been several times that they
have.
Let's find out actually what the biggest
bounty was,
lot.
Let's take a guess.
Well you've got to figure the
technology's probably just improved,
right?
And like the last 30 years,
right.
Has made such a jump,
so why it's probably a good time to do
it.
People have been probably trying to
search but couldn't go down too deep or.
Well,
they're really good at it now you know,
there,
but it's also the ocean is fucking huge.
So if you find something,
the odds of somebody else finding it
without you telling them about it and
without somebody leaking some
information so it's really touch and go
and these guys invest a shitload of
money.
So they have the divers who are these
people that are usually the people that
are knowledgeable but they don't really
have the funds and then they meet
somebody and that guy funds it,
but it's super squirrely.
Like who gets the money and how much do
you get?
And his brothers,
like a coke dealer,
right?
Someone's got a gun,
someone's got her girlfriends to Tan.
Everything's just super confusing.
She's really friendly.
She being so nice to me.
She want to fuck,
this is going to be murder suicide.
It's,
it's all gonna.
Go down,
I watched this one and these,
uh,
these guys had found,
I want to say it was more than a hundred
million dollars in gold.
Oh my God.
They had found at the bottom of the
ocean,
but I might be making that.
That's a really good one.
I found their operations have to be
related to the discovery of the San
Jose,
Shipwreck and Columbia and 2015.
How much.
Okay,
let me guess
really high.
It's really,
really done.
That do.
You shouldn't have done that.
I would've come in low.
San Jose.
I was going to say two point
$4,000,000,000.
Woo.
That's a lot.
I'm going to say one point $8 billion.
I never would have said billion by the
way.
He didn't say that.
Okay.
One point eight.
What did I say?
Two point something.
Two point 4 billion.
Jesus Christ to discovery the San Jose
shipwreck has all the elements of a
great drama,
international political intrigue,
a treasure of golden emeralds worth up
to $17,
billion.
And now accusations of lying.
Everyone always forgets about emeralds.
Everyone forgets about emeralds.
I sleep on Emerald,
I sleep on them all the time.
I never take them seriously.
He's like,
he's like,
Yo,
look at my emeralds.
That's not even the best rock you could
get.
And then weird emeralds,
emeralds,
and they're only for women who just
shiny everything other than diamonds are
producers and diamonds aren't really for
dudes.
They met for dudes.
I know they're all for women mostly,
but a guy can wear some diamonds,
like rappers wear diamonds.
It looks fly.
It's sparkly.
Girls like sparkles,
but rappers can't wear a ruby's.
Right.
Nice.
Ruby,
check out my ruby red teaming up.
They can.
Someone's wearing ruby's bawling.
My Rubio.
Of course they are.
What about emeralds?
Can they were emeralds?
I bet conor mcgregor.
Where the fuck out of some emeralds.
Oh Man.
Being all Irish and chin.
Yeah,
just a big Irish.
The sash and were like,
oh,
like a chest plate man.
I am.
Roads mean looking at my am roads and if
you're wearing turquoise and you're not
native American.
I got questions.
Yeah,
right.
If you really turquoise and silver.
Yeah.
Slow down buddy from New Mexico.
Show me your artwork.
Show me that you're really kicking ass
with some Indian artwork because it's
not showing me the guy on the horse.
I know you have it.
You fuck.
Let me see.
The dream.
Catchers are selling
like a man with a turquoise bracelet.
Oh Man.
There was a place called the Silverman
when I was in school.
It was a in New Jersey near my high
school and when I was first getting into
girls,
that's where I would go to buy jewelry.
That gifts to my girl.
I don't remember being there.
Like I wonder.
I wonder if I could wear some of this
myself.
That's hilarious.
The Silverman,
I remember there was a movie that was
his great wrestling movie called vision
with Matthew Modine
and his friend on the show is this
native American kid turned out to not
really be native American.
Ah.
It turned out that that was like his big
hustle in the movie was that he was
telling everybody who's native American
talking about you going on a vision
quest and your spirit journey and all
this stuff.
Because I don't know what it was.
I don't remember,
but I remember that in the movie.
Yeah.
That dude right there.
That turned out to not really be native
American.
It was just bullshit.
Well,
bad on you,
Matthew Modine for thinking that it was
a.
It looks native American.
Yeah.
It looks more like culture club.
It looks like an Indian man.
Come on.
Oh,
that's the guy from 16 candles.
Is it?
Same Guy?
Yeah.
The guy who was really ringwald really
loved.
Oh really?
Yeah.
I remember that one.
You know too much about those movies.
It was the eighties.
I want it to be that guy because he was
like the cool guy,
but he was so cool.
He didn't hang out with the cool people
and Molly ringwald fell in love with
him.
That is the movie that wrestlers watch
for inspiration.
Quest Vision quest.
That is the movie.
Yeah,
that is.
That is an amazing movie.
Isn't really good.
Stocks today.
You'd probably go back and watch it
today.
It's probably like altered states.
A lot of synthesizer.
Yeah.
I've recommended altered states to be
blend.
I went back and watched it myself.
I had to come back on the air and go,
okay,
sorry.
Do you people.
I saw rob.
Do you have an hour and a half of your
life?
I remember thinking it was cool.
It wasn't the day.
I mean,
it was really cool.
It was really cool when the movie came
out.
I loved.
Movies are just different now.
Yeah.
Unless you see like the Godfather,
the godfather 100 percent holds up
totally for the shining,
the shining 100 percent wholesale.
One hundred percent.
One hundred percent caddyshack.
Oh yeah.
Caddyshack is fantastic.
Blues Brothers,
Blues Brothers back to school.
Yeah.
Come on.
So that means that maybe altered states
wasn't that great.
It was different and there was a book by
a lot on the different.
It was an intriguing story.
The whole thing was crazy.
You have this brilliant doctor and this
beautiful girlfriend who was also a
scientist too,
or think you don't remember.
Um,
and so he takes this shout shamonic drug
and it changes him.
He morphs back into a monkey and he
breaks in the zoo and kills things.
Right?
That's right.
I remember right.
He was in the with like blood on his
face.
Yeah.
Killed something in the zoo.
Right.
The movie was based,
not really,
but based or I should say inspired by a
guy named John Lilly who made the
isolation tank.
There was an isolation tank in it.
Yeah,
that's actually how I found out about
this movie in the movie.
He actually goes through several
generations of Lilly's isolation tanks
and sort of an Ommaya,
like he starts out floating with the,
uh,
the head given where it's like a scuba
tank,
a helmet on.
That's the beginning of the movie.
Then the end of the movie,
he's lying down.
See,
that's how I really did it in the
beginning and the beginning.
Lily had it set up where there was
literally like a tube connected to his
asshole so he could shit and into the
water and it would be filtered out.
So we never had to leave the water.
Well,
that would be good for road trips and he
would,
uh,
lily would do it with ketamine.
He would shoot up ketamine,
which is like a cat tranquilizer.
I'm not really close to before.
It works with.
That looks claustrophobic.
It's not.
No,
no.
I had done that one.
I've never done that one.
The one I've done is later in the movie
as his character evolves and as the plot
evolves later in the movie,
he has like a more modern version,
the isolation tank where he's like
laying flat and they don't ever
mentioned that he figured out a better
version or anything like that.
They just kind of put it in there,
which is pretty fascinating.
It's pretty cool.
So he really was into it.
You'll see the,
the top one.
Okay.
I guess the top one is the tube is
coming out of the top of the tooth,
but there was another one we laid flat.
What's the actor's name again?
That was William hurt.
William hurt?
Yeah,
he was cool.
He's a bad motherfucker.
Remember him in broadcast news?
Yes.
He was so good.
He's been in a bunch of great movies.
Yeah,
he just came back recently in something.
I forget what it was,
but that John Lilly guy who made that
tank was a like a legitimate,
brilliant scientist who would take all
kinds of shit.
Oh yeah,
he would experiment all the time.
He was,
he was a pioneer in interspecies
communication research with dolphins.
Really.
You don't know if you've ever heard this
story,
but the woman who was doing the
research,
she was living with a young male dolphin
and she lived in this place that was
like waist high and water,
but so she would walk through the water
to get to a furniture to get to where
she would cook and the dolphin lived
with her and swam around with her.
Wait,
wait.
So she would be like up to her waist
like.
Yeah,
in the hallways and then she got to come
up to a platform to cook or she had some
setup where she lived with this dolphin.
Wow.
They all.
They lived in this tank.
Never heard of.
This is crazy and when she did it,
she was there.
Were working on these ideas that they
had to try to get dolphins to recreate
human words like.
But the dolphins,
even if they're not as intelligent as we
are,
which they might be,
who knows?
They don't have the ability to make the
sounds that we make because they they
have.
They don't have lips and tongue.
Yeah.
They have a weird way of making noises.
So they,
they would see the dolphin came super
close to saying hello,
Kim.
Really close to it.
It's kind of weird when you hear it too.
There was a movie done where they were
talking to the dolphins and they and it
was like,
yeah,
she had a sexual relationship.
You're pulling that up positive to get
to that.
Jamie,
do you remember that movie?
Yes.
This is why they canceled it.
Oh,
does it say it says a woman in a
waterproofed house in 1964,
a woman lived in a waterproof health
with a,
with a dolphin called Peter tried to
teach them English and had a sexual
relationship with them.
Oh,
my sword of she would jerk him off
because he would get super horny and
that's all he would want to do is fuck.
And he was confusing and it was
interfering with the research.
So she didn't think there was anything
wrong with jerking off this dolphin.
Yeah.
I don't either.
Look,
there's nothing wrong with it.
Hey.
It's like they live together.
Well.
What?
Why are we so weird about sexual
pleasure?
Like,
what the fuck is that?
Man?
We're so weird.
It is a weird.
It's very complicated.
It's the driving force of all of us and
it's,
you know,
it's a bent and twisted and it's pure
and it's nice and it's,
it's a weird thing,
right?
But if you have friend,
like I had a friend who's a jerk off his
dog with his foot,
doesn't have that friend he got,
I go free.
Real lucky touch.
We put my sock on and I said,
what'd you do?
He goes,
he was fucking dogs.
Dogs horny.
So put my foot on his dick.
And I rubbed it back and forth and he
came all over stomach.
I was seriously,
he felt better and I go,
you know what,
man?
I think it's me.
I don't think it's you.
I think it's made with a stupid problem
in my head about it.
The dog likes it.
How come you can scratch behind the
dog's ears where he can't reach and
that's okay.
But come,
you can't rub his dick.
Have you ever touched your dog's Dick?
Accidentally when you're rubbing his
belly?
My dog has a vagina.
Okay.
And um,
I've never touched it.
No,
never.
Accidentally.
Well,
no,
I don't think so.
Touch my dog's Dick 100 times and he's
only five months old.
It's flying all over the place.
Only nine months old.
And uh,
she's in the vet right now.
Actually,
I got it.
I got a call her.
I left in a,
it could have been a snake.
Could it have been a snake?
That's.
Did she get,
she just looking swollen and puffy.
And this rattlesnake season is happens
all the time.
You have a lab?
Black Larry Possible.
She got bit,
my dog's been bit many times.
Really?
Yeah.
My,
my two dogs that had been bitter dead
now.
But they,
um,
they,
one dog got bit and I took him to the
vet and he,
I knew he got bit and swell up yet I
took her to the vet and he was so
excited because he'd killed a
rattlesnake,
was all fired up and you know,
he'd killed a rattlesnake.
Oh yeah.
Well,
you know,
okay,
this is a disaster.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Once he got to,
once it bit him,
he was like,
fuck,
you tore this thing apart.
And Nice.
Um,
that was Frank Sinatra.
That was my dog named Frank.
Oh,
that's awesome.
But uh,
he wasn't swollen when I brought him to
the vet.
Then when I got him home he started
swelling up like a half hour later it
starts swelling up and then it just gets
like to these cartoonish proportions,
but half their faces hanging off.
Yeah,
it's a,
she was just asking
a little weird this morning and you
know,
we have a yard.
So like,
I don't know,
maybe someone got into the backyard,
but she,
all of a sudden her,
I was a little puffy and I said to my
wife would look at her eyes,
she look a little weird.
She was like,
I think she's having a reaction.
So he brought her into the vet on my way
here and uh,
they rushed her right in and they're
like,
good thing you got here early and
they're going to work on her.
So I don't know what's up,
but we're trying to figure,
uh,
we can they get sick from eating,
raccoon feces.
Ever hear that?
I would
not imagine it'd be good for you.
I noticed because we had a trainer that
was like,
she's not eating that is here.
I'm like,
no.
I mean,
is that big deal?
she eats everything.
He's like a goat.
Yeah.
I'm like,
as,
that's the only thing I could think of
because I couldn't.
Well,
there's definitely got to be something
in that.
I mean,
raccoons have to have parasites.
They're wild animals.
Yeah.
It's got to have some weird.
They're wild animals too.
And they eat animals,
so as soon as an animal is eating other
animals,
that's when shit gets weird right now
for wild animal.
Like you could eat a deer raw.
Right?
And there'd be no problem at all.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
The real problem is animals that eat
animals
because the deer doesn't eat.
Animals kill the deer.
Could get a pair of side and deers have
gotten worms before.
I've heard of people that in lyme
disease that had.
No,
no,
that's just the ticks cause severe
inflammatory reactions when that's not
really a specific around severe
inflammatory maybe will migrate to other
organs including the brain.
Oh Geez.
Well I,
I've had dogs that have worms before
that were coming out of there,
but like they poop and as they would
walk away you would see worms literally
crawling out of their butt and you're
like,
oh,
okay.
And your lifestyle have whacked you off.
When we had the kids
would be so confused.
Let me put on a sock.
Get over here.
So not true.
Yeah.
Parasitic relationships.
Like when you think about how many dogs
have worms is like one of the number one
things you got to do what your dog get
it dewormed.
Yeah.
So often.
So often just eating shit.
They eat everything.
Everything.
My dog ate a magnet.
You know how they have those magnets?
We stack magnet kids play with them.
Strong thick ass.
Heavy magnet.
Yeah.
I've found it in his shit.
Oh,
I'm surprised it came out.
You had came out,
came right out.
I mean dogs.
Intestinal tract is made out of
barbwire,
you know,
things just co writes shits and all of a
sudden a metal rollerskate comes up to
the ship.
Just a thrilling thing.
Nastiest dog I've ever had in terms of
eating his own shit.
This new one.
Yeah.
He tries to eat his own shit when he
doesn't anymore.
He stopped.
But I'm sure he has like recently.
But for the most part he does.
It's weird.
Leaves it alone.
But when he was a puppy,
like when I just got him and he's a few
weeks old.
Yeah.
He would take a shit and literally
trying to bite this shit as it's coming
out of his ass.
You would have to like grab him to keep
him from eating the shit as it was
coming.
He thought it was like a Mr. softy
machine.
I can't believe it comes right out of my
thing.
It's like,
look man,
I love you,
but you got to stop doing this.
Why Joe?
You want get a cone?
A cone.
Come on.
But good thing is it made me like really
diligent about scooping poop up in the
yard.
Dive on that.
You got to get it up quick,
quick.
Let them.
So we,
we,
we bought like a special trash can that
you just,
you know my other dogs going through the
same thing.
We're going through the same thing.
How old is,
he's a baby.
He's five months old.
Yeah,
we're at nine months.
Babies are babies.
One that's in the hospital,
baby?
Yeah.
Nine months.
I hope she's okay.
She comes home with like mystery shit on
her head.
Like where did you even get this?
Just walks in all happy to see what the
big blob of shit or Emma has on our
head.
I killed a rattlesnake a month ago.
You did?
Really?
Yeah.
It's on a walkway.
I court where I was walking.
I was like,
fuck this by your house,
by a friend's house actually had you
kill it.
Stomped on it.
Just went up and stomped.
Didn't try to bite.
You know?
I got to it before it got to me.
Oh really?
Yeah.
It wasn't a big rail snake,
but it's.
Well,
what kind of shoe?
Where were you were wearing?
I don't remember.
It'd be a nice boot.
It was definitely not a wise move.
No,
no.
It was just something in me like said,
like,
first of all,
my friends would want me to kill this
isn't one fucking snake in his yard.
Words kids live.
Right.
And second of all,
um,
I think I could do it right now.
It was one of those things like,
I think this snake is slipping on me.
He's not looking.
It doesn't know because most people are
not going to just stomp your fucking
head of your rattlesnake.
Yeah.
But I was like,
dad is the move right now.
Just try to.
Yeah,
the rattlesnakes instinct is humans run
from me.
Yeah.
And it's,
it's like you kinda see some people tell
you not supposed to do it.
Okay.
And I understand what they're saying.
Like I would not want all the rattle
snakes to die.
I'm not a rattlesnake hater,
but I have rules and if you get into my
house,
if you're a snake in your,
my house,
I'm going to fucking kill you for sure.
One hundred percent.
And it's not my house,
but I mean it was in front of my
friend's house and he has kids.
That's a dead snake.
Yeah.
Kill that sense.
I personally would not have done it,
but it was a garter snake.
It was like,
I've seen those.
I don't bother them.
No,
they're not.
Where they're going to gum you to death.
No.
But this guy also has a little dogs to
dogs get jacked.
Maybe she got bit by a snake.
Oh Dude.
Easily,
easily happen.
I've had three dogs.
Bit By rattlesnakes in California.
Yeah,
they're all over.
I almost got bit by one.
I was,
while I was hiking down a little trail,
I might have said this last time I was
walking down a trail and uh,
my wife was behind me and uh,
it was a narrow part and I just came
around the corner and the thing just
went,
oh,
fuck,
right at me.
And I just backed up.
I just ran right past.
My wife says,
why are we running?
And they came back and he was pissed off
at the edge of the trail and this little
Bush and uh,
I just threw rocks at it and ran past
it.
Coulda.
Got You.
I can totally.
Then when this is now,
that's the thing,
and I'm still not clear on it.
We're two miles up in the mountain.
They say you're not supposed to move or
else you'll get it pumping through your
system.
Oh,
Jesus.
Do you make a tourniquet?
I don't know.
I still,
I should have learned since then,
but the idea that my wife would have
carried me out doesn't make sense.
We'll go for help,
right.
Is kind of tough,
you know,
two mile hike down the mountain and
back.
They make snake proof boots.
You should look into him.
Maybe snakes like you maybe like one of
those people that like,
people like mosquitoes,
mosquitoes,
like people you know,
like I could be right next to it by all
the mosquitoes everywhere.
There's rattlesnakes.
There's no problem.
You said you cook.
Oh,
I brought you bread.
Oh fuck.
You know,
I know.
I know you don't really eat it and I
don't want to mess with your condo and
elk thing or you eat it occasionally.
But look at.
Look at the bag that I have.
Okay.
I have these bags now.
Paper Bag.
This is how much the perfectly shaped
for these bread.
Oh look at that.
It does look really good,
but if a just came out this morning,
look at that.
Beautiful.
It smells amazing,
but I figured his art,
even art,
even if you don't want you to give it to
your family,
I'll eat a piece of that for a little.
A little butter.
Oh,
give it to the family tonight.
I've perfected my methods and so it was
here last.
Wow.
You know,
it's really intense with that brand.
Do you ever hear of a gentleman's
breakfast?
No.
Pool comes from England.
London.
Is it like blood sausage or something?
Not as intense.
You take a butter at night.
Let it soften on the,
on the counter.
Chop up garlic and anchovies.
Mix it all together into the butter.
Put it in the fridge in the morning.
You toast some of that delicious
sourdough bread and thick layer of that
butter on it with some eggs on the side.
It's called the gentleman's breakfast.
There's something about first thing in
the morning,
garlic anchovy butter.
Dangerous.
Oh,
it's so good.
It's a bold choice.
You don't give a fuck about your breath.
No,
you're not.
You don't want to be near people that
you don't want to be near people for a
good day.
You might've just eradicated in morning
breath,
brush your teeth and then you got down
with this.
It sounds nasty,
but I'm telling you,
it is the most delicious thing I've ever
had.
Sounds amazing.
I want to do an amazing anchovies.
Garlic.
And what else?
Anchovies and butter.
That's it.
Just those three things.
Just let it soften.
Mix it all together.
Chop up the anchovies and the garlic.
Really fine.
Throw it all in there.
Do you know what will ruin you if you
get real anchovies?
Like you ever get like fresh anchovies?
Like in Italy?
No.
Oh,
I mean maybe in a dish of something,
but yeah,
I've gotten fresh and trophies and fresh
sardines.
Sardines,
sardines in Sicily.
Amazing.
You go with this.
Women.
This is what a sardine.
Yeah.
It's not all covered in Goo.
Thick paint.
Like oil mustard.
Yeah.
So fresh anchovies.
I have never who that would make the
gentleman's breakfast even better.
I bet it would have like when you get
like a really good Caesar Salad at a
really good restaurant and they do it by
the table.
The real old school.
Yeah.
And it takes like 10 minutes.
He's there working on that thing in
front of you.
That'd be like,
yeah,
that's a real old school move,
right?
Like some show and frank's type thing.
That's right.
They don't.
Yeah.
Oh,
I love Musso and frank's.
is that place 100 years old?
It's the oldest restaurant in la.
Yeah,
I think it's one years.
I think you're reading.
It's like 1915 or something like that.
Yeah,
you get a Martini in that place.
It is just.
It's just perfect.
They know what they're doing.
It's all old school stuff.
It will keep the stakes.
They put it in a tiny glass instead of
these giant glasses like they use now
it's a smaller glass and then they give
you the extra in ice on the side of your
glass.
Those guys and they look.
Any place that has a 70 year old guy
waiting on you in a uniform.
Look at that.
Yeah,
that guy.
Then you know you're in good shape.
Let's go there.
Let's go there one night for dinner.
We should.
We should go before the store.
Yes.
Go for steaks and a bunch of guys
together.
Yes,
girl come,
eh?
The problem is girls don't really like
it there.
I've taken girls,
they're my wife's downloaded and they're
not that into it.
They don't like an old man's pickle
fingers given you your meat
that turns the ladies off.
But funny though,
those places that still have that kind
of.
There's like,
you can't fake that in a mall,
you know?
You know what I mean?
You have like a new Musso and frank's.
Yeah,
there's like a.
what's the Rayos in New York?
It's like five tables.
It's hard to get into.
It's like where Joe Torry eats with
Derek jeter and Giuliani,
the inside this Musan.
Frank's Mussa.
Yeah.
God,
it looks awesome.
I sat at that bar with a couple friends.
I've sat in that booth,
like the curve booth at the back with my
wife and a friend.
What's that one?
Steakhouse in New York where they hang
pipes from the sealant.
Is it called keen's?
What is it called?
Keen's.
The clay pipes.
Is that the name of it?
Yeah.
Am I seeing the right name?
Keens k e h n e phenomenal steakhouse.
And um,
for some reason,
like back in the day,
like famous people would bring their
pipe and they would hang the pipe on the
wall.
They would give you a pipe,
they would give you a clay pipe and they
have pipes that from everyone that's
smoked them,
they're Einstein Pattern,
Roosevelt,
all of these people and they ended the
place is covered with it and then I roll
in there for the first time in 2001 when
the smoking ban has gone into effect and
you're not allowed to smoke a pipe in
this legendary place.
I've felt so cheated,
cheated,
like when I be like,
well,
when I went through puberty and aids
showed up,
you know what I mean?
It's like,
why us?
Why can't I smoke and put my pipe next
to Albert Einstein's?
Yeah.
When I was.
When I was 16 or 17,
if I remember correctly,
they raise the drinking age to 21.
It used to be 18.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's right.
Eighteen months.
Twenty one.
Just missed it.
We did.
Just miss it.
Wow.
Look at these.
Babe Ruth.
Babe Ruth Pipe.
Peewee Herman.
Now limit different kind of pipe.
Hey,
wow.
Theodore Roosevelt's pipe.
Whoa.
Look at that.
And then we roll in there and we're not
allowed.
Come on.
I know it's like that week I understands
cleaning up the city and stopping people
from having cancer,
but of one night buffalo bills pipe
buffalo bill,
they have a beautiful nude behind the
bar to this huge paintings.
Yeah.
Keans.
It's a beautiful painting of this
beautiful ceiling at one ceiling.
We see all the pipes.
Jamie,
look at that.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
it shouldn't.
Joe Rogan's pipe be up there.
Not Be faking it.
I've only been there twice.
I know,
but I've only smoked a pipe.
Wants on this show.
I like,
I like a nice pipe once in a while.
What happened at pipe smoking?
Where'd it go?
I don't know because they're so much
more pleasant to people that are around
you.
Like a cigar drives everyone out of the
room.
I love cigars,
but I likes her.
There are so they're rude.
But uh,
you smoke a pipe.
The ladies aren't as offended.
Why is that?
Because it's more aromatic.
It's Perfumey two gentleman's craft.
I have a pipe in my,
uh,
in my little pencil case,
hybrid here.
I just take it out.
I don't smoke it,
I just walk around with it.
Pack One and right now for you.
These guys with their pipes.
Pipes.
No wheat.
Huh?
Why can't we be like that?
I don't know what happened to us.
I don't know.
A bunch of babies.
Such babies worried about cancer.
I understand trying to help people with
the cancer and all that,
but none of that one place.
Can't keen still smoke.
There should be places that you could go
there like a club.
I go to the Soho Cigar bar when I'm in
New York.
That's a nice little spot.
I've,
I've smoked there with Chappelle and uh,
Allen Havey grabber.
Kelly.
It's a great hang.
You Go and you sit like gentlemen,
Gentlemen,
Gentlemen.
Just discuss your life and you meditate
after the day.
It's a beautiful thing.
Yeah.
You could do that in a cigar bar.
This is a place that I go.
You can order food and you could smoke
cigars.
It's great.
It's amazing.
It's good.
Good restaurant to that.
Smells good.
It does smell good.
Right?
Thank you.
Steven crowder for the lovely pipe
tobacco problem with the pipes.
You've got to keep it going now.
Could you,
whenever you see at the Improv and
stuff,
that picture of Jay Leno with his pipe
in the old days when he was playing the
Improv like we are,
he would smoke.
He would carry his pipe around.
Could someone pull that off?
Could somebody do that today?
You'd have to do a lot of drugs.
You'd have to be like that hunter s
Thompson guy that does so much drugs.
We'll let you have a cigarette holder.
Right?
Remember when Hunter s Thompson used to
rock a cigarette holder?
Nobody else rocked a cigarette holder,
done hills.
In the end.
He did it because he was just so far out
there that everybody was like,
it's fine.
Right?
It's real.
I guess you'd have to have really
kickass material like you couldn't be
happy with a pipe.
Yeah.
Chris Rock and rock a pipe.
If you have killer,
killer material,
you could have a.
You can do whatever you like.
Chris Rock.
Now that he's divorced to go onstage,
one of those who have nerve lord jackets
on Velvet,
right?
It'd be velvet jacket on,
a smoking jacket.
Smoking pipe.
I have one of those.
Yeah,
it's a red from brooks brothers is nice,
nice.
Smokey,
deep pockets.
Like you put all your pipes and lighters
in it.
Do you walk around your house like in
your underwear with a robe on ever?
Uh,
yeah.
Do you closed?
But yeah,
I wear a robe because it's all girls in
my,
in my place.
It's weird to.
At what age is it inappropriate for kids
to see your deck?
Uh,
I would say for boys,
no age for boys.
No Age.
The boys?
No age for girls.
Um,
I'm going to say like three,
four,
like three,
four years.
They're pretty really.
They would climb into the shower and
like point and the laughter that let
them look at it.
They can't see it now.
What if you climb of the shower and
they're right there.
Do you hide?
Yeah,
like when I come out of the shower I've
got to walk down this little hallway and
that door is sometimes opening.
It's towards my daughter's rooms and uh,
I'm really conscious of and it's such a
weird.
I catch myself a lot.
I'm totally naked,
but as long as I put everything in my
palm of my hand,
that would be okay if they happen to
catch me too.
My sister weird.
My seven year old stands in front of
shower door points in my deck and laughs
at seven.
My youngest is hilarious.
She's really funny,
man.
She's just like,
all she wants to do is go for the laugh
like all the time.
She's constantly just going for the lab
and that's her thing is that she's like
really silly,
but yeah.
And so like,
she's like really silly at school.
She's really silly at home.
That's my little one.
She just loves having fun.
Yeah.
Good student.
Yeah,
she's real good.
She's a great kid,
which is really interesting to see kids
grow up without the same kind of
financial pressure that I grew up with
or that you grew up with two or the not
the same kind of weirdness in the house
he had.
There's no like when the dad isn't.
It's,
it's Dan.
That's when dad's not freaking out that
too.
And also,
you know,
I just think people know more about
people now.
Oh,
I think our parents didn't even have a
chance.
No,
they were trying.
They didn't even understand themselves.
Let alone understand time with you and
what was going to make you feel good and
most likely they were crazy young.
Like how old were you?
Twenty?
Yeah,
my mom was 20 or 21.
She was 20 when she got pregnant.
Twenty one.
Chad.
Me?
Yeah.
If I can go back and think about when I
was 20.
If somebody told me how to raise a kid
at 20.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
I'd have a grownup.
A psychopath right now that I've been
trying to manage.
Dude,
I'm sorry.
I got the whole thing wrong.
I don't know how we can redo this.
I think about that sometimes.
You really have to let.
I let I let my parents off the hook all
the time now just in my memories because
like when my dad said that to me,
he was.
He was 28.
You know what I mean?
He had no idea when he was 28 before the
Internet.
Yeah.
I think 28 today is way more
knowledgeable.
Yeah.
There's pockets of flat earthers and
shit out there that ruined the curve,
but other than that,
28 today is way more knowledgeable I
think then 28 of 20 years ago and yet so
much more immature.
Maybe some in some ways,
but I think that's generalizing.
I mean it's think it's really hard to
say people today is you're talking about
so many people.
You're talking about $350 million
people.
Yeah,
but you know the idea that people were
like men and women were raising
families,
doing all their hard work,
doing all that like very adult stuff.
There's an adolescence now that's
extended until your mid thirties.
That's true.
You know what I mean?
It's like they may not be as intelligent
because they don't have as much.
They didn't have as much knowledge and
stuff,
but they were grown ups.
There was a distinction like I'm doing
grown up shit now.
Do you think that's almost like an
evolutionary course?
Like life gets easier and then people
learn more about stuff,
but they don't have the same sort of
physical resolve that people did back in
the old days.
They had to work harder.
Yeah,
maybe.
And also it's kind of like the two kind
of go together.
It seems like there's a direction that
people are moving into.
Yeah.
And we'll think about it.
You know,
back then people were dying at 60,
70.
Now if you're living to 100 W,
why shouldn't your twenties be a little
more adolescent?
Yeah.
Because you're going to live so much
longer will apparently deliv longer
thing a big,
a big part of what the live longer thing
is.
They,
um,
they reduced a lot of infant mortality
and a lot of is like the average of how
people die.
It's also infections when you're
younger.
Colon,
all sorts of things before medical
science.
But the actual age that people live to
hasn't really changed as much as people
think.
Really?
Yeah.
I thought it did too,
but it's what it really is,
is that.
Didn't Chris Ryan explained that to us?
I believe it was Dr Chris Ryan Phd.
Oh,
author of sex at dawn.
A good friend.
I know him well,
but he,
I believe he was one who educated us on
that.
That what,
what's going on is that you're counting
in infant mortality.
I'm like,
used to be like,
if people got an infection,
like a blood infection before
antibiotics,
guests.
Well,
you're dead.
Right.
You know what I mean?
You get septic,
guess what?
Your Dad.
Yeah.
Rabies.
You're dead snake bite.
Yeah,
your dad.
Everybody's dead.
But yeah.
But are people living like,
aren't there,
there's more like a 90 year old people
aren't there?
I don't.
I would like to find that out.
Let's find out.
It also is probably cultural.
Like,
you know,
when I was in Africa,
I was talking to a guy who's 50 and he
was acting like he was at the end of his
life just matter of factly,
just stoically.
He's like,
I don't have much time,
you know,
and for people in the Maasai,
they don't live that long.
Yeah.
Because lions around fucking lines.
If you're 50 and you haven't been eating
yet,
you're like,
Holy Shit.
What a great run of God on the goods
have smiled upon me.
I will continue.
Cecil has not taken my life.
Says the US,
uh,
March of 2016 said for the first time in
human history,
I guess people who are 65 and older will
surpass those under five.
So there'll be more people that are
older than there are that our young
people are staying alive.
But um,
are they last longer?
Uh,
so would you know what I'm saying?
No,
no,
no.
They're not living longer to like 100
years old,
but there's more people that are alive
that are 65.
So it's like people are staying alive,
but are they living longer?
Like what is the long age that people
live like if you don't die of something,
if you just die of old age,
what is that number?
And has that number moved?
Yeah,
I think that number one,
that we just fixate on that one.
Do I die?
It's heavy man.
The man you ever watched Netflix and you
accidentally hit the remote and you see
it like there's a 48 minutes left and
you're like,
fuck,
now I know.
Yes.
I could have just been locked into this
movie enjoying to what it is now.
10.
Okay.
Forty eight minutes.
No,
I kind of have to pay.
Should I hold it?
Should I pause?
And sometimes you feel shitty about
yourself.
When you check,
you're like,
I'm really enjoying this.
Why do I have to know?
Because we're retarded.
I feel bad sometimes if I check my phone
and there's nothing on it.
Like why did I even do that?
Yeah,
I got it.
Like if you just obsessively like look
at your phone and see if you got a text.
Why it's the worst thing is such a,
a life suck.
It is sometimes,
but again it's also something that just
needs to be managed because it's a main.
A major connection to news was fucked
up.
Now I get the Time magazine alerts.
You get a New York Times alerts.
I don't.
I don't have the alerts.
I'll have the swipe left and see it.
I have alerts for a certain breaking
news things and four days it was just
trump.
Yeah.
So every time I followed a fibrate I
take a deep breath.
Please don't tell me what were at war.
Like look at my phone.
Please don't tell him he dropped a nuke.
Please don't tell me some shit has gone
down every day.
It's a new Russia shit every day it was.
It was so rapid fire like those last two
weeks before he took off on his
vacation.
Or is his world tour?
Well,
you know,
it was nonstop.
There's something that was just revealed
that is really interesting that James
Comey has said that he ended the Hillary
Clinton investigation early because
there was some evidence that was
introduced against her that was clearly
counterfeit and from Russia and so he
didn't want that evidence to leak.
Excuse me.
That.
How crazy is that?
I know.
Well,
that's what I heard.
I heard some congressmen on face the
nation say that.
He said,
this is why this is what is going to
getting gigs.
Get scary about all these leaks and
stuff.
He goes,
they're taking the information from the
emails,
from people say like,
you know,
the emails from the DNC or whatever and
they're leaving 99 percent of it
perfect.
And they put just one little line in
that says something that's heinous or
says something about somebody doing
something toward or something and they
put that out [inaudible] that's more
dangerous than just in the old days.
You just try and like launch some big
story now that just bury this one little
item in this huge dump of information.
How do you sift through that?
How do you need something and it's been
leaked to Wiki leaks.
How do they know that it hasn't been
altered exactly.
Is that something that they do checks
on?
Do you know?
Find that that's what the comey thing.
It's like,
but it took a long time,
you know,
in the initial dump it was like they
just go through it and what's this.
But it takes a long time to sift through
it and see if that's really a true story
or not.
Because that is like bubble gum right
now.
Yeah,
I mean that's crazy.
That would be an amazing feat if they
could verify 100 percent the veracity of
these emails that are being leaked,
they probably verify the sources.
Yeah.
But whether or not they could verify
that this hasn't been altered in any
way.
I don't know.
Maybe we just don't understand the
technology.
Maybe they can do that.
They'll probably get there.
I mean they've got to be working on it.
What the fuck that.
That's my whole philosophy with
everything in life right now is
someone's working on that.
Right?
Well,
it is so crazy as to go.
Someone's working on that.
Will they have.
They have been working on that,
trying to figure out a way to use it for
fuel.
That would be cool.
They think they can do it too.
They think we're,
you know,
who knows how long away from using all
of our nuclear waste as fuel.
Who were like a,
I don't know,
a rocket ship.
I don't know.
They were talking about using,
making batteries with it.
A diamonds.
Remember that they were talking about
using nuclear radiation from nuclear
waste to charge diamonds as batteries at
some star trek stuff.
I know it sounds like where you have
like this one little orb of stuff in the
pirates.
I needed second Jamie a standby.
Right now.
It seems like they can't,
like,
they can't actually confirm authenticity
of the stuff they're getting.
They can't.
Oh,
if the email wiki leaks.
So when wikileaks gets an email they
can't necessarily guarantee the
veracity,
confirm it,
but then they did at some point like at
the hip they couldn't with the hillary
stuff in the beginning,
but at a certain like now companies will
call me saying that one thing seemed to
be a counterfeit.
So one thing being counted for his like,
okay,
how do you know?
Like they're not gonna release how they
know yet.
Right.
There's,
there's a whole crazy constant
information going to go on with him and
this and it gets trapped.
Yeah,
it's.
it's,
it's big stuff.
It's weird time stuff.
It's weird.
I don't know how weird it is.
I mean I really feel like.
I feel like trump was running.
He didn't know what he's going to win.
They were just like,
you know,
there was still,
he's still a businessman.
They're dealing with Russia and they're
doing with all this stuff.
They weren't thinking like politicians
like this might look bad one day.
Then holy shit,
he gets through in the momentum carries
and now he's the guy now it's like,
oh,
so manafort probably shouldn't have
promise made that deal with them in the,
you know,
what me and like all this other.
He kind of got caught up because he just
wasn't.
He was a businessman.
He was doing that stuff,
but he definitely wanted to.
When you know,
you don't think he expected to win.
I don't think he expected it to it.
Now he's still talking about it.
Like,
Holy Shit,
I won.
He says that every,
every time you ask him a question,
you'd be like,
so what do you think about palm trees?
Should we save those?
I don't know,
but you know,
it's really hard for a Republican to win
the electoral college,
but I did it.
Did you see the map?
I just put up a map in my office and
doesn't that just because he likes to
congratulate himself partially,
but he's also a little in awe.
Like Paul,
I don't see it that way now.
I see him as extremely self
congratulatory part of his whole Shtick,
like when he talks about a television
show,
say,
oh,
it's number one because he watches it.
Right.
All the rating.
You seem shoved the guy out of the way.
What the fuck was that about?
He's out of the way and then straighten
his jacket,
like a guy in a movie and when he pushed
him either way he gritted his teeth,
like get the fuck out of here.
So that's so weird.
Who is the guy who pushed out of the
way?
He's the.
I'm the leader of Montenegro who's just
coming into the European Union.
So he's there like,
this is my first time with all the,
with the whole EU.
This is my first time being here and
they're coming up for a photo and he
shut trumps,
shoves him out of the way and then
straight to this thing like I'm all
right.
Photos,
the glowing,
glowing or the counter terrorism globe
kind of find that you see in the photo
from the other angle,
like what shows what they're looking at,
like all the desks and the crazy cli.
No,
it's the fucking pictures.
Preposterous.
That's everything that every conspiracy
go back everything.
Every conspiracy theorists is fucking
terrified of.
You're right.
There's a dude behind him who's dressed
in traditional Arab garb.
Yeah.
The Saudi guy was probably worth a
trillion dollars.
He touching the globe.
The other guy.
Where's he from?
With his perfect suit and his Iranian
face.
Right.
He looks like a Middle Eastern gentlemen
also touching that globe than trump with
his expensive suit on his crazy hair.
He's touching the light coming up from
underneath like a scary camp.
A fucking story man.
As a movie touch.
They're holding onto a globe at the same
time and it's glowing.
It's so weird.
Comic Book Right now.
It really is to comic book.
This is a scene in star wars.
What the fuck is that?
That's so crazy.
Why do that?
Do you think Obama would hold onto that
globe about would be like,
hold on.
What are we doing?
The globe glowing.
Okay.
What does that represent?
I don't think we're gonna pass on the
globe.
Why is it?
Why is it glowing?
Raving explanation for this.
Exactly.
Can we take this?
Uh,
let's take a picture.
The Fountain and Steph.
Fuck.
Just all of it.
This is so hard.
It's so a.
it's a big oil grab.
Now I understand why dudes are out there
with the fucking metal detector.
Man's simplify life.
Just looking for shiny rocks.
Joe and shit.
I'm telling you,
this bread obsession of mine is if
things are going well,
I'm probably not making as much bread,
but to just go in simply and just be
making bread with the news off and just
put on some Bob Marley and just go and
make bread and give it to my friends and
family.
It's a calming thing in these chaotic
times and I'm not,
you know,
it's Corny,
but I'm not trying to be corny,
but I really believe that back to basic.
It seems like people are just like,
let's just simplify things.
This is out of whack.
Totally.
Let me just.
Well,
bread is a task right now.
You've got your ingredients,
you know what to do,
and if you do all the things that you're
supposed to do,
it'll come out this delicious,
amazing food that you can eat.
Yeah,
and yet it's elusive.
It's you have to attend to it and it's a
craft.
Yeah.
Right.
So this task,
it becomes this thing that your mind is
fixated on and you can fill your
consciousness with the nuances of this
task and not thinking about all the
bullshit,
like these fucking Weirdos grabbing
globes.
Right.
Exactly.
Makes Shit Weird.
Oil deals all over.
The other question that we were asking
about when we were trying,
I was trying to double Jamie Montenegro.
Well,
the death,
the average death.
Oh yeah.
That didn't really get to yet.
70 eight point eight is what it.
It hasn't changed from 78 point eight
for men.
Yeah,
but I think that's still based off of
that infant mortality thing added into
it.
That's always added into it just like
right out of like a James Bond.
Totally.
This is like x man.
It's like star wars,
like you expect darth vader to like be
at the end of that and the guy comes in
after his to give her the report on what
happened
seriously though,
could you imagine being trump a guy who
used to host a reality show on NBC?
Yeah.
He's a successful businessman.
You know,
he's a well known guy,
but I mean how much of that is a ramp up
between you or I or a lot of people that
we know that are famous,
like how much of it like Jerry Seinfeld
is Donald Trump a ramp up in popularity
over Jerry Seinfeld.
I guess he is now that he's president,
but when Jerry was on TV and Traumas,
they're kind of commensurate.
You could see like Jerry Seinfeld being
president as well.
I sure Ronald Reagan go back to that
original picture that we were just
looking at.
Just a couple of frames go now go and
think of a guy like this.
Go full screen on this fucking thing.
Imagine Jerry Seinfeld and all of a
sudden Seinfeld gets invited to this
league of nations thing.
It looks like a superhero comic book
scene in one of those movies.
I mean,
there's a goddamn picture of the earth.
That's a light that's on the wall.
All the light on the floor is blue.
There's little spotlights everywhere.
It's all freaky and clean and perfect.
There's these little screens in front of
every chair.
Like,
what the fuck is this?
This is where all the world's decisions
get made.
Yeah.
It looks
like the,
uh,
what's the Peter Sellers movie will make
with the bottom of the strange.
It looks like that's just strange.
It looks like.
Exactly.
Well,
just,
I mean,
why would we expect them to make more
sense than us?
That's the thing about world leaders,
like they're just people and they're
people that have an extraordinary amount
of power with not nearly as much
oversight.
Right?
In most countries.
Right.
And most of these Middle Eastern
countries and most of these,
I mean,
they don't really have to fucking tell
people what they're doing.
They do whatever the hell they want.
Yeah,
for sure.
A lot of these places that we have
relationships with,
if crazy human rights violations,
I mean you get,
you have to deal with good and bad.
You can't really have a look at that
man.
Imagine someone like Seinfeld there.
Imagine if he won.
Like what if Seinfeld became president
and like,
what is this globe?
What are we doing with this thing on the
wall?
I can't find my translator.
Trump is he's.
I mean,
we always think of like politicians the
same way.
I used to think about celebrities before
I met a few of them.
Yeah.
When you go,
oh,
let's just a dude.
He's just a dude,
right?
He's just a guy.
Yeah.
Just a guy just happened to be there to
become famous.
Yeah.
Well,
I think that's kind of the same way with
politicians.
We've always thought of people.
That's one of the reasons why we've
almost like allowed them a certain
amount of leeway when it comes to
insincerity and you know,
getting caught in corruption and lies
with.
There's a certain amount will like she's
a politician,
he's a senator.
Just what they do.
You let it slide a little bit of it
slide,
but if it was like a friend that was
doing that,
you'd have like serious problems with
them.
Yeah.
You know?
But look,
it's.
Things have to be a little dirty because
you're dealing with everybody.
You know,
There's so many interests.
You got to.
That's what a politician is.
It's a compromise.
It's playing both sides of trying to get
stuff done.
You know,
I think we've gone to.
This is absurd point of
misinterpreting.
Good for flawless.
You know what I mean?
There could be good people who have a
lot of dirty stuff going on.
No one's flawless.
The idea that based on the Internet,
we're able to get all information on
everybody all the time.
We can't hold people to a standard of
being flawless.
It doesn't exist,
but I think you can be good while still
making some.
You know you can.
If you set that parameter,
that bar,
you're never going to have people that
are good enough.
Yeah,
and you're going to have these Weirdos
that have insane egos because those are
the only ones that are willing to take
the punishment of being criticized the
way trump's taking it right now,
but he's,
you know,
he's taking it away that no one's ever
taken it before.
You could say he deserves it.
I'm not saying that I'm not,
I'm not making a judgment call.
I'm saying,
well,
it is absolutely fascinating the way the
media and the way people online are
treating this president of the United
States,
it may be justified.
I'm not,
I'm not
arguing that it's not.
What I'm saying though is it's a very
unique moment in time where you see so
many people attacking the president.
Well,
it's such a rush.
I mean,
you know,
you could say I was having a discussion
with my teenage daughter about
navigating online stuff and seeing what
people are doing and it's almost like
the president is going through the same
thing that you're going through as a
comedian that teenage girls are going
through.
This is a flood of information and
access and attacks and praise and
everything from everybody all the time,
24 hours a day.
So the same way we have to navigate,
you know,
when haters and all that kind of stuff.
The same way kids do.
The president has to deal with a flood
that's never been this raging before.
I mean it is an intense,
intense thing and it almost is like who
else?
But somebody built for television is
ready for this job
at this time.
Not even him,
but what I was saying is that like
politicians were always like a thing,
not like you or I,
but then all of a sudden they are thing
like Uri because now it's trump and he
might not be like the average person,
but he's like,
you are.
I,
you know,
like I almost did a show when I was
doing the free version,
the new version of a fear factor.
They invited me to do it and I thought
about it for a while,
but I would have had to live in New York
for a few months and I was like,
I don't want to do that.
The new thing that's coming out,
the old.
Oh,
the old one,
like in 2011 or whatever the hell it was
when we redid it again.
Yep.
But I mean,
he would've been with him.
I could have been hanging out with him.
You know what I'm saying?
On the marriage riff.
Yeah.
I sat with him on the marriage trip.
We stage.
The first thing he said when he walked
into the dressing room was,
we're going to get great ratings
tonight.
We're going to get great ratings.
He was so focused and he was impressive.
He was tall.
He was a dominant guy in the room.
And uh,
yeah.
And then I'm sitting on stage with him
and we were all talking about married
couples.
It was like a,
like a,
you would show real people and then
you'd discuss their marital problems and
the celebrities would weigh in and the
whole time he's next to me and the whole
time he's making jokes about the girl's
breasts.
He's just like,
you know,
nothing really funny.
He was being funny and he would be like,
well,
you know,
she's got something going for and then
he would look at me and give me a little
wink on the side and it wasn't for the
cameras,
it's just for me and it felt kind of
creepy,
but it's kind of like he was just a
dude.
He's sitting there with me in equal
footing and now he's the president of
the United States.
Think about how powerful.
There's not one human being,
I don't believe in the country that
doesn't have the word trump go through
their brain.
Whether they say it out loud or not
all day,
or at least a couple times a day.
You know what I mean?
It's so insane.
Yeah.
There's initial disbelief.
Then there was an aftershock and now
there is a waiting for the next shoe to
drop.
That's what every day.
Everybody's just sitting around waiting
for the newest scandal every day,
waiting for the impeachment,
waiting for the lawsuits,
waiting for the jail.
You just want calm.
You know?
You have a great joke when you.
You've been working on about a.
This isn't a job for one person,
right?
This,
she really should be a committee of
people running this country.
It's too much for somebody and I love
that joke,
but I think that what his job is what
that president's job is more than
anything is to just lead people.
You Ha.
He has power.
All those people in those positions,
they have power and what they say and
what they do affects people.
Not Policy.
Just the Reagan ask her all,
carry themselves,
make you feel good about the direction.
All that,
and right now everybody's filled with
anxiety because he's not doing that part
of the job well,
but he still goes on twitter and calls
people losers and you're like,
wait.
It's like it's like a kid.
Like you were saying before,
it's like a kid hearing,
like having a be batshit crazy in the
house.
The house is going to be crazy.
If Dad is shooting heroin and he's
laying on the couch is covered and
cheetos and he's yelling at the wife,
the whole house is going to be freaked
out.
That's what's going on.
But is that the price that we have to
pay to realize that our system is
ridiculous?
Is there any the throwing the card table
up and is there any value in that
thought?
I mean other than the real issues with
the environment,
the rolling back,
the standards on the EPA and all the
different things he's doing to free
people out in the code access pipeline,
which I don't understand enough to know
whether or not they were going to
restart that.
Anyway,
I know Obama shut it down.
Right.
And then trump brought it back up again.
Who knows if they had made some sort of
an agreement.
Yeah.
Who knows how that works.
Who knows if they,
you know how that business is very
dirty.
It's very dirty.
Totally.
You know,
I mean it's,
you know,
you could make a case that all of this
is a big oil grab,
right?
I mean,
well the Dakota pipeline stuff was
terrifying.
Dakota pipeline stuff.
The head of the EPA is an oil guy.
The secretary of state is an Exxon guy.
The people he favors more than our
Russian,
more than our European allies are Saudi
Arabia and Russia,
big oil business partners.
You could say this is just business as
you.
And it's right.
And the thing is,
and this is what's so complex about it,
it's okay.
So maybe it's an oil grabbing,
the he's getting his friends rich,
but oil also is so much more than just
what's coming out of our cars.
We are so deep in oil,
it's,
it's not.
I'm my whole.
My main thing is the planet and its
beauty and trying to sustain it.
I'm a complete believer in climate
change and all of that.
But to naive Lee say we can just shut
down oil and be like,
we can all just move along.
It's so much deeper than that.
My nephew is a,
uh,
went to just graduated from school and
he's big agro guy,
like that's what he wants to do with his
whole life.
His revelation was that oil and food are
so interconnected.
All of the fertilizer that's creating
all of the food that we're eating every
day is oil based.
He said,
so you're trying to separate,
uh,
emissions and all this stuff,
but just the food that we eat is so tied
to oil.
We need oil,
so I don't know how you fix that and how
you try and make good policy about it.
Well,
um,
there are alternatives to fossil fuel
based oils that they used to make
plastics and know that I know they can
even make class to get a hamp.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And it's biodegradable and they've just
started to make these biodegradable,
um,
natural fiber plastic bags that are not.
They're made out of like a plant
plastic.
Yeah.
Like in the supermarket.
And you put your vegetables in those.
Yeah,
they're supposed to.
They will,
they will,
they will.
When they go into the environment,
they all actually biodegrade.
They will become dirt again,
post like a regular plastic bag,
which probably takes like a fucking
$100,000 company here.
Then birds,
he didn't die and choke on the plastic
caps,
but apparently you can make plastic out
of hemp and it's super easy to make in
terms of like,
it regrows itself very quickly.
I'm like,
if you have a forest and you're trying
to make paper,
like you know,
you're,
you're trying to make paper out of a,
you know,
you have a forest,
timber that you chopped down
specifically for paper to regrow it to
the point where he could grow paper
again,
can take years.
I don't know how many years,
but many years.
Whereas hemp regrows itself every year.
Really.
Every year.
Yeah.
What is this right here?
Jen?
Edible plastic.
Made out of milk protein for food
packaging.
Holy Cow.
Not Vegan.
Yeah.
Packaging,
like dairy products and whatnot with it
at least is what the video shows.
But uh,
that's fascinating.
Video.
Yeah.
Like two days ago.
Well that's certainly something that can
be worked on.
You know,
the idea of biodegradable plastics would
be huge.
The that's one of the scariest things is
that we started making waste and never
had a plan to do with anything,
do anything with the waste,
and then it stacked up to the point
where we're dealing with enormous
amounts of waste being put up by human
beings.
Every single second I've ever seen that.
Well,
I was in New York last week,
just work in the comedy cellar all week
and every night I left the club just on
Macdougal Street,
just between third and bleaker.
The amount of garbage that's thrown out
of these restaurants and these juice
places and coffee places stacked
just high all the way down the street.
Every single day.
You see rats Darden in and out of him.
A tons of tons of rats.
They're creepy.
Yeah,
it's.
We are.
We are a weird creature man.
There's so many of us and we're not
really thinking about that.
Like you think about how many,
like on an average day,
how many water bottles you come across
in La.
She's like 10 of them here in this room.
I know.
I feel guilty drinking it.
I got gas this morning.
I threw a bunch out of my car,
I thrown into the garbage.
That's when I got gas.
I threw it at the garbage cans of gas
station.
I was like,
well,
how many fucking water bottles I have my
car.
It's crazy how many times someone had to
make plastic.
How many bottles of plastic are being
made?
And then that plastic has to be in a
landfill somewhere or you know,
in,
in the ocean.
Giant island in the ocean.
That big plastic bottle island.
Yeah.
Oh,
it's terrible.
Apparently it's not quite as an island.
They call it an island,
but it's really just like a floating
patch.
But it's disgusting.
It's horrible.
It's really bad.
So we're just seeking out a way to fix
that.
There's so many people.
Yeah.
Just,
I mean there's so many of us,
like I'm well for farm to table and like
knowing where your meat comes from.
I get it,
I want to do it.
I'm trying,
you know.
But when you think about how many people
are looking for lunch at the same time,
all those mouths looking to feed.
I mean you need like a Mcdonald's.
Somebody's got to feed these people.
You know what I mean?
There's.
There's definitely an issue.
Sure.
I don't know if you need a Mcdonald's,
but you need something.
You need food and there's 20 plus
million people in this area that aren't
growing anything other than the
occasional pot plant.
Right,
exactly.
I have a friend in my kitchen.
I'm growing my own basil.
I'm growing my own peppers.
Pepperdine,
who the fuck do you know that grows
enough to live off of?
I know you can't do it.
You can't do it unless you live on a
farm.
Nobody's growing enough food to live
off.
I mean not.
I mean just the people you see like on
the four.
Oh five.
I mean just feed those people.
You know what it is to have like on this
great Memorial Day weekend,
if you could have some people over and
have a little barbecue,
you bring 10 people over.
You gotTa,
you gotta get some food.
This is some serious amount of food.
You need to feed 10 people,
billions of people and then they want to
eat again an hour.
Yeah.
And their chips.
Chips.
Do you have any soda?
Soda?
Do you have taken dumps in your
bathroom?
Filling up your fucking pipes with their
shit.
Thinking about shit is going on the
bowl.
Chewing on a rib and taking a dump.
Pick how much shit is going through
under the city.
Every minute.
Comedy store has a bathroom.
There's a new bathroom.
They just put it in.
Oh yeah.
So other nancy it backed up last night.
Oh no,
they have old pipes and a new bathroom.
I don't know what they did replace the
pipes,
but something went wrong and I walked by
the bathroom last night.
I was like,
what the fuck is
that about the smell of shit outside of
the water.
That is just so.
So Chris,
back to the dog thing.
This is my.
We were talking about our dogs like
rolling and shit and stuff.
My cousin stuck the other day.
They had people coming to paint the
house and my cousin's wife told them,
hey listen,
you can use our bathroom.
Don't worry about.
You know,
you don't have to go outside.
They just,
our bathroom is your bathroom.
But they didn't really speak English.
They didn't really listen to her and
some guy took a dump in the bushes.
The dog
rolled around and they came running
inside and she's like,
what is?
Oh my God,
how did you get human shit on your head?
How she knows human shit.
It smelled different.
And then they went outside and looked
and they're like,
you guys use our bathroom.
So sorry.
Oh my God.
Let's August.
So
look what I found.
These guys are great.
Have you seen these guys?
They're so great.
Why does a dog want to Roland Shit?
He doesn't know what is that?
Possesses it to think that that's a good
move.
Just so happy.
Oh Man,
I guess a role in this.
No one's going to throw a ball.
Oh,
rolling.
Damn well.
Could I found.
Have you met these guys?
They're awesome.
They're shit.
Smells terrific.
Barely smeared his own shit on his face
during the podcast.
Why?
I don't know.
They were talking about it.
One of their podcasts,
they did.
He,
uh,
he went to the bathroom and I guess he
didn't get to do a good job of wiping.
They've reached back and felt as but and
then I was faced like warpaint got taken
off of Youtube for that.
I can't find a weird.
I want to follow.
Youtube would get behind that with all
their advertising money.
Oh,
it's terrible.
So fucking bro boiled his brain out
there in Thailand.
He sat there and fucking Vietnam in the
hot sun for too long.
Yeah,
he,
he comes.
Every time he comes back he's a little
different.
He's living in a very unique life that
felt good.
Good.
God bless him.
Is he off the cell phone now?
Like even though he's here,
he'll chew,
you know,
you can text him.
He texts.
He is one of those flip phones that you
can text with.
Right.
You know,
flip sideways and it's got like a
keyboard and you a text,
but you can't like say if you send him a
picture,
he has to forward it to his email.
Oh good.
Because he's got to go check it on his
computer.
It's got to go to a library
and they won't let him in because he's
got shit on his face.
The Guy Shit face to face.
You get out of.
It's so funny.
That guy went away for four months,
man.
Yeah,
I know.
Vanished for four months without talking
to anybody and then he shows up and it's
like,
all right,
it's time to tape this TV show again.
Yeah.
It's not a bad move.
Well,
I mean,
I guarantee you he's got some crazy
stories.
There's no way he doesn't because he's
probably out there making stories happen
to know knowing that he's going to need
some stories.
Yeah,
it's true.
Know.
I mean this whole show is a stories.
The stories.
It shows me the best shows on comedy
central.
It is,
it's really good.
I really hope comedy central never
cancelled that thing because that's one
of the best shows on comedy,
central standup shows.
There is.
It really is good.
And I did it twice and uh,
I get more hits off of that.
Then I do like stand up sets.
Well,
it's just different.
Yeah.
They just doesn't stories.
There's,
you're talking about stories and it's
also different because like guys like
Henry rollins did it.
Yeah.
Like he's not even necessarily.
Comedy is great storyteller,
so he'll do the standup comedy
storytelling show and just tell stories
and the setting's really cool.
Looks good.
Like in that Strip club.
It really suits chimp club off.
Outside of now I want to go there one
day when he's not filming the show.
Just go get what it's like when you
really see it clearly like we're seeing
like yeah,
side of it.
That's not real.
No.
You're seeing like Atlantic city in the
daytime,
it's like this is very different than
what,
like what happens when the sun goes
down.
Atlantic city in the daytime is.
Yeah.
Is that it's true.
Strip around a pole right there.
Hey,
put your girls in the honest fuck is
this shit.
Yeah.
It was fun.
When I was a kid there was no girls that
went to strip clubs.
None.
Zero.
Now everybody's like,
yeah.
It's like going to a sports bar.
It's like girls who go to cigar bars.
Yeah.
I'm just like you guys.
I'm one of the guys.
Right?
Right.
That's what we're here to not be with
you right now to try and trying to test
your resolve.
Young Tom,
papa trying to calm down.
They're trying to get you to come over
their side.
Slowly but surely they turn.
You know man,
she's cool.
She's different from all the rest.
How about the guy who brings his
girlfriend everywhere?
How about that?
Brutal motherfucker.
Gonna have fights over your house.
Hey man,
you want to come over?
Watch fights?
Yeah,
sure.
I'm bringing cindy.
Oh you fuck you.
Fuck.
It's cool.
Guys who don't even ask.
He just opened the door and you'd go
over the house laugh and people drank in
pot.
Small in someone's jerking off the dog
with their foot and then she comes in.
Are you guys ever going to grow up?
I did that once in college.
I came in and I was the guy who brought
the girl and walked in and you could
just feel the hate was so thick and they
just got so silent and change the vibe
and until you got her out of there,
there was no other way to cares.
The Guy Comic brings his girlfriend to
everything and then expects her to be
able to talk on podcasts.
There's a special place in Hell reserved
for those gentlemen.
You know who you pussy whipped hmong
girls are.
You get your shit together,
get your shit together and don't you
ever do that again?
Yeah.
Look,
you want to go to dinner?
Sure.
Bring her along.
You want to do it?
Fine.
Problem is that he doesn't listen to me
enough.
No,
that's so great.
You're here to tell me that.
That's what I want to do right now.
The the same exact thing.
If we showed up for one of their 50
shades of grey parties,
they're all wearing ball gags and
ready to go to fucking tie each other up
with stockings and we show up.
Oh Great.
You brought Jamie?
No.
Yeah,
a guy going in with all girls.
You ruined the whole night for the vibe,
man.
Show up at a tupperware party.
All of a sudden,
fuck away.
Tom Makes Bread.
I made bread ladies to seal on this is
not going to be enough to keep my bread
fresh.
Fucking
no.
We ever see girls that are at your shows
and there's like a whole table of girls.
They're so free and they're so.
They're laughing,
they're having a good time.
One guy sits at that table,
ruins it,
ruins it.
Yeah,
because he's playing sexual politics
with at least two different girls.
Like you might have a girlfriend there,
but he's a little too friendly with her
friend where she's getting pissed off
and you complimented her dress.
Who thought she was your friend who
knows drugs.
You look better now say that he didn't
just need a great test in stand by me
just in your face.
Sometimes you just need to.
You need a break.
You need to light a cigar and be alone.
Get out of that.
Yeah.
Too much.
It's absolutely important for any
friendship,
any relationship.
Anytime.
Two people interact with each other to
take time apart from each other.
A little bit of space,
you know all the time,
like if you're on top of each other each
and every day,
unless you're a really unique cup of
which I have met before.
They're out there.
They make you feel really bad about your
own relationship.
Do everything together and they're
always looking at each other laughing.
He had nowhere.
Great.
We worked together and we play together.
Well,
we just get along,
we finish each other's sentences and
all.
They're holding hands all the time.
It does happen.
I hate them.
Well,
you know what it is,
man.
It's just like they found that
frequency,
that unique personality frequency,
because oftentimes your frequency in
someone else's frequencies just off.
Yeah.
And that doesn't mean you don't love
each other.
Like one person might be the WHO and the
other person is the doors,
you know,
like,
okay,
we've got to figure out what we're doing
here.
This is the uh,
we both really liked the Beatles.
Yeah.
My only friend.
How can you believe?
Like,
no,
no.
You're too hyper to be different.
I know what I'm doing in those two
people are together for 15 years,
but on his throat,
it's really interesting when you see
people that are clawing each other's
throats.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's a good question.
Who would you rather be around the
couple that's stabbing at each other or
the ideal couple who's making you feel
like your relationship isn't so great?
The ideal couple for sure.
I want to be around happy people.
Yeah.
I want to be around people that are
enjoying each other's company.
There's nothing more frustrating than
being around to people that insult each
other.
Like slyly in public.
It's brutal.
We know a couple of apartments.
Wife used to do that all the time.
Really?
Yeah.
They say you shouldn't speak ill of the
dead,
but when they kill your friend and then
killed themselves,
I think you're allowed to talk shit.
Absolutely.
There's no reverence in the effort of
the day.
Had a very,
a combative relationship,
but she used to talk shit about him in
front of us.
Really?
Yeah,
right in front of him and us.
It was just like she would say he was
old and she would,
you know,
like one time she's talking about her
car.
There were.
Phil was talking about a car that can
fills a car,
aficionados loved cars.
So we were talking about a car.
I forget what it was,
and then she goes,
I love pickup trucks.
I want to get a pickup truck.
All my boyfriend's back home had pickup
trucks
and you just picture and her getting
stuffed in the back of his pickup truck
by some fucking farmer boy.
Some dude with thick wrists,
a catcher's Mitt has just laying his fat
dick because he would take his pants
off.
But saying that like,
I dunno,
it's terrible.
It's just weird.
It was constantly like that.
She was always belittling them,
always tearing them down.
They would have these horrible fights.
Man,
I never understand that.
It's like you're together.
Like it's for the good,
like his success is your success and yet
they'll still tear them down.
Well,
people don't think logically know what
you're saying,
but that's not a logical thought.
I mean the,
I think they just didn't get along
great.
You know,
for whatever reason feel was really
fucking smart too.
He was the coolest.
He was a really smart.
You're so lucky.
You got to know him.
Yeah.
He was,
um,
like,
I mean he would do things like he
learned how to be a pilot,
so he would be on the set and during the
downtime he be reading aviation books.
She sit in there reading,
going through him,
he was the most studious guy,
disciplined with his notes.
He would have his script and each one of
his scenes that he was in would have a
certain highlight,
like a,
like a tab,
like a green tab or whatever the color
tab was,
and then all of his scenes we'd be
highlighted,
he'd have notes beside them,
specific parts of the scene where he
wanted to do something different or
questioned his intent or go in and he
would just,
every time he would nail it,
every time he would never use the
incredibly rare time where he would
crack up during the filming.
You know,
I'm just having fun.
If it was never like you fucked up,
but he never fucked up.
Right.
I mean everybody fucks up and laughs
when you're not supposed to laugh
because it's funny.
But he was on his game.
He was so professional,
but he was a very,
very,
very intelligent man.
But he was an artist too,
right?
Yeah.
Sydney started out like designing like
design album covers for bands.
Yeah.
Before he was ever even on snl.
He was also one of the greatest for pee
wee's playhouse.
Right.
And he was on pbs but he was on peewee's
playhouse and I think he wrote the first
movie because he think he wrote peewee's
big adventure.
It's one of the writers,
but a great.
That's amazing.
So you got to hang with them a lot.
You guys are hanging out at the time.
He took me up in his plane.
He did,
yeah.
It was crazy because I want to buy a
house.
And um,
he was suggesting all these different
areas
and they said,
what do you like?
I said,
I just like quiet.
I like peace.
I like to see things that are pretty
like nature.
And he's like,
okay,
because I think there's an area like
right around like thousand oaks area.
I want you to check this out.
So take me up on this plane and flying
around.
Yeah,
it was crazy driving.
I'm a one on one to go look,
but he had like a small plane and it's
like freedom you have when you have a
plain man you ever want to do that?
Fly Yourself?
Yeah.
But weird way to go when you know this
fucking planes dying on you.
I've had cars die on me.
Yeah,
no,
I know the mechanical end of it.
Are you in mechanical or you?
I'm not really.
I mean,
I know certain things,
but it's like someone saying,
yeah,
I took karate when I was 14.
Right.
I ran my own stereo in my Toyota
Corolla.
I did that.
But I wouldn't tell you that I could
install stereos.
Yeah.
I know a little bit about cars.
I love them.
Yeah,
I do too.
But that's the thing.
It's like A.
I feel like if you're gonna have your
own plane and you gotta be you gotTa
know,
really knowledgeable and on top of it
and you gotta know your limits.
And that's kind of my limit.
Yeah,
it was intense,
man.
The landing was intense because was a
little tiny plane man.
It was a little two seater plane so it
was just me and fell and uh,
we're coming into this land named white
cheeses.
It's right there.
Like the grounds right.
Crazy.
It's weird.
It's a small plane and knowing that it's
like you're goofy friend from the set
taking you in.
Well,
he was always like an older brother to
me was in the set.
Yeah,
because he was,
he was older than me.
Varianced
like at least 16 years older,
maybe more,
maybe 17,
18 years old or something like that.
And he was a star already right when he
was us,
like when we were on the set,
he is in movies all the time,
you know,
he was just getting off a Saturday night
live and uh,
you know,
and then of course Dave Foley was a big
star from kids in the hall and he was a
big alternative star to like everybody
loved him because he was so smart and
the writing was so good.
And then Andy Dick was like a known
Weirdo and so it was,
it was a fascinating little grey.
Bruce,
every
crew,
I remember spending a whole summer just
watching fills best of snl disc,
the funny and stuff that wasn't even a
hit,
like him playing the acting teacher.
I mean I in a loop,
I could not stop watching it.
He was so,
this is something,
this is nothing,
this is nothing.
And then he would like somebody like
Sarah,
can I get out of my class?
It was on the money 100 percent of the
time.
Yeah,
man.
He stand up to for the audience for fun.
Oh yeah.
It would warm up the crowd,
but really,
you know,
he was like putting together almost like
a little routine that he would do well
and we talked about is like,
oh,
I think I'm going to go on stage
someday.
Wow.
He just never.
I don't think he ever really did it
though,
but he could have easily
done it and his wife just got dale.
Hey Man.
She was troubled,
you know,
choose a troubled person.
And she was also on Zoloft and cocaine.
Oh my God.
Which apparently leads to psychotic
thoughts and it's apparently a very bad
combination,
especially for some people which people
have their own particular sort of human
neurochemistry they got going on up
there and with some people when they do
coke and Zoloft together,
it just makes them insane.
Yeah.
But the real,
one of the real losses as a fan of his
is that he was the kind of guy that the
older he got,
the better he would become.
He was playing guys who were older than
him.
He had that very fatherly,
intelligent,
older kind of vibe.
Anyway.
So it's as a 75,
80 year old,
he would still be killing it.
Yeah.
I think,
um,
I think there's a million different
kinds of tragedies with the big one is
those kids had to deal with the fact
that mom killed them and then killed
herself.
How many?
Two,
two kids.
And then they went and lived with family
afterwards.
Just the whole thing.
So dark.
It's so sad.
It is,
man is the worst.
But I mean it was,
it,
it was also,
it's just more evidence of what happens
when people are in those combative
relationships and they just don't know,
don't Gel together.
Well,
you know,
you have somebody look,
if you've ever been around like just a
toxic person and it's like just one on
one.
You leave,
you're like,
it's an energy that just drains you.
And then imagine living with that
person.
It's guest.
It's got.
It's too much work.
Yeah.
Too much work.
But you know,
he ever dated somebody who was really
kind of toxic.
It's kind of exciting.
At the same time.
Time's the freaky ones are the most fun
in bed.
Really crazy ones.
Yeah.
It gets a little crazy sometimes.
Sometimes when you're young too.
Sometimes those breakup makeup fights
are awesome.
Yeah.
You know,
when they come back you didn't think
they were coming back.
And next thing you know you're making
out.
It's crazy when you hear the cops.
Like,
what the fuck do you call the cops?
Call them before I knew we were getting
back together.
Jesus.
We're okay.
You're to escape.
No,
it's fine.
We're all right now.
Just write an argument.
You're lazy.
Get on the roof.
I saw a house on fire yesterday.
Really?
Yeah.
Like up the street from me.
A whole like a house ablaze of the roof
was ablaze and it was up in the hills.
So they had two bad.
Yeah.
To get the fire trucks up there.
But then they stopped it like it's still
standing today.
But the roof is all,
but I've never seen like a whole house
on fire.
Dude.
I saw an entire,
I have to outdo you
have oprah.
She used to like outdo people.
But um,
when I was um,
working,
doing fear factor in like 2003,
it was 2002 or three when they had that
giant fire,
there was a joy and fire.
It was like on the way towards
Bakersfield up the five.
And we were filming up there at
the home ranch.
There was a lake and we were dropping
these people off from helicopters to the
lake.
And normally without traffic it's about
an hour 20 drive our half drive to la
from,
from ranch.
But this day it was bumper to bumper.
And uh,
a guy died,
a guy ran out and got hit by a car and I
saw a sneaker and I saw him laying on
the side of the road like briefly as I
was passing while people were trying to
attend to him and I,
you know,
I didn't,
I didn't like see his head splattered or
anything like that.
But I saw his leg.
And then my friend Matt told me that guy
ended up dying.
And uh,
so that was the beginning of this eerie
drive home.
Then as we got closer to la,
it was literally snowing,
ashes and the entire right side of the
highway was ablaze.
She as far I'm talking like a mile in
whom?
Like as far as the eye could see,
it looked like the fucking Lord of the
rings.
She was like,
I was waiting for demon horses to come
riding over the top and crazy high.
Like it was insane.
There was tornadoes,
a fire,
I mean it was fucking fire everywhere
and you're in traffic at that point were
in traffic.
So you're just sitting there really
removed from it by a patch of grass,
a bunch of asphalt.
And I'm telling you man,
I'm not bullshitting that side of the
road was like that for an hour,
hour of driving.
Like the whole right side was like fire.
Yeah.
That's when we were coming from the
[inaudible] were coming up the
[inaudible] towards like,
um,
encino and the entire right side,
like over the crest of the hill over
near the 1:18,
the Simi Valley area ablaze ablaze.
It was crazy.
I got evacuated from my house.
Really?
Yeah.
Threw the dog in the back of the truck
pack,
grab a laptop and some stuff.
No,
this was Johnny Cash and a of the
effects.
Not just dead at the time,
but uh,
it was,
it was crazy,
man.
It was crazy.
We just intense here.
Yeah.
People in my neighborhood,
you could see them like my stuff packed
to the roof and shit coming out and like
rows of cars,
people pulling out of garages and Shit.
It was trippy,
man.
That's the problem with some of those
more remote areas.
It's like,
oh no,
he's surrounded by beautiful trees.
But after a couple of dry summers and
then some asshole with a cigarette.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It was,
it was fires.
Fucking terrifying man.
When,
because I talked to this fireman and
this was,
it scared the shit out of me because
there's been a few of these big rock 'em
sock 'em fires that have hit the La area
most of the most.
It's in the summer when the winds kick
up,
one firefighter told me,
he goes,
dude,
it's just a matter of time before one
day of fire catches and it goes through
the entire city and we can't do shit
about it,
and I go,
really?
He goes,
yeah.
it's just the right conditions,
the right wind,
the fire coming from the right amount of
angles.
When the wind taking the the embers in
the air,
lighting more houses on fire.
Oh my God.
He goes,
it's just a matter of time for one day.
It goes right to the ocean.
I hate the.
It's just a matter of time.
Guys,
the earthquake,
just a matter of time before this whole
place just falls off into the ocean.
Yeah.
That's like glass half empty square.
Just a matter of time before the big
plague hits takes us all out.
They do say that a lot,
just matter of time before there's no
more food left,
she's got,
but where do you want to be?
Do you want to be somewhere?
You don't want to be a prepper right
now.
She don't want to be the guy who dies of
starvation because he can't figure out
how to get by now you will be.
You want a couple?
You want to try your best?
Do you want to be rick from the walking
dead?
It goes through several seasons of
horrific events.
Basically.
Shattered man,
by the time I abandoned the show.
Or do you want to be one of the people
that gets killed early on?
So it's to wrap.
I probably go somewhere in between.
Get a little adventure,
meet some new people,
make some mistakes.
You think you got it together and then
Wacko,
but isn't like the walking dead,
the ultimate existential crisis because
if you do die,
you're going to come back as a Zombie.
Yeah.
I think the only thing that can free you
is,
I guess if you shoot yourself in the
head,
uh,
you'd have to shoot yourself in the head
because if you shoot a Zombie in the
head,
they just stopped being a Zombie
anymore.
Somehow or another,
there's a little button,
you know,
I feel like they're getting very,
a wishy washy with the Zombie rules
lately.
I don't watch it anymore,
you know what I mean?
Either I watched live zombies definitely
aren't consistent in their ability to
fuck things up.
Yeah.
They used to be able to tear apart
horses and now they can,
like,
you can just push them aside,
just like get outta here.
And they're like these bony little
things and yet they're kind of strong.
I don't get it.
Yeah.
Now here's my question.
What are the,
um,
why don't they rotted altogether by now?
Like why aren't they just a bag of
bones?
Like what's going on because they're not
real.
Oh,
did you see what happened to big Sur?
What their big serve Ventana,
whatever,
Ranch Canyon ranch,
whatever it is,
they're completely isolated.
They've had giant mud slides and that
part you can't enter or exit the town.
Yeah,
they closed off like the one.
Yeah.
They're completely isolated right now
and they're think they're going to be
able to open up the road coming from the
north by like September.
What?
And they don't know if the south is ever
going to be repaired.
Oh my God.
Go,
go,
go.
It's crazy.
Look at that,
but let me see what it looks like.
Look at the title.
You have the title obscured.
Oh,
landslide.
Barry's California scenic highway in big
Sur.
If you don't know big sir.
This is the most beautiful part of the
ride between La and San Francisco.
My God,
the one look at the fucking landslide.
Yeah.
They think that the only way they're
going to be able to do it is to just
build on the landslide.
It's that much dirt.
More than a million tons of rock and
dirt fell dot.
Look at that.
It's insane.
The lance sladek skins a quarter of a
mile.
It's just mountain.
Now the road is covered in a of dirt 35
to 40 feet deep.
How many people are dead in there?
I don't think that many.
The highway runs through big Sur,
which is a major tourist attraction.
Authorities of clothes all access to the
highway and don't know when it will
reopen.
How about get us fucking shovel?
All you need is 100 Mexicans.
It'll be done by tomorrow.
Hey,
those people work hard metal detect
bullshit about the wall.
Have these messages.
Let me show you Mr Trump.
We can do again the metal detector.
Oh,
you go crazy.
Look at today.
I mean,
back then people died there.
It's million dollar.
I,
there's,
um,
what is the Henry Miller Museum and the,
uh,
serve and Tana,
all these beautiful places where you
would drive up and be able to stay
overnight and eat on the coast.
You can't.
Those places are isolated.
They weren't covered in the slide.
You just can't get to them.
Yeah.
So what you gotta do is you got to buy
real estate there.
Now policies will be panicking,
selling cheap.
You're right.
Scoop up a nice,
nice scenic view.
Magic if that's your house sitting up
there chilling and all of a sudden you
slide all the way down to the ocean and
that's how you die.
So courageous thing.
I finally made it.
I got this beautiful view.
Look at my deck,
hated him.
Come on over.
Bring bread,
Joe.
I can't believe you did it.
Did it buddy.
We're having a.
it's still a moving.
We haven't been able to go up there and
says it's still moving.
Hey Joe,
was the yard supposed to be moving like
that?
We have geologists and engineers who are
going to check out this week.
Check it out this week and see how do we
pick up the pieces?
The highway.
Oh my God.
Snakes around the California coastline
is a major tourist destination.
Cruz called the landslide.
One of a kind,
but it happened like a,
like a,
like a month ago.
And then there's just like last
Saturday,
another chunk just went.
So it's like,
it's still in motion.
Yeah,
man.
That's what keeps me.
Things like that.
And what keeps me from living on the
ocean.
I know I rented a house in Malibu and
uh,
one time I got super baked in and I went
down to the bottom floor.
I was only in this house for like three
months,
but it was like,
oh,
it was the bottom floor bedroom was the
water would literally go under it.
Right?
And at night time it's fucking
horrifying.
It's scary in the daytime it's gorgeous
looking out and you see that blue water
and so inviting.
But at nighttime dot water is dark,
sky is black.
And you're like,
oh my God.
He'd like shows you what it really is.
I mean,
the ocean,
you're essentially at the whim of this
everchanging.
See you are riding on a gamble.
And that gamble is what are the odds
that it's going to shift?
Now you know,
it's going to shift eventually.
That's right.
This house is probably worth like
millions of dollars and it's just
sitting on this water crazy.
You don't even have a front yard.
Your backyard is the ocean.
There's,
um,
my cousin has a place down,
uh,
down towards San Diego and all these
beautiful multimillion dollar homes on
this cliff.
And they just keep shoring up the cliff,
they just keep putting in new planks,
got concrete rivet and they're just
hanging on.
It's like someone some days in this
habit of mind when it goes down because
people,
man,
when you're sitting there at the sunset
and you're the,
it's just you and the ocean.
It is pretty spectacular.
It might be worth sliding and eventually
you have to have is super baller money.
So you have that house on the coast and
then you have a house somewhere else or
you don't have a family and you're just
a dude with a surf board and you're
like,
this is the perfect spot.
If I lose everything.
So a,
so what?
I'll rent a house somewhere.
Yeah,
I've done it already.
you could do that.
Yeah,
that would be good.
But you don't want to.
You don't want to want your kids get
sucked away by the tide to you.
You're enjoying that pipe.
I do.
It's good.
Right?
It's a little buzz.
I wish I had a cigar though.
I know.
I was actually thinking about bringing
cigars today.
I didn't to remember if you said we
could smoke in here.
Yeah,
we can.
Well,
in the new studio,
the new students,
like a mythical place that we keep
talking.
I know what's it actually exists.
People go like,
oh,
he wasn't bullshitting.
You have been talking about it for
awhile.
New Studio.
We're actually having ventilation
systems put in the ceiling so that it
can hit a button and it'll suck the
smoke out of the room.
Smells like rice.
Clay's here.
Dice likes to smoke.
I don't smoke
everywhere,
but he'll smoke a pipe.
Won't make me nauseous.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
And then you will go home smelling
people won't get secondhand.
We'd smoke too,
so it won't put you under.
Right?
People complain about that.
Um,
no.
I would never smoke in front of someone
that has an issue.
Like that was something I've had people
that have come on that uh,
specifically requested me not get high
in front of them.
They didn't know me that are like,
yeah,
that are in the program.
They're like,
please don't have him to drugs in front
of me.
Yeah.
That makes sense.
You to get a little squirrelly,
Iowa.
Next time I'll bring.
I have A.
I have a big box of Cuban cigars,
so nice,
strong.
They are strong.
They're big to kind of.
He was so nice.
The head rush is like,
yeah,
you might as well go to bed.
I used to like those oil de Monterrey,
double coronas,
those big fat posts.
Stake cigars,
a big steak and mashed potatoes with
sour cream and chives after Musso and
frank's.
Do you ever go to the cigar place next
to the Improv?
No,
I have not.
I know that spot,
so that's not.
I've never been in there.
If you're ever doing two shows,
they're screwing around.
It's a nice little hang.
You want to get away from the club for a
minute because sitting there,
they're really the guy who runs.
It's great.
It's a good spot.
That's cool.
Yeah.
I really liked the Improv,
man.
The improv is a different vibe now.
I've been going there a lot lately.
Have you?
Yeah.
It's a different vibe.
It feels good.
Everything feels good now,
man.
Comedy feels great.
This is a good time,
man.
It really is.
Beautiful.
Where did you do last night?
Well,
one of the things I did that was really
interesting.
I did a podcast with my friend Owen
Smith.
Do you know?
Oh,
in laval and he's hilarious.
He makes me laugh.
Funny.
Such a good subtle,
solid guy.
Good guy.
Yeah.
Anyway.
Oh,
in has a new show that he's coming out
with a called a something notebooks with
Owen Smith and what it is is you find
your oldest comedy notebooks and bring
it out and go over your material and I
found some notebooks from 1990.
That's great.
I had a list,
a setlist from 93 new material lists
from 1993.
March of 94.
I was like,
wow,
this is crazy.
It was terrible.
It was like needles through my soul.
Reading off my lines said so hard.
Terrible Bullshit when I was 21 is.
This is really saying something,
man.
I had A.
I had orchestrated crowdwork I'd like
written in crowd.
So terrible.
It was so bad.
I showed it to the.
I showed it to the
learning.
I have a tape.
I have a cassette tape.
The video tape,
vhs tape of me doing standup at stand up
New York like in my first year.
Oh my God,
like 93 and I am 30 pounds heavier tight
jeans.
I think I'm wearing a vest,
a curly hair,
and I would lunge when I would tell the
jokes like this Elvis Kinda of love and
I wouldn't.
I was so scared to hear if they were
going to laugh or not that I would just
go a thousand miles an hour just
yelling.
I thought it was kinison
kid isn't without the jokes.
They gonna catch you.
If you pause for a sec.
What?
I didn't give him a split second.
I just went,
yeah.
That one thing that some comedians will
do,
especially in the early days with they
like say a bunch of things in a row and
then memorize it and the audience will
clap at the end of the.
At the end they're big memorization
and that edit,
edit,
edit.
It's the closest you get to a guitar
riff.
Well,
that in my opinion is where dice had
everybody beat in the 19 eighties
because people would go to see him and
it would repeat his lines.
They wanted to hear what's in the bowl.
The whole audience do it.
Just like a fucking rock concert.
Hazy that you can't.
That's,
that's a one of a kind experience.
Yeah.
Can't replicate.
I mean dice had something that was
different because they were going to see
stuff.
They already knew that he would go.
I'll go rick dog.
Crazy.
I'm still weirded out when I hang out
with dice still to this day.
He was a rockstar.
Well,
when I'm in the room with them,
I weared out.
Oh,
I can't even believe that.
Dice Clay.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It was.
Now he was so big and my girlfriend,
we were 19.
We're sitting in my car.
I was dating this hot Nicaraguan girl.
Nice.
She had a great sense of humors.
Hilarious.
But we're sitting in my car listening to
this fucking dice.
Clay tape.
Just house crying,
laughing.
It was so stupid because when you're 19,
that is like the perfect kind of comedy
for you.
Oh God,
you know,
it's just on a tough fit.
Little boy blue.
Do you ever see him do a long setback
then?
Was it?
I only saw like short sets.
Yeah,
like I went to see him live.
I saw him a couple of times and then I
saw him.
Would he do that?
The hallway I saw in the store a lot in
the nineties when it was just sort of
fucking around.
But when he would come to the store,
it wasn't like a set,
like a concert set.
It was like he was working on new
material.
He was fucking around just just working
out when we do long sets.
I mean everyone was waiting for the
nursery rhymes.
Oh yeah,
she still does nursery rhyme stuff.
I saw him,
me and Jim Norton and Anthony Kumi.
Uh,
and who the fuck else was it?
I think Bobby Kelly and red band went to
see him in Vegas at the Riviera.
That's great.
Which is just recently.
No,
obviously the Riviera is dead now.
Yeah,
I think it was probably five years ago.
Maybe.
Maybe a little more,
but God,
Dan,
we had a great time when I saw the whole
set.
I saw his whole set and it was great.
It's great.
He was a monster dude.
He was a killer and human.
The Woody Allen Movie,
I'm sure.
Yeah,
it was really good.
really good.
That Woody Allen movie weirds me out
though.
That was movies all weird me out now
because it's so crazy because of the guy
because of who he is.
Who he is.
Yeah.
I think he's still a brilliant director
and a great screenwriter,
but it's just like,
you almost.
There's certain things you expect,
you know.
Ah,
he got hooked on pills that happens.
Uh,
is a boozer happens.
It turns out he was gay.
Happens.
Oh,
he's fucking his daughter.
That happened.
How old was she when he met her?
Yeah,
she was too.
I don't know.
That's that great.
A great joke by Emo Philips,
one of the
Woody Allen adopted Sunni when she was
four years old,
started dating her when she was 15.
Patience of a saint.
Is that what he did?
He started dating when she was 15.
Is that right there like that?
I don't know Christ,
but you know,
you find out anything about an artist.
You're gonna Mount Lake.
Right?
But here's,
here's the question again.
Is it me?
Is it the same thing about my friend
jerking off his dog with his foot?
Is it just on me?
I mean,
what if.
I mean it sounds gross,
but what if after all those years they
really were in love with each other?
Does that make sense?
It seems like it now,
right?
I mean,
he's
an old man and they're stolen.
They're still in love and hanging out.
And is that unacceptable?
I don't know.
It's unacceptable.
If people get hurt,
no one got hurt.
You can't.
Do you what?
I mean,
there's a lot of pictures before and
after.
Yeah,
but I heard some of these are.
I heard there was some
weirdness and some of the weirdness
here.
This is a little girl and he's with her
and then he wound up marrying her,
but that's weird,
man.
It's just weird.
It really didn't make her,
but he will look.
He's not arrested and he's not in jail,
so it's not right.
And it didn't everything.
Wasn't there a case.
I mean,
didn't they investigate and find him,
find him innocent of all this?
I don't know,
man.
That's the problem with the problem with
these accusations to.
I mean,
you know,
the accusations of that stuff is so
huge.
Even if you're found innocent,
uh,
that doesn't compare to the charge.
Was He found innocent?
Like did they go to
court?
I don't know if he was a criminal.
He tried.
I don't think he did anything criminal.
So there was no evidence to even.
I don't think so.
I think there was a time where Mia
Farrow was saying that he had done
something to one of their other
daughters.
Right.
And then what he was saying that the
daughter was coached by me and that me
is crazy and she's furious that he wound
up with Suny.
It's all crazy.
But I'll tell you,
I can shove it aside and watch crimes
and misdemeanors over and over and over.
So one of the greatest of all time.
What was the one we.
It was the space movie.
I'm
a sleeper sleep,
right?
Yeah.
That was a freaky movie.
I mean,
so,
so good.
Just what he's doing now and he's made
two movies a year for how many years
does it make to a year?
Does he?
Yeah.
The spring project,
the fall project.
It was really funky.
Barcelona,
midnight in Paris,
midnight in Paris is amazing.
What was really weird watching Owen
Benjamin,
that not on Benjamin Owen Wilson and
Owen Wilson basically doing with him.
I mean he really was doing a version of
woody allen and it totally worked.
It totally worked.
Totally worked.
I mean,
I wouldn't did a great job.
Oh,
that movie was so good.
He was really like.
He was channeling like a woody allen.
Like even the way you read the lines.
Same
vibe.
Yeah.
Just the just the exist is amazing and
tolerating ridiculous shit.
They were full,
tolerating ridiculous shift from each
other and having affairs.
Yeah.
You know,
just the Paris exists.
Isn't that a beautiful film?
I'm pretty amazing.
Amazing work.
While he's a Weirdo,
I heard it.
Weirdos have weird thoughts.
That's the thing,
like some more creative.
I mean,
whatever reason I know and I just don't
have the connection that Ronan Farrow
obviously has to do it.
He can't watch those movies,
but Tom Papa sitting in is a place
watching the movie.
I'm not connected enough where it to
bump me out of watching the art.
All artists are freaky.
If he'd get down underneath it,
I'm sure there's a lot of people that we
adore who did some pretty heinous shit.
Yeah.
When someone like David Carradine dies
wearing a wetsuit with a dildo or
possess hanging in a hotel right now,
didn't he die?
Autoerotic expectation.
The guy from nxs,
same thing.
It was like a lot of people die doing
really freaky shit and some weird stuff.
People are weird.
Don't,
don't dig too deep.
It's better just to know people on the
surface or just let it go.
Accept.
Yeah.
No,
but that's just the the only.
I mean I'm almost always willing to do
that.
Almost always willing to do that,
but the woody allen one makes it go,
but the bill cosby one does not make me
want to do that.
I don't want to.
That one is just like I got to write you
off forever.
Forever.
Right?
Drugged and raped.
50 women.
Yeah.
That one.
Definitely.
That's a.
that's a lifetime right off.
If he had made crimes and misdemeanors.
Maybe Polygon.
Albert just to up.
What about Roman Polanski?
Deacon.
Can you still watch fat Albert,
her,
her.
Hey.
It's like fat Albert.
Difficult to fund.
I doubt it because it seems like fat
Albert kind of reinforced a certain
racial stereotypes that he might
probably disagree with as he became
older.
I don't know.
There was a little moral stuff there and
was everybody getting along?
Yeah.
Do you remember?
That was always the rumor that he had
bought out the little rascals and then
he had kept it from being aired because
it was racist because of the buckwheat
stuff and all that racist stuff in it.
Was that true?
I think that was snopes and I think they
found that it wasn't true.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That he bought the rights to it and
wouldn't let it be shown.
Yeah.
Find out if that's true.
There was a lot of racist stuff back
then.
Dude,
we were talking to the comedy store last
night about how,
uh,
people in the old days used to smack
people,
like how often you'd see a movie of were
like Humphrey bogart would smack some
woman in the face and that wind up
making out with her.
Yeah.
It's just how it went.
Smack each other.
Women would smack men.
Men would swhack women smack,
smack.
I love watching.
Uh,
it's a mad,
mad,
mad world wars that you've never seen
that.
Oh,
come on.
It's one of the greatest comedy films of
all time.
Who was their
Buddy Hackett?
Oh,
Jonathan winters.
Jack Benny,
Mickey Rooney.
I'm Henny youngman.
Really?
I mean Milton Berle.
Wow.
I mean,
it's endless.
It was just all Spencer Tracy all
putting this crazy film about a trying
to race across from the desert to Santa
Monica and Phil Silvers,
all these.
I mean,
great.
It was like the,
the comedy film of its time and it still
holds up.
It's still great to watch.
You would love it.
You have to watch all.
The thing I love is everybody screams.
Everyone is just yelling at each other.
You Moron,
you,
Eddie had.
You got to be into this way.
It's so cathartic.
A time where everyone
has to be so reserved and say the right
thing.
Everyone's just like,
you're a moron.
Slapping each other in the face.
It's so much fun.
People would just harsher to each other
back then.
Oh,
it's great.
I mean,
it's a different world,
right?
A totally different world.
Not that long ago,
you know,
you would little rascals.
And Bill Cosby did bill cosby sat
status?
False.
It says origin Spanky,
Alfalfa,
buckwheat.
Darla,
just a few.
The easily recognizable names were a
fond part of the childhoods of
generations of kids,
beloved characters,
blah,
blah.
Just a rumor that started around 1989.
Where can you get little rascals now?
Uh,
you can probably buy it online.
I don't know if it's officially on Hulu
or anything.
I didn't look for that,
but it says it's been licensed in this
indication since 1997.
Bill cosby has never owned any part of
the rights of the little rascals.
Oh,
so it's.
Oh Shit.
Another one that popped up at city tried
to block Amos.
And Andy from being on TV to CBS with
syndication know Amos and Andy,
Ted Turner had bought up the rights of
the TV show the Dukes of hazard to keep
it off television because of his
demeaning,
demeaning portrayal of southerners.
That series is well.
This is old and says it's currently
syndicated on Tnn.
It's not anymore.
Neither rumors,
but that's not true either.
They don't.
Um,
they don't hear it anywhere anymore.
Right?
Isn't that the deal?
Like they didn't like digitally remove
the confederate flag?
No.
There was a,
um,
something today about the confederate
flag.
Oh Man.
What was in the news today about the
confederate flag?
The mayor,
the mayor of New Orleans has given one
of the best speeches I think,
of our lifetime.
That guy did then.
Someone else did something terrible
today.
Oh,
really?
Civil war museum closes after spat with
confederate flags.
That's not it.
Um,
the speech,
if you.
Something about someone refusing to take
down the confederate flag.
Confederate flag comes down.
Accusations fly.
There's no,
no,
I don't think that's it.
It'll just be searching.
You'd be searching.
But it was some,
another politician who was refusing to
take down the confederate flag and you
know,
Mississippi has it as a part of their
state flag.
Oh really?
Yeah.
The Mississippi state flag is like
confederate flag in the corner of.
Right,
right.
The mayor of New Orleans,
I forget his name,
gave this eloquent 20 minute speech
about the removal of four statues in New
Orleans,
Robert e Dot Lee civil war era things.
So eloquent.
The points he makes.
It's really about togetherness.
Moving ahead.
We have to realize that this was a part.
This was a wound to our country
and it never healed.
Right?
And this is part of making it.
He'll write and taking down these
statues,
try and explain to a five year old girl
who lives in this city of what that
means,
but it was put up right after the civil
war to let people know that this is the
way thing.
It was a white supremist supremacists
movement that put those up there.
You explain that to a five year old
girl.
How are we going to move forward in the
culture if we don't get these removed?
This isn't about,
hey,
this isn't about revenge is about moving
forward.
He 20 minutes in in a time like we're
talking about a rush of just news and
constant noise and chatter and tweets.
Sky Takes Twenty minutes,
eloquently commonly makes the case in a
way that my paraphrasing doesn't do it.
Any justice.
Bulletproof bulletproof case,
bulletproof.
It's so great.
Yeah.
You know,
I think the problem with the confederate
flag and even some of the figures in the
civil war,
they get connected in a lot of people's
mind to southern pride in where they're
from.
Like southern southern pride,
Leonard Skinner heard,
you know,
that kind of shit.
I mean,
I always had that fucking confederate
flag and their shirts,
I know Mina was.
It wasn't just a racist symbol of white
supremacy,
but it is a racist symbol of white
supremacy.
It's both.
Yeah.
You,
you right.
And you got to kind of give that up and
have pride.
You could still pride in the south.
You can still be a kick ass southerner
who loves the south for all the good
reasons.
You know,
what they need to do.
They need to come up with a new flag.
Like there's nothing wrong with the
south avenue flag as long as the south
recognize it's part of America like
that.
Just something that replaces the
confederate flag,
but includes everybody know,
like something that's not connected to a
totally meant to try to keep slavery.
That was one comment he made to just.
This was a move,
a flawed movement.
This wasn't fighting for America.
This was fighting to tear apart America
and we need new symbols.
You know,
like a perfect example is the flag of
Texas with the star.
Yeah.
Bad Ass.
That's,
that's,
it's,
that's like taxes might as well be its
own country,
right?
Yeah.
And that flag like that means something,
you know,
they,
it's not about right supremacy.
It's not always about Texas is a bad ass
place.
That's a bad ass flagged.
You have to have a mentor
tality to live here and it's inclusive
mentality of your texts and your a text
and it doesn't matter if you're black or
way.
Yeah,
I know.
They really had to let that go,
man.
The coming winter and you know,
what made me think that the.
I was always kind of back and forth on
the red skins and the Indians and uh,
know why pride is the thing.
It's just like what?
Because you and your grandfather used to
has poured and the warriors.
We used to go watch those games
together.
Me and my grandfather
made,
we can't be the red containing more of
where a few liberal,
but he's,
my friend get made a great point.
He said,
just as a businessman you
say if you own the Redskins,
alright,
we're changing it.
All that old merge people are going to
be paying through the ass to get.
Then you have this new logo.
Everyone's going to be buying the new
stuff.
Just it's going to be a windfall just
from the merge.
Just,
I mean if,
if you,
if you're not,
if you're not thinking about the social
issues of it as just a dollar
issue and go for it,
people don't want to give up ground.
Didn't make sense because they're
worried that crazy liberals are gonna
come in,
nerf everything.
It's not liberal.
It's just being nice.
Right?
I know in this case it is,
but it's one of the things that people
worry about that worry about giving up
ground because people were so ridiculous
today.
They give up a little ground.
They'll go fucking crazy,
no more taco Tuesdays,
cultural appropriation and can't serve
Sushi if you're.
Yes,
I know people just start getting really
wacky.
Will come till even up ground.
This is appealing.
It's running out of steam.
A little guess.
It feels like it's becoming more and
more preposterous.
Like being a social justice warrior is a
really ridiculous thing at this point.
They really feels like it's become so
absurd.
Yeah,
I mean it's not from that.
I think there's a correction that's been
made.
I think there are people like taking
more things into consideration about
other people and now we didn't really
think about,
oh yeah,
for sure those families or with that
group or whatever,
but yeah,
it's been done.
Yeah,
I mean,
but that's how it always is.
The tide goes out,
the tide goes and you can't explain it.
Yeah.
Now.
Right?
Right.
Bill O'reilly.
Yep.
No,
we don't remember that.
no.
I was one of the worst arguments he ever
had on the show.
It was talking about how he's putting
his chips on Jesus because you can't
explain why the tie goes in.
The tide goes out.
He was talking to some guy who was an
atheist who is a docket.
Two doctrines.
No,
it wasn't dockets.
David Silverman was so dumb and dumb
argument and he said,
no,
you can't explain it,
but you can't explain it.
Of course you hear you hear it.
So stupid.
That's a scam.
No,
I don't know.
I'll tell you why.
It's not a scam in my opinion.
Right.
Tide goes in,
tide goes out,
never miscommunication.
You can't explain that.
You can explain why the tide goes in,
goes in,
tide,
goes to the water,
the tide comes in and it goes out.
Mr Silverman.
He always comes in on top of Mount
Olympus who's making the time.
That's great.
The look in his eyes like.
Yeah,
I can explain that though.
What the fuck you talking about?
That there's gravity causes the weight.
Come on man.
It's terrible.
You can time the tide.
You fuck.
I know exactly when it's coming.
It's such a bummer being smart
sometimes.
It's a bummer.
It takes away.
He's not dumb.
I think he's deceptive.
Like bill route.
It's just crazy.
It's amazing that he got kicked out of
Fox.
It's amazing.
They kicking everybody out.
Hannity seems to be holding on.
Maybe he's like one of the.
The orgies.
Yeah,
but you don't have enough dirt on them
selling crazy fuck party over there.
All they're doing is trying to get laid.
I feel rallies beaten off on the phone.
I read some article about it.
He'd call women up and it'd be beaten
off and he's talking to them like,
whoa.
Remember when the transcript came out
and he was like,
I want to be the Loofa on your body.
Yeah,
Snow workplace boy,
disgusting,
but what?
But odd,
right?
Yeah.
You know,
I know that that whole place was running
like it was like the cosby thing.
It's like once the one came out it was
just rapid fire.
Yup.
Well,
when you have a guy who's got that kind
of power and is that,
you know,
it's just so weird.
Yeah.
They get bored.
Again,
the weird sexuality thing,
right?
It's like it manifests itself in this
guy in this way and it's abusing these
women,
those fucking shows too.
Like all these shows,
like when we really think back,
like we look back at 2017 from the
future and we look at the state of the
media today and how like one side,
whether it's Fox News or whether it's
CNN,
we so heavily leaned in one direction or
the other.
So obviously editorializing what's going
on the news and their opinions of the
news.
Well,
it's all just entertainment at this
point.
So gross.
I mean,
you know when that horrible thing
happened in Manchester at the,
at the concert,
it's like,
okay,
that act is heinous and what happened
that night to those people is heinous,
but then who does the all of the other
work of scaring the daylights out of the
rest of the world.
CNN running it nonstop for 48 hours,
this grainy footage of young girls
screaming and crying,
so much more powerful than what that
schmuck did.
Blowing up those people in that place
there.
They're just as negative of force for
the public.
Then the terrorists,
but they don't care.
They're just trying to get attention.
They just want you to.
It bleeds.
It leads.
That's a big story.
Horrible know that people,
but what is their responsibility and
their responsibility to report on the
news because that's a new story.
That's a giant,
crazy,
tragic event.
It would be remiss if they didn't report
on it,
right?
You can report on it,
but you don't have to have me walking
with my daughter through an airport and
having it blaring out of every
television set.
The girls screaming.
You could have grown up sitting there
and analyzing it without
sensationalizing it,
but it's entertainment.
It's this big balls out entertainment
network.
It's heinous.
I think that's a real good argument.
The when people Washington voluntarily,
like at the.
At the airport scape it.
Yeah.
I cannot escape it.
I was trying.
I was working on this book.
I was at the end of this book.
Had a deadline.
I'm just head down,
not trying to follow anything,
but I was traveling at the same time.
Wolf Blitzer is popping out in bars,
in restaurants at the gate.
Wetzels pretzels,
more breaking news.
Trump did this.
Now knowing that you can't escape it.
So much pressure.
There's no responsibility about these.
Like you know,
being an old man,
be an old.
What happened to like the news reporters
being like a shitty guy,
but just delivered the news as the
grandfather with the news third running
ads now and CNN have them like Wolf
Blitzer and another couple of them
walking through the hall.
It's like those espn ads on espn would.
They'd be
walking through the net who?
The officers of espn making jokes with a
mascot.
That's what Wolf Blitzer and cow bell
and all these people are doing on CNN.
It's like they're walking through and
they're like,
hey,
look,
there's Anderson Cooper.
What's he doing in the office?
And it's a comedy bit.
Yes.
These are the people that are supposed
to be delivering the hard news.
Tell me rationalize and make sense of
the world.
Hey,
look at him.
He's in there.
What's the Anderson doing in there?
And a punchline?
Well,
you know what really disturbs me when
they do that podcast thing or Anderson
Cooper does that threesixty where he
sitting in the desk and allow for people
to is right for people to his left one
people.
There's nine people.
The last time I saw nine people yelling
at each other people and everyone's
talking over each other.
Right?
And some people never get a word in edge
wise and people are just jumping in and
it's just.
It's the worst.
It's all entertainment.
Yeah.
It's.
But it's also Edra editorialize too.
It's like how can a person just relayed
to you the information as unbiased as
they possibly can?
I know.
Is that possible today because pbs,
pbs is as close as I can find it.
Yes.
It's kind of just factual.
They just put it out whenever they have.
They have shields and Brooks on.
It's a snap.
Brooks and Dunn.
It's now Cheryl's in your now it's a and
they just.
Two guys who would never be on any other
network is they're funny looking and
they have the conservative view in the
liberal view and but it's very matter of
fact and factual and not sensational.
Not shitty to each other.
It's.
It's is evenly balanced.
Calm as I can find.
His PBS news hour,
who is Sean Hannity arguing with when he
was telling Sean Hannity that he's bad
for America was a Ted Koppel.
Ted Koppel's.
Ted Koppel told me it was bad for
American and saying something along the
lines of,
don't you think America smart enough to
make up their own mind,
which is just so ridiculous.
Well,
so candy ass of him is that he backs out
of it and says,
well,
I'm not a journalist.
I'm a talk show host,
mirror those.
You think we're bad for America.
You think I'm bad for America?
Yeah,
you do.
In the in the long haul,
I think on all these opinions,
ted.
No.
You know what's sad?
Because you're very good at what you do
and because you have,
you have attractive,
a significantly more generic.
Let me finish.
Let me finish the set
with all you.
Yes.
You have attracted
people who are determined that ideology
is more important than facts.
Oh,
that's what you need.
Those old dudes should be really tells
Joe Riley,
he ruined journalism to Ted Koppel's on
a goddamn rampage.
The loofa sponge.
Bitch.
I got something to say.
I've interviewed him a number of times.
Not An easy interview.
How would you do it?
You know,
some and I have talked about this
general subject and many times over the
years it's irrelevant how I would do it.
And uh,
you know,
who made it irrelevant.
You do.
You have changed the television
landscape over the past 20 years.
You took it from being objective and
being subjective and entertaining.
And in this current climate,
it doesn't matter what the interviewer
asks him,
Mr Trump was going to say whatever he
wants to say it,
as outrageous as it may be.
Okay.
But you know,
your old network,
ABC does interview Mr Trump on a regular
basis and you know,
our job,
whether I'm a commentator or a reporter,
is to get as much information,
number one,
and to show the viewer who the person
really is.
So again,
I'll go back to he sitting on nightline,
your opposed,
right opposite him.
How do you do it?
Well,
the first way you do it is nothing in
the end if you do it,
but some reporting,
it's an old fashioned concept.
Another think demonstrating who and what
Mr Trump is and what his various
policies really amount to a something
you don't do in an interview.
He doesn't answer the questions
pointed out.
It's a whole different ballgame on
cable.
TV commentators like me have just ruined
the country I copped to that.
It's true,
right?
I've ruined everything.
It's true.
It's entertainment.
Like just give us the news,
but there's,
you know,
there's so much money in it.
And it's sort of been,
why did they have to.
Here's the question,
why can't they just put on an
entertaining show that makes money?
Like whose responsibility is it to relay
the news to the people?
Is it Fox News responsibility?
I mean,
don't they have some sort of an out that
they're an entertainment program?
Yeah,
but they're not.
What are they?
What is it?
Let's say you decide,
I understand,
but let's say you decided to call the a
show the Tom Papa News and you start
talking about the news,
like do you have a very specific need to
like if we know you as an entertainer.
And Bill O'reilly was always an
entertainer.
He was a entertainment news reporter on
hard copy before he was ever on,
on this.
Right?
So we know he's.
That guy did.
Would you have a responsible who has a
responsibility to tell the news in an
objective sense?
Like if you can editorialize,
you can write things out and you can
decide which stories should get the most
coverage.
During the campaign,
CNN was all about the sexual harassment
cases against trump.
And then Fox News was all about hillary
and her email scandal.
I mean they were,
they just decided once I was going to
go,
like,
who's to say what you can and can't do
when it comes to that.
We don't really have like a hard fast
rule when it comes to television
journalism.
I mean we think New York times we think,
you know,
in certain news papers that have a
great,
you know,
we have respect for them.
They have a certain amount of fact
checking and
reliability,
responsibility rather you can reliably
assess that this is going to be the
news,
right?
To a certain extent.
Yeah.
I think it's,
you know,
it's,
once you start a 24 hour news station,
it's a beast.
It's got to be fed.
And how do you keep those people
attracted
but isn't even really a 24 hour news
station.
When you think about what CNN is,
they have w Kamau bell show,
right?
They have Anthony Bourdain's show.
They used to have that Tim ferriss show.
They've got a bunch of shows that have
Morgan spurlock show nothing to do with
news.
Yeah.
I mean,
other than,
you know,
you haven't seen the show before,
this is new,
like they might be talking about some
information you might not have heard
before,
but it's not like breaking news show
I think.
I think that,
I mean,
what does CNN stands for?
Cable News Network and Fox News.
I think once,
people,
once you know that people are looking to
you as the news,
there should be some responsibility.
I think that there's somebody,
some grownup has to be,
you know,
in control of that.
But you know,
these are stocks,
you know,
these are,
these are parts of giant corporations
with stock prices and the people running
it.
I'm going to meetings and get raked over
the coals when their ratings are down.
And what are you going to do about it?
Jeff Zucker.
Maybe it's going to be like when wwe f
had to change her name to ww II.
So there'll be c and e.
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean,
look,
if you put an old man news station on
right,
and we'd be like,
okay,
finally this is like all measured in all
sides and this is America first before
party it probably deep dog shit ratings.
You know what I mean?
Because it doesn't have all the other
people going crazy on it.
Yeah.
You know,
it's just,
you just hope that a little kind of
muddle through it and end up.
It just won't grownups in charge.
What's the dude?
The CNN,
the dude,
a Gq guy that's in his basement.
Again,
the resistance.
Keith Olbermann
is kind of put that dude on TV.
Comedy Central.
Just let him write his own shit.
I saw like a clip of him,
like it really looks like it's on a
cable news network somewhere.
It doesn't have a makeup person anymore.
I just had to make desks and these
incredibly verbose speeches and
assaulting trump over and over again
saying so cool.
When they were sold out to the Russians
and this was an invasion,
make no mistake about it.
We are the resistance.
Super intense.
Yeah,
I know,
but it's got that weird cable access.
Feel to it.
It really does.
He's.
He used to be like,
with all these people around,
now he's down to printing his own pages,
coal,
landing his own scripts.
Somebody.
Somebody tweeted about it the other day
about what a fucking nut here is.
Oh really?
I didn't know.
I hadn't been paying attention.
It's hard to find.
Well,
he's not.
I mean he's,
he's out there on the Gq page.
Yeah.
I don't know what they're doing.
Just coming in.
Yeah.
My dog has the emergency room.
What did they say?
Is it a snake bite?
A Bella can come home between 4:30 and
six.
Well,
that's good.
So she knows that we're on the air so
she doesn't want to disturb,
but I want to find out what it was.
Yeah.
I hope it wasn't a snake bite.
Snake Venom.
As expensive as the snake.
Antidote.
Very expensive.
So if you're on the trail,
like I was in the and the and the snake
bit,
you in the leg,
your.
I find that out.
What do you do?
It's a good question.
That could happen to us.
That's one of the things we really
should know to went over a snake once I
was running with my dog,
a snake.
Now this one I didn't run over like hit.
Yeah.
This one I just saw in the road I was
running and I jumped over this stick and
as I was jumping over the stick,
I realized there was a rattle snake,
really big one.
Stretched out who flattened out on the
road on the trail.
Completely flattened out,
and it was,
you know,
the length of my arms.
Yeah,
it was.
It was a big ass fucking snakes.
Snakes thick like my wrist around.
It was a fucking thick old snake.
So that's a lot of venom that would come
out of that head.
I guess I've heard of.
I don't know if it's a myth or not,
but I heard that the young ones are
actually more dangerous because they
unload all their venom.
Whereas the older ones just give you a
little zap.
The old ones like,
dude,
relax.
They're smart.
Keep the snake bite victim,
victim,
calm,
keeping them still and quiet.
Restrict movement and keep the effected
area at or below heart level to reduce
the flow of venom.
Remove any rings or constricting items
and clothing as the effected area may
swell.
Allow the bite to bleed freely for 15 to
30 seconds before cleansing.
Create a loose splint to help restrict
the movement of the area.
Contact medical help as soon as
possible.
See below.
Evacuate the victim immediately by
hiking to a car,
a helicopter or medical staff.
Monitor the person's vital signs,
temperature,
pulse rate of breathing,
and blood pressure if possible.
But does it say you do so?
So number six,
evacuate the victim immediately by
hiking to a car.
So does that mean that the person has
been baking?
Hold on a second.
Would it do not waste time hunting for
the snake and did not risk another bite.
If it's not easy to kill the snake while
they're trying to tell you to kill it,
after it has been killed,
a snake can still bite for up to an
hour.
So be careful what transporting it.
Holy Shit,
that's scary.
But that's kind.
They're Kinda like saying,
look,
I know you're going to kill this fucking
snake if I looked it up for a hiking
because a job and you're in a house,
it's given you other information
specific for a hike.
Still doesn't save.
You should move or not.
Definitely says you're supposed to stay
still,
but if you have to walk a mile to your
house.
Yeah.
Uphill.
You got to go.
I guess the splint is aloof splint to
help restrict google.
What do you do if you get bit by a snake
and you're hiking alone?
A lot of words.
Yeah.
My dog is uh,
we have no information.
The doctor will tell us when we get
there.
Interesting.
What it's need to know basis.
What does that have to show your papers?
First.
Fence of the worst.
My glass cat that died.
It was like,
we don't know.
We're going to have to run a test.
Okay,
fine.
Run the test.
It's going to be $1,500.
Okay.
Granted,
$1,500.
Okay.
That didn't come.
It's inconclusive.
We're gonna have to run another test.
Oh,
why?
if you want to try and save it,
we're going to be up to three grand.
All right.
We're on the test and then right now
we're three grand in the hole.
We didn't find out.
There's no way to cure it.
They put the cat down and then they say,
do you want us to do an autopsy?
Why?
Sure.
Why can you do one on the moon?
Snake questions on Reddit.
Okay.
No.
First Aid,
it is much better than performing bad
for.
Oh,
no.
First date is much better than
performing bad first aid.
Don't cut at or around the site of the
bite.
Don't compress the bitten limb with a
cord or a tight bandage.
Don't attempt to extract or neutralize
venom using electricity fire permit
grant program at granite and that says
permission granted,
hermine granted permission granted salt.
What is that?
Like an orange blackstone's,
more mouths mud leaves,
etc. All snake bite kits are dangerous
and should not be used.
Wow.
This wAs also confirmed by the snake
snake bite poison line.
A lot of snake bite patients injured
themselves by panicking directly after a
snake bite by tripping over a rock or a
tree trunk.
Oh,
by falling off the cliff side of the
trail.
Staying calm is important.
After snake bite,
walk about 20 to 30 feet away from the
snake.
Find a safe,
safe place to sit down asap.
The venom can rapidly diffuse into your
system.
This can drop your blood pressure too
low to pump all the way to your head
while standing.
Whoa,
sitting down reduces your chances of
feigning within the first few minutes.
If you faint,
shouldn't be more for more than a few
minutes,
remove any race,
any rings,
watches,
or tight clothing while it's going to
swell up.
Yeah.
Anything else from the benton limb?
Because of swelling,
we will make a lot,
a lot bigger as soon.
Take five minutes to calm down and plan
your evacuation.
The only effective treatment for a snake
bite,
even animation is the right antivenom to
neutralize it,
to not Wait for symptoms to appear.
If bitten is important to get in touch
the emergency personnel as soon as
possible to get you to a hospital.
If you have a cell phone and service,
great call nine,
one,
or the park ranger.
If there's no service.
Think about the last time you had fallen
phones,
man,
that we didn't have a cell phone.
That was the other thing.
I was like,
no,
we're going to disconnect.
Look at this.
You're supposed to circle the location,
the snake bite and write down the time
next to it so when they find you dead.
Yeah,
draw.
Circle around the border of the swelling
and write down the time.
Write down all the things you're
experiencing that are not normal.
So now we have pens on us.
You know we have markers and
examples are metallic.
Taste in your mouth.
Changes to sense of smell,
sudden loss of vision,
double vision,
visual disturbances,
ringing in the ears,
headaches,
nausea and vomiting,
bleeding from anywhere,
dizziness,
shortness of breath,
etc. It's bad.
That's not good.
Oh,
down there and make contact via cell
phone.
If this is not possible,
walk slowly to get help.
That's the key.
Drink some water and take some calories.
If you have any.
Some snakebite victims walk several
miles after serious snake bites to their
legs.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
They make it out to medical care.
Yeah.
You hike out.
Don't be messy,
man.
The fuck up.
You killed that kind of a snake.
That evil.
Look at serpent.
How did you kill it?
You just stomped on.
It stomped on his head.
His heAd?
Yeah.
That's where the body part comes from.
If you're faster than the body part.
I got a good sidekick.
You are not wearing flip flops?
No.
I was wearing.
I think I was running a trail.
Sneakers.
oh,
it got a little something to him.
A little grip.
You shouldn't do it.
I wouldn't recommend it.
I would probably never do it again,
but in the moment it was the thing to
do.
I like that.
That you just thought,
I have a shot here.
I'm going to take it is predatory
instincts.
I was like,
this mother fucker sleeping on me.
He does not think I'm going to stop him.
I have to stop them.
This is good.
Memorial weekend stuff,
things to bring on your trail,
a phone and a sharpie.
Well,
I always have that with me in case
people want autographs.
it's a good move.
I'm thinking about getting some snake
boots.
jamie.
Pull up snake boots because I've been
looking at some snake boots.
If their thigh high,
I'm walking out.
I will stop the fuck out of every snake
I see.
If I get some sky high wonder woman's
style.
hey tom,
you want to come stomping this weekend?
We're going snow snake boots.
If it gets you right above that and you
feel like such a fucking idiot because
you're walking
up to your knee,
what are those cowboy boot looking ones
with the red.
Are those like kevlar on the side of
them?
Click on that bitch.
Keep it ship a chippewa,
but I could see with knight,
with a big red hat himself,
a girl on a farmer's only.com.
I don't know what to do if I get bit by
a snake oil knows how to catch a bass.
This 17 inch boot has a brown leather
foot and co dura top to allow for
breeding.
There's also a goodyear leather welt.
What's a welt?
The bottom,
I guess,
cushion in souls and leather line.
Don't get caught by a snake without a
pair.
The leader in snake proof boot business,
she's become the standard of quality and
durability that will support the hunter
in reptile infested areas.
Merry christmas,
honey.
I got you something.
Most of the time they probably just bite
straight ahead at these things.
Probably work.
Yeah.
Got a bad one.
Where these people live that they need
frequent scott over the knees.
Snake proof boots has got snake proofs
to levels that look like a snake.
That's just vicious.
Are you looking for a blow job in a bass
boat?
farmers?
Yeah.
Like could you imagine wearing those
stupid looking boots and that fucking
snake lunged forward and you saw the
teeth like this client is going to get
me right above the boot and bambi locks
onto your kneecap and fills it up with
them.
You have to look in his fucking
reptilian.
Ancient eyes is a heartless,
soulless eyes as he pumps is toxin into
your bloodstream and you're still
wearing those stupid boots.
you're looking for a hand job in a
motorboat.
Yeah.
How much sex has ever had happened in
those?
Those boats in Florida with a fan?
The giant fans.
They'll get that bite him.
Bite.
Yeah.
That was a cool,
but where?
Where are these people hiking?
All the time that they see so many
rattlers dude.
Here you go up in the hills right above
the studio,
man.
There's fucking snakes all over the
place.
The point of wearing these boots,
if you're a guy who has to do it all the
time,
if you're a person that's up there all
the time,
I would recommend them like,
okay,
let's find out.
Where do most people get bitten by
snakes.
What part of the body to most people get
build parts of the body.
Yeah.
I thought your fucking city.
No,
I was going to say st.
Yeah,
I bet.
It's a bet.
It's the.
The calf,
the calf area.
Shin,
calf area.
It makes sense,
right?
You're looking for a hand job in a
haystack
is greater than 90 percent happened on
the leg and the leg.
Yeah,
they're lOw.
They're in grand creatures.
They're not flying around.
What if you have good moy tai and you
have good leg checks?
You get those knees up high.
I think common.
You check it.
Yeah,
I bet.
I bet none of those guys have gotten hit
by a snake,
but none of them.
They're fast snake.
They're not.
You know,
they're not that quick.
There's sprinkle problem as if you.
If you start alum.
Yeah.
That's where it's really fucked up.
If you startle them,
they have to.
What I did,
the thing about a snake is that they
have to come up in order to get you.
So if a snake is flat like that,
like the snake that I saw,
he was flat and I was like,
oh,
you're dead.
Like you're not gonna be able to get up
quick enough.
Mine was coiled.
Mmm.
This is.
They have a,
what they call a strike height and they
can make it above some other boots.
Some people are asking about if they can
get kevlar jeans so that they don't go
through their genes.
That's a good move.
So they don't really.
You don't have to wear a snake proof
underpants.
I want a snake proof condom,
maybe steel James Michael analysis,
talking about it.
Does it probably help guide the venom
right into your fucking leg.
Act as like a hill slide
you want to do,
do it doggy style or the blue collar
concert,
the state fair
state fair
state fairs or odd man.
They're really weird.
Weirdly,
abandon the State fair.
Even if there's a lot of people at the
state fair,
you.
The caveat is that as a state fair,
the state fair,
I go to see ted nugent at the state
fair.
I packed
contents here.
You know,
I once got an offer when I was first
starting as a comic to do,
uh,
the offer was get a,
you would drive a van with all this
stuff for the stage in it to the state
fair.
Help,
help the crew,
build the stage,
load everything onto the stage and
stuff.
And then you drive at the end of the
show,
you know,
you do a little comedy,
hosts little,
and then you drive to the next,
breakdown the stage,
load it up.
Then you drive to the next city.
And the routing was like,
starts in buffalo next night in phoenix
next night.
Charlotte,
North Carolina,
then rochester,
then back to tucson,
Arizona.
I was like,
I said to my girlfriend at the time,
who's now my wife.
We should just get on the motorcycle and
just drive all these places without the
state fair shows.
Yeah,
that's what we did.
Yeah.
And then they pay you,
but it was not much right now is
terrible.
So we ended up.
ThAt's what we did.
We took the motorcycle and went for five
weeks just to go around the u.
S motorcycle.
Yeah.
That's a pretty gangster.
Who was gangster.
We'd only been dating for like six
months.
A show
you care.
That's.
Yeah.
That's a good show.
A galleria care move.
You're really invested.
That's what we got trip with her.
Got back from that.
We were like,
all right,
I guess we'll get married because that
went well.
That's bill murray's advice.
Bill murray says,
if you're thinking about married,
someone travel the world with them.
Yeah.
He'll be hot and miserable.
You find out what they're really all
about.
Absolutely.
I've lost some friends.
We went on vacations with berlin.
Yeah,
the fall apart on you.
Yeah.
They get shitty.
They can't go with the flow.
They get all pissy,
you know,
because the car didn't show up or you
missed the train and you know,
it's a little stressful when you travel.
Yeah.
That is a problem with some people,
right?
Just don't know how to keep it together
when things aren't going the best.
They're pissy.
Yeah,
bet.
Bet hannity,
moe move when he's like,
really 10.
Really that sad.
That guy.
You don't want to travel with that guy.
He's silly.
Boy.
You just get pissy that kind of like the
kid who's been picked on kind of thing,
but you know what the problem with those
guys is as many problems,
but one of the big problems is they're
always in combat.
They're always,
always fight,
always forcing their opinions.
They're always pushing their opinions
with a lot of energy and emphasis and
they're always resisting anything that
is contrary to their opinions.
Never considering them.
Never going over it like,
yeah.
Really objectively.
It's always this,
this interview,
which is a natural,
not natural knee jerk reaction that all
oF us are subject to.
Yeah,
we're all subject to that kind of
unfortunate defense of our ideas.
Our initial idea,
there's a book,
I do not know the name,
I'll find out and post it,
but that my friend read and he's a
conservative and it's basically about
that.
It's how to take here something,
recognize what your initial knee jerk
reaction is because of where you stand
on what you believe
and evaluate it and give yourself a beat
to say,
wait,
maybe I'm wrong,
and trying to work your way around the
argument.
And uh,
he's,
he really believes in this book.
It's like we're so all naturally set for
these trigger words.
Like you hear hannity or you hear trump
where you hear hillary,
where you hear the clintons and
everybody has their preconceived
beliefs.
So you just back up.
Whatever's those stories are in this
book is about breaking that down and
trying to be more open and more logical.
I've definitely tried to work on that a
lot during my time that I've been doing
the podcast.
I've gotten way better at it.
I'm definitely not the best at it.
Yeah.
But it's something I'm way better at now
than I was when I first started doing
the podcast.
So yeah.
Yeah.
Because you realize like how much iT
gets in the way of a good conversation.
It gets in the way of understanding how
other people think and you know,
sometimes you have to dig your heels in
and defend your position because you
think the other person's being illogical
and that's okay too.
But I think it's also important to look
at what someone else is saying and try
to make,
see if it makes any sense at all.
And it might not,
but give it a chance.
Give it a chance to give it a chance.
yeah,
no,
it's great.
I tried to look at someone from someone
else's point of view.
I try to go,
okay.
So where would explain it?
Like where are you coming from?
Like just try to.
I try to do it with no judgment.
I try to just like really
get into bed.
So when you,
when you do take opinions and you do
analyze it and come down and say x is
wrong,
I believe x is wrong.
Do you
read your twitter feed?
Do you like.
Because it seems like anytime you're in
something public and you side anyway,
you know,
one issue and you go this way or that
way you're getting attacked.
Do you have That?
You would definitely have that.
Yeah,
I've got the end.
Do you take it to heart or you're just
like,
no,
these people just exist and that's just
the way.
I mean I analyze myself.
I mean I'll,
I'll listen to some of it.
Yeah,
if it's valid,
I know,
I definitely know I fucked up before.
Sure.
and when I have fucked up before I've
read things that people said that it
didn't feel good to read it,
but I knew that they were probably
right.
And so you just,
you know,
when you're doing a live show and you're
just kind of free balling the time and
it's.
And sometimes comedy and sometimes it's
just,
sometimes it gets heated,
sometimes there's booze involved in
lows,
but um,
you know,
I mean it's just,
are you trying to get better all the
time trying to do it better,
right?
If you are,
this is just the part of the process and
um,
there's value in feedback,
but there's also you have to understand
like how many people would you know,
how many people are just trolling you,
how many people don't like you for
whatever reason,
how many people just go,
I've gone to people's pages,
they'll say something insulting and you
go to their page and it's just them
insulting everybody.
Anybody they can.
I know there's some people that choose
to do that with their time and hey,
this is America.
You're allowed to do that.
But I think overall the more time goes
on,
the less I spend looking at any of that
shit the better off I am.
So I'm less likely to look at that shit
now than I ever have before.
Yeah.
It's just a.
Yeah,
because like you say,
like some of it you want to see.
And it is good feedback and like,
you know,
there is a good rapport like with,
and then other people just like,
they make it almost impossible to find
the good ones because it's just,
just because you said one word and look,
you know,
we're comedians were just curious.
People were always trying to figure
stuff out.
You know,
we're very similar in that we're not
down on neither any one side,
any one team.
We're really trying to figure out life
and try to figure things out.
So you're allowed to try and be like,
I don't think this is right or I don't
think that's right.
And then.
But the teams,
people from the teams just pounce.
Well,
you can't think that way.
I'm trying to figure it out.
I don't know if this is a,
an oil grab.
I don't know if this is,
but don't you think that's also what
makes,
um,
social in social media and interaction
with people so interesting is that
people can throw their opinion to the
ring,
throw their hat into the ring as a word.
You know,
like they,
they read something that you say or they
heard something that you said in a clip
and then they,
they argue with you about it.
If it's,
if it's,
uh,
a smart argument.
yeah.
Not just a knee jerk,
you know,
I hope you die because you said that.
You know what I mean?
You'd love to,
you know,
I mean,
that's some of the best conversations
you can have or when you don't agree
with somebody and you're just kind of
like going back into cam,
get here,
but it's not insulting.
Yeah.
That's the big key.
And it's also you,
when you explore why you believe
something and I believe something
different and you go back and forth
over.
if you do do it respectful and you do
get to understand where that person's
coming from,
sometimes it makes it even more obvious
to everybody listening and to you that
they're wrong or that you're wrong.
Whatever the fucking honest answer is it
gets.
It gets sort of illuminated and it
doesn't get illuminated.
When you get locked up in this battle,
there's people that will form sides,
but if you can get to the objective bow
k,
what?
What makes you believe that that is true
and then they tell you and you go,
well,
that is actually not true.
Let's find the facts or I didn't know
that.
Now I'm looking at my initial position
different in life and don't be married
to that initial position because it's
just an opinion,
but opinions to us are almost like
markers of our self esteem.
If you can't,
if you can't defend that position,
then you fucked up initially and you're
in the year,
you're flawed so people like dig in and
they try to defend that position and
even when they know it logically,
it doesn't make sense.
It's like they get married to it
and even if you.
You're with somebody and you're engaged
and you're having this real back and
forth about something and you both are
dealing with the facts,
but you still have your opinion that now
I'm still siding with this way and I'm
siding with that way you can still
respect each other.
Yeah.
It's when you go,
when it becomes this personal insult is
where you lose it,
right?
I mean,
I know people in my family,
people you know,
that I work with whatever,
who have total different views,
vote differently,
act differently,
do whatever,
but I love them.
They're just great people and you can't,
they're to,
you shouldn't have to dissolve
relationships because of a political
point of view about a certain issue.
There's,
you know,
that's what's so great.
my whole family was like,
my grandfather was hard,
right?
My uncle was hard left and they would
argue and fight,
but they loved each other and everybody
kind of got along and just ate the
potatoes after the argument.
Some people can't do that.
Right?
So you can't,
if you don't agree with them,
you can't hang out with them.
Yeah,
like about everything.
Yeah.
And then some people will have like
these crazy arguments where you just
can't be right or wrong.
You don't know what you're talking about
and you're still like climate change.
How many people have you talked to that?
We'll just go hard one way or the other
on climate change.
Yeah.
And then when you start talking to them
about it,
like you actually ask them,
what makes you think that climate change
is just a cycle and that human beings
are not involved and it's been shown
that it's been a lot of the data has
been hoaxed and a lot of the.
And then if you just go deeper,
deeper,
deeper down the rabbit hole,
you find that they haven't looked into
it that much.
Right?
Very few people arguing pr pro or
against manmade climate change have
really looked into it.
Most people are just sort of taking the
consensus view that they hear from
scientists are from pundits or from
people.
And if you were on the left,
you're most likely thinking that we're
in deep trouble.
and if you're on the right,
you're more likely to dismiss it.
Yeah,
I mean that's why.
Back to why we need grownups to like
control some of the news and give you
facts so you can kind of decide stuff.
It's because you don't have the time to
research climate change on your own.
You've got kids,
you've got a dog that's got a wants you
to whack off with the two.
There's a lot going on in your life,
so you depend on others who are really,
who are invested in giving you the right
information.
So what do you do?
Do you tell them that they have to just
say like,
okay,
if you're going to call something in
news,
should we have like a thing where
there's a,
you have to like meet a standard of
ingredients like we looked at your
ingredients and you have trans fats in
your news,
right?
You have all this other bullshit like
this.
He can't sell this as food,
not news.
You can't make this fit should be.
It should be because like for,
for like hannity to say I'm a talk show
host,
that's fine.
More power to you,
but then there should be a thing,
a little logo in the corner that says
opinion show,
right?
The little.
oh,
and then there should be an n on the top
of the whatever show that just giving
you facts for the day.
Right?
The problem really is calling it a news
network and having an opinion.
People on a news network.
Right.
But that it's the same with anderson
cooper when he's rolling his eyes at
kellyanne conway.
Yeah,
the same shit.
It's the sAme stuff.
Same shit.
He's just do it on the other side and
maybe he's correct that what she's
saying is ridiculous,
but he's clearly editorializing by doing
that.
Yes.
It's all opinion shows,
you know,
and then you need buddy don lemon.
You meet an old ted koppel to just sit
there with his little face and just gave
you the boring news and put an n on it
and then he goes on an opinion shows he
lets them know.
Yeah.
I mean he's letting these guys know
like,
hey,
you're ruining everything.
Yeah.
There was enough time to watch anything
frankly.
Good for you.
But where do you get your news?
Do you just read articles I read?
Uh,
I,
yeah,
I mean stuff pops up on my phone,
read the times.
I read the times.
I got the times delivered every day.
Look at you like a real man.
Yeah.
To have toast gentleman's toast.
Yes,
I do the gentleman's breakfast
gentleman's breakfast and eat the van
gogh is this great.
A great painter has this great.
Had this great quote about what it takes
to do good work and you have to have a,
you have to have your,
your smoking,
your pipe,
have a uh,
a fling once in awhile,
something like a and have a moment to
yourself to have coffee,
to have your coffee by yourself.
And I really try and carve out every day
I have.
It's not going to make me van gogh,
but it just,
I really believe those things like to
just sit with your coffee for a couple
of minutes and just in peace.
Just have that.
Those moments like even when you're
talking about making your bread,
yeah,
those moments make you more of a person.
Those moments of thought and careful
consideration what you're doing,
relaxation,
you sitting there and eating the bread.
Just having a slice of toast and a
coffee and just sit for 10 minutes and
before you embark on whatever madness
you're going to do for the day,
that's one of those moments are
important.
It's one of the big rituals for back
country hunters bringing coffee guys
will,
you know,
weight is a very big thing.
Your back country hunting and hiking.
Like when these guys go deep into the
back country,
you know there are several miles deep
into the woods.
Yeah.
I used to do it all the time and they,
the guy,
a lot of guys will bring like a little
jet boil and packets of coffee and
they'll cook up some hot water and
they'll sit together and they'll,
well,
they'll like have a moment to be a
person again,
sit down,
let's have a cup of coffee.
Interesting.
And they'll,
they'll use these little plastic cups
and you know,
the poor have their coffee and they're
sitting there drinking the side of the
mountain and then they feel like,
oh,
I got a moment of pleasure,
a moment of relaxation.
And there's other stuff they didn't put
in the packs.
Just so they can have that.
Yes.
Well they just carry that extra weight.
Especially the jetboil jet poles,
probably compounder.
So you know,
you're carrying water anyway.
So you just boiling that water and you
pour in those,
you know,
they have those starbucks little virtue.
I think they're called.
One's called starbucks.
You have little packets called.
What's it called?
That was called [inaudible].
Yeah.
It's just like,
yeah,
like a little pack of like instant
coffee or anything.
It was a to what is a virtue that's
assumption right now that make
electronic or some shit.
But yeah,
whatever those star wars,
those,
those starburst.
So starbucks are really good.
Those are good.
Yeah.
I mean it tastes like real coffee.
Make figured out how to do it now with
my shitty New York apartment because.
Yeah,
because they didn't have a good coffee
maker.
I was like,
these,
this will do me.
Well
dude,
if you want to make coffee,
if you're at home,
all you need is a french press.
That is the way that he has a way to go.
It is the best.
It's a little mucky cleanup.
Yeah.
I guess that's where it's at,
but it's a few steps,
but the oils from the coffee,
like if you're a person who enjoys the
actual flavor,
no milk,
no nothing.
Just give it to me like a man.
That's what I would drink it these days
and I get way less complaints on the
podcast about me clearing my throat.
Oh yeah.
That was a problem before.
Why?
Because you had stuff in the coffee.
I drink bulletproof coffee with butter
and mct oil and it was making you flemmi
that butter coffee makes you super
fleming.
That'd be like,
what am I drinking here?
Black coffee.
Just black man coffee.
The best sabretooth roast.
it's really good.
god damn savage was good.
Uh,
now there's those moments are really
important in life.
I really believe like those little quiet
things that have been passed on,
like if things had been around for
thousands of years and people have
figured it out the cocktail hour,
the moment,
the quiet moment,
you know,
before bed or in the morning when you're
having your coffee,
those things are figured out for a
reason.
There people have figured out this is
the way to live,
this is,
you know,
it really is.
It really is the way to live.
Yeah.
And if you could pull it off and they're
so small and they're so deep and they're
so valuable,
you know what I mean?
it's not a giant trip to vegas.
It's not,
oh,
I've got to make a million dollars.
It's sitting with your pipe and a
coffee.
that simple little thing.
so much better for your soul.
Then all this giant stuff that we end up
chasing small.
Yeah.
Um,
I was uh,
interviewing dr robert sapolsky
yesterday,
famous scientist and one of the things I
was doing is going over some of his
work,
listening to some of his previous
interviews and reading some of his
articles and stuff.
And he had this thing about meditation.
Oh yeah.
And essentially one of the things that
we're saying about meditation is like,
it can be effective,
but you have to do it all the time.
Like it's not something you can do once
a week.
Like meditation is something that should
become a daily part of your routine.
Then you can,
it'll help you mitigate stress,
but I think it's twice a day.
once a day.
He didn't specify,
you know,
he's talking about all the different
forms that it takes to.
There's a bunch of different kinds and
there's not necessarily one that works
best one,
but I think that what you're doing when
you're making your bread,
I think that's a meditation.
I really do.
Yeah.
In a weird way.
It's not like when I really meditate and
you sit for 20 minutes and you don't
slow,
like it slows your heart rate,
it says,
and you're not asleep.
It actually calms you deeper than sleep.
I used to and I still do call martial
arts,
moving meditation because martial arts
make you think so much about the
movements and about what you're doing.
So
much inTensity and so much danger
involved in them that they make you have
like very singular focus and then in
that singular focus there's some sort of
a cleansing that happens with your mind
by just going hard at these things.
It relieves stress in a way completely
that uber focus on anything.
Right?
Like when I used to,
when I had a motorcycle and my father
still does it and you know,
I mean it's his thing like,
you know,
I've comedy and other things to put my
mind into,
but he still does it and I get it.
I mean,
when you're on that bike,
it's your survival.
Where's your dad live?
He lives in New York city?
No.
Uh,
upstate New York.
So is he in a place where you could ride
a bike and not worry about?
Yeah.
It's not like running you over whether
texting,
but he goes everywhere.
He goes on these trips,
like,
excuse me,
up all the way in mostly east coast,
but he's done all of europe.
He's done all of the.
You ever wipe out?
No,
they never wiped out.
Never wiped out.
Wow.
No,
that's incredible.
Yeah.
How'd you do that?
You're the only guy I've ever heard of a
really?
I don't know.
I was uber safe as you know,
as I could be,
you know,
you're still dependent on other people,
but the only time I fell over was my
wife and I pulled into a days inn in
like Kansas and we'd done a lot of
highway,
just straight,
you know,
hours just going and we pulled up to the
days inn and the routine was we'd pull
in at the end of the day and she would
go into check into the hotel and I would
take care of the bike and we pulled into
a days in and she got,
she hopped off the bike and I just never
took my feet off the pegs because I was
so tired and I just like benny hill just
slowly tipped over,
get her now the bar kind of caught it.
It just feels like a nub.
That's pretty good.
Yeah.
As far as like all the friends,
no.
I went with a couple of friends from
fear factor were all taken at the same
time.
Motorcycle safety course.
Oh yeah.
While I was doing it to people I know
got in car accidents on motorcycles.
Really?
Yeah.
And then one person I know saw a person
get hit,
saw someone stays out on their phone,
ran into some guy from behind,
so flying through the air just just hit
him.
He just bang.
It's terrible.
I know I,
I was lucky,
but once I came out here,
I had it in New York city for a long
time,
which was kind of manageable.
I would do like spots me and greg
giraldo would go between clubs and it
was night,
so it was kind of a little more mellow
and it was all right.
But once I came out here I was like,
there's no way I just had kids and my
career was starting to go.
Okay.
And I'm like,
there's too much to lose.
I mean,
and this place is nuts with driving as
it is.
And uh,
everybody drives out here too,
as opposed to in New York.
Those are professionals.
That's right.
Yeah,
you're right.
You're right.
It's not that they're better at it,
but you know,
amanda was in san francisco a couple of
weeks ago and I went into a ducati
triumph
shop.
Oh god.
It made me want to ship back on.
Oh,
they're so beautiful.
I've never written a ducati,
but I of them and these were like
touring ones.
Like I wasn't even interested in like
the real crotch rocket.
Like they've got these touring ones that
are so beautiful,
bad ass two copies of a cool sound to
them too.
They really do.
Very distinct.
Yeah.
I,
uh,
I do miss it for sure.
Who fucking things?
Yeah,
the new triumphs.
They're made to look like the old
triumph and those are great.
I know.
It looks like so much fun.
So much fun.
Oh,
look at that fucking bike.
That's a double tailpipes oh my god.
How could you not want to just leave
everybody just go.
It's probably so fun now.
Apparently those things kind of have
like self balancing properties to them.
Really.
Gyros will.
They have like a traction control.
Some of them do now.
And there was one that jamie showed that
some bike from the future that holds
itself up.
Who is that?
Who made it?
There's some new bmw bike that doesn't
really to any bike you've ever seen
before.
It looks like some total tron shit.
She some space age shit and this bike
is.
I think it's right.
It's a concept right now.
Go fullscreen.
So we could look at this shit.
You know what bmw is doing this,
but if this happens.
Jamie was saying they were saying you
don't need a helmet,
which is really.
I mean I'm just repeating what they say.
So look at these guys declared you don't
even need to wear clothes.
Looks at the goggles they have on.
She's got these goggles that are like
virtual reality headsets.
Go back.
So you could see those goggles before
she puts them on.
Like look at this.
Look at this fucking bike man.
Gordon.
This thing like tom cruise and the.
Yeah,
it looks so.
She can see like the speedometer and
everything comes through your vision.
Oh wow.
Look at that.
This is crazy.
It's got big fat batman tires.
That's going to look.
It's got the navigation system.
It's showing on the goggles.
She's running around like this is crazy.
That's amazing.
Is this coming soon?
I don't know if it's ever come and
really it might be bullshit.
No way.
All this stuff always comes out,
but watch.
She stands off of it and it stays up on
its own genres.
God,
of course it's coming,
but she doesn't.
She is.
She's so hot.
She'll totally would be with me.
Hotter,
hotter.
When you're on a bike like,
oh my god.
I find I follow on instagram.
It's look at that thing.
It's batman motor a list.
It's just fuck.
Just beautiful girls on these old
vintage bikes.
It's the sexiest thing I've ever seen.
Look at that.
Like she doesn't even have to balance
it.
It balances itself out because she's so
hot.
It's her pussy.
Pussy gyroscopes got such a
gravitational force at the whole thing.
I stay centered.
She's so.
You put a girl on a bike,
it's hot.
You know?
If you put a girl in a place where you
don't expect you,
could she?
She goes up and bright girl on a golf
course at a boxing gym with her hair
pulled back.
Oh my god.
A girl on a crew with just a tool belt.
Yeah,
girl.
On a golf course?
Yeah,
they go up because it's always fat guys.
Right.
Do you think a girl on a golf course,
just looking for deck,
how do you think they actually liked
golf?
Some completely
play.
Really entertaining.
What question?
It takes all types.
Real consideration.
probably all this looking for dick
possibly like it.
It's like guys playing with dolls.
Do you really like to play with dolls?
Yeah.
No,
I.
If you're out there on the links
playing,
she can play in some girls that couldn't
play it all.
We're just flirting with guys at the
driving range.
What are you showing me here?
Jamie?
Like the hottest.
Arguably female golfers.
Shag million followers on instagram
where she does female golfer and showing
her,
but imagine if that was a male golfer.
Standing like that.
Backup one.
Okay.
Male golfers standing like that show's
over.
Fell over.
Okay.
But she could do that.
You can stick her blood at you.
Yes.
Well he got to work.
Hey.
Well I'm sure she's got more than that.
You son of a bitch now.
She's talented.
Sexist.
I can't even believe my friend that's
going on here.
She's got tits hanging out and she's
wearing little tiny skirt.
You gotta work with what you got?
I'll come.
Dudes don't trust like that when they
hit balls.
Seems weird because we don't.
We don't have those bodies.
Our bodies are gross.
It looked like that.
If we were sleek and thin,
thin,
smooth,
hairless moves.
Not offensive.
No appendages dangling.
Yeah,
no disgusting and gross gross hairs
coming everywhere.
Everywhere I get harrison my ears.
Now I have to shave him some new thing
so I get older.
I get hairier.
Have neck hair now back in the neck.
Heron.
Yeah.
A beer here knows hair.
I'm covered.
I'm like a bear except where we want it.
Yeah,
exactly.
I had a barbara and old italian barber
shave my ears when I was 15.
Just put like he took lotion shaving
stuff and put it on my ears and shave.
Great razor.
Yeah.
And ever since then just weeds growing
out of my ears.
Yeah.
I totally work that just grew that way.
Anyway.
That's why we shaving your ears at 15.
most kids don't have to get the fucking
marriage.
You're 15 your goddamn little wolf.
Boy,
like michael j.
Fox in that movie.
yeah,
but it was soft little fluffy hair.
Now it's like cactus
works that way.
Man.
I don't think like when you shave it,
it doesn't grow back thicker.
I think that's a myth.
I don't think that's true.
I think it definitely grows back
thicker.
Really?
Yeah.
I don't think it does matter.
I think this came up the other day I was
on here if I saw it,
but yeah,
definitely grows back then.
I'm pretty sure it's a myth.
My wife started shaving her mustache.
Now
john go,
but it's a war.
We will.
When we hack away,
I've got a.
I've got a trimmer that goes inside the
ear and the nose.
I got out at the nose.
One thing I shaved with my regular
razor.
As I'm shaving my face,
I shaved the back of my ears.
I am a hairy mess sometimes when I'm
driving in my car,
I'll grab a finger full of notes.
Terrace and all yank them out by the
roots feels good.
It's very satisfying.
When I look and I see a bunch of hairs
that are pulled out of my nose,
you got to get a trimmer.
Yeah,
I know I do,
but sometimes I can grab them and I'd
just like to grab my one.
My one part of my back is heavier than
the other side
fact or fiction.
If you shave or wax,
your hair will come back thicker and it
may look that way,
but it looks good.
I don't believe this science.
oh shit.
What the fuck.
In scientific America,
bunch of liberal nonsense that is simply
not so.
There are several reasons that the myth
continues to flourish.
One is the limitation of human
perception.
People are just not very good observers,
but there is no science.
Just no scIence behind hair growing back
thicker says amy,
me,
michael.
first of all,
it's a girl which she know,
chair of the department of dermatology
at wake forest baptist health.
We're just kidding.
Amy.
I'm sure you know a lot more than me.
There's also the power of coincidence.
Indeed.
Pervasive myths.
If a young boy shaves his mustache,
will grow back thicker,
are grounded in a kernel of truth,
it might,
but that's because the shaving may
overlap with the timing of natural
hormonal fluctuations in his body that
are developing his adult facial hair,
not because it was hair removal,
hair grows at different times and at
different rates.
For everybody.
Case closed and papa.
I had little fuzzies on my ears and now
I have cactus barbs that hurt my wife in
our sleep.
Whoa.
It's.
I'm a hairy mess.
I had a birthmark on my left side of my
back when I was young and it faded,
but what's remained his hair?
So my right side is not very.
Harry has some here,
but this side is just like a jungle.
A patch.
Well,
I used to have a song for it when I was
in high school.
What was it?
Sammy on my back.
Sammy.
I'm a back.
What you do in there with all that hair?
Sammy,
you got a million for it.
It was sammy my punch called sammy.
I'm one of my friends named it.
Wow.
That's some weird fucking jerk off.
To what you do in there with all that
hair.
Sammy.
And on that note,
ladies and gentlemen,
we just didn't know.
Three hours.
We did.
Yeah.
It's the best show ever.
Crazy.
How the fuck does that happen?
It's 4:30 already.
I'm dawn pop to you,
so when you're at home enjoying my bread
over memorial day weekend,
will I be enjoying any gift from milk
for you?
So yes.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
I have also,
I have purchased a new commercial sized
yoder pellet smoker and I will be
cooking from the new location.
So next time we do a fight companion or
maybe next time you and I do a podcast,
we will sit down to a meal.
Really I will cook before you ever get
here.
So we'll have a meal and we'll put some
cameras on us and we'll talk some shit
while we're eating a nice delicious wild
game dinner.
I will bring the wine and the cigars.
Come on and dinner with gender,
with joe and tom dinner with dinner for
two and you bring bread and we'll have
some gentleman's butter.
What is it?
Gentleman's breakfast.
Three cigars?
Yes.
Bottle of wine that's done,
done and do that.
We're,
we're done.
It's a great idea.
So I have this,
uh,
it's a yoder.
Pull this up.
So yoder 1500.
I got one so I could cook for like six,
seven people at a time.
Perfect.
Yeah,
I got it.
IT's a big.
Ask her to this.
Well,
I'm a big fan of these pellet smokers.
What I like about these yoders is this
is by the way,
not an endorsement.
I paid full price for this thing.
Didn't ask for.
It.
Looks a little sponsorship.
It's big.
It's just a dope pellet smoker.
Holy cow.
It's made in America.
What do you keep?
What's pellets?
The pellet.
It works on pellets,
meaning hardwood pellets.
So what they do is they take,
you know,
when the lumberyard cuts up,
like maple or oak or some hardwood,
they take the pellets a,
they tape rather the saw dust and they
compress it and the natural sugars
compressed down into pellets.
And then pelvis hold together and they
pour these pellets in the hopper and the
hopper feeds into a worm drive that
feeds to a heating element.
So it's.
Keeps it at a very consistent
temperature heading.
Have you laid it well,
it lights itself just to.
Just to switch.
Yeah,
see it.
That's what it looks like.
And if you,
uh,
jamie,
see if he could find like it's dope.
I love these things.
And there's another company called
trager that just came out with a really
super high tech one that's thick and
insulated like a yeti cooler.
It's like they're the best model yet.
And you can control with an app and it
has digital thermometers that are built
into it.
So you can tell the temperature,
your food.
What's your,
what's your signature dish off of this
thing?
Well,
mostly I eat wild game because I shoot,
try to shoot an elk a year,
which is like 400 pounds of meat plus
god.
I give away a lot of aly for Japan,
but it's at 400 pounds of me.
But this year was a good year.
Yeah.
I shot two deer.
I shot a pig,
I shot an elk.
She's so,
I shot a lot of animals this year,
so I've got a lot of a big fridge at the
house to commercial freezers in the back
here and I have two more commercial
freezers at home.
Oh wow.
But I gave away a lot of food to my
friends.
Yeah.
I'm very proud of gave food to duncan
trussell.
I gave elk to Gary Clark jr.
Oh yeah.
One of the greatest guitarists of all
time.
Eight.
My.
Yeah,
that's great.
It sounds like a real group,
but yeah.
So triggered has this new one.
Um,
what did the timberline.
That's it.
That's a good number.
Line is their new one and this new one
you could see like it has this crazy
convection oven cycling of the smoke and
the triggers got this really thick door.
My friend John Dudley has one of these.
I think there's some sort of a discount
that you can get.
I didn't want to buy one with his.
I don't know.
I uh,
I have a gas grill thing though.
And you just don't get that.
Not the same.
It's not the same.
This is,
this is.
No gas,
this is just would see the pellets.
There's no chemicals in it.
Oh,
so you just didn't know gas line or
anything?
No,
no,
no.
IT's just electricity heats up that
heating element and there's a fan that
blows air on the.
The,
the wood chips while they're getting
cooked and then it's just smoke smoke
and he cooks the food.
Dude I am.
I am sold.
There's another company,
a really good company called green
mountain grills.
They actually gave me a grIll back in
the day.
They were the first ones that ever
tried.
Those are excellent too,
and you can get a good one that's not.
Not even too expensive.
Camp chef has another really nice one
too,
so I was not.
I'm not trying to tell anybody to buy
anything,
but I'm saying if you're thinking about
getting a grill,
I will look into one of these pellet
grill.
That's pretty bad ass.
Well,
it's super easy to use too.
You just pour the pellets into this
hopper and then you set the temperature.
How often you have to refresh the pellet
duty.
They're so.
They're so economical like it doesn't.
They don't last long because they keep
the exact right temperature or real
close to it within a few degrees up or
down.
You uh,
like the hopper.
I fill it up like every four or five
cooks.
And if that was like charcoal it would
last for one.
You know,
like you said that was,
that's what it looks like.
See those things.
They look like some sort of a brand
cereal,
right?
Doesn't it like one of those?
Yeah,
that like terrible food.
Yeah.
So what it is is just hardwood sawdust
and they just smush it and the naturaL
sugar is make it stick together because
you could break it up with your fingers,
like you break it up easy.
So you pour it into the hopper,
it grinds down,
see that worm drive below.
It feeds down to that thing on the
right,
which is like where the heating element
is and so it just catches fire and then
the flames make smoke and then it fills
up that chamber and the heat comes from
the smoke.
So when You put a an elk steak or
something on there,
can you cook it like in just a couple
minutes or is everything just smoke
slow?
It takes a long time.
So like the way I do it now,
I've done it a bunch of different ways
and all of them are delicious.
Like elk is my favorite meat.
It's delicious healthy meat.
But my favorite way to do it now because
of this guy Chad whiskey bent barbecue
on instagram was my friend john dudley's
buddy who's a world champion.
pitmaster like one of those.
Oh yeah,
bad motherfucker grill guys.
James says don't ever cook meat above
275 degrees.
He says when you're cooking you should
cook it slowly and don't allow the meat
to dry out and use a meat thermometer.
So since I started doing that,
I've been very happy with the results
because I get it hundred and 30,
135 degrees somewhere around there.
Then I pull it and then I reverse sear
it.
The way I do it is on a frying pan.
I use butter in the frying pan with
garlic and I see her,
that shit out of it on each side real
quick.
Like 30 seconds.
Like you're walking into the house.
Yeah,
breaking into the house.
Then I get even crazier and I wrap it up
with aluminum foil and I put it in a
yeti cooler and I seal it up for 15
minutes.
Let it slowly keep cooking,
cause real slow cooled down.
And then I opened it up and I let it sit
for another 10 minutes and then I slice
into that.
So what should I do with the gas grill?
We'll talk,
we'll talk.
Throw that thing in the fucking.
Give it to homeless people,
throw it in the la river.
Say this is when you can do something
like that and you get good at it,
right?
This is the bread thing.
It's like,
yes,
you're in.
Yes.
Well for me it's a.
It's.
I love cooking.
I've always loved cooking and it's not.
There's a little bit of a manly thing
that I like more with cooking,
with lump charcoal over a charcoal grill
smell and something very manly about the
real fire chemo,
but honestly as far as taste and as far
as ease of use and repeatability,
it's hard to fuck with these pellet
grills because you're cooking with real
wood fire.
Yeah,
it smells great.
it tastes great.
Like when you open the lid up,
the smell of like maple and see the
different,
you know,
you can buy a bunch of differently.
Applewood,
all kinds of different cherry by all
kinds of different pellets.
I need a bigger yard.
Isn't even that big man?
No.
And again,
it economical like I know green mountain
grill go to green mountain grill.
They have a pretty small one that is
only like a few hundred bucks.
And um,
my mother in law has my old one.
It's great.
Yeah,
they're fucking great man.
It still works.
I've had it for years.
Really?
Yeah.
And that one has a built in thing.
It's called the Daniel Boone.
You know,
one thing I took off of your instagram
was the,
uh,
the eggs and just throwing the kale on
top of it.
Oh yeah.
It's a lifesaver.
I mean,
that's such a simple morning.
Oh,
it's the best.
So he's,
what I do is I take some kale,
I chop it up and then I chop up some
garlic and usually I do jalapenos too.
Then I get some butter cooking.
I put the kale in the butter,
I saw to it and once it really starts
getting darker,
it's ready to rock.
I just crack a few eggs and right on top
of it and mix it all up,
put it on a plate and it's fantastic.
You mix it up.
They look like they were sunny side up.
Sometimes I do that too.
Sometimes I just put the kale right next
to the eggs.
Right.
Sometimes I cook the eggs in the kale.
yeah.
I've just been throwing the kale on top
of the eggs.
Great.
Two.
Yeah.
Great.
So fast.
Yeah.
Super easy.
The best.
What's this one?
Have you tried one of these?
I have pretty,
yeah,
those are great shoes.
I have a,
I don't think I have that one.
I have another one like it.
What is the.
Yeah,
what you do is you vacuum seal your food
in a plastic bag and then you put it in
a pot with water and then
the hot water,
the thing will heat up to temperature of
the water,
like 125 degrees.
MY question would be like,
is the plastic leaching into your food?
They say it doesn't and it's a good
question though,
but how do we.
I mean you can't microwave plastic if
it's a certain temperature.
Maybe the plastic needs to hit a certain
temperature to melt.
well they say you should never drink
bottles that have been in your car in a
hot day in la.
I was wondering about that reCent.
I was just like,
hi.
And thinking about that.
Where did that story like maybe come
from maybe the glass bottled water
people are putting out false.
Who's good?
Is there a glass bottle?
Water business,
yay.
And all those are all glass bottles.
They started off.
What's the trend on it?
I think there's actual science behind it
that I was just wondering was all
conspiracy.
You were high.
That's what you're saying.
The sous vide is good.
I have actually a blow torch that I do
with zeus feed.
Oh yeah.
So I do sous vide and then I cook the
outside of it with a torch.
Yeah,
get that brown on the outside.
I've done that,
but I don't prefer it.
I prefer the trigger style mountain
grill.
Yoda grill was pellet grills.
Again,
there's a bunch of different companies.
I'm not trying to endorse one.
I like green mountain grill.
My friend John Dudley loves those
triggers and then.
But that new trigger timberline's pretty
revolutionary and it's supposed to be
amazing in its ability to insulate.
Think actually the best one to.
There's another one called the memphis
memphis grills.
Supposed to be really good at that.
Someone told me if you have a glass,
a gas grill to put a cast iron pan on it
and you do your steak that Way.
Yeah,
that's a good move.
Yeah.
To get that,
that seared flavor from a cast and it's
more even.
It's gets a little more,
a lot of big times.
Take restaurants,
still use cast iron pans,
cast irons.
Pretty bad ass.
You know,
you get iron from it too.
You to dietary iron.
Yeah.
It was just crazy.
You don't really explain him.
Good for you.
You get like,
it's good to cook.
Even vegetables like cooking vegetables
in,
in an iron pan.
You get a little bit of iron.
Oh really?
Yeah.
that's good for my wife.
So true.
Make sure that's true.
Was a little low iron.
I feel like I might be lying.
No,
I think you're right.
I've heard that
cares.
I do so many podcasts.
There's so many things that I've said
that are not true.
And then I try to deceive you folks.
We're doing our best.
I'll do my best.
I am doing my best.
Tom papa,
working these fine people.
See you perform.
You're wonderful and magical.
Standup comedy.
I'm going to uh,
do some shows in oakmont,
Pennsylvania and a theater in richfield,
Connecticut.
And old saybrook go to tom.
Papa.com.
I've got a bunch of stuff in june and
then starting up again in the fall and
my specialist,
a streaming on hulu and amazon and I'm
following my instagram.
If you want bread tips,
how old is your special now?
It was about six months ago.
Five months ago.
Six months ago?
Yeah.
And when do you think you'll think about
doing another one?
What kind of schedule you on?
I feel like I could start lining it up
because I've got about a.
I've got about 35,
40.
That's really solid
fillable stuff.
Right.
And um,
you know,
keep working at that pace by the time I
set it up and go do it.
It'll be probably I did it last july is
when I filmed it.
So we're coming up on a year and if I
did it probably like a year and a half
to two years,
it feels like two years might be a
little long,
but it feels like a year and a half will
be.
It will be ready and I know it was a
clock on it.
It's really like when is it ready?
But if I'm already at that point,
I feel like I should crank it out.
Yeah.
I'm on the exact same schedule.
A lot of people I've talked to have that
Same opinion.
That seems to be like that.
Like a year out,
a year and a half,
and you start feeling this is real.
It's ready to go.
Yeah.
It takes time.
You know when you want it to be.
I don't want to just eat.
You cross the finish line.
I want to,
you know,
you want it to be better than the last
one.
Yeah.
You want it to be representative of
where you are.
You feel your standup is right now.
You know exactly what a great nights and
you have.
You're not like,
it's a matter of being,
getting it so consistent that you get to
the ball like this motherfucker's ready.
Right,
exactlY.
It's,
you pulled the bread out of the oven.
Right?
Exactly.
Some pellets.
And on that note,
ladies and gentlemen,
oh,
that's the end of this podcast.
Wait,
I mentioned that papa podcasts.
I always forget to turn people on to
that,
but that's the best.
Comics are the worst at self promotion.
I know.
That's a good thing my friend.
Thank you.
So I'm getting.
Are you at the store this weekend?
Not this weekend.
I'll be there next week though.
Okay.
Yeah,
I'll see you there next week.
Sounds good.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be back next week.
Thank you everybody.
Love you.
Bye.
my ears are.