The Joe Rogan experience podcast is
brought to you by the fleshlight.
If you go to Joe Rogan.net
and click on the link for the flashlight
and enter in the code name Rogan,
you will get 15 percent often.
Number one,
sex toy from men.
Yay.
As is in the house gritches Buckler
Rogan experience.
We're fitting to make shit happen.
I'm going to say that all the time.
Now we're fend to do this friend to make
shit happen.
Don't even know where that came from.
I don't know why it exists with Finn
will fend to do this,
but I like it.
I'm a fan of were fin to.
We're going to do this.
I don't know what it means.
You lost me on that.
We fend to go do this podcast.
Some guy tweeted me saying he doesn't
like when I do a black force and to him
I say tough shit.
You're gonna.
Have to deal with that.
If there wasn't people that actually
talk like that,
you know,
if I was doing that white guy voice that
Richard Pryor always did,
that never bothered me.
It was like either Mr.
so Mr Pryor,
my,
my mom,
why she's a great old Gal.
I guess there are a few people that talk
like that,
but there's a lot of motherfuckers who
talked like my black voice.
Okay.
It's not like you have to go find them
like,
Gee Golly Gee Whiz,
Gee Whiz,
Gee whiz or maker.
No,
there's a lot of dudes will be like,
we Finna do this podcast.
That's not even ridiculous.
That sounds exactly what a lot of black
people sound like,
but for whatever fucking reason,
man,
black,
feeble are so super sensitive about just
a little good natured joking around.
I,
I got it.
I got in trouble the other day.
I went to our fi,
like a five star restaurant called the
Ritz.
I don't know if you ever heard it,
but it was like,
like the most widest place ever.
Like there was four waiters,
one for just your glasses and they were
all standing by your tables for my
birthday.
And I twittered a joke.
Like,
Oh,
I really wish they would let black
people in here.
Ha ha ha.
You know as a joke.
And people got so fucking pissed off at
me and I had to explain like,
no,
I was making fun of that.
I was making fun how,
how wide,
how wide it was and how it was
disgusting.
Yeah.
People are Super God damn sensitive.
I made one fucking joke and I think the
joke was because there was something
real obvious in the news.
I forget what it was and my response to
it was a.
So they're telling us some shit that we
already knew.
Like what?
What's next?
You're going to tell me that many black
people don't tip.
You know?
Which by the way,
I'm not saying all but I'm saying many.
I'm saying it's,
it's a known thing that if you work in
restaurants,
a lot of times black people don't tip.
If you're black and you tip,
God bless Ya.
You know,
I'm not saying there's anything wrong
with that,
but I am from Italian descent.
I'm Italian,
Irish and I have said on many occasions
that my people are fucking monkeys.
Those fucking dummies,
those wanna be soprano dummies.
There's so many dumb Italian.
It is embarrassing to be Italian all the
time.
Italians make some bad ass food and
there's a certain Robert Deniro,
percentage of Italians that are bad
motherfuckers.
There's a few rocky Marciano's out there
in the world,
but by and large the great percentage of
Italians are douchebags and that's me.
That's me.
We're just being realistic.
Nothing wrong with that,
but for whatever fucking reason I say
this thing about black people tipping
and people are calling me races and all
this fucking shit.
So this weekend I'm in Philadelphia,
right?
We're there for the UFC and I'm with my
boy Tommy Jr and his girl Katie,
and we get high as Jesus on the fucking
space shuttle we got.
We got down Joe Diaz.
We went deep.
We just kept smoking.
Got To break up the we'd when I come up
here though.
What are you talking about that we don't
do shit to me?
If you make me drive 40 minutes up and
you've got to get me stolen,
bro.
That's will handle.
We'd.
I've been telling you about that.
She's crying.
Yeah.
You broke that shit to the ice house to
that shit.
Don't do nothing to you.
Just so crazy.
What the fuck,
doctor,
you got to bust out some good weed.
Dug enough is enough with this show.
You can not look at my fucking eyes,
but I look high to you.
Got Fuck because I smoke on the way
because I knew you were going to give me
that sasquatch and fucking weed.
You better start getting some good
fucking hand on my shit.
But that's the second time in a fucking
rock.
Yo.
Dude.
You know luxury then rick.
That was garbage.
They sold you on it in my eyes.
So relax.
I love you too.
Love you.
Got to go to a doctor.
Damn.
You always sit here with the weed and
shit the fuck are you smoke and look at
me.
What?
Broken.
Fucking broke and he hit me with this.
Let's do this bro.
Motherfucker,
are you right now?
He gets high on a fucking fuck.
Look@them.one
ambulance show up.
That's the biggest thing was that it was
a tightly rolled joint power hits where
he's just feeling in his lungs,
you are,
you're you like big.
I couldn't get a hit off of it was too
fucking tight.
Fucking screaming at America,
listening to you saying that you're high
and you give me that stuff.
You know I love you to death,
but you got to pack the 18 joey.
Jesus,
fucking Christ.
Love people who are listening to this.
You understand that?
This is entertainment.
I know all you're doing is complaining
about not complaining.
I'm just saying that I want to get high
when I'm not complaining.
Listening to what you're doing that's
complaining.
You invite me to your home and you give
me.
This sucks Hannah.
We have Hannah.
What else?
What the fuck are you talking about?
No Avenue.
Costello was cheap.
Fucking hat.
You got the eight team here and what
fucking planet are you from?
Fucking smoking.
That shit.
Shut the fuck up.
I'm talking about the Goddamn thing I
did this weekend.
I didn't know about that shit.
Weed.
You just.
You are so fucked up.
Fuck.
Look at my eyes.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
It's not that you weigh 300 pounds and
he smoked pot all day everyday.
That's what.
That's not what it is.
Fucking fucking do it.
Blame.
It's not fat.
It's the physical size of your body or
you're crazy.
I go to other stores.
I go to other stores the fuck.
That's the second time.
So fucking whining.
Complaining,
whining,
complaining.
So brody here.
So this is showing like bad.
Will you please shut the fuck up man.
This is a Goddamn podcasts.
You've been complaining for five fucking
minutes about weed telling me that.
What such what?
Hannah.
You know what?
I don't know what [inaudible] is.
No more fucking late night podcasts for
Joe.
No more.
You can't handle a dog.
I love you too.
But there's 2000 people listening right
now.
Hundreds of thousands of listening
online and all you're doing is
complaining about weed for five minutes.
Fucking podcast that.
Yeah,
that might have been ruined.
I,
uh,
I've been a big fan of her youtube.
Shut the fuck up about this thing.
I've got to tell you about Philadelphia.
Fuck God dammit.
You try and change the subject after he
beats me down.
I was just trying to calm them down for
a second.
Don't talk about.
We dogged out around me dog.
I got,
I got to Philly.
Is that
cracked bell?
Yeah,
we're in Philadelphia.
We,
Tommy junior brings us Connecticut.
We'd,
I am thinking this is going to be just
terrible.
I don't think there's going to be
useless,
but it was,
it was Joey Diaz style.
Gee,
Kush Endeca the shit that you used to
smoke and we just go eight,
nine,
10 hits deep to the point where we don't
want to leave the balcony.
Okay.
We're terrified.
We're out there and we're looking at and
it's a beautiful summer night and um,
you know,
Tommy Jr is my boy.
I've known him since I was like in my
early twenties.
And you know,
his girl Katie is really cool and we're
hanging out in.
The three of us are just giggling or as
I've gone,
we're too high to go outside.
We're so high.
We so nervous and paranoid,
but we're going to see planet of the
apes.
We had decided that the evening was.
I was looking forward to this weekend
very much because usually on Friday
night before the UFC,
I always do a show.
We always do a show somewhere,
but this weekend I was just going to
play pool with Tommy and Tommy,
uh,
texted me somewhere during the week.
Dude,
planet of the apes opens this week.
Let's do that too.
Like,
fuck yeah,
we gotta you know,
for me,
man,
I've got kids,
little babies and they constantly need
supervision and I don't really get a
chance to just go fuck off for a whole
day.
So this is,
I do the,
the,
the uh,
Wayne's are done by 5:00
and I'm hanging out with Tommy right
after that.
I do some UFC shit for like an hour and
then we're hanging out.
So were so high we can't,
we can't think straight.
We're just giggling,
but little giggle,
silly high.
It wasn't like my kind of high where
it's like thinking about Jupiter and you
know,
what happens if a planet hits another
planet?
No,
it's the,
it's Joe Diaz style high.
So we're giggling and we have a driver.
Luckily I have this God taking us
around,
you know,
like a big town car.
But uh,
you know,
whatever those suv things.
So the guy takes us to this movie
theater,
I go take us to whatever the good movie
theaters in town,
right?
And he goes,
well,
the good movie theater is over here.
And so it takes me to a super white
neighborhood where all the movies are.
Shit movies.
It's all like foreign films,
you know,
those weird,
those.
What are those theaters call?
Will you go there and you go,
what the fuck is this movement to look
for something that you recognize?
But everything's alternative.
I'm sure some of them are good,
but I,
I've seen some that everybody told me
were good because they were alternative
like,
like fucking was ghost dog,
whatever that Samurai one was with
forest whitaker episode a good.
So amazing.
It was such a piece of shit.
It was such a dumb movie.
And everybody's like,
it's amazing because it's because it's
an independent film.
So it's one of these Lemley films.
So anyway,
we uh,
we can't go there.
So I go,
you got to go to one where there's
planet of the Apes,
man,
we're going to go see planet of the
apes.
So I look on the iphone APP and it says,
okay,
take me to this one.
And the guy goes,
okay,
he goes out in a good neighborhood.
It's like,
oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Got Barely speaks English.
He texts us there,
we get out and we're giggling.
Is he putting the names?
We walk into planet of the Apes.
We walked into Africa,
did we?
We walked in the door and there was no
white people.
There was no white people.
We plan the act didn't take place in
Africa.
I was a racist thing to say,
but you see what I'm saying?
What I'm saying is fine automatically
stuck to your hands.
What would happen is we walked into the
blackest neighborhood we could find.
I mean,
it was,
there was literally no white people.
It was amazing and everybody was super
cool,
you know,
it wasn't a negative experience.
And this was something that I wrote on
on twitter that,
uh,
we all went to see a planet of the apes
in a black neighborhood and experience.
I highly recommend all these fucking
people started calling me a racist.
I mean,
dozens of twitter.
People do what?
I didn't know you were racist.
Fuck you.
Like black people were saying,
fuck you.
I'm like,
listen man,
I am saying it was a positive
experience.
It would sit on highly recommended and
it was a black neighborhood and we get
in there.
Right?
And we're so we're so deeply
heartbroken.
And then I realized like,
Whoa,
everyone's black.
You're like,
well,
I mean everyone's black.
This is crazy.
And then a bunch of people recognize me
and they don't want to take some
pictures and it's all good.
Everybody's cool and friendly.
Coolest shit.
Cooler Shit.
Like this guy goes,
Yo man,
I don't wait.
I know you from.
I don't want to.
I don't want to bother you man.
I'm not trying to use up your time.
I know you from.
I go,
fear factor.
yeah,
that's it.
But it's the way you said it was like so
cool and we're giggling.
Oh no one did the smoke rocks thing,
but it took a lot of God damn pictures
and see,
like I said,
super cool,
super friendly.
This is not a negative story.
So then we go into the movie theater,
right?
It's me,
Tommy,
and like maybe there's another white
person,
maybe one other white person movie
theater filled with black people and
they are having a good fucking time.
You know,
people always complain that black people
talk to the movie theater and talk to
screen.
Yes they do.
Yes they do,
but it's good.
That's totally fucking.
Yeah.
If that's what you know.
And so way I felt like I'm like,
look,
I'm in their neighborhood.
This is how they go to the movies.
Who the fuck am I to be offended by how
they liked to go to the movies?
They,
they were at the movies and I'm not
saying all black neighborhoods do this,
but this particular black neighborhood,
these people brought babies,
bro.
I mean there's a lot of people with
babies.
Yeah.
I mean it wasn't just one.
These,
these people in front of us walked in
and they had toddlers,
like little two year olds sitting on
their lap to see planet of the apes at
like 10:40
on a Friday night.
Give a fuck.
Fuck.
Not,
didn't give a fuck.
But I'll tell you what made me really
nervous and made me feel kind of weird,
was watching all of these previews of
all these different TV shows or all
these different movies around them that
are coming out and I'm watching these
movies and all of them are about white
people and I'm sitting there and I'm
going,
wow,
this is weird.
Like w imagined being a blank person.
And I always thought like people would
complain.
Like I'd hear Black People Complain
About,
oh,
there's no films for black people.
There's no roles for black actors.
And I'd be like,
so you go make your movie,
when do you want from me?
You know?
But when you go to a goddamn movie
theater with all black people,
that's when you really feel it.
I'm sitting there in the audience and
all these people are black,
but every movie preview is white.
There's no black characters.
And then finally there's this movie with
Jonah Hill and they show a preview for
the movie and it's Jonah Hill and he's
doing all this different shit.
He's babysitting kids,
but he's supposed to be like a cool guy.
And the way they show you who's he's a
cool guy is there's an old black guy
working like at a door at a club like
the black guys there and Jonah Hill's
talking black to them,
you know,
it is what it is,
brother,
it is what it is.
And I'm watching this with all these
black people watching this white guy
talk like a black guy and I'm in this
fucking theater film.
And I'm like,
and I'm high as fuck.
I mean just barbecued sitting there
soaking in this experience going,
wow,
this is fucked up.
Like what?
No one knew why black people are angry
and they feel disenfranchised.
Like they're completely removed from the
mainstream cultural experience in a lot
of ways like that.
There's a tiny percentage of black
people that are included in movies.
So finally planet of the apes place,
everyone's white in the movie except the
bad guy.
The bad guy is a black guy.
And I thought it was so strange and I'm.
And not only that,
he's a bad guy who owns this giant
company and he has an English accent.
It was like,
not only is a,
but it's like you couldn't have a
brother from Philadelphia that figured
out how to own this corporation.
It couldn't be a guy.
Even a brother that talks like a regular
businessman type dude,
you know,
who's like,
well,
well we need to do is acquire this and
you know,
once we get that and then we'll be on
moving and then we get in the forest.
No,
no,
no.
This guy has an English accent.
He doesn't sound like anybody,
you know,
and this is the only black guy in the
fucking movie.
And I'm like,
wow.
And then the rest of the movie is just
bad ass monkeys.
Just bad ass chimpanzees.
So this was a CGI.
Awesome.
Was it?
Oh my God is a good.
First of all,
the movie is good shit.
Planet of the apes is a dope movie.
It's a good movie for everybody.
I think it's PG.
13 believer or not.
Yeah,
because the violence is all sort of
implied like,
you know what the fuck went down,
but they don't really show it to you,
but it's not removed from violence.
It's a terrifying movie and the like,
he,
you know,
I don't want to say I can't,
I don't know.
One of the old ones.
Did you watch?
Oh,
I watched all of it.
All five.
Watched all of them.
And what'd you think of the first one is
still sensation.
It's.
Well,
you know,
you have to put yourself back in the
time because back in the time it was a
great movie.
It's like a lot of movies they don't
hold up because you,
you have to realize that culturally
human beings have evolved in a shoot way
from 1970 to 2011.
I mean if you want any proof of that
something is happening to our culture
and that things are expanding and moving
forward at an exponentially increasing
way.
All you have to do is look at old
movies.
Old Movies are almost unwatchable
unwatchable.
The abd concept is unwatchable.
We don't last that long.
Well,
not only that,
it's just not good.
Like I watched altered states are
trending ultimate states when I was in,
you know,
I,
I'm captain isolation tank,
you know what I mean?
I mean,
I'm in that goddamn thing all the time
and I got.
I learned about the isolation tank from
that movie.
I learned about Iowasca from that movie.
I learned a lot of Shit from that movie.
That movie was a big fucking 84 or
something like that.
I think so.
I'm just talking out of my ass.
I'm guessing though,
that again,
altered states.
It's not the Christopher Walken away
takes no William hurt,
right?
It was in 1980 or even earlier than we
thought.
Thirty one years ago.
Yeah,
it's so bad.
Or You fucking years ago and somebody
needs to Redo that goddamn movie because
that's a fascinating thing.
Especially with Iowasca being so
popular,
you know,
and isolation tanks were pretty God damn
popular right now to footloose instead.
I think it's amazing that isolation
tanks a lot of wildly popular is us a
lot of walls popular is talking about on
the podcast and talk about it in videos,
you know,
that's incredible that no one is talking
about one of the most amazing tools for
the human mind ever created.
And it's not like it's a fucking,
you know,
one of those things that they had to
build in the movie contact and it cost a
billion dollars.
You need fucking cranes to put it into
place.
Now.
It's so fucking simple.
I mean there's directions for building
these goddamn things on the Internet.
Was the movie in Three d?
Um,
no,
not,
not the one I did.
I was not in three D.
I don't know if it is in three d.
I don't know.
I'm not aware of what truly crazy,
but it was awesome.
My witness,
we went to philly about 18 months ago,
two years ago and we ran out of weed.
If somebody gave us a joint on the way
to the club and the same thing happened
to us.
So you don't fucking remember when we
brought them.
Need to fill this shit was probably less
than what was the DJ gave it to us.
It was one of the guys who works at the
radio station and all four of us were
like,
we don't want no more and it's something
that you really have to think about that
I got to come out here and pay $300 an
ounce and back.
They're 1:25
and they get fucking bullets.
Yeah,
they,
they're getting that,
that indycar the craziest.
It's Brown and it's fucking strong.
It's definitely a different highs.
Definitely a different vibe that I got.
Was that east coast high?
It was,
it's um,
it's silly.
It's a silly high and you don't like
think we weren't thinking about the
universe,
but I was very sensitive to this whole
situation,
you know,
it was like,
it made me feel like,
man,
you know what a black people have and
they are fucking Tyler Perry,
you know,
they have Tyler Perry,
that's their mogul.
That's the guy who's making a lot of
movies.
And so these,
Goddamn,
I ate a movies.
And what else does it.
I mean,
so there's not that many movies.
Every three months they put out an all
black funeral,
which was horrendously bad.
It's sad man.
I mean for every spike.
Lee,
how many fucking real good.
Every John Singleton,
how many real good representatives for
black people are there out there?
You know,
it's Kinda,
it's.
It was really interesting to be in a
black theater and you had a good.
I had a great fall.
You know what?
I have a good time on Tuesdays.
You want to have a good time with black
people and I'm not being fucking
prejudice for funny.
I'm just.
See if you want to see black people,
their natural environment,
you go to fucking Popeye's chicken on
Tuesdays.
They give you a wing and a breast for
ninety nine cents and I made the mistake
one night.
I got to tell you,
you want to go?
I like Bob.
I strictly what you love.
Spicy,
spicy.
We had that at the end.
I went to Popeye's chicken and it and
it's a one on Laurel Canyon.
Like if you go to Popeye's chicken
around Hollywood and it's full of full
of brothers name,
nothing you could do,
but Laurel Canyon,
you ain't going to be a brother.
I didn't even think about it,
but either way and I'd been there before
on a Sunday at least a special.
It's a wing and a breast for ninety nine
cents dog.
They'd come out of the woodwork for this
path when you understand me around the
corner,
but the best ones I've seen a real
mother fucking gangster brother.
This guy,
8:20
pieces of chicken and didn't get off the
phone.
Now one flip and time.
That's a real bad motherfucker.
The only time he got off the phone was
as the bitch for hot sauce and still sat
there and watched the whole certificate
on the bones are breaking them in half
while he was on the phone to call his
bitch out.
Fuck it.
I'm getting my.
Another thing that people got mad at me
for,
for asking,
why is it that I keep seeing black dudes
talking on speakerphone out loud by
themselves.
I see it all the time and public black
dudes holding the phone.
The next phase go yo what it is.
Oh,
okay.
And they're talking on the phone when
it's not near their face.
We talked about this once,
but my ex people got mad at my ex
girlfriend does that too?
She's black.
Will add so much flavor flavor to the
world.
Oh,
if it wasn't for these fucking black
people would just be a bunch of cowboys
on oysters listening to fucking think
about white people from Utah.
They fucking entertaining drove my wife
this morning at 7:00
you had to go get a blood test
assumptions done at Kaiser on the way
back.
I cut back to two and I went to North
Hollywood park.
You ready for this one?
This is food for thought.
There wasn't a soul in Hollywood park,
north Hollywood park,
but black people teach them karate,
north Hollywood park.
Beautiful Park.
You know those squirrels will let you
feed them.
Oh,
please.
It's a beautiful fucking part is a dude
and Chinese dude that sits out there
with a bag of squatting back at Magnolia
to hunting their dog.
That's a great fucking dog dog dog talk.
His language guy sits out.
This Chinese guy sits out there with a
fucking peanut and he'll just have a bag
of m and he lies on his back and he puts
his hands out and those girls come up
and they just hang out with that dude.
They take the things like they don't
even run,
didn't even back up before they eat.
They eat right there.
They just take it right from them.
That's a great fucking park.
It's one of my favorite color is black
dudes doing karate.
Karate sticks doing forms,
but they're out there doing
motherfucking karate.
Only brothers go to and you really want
this.
There's two movies I've seen.
The black movie dealer was the one movie
was rambled too.
I told you the other day,
but the best movie ever.
I seen the one about the black.
What's the guy when he comes?
I'm the black show gun to Harlem.
I've seen that in Harlem and last Dragon
Dragon was entertainment like I'm sure
that's a great movie.
This headache.
If I ever make enough money,
I would just buy a black.
We didn't just go there and laughed my
ass off,
fucked up,
and you go over to this one.
What's this one on sunset?
The atrium.
What's that one $90 to go to the movie
data's quite fucking dollars.
I went last year 20 tool and for 50 for
a sausage sandwich and I just want to
see a fucking movie guide's $90 of the
food that I just want to see a fucking
movie.
I worked new Jack City opening night in
Columbus,
Ohio.
One of the scariest movie theaters.
You don't want to go to a.
This is the difference.
You don't want to go see a gangster
black neighborhood.
No,
definitely want to go see a martial arts
martial arts film or an action film
to sit in the back of the theater the
whole time and watched that movie
because it was like midnight opening
night.
New Jack City.
I'm sitting in the back.
I'm a white general manager.
All my staff is black and so I'm sitting
there like,
what is this new Jack City movie?
Watch the head,
the watch,
the whole thing,
and there was fights.
There was one time where this lady
started hitting this other lady and went
into the hallway and I had to like kick
him out.
It was the one that the most scariest
moments of my life work in that movie
and one of the best movies ever saw too,
so.
Well one of the best ones that houses I
had but went to,
we went to Asbury park for Halloween to
a haunted mansion,
the city of North Bergen,
rented buses and they took you to
different places and we went down and
they,
this thing,
the Brigantine Casper,
I think I told you already.
We went in there and you know,
they got Dracula and Frankenstein when
you walk around and boom,
I supposed to get scared bro.
We had to beat like maybe 12 and a half
and you know,
you got a little scared.
We didn't smoke dope that or not.
Then we just walking around.
But Bro,
that Dracula bumped into a Black Dude
Dracula.
He said,
what the fuck you and these guys were
from east orange.
That was the other time that was.
And this guy looked at him.
He was like,
what the Fuck is wrong with Dracula
motherfucker?
They started beating the fuck.
They were 12 just like us.
We thought we were bad.
They started
get to them like 16 little black dudes.
I never laughed so hard in my life that
they fucked dracula.
By the time I got out,
the cops were there and nobody could cop
to it.
They had the kids with their hands up
against the wall.
You don't fuck with it.
It takes a broad spectrum of people to
make this world interesting.
You know?
And that is true that if you look at
like our culture,
first of all stand up comedy,
you know,
besides Lenny Bruce,
the number one contributor is black
comics.
Richard Pryor,
you know,
in later years,
Eddie Murphy,
Eddie Murphy contributed and Chris Rock,
they're the real greats.
You look at music,
there's so much black music,
so much black influence on led Zepplin
even on fucking Leonard Skinner,
man,
you know,
Lennon skinner,
they were influenced by a lot of black
guys.
That fucking song,
the ballot of Curtis Loew Amazing.
I'm writing song about a black guy in
the south who's teaching them how to
play the blues,
you know,
or playing the blues form when he was a
little kid at.
It's.
It's a.
It was a fun experience.
We had a great God downtime at that
movie.
Did.
It didn't matter.
There was babies talking.
It didn't matter because that was,
that was the,
that was the experience that we signed
up for and I'll tell you what,
man,
Ilana dudes saying Shit and made the
movie better.
There was one scene with the do goes,
oh,
he running shit now.
And everybody started laughing.
Diane,
they started shyman in with their own
shit and the women were talking to each,
oh,
he'd be like this,
look at that.
Motherfucker was happy and it was just
back and forth and it went on for a few
seconds where as long as everybody
thought it was acceptable and then the
movie kept going,
but it was.
They made the movie louder.
The movie was really loud and I was
wondering like,
I wonder,
they may get loud because people talk in
the movie theater a wonder because it
was loud as fuck,
but it was such an action movie that
there's not a lot of moments in that
movie that where there's like,
you need quiet,
you know,
the movies are good goddamn movie man.
They did it good.
Like I was wondering,
you know,
it was like,
well I bet the CGI will be cool,
but maybe it would be corny.
Like I didn't like cowboys and aliens.
I went to see cowboys and aliens and it
was good.
It was a good movie.
I mean I didn't hate it,
but it was like kind of all over the
road and I'm a huge fan of Jon favreau
and I thought that Ironman was fucking
awesome and I just love him.
Anyway,
I love him from swingers and I've met
him a couple times and he's super cool.
So it was really looking forward to it
and I,
I love a good alien movie and I love a
good cowboy movie.
I'm like,
this is going to be perfect.
So I was kind of expecting that that
planet of the apes would kind of be
like,
that sorta was probably a lot like that
level.
No way,
dude.
It was a strong nine strong,
nine out of 10.
The fucking.
First of all,
you realize how pathetic and fleshy
human beings are when you see like
[inaudible] they,
they dead.
These chimps,
super realistic.
You know,
and you think of like a super athlete,
like a Ray Lewis,
you know,
like,
think like a brock Lesnar,
like the biggest,
strongest super athlete,
human.
And you'd look at what like a hundred
and 50 pound chimp does in this movie.
She has run shit,
throws things around.
Like the way he handles people was so
realistic.
It was really,
it was really fucking well done,
man.
The CGI you're watching it,
you could still come to town that it's
not really a champ,
but only in the face.
Only like the ways face moves for the
one that was like real human,
like just a little bit.
I mean I hair,
they're so close,
but the gorilla God damn the gorilla
looks good.
There's some scenes where this gorilla
shows up,
the gorilla just run shit,
but I don't want to tell you anymore.
I can't tell you anything.
No spoilers,
but just the way they did it,
they'll fucking the way they're able to
have these artificial things interact
with what looks like a real physical
environment like this,
jump this gorilla smashing things and it
looks real as fuck,
man.
It looks real as fuck,
but you're getting a a gorilla to do
some shit you could never get a real
gorilla to do.
You couldn't get a real gorilla that act
exactly the way you want it,
but that's what it looks like.
It's going to be crazy as in five years
when you rewatch that movie,
it's gonna look shit like shit like
going to see I am legend.
That stupid scene where the lions walk
out like as fake gas line.
It ruins the whole movie for me.
Like I think they shouldn't have had
that scene because that line looks so
stupid.
Like I can't believe they accepted that
stupid looking fake line.
This is not like that.
This is way better than that.
This is the next level.
This is next level shit.
It's a good plot to.
It's well made.
It's well directed.
It keeps you fucking captivated.
It's a perfect summer movie.
Best summer movie next to red state.
I went to see red state last week.
I went to Kevin Smith,
invited me to go to a screening and I
sat right next to mark Marin,
which is another of kiss.
We did.
We hugged,
we did dog.
We made up.
He actually apologized because uh,
you know,
I talked about on the podcast.
He's so fucking negative.
I'm like,
why you say you know,
what the fuck man.
And that we went over some shit on the
podcast.
He totally copped to it.
And so you're right,
I apologize,
I'm sorry.
And we were cool like right away and he
looked really happy too,
is with this really pretty girl.
His girlfriend girls real pretty and
he's doing real good now.
Just got back from Chicago.
He's telling me sold out these shows.
So he felt like real good.
So he felt good.
He looked good and you know,
it's like people just need some,
some success.
They just need some happiness in their
life,
you know,
now he's got a girlfriend and she's
really pretty and she seemed really nice
and obviously love each other together.
All Nice.
So it's like good,
good love.
So you got some love now and now you
want to give the love back?
Yeah.
Terrific.
Anyway,
redstate is fucking bad ass.
Kevin Smith made this movie,
right?
He didn't tell me Shit about it.
You.
So dude,
I really want you to see this.
I know you'll dig it.
Okay.
I'm,
he's a real nice guy.
He's going to do.
He's doing the podcast next week.
It's super nice guy.
I did his podcast.
I love men.
And before I love the guy,
he's.
I love him.
His movies that I've seen there.
There are always these silly comedies,
you know,
so I'm expecting,
I'm going to go see a Kevin Smith movie.
It's going to be a silly comedy.
We get there.
It is this apocalyptic like cult,
this cult that believes that Jesus is
coming and that's what the movie's all
about.
And how they interact with a bunch of
people.
I don't want to tell you anymore about
it,
but it's about this religious fanatic.
It's like basically it's basically a
horror movie,
you know,
it seems like it's kind of like,
it's an action movie,
but it's really like a horror movie.
And God damn is it good.
I mean,
is one of the best movies I've seen in
fucking years better even than planet of
the apes as good as I said,
of the aim.
Redstate is slightly better.
It's good.
Stephen Root.
Rude,
isn't it?
Stephen Root is fucking bad ass in this
movie,
man.
And the dude who plays the,
um,
the dude who plays the,
uh,
the guy,
um,
I don't want the fuck is his name.
The dude who plays the,
um,
there's a guy who plays the um,
John Goodman's in it too.
I don't know who the other guys they're
appointed in the movie where John
Goodman and goes,
no.
Michael Parks,
that's the guy's name.
Who plays the,
uh,
the,
the bad guy.
Fuck,
is this guy good?
I mean,
he's,
he's a guy who's been around a long ass
time.
Apparently it's got some crazy ass
stories,
um,
about dudes trying to kill him.
John John hurt is that guy's name stamp.
Kevin's friends was telling me,
he was like,
y'all got to tell you the whole story
later.
But this guy is famous actor,
like literally tried to kill this dude
twice,
but this guy plays the.
He plays the preacher in this movie.
God Damn,
that's good.
John Goodman's in it.
God Damn is he good?
There's no soundtrack to this movie.
So during the movie,
what I loved about it,
one of the things I love,
I hate when a movie gives me.
I mean,
I loved the planet of the Apes.
Don't get me wrong,
it's a well packaged,
entertaining vehicle.
It's good,
but I don't like when a movie plays me
some fucking music and tells me how I'm
supposed to think.
I don't,
that's,
that's retarded to me.
I've never enjoyed it.
I'll tolerate it,
you know.
But I always feel relieved when a movie
doesn't have any music,
you know?
I don't need like the,
they start kissing and fucking violence
play,
get the fuck outta here.
Obviously there's good examples and bad
examples,
but there's definitely some movies that
the soundtrack is 90 percent of the
movie [inaudible] I disagree.
I don't like it.
I don't mind it all and that's different
man.
You're talking about.
It's like some music with songs and
singing and shit.
I like to.
I don't mind when I hear led Zeppelin
houses of the holy.
I know it's 74.
That's.
I don't mind,
but I don't like what you're saying when
you hear music to people dressing and
them telling you.
You know what I'm saying?
In the time period I said it wrong
because it's not that I don't like
soundtracks because I do in goodfellas.
I like it when it's done the right way.
That's what I'm saying.
He accepted up as a boogie nights.
I don't mind that your book,
like you remember when the rolling
stones or plan and he's coked up and
he's got a bag full of guns in the trunk
and he's driving around in that movie.
It works.
What I mean more is the werewolf is
running through the woods and you hear
the fuck out of here with that.
Stupid Shit that drives me nuts.
I told them,
there's no music in this movie,
man.
This music is.
This movie is brilliant.
It's kept you and Kevin Smith describes
it as his talking dog movie.
He's like,
because if a dog started talking,
he'd be like,
what the fuck?
And he goes,
that's exactly what this movie is like.
You don't expect it from Kevin Smith.
Did you see an early cut of it that they
know it's done.
It's done.
The movie's done.
Kevin did it all himself.
He's going to release it all himself.
He did it all himself.
No,
no one else had any involvement in it.
And that's the brilliant.
The brilliance of this movie.
He didn't,
you know,
he was gonna do a mass release of it,
but I guess it was just too expensive.
So he's going to release it in a limited
way just so that it's,
it's,
um,
uh,
eligible for the Oscars and then they're
going to do it video on demand I think
in September.
And you know,
you can get it on DVD and all that shit.
I'm sorry.
It was a really weird thing,
Joe Rogan,
that you mentioned that I have to stick
up for this for the seventies timepiece
though,
when we watch a movie and it trump
seventies now,
it's unbearable to watch,
but if you really.
Not always though,
except for the Godfather,
there's a bunch of movies that are still
good,
like a hard time.
You could watch maybe if it's not 11:00
ever see friends of Eddie coyle.
Tremendous.
This fucking movie.
I got turned onto that bike.
Anthony.
I'm Anthony Bourdain.
No reservations.
Well,
if I showed you a bother you when I saw
bad ass move,
I just wanted and I thought fuck it.
Movie Theater.
I just went about a month ago.
They had it for.
I like movie.
I always go to the dog or where's this
place?
The place in beverly.
Beverly.
I go there when you can't find me.
I'm at the bellboy for five bucks,
Bro.
I ain't got time to waste with people no
more.
I go to the back.
All those memories.
I want to see him on the big screen.
Yeah,
the friends.
Eddie quote,
look at the cast in.
They're great.
What's the name of the storming that,
bro.
How bad is it?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
What's his name was Eddie coils name
that guy to me.
He reminds me for some reason.
Got a laugh.
He just like a brock Lesnar,
but the way he talks to people,
Bro,
the way he would talk to people in the
Robert Mitchum the fuck the size of his
hands.
Have you seen the dude that's a big
motherfucking country bumpkin that.
But you want me to tell you something
about the seventies.
Tell me something about the seven years
old.
Better movies came out and in the
seventies really let's get down every
which way,
but loose.
No,
let's just talk about the excesses
because father,
let's just talk about planet of the apes
because Bro,
let's get down to first.
I came from I what?
Rocky.
I came from Cuba and the first movie,
one of the first one was I went to see
was beneath the planet of the apes.
At the time I lived on 88th street and
Broadway.
Fuck.
All these motherfuckers.
If you look beneath the planet of the
apes,
they were under the subway systems
really in New York City.
Look at beneath.
You got to start from scratch.
Dawn,
you're not going to send me the planet x
unless you start from scratch.
I don't have to sell it to fucking
awesome.
You don't remember the part where you
can torture yourself by not going to say
I'm going to go see it,
but what I'm trying to say to you is you
have to watch that again.
I've seen it.
I just haven't seen in years.
You got to check yourself.
That's all.
I'm [inaudible] 70,
19,
70.
When they put their mask off,
I came home and I remember telling my
mom,
these apes live under the fucking
subway.
Like they sold me on it.
It's all through New York number.
They get by the Statue of Liberty
member.
That shot did flux.
CGI,
CGI.
The Statue of Liberty backed over.
And then what's the blond guy number?
The first one with the girl.
Come on guy.
What's the fruit?
The gap.
Get the girl out,
a hot girl that couldn't even fucking
clock and he was running Jane Fonda.
No,
no.
The first one killed it.
It was 1970.
Everybody's mad at over Vietnam.
Still rose to planet of the apes.
Raquel Welsh.
No baby.
I don't think so.
First Raquel was.
We wouldn't be it right now.
Is the frozen right now.
Everybody would've been jerking off the
depths.
You 1968.
What was the original chicken?
That chicken that couldn't.
Kim Hunter,
Bro.
I don't know what it was.
But next time you get a minute,
just watch the first two again.
Get really.
You're giving me the gimbal.
Ever see that movie?
I returned to the valley of the dolls
are.
What the fuck is wrong with that movie?
Is that Jane Fonda?
Was that?
No,
it wasn't Jane Fonda.
It was written by Roger Ebert.
Ebro.
Yes.
You fucking did it.
I sat there and seriously tried to
follow that movie.
That makes zero sense.
Hunter was one of the monkeys.
It's Linda Harrison.
She's the bad ass bitch.
Oh God damn.
Is She hot?
You got to watch the first two,
bro.
I'm sorry,
the Heston is a bad motherfucker too,
and he's like 50.
Did you know Robert Herbert wrote a
movie
and it's one of those stories so bad in
the whole entire was.
Of course it is and that's why he's a
critic.
Listen,
I've always said this.
I've met some good critics.
I met some cool people who are fans of
movies and there's no hard fast rule to
anything.
There's a lot of people like Doug Benson
might as well be a critic.
He's a huge movie,
but he's still a very good comic,
but he's a.
he's a huge movie,
but he might as well be a critic,
but most critics are critics because
they got nothing to contribute.
That's why they don't want to be
critics.
They really want to.
They want to be writers.
They want to be screenwriters.
You want to be authors.
They don't have anything to say.
I don't believe critics.
Anyway,
sometimes it wrong.
God,
I thought I saw Doug Benson said that he
hated that the new planet of the apes
movie didn't fun at the CGI.
Everything.
Let me just start with that.
For the Dragon,
which is one of the greatest martial
arts films,
all those seven of these movies,
all those clint eastwood movies,
all those jobs,
Bronson movies that were stealing from
today that we're remaking all those
westerns.
Westerns were in the seventies.
So the time piece was fucking brilliant
that the thinking was brilliant.
It's not these momos knowledge.
Just remaking shit.
What is the clinics would movie where he
plays a ghost to comes back to town.
It fucks everybody.
Puts the shield on at the end and they
can shoot the body because the people
don't shoot the head.
So every time they shoot the body he
fall down and get back up.
No.
Yeah,
that's the one.
He's a western.
Yeah.
So they think he's dead.
No,
no,
no.
Dad came back to town to kill everybody.
Oh my God.
Which one is that?
He came back to town to kill the whole
10.
They whipped him to death and he came
back and he was raping bitches.
Dude,
he raped this one chick and it's really
kind of crazy.
Like the way they show it,
it was a real super realistic pitch in
every movie.
He always told them what time it was.
He raped her and he,
he like,
he only fucked her for like four pumps
and I watched it with my friend John
wants my friend John in New York and he
goes,
see that's how we're supposed to fuck.
We're not supposed to fuck a girl for an
hour and make her come.
You're supposed to just fuck four times
and shoot your low because that's what
feels good.
And I was like,
Whoa,
how crazy are you
dude?
I am not Doug Benson at some other
comic.
And I was really surprised because he
was the only person I saw that,
that didn't like that movie.
Everyone was talking
high plains drifter.
It's a bad motherfucker right there too.
That's what it is.
That's the one when they whip them.
You're right.
You're absolutely right.
I Bro,
you know,
I got so many of those classics and
that's not in the high plains.
Drifter is another one.
God Damn it.
What the fuck is the movie driving me
nuts,
Ramos?
Shit,
I can't.
It's Rick Grandma,
so master of Queens.
Really,
so one of us would have people would let
us know this for the good,
the bad,
the ugly for a few dollars more.
A fistful of dollars in high plains
drifter.
It's got to be one of those.
Maybe this high plains drifter.
What's the one?
What he paints the town red paint the
town white.
That's it.
The paint.
The town red.
When was the last time somebody painting
the town red in the last 20 years and
you've seen the movie?
Nobody.
That was the original idea.
Ever paint this fucking.
What did he call the town to help?
Yeah.
I'm.
This isn't.
This is not the movie because in this
one it says a stranger rides out of the
hot desert into a small town in the wild
west towns.
People are scared of him and three
gunmen try unsuccessfully to kill him.
He takes her room and decides,
Oh yes,
yes,
yes.
Yeah.
This just weird.
Veered into a summary and they kill
them.
M One m one will they shoot them and the
people that shot him only shoot the body
that don't shoot.
The head isn't hanging high,
so he fucking gets a shield and he
builds a shield and he puts on his chest
and then when he approaches the people
they would shoot at him,
but he was thinking,
I think confusing movies.
Yeah,
we're confusing.
All of them were confusing movies.
Just go home and put on tonight.
I
got them all on my own.
I have a great movie for you guys.
Both the watch.
It's a documentary,
a tiff,
tiffany stockers.
Have you heard of it?
It's called.
I think we're alone now.
It follows two guys that are a stock
stockers of tiffany current stock or
current stockers and one of them was the
stalker like like 20 years ago or 15
years ago when she,
when she was really young and stuff and
one guy is a transsexual or transgender
guidance deal going through being
becoming a woman and the other guy they
both have ass Berger's disease or
whatever it's called and it's just like
in the autism spectrum.
Is that what that is?
Yeah.
It's like they're super,
super smart,
but they can't shut up about it,
you know,
like I can't stop talking about it and
obsessing about whatever it is.
Coke,
smart people and smart people on Coke.
But it is so interesting and the fact
that they're both are backup like they
were both like,
oh yeah,
if I would never be able to marry her,
but I,
Alyssa Milano on the other hand and both
of them had like a backup.
Alyssa Milano.
Yeah.
And it's so weird.
It's on Netflix streaming.
I,
they all love Tiffany,
but they couldn't marry her but they can
marry Alyssa.
Alyssa Milano was or more realistic girl
that they both were obsessed about it.
It's more realistic.
Tiffany.
Yeah.
Tiffany is married now or something and
they went through.
I have no idea.
Yeah,
well I don't know,
but it's good.
So it's called,
what is it called?
Very creepy and very fun to watch.
It's called.
I think we're alone now.
She's running after it was over.
There's another movie all about Dolly
Parton stockers,
I forget the name of it,
but there's five Dolly Parton stockers
and I will watch that too.
And it's also good.
So tiffany at the other one's about
Dolly Parton too.
So,
um,
high plains drifter is the movie that is
the more it comes back as a ghost and he
kills everybody.
They killed him.
They whipped him to death that I was in
the seventies of all time.
Can't even fuck with it.
Warriors fucking.
You can't even fuck with it.
The list goes on.
Can't even fuck with it.
Fuck box office.
I'm talking about creativity.
Yeah.
There was.
Once you know,
the getaway with McQueen was out.
All the Charles Bronson,
great ones we've done in the seventies.
All those movies were original.
These dumb fucks to the edges.
We making shit.
He's Momos with their fucking things are
going to see it go from shale writer.
I wouldn't go see none of that shit
gone.
I don't go.
None of that shit.
Any of these movies that come up,
nothing.
Not that I'm going to go see planet of
the apes because I'm a planet of the
apes guys since 1970.
I'm going to go give it a chance.
But besides that,
the all of these movies,
I wipe my ass with them.
All of them.
Well,
I think something that was going on in
the seventies,
same was going on with music.
You know,
I've been on this lennon skinner kick
for the last month,
or I listened to Leonard scanner like
every fucking day.
I'm in my cd right now.
Every most,
every day since I bought that CD.
I've been breweries.
It's brilliant.
And the story of what they do.
Don't,
don't ever Mark Leonard Skinner.
You Suck fucking weezer.
Listen,
this is garbage.
It wasn't just say music today is so
fucking bad for the fucking black keys
and fucking the foo fighters and later
everybody else could suck my dick
because it's garbage.
It all sounds the same.
Fucking black keys.
Throw that on.
They got a video of them motherfuckers
playing at Tennessee at a fucking record
store.
Go ahead and put it on airplane.
A fucking drum that's town.
The foo fighters,
everything else,
all these kids send me these videos.
I look at these guys redoing black
Sabbath.
You can't redo black sabbath.
Bitch can't redo black sabbath.
They'll oasis to always just suck my
dick dog.
They ain't the fucking racists they can
do.
Did Black Sabbath,
whatever the fuck it is,
they can't touch what's going on.
What we grew up with,
garbage with.
The black keys are as real music
musicians.
That's where the real music.
Now the music industry is dying and they
could blame it all they wanted to be.
Nobody wants to go see these people live
in your magical.
I love Rihanna,
but it's 45 minutes of dead time.
If you go see Rehab,
please don't stop the music and the
others song just standing there watching
somebody sing over a fucking music.
There's no instruments on stage and
that's half of these shows.
Well,
it's also recession,
man.
It's hard to sell tickets.
Music is music where the eagles play
last year for 3:50
place was sold into the three nights.
Fuck the recession.
Music is music statuette all these old
time.
Is it coming back?
Because the new kids can't perform live.
Really?
Go look at your schedules.
Everybody's back.
Even Steve Miller's,
his grandson came.
You could go on stage and say you're
Steve Miller and no one would know the
difference.
So nobody knows who steve fly like an
eagle browse genius.
Jungle.
Love jungle.
Listen to the fuck that motherfucking
Steve Miller had to do the what?
Oh yeah.
Why tucked that?
Not More?
Yeah,
he was genius man.
Steve Miller is the only guy who made it
famous,
made huge hits,
and he just never got fucking picture.
Why would you?
I know there's pictures of her,
but you know what Mick Jagger looks
like,
man.
It's unmistakable.
Mick Jagger walks into a restaurant.
You fucking go,
Oh shit.
Mick Jagger's here.
Steve Miller can go to target and his
underwear and no one knows that's true,
right?
That's weird.
What the fuck was going on in the
seventies that led to this big creative
explosion?
I mean the sixties and the seventies and
good acid.
No bullshit asset.
You had a brilliant bullshit when you're
reading and music outdoors here.
Whenever the fuck they on what you can't
use,
your eating laxatives and was a cough
drops because it was pure.
The people were pure little less time to
fucking take off their mind.
We have all this garbage that take up
our mind to creativity was more listened
to and everybody was great from Jimi
Hendrix's shit.
Jimmy Hendrix pulled out,
listen to the cutting edge shit.
Fucking Leonard Skinner put and I was
cutting edge.
There were,
let's face it,
let's get down to.
Basically they were fucking rednecks guy
from Florida.
Yeah.
You want me to some other rednecks.
Put the allman brothers.
Not put all of those bands on.
These guys had nothing to lose.
They had nothing to lose,
Bro.
Joe,
you know what you need to do.
You need to do an info commercial for
one of those cds like the songs that are
seventies.
Fuck.
You need a lesson?
Two,
hands down.
It's hands down.
It doesn't even compare.
You can't even compare.
You haven't heard.
I haven't heard what lady Yankee Yankee
albums.
They can't cut the spread bro.
They can't do it.
Look at the whole 90 fucking albums,
led Zeppelin,
pink floyd,
put out four albums in a role that most
bands could never even release.
Flood Piper and the gates of dawn and
all that noise.
What is that?
Just that's their first time,
which just freaky things.
People hidden cow bells and shit.
They go for acid heads and that shit was
great.
Listen,
go,
hit yourself in the head with a fucking
habit.
Wasn't glue but metal,
dark side of the moon,
animals but war.
It's something that no abandons ever
come out with five items in a row like
how beautiful his dark side of the moon
to where every song flows into the next
flows and it saying that to do asset to
that.
He's the prettiest thing in the world
because pink floyd did something that
nobody else did.
They tap into your soul when you do
acid,
if you listen to all the music and
always has the boom,
boom,
go book.
I got molested.
The comfortably Numb,
but really?
Yeah,
but it's 21 year old girl lived up the
street.
You got molested a girl also.
I was 13.
She was 21,
she was in town slut,
she molested everybody on that.
She didn't do much,
just kinda grabbed my dick,
but it was like,
Whoa,
that's just the.
But it was crazy because she had like A.
I think I've told this story before.
She had a grown man who was a boyfriend.
He had hair on his chest and shit.
I was a little boy.
I was 13,
but this girl was all kinds of fucked
up.
But she turned me onto a lot of
seventies music man.
This crazy bitch was into.
She was into Zeplin.
She turned me on to black dog and she
turned me onto a comfortably numb,
not like pink floyd passage shit.
That's what they were doing.
Everything that everybody talked about.
All these people that wrote books on
acid,
they did it through music,
which everybody could suck my dick.
That's globally.
We're talking about drugs and
psychedelics.
This is a great story about,
um,
Roger Waters in rolling stone that I
read.
He was on the cover because you know,
he's making a comeback.
Yep.
Yo.
Fuck
that.
And then backed off and watch what
happens next.
You see if there's a recession,
so that if they charged 3:50
without David Gilmore,
that's going to be a $500 ticket
Gilmore,
and let's see if there's a recession for
them.
DNC,
about that record.
Sales of the recession.
There's no recession for good.
That's 30 years,
but war was a masterpiece 30 fucking one
years ago.
It's like doing your rack 31 years and
never writing a joke.
Well,
they hit,
they hit a high.
That is almost like a level of
perfection.
Perfection like that song time.
Perfect Shit.
It was just on and on my way up here.
Take the makeup in the world.
It's about the four people live in the
world.
Sheep,
pigs and fucking bugs.
That's it.
That's what we are.
Sheep,
the pigs or the politician and the dogs.
The motherfucker that sling Dick,
the rest of them are fucking sheet and
they got three types of sheep.
And that's the name.
That's what the album is about.
It's three types of sheep for fucking
sheet.
People think everything's cool and oh,
Lou Reed,
three types.
One of these done.
Uh,
I did that walk on the wild side
already,
five fucking yellow and Lou Reed is good
for pretending your pool if you like,
literally a cool Blue Ridge and Inga
Rafa law,
you know cousins?
Yeah,
he lives in the East village man.
Walked round with a leather jacket or a
leather jacket and smokes camels 30
fucking years.
And I'll tell you what,
that one song is,
walk on the wild side a bad.
You know what?
But tomorrow when I leave here tonight,
I want you to go on youtube and just
press Lou Reed knows it and I want you
to hit three songs with Lou Reed and
call me.
Somebody tried to convince me that iggy
pop was really good.
You got to listen to achy problems with
the stooges and he plays.
He sends me this link.
So I go and click on this link and
listen to this fucking song.
I'm like,
this is so uncoordinated.
It's all over the place.
I mean maybe if you were a big ass iggy
pop fan already,
maybe if you liked it already and he got
into this style of.
But then I get that way about like some
music that people go nuts for like the
dead.
I don't understand the data.
It doesn't.
A few of their songs are I think are
really good,
but a lot of it just doesn't ring with
me and I think it's like a frequency
that I'm just not tuned into that other
people are.
I went to see him and they run with me
until I smelled those motherfuckers,
the smell of those filthy fucking
animals.
And I looked in boulder,
which collaborate those they were
everywhere when I left being an army
brat and hair and asked like some people
just don't want to pay.
But the deadheads it was like ass and
feet and fucking Brett and ears.
Who has stinky fucking is besides the
German shepherd.
Those fucking dead heads.
I think he is.
I want to see the data you smell in
there.
I've been with.
Next time you had a concert at red
rocks.
I went to see the dead Santana and
public enemy.
Oh God.
That was scheduled dead Santana and
public enemy of black people with guns
and a bunch of stinky people with no
fucking soap and somebody actually shot
a gun at the fucking constantly.
Benefits were crazy.
Holy Santana came on and did a black
magic woman dog and it was little off
even that.
Even that.
Listen to the abraxis.
Get yourself the first or the second
Santana job.
Listen to that brilliance.
This fucking Mexican kid cook took a
guitar and trying to fucking rock music
and he mixed it with Spanish music and
those first two albums are brilliant.
Oh yeah,
go bovine fucking black magic woman is
what the fuck happened.
That one dude that made that really
successful song with him recently,
like within the last 10 years,
just the underdog or what is that song?
That's Rob Thomas from matchbox 20 where
what happened to the fucking sing a
great fucking writer.
I mean that dude is bad.
That dude made all those songs,
wrote songs for a bunch of people and I
think matchbox broke up and then he went
and did that song with Santana.
I think matchbox put another house.
He put a pretty nice.
It wasn't a bad single lab,
you know that song,
that song was Santana?
No,
goddamn.
It's one of those songs where it's like
the perfect harmony of his voice and
Santana and [inaudible].
Santana was one of those dudes that he
put out a Santana song and I had to
figure this out when I was a kid and I
was like,
wait,
this is a different dude singing.
Every time it was like,
I don't get it,
and then I realized,
oh,
it's not even a bad.
He's such a bad motherfucker.
It's not even about the singer.
It's about the guitarist.
It said one dude Carlos Santana,
his shit is so tight and so bad ass that
who had no matter who the fuck is saying
it.
Yeah,
it's a Santana Song pitch you this the
vocals and the song itself almost plays
second fiddle to that God damn guitar.
Now what a amazing dude that guy is
because who the fuck else can claim
that?
There's like.
I guess there's a few other guys that do
that,
like,
like
be like a black wall was a back.
What's his name?
Dave?
Well,
they forget to fucking Jeff.
Jeff,
Jeff Beck.
Jeff Beck was another guitarist who can
put out songs that weren't really Jeff
Beck.
I mean it was,
it was called a Jeff Beck Song,
but it was just because of his.
He was an egotistical motherfucking
invaded that jam.
Would Rod Stewart early in the morning?
I can't sleep.
Remember down there.
That was a great factuation yeah,
it was him.
And then he canceled before the fucking
tour.
Once he left Rod Stewart go out there
alive without a guitar because he's an
ego maniac.
Oh really?
So he didn't want to deal with being
second fiddle.
The Rod Stewart Rod Stewart was too
fucking strong
back as a Greg Guitar.
But you can't fuck with Maggie May.
I saw Rob Stewart last night and um,
some,
it was,
some show that was at was like an
infomercial where they were advertising
some album,
a series of.
It was cds and dvds with all these.
I guess it was all dvds.
It was all musicians and comedians from
some midnight special show and Rod
Stewart was one of them.
The rocking on the rock when you were
out there looking like a lady.
He looks like a ugly lady.
He's in this little skinny guy in his
weird outfit and he's prancing around
stage in this weird way,
but his songs are so.
God damn good there is so soulful and he
had some fucking songs,
man.
Maggie May.
Yeah,
he's got an album called blind
infatuation was already when he was
starting to get weird.
He's got an album called blondes have
more fun.
Oh my God.
It's so hard.
They called.
You're insane.
It is fucking bad.
I listened to her once.
I got to find it on Youtube.
It's in that deep.
But Rod Stewart,
I went to see him.
I never see fuck.
Van Halen.
I seen them bitches sucking Dick.
Wrapped the show.
Rob Stewart got on stage.
There was two people made you want to
suck my Dick and that's rod stewart and
Kenny Rogers and do what?
The white head.
What we saw as soon as that
motherfuckers started singing lady,
but
that's such a unique voice,
such unique voice like vocally and like
the shit that he sang about,
like the way he would sing,
like they will kind of vulnerable songs,
but in a weird way like,
like Maggie may wake up,
Maggie,
I think I got something to say to you.
It's late September and I really should
be back in school.
Like what is this song?
Like,
what is it about?
It's like some guy was trying to find
himself,
you know,
steal my daddy's q and make a living out
of playing pool,
you know,
found myself or rock and roll band.
The needs a helping hand.
I mean like the songs were so weird and
unusual man.
Like his,
his,
just his stylistically the things that
he was into singing about,
you know,
he was a,
he was a bad motherfucker.
Really?
Meek voice.
Seeing your face bad.
Fuck God.
Damn.
That's a good song.
That's a song that's like,
it's still,
no matter where you are,
when that song comes on,
you're happy.
You know,
I will stay in my car until he,
I'm even if I'm in a rush until he say
steal my dad his q and make a living
that,
a plan.
Every time you're in a car and stuff,
I just got to sit.
I got to sit tight.
I don't care if I'm late,
I'll tell you.
I'll go to your house.
Dude.
I would've been here five minutes ago.
Fucking Maggie Mae was on and I'm,
you know,
I got out of respect.
I got to listen to that song.
There's a few songs is a few songs.
Call me the breeze,
call me the breeze comes on.
She is
cleaner.
Sisters,
jump shot like vocal trouble.
I like fucking all that crazy skiddish
shit.
They got another one on that album.
I got an inside that is just so fucking
cool.
You know?
I knew in high school when I was 14
years old,
when jump came out,
van Halen jump came out.
I knew there was something wrong with
using keyboards.
I knew back then like because everybody
was in the van Halen,
but I was in high school.
Okay.
When I was in high school in 1980,
one was my freshman year of high school
and my sister's boyfriend at the time
was this kid.
His name was jeff and he was John.
Yeah,
John Jewett,
sorry.
And he was really into van Halen to the
point where he's going to be mad at me.
Forgot his name.
Um,
hi dog.
And uh,
uh,
he was really into van Halen to the
point where he had it on his license
plate.
His license plate was van Halen.
I was car and everybody was in the van
Halen.
And then the new van Halen came out.
It was 1984.
That was the album,
right?
Wasn't it?
With jump.
The new album came out,
I remember in high school and
everybody's like,
oh,
the new van handles out.
It's awesome.
And I was like,
dude,
dude.
I'm like,
what the fuck is this?
Love that shit.
I remember thinking this is lacking in
Seoul.
What's lacking in sold jump?
That's on jump as well.
Job.
That song,
that keyboard,
that electronic keyboard manner that is
not as good.
You hear running with the devil,
you know,
hot for teacher,
you know those are.
Those are real songs.
But geometry.
What,
what song is being streets on?
Oh Shit.
Oh God damn means treats is good.
When that album came out,
when the boom boxes were becoming
popular member,
everyone had to move their shoulders,
stereo boom boxes.
And that song was one of the first songs
I remember hearing.
And just awesome stereo.
That seems so future.
Like eighties was like all about break
dancing and you know,
like the future and stuff like women and
children first.
No,
that was the second one.
Really.
So it's van Halen one.
Fair warning,
fair warning.
I got wanted log.
Strike that pool boy down.
They had some fucking jams.
We had some good fucking unchained.
Yeah.
Main streets.
Unchained.
Woo.
If this is love or hung out with David
Lee Roth at the comedy store once
videotaped.
Yeah,
he is cool.
But we had it.
We had to not release it because he
talked to a lot of shit about some
people.
He didn't want it released.
Um,
but uh,
he,
he actually,
they contacted you right the next day,
the next day his,
his fellow,
the guy who works for him contacted
Brian is like,
please,
please don't release that because David
Lee Roth,
just,
he's just a,
a free talker.
He just hangs around and starts talking
shit.
He was talking shit about girls.
He was talking shit about,
you know,
people in other bands and music that
sucks.
And guys who can't fucking,
he's like you.
And in a way,
Lisa,
he's got a little bit,
he can't carry the spread.
He's got a little bit of that in him.
But he was funny,
man.
He's a funny guy.
He's a real guy.
He had a real band and something
happened and they replaced them with
that fake fucking Sammy Hagar been open
for Sabic when they had deal.
People were spitting out of Philadelphia
in Philadelphia.
They were rolling,
just spit off their fingers.
They call it like whatever they do when
they throw it at you.
And I remember watching fucking singer
and spit flying by and he's trying to
duck and shit.
It was like,
I always did.
Did you,
did you like David Lee Roth when he did
his own solar stuff?
No.
David Lee Roth needed Eddie van Halen
and Eddie van Halen needed.
Look,
man,
the.
It's,
it's not just one person man.
It's fucking teams.
It's the creative juices of everybody
together.
That's the really interesting shit.
It's just hard to get that to work
because you got egos and then he got
Valerie Bertinelli who most likely
probably wanted to fuck David Lee Roth
but couldn't get them and got Eddie van
Halen instead and then shit got weird
and she was like,
why do you keep them around?
He's such an Egomaniac,
you know,
because she really wanted to fuck
David Lee Roth.
At least that's what I would assume.
But David Lee Roth was cool as fuck man.
He was one of the first guys that like,
I came up to me after the show and I was
actually nervous.
I was nervous to talk to the ugly raw
and when he was telling me I was funny,
you know,
like dude,
I fucking loved it.
That was great.
It was like,
I had no idea.
I thought you were just that fear factor
guy.
You're a fucking liar.
I'm like,
Holy Shit.
I'm talking to David Lee Roth,
like for me,
going back to Newton south high school
in 1983,
you know,
listening to the,
sitting out in the courtyard with
everybody listening on the cassette
player,
listening to fucking Van Halen,
and then all of a sudden I'm sitting
here,
just me and Eddie Bravo and Brian and
we're hanging out in front of the
Goddamn comedy store.
There's no one even surrounding them.
There's no moms of people were just
hanging out.
He just showed up unannounced on like
some random Tuesday or Wednesday or
something like that.
Hung out in the back of the,
paid for his fucking ticket,
hung out in the back of the club like a
normal person and then came out to give
me props and I'm sitting there talking
to David Lee Roth and I'm shell shocked.
I'm like,
I'm talking.
I can't even believe I'm talking to
David Lee Roth and we're talking about
my comedy.
I'm talking to David Lee Roth,
but how much he liked my set.
I'm like,
wow,
this is crazy.
This is bizarre.
And he was just a UCP,
but the store,
they're not looking for attention.
Yeah.
When you see somebody who's not looking
for attention,
like I seen Chris Cornell at the store
would not go Wednesday night.
I kept looking around this motherfucker.
I seen Dr Dre there a couple of times.
A couple times.
Yeah,
I slipped up.
We were there one night when he came in
with that chick black Michelle a go.
That's the one who was married to.
Right.
He was married to him,
but he came and not dating her,
but he came in with her like they were
out in the night and they all went up to
see Eddie Griffin.
I can't remember what her name was.
A cute little chick with black kid.
Just got a reality show now with all
black sisters really kind of looked the
same.
I got to think of her name.
She's a comic.
No,
no,
no.
She's a big time.
Big Time.
Second time black.
Okay.
Well,
I don't know who that would be,
but the comedy store was famous for that
because the comedy store,
even though it's run by retards,
it's,
it's a god Damn Hollywood landmark.
I mean,
that's spot.
First of all,
I would always be bad.
Just completely baffled that here.
I mean this is no recession going on and
this is,
you know,
the Hay Day of the,
the nineties and the early two thousands
and it's across the street from the
House of Blues and yet on a Friday
night,
there's nobody there on a Friday night.
There's fucking 50 people in the car.
Like,
this is criminal.
You guys have the greatest spot on the
planet earth.
Not only does it have the greatest name
and the history of comedy,
not only is it a place where Richard
Pryor film live at the fucking sunset
strip,
I mean,
this is,
uh,
an amazing place in history and yet
there's 50 people there on a Friday
night.
Like,
that's so fucked up it was.
But it's such a Hollywood icon that
people are always going to gravitate to
that spot just to peek in,
you know,
it's like,
it's what it is,
is basically las version of the comedy
cellar,
except it's not as good.
It's not run the same way.
It's not as like the comedy cellar in
New York is where all the top guys go
and fuck around and workout.
It's known and it's kind of like a
restaurant attached to it.
People eat there and shit.
And you know,
Jimmy Norton Rose wrote his fucking road
is booked there.
He brings a laptop and dudes are always
hanging out there.
So it's,
it's a real,
like a place where all the comics come.
But in la,
the comedy stores,
the closest thing you know,
it was like the closest icon place.
I mean the Improv is the best club in
town,
but the comedy store has the best name.
It's get the best feel to get the best
location,
you know,
even to the Long Beach Laugh factory.
That's was fucking awesome.
It wasn't really great.
Location is a really,
really nice.
What is the deal with that?
Can you go if you're not friends with Jo
Koy?
Nobody has.
No.
Uh,
oh,
that's right.
He left a job,
but he used to keep all the other
Filipinos out.
Right.
Oh,
the Asians.
He didn't want anybody making any Asian
jokes and he would work.
He wanted only,
only his Filipino jokes.
Did you watch the,
didn't it?
Louis show with Louis Ck.
I watched it on a line.
I've watched that segment.
It was more than one segment with Louis.
There was Dane Cook.
It starts off with Jim Martin.
Yeah.
I watched it is interesting.
It was like there's a little bit of
revisionist history there.
You know,
I think it was unscripted.
It almost seemed like real,
like it almost seemed like they actually
just sat down or like,
I think they worked it out.
I worked out the beats and then they,
they did it,
but I didn't like the arch I did.
I thought Danes argument was kind of
silly.
Like why didn't you stick up for me?
Like why didn't you didn't say that I
didn't steal from you,
like,
you know,
like I've never stolen.
Why would I steal a joke?
I never told a joke ever.
Like the argument was like really
strange,
you know?
Yeah.
I guess if you really think Dane Cook
was guilty,
then yeah,
there was one of the jokes.
I don't know if Dane Cook was guilty,
but I do know he saw Louis Ck do those
jokes before he did them and that's
enough.
That's all it is.
All three of them are on the same seat
and Louis did those in front of him and
he did it in front of everybody he did
in front of all of us.
It's not.
Look Louis Ck is the most prolific guy
working today.
He puts out a new hour every year,
but back then he didn't.
Back then Louis was doing the same act
for a long fucking time.
So those bits.
The bit about the guy getting hit by a
car.
He did that bit for years.
She did it before the dude about a guy
getting hit by a car.
Steve Martin?
No,
no,
no.
Steve Martin did the naming the child
naming the child a crazy name.
I thought he got the wrong bit.
Really?
Yeah,
I thought I hit by a car too,
about what you're trying to say
something to them really well or
something like that.
Really.
I think you're wrong,
but I'm pretty sure I'm pretty sure
you're wrong.
I'm pretty sure the Steve Martin joke
that,
and this is true that Steve Martin came
up with a um,
a bit that's really similar to both
Danes bit and Louis Ck is bid that if I
have a kid I'm going to name them some
crazy name.
It's unpronounceable,
you know,
this is being silly.
Like that's not,
that's not stealing.
I mean,
I mean obviously those guys,
you know,
it's kind of stealing.
Look if those guys had heard Steve
Martin and forgot about it and then
reintroduce the joke,
you know,
like I didn't realize that they had a
like,
like just forgotten it,
but you've got to stop doing it once you
hear it about Steve Martin's bit.
But the difference is Louis was doing it
in front of Dane.
So whether or not Dane is a joke thief
that,
you know,
look,
I liked Dane.
I think he's a talented guy.
I think he's a great marketer and I
think he's a good person.
I really do.
But I also think he's wildly ambitious,
you know,
and I think that sometimes when you're
wildly ambitious you don't even realize
what you're doing and you're doing it.
You don't mean to do it,
but you start doing it and those bits
work and then you don't want to let them
go.
And even though someone's like,
hey man,
that sounds like Joe Diaz was bit.
You don't want to let them go because
they are weapons and you use them and
use them to get what you want,
which is you want love,
you want that love and adulation.
You want to be killing up there and you
get addicted to it and you can't let it
go.
And if he's addicted to,
if he's guilty of anything,
he's guilty of that.
So that's why I thought it was the
argument was weird.
I was like,
man,
you guys are like,
you know,
it's weird.
But I liked how Louis such a good dude,
man,
you know,
like even his whole way he's approaching
it like I didn't like what people were
saying about you and I didn't like that
people were getting mad at you.
And I was like,
wow.
Like he's,
he's just,
uh,
you know,
one of the reasons why he's doing so
well is that he's his,
his,
like the way he thinks is a good way to
think he's a good guy.
Yeah.
He sticks to his fucking.
He's not like these other folks that we
have around 24 fucking hours a day that
I've seen Louis.
He came up to me with the comedy store.
I used to host on Sunday nights and he
would come up and do a set every night.
Very polite.
One night he came up to me,
he goes,
are you available next week,
Bro?
And I go,
yeah.
And he goes,
I'm going to put them on,
put you on my show.
He took my name and number or like,
whatnot,
not good at grammar coke and never
thought anything of it.
Later he called me.
He paid me more than anybody else has
ever paid me,
and he took care of me.
They had me there for the weekend.
He came with his word.
So because of that I give him my loyalty
forever because he's one of the few of
the.
All of these fucking weak motherfuckers
we got around this.
That sticks to his fucking word.
He's a real.
His real not give them props.
I don't give them none of these fucking
Beasley motherfucking prompts,
but Louis deserves my heart because he
put me on television without every
expecting anything from me.
And he just told me he was like put me
on.
Two days later they called and I respect
that to the.
Especially like I said,
with these fucking much we have around
us as a comedian.
He's the most inspirational guy to me
and I think to everybody because he's
the most prolific,
like you can argue over who makes you
laugh the most because I always say,
you make me laugh the most.
You're you're favorite guy to watch.
You know,
and I think there's,
there's some moments.
The moment when we were hanging out at
the Improv and you're on stage,
we were doing the weekend there and you
did that fucking bit about about dead
Dick,
about you don't accept dead Dick and
you've made it up on the fly.
He goes,
you take two popsicle sticks and you tie
that pick up and
back in like a wounded soldier and when
you sit,
when you say,
when you said it,
you,
I knew you ad libbed it because I know
you're,
I know you're act by heart and you knew
you had lived it and it fucking destroy
you or beat red in the face laughing at
your own shit,
but you want me to do and me and ran
should fear in the back of the room and
we just go.
He's the best.
Nobody makes me laugh harder than you,
but Louis Ck is more prolific.
He's the most prolific,
cool conversations about standing up
with Louis or my act and my life has
changed.
I'm telling you this right off the bat,
I believe it.
I had to.
I think he's changing the way a lot of
comics do it and he's making guys write
more.
What was the conversation that you had
with them?
I had a conversation about storytelling
and about jokes and he said that he had
watched me and that,
uh,
the material was a little fucking crazy,
but he loved that.
He respected it,
but he goes,
you have so much more to tell people.
He goes,
I want you to talk about what is dark to
you.
That's why I started talking about
mugging the hooker.
That's why I started talking about all
the crimes I had done outline and that's
why I'm writing them on stage.
Now you know what you need to talk about
onstage,
what brother you need to talk about
finding your dead mother when you were
high on acid.
How fucking craziest you gotta.
Tell them about that onstage,
bro.
That is.
But that's a show stopper.
I know Joe.
I got nowhere to go after you find your
dead mother on the floor.
Jesus can't follow you.
Jesus can't.
Fuck.
I tried it already.
You could end with it or you could end
with it.
And what about the rest of the fucking
show?
I got to let him eat in 20 minutes.
So bad,
you know,
it's like going up to somebody going,
hey bro,
how you doing it here?
We go up to somebody like by mistake and
go,
hey bro,
how you doing?
How's your brother?
He just died.
Yeah.
Boom.
Do you feel at a comedy?
Show it a one man show setting.
I could do it,
but at the comedy show I cannot do it.
It's too hard to recover from it.
What does that mean?
He just tried to change this act over
the weekend and Ontario and Katt
Williams.
Tell me what happened.
Uh,
he,
uh,
tried to do something different
supposedly like he tried to do more of a
serious,
uh,
kind of like one man shows where
California Improv Improv.
Yeah.
And then the audience,
which I knew he was there,
I wouldn't want to see him.
They wasn't having it.
And so they started like,
I guess booing or doing something like
that.
And then a cat starts screaming at him
or doing something.
And then the Ontario Improv.
So this is,
by the way,
all based off tmz a interior.
I've kicked them off stage and kicked
them out of the building and then he
wouldn't leave and so then they called
the police and the police had to take
them off the premises and they canceled
the whole weekend.
Well he's definitely crazy because he
keeps getting arrested and there's a lot
of shit going on with him.
He got caught with guns a couple times
and.
But he did a show recently in New Mexico
and a bunch of people wanted their money
back because he got on stage,
it shows a 9:00
show.
He didn't get on stage to like midnight
and he goes on stage,
the music stays on while he's on stage
and we use it stays on and he's,
he takes his shirt off and he starts
dancing and he's dancing around with a
shirt off.
Then he starts doing pushups and then he
starts talking to pushups,
doing pushups on stage with no shirt on.
And then he starts talking to people in
the audience.
So either he's just like trying to come
up with some new material and just going
deep into the crazy ben or he's really
legitimately losing his mind.
You know,
we said it before,
man.
We've said it so many times.
Brilliant people.
There's a lot of brilliant people that
are very close to insanity and I know
you've been close to and Saturday
because I've watched you be close to
Saturdays here.
Joey.
Joey's been close to.
Yeah,
that was normal for Joey.
That's pretty fucking normal.
I just have to wait for that storm to
end,
but.
No,
no,
I see.
I know.
You know what I mean?
I feel it at times.
I feel it when I get home writing out
your podcast,
I've got to force myself out of the
fucking house because of that.
That's why you go to into your head.
Yeah.
You don't want to be alone with your
head.
Sometimes.
There's moments where you need to
interact with other people just to get a
sense of normalcy.
Right?
When you add them to the point where
sometimes you're writing and you get
into it and you're,
you're there and all of a sudden you
fucking mind just go somewhere,
bro.
It just goes somewhere where it just
hasn't been in with standups.
I could see it.
I feel myself slipping.
I tell you,
I felt myself slipping a lot with the
cope when I was on stage when I was
talking to myself and I caught myself
with four to eight and that would catch
myself at eight.
Wait a second.
I was just at four a fuck that I get to
eight when I was talking about earlier
about Roger Waters.
Roger waters the article in rolling
stone.
One of the things he was talking about
his childhood,
his dad was in the military.
My Dad died when he was really young and
uh,
you know,
he grew up without.
There's photos of him and his dad and
all of sudden his dad's gone.
That whole,
that void.
You know,
there's something about loss and
childhood.
You know,
when you,
when you're young and fucked up,
things happens.
That creates like seemingly the most
brilliant people the most,
but they're also the most likely to do
something fucking crazy,
you know,
crazy like looking fucking look at
what's going on with Dave Chappelle here
with Dave Chappelle,
did the other dap and now he goes on
stage and for 45 fucking minutes it
tells one joke and then he says,
this is a test of wills,
you know,
I'm not gonna say nothing.
You know what I'm saying?
That Nita and like stays up there for 45
fucking minutes and know and you know,
and people like,
I just want,
I just want to be entertained.
We tell some jokes.
He's like,
you know,
go see,
go by my dvds,
you know,
you'll see you'll be entertained.
Like meanwhile he was just standing on
stage like saying nothing for 45
minutes.
And again,
this is a lot of hearsay to,
I don't know the exact story of what
happened,
but this is what I keep hearing.
And there was a,
another video of him going on stage at
some festival and he bombed there too
and he was doing the same thing.
Just standing on stage with no,
no,
no.
This is not this.
He's not doing anything gross.
Just standing on stage.
I don't know what happens to Comedians,
the comedians life and I could sit here
in the next 20 minutes and give you a
list of them that they think that they
go from becoming comedians to thinking
that I listen to what the fuck they're
saying.
Well,
that's it.
I was listening to his reading his
texts.
He was getting tax was on stage on
reading though.
He has this whole new thing,
style of comedy that he's doing.
I've seen it.
I've seen it twice.
My friend Demar seen it four times or
three times and what it is,
it looks very organic.
Like he starts off and he automatically
starts going and we talked about this,
but that's not what he's doing.
He was doing that.
That was not what they need to show.
What they're saying is he's not doing
anything but you're standing on stage.
Not Saying a word.
No.
He said he was talking.
He wasn't just sitting there ninth St.
Jude.
It this latest show that I am talking to
you about.
I'm not talking to show that you saw.
I'm saying the show that he did
recently.
He got on stage and he was talking about
how it was a battle of wills.
I'm not gonna say nothing and we'll see
how long we.
Last year he was gonna.
He was being quiet and he wanted them to
be quiet until.
Let's see who breaks first he said
nothing and people were losing their
mind like he.
He told one joke and then the rest of
the set he sat around and did nothing.
He.
There's a point with these fucking
comedians that they think that they go
from being a comic.
The social commentary,
like they did something to that I
deserved this social commentary and
that's what's really going on.
We've seen it with Eddie Griffin.
We see it with this fucking guy.
Now we see it with a bunch of comedians.
I see that I put on that button,
green room or whatever was just to watch
stand hope and I had to put up with your
buddy from Svu and Janine Garafalo.
The guy says to the fucking guy,
Richard Belzer,
you know a guy that never said nothing
funny this whole fucking life,
and he's asked Dan hope.
Why the fuck is he there?
But they're sitting in there,
not even stand open.
Why are you here?
And Stan hope goes because I came to see
the suck my dick fest.
Between you and Janine Garafalo.
Yeah.
And then he goes,
well,
a literally like trying to be cute.
You know,
like these fucking idiots in Hollywood
do like literally.
How about I get up and put my dick in
your mouth and prevents Matt just to
show you how we're going to do this
here.
Somewhere along the line these comics
think that we need their social
commentary and we fucking don't.
We fucking don't.
We don't give a fuck what you think.
Just tell us fucking jokes guy.
Just tell us jokes.
We don't give a fuck.
Nobody gives a fuck.
That's when a show goes sour because
nobody gives a fuck.
We paid to see you do an hour of
material.
If at the last two minutes you want to
summarize your set and do it,
do it,
but if you're going to summarize it with
bullshit that don't live by anyway,
shut your mouth and just do the fucking
jokes,
Bro.
That's my big problem lately.
Nobody wants to shut that fucking mouth
either.
Do the jokes to shut the fucking map.
What is all this chitter chatter about?
Stupidity for that day in that green
room.
I'm trying to watch stand hope.
One of the most brilliant comments,
a dear friend of mine,
I couldn't watch it.
Janeane Garofalo saying that the guy and
in Tucson that killed the fucking,
that tried to kill the congressman was
pushed to kill him because social media
force them.
First of all,
when she said that,
that's not what a comedian worries is.
She really says that.
What a career.
A real comedian doesn't worry about
that.
That's somebody who wants you to think
that they care.
So like me,
because I do care.
You don't care that it's fake tattoos.
You got to fake.
You know?
That's what they care about.
That's what we're talking about.
Whether it's a fad or whatever the fuck
it,
I can't deal with it no more want me to
make me feel,
make me funny,
make me laugh.
I would refuse to go on stage and give
you my opinion of the White House,
so the tea party,
because at the end of the week,
nomadic guy,
I paid to watch you do jokes.
I want you to take me through your
world,
but that's it.
I don't want to hear no social
commentary and we've seen it from a lot
of comedians,
bro.
After a 55 minute mark,
I think I got to listen to this shit.
Do your 55 minutes.
Well,
they also,
they've developed a following of people
who hang on every word and you know,
there's a lot of them that think they
have something brilliant to say and so
they choose the venue of standup comedy
and look,
this fucking podcast is a perfect
example of the.
A lot of times people have something to
say.
It's not necessarily funny,
but it's interesting,
but this is the right venue for it.
A podcast is the right venue for us.
This is not what I would ever do on
stage when I do,
when I do my set,
I have a fucking set I'll fuck around a
little bit,
but I'm trying to be funny period period
and that's because people used to always
think that like comedy should be used in
some way to like educate,
educate people in the light and people
and then it's important to do that.
And almost to the point of sacrificing
comedy.
Like,
you know,
Bill Hicks had some material that was
like that where it was not funny at all.
At the end.
Bill his wasn't funny.
Let's get out of the way at the end,
the Lance Williams garbage.
Listen to the live from the village
gate.
That's almost.
You could even hear the people like
ready to laugh and was like,
Oh God.
Well some of his stuff like he.
Yeah,
that was actually before the life in the
village gate one was earlier and what
that was like.
He did the bid on abortion and this is
what I'm talking about him.
He was like,
you know,
like you don't want people to abortion.
Then you fucking raise them,
you fucking raise them.
That's what he was yelling at.
You fucking raised the kids and there is
no joke and I'm like,
wow,
this is a mess.
This is a mess.
This is a comedy club.
Okay.
You just yelling out.
You fucking raise them and being irate.
Yes,
you're right.
I see your point.
If you don't want people to have
abortions,
then you should raise their children.
I see what you're saying that you should
get involved.
I see what you're saying,
but you're not being funny period.
That's not a joke.
You know,
and that's a thing that happens to a lot
of comics.
It's they,
they start to get people who want to
listen to them.
They start to get people who think
they're deep and they start listening to
those people and they do this at a
comedy club and they up at a comedy
club.
We've seen it happen.
We've seen it happen in so many titles.
I thought there was this fucking kid
from Jimmy's comedy.
Allah.
God Damn,
I forget his name,
but he's really.
He was really funny.
He was kind of crazy.
He was really funny and this was like in
the the late eighties,
early nineties,
and he came to Hollywood.
He drove to La and it was working at the
comedy store for awhile.
Do you remember the kid?
Kind of good looking guy,
but overweight.
Fucking forget his name.
It drives me nuts,
but he was a perfect example of that.
He would go on stage at the comedy
store.
They fucking tortured him.
They tortured him.
Can you go onstage and try to be like
deep and meaningful when he was funny,
he can be really funny.
Like you had some good bits.
I'm fucking good.
Bit about hair club for men.
It was really funny.
You know,
they show the guy playing tennis and
they show the guy swimming.
He goes,
what?
They should show a guy.
It's pulling out and shooting his
fucking load on some chicks back,
you know,
and she goes,
nice hair.
He had a fucking real good bit about
some good bits.
We went to the store one day.
I mean,
you know,
like when you go to an open mic and just
sit down.
Yeah,
we do that all the time.
Kid,
that window that was older and he goes,
let me give you a personal issue with my
Italian family portrait.
That would be bad.
We just die like this joke ever goes.
This was in my impersonation of my.
This is a portrait of my Italian family.
He was leaning for folks at home.
He had put his hands up like someone's
trying to take his picture,
but sometimes like I was telling
somebody that they're the best joke.
I heard that you off my fucking ever was
Charlie Hill at the store when you're
stoned talking to somebody and he's
back.
Then he goes,
how are you doing?
My name is Charlie Hill.
My real name was mountain,
but they shortened the dog.
I fucking lost my cookies at that dumb.
Just because you're high.
No,
but that Joe Rogan Milwaukee this
weekend I can the white patches theater,
blue ribbon be Athena because we're
going to have a good time.
The last time you went to Milwaukee was
with Chris Mcguire at that fair?
Yeah.
It wasn't really.
That was something we did summerfest I
went like a year before you and a year
after you.
Some fucking,
some guy that was there.
I remember going,
Oh,
you're too dirty to work my club.
I'd like to have you in my club or your
tutor the fuck fucking clubs.
Uh,
fuck it on.
What was the,
what's the clubs they have that they had
green bay,
funny bone at the time.
Had A,
the guy that that are really going to go
work up at the comedy skyline comedy
club,
which is at the other part of the Green
Bank.
One guy that was the other one that was
the gangsters,
the moguls with the biker gang.
He owns it.
He pays you with a gun on the table and
shit.
Really?
Come on.
Oh,
he puts a gun on a team when he pays his
staff as fucking double breasted suits
on Fridays and Saturdays.
You got wear a double breasted suits
guys,
a Hawaiian six foot six,
400 with a motorcycle.
It's Easter and now he's one of those
biker.
Whatever's up in Michigan and he's like
the treasurer.
He's got the fucking Porsche.
The whole thing,
and they fuck it on Saturdays,
they pay him,
the guy puts a gun on the thing,
but he's big motherfucker some all and
you know those big samoans and he's up
there anyway.
A lot of bitches coming there.
They suck your Dick and everything,
but I didn't like it.
I worked at one time and that was it.
But the fucking neighborhood.
I can't wait to get spaghetti and clam
sauce.
I can't wait to go to this place and can
really bought sandwich.
I can't fucking wait what?
Milwaukee.
Listen Bro,
let's get one of the first bitches I
ever robbed in Colorado was a named
chick named stacy corine who have.
Uncle was a big time gangster up there.
I never knew what they told me after it.
You know you robbed,
robbed.
I robbed her in Aspen.
Robert.
I broke into a fucking house and she had
1800 cash and a chunk of Hash.
Not This ally ship that these idiots are
smoking this shit.
That stat from the fucking emperor of
each stamped fucking gold stamp.
And you see that stamp on a piece of
Hash when somebody gives you a pizza ash
and you see that little rim with a
stamp,
your fucking smoking.
The good shit.
This shit,
they give you a Hollywood.
And what happens is,
is the thc that they just there to have
all that shit.
How do you make it at what,
uh,
what am I a fucking bakers knowing that
it comes from,
you know,
someone,
they just made a fucking law recently
where you can get life in jail for
fucking making hash.
I just read somewhere that it was just.
No,
it's not necessary.
There's a method to making it.
I don't know what the method is.
Jail for making fucking passed in some
stupid state.
So she was retaliation from whatever.
And she was a drug dealer.
That's why I robbed because she was a
drug that in Robert's decided because I
wanted to Robert,
but she used to always tell me that
there was great food in Milwaukee.
And I'm like,
are you fucking middle?
What are you going to do?
What do you eat?
Cheese with it.
Well,
this is another part of it that a lot of
people don't know with Donnie Brasco
busted all those people.
Half of the people he busted weren't in
New York.
They were in Milwaukee.
He busted this crew up there.
That was the ballasts theories.
They ran a vending machines all over the
country,
big time.
All over these vending machine
companies,
whether he's guys.
So he went to Milwaukee and busted these
motherfuckers like 40 of them.
I'm not kidding you.
It just doesn't say in the movie because
don't have enough time to put it in the
fucking stupid movie,
but there's a big Italian community and
fucking Milwaukee.
That's amazing.
Big Chinese.
I'll tell you,
one of the best meatball sandwiches I've
ever had was in fucking Milwaukee.
Really?
I'm telling you one of the best sauces I
went there and five days in a row.
How long have you known me?
Five in a row for lunch and they will
open for dinner.
I would have gone for dinner.
They we're open for breakfast and lunch.
It was one of those Italian,
but it's the delicate Toros,
you know what I mean?
Not with the shit hanging in the goat
hang and a fucking cheese and cheese.
So we're going.
All right.
I'm down.
Definitely going.
I.
He misplace Kava.
Does that.
I have up here in the valley.
That place is fucking great food.
Listening to California and the fucking
valley though.
There's some shit and the value.
That is brilliant.
What is it?
Canoga park there.
Cabaretta.
God Damn.
That place is good.
If you are looking for.
If you're in the valley and you looking
for real Italian sausage and pepper
sandwich.
Oh my God is a good sausage and peppers
with tomato sauce.
I.
It's terrible for you.
So I only get it once a month,
but what I get it,
it sits in like once a month.
Once a week?
Yeah.
Once a day.
Dog.
You have a fucking audit tax.
Trust me,
I have to fucking Tanya Cabaretta.
They say they sell it in a giant tray
and you take it home and eat that shit
up and it's fucking jamming.
That place is full.
Legit.
There's not another sausage and pepper
sub you could buy in La.
Where the fuck else is there?
Where's your sausage and pepper sub with
tomato sauce?
A real one.
I got this place is good and if you take
the hot peppers off the shelf and he
said,
well you chop these up in there,
they'll take you those hot because you
can't buy hot cherry peppers were the
fucking.
You get them.
Only if this place Italian place.
I must be in a tiny place with the.
Oh,
the presumed inside and cheese.
Oh my God.
I get they called Hepa Obama's.
That's so good.
I put it.
Just gives it to him because the other
fucking day,
not so once place cabinet is they have
kind of two big giant,
legit canola.
Canola guy.
They'll eat the fuck.
I it really know.
I'll beat the fuck out of this place is
don't want to show this to.
You could print this up.
Not Printing.
What is it?
You're one of the guys from Joe
Rogan.net
hit me up and he wanted a copy of this
when I got bugged by the feds at your
address.
Don't give a fuck.
It's my old address.
What is it?
They have to after nine slash 11,
if a drug,
if anybody whose phone is tapped,
they call you right after the person
goes to trial,
the government supposed to send you an
affidavit claiming the date you were on
the phone with them and all that shit.
So I was telling this kid this.
I was saying on the podcast before,
and I think he doubted me.
He goes,
can you please bring the paper?
Yeah.
You know what?
There's a lot of people on my message
board.
You guys are some disrespectful fucking
shit heads.
Some of you guys who don't believe
things,
you're so fucking rude about it.
And one of the things is joey.
So don't,
don't hold this up bro.
We gotta treat this like everybody can
hear this.
You can read it if you like.
But um,
so many people say,
oh,
this good comes onto the podcast.
We just launched and tell stupid
stories.
Joey Diaz was not allying crazy,
crazy life.
I don't give a fuck.
I've known.
I've known Joe.
If you only think about me,
I don't give a fuck about.
None of your motherfucking got no reason
to lie.
I don't owe you nothing.
They don't know.
Send the thief lighter.
No one.
Why ruin it with ally and if ain't
nothing,
it ain't gotta lie.
They don't know how you're living.
I got to know when I met you roles and
hang on your all day
saying shit.
The people get a fucking life.
You fucking maggots get a fucking life.
It's over.
He don't want to say to you,
but I'll just read.
Most of them are taken advantage of the
fact that there are non day and they
judge people and it's not just mainly do
everybody.
I've seen somebody do to fucking like a
music thing with kids the other day.
It's like,
you know what man?
Who the fuck are you?
What have you done?
And then when you go to the youtube
page,
they have done nothing.
They're nothing.
They just to put videos up a burden.
Shit.
Well I don't think you have to do
something to have an opinion aside,
but you know what,
if you don't have to be a can't,
you'd have to be a cut.
Be Straight instead of given it to me
with an anonymous fuckin and give it to
me intelligently.
I had a chick last much Joe Rogan who
sent me the best emm or an email I ever
got.
She said she went to a show and she was
very unhappy with my family.
She didn't like that it was dirty and
you know what?
Ten years ago I would've said suck my
dick.
And I emailed her back like a man.
You know what she said to me?
She weren't.
You were funny,
but they didn't need the necessity,
that curse.
And I said,
you should have said that you hurt my
feelings.
She goes,
I didn't mean to hurt your feelings.
I just thought there was more to you
than curse.
I'm picturing Joey Diaz along with his
nine fucking carrots answering this
pitches.
Email 11.
No,
I got gotta.
I got it.
You know you gotta answer these emails
from people,
but it's really funny,
like when somebody,
like somebody said you didn't put the
drain on your Dick,
who would make that up?
Why would you make that up?
I'm telling you that I'm.
It's like you don't have an agent like a
big time agent that moved away and now
he's in Dallas,
so his name was first on.
I am Deb.
Do you know how many fucking people send
him emails once a week telling me to
take the.
Had a Mug,
a fag video off.
So wait a second.
I'm telling you a story that a fag beat
the fuck out.
I go confused agents,
but this agent is the tap,
but he moved.
Now he's in Dallas.
He's a big time,
big time agent.
He handles athletes now and he was
telling you to take that video now.
Me One morning he was dog.
You have a video on there,
but bargain fags.
He's in fucking Austin,
Texas.
He,
he's a sports agent and he got his dog.
I keep getting emails from people.
It was late last year saying that you
better take the video.
Did you mug a fag?
And I got.
Why would I lie about getting beat up by
a fucking guy?
Why would somebody lie about something
like that?
Like why?
What would make something like that?
I can say if I beat up 10 fags or I
stabbed him and throw him over the cliff
or fucking Joe,
he's lying,
but who would lie about getting beat up
by the fucking guy?
Who Will?
Why would somebody make?
People wouldn't make stories up,
but the point is you don't know.
Why would I would?
Because you're crazy if you're a crazy
person.
Ever understood what it was.
I can't even lie on stage.
Oh,
I know a lot of people who lie.
they all make up stories on stage.
They might not.
I don't want to hear about that,
but I can't even.
Like I see.
I see a friend of my neck quit drinking
and she's still doing drinking jokes on
stage.
Why are you doing that?
Really?
You're doing that.
You can't commit that.
Why doesn't she does talk about how she
quit drinking,
but she used to do this.
What?
Fuck up my that say something
to them.
I just move on with my life.
I'm just making a fuck quote here.
It's like we need to go on up on st and
doing cocaine jokes.
I'll do it.
I don't live it no more.
I don't even know what that's like.
Why would I talk about it?
I talk about it.
Yeah,
in the years before,
but I can't stand with those.
Another thing you did that night of the
wounded soldier,
you were making fun of me because I had
a five hour energy drink and go,
what are you doing with that fucking
five hour energy?
And you went on stage with that.
He goes,
five hour energy drink.
you know what?
I do a and I wake up in the morning and
I have all fucking big line.
I snot a big line of cocaine as y'all
fucking five hours,
eight ball.
That's it.
But for five hours it was red bands
birthday and this week Mr Rogan has a
birthday this week.
He told,
I forgot you're 37 now you're going to
have to grow up eventually.
You know what is your birthday?
Don't you start getting the 11th,
August 11th.
That's,
that's what is this day.
Two days.
Two days for.
Oh Shit.
I thought you will invite me up for the
fucking bright.
Come on Thursday.
Thursday.
Bitch you want to do,
but we'll do it.
We'll do it.
Who's coming?
Why don't you have all of us?
Because I got to work all this week.
I'm back to the grind.
Back to fear factor family after I got
them doing everyday this week because
Friday we're bolting to Milwaukee for
this pabst theater.
That's August 13th.
Milwaukee,
PAPP's theater.
Me and Joe Diaz.
Tickets are almost sold out.
Get in it.
Pitches,
don't sleep.
I'm looking forward to that.
We're going to have a good time.
I can't wait.
I've been looking for is the last time
we did a Gig was a vegas.
No,
we just did Irvine.
Oh No,
no.
Pasadena.
We did the Irvine in Pasadena,
but I still got an email.
The last theater we did.
I'm thinking that's the theater we did
on the road.
Pittsburgh.
Pittsburgh was fucking awesome data.
That library.
It used to be a library.
Fucking great.
Carnegie Library Music called fucking
place was awesome.
Pittsburgh is great.
It's one of the things we were saying.
It's one of the most underrated fucking
cities.
We didn't like it when we did that
Improv.
I didn't go with you that time.
I had been there before.
I used to go to the funny bone.
It was okay.
Like the Chinese food as well when we
were there.
The one of the reasons why we didn't
like it is because there was apparently
there was some fucking sports thing
going on,
some did.
They're a really loyal to their teams
and when you got like a big game going
on,
nobody wants to go to see nothing.
And even people that bought tickets
didn't come to the show because it was
some big sports game.
Some football game or I don't know what
the fuck it was.
Team is in first place in baseball and
you know what,
didn't they win the world series or
something this year?
No,
no,
no.
But they're there right now.
They're super long.
Uh,
what did the steelers.
Yeah,
I think so.
Sorry.
I can't remember.
How funny is that?
We don't know.
Shit.
I can't fucking remember.
But you're trying to be funny Brian.
There a cricket doesn't.
They don't play cricket in the manual
that you fucked her room.
There's nothing in there,
bro.
Empty.
I drank,
yeah,
8:50
of those fucking coffee shops.
They make you thirsty,
dude.
That was fucking birthday boys in the
room is shit I got peed on today by who?
I grew up.
We were having sex and she accidentally
p for first time everyone was
coming and it was like it felt going
down my leg.
I'm like,
wait,
that's not normal.
And she's like,
oh my God,
I think it is p.
If you ever had that happen to you might
be dating the retarded girl.
No,
she said that.
She just didn't even know.
Why do you always go?
I've noticed every time I say something
you automatically get angry.
I'm angry.
Retard.
You say a lot of silly shit and I'm
making fun of it.
It's not called defensive.
That's not defense.
So I pissed on myself.
Good.
They'd be mad that I'm.
Every time I say something like,
uh,
anytime I say anything,
you always get angry,
get angry,
but you say some ridiculous shit.
Dude.
What's those pills?
You got a mocking you or clowning at
you.
It's like you can't just say ridiculous
shit and have me not say anything.
Yeah,
but a lot of times I say something that
you think is ridiculous,
like hash is actually a resin resident
residents.
One of the ways they make it as resident
that's not hash rehashes.
There was a process to make cash that
doesn't involve burning it.
Resident is when you scrape a pipe,
that's what resonance Hash Resin is a
different process.
It's not the resident of smoking been
multiple ways to make it,
but one of the ways,
one of that ways to make hash is rising.
One of the ways to make cassius scraping
residence.
I don't know if that's anything.
Neither one of us know enough about how
to make have to assess and shouldn't
they?
They take the thc as some somebody
you're pretending that you don't like
say silly shit on purpose,
like you're playing a role and I mock
you for it.
Now.
Also Syria as an example of me staying
on just saying,
you're just upset because you love this
girl,
and I said she might be.
I mean I'm just saying in general,
every time I say something you get
really angry at me.
Really angry.
You just noticed it.
I noticed it,
I noticed that all the time.
Okay.
I noticed you say ridiculous shit all
the time and I,
I clown you for it.
But it doesn't mean that I'm really
angry at,
you know,
I know,
I know.
But why does it every time I say
something,
you always have to completely shut down.
That was barely bashing your girl.
Pissed all over you.
And I said she had an orgasm and she's
never done this before,
but she had the same time and she was
like,
whoa,
this is crazy.
You don't think that it's appropriate to
say you might be dating retarded girl.
That's a joke.
That's a joke,
dude.
Obvious.
I know.
I liked her girlfriend.
She's a nice person.
What?
You're following the same thing that's
wrong with that.
Just,
you know,
she's your girlfriend about this shit
unless you tend to follow what I'm
saying.
Nothing wrong with that.
But Brian,
you can't get the,
the reason why I do this because in the
past we've talked about where girls are
really juicy and we spray that,
that it.
Is it p or not?
And uh,
I,
I actually said no it's not,
I just know girls that have done that
before,
but when she did it,
it felt like she was coming like crazy,
like,
like I've had experienced before.
But when I smelled it it was 100
percent.
So with other girls at squirted it
smelled different.
So this time you smelled it,
smelled it because it was just like,
Whoa,
why is it all over my asparagus now?
Is there anything else that definitely
makes you
pee?
Smell pineapples,
pineapples.
It makes it smell good or taste good.
Your loads.
Pineapples.
I supposed to make your loads tastes
good,
but that's what I hear.
But pee smell a pea.
It's always asparagus,
right?
That's the number one thing.
If you thought of,
like if I said,
what makes you a piece?
Think you'd say parents,
asparagus.
There's nothing else.
Right?
And see vitamin C,
vitamin C,
that's when it makes it bright orange
and bright orange.
Well,
all vitamins make your pee bright.
I mean maybe it is the vitamin C,
Vitamin C,
is it the more you're dehydrated yellow
your pis gets yes.
Or if you have a lot of vitamins,
if you take a lot of vitamins,
that's why people say,
Oh,
well you took vitamins,
which comes out in your pee.
No,
some of it does come on your p and it
makes you appear different color,
but a lot of it affects your body in a
positive way.
That's one of the weakest arguments
ever.
Like you shouldn't take vitamins.
Just pm out.
I've heard people say that so many
times,
Jesus Christ.
Are you really going into every cell and
monitoring how your nutrients are
distributed and you know for sure it all
goes out in your urine.
You Lazy.
Fuck,
you're so lazy.
You won't even take vitamins.
I've talked to so many people like that
and they say,
well,
I'd like to take vitamins or just can't
be bothered.
Like you can't be bothered to stick a
pill in your mouth and drink.
How hard is it?
You're eating,
you're eating all this food.
How hard is it to remember to put
something in your mouth and drink and
then you're healthier.
You get nutrients that you're not
getting from your diet.
Things that I do like that all the time.
Then I'm like,
that's so dumb.
That entity like floss,
I should like.
I hate flossing the debt,
but it's so easy.
It takes what,
two minutes and floss your teeth,
but I can't do it.
Like my body won't let me floss.
I,
I tried out for a couple of days and
then I,
I just hate it.
I think we're programmed in a certain
way by the way we were raised and
there's a lot of shit that people got on
you when you were a little kid that you
still to this day don't want to fucking
do because your parents told you to do
it.
I have this problem with work,
man.
I don't like doing things that are work,
you know,
I don't mind doing things that are for
me.
Like I could work forever on.
Okay.
I can train,
I can write,
I can,
you know,
work on things.
I can draw.
I can work forever on things that I want
to do,
but if someone tells me I'm supposed to
do something,
I have a hard time.
I have a hard time showing up for things
on time.
I don't want to.
It's like part of me that wants to
resist being on time and part of me that
wants to resist doing work and I know
it's from growing up.
It's from growing up,
being forced to work,
growing up,
being forced to,
you know,
like to say that the thought of your
work is dreariness and going to work is
you're going to be miserable and you're
gonna have to contain your emotions and
contain your disdain for what you're
doing and just force yourself to follow
through.
And I think that's a lot of us.
It's like shit,
like brushing your teeth.
Brushing teeth is great,
you know,
but when you're a little kid,
man,
everybody told you to brush your teeth
so it's annoying.
So you're like,
fuck you.
I'm an adult.
I'm going to eat.
I'm going to go to sleep with fucking
shit stuck in my teeth.
Fuck.
You know,
you do it on purpose.
These spite yourself by,
by rebelling from your childhood and
Joey.
I mean,
you grew up in the craziest way
possible.
You grew up,
you were sort of taken in by your,
by your neighbors,
right?
Yeah,
but when I was 15,
I come from a house,
get up,
can I come from a house where my mother
taught me wants to get in the shower,
brush my teeth though,
and if not,
you got to fucking smack to them.
But once you,
once you've got outta there though.
Once my mother died at 15,
I moved to the other people,
the neighbors when I met you.
Right?
This is,
let me tell you something about when I
met you,
you know,
when I met you,
like,
um,
you know,
I've known a lot of like wild
motherfuckers my whole life and one of
the things I said,
I've said this about you on stage.
And it's true.
Like one of the things I love about
hanging out with you is that there's a
lot of people think there's rules to the
way you're supposed to behave and live
and think.
And then you meet somebody and go,
Hey,
this guy's not following any rules.
I could say,
Oh,
I'm going to go follow him for a minute.
Where you going,
hey,
where'd you,
where'd you come up with this idea?
Why are you doing this?
He just,
he just pulled you dig out.
Are you sure you're going to go to jail?
You see you smoking pot out in public.
Like there's some people that,
you know,
when I grew up,
I grew up very disciplined because I was
a martial arts competitor and my from
age 15 to 21 my life,
my life was very,
very disciplined.
I didn't drink,
I,
I ate healthy foods.
I trained all the time and the reason
why I didn't drink a very rarely I might
have smoked pot five times in my whole
life from the time I was like,
you know,
10 till the time I was like 21,
maybe six at the most.
I might've got drunk three or four times
because I was always worried about going
to the gym the next day and getting
fucked up.
I was always worried like if I got drunk
and then four weeks from now I have a
fight.
Would if I get my ass kicked in a fight
that I would have won,
if I didn't get drunk on that one day,
I would so I would think like that.
So I was super disciplined and then I
met my friend Johnny B and my met my
friend Johnny when I had gone from being
a comedian or from from being a fighter
to being a comedian.
There was this drastic shift and drastic
shift in the human beings and that was
around.
So I was around all these wild
motherfuckers,
but they were fighters.
They were wild motherfuckers who were
fighting in tournaments and kickboxing
and you know,
I knew dudes that would like fight in
different tournament's just for a goof.
I knew dudes that would just go to a
judo tournament.
Didn't even practice judo.
They would fight and karate tournaments.
They weren't karate fighters that were,
you know,
they were talking about no guys,
they don't just go and just try it out.
They would do wild dudes who would just
would take chances and start boxing.
Yeah.
I've been boxing.
I'm hanging out with this gym in South
Boston.
I started boxing like,
you know,
this guy started wrestling.
I mean I knew a lot of dudes who did a
lot of wild shit,
but it was always wild.
You like martial arts type shit.
It was crazy and dangerous,
but it was,
it was a discipline,
sort of a crazy dangerous.
And then when I started hanging around
with Comedians,
then all of a sudden I was hanging out
with these wild Fox who are different.
There's a different kind of wild fuck.
There was like an insecure and needy,
but they would get drunk and fucked up
and dudes would do dangerous shit and
you know,
it was a weird kind of a human being was
a different kind of human being that I
was ever around a lot of partiers,
lot of people doing cocaine,
people getting nothing.
And then I met my friend Johnny and that
was the,
the total other end of the craziness.
I mean,
standup comedy was a craziness,
but they ain't no crazier than a person
who's a professional pool hustler.
And that was my friend Johnny.
My friend Johnny,
when I met him,
had nowhere to live,
had nowhere to stay,
did not know where he was,
he didn't have a diamond is pocket and
maybe had,
if he had $5 he was playing someone for
that $5 and that was all the money he
had in the world and he,
you know,
he played with a house queue or
sometimes he had his own queue,
but I mean this dude was living wild,
like completely wild and when I met you
and um,
you know,
he was my friend,
my best friend for years and you know,
he died and um,
I think it was like shit.
I v eight somewhere around there.
And I remember when I met you at the
comedy store,
I remember meeting you and it was
probably around that same year,
somewhere around that same time.
Yeah.
I remember looking at this motherfucker.
Here's another one.
Like here's another dude just out there,
wild in the streets.
You had a pager sometimes you had a
pager,
you to pay the whole time.
The same fucking page.
I got it from J and J dot B dot.
What year was this?
You got this page?
Ninety seven and I held onto that page
until 2004 and that's what fuck these
motherfuckers and this stupid rule never
knew where joey was my rules bitch.
You never knew what joey was and my
friend Johnny had a page or two.
That's how you got ahold of him.
But that was back when nobody had a cell
phone,
but through the all the years of cell
phones until we'd never had a cell
phone.
Joey didn't get a cell phone until like
2004 first.
Jackson,
Spiderman two you've got to fake.
Talked me into going to get Sam Raimi as
by the man who was like,
Yo,
yo.
So far.
Yeah.
Joey didn't have a cell phone.
He was living on different people's
couches,
sleeping in a car until we got code.
Yeah.
Fucking going on the road with no
clothes.
Just fucking living off a fucking
advances.
And just.
And by the way,
by the way,
he's doing comedy back then and he
wasn't good.
You weren't good you,
you were a different comedian man.
You know,
and I always say that there's never a
person that I've ever seen make the
switch,
flipped the switch and go from a guy who
wasn't doing well on stage to a guy who
was just destroyed,
lost my inhibitions.
I lost,
but it was amazing.
It was because one of the things that
was holding me down was going on my
daughter.
It was really holding me down and who I
was.
I felt.
I kept thinking I was doing the role of
choice,
so until I committed to doing comedy and
being a broke fucking comic the way you
supposed to commit yourself to anything
you dive into,
I couldn't be good because I kept
thinking of a time I was to back to
Colorado will be a dad.
That's what I kept thinking.
I'm like,
I can't be doing this shit.
Dad,
but this is what was pulling me.
I had nothing there with my daughter.
I wanted to raise my daughter my way.
I knew how I was going to raise a
daughter.
I was going to raise a daughter that she
didn't grow up like these fucking dumb
woman.
You see that have dignity and they have
fucking respect the same way.
My mother,
that's why I don't do what other people
do a beat of the drum because that's how
my mother raised me dog
to beat my own fucking drum if you don't
like something,
say it and how that wasn't a raise my
daughter and.
But the whole time I thought I was going
to come to la and anytime I want to go
back and get an apartment of boulders.
I wasn't committed.
One day I fucking got a thing that you
wanted to change her name and the mother
correlate with some bullshit story and
this and I had to be this nice person.
I don't like being nice if I don't have
to bro.
That's why I've changed so much.
Especially after the blow.
I don't take nothing from nobody now.
Nothing.
You can't get away with nothing.
So will you're saying is because I left
my inhibitions.
Go to be a good community you to.
I wasn't committed to it.
That's what it really was.
Fuck the inhibitions.
I wasn't committed.
I thought I wanted to be a dad.
I wanted to be a dad.
I wanted to be a dad,
but they weren't opening up the door for
me.
I couldn't run that shit if I didn't
like.
What do you mean by the way?
This is where it all goes to right now.
We're going to straighten this out.
This thing that happened in Denver,
she threw me out because a lot of people
have been tweeting me.
What happened for sexual harassment?
What are you talking about?
The thing with the club,
the comedy works comedy.
There's a lot of people because most
people have no idea what you're talking
about because last week got a couple
people asked me what Joey did.
Here's,
I'll fill you in.
Joy Diaz has never been able to work
with me at the comedy works in Denver
and people always ask,
when is Joey Diaz?
Colin,
why can't you bring Joey Diaz at the
comedy works?
He has never been allowed to do that.
Ever since I've been performing.
So she told a bunch of.
It was the woman who owns the club.
Right.
And it would have happened with some
girl ran down and jumped and when I went
to grab her I grabbed her ass.
There was a kid there that was like in
the same league as me.
We're starting to get star spots and he
was kind of weird about star spots.
That's what they call them.
Guest spots.
Comedy works in those days.
That's when you did Thursday.
You were good enough to do Thursday,
Wednesday and Tuesday.
And we do like 10 minutes,
right?
Ten minutes and you get off.
And Wendy liked me.
Wendy likes Italian guys,
you know who she likes to?
East Coast and she like rocky whatever
the porch.
She likes those guys.
Right?
So she kinda liked me and this guy kept
seeing it.
And one day I hear that shit.
I'm supposed to open up with George
Lopez.
I got a call from Wendy.
I did sexual harassment,
sexual harassment as well.
The girl,
what girl came in here.
So I got the whole story,
but a bunch of comics had seen the girl
jump into me and me grab arrest.
We were partying.
It's like be us being at the store and
Katie can you and running to you and
when she jumps at you grab it.
Right?
So the girl didn't say nothing that
night.
She didn't say nothing.
We kept drinking and we did a couple of
lines.
Three days later she was silent with
sexual harassment because one of the
comedians talked her into it.
He's like building.
That was sexual harassment you should
call Wendy.
So she called.
That's what happened.
That's all I want.
That's all it was.
And even at now.
But that's not even what it was.
That sexual harassment is sexual
harassment.
Harassment is whatever you.
What's the definition of it though,
isn't it?
Well,
I always assume that it's someone who
has power over someone and like,
like a boss that's like saying stupid
sexual shit to an employee any unwanted.
The fact that she ran towards and on,
she read souls.
The thing was that saint can't be sexual
harassment.
It doesn't really matter.
Girl,
the fucking buddy told her and when the
shit and told me I couldn't come in and
that,
you know.
And then you went on the radio and then
you signed the radio.
You know what,
I'm a thief.
I'll fucking shoot you if I have to.
I'm not a sexual predator.
So for that fat to say something like
that is fucking wrong,
but let me give you the flip side.
She's still stuck with her fat ass and
then when I'm here living in my fucking
life.
So she did me a favor.
The best thing about what's going on in
that was going to kill my ex wife,
my ex wife or husband.
I was going to kill him.
I was already content to get a fax
machine and write jokes for fucking
Leno.
They weren't going to present me what
they were doing for my daughter.
I was gonna have my buddies chip in $10.
It was 94.
I wasn't having to get me a fax machine
that was going to be in jail.
Writing jokes for them.
I already had a plan and really.
And one day I actually caught myself
saying,
all right,
I'll just kill him because I can't kill
her.
I know what it is to live without a
fucking mother,
so I can't kill the mother.
And I said,
Nah,
just kill him.
And I went down there one day with a
fucking butch and I.
it's just that you don't normally do.
When I get a beef up my hand,
I took a butcher knife and I smacked him
with two felonies.
I had two felonies in boulder and he
caught.
I picked up my daughter at the daycare.
My daughter got into the car and we're
driving and she goes,
Daddy,
what's a spic?
And I go,
where'd you hear that?
And she goes,
whenever you call the house,
that's what John says.
Close the fucking door.
Those was the Washington speakers.
I drove with a Safeway member.
You know,
you'd never go out to the baseline and
28th street,
that's where it had a returner.
I used to get my daughter on Sundays and
Wednesdays,
so there's one Wednesday and pull up my
little girl in the car.
She got a little princess solution
three,
maybe four,
get out of the car and I go,
what did he say?
She goes,
Spit Daddy.
What does that mean?
I get out of the car,
I'd go up to my mommy and she something.
John,
did you say speak in front of my
daughter?
And he goes,
no,
I didn't think.
Well,
she's three and she's never been to New
York.
So you got some explaining to do.
And he goes,
well,
I didn't say it Joe.
I go,
well,
you got a problem.
Just tell me you said it and we'll end
this,
but if you keep sitting there telling me
you didn't say this,
I'm going to fucking knock you out.
So one more time,
did you say spic in front of my
daughter?
And he said,
no,
Joe Rogan.
I lick this mother fucked up right there
in the safeway parking lot with two
shots to the fuck.
And then Bam,
but that blind people yell and leave him
alone.
I'm like,
fuck you bitch.
And all this.
In the middle of all this,
I turn around and look at the client.
I said,
my little three year old princess bride.
She was scared when I was five and six.
I see my stepdad blast motherfuckers
with your flapping hands on the street.
I seen him shoot a gun on 48th street
and I would say to me,
I was raised.
I was a fucking animal.
I didn't want my daughter to go through
that barrow at this time already.
She was already seeing this shit.
Now I smacked his fucking dude I had to
go to.
They didn't give me a ticket because if
you check bold and next time you go.
If you use a racial epithet and the city
limits of bold that you got get what's
coming to you.
Really?
Yeah.
So when there's something,
cause he called you a Spec,
you were allowed to beat him.
My one clean when he went to court the
next day with the black eye according to
the judge even said,
next time you call somebody a fucking
racial epitaph,
you got won't come at all because ofj
dot j.
Dot Flannigan.
Nineteen 87.
A football player in the early,
in the late eighties that a lot of
problems in boulder with the black
football players.
They were up there fucking those white
chicks three at a time banging them j
dot j Dot Flanagan,
Kuneva Mcgee,
and one kid says something.
The Jj flank called him a nigger and he
smacked him.
The kids.
I fucking flew up.
Kids fucking.
I flew out of his fucking head.
So something happened after that.
They made it the judge j Dot j Dot
Flannigan law that you can't say a
racial epitaphs.
They sided with him in the city of
Lynwood inside with him,
but some fucking word man.
Yeah,
I agree.
Don't say it.
It's not nice,
but that's the knocked out.
At the time I was going to kill my ex
wife and her fucking boyfriend at one
side of me at the time.
I'm going to kill these motherfuckers
joined.
I'm telling you,
this is sincerity of my heart.
Everybody.
Nobody was going to fuck with me.
That's the way my mother raised me.
So this is after he called you a Spec.
You want him to kill him?
I was still gonna hunt them down.
I still had a plan for hunt them down.
I was in a hunt him down.
I was.
So what was going on though?
You're white.
You broke up with your wife and my wife
broke up and then this new guy came in,
the pit them against my wishes on
whatnot.
She told me she wasn't going to date.
Nobody for me.
Not to date,
nobody.
I got into comedy and then one day she
came to me when I was at a conference
with the broker and she goes,
I was late for hours because I had a
date and that's how the war started and
she moved my daughter in there and
here's how the war started.
White come from.
You can't move my daughter into
somewhere though,
some man's house.
She,
if she's with your daughter,
you think she should have been by
herself forever?
No,
you come to me and talk to me like a
man,
you're going to move my daughter into
another man's house.
Understand me.
That I don't give me the tricky.
No,
no,
no.
It's not tricky.
That's my daughter.
I paid child support before you move
into another motherfuckers house.
Don't say tricky because if it happens
to you,
you understand the feeling,
still triggered all know the feeling and
when you pick up your and that was like
another man so nobody could judge me on
this.
Nobody.
I don't ever want to hear it from nobody
knows until you know that feeling.
Don't you ever say nothing to me ever
until you know the feeling when you pick
up your fucking daughter and she smells
like another man.
Joe,
I'm sure somebody can say something to
me,
but until then,
don't ever say something like that.
But this woman is allowed to live her
life.
She's a lot to live her life,
so she.
You think she's got to get your
permission before she came in with a
man?
What are you especially is raising the
girls.
That's where it gets tricky.
Support.
You were fucking joint.
So what does that mean?
Joint fucking custody.
You still cost money to raise the kid
and she lives with a guy constantly.
I understand,
but I'm paying child support.
What?
I don't know how that works.
What do you mean a woman can not just
moving your daughter's room with a man
is illegal.
It's it.
It's us.
You just can't wake up one day and your
daughter moves a fucking.
What is her?
What are her rights or her legal?
No,
I didn't quote Perry.
Mason.
I,
I'm,
I'm from the street of rights to come
through like a man.
But you know what I'm saying?
Joey,
if she doesn't want to deal with you
anymore,
she wants a minute ago with the guy,
she has to get your permission.
You want to do whatever the fuck you
want to do.
You do the fuck you want to do,
but you can't take your daughter into
some other woman's house will.
I've seen that woman and saying,
Hey,
I got a woman and I want to.
That's all I'm asking from anybody.
That's it just commonly looked at me in
the eye.
Don't give me no bullshit,
bro.
This is what men don't tell me.
You asked somebody if your daughter and
your wife are going to move in with a
guy right now when you want to come to
you and the Lord Christ.
Joey,
what are you?
You're getting in an argument with
someone who's not even.
I'm arguing with society.
I understand.
That's what I'm saying.
It's hard to listen to the saying to me
that,
yeah,
you get crazy right?
A woman has a right to be away from my
man and what is she going to go?
She's raising a kid out less.
You got to.
When you.
When a woman wants to leave another
Dick,
that's one thing.
You don't have to tell me nothing.
You're moving your daughter.
She's three or four.
You got to come.
Well,
I.
I agree that it's got to be a very hairy
situation to have some man around your
child,
especially when you know that he's
talking some shit about you and he's was
raising your daughters terrible before
somebody moves.
You're kidding with another person.
They should contact you and say,
Hey,
I fell in love with somebody.
I want to move my kid in there,
but most women make the mistake when
they get separated,
the jump in the sack with somebody just
to hurt the other person.
I've seen it a thousand times.
Do you think that's why they do it?
They just know they do it because they
want to jump into bed with somebody that
you know,
think about all the time.
Look at what happened with being candid.
His wife jumped into bed with Zulu
nation and he fucked cane.
What?
Dean Kane came home one day and he
didn't know who the fuck knows this
story?
Well,
I'm telling you were right.
He's like,
it's like,
no.
Come on.
Everybody knows the dean,
George Washington,
the apple tree details Zulu nation.
He came home one day.
Christmas had moved the kid in with
another guy.
You know,
he came home and the wife had moved the
kid and with another guy and whatever
the fuck.
You know what I'm saying?
They were separated and she moved in
with another fucking guy.
He did the same thing.
He took the bits of the court and took a
fucking jeep.
You did everything.
You cannot.
You have to come to me though with
without the court.
So that's the.
That's the problem where I lacked.
I don't understand court.
I don't understand.
Cool.
We're friends.
Don't hit me with court.
I know you're 20 years used to suck my
dick and I used to eat your ass.
Whoa.
You don't have to go to cloud.
Have a relationship with this man.
I'm missing what I'm trying to say.
She's had a good time with Joe.
Did assistant position at this time in
my life.
When did that favor by banning me.
She doesn't mean she made you leave
Denver.
She took me a fucking favor.
Look where I am now,
but you fucking mom was smoking dope.
Not Good.
Dope.
But I'm having a good fucking time.
The reason this,
this crazy fucking argument with nobody
just got started.
The story got started because of the
paramount.
Bob,
I'm just telling you the truth.
September 23rd paramount there.
Joe Diaz returns to out there.
Say,
hurry up.
It's almost so bad.
Oh Joe,
you asked me what was going on.
You asked me and I'm telling you I
didn't know that we're going to fuck
around with people you want to know.
I tell the St Joe jokey pools or
nothing.
She'll keep it match what happened with
me.
So when they came to me and said you got
thrown out of the end of economy was I
was bummed out for like two weeks,
but I knew I was losing the war over
there because I wasn't going to lose
that.
Glad you never killed anybody want to
come back with a hand?
Was there any kind of love interest
between you and Wendy at any time?
No.
You sure?
Did you ever kiss her?
No.
Nothing because that's what I heard.
I heard that there was some kindness and
you didn't hear that.
Did you hear that?
He's been in fucking jail.
I wonder when people yell at,
you know,
I swear to God.
I swear to God though.
What'd you hear?
I heard that,
that they were like kind of fucking
around with each other.
I don't know who told me,
but somebody told me,
you told you.
Nobody told him that.
He's just trying to.
You?
No I don't.
He's not going nowhere with it.
Stop.
It's not cute.
It ain't gonna fuck.
I swear to you.
Make it funny.
What are you still people at Rogen on?
You ain't even funny.
Stop it.
People are explaining me.
Hash online and there's nothing more
than compressed keef or thc extracted
from plant material says high tech con
man.
People are also telling me that there's
many different kinds of Hash tricombs
and yeah,
I guess some people actually do call it
resin.
It's not resonate as a.
I understand resin I think.
I think.
Yeah,
tell them about the shit that I was
getting with the fucking stamp.
Hello?
Knows about that shit.
It's just like,
it's just like the Olympic
fixed.
They would stamp it with like,
you know,
it would be like the medium grade would
be bronze,
medium will be serving the best would be
like Goldman.
They used to have them.
I have a platinum coding,
so that's how you judge Hash in the old
days when you got it,
people would say,
oh yeah,
fucking platinum.
You can't get no that.
So that's,
that's the emperor.
I'm not kidding.
These are jokes.
The emperor,
wherever it would make the hash,
before they shipped it over here,
they would stamp it for your approval
and that's what you always wanted to
get.
You always wanted to get the hash with
the stamp.
What I was talking about earlier,
Oklahoma,
Oklahoma Senate approves life in prison
for making hash of you make Hash.
They will give you life in prison.
That's amazing.
It's amazing how stupid they are in
Oklahoma.
That is so fucking dumb.
They think that somehow or another,
this is some dangerous drug.
Who Do they think this is math?
What do you get from making meth in
Oklahoma?
Because if you get life in jail for if
you get life in jail for making hash,
they should shoot everyone you've ever
met.
If you make meth,
they should kill you and then shoot
everyone you've ever met.
Everyone you love should die for shut.
The Hash has never killed anybody.
The only times I was smoking hash and
I'm like,
I've just said,
wow,
I'm really high.
That's it.
Hash is really good.
If you work at your store,
you eat little pieces of it.
Oh God.
The next day you wake up,
often
there's a beautiful fucking story on a
kid who had autism and his parents were
given them hash and it killed his
autism.
It's amazing.
The kid like wouldn't interact with
anybody.
The black chicks I did.
No,
no,
no.
It was a different one.
So different was a white kid.
It was a guy in northern California and
he cut a little tiny piece of hash and
he would stick it inside of a melon and
he would give it to his boy and all the
sudden this kid was interacting with
people and he was calm.
He was relaxed and there was another one
with a black kid to where they're given
a medical marijuana.
Meanwhile,
in Oklahoma,
that's shit puts you in life.
In prison in April 20.
First of 2011.
That's an Oklahoma.
So not anymore.
Not Anymore.
There's certain places where somebody
else might.
They got to get this test for welfare.
I like it.
That's a good move.
That's a fucking bull.
Welfare is such a tricky thing because I
love the idea that people can count on
people to help them out if something
goes wrong,
but human nature is a motherfucker and
human nature is.
If you give people the ability to not
work there,
they're going to take it.
I never understood.
People went there and said,
I claimed craziness.
That's $600 a month so you don't have to
work and you're crazy.
You're getting $6.
You can't live on that,
so I don't understand why you're jumping
up and down so happy for.
Some people are happy just to know a
month or something.
I just seen him about a year ago on TV.
If you claim craziest 6:40
and those people in that documentary I
was talking about earlier were
documentaries that I think we're alone.
How they made their money.
They claim crazy.
Yeah.
Well because they're not claiming it
because they had that asperger's or
whatever it's called asperger's.
You can get money from you.
Look,
I think you should be able to get some
money if there's something fucked up
with you and we should help each other
out.
We should help out our brothers and
sisters.
The problem is,
like I said about hippies.
The problem is it's beautiful if
everybody helps.
If you've got a circle and everybody's
handing out love to the left and like
man,
here have some live,
it's going to come around back to you.
It's all.
We're all community,
right?
But with hippies,
a lot of hippies when they're in a
circle and they're handing out love to
the left,
the love gets to them and they step out
of the circle and walk away and they
take that love and they don't pass it
around and they're always taking and not
giving and that's something that happens
when you have a welfare situation.
You have people who.
It's nice if we all help each other out,
but some people just,
they're greedy and they take that money
and they just.
They think that somehow or another
deserve it and other people,
they use it as a crutch.
Well,
I don't have to work because now I got
money.
There's so many flaws in human beings
and and just just human behavior.
It's hard to make something like welfare
work.
It's hard to make it work the way it's
supposed to work.
Here's the way it's supposed to work,
right?
Here's the way society is supposed to
work.
We are supposed to live in tribes of 50
people.
That's how it's supposed to work.
We're not supposed to be connected.
Three hundred fucking million of us all
on this one patch of dirt.
That is pro postures.
The idea of a fucking community that has
300 million people have it is
ridiculous,
especially when people go on Rob,
rob,
bullshit and fuck you.
So you will say,
no,
no.
That's.
That's crazy.
You can't have everybody in.
You can't have everybody in the same
fucking team.
It's not that you shouldn't be one
community in your community,
should compete against every other
community.
You could all have be under the same
idea,
our umbrella,
but the fact that all people are
responsible for all the rest of the
people,
$300,
million,
it's too many.
There's too many.
There's too much room for craziness and
douchebags and too much neglect and
there's not enough people that are good
enough focus or attention.
It's just the numbers are too vast for a
human being,
a human being belongs in a tribe of
small people,
but the fact that there's so many of us
are a small tribe of 50 people,
but the fact that so many of us that we
kind of are forced into this situation
where we interact on a daily basis with
millions of people that we have no idea
who the fuck they are.
We don't know anything about them and
yet we're all combined under the same
group.
That's crazy.
That's when welfare becomes nuts because
you're getting money from some people.
You don't even fucking know these
people.
Fuck those people.
Give me my money.
You know?
Instead of being in a tribe of 50
people,
they go,
hey man,
why aren't you doing your work?
You need to contribute.
We're a part of a community.
And then you feel it.
You feel that your.
Yeah,
I am slacking.
Yeah.
If there was 10 people on an island and
one person was sitting around,
you know,
if they all got shipwrecked and one
person was sitting around going,
yeah,
bring me my fish year,
where's my water?
You'd go,
we got to kill that guy.
That guy's not using.
He's not helping.
You know,
he's using up our valuable resources.
We have to risk our lives fishing and
getting water and this just sits around
doing.
You'd want to kill him,
but in a society with 300 million
people,
it just becomes another thing you just
told me.
Do you know how easy
they make it for you?
I don't know about now,
but because what's going on?
But you know how easy they make it.
For some people,
just verizon.
I'll tell you how easy it is so you can
really shit your pants because I really
always dropped some money.
When you get out of prison,
no matter how old you are,
you going there for heck of a mass
followed with a Dui.
You come out when you're 26,
you could do paperwork and claim
disability because you're a convicted
felon for the rest of your life.
What disability law,
how is it a disability that you're
convicted?
Thought of them will say they can't get
the job because they're felons who's
going to hire a felon,
so you get disability or $600 a month.
You probably just want to keep you from
robbing somebody.
That's probably the logic.
Not going to do it.
What's he going to do if you're on to
give you a little something.
So it was really weird.
I remember leaving there,
but when my mother died,
she worked under her alias.
My mother had an alias all those years
because after she stabbed the guy in
Cuba and she came back,
she had to change her name because she
came back with her friend's ID.
My Jimmy runs Jesus Christ deal.
But it was funny that I had a fight for
social security when my mother died and
I was 15.
I needed the money.
Like I went there 10 times to fight them
and oh,
we don't know what the fuck.
Don't you know,
at least give me a $200.
I didn't need the money Joe,
but it was just so weird that finally
when they're selling me this,
I'd go steal for a living.
I go sold drugs.
I never took after all the drama they
put me through for social security,
but they give it to me after I got a
felony.
Wow.
Just like that
for the rest of my life.
$600 a month.
That would get on the fifth of every
month and if you claim that they talk
about the different disabilities and the
difference,
you could get up to like $1,200
a month.
I wonder if people were ever going to
evolve to the point where a society
actually can work if like what our
problem is is that society and cities
and these giant ideas of countries,
they happen so quickly and the
development of the human animal that we,
we,
we haven't really evolved enough with
our minds and our behavior to,
to,
to operate,
like to operate really in a harmonic way
with a society.
And that's why there's all this crime.
And that's why there's all this
bullshit.
That's why there's all these things that
would not be tolerated in the natural
group of 50 people that all know each
other and love each other and support
each other like we are.
We're designed to operate in tribes.
It's very obvious.
Everybody wants to be on a team.
Everybody wants to have a family,
everybody wants to have friends.
Everybody wants to have a group.
You know where the death squad look.
I mean we are like a little family.
We call ourselves a death squad.
All of us together,
you know.
And the reason why we call it with Opi
from opiod anthony named is that.
And like 19 fucking whatever the hell it
was,
2003 or whatever it was.
I came in with Eddie Bravo and tate and
you know,
when he goes,
oh,
it's Joe Rogan and his death squad.
And then we're like,
that's hilarious.
Does squad,
because we were giggling,
we were like a cost offset.
Desk Squad were the desk right now and
it sounds so stupid,
but we call ourselves that and we have
this desk squad podcast network and all
that,
but all this group of comics that we all
hang out together.
We are like this,
this little tribe.
We all liked this little family.
It's like a natural thing,
but it's not natural to do it with 300
million people.
If we were all together and we all lived
together,
it would be normal.
We all love each other.
We all take care of each other.
We look out for each other.
If something's happening to one of us,
we want to help,
you know that's.
That's normal shit.
I wonder if if it's ever going to get to
the point where we could operate like
that with 300 million people because it
obviously doesn't work right now when
you have crime,
but it's that,
but I don't want to say never because I
think that human interaction and what
where we are right now is so different
than where it was in the thirties and
the twenties in the fifties and just
really 10 years ago.
Social Media and the interaction that we
have with human beings today,
the interaction that we have on with
just with twitter alone,
it's so different than than human beings
who grew up in a different generation
that didn't have this and our connection
with each other is very different than
people that grew up in a different
generation and I think that that's part
of the evolution of the human being and
I think that human beings are slowly
trying to figure out how to work
together in these big giant ass fucking
groups.
I don't think it's impossible.
It obviously depends on raising children
correctly and not developing incredibly
fucked up human beings that are a
liability,
but that's possible too.
You grew up fucked up and you're not a
liability.
You know what I mean?
Thinking about the craziest stories
you've told just today about wanting to
kill people,
smacking people,
the fact that you're a criminal and a
thief and that you've been to jail and
all these different things,
but yet here you are hanging out at my
house.
She went on to my best friends.
You're very productive.
You're a fucking beautiful standup
comedian,
you're a great guy,
you've got a great podcast,
you know what I'm saying?
Like you pulled it together to become
something different.
And Brian,
you know,
coming from fucking Columbus,
Ohio and working in a fucking gateway
and being stuck in this town and you
know,
and being surrounded by a bunch of
knuckleheads,
you've pulled it together,
you've become someone different.
We all evolve.
We all move into some new phase of life
and interact with everybody that's
around us in a very different way.
Is that possible on a mass level?
Is that possible as a society that we
all hold each other accountable,
all of us individually.
And you become 300 million people
together.
No,
no,
no.
We come from a society where people
don't give a fuck with two fucking
selfish.
Some computers and shit.
I've separated us even more.
I think they can separate us even more.
I like human contact.
I do too,
but I like this.
My computer guy was really good too.
And I said to Eddie,
Eddie,
can you call and you take a picture and
this is something that we.
You said to me when that,
can you take a picture and put it on
twitter?
And he goes,
yeah,
my wife goes,
you could do it too.
And I said,
you don't want.
But I'm out.
I'm living my life.
I don't want to be beat a fucking
computer when I'm out.
That means you're not fucking livid when
I'm out of my house.
I don't want to say twitter.
I don't want to see facebook.
I don't want to seem nothing.
I'm living my fucking life.
That's what the problem is,
that people are not living no more.
They were on these fucking things too
much and it's losing a little bit of
human touch.
That's what we all do.
That's what I feel I feel between the
texting and a lot of stuff.
It cuts time,
but we'll losing human contact.
It's making us lazy.
A couple of years ago,
commercial came out and it was about a
business and the guy goes,
I'm having a meeting.
And he started giving away plane tickets
and the people will like,
the salesmen were like,
Whoa,
what's this?
And he goes,
we've lost our fucking human
[inaudible].
Everything is a twit or a fucking email
or something.
We're going to go back to belly to belly
sales to,
to,
to look at people in the fucking eye and
talk to people again.
And,
and that's,
I mean,
we're so lose now,
this fucking crime.
They're jumping up and down and fucking
England.
Mexico's as volatile as it's ever been.
We're in no danger.
We can't even drive in fucking Hollywood
because people won't even put that
fucking blinkers on.
They're so selfish.
That's the first way of changing Joe.
The way I changed was to start from
scratch.
If you can't pick up a piece of paper as
you're walking,
you're not going to change if you can't.
You know,
I used to,
when I got the longest shot and I used
to go to all these meetings in Hollywood
and you go to all these meetings and
every fucking meeting you go to some
dumb motherfucker shows up 20 minutes
late and says to you,
well,
what's the traffic one?
Motherfucker,
you live in La,
you and guess what?
I started doing joe.
I started being laid and then one day I
caught myself and I go,
you don't want.
This is what I'm talking about.
For me to be a better productive,
I have to show people,
not tell them,
show people,
and now when I get to a meeting and
you're 20 minutes late,
I say
I say something to you because we're
men.
That's how character you never like an
angry is he today and never very angry,
very angry,
never let your character ruin your
destiny.
And it all starts with little things.
It doesn't start with being a fake and
it starts with little things.
It's character is what people don't see
you doing.
It's the things that pit and that's what
we've forgotten.
Driving Hollywood the other day.
Data was eight,
conquer lap.
Okay,
I agree.
I think that there's definitely people
need character joey,
but you're discounting the idea that
technology is connecting people and
that's ridiculous.
You're discounting the idea that twitter
connects people in the facebook connects
people.
Yes,
you should have human interaction and
you know what?
You should have human interaction
showing up dog to people making.
So you got a couple of idiots parking.
No,
that doesn't mean that there's not a
trend of interconnection.
Douchebag,
mothers,
some of them,
some of them.
Not.
Everybody starts and we want to make the
world a lot better.
Starts with the little things.
We could talk all this nonsense to
people because before it all starts with
you dog.
Oh my God.
Because the word,
all these people are,
you know,
so kind of a world and all this shit.
In the last.
I've never seen him angry.
I believe in doing.
I'm.
I know.
But Joey,
we're talking about a positive thing and
all of a sudden you turned anything.
We talk about into something where
you're yelling at someone.
No,
no,
no.
I'm not yelling at me,
isn't it Brian?
I'm passionate about something.
I'm not.
Y'All understand what I'm saying?
Everything is some fucking molds.
Just fucking idiot.
Compassion.
I'd done it.
I understand the fuck to tell you.
You want me to be honest with you on
your podcasts,
right?
If not,
you quote one of your buddies.
Joey.
I want you to be honest,
but I think we should be able to discuss
ideas with you screaming about some
personal.
I understand why you got to get me real
stone when I get here though.
That's what happened.
Did you say you peed on yourself?
I peed on myself.
How did you do that?
Fucking sleeping.
Woke up.
I was so cold in your bed.
The in my bed.
I beat up because I had the sleep apnea
mask on.
So beat up word fuck in the pants with
purpose.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
I'd do that every day.
I was asleep.
I was,
you know,
sometimes my room,
my room was fucking 50 below zero it
now.
So some nights at six.
I'm like to the what is your wife?
Did she bundle up bumble up big time?
She was so she bundles up saying you get
that AC cranked on winter.
How many cats are sleeping with you when
you're doing this?
To only to your same two every time.
Yeah,
and the other.
The other nine don't get embarrassed
about with the cold and cold there.
They find they can't take the cold
there.
Sometimes I get up and move on that my
wife has gone.
How do you keep your,
your place from smelling my cat shit
because I have a problem with my fucking
office.
Clean.
You clean it every day,
right?
Everyday.
If you're a filthy animal,
that's what happened to change every
day.
It's still stinks.
No like shit.
Every time I.
my little girl,
she loves wet food will spazz.
She loves wet food,
but when I give her that wet food,
God damaged the wet food will kill you,
but they love it.
They love it.
I only give her wet food every couple of
days.
Get these achievement house.
I pay a little extra for these crystals.
Yeah,
right now.
Do you like the Blue Crystal?
Are you talking about the blue light
will watch them.
Shit.
Just like we do a podcast once a while,
all about a cat called podcasts and
that's all we were like.
We talked about litter control and
thing.
You don't get one of those electric ones
that like a month and they didn't
do.
You have a litter box with a dome over
it.
You have got to have that.
I got four dorms.
I got one day.
They say,
oh,
it's a carbon filter.
My little girl,
that little spasm,
she will make the stinky shit.
I almost get upset at her,
you know,
but no,
you can't get up such.
As soon as I smell something,
I'll clean it out.
I got to scoop it out and flushing,
but it stinks to do.
I scoop it out and flushing and I
changed every two days,
but I stay on it.
It's just so gross as creepy little
animals.
They're in there scratching on the
Shitty fucking glitter and pissy litter
and then they get out and just walk
around your house.
Shitty litter and pissy little pause and
it's,
you know,
definitely.
He definitely has feline virus for sure.
Sure.
Honestly,
I think this will be great for the
podcast,
get it tested and we give it like live
results.
Those don't know
we're talking about.
There's a cat parasite called toxo
plasma.
Look it up on the Internet.
A lot of people infected by this cad
parasite and it alters human behavior
and it makes you more impulsive and
crazy and that's probably true.
Make girls more submissive.
Guys.
Keep believing that dumb shit.
You keep believing what toxoplasma.
It's 100 percent true.
No,
it's not.
It's 60 million Americans.
I've had cats.
Was six fucking Joey.
It also makes your wife or your
girlfriend whatever.
You were saying that.
No,
no,
no fact that says days are over when you
come.
Correct.
Because if not,
I walk out of the fucking room.
Shelly toxo plasma is nonsense.
Now I got a cat disease.
What I might cat,
man,
listen to you talk.
That sounds exactly like they say what?
Someone who can aggravate someone who
has a cat disease talks exactly like
that.
I know,
I know.
That's what it is.
Look Joey,
a lot of people have it.
They don't know that they have it.
I'm sure I have it.
Sixty dollars million
Americans have it.
Sixty dollars million.
No,
no.
What do you mean here?
They all.
They all got iphone.
So what time you got time for you to go
home?
What is it?
10,
15,
55.
Zero.
You should do this with your wife
earlier.
It's awesome to have her put her mouth
inside of your mouth and talk inside
your mouth.
It's cool.
Okay.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Breads.
You wonder why people yell at you.
Knock it.
You'll like it.
No.
What?
No one talks inside my mouth.
Dude.
Echoes in the head.
It's so creepy sounding.
This what I'm saying?
Just try it out.
Make sure there's no errors.
Fight in this podcast.
We have really covered the full spectrum
of welfare and black people in the movie
theaters and stabbing people walking in
air conditioning.
There is air conditioning here.
Believe it or not.
And we've covered everything.
We've covered it all folks.
And you know,
it's been a wild ride.
And uh,
I enjoyed it.
So most of the time,
most of the time it was a few times.
I love it when Joey Diaz goes crazy.
It's one of my favorite things ever.
Yeah.
I love when you go off to,
but you know there's no absolutes on
these.
I love you to death,
Bro.
You invite me up here,
but have you got to get me in here and
good shit from the jump.
You know how I roll?
I can't have that shit that you had this
guy got to get the a one weed and calm
me down.
I think you need to go to the gym
between Rick and Hollywood is different
from crazy.
You're so crazy.
I got to shit on labrea much.
I got this shit at the clinic where the
guy.
This shit show now.
This is from the brand.
Believe he did it.
I can't believe you that.
It's just.
Yeah,
I know.
I gave him some bunk.
We'd right.
What is it a fumble?
Lumps.
It's Hannah Montana.
No,
fucking.
When Abbott and Costello,
he used to pull scans.
They used to always work for the
subsequent of that company because it
was make believe.
How do you remember that?
That's comedy.
That's real comedy.
Shit.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I hope you learned a lot today.
Stay black because we sure did.
The fuck is.
This is.
Look,
there's a full spectrum of Joey Diaz
today.
We got an angry intense Joe Diaz
birthday Rogan.
Happy Birthday.
Thank you.
It's not quite my birthday.
Happy Birthday.
You Brian [inaudible] birthday already
passed and we haven't brought up.
Go see planet of the apes.
Go See red states.
If I'm see us at the PAP,
Steve,
I'm bitchy us at the Milwaukee team.
August 13th.
Come see us at the paramount theater in
Denver.
September 23rd and last year.
Joey Diaz,
his ex wife or her ex husband.
Is He still married to that guy?
Don't come if you're that guy.
Don't come.
Oh,
by the way,
Brad.
Tomorrow night.
Oh,
San Jose Improv.
The 25th of August.
Who's with you tomorrow night and brand?
I have no fucking idea.
You don't know.
Maybe I'll come down.
I'm working in Pomona tomorrow night.
Is that close to brand?
If it is,
I'll come down.
Listen folks,
I fucking love you.
I love you.
I hope you enjoyed this.
This is not a normal one.
It's a little different,
but it is what it is.
It's all love.
We love you.
This is the only podcast we're doing
this week.
Very busy this week with the fear
factor,
but you know,
that's why I love you guys is why we
decided to do a late night one.
I worked all day and uh,
and that's it.
So this is me,
me on Joey or probably do on this
weekend.
We'll probably do it on the plane on the
way back home and that's it.
See you next week.
Next week with Kevin Smith.
I'm trying to get Duncan in here next
week too.
And um,
we're supposed to do Jane Moore,
but Brian and him had a twitter feud.
So I don't know if that's going to take
place or not.
We'll
see.
Either way.
Shizam Salaam Alaikum.
Big Kiss,
Tmr Mama.
Anything to say?
Brian?
I love the fleshlight Joey Diaz.
Jordan.
I liked j dot ward.
You don't lecture anymore anymore.
He's think he got a little crazy when a
little baby.
Did he get a little,
you know,
there was a little twitter war out of
nowhere.
You want to explain that.
He said,
all right,
here's the whole j dot region in
nutshell.
He's friends with Tom Segura,
right?
And Tom's like,
hey,
can you please help Jay Mohr out,
give them some information.
He wants to do a podcast if he could
just talk to him.
So I was like,
yeah,
sure.
I'm to give me a call.
He calls me up.
I'm like,
Hey,
you know,
I'm really busy but I can lead you in
the right direction if I ever have any
free chance.
I'll help you out here and there and
stuff like that.
He goes,
well,
can you just email me all the things I
need?
So I emailed them like some some
equipment that he should buy on
Amazon.com.
Amazon Dot Com gave him a web host that
he should go.
And then he wrote me back like,
hey,
how much this is,
all this stuff costs.
And I'm like,
well,
just click on the links,
you know.
Anyways.
So I wrote back and said he asked you to
add it all up.
Yeah.
He and he,
uh,
how did he say?
He's like,
Hey,
can you add that all up for me?
Or something like that.
Can you add that all?
Yeah,
like he wanted me to click on all the
links and added up for him for some
reason.
Wow.
That's asking a lot.
Well,
it's asking a lot from a guy you don't
know,
don't know.
The guy's sudden you,
you went out of your way to provide him
with all the information.
And it was like,
I don't know,
this guy,
I'm doing this favor.
I had to go on Amazon,
find links and copy and paste and
actually spend some time like for a
complete stranger,
you know?
Right.
And so then he said,
you've never met Jane Moore,
never met j dot Moore.
I sold them and he says,
can you add all this shit up?
Yeah.
And so,
and I said,
you know,
look,
I,
because I think he was kind of confused
with everything.
He's like,
you.
I said,
hey,
if you want to use my studio,
you can use it anytime you want to,
you know,
and he completely ignored that and he
goes,
hey,
you know,
stepping yet another email.
We're on the road at the time I missed
his last email he sent me.
I didn't even know he sent it to me.
Come to like a month or two later
Thompson.
He goes,
can you please write jay more a real,
like a letter detailing everything he
needs to do to do a podcast.
I'm like,
okay,
I'll make it super detailed.
No,
that's fine.
Get on itunes on Itunes,
do this.
Take the SD card.
Actually was saying take the SD card out
of your computer,
you know,
like it was that detailed.
I was writing it and then like two days
later I'm still writing this letter a,
I see that he has a podcast.
So I just like,
Oh I guess with Kevin Smith.
So I'm like,
you know what,
I don't have to send this out anymore.
So I just ignored it.
And then I noticed he started tweeting
me like fucking crazy,
like tagging me if you search his
timeline since March,
he's tweeted my names and their 24 times
I've never tweeted that jude wants all
right.
I don't know this guy.
Right.
So then finally I'm on my birthday
weekend and I'm out of town.
I'm at Disneyland and I'm like looking
at my phone and it's like,
fuck you red ban,
you know,
once you return a phone call.
And he's like saying I don't return
phone calls,
check my phone records.
He's not called.
I've talked to him once on the phone.
He's never called me again.
So he's like making up all this shit and
telling me to fuck off and about.
I have no idea.
But you know,
from,
from the people that came to me after
that,
like a lot of,
a big comedians came to me and was like,
dude,
you know,
we,
I have problems with him,
you know,
f this guy.
Don't,
don't worry.
Doesn't like them.
Yeah.
Stan hope doesn't like him.
That's pretty well known.
But uh,
yeah,
I mean it's,
you know what?
I don't know what his problem is.
I have no problem with the guy.
I just,
you know,
he had a little hissy fit and now just
so I wouldn't it though,
it doesn't make sense that he would just
go after you on twitter like that and he
was like,
be a man while he's going after you on
twitter and he's saying that I'm not
returning calls.
I'm making a pretty much fake bullshit.
How weird is it to,
to go after someone on twitter saying
you're not calling me?
Yeah,
like,
that's,
that's weird to will be a man.
Are you going after someone on twitter?
And I liked Jay.
I've never had a single problem with
Jay.
Jay Moore and I have always been cool.
I was looking forward to having him on
the podcast and I actually wrote him a
message saying,
Hey,
let's work this out next week.
I'm busy with fear factor.
I'll call you soon.
And then right after I wrote that,
then I read all these tweets that you
and him were going back and forth with
wasn't doing shit.
He,
towards you were just getting tweeted at
when he was calling you a bitch or
whatever the fuck he was saying to you
and I was like,
this is just weird.
Did he get drunk or something and just
know from what people have been telling
me that he has a,
a,
a side of him where he spazzes out and
uh,
this is normal for him.
Like I guess like he just goes after
people.
He just has a temper,
you know,
you have problems with them.
I've just made a lot of people know,
you know,
your buddy now.
Either people is that magical problems
with them?
I don't know.
Problems.
I just avoid them.
When you told them you're buddying up
with them.
I just closed my fucking head because I
knew that was going to be a disaster
because just,
just why?
Why?
Well,
I was just going to do his podcast.
So I like him.
I looked at,
I said,
I think he's funny.
He's got great impressions.
That dude that does the best.
Christopher walken on the fucking face
of the planet.
He's a,
he's got a Hilarious Colin Quinn,
his Collin Quinn is.
This is funny as colony Quinn.
I mean I think he's a talented guy.
He's Kevin.
I don't know.
It's not the commerce.
Oh,
look what I know.
I know that's the problem.
I have to judge them.
I have to judge them based on my
interactions and my interactions with
him have always been cool.
He's always been nice to me.
I've never had a problem with them.
He's always been cool with me,
but you know,
I don't like reading all that shit.
I don't like seeing anybody doing shit
like that.
But you did that to Brian to you know,
you,
you wouldn't have to Brian to on twitter
just the same way back,
but it's the same fucking way he went
after him on twitter the exact same way
that you're criticizing right here.
First of all,
I didn't know what was really going on
and if you want to really know Brian,
it was these motherfuckers that got us
all going because me and you will cool.
Who's calling me back?
All these outside forces that we call
our [inaudible] friends
were the ones that with twitter,
me and st all this shit.
So next time you sit on a fucking tell
you and that's why I got pissed off when
I went to Jerry's that night and that
dude came up to me.
That's what got me pissed off because
you're my brother.
You want me?
Never had a fucking problem.
We goof around all the fucking time.
That's why when,
when they told me that you were furious
and stuff,
I got hurt.
I called you right away.
There's no.
You know what I mean?
I call or I show up.
That's the worst thing about it.
I love showing up.
Guys.
Just haven't found it right here,
bro.
I love you to death.
And then I left him like every fucking
nothing like that though.
I know.
You know.
Listen Bro.
That's why I don't deal with a lot of
these fucking guys because I know it's
going to end up and this is the type of
person I am.
I don't know how that deal.
I don't know how to argue that.
I don't know how to go to court.
I don't know how to play those games.
Those are not games that I grew up plan.
So when people throw that at me or be
bureaucratics,
whatever the fuck that word is,
I can't deal with that.
Talk to me.
I know,
but just come talk to me like a man
because if you don't know that,
I suspect
if they don't come talk to me like a
man,
Brian,
they don't come talk to you like a man.
Then you got to suspect that containers
and then you don't want after a while
they want to do it on them because I
know like my mom used to say if it sucks
in the beginning it's gonna suck all the
way through.
So just leave it alone.
If you have a bad week the first day
with them,
you know what?
This is going to suck all the way
through.
So let's just shaking part friends
because why put yourself
through the shit before I start getting
angry at someone is not here again.
I'll tell you,
I was fucking 12 years old.
I told that cock sucker.
Then I'll tell you now,
ladies and gentlemen,
play the music.
Let's,
let's wrap this bitch up.
Let's bring this mother fucker home.
Let's bring it home in a positive
direction.
Joe Diaz,
and I know you said something on twitter
the other day that people will talk
about positivity or probably concert.
They all really are really,
really.
I talk about that shit.
You gotta lighten up,
but you got to stop beating on my
fucking cough drops.
You came over here and yellow,
100,000
negative things today.
Don't you tell me what to be positive
and negative.
No,
it helps people.
It helps people recognize that other
people like to think that way too.
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm talking about whatever the fuck I
want.
I got a podcast.
Bitch.
You can't stop me.
You can't tell me what the fuck they
talking about.
I'm going to keep it going.
I'm going to keep the bumping.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that squad.
Two thousand 12,
Tuesday,
August ninth.
Go Holla at your boy.
Thank you to the fleshlight.
Please go to Joe Rogan.net,
click on the link for the fleshlight,
entering the code name Brogan,
and you will get 15 percent off the
number one sex toy for man,
and you could shoot little jeanette to
your heart's content at a discount.
They don't pee on you.
See you next week.
Thank you guys.