Don't crash, crash as much. I
don't think that's the issue.
Four, three, two,
this time we're live.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are live with the great and powerful
Russell Peters. Hi. And one of the baddest
motherfuckers ever get into the ring.
Lennox Lewis don't mess with the best.
That's a fact that you go,
you're walking around on this earth,
one of the baddest motherfuckers of all
time verified 100% feel good about it
too. It's kind of feel good. Yeah.
Don't get into the new fights,
but you know what else? You have
your wits about you 100%. You,
you smooth and relaxed, you
know, how did you do that? Oh,
I started out that way.
It's like, uh, you know, uh,
apple don't fall too far from
the tree type of thing. Uh,
I've always been that way.
Uh, co collective thinker,
a soft spoken. And what?
You don't know about me?
Well you don't know about me when you
do know about me or love me even more.
Do you exercise at all
anymore? Boxing wise? Yeah.
Hit the bag and not hit the bag. I'm more
into like working out with the weights.
It wasn't like it was hard for me when
I retired. That was the worst part.
What was the hardest?
Just you know,
saying okay you know I'm eating
more so I need to exercise common,
not doing no exercise, but when I start
exercising I'm training for a fight.
Right. So it's like okay train
and train and why am I doing this?
I'm not going to fight but I'm
still training for a fight.
So mentally I had to say to myself,
well let me try the soft things,
you know and play tennis and all these
different sports which I can play and
that kind of helped me a lot better.
Yeah. That is an interesting
thing with fighters.
A lot of times when they're done, they're
done. They just look at my data. Yeah.
Well he's apparently got training.
He's got these back in training camp.
But my Diana gum in the why,
cause he probably got an Instagram.
People started talking shit cause kind
of fat and that's what made me want to
lose weight. Yeah. People Talking
Shit. He were like, holy fuck.
Did you eat your whole cast?
You do look like he losing weight though.
You looked pretty slim. I Fed,
I lost 21 pounds with our, uh,
with our dear friend Jean Jacques
Machado who, Hey Jiu Jitsu,
we'll peel that weight
off. Yeah. That's a fact.
That's some strenuous shit you ever
thought about doing Jujitsu legs.
He's scared of me. He won't do
it. Whoa. Let me, let me tell you,
when I was growing up,
I had that,
I had friends that did wrestling,
I had friends that did kickbox
and all these different, um, uh,
mediums and um, you know, we would always
practice with them where this wrestling,
whether it's a kick in, whether it's,
um, doing whatever play, fighting,
you did all that stuff.
Yeah.
Because everybody always wants to
test a boxer and say, well, you know,
how does he fit up against the karate guy?
How's,
if you're up against that a kickbox
how's he fear up against a MMA guy?
Yeah.
They always fair financially better.
So, uh, you for, for me,
I didn't really throw my weight
around like that. You know, it's like,
don't mess with me. Okay. If you mess
with me, something's going to happen.
And then they don't really mess with them.
I kind of carry myself like that yet
cause I'm so serious at sometimes like you
know, they can take the
consents, the seriousness of it
series, but still easy going.
So no reason to push you. Right.
I'm s I'm silent but
violent. Ooh, I liked that.
Silent.
Silent or violent.
It is an interesting deal about
about fighters is that your,
when you think of exercise,
you think of exercise as you're
preparing for a big violent event.
Whereas for most people, they just don't
want to be fat. They want to look good,
they want to get in shape.
And you know,
it's a lot of people on Instagram that
just working out really hard every day.
But there's no reason. Right.
You had a reason. Yes. Yeah.
So when the reason's gone,
it's like, hmm, now what?
How do I maintain this shameless and
without maintaining that lifestyle.
You think of another reason.
Yeah.
Oh, like you, you know,
you look good by the way.
Thanks. Does or could makes seen
me since I was 147 pounds. Really?
You were 147 pounds at one point.
I was kind. I first started boxing.
I was one 47 how old
were you? 15 oh, okay.
I met him probably when
I was 16 Oh really? Yeah.
You guys have known each other that long.
Yeah, I know his parents. Yeah. Wow.
And his and his mom and his
brothers. Every, wow. It
goes back, we're deep creek.
You don't realize that. It was like,
you know, I see him as a big star now.
I seen the movies and commercials
rescuing people, you know what I mean?
I'm like, Yo, this is the kid, you know,
he's grown up. He's like literallyZ ,
literally just selling mix tapes in the
90s he was already world champ and I'd
be playing a mix tape. Yo Send me that
and I'm like, I just made it. He was like,
I'll give you 20 bucks. I'm
like, you just made $100 million.
Can you give me 100 bucks?
Yeah. Well, you know,
everybody was making tapes back then.
Those days when people are aggressively
trying to sell tapes on the streets.
I wasn't even trying to sell it. I was
just playing it in my car and he was like,
yeah. So he got, he had the new shit
going on, you know, that
was, you had the real shit.
So I had to get a go get it.
I didn't,
I didn't have that contact to get the
music, so he had the music contacts. Okay.
A lot of people don't know Russell's a
legit Dj. I reluctantly gave me mix tapes.
Reluctantly. Yeah, it's a
good move. Um, when you know,
when you see him wrestling with
people on Tmz, you see that shit
wrestling with the jewel thief.
Always trying to see what happened
after he didn't throw no punches. Go on.
Good kid. His neck, if
you watch it, you see,
I went for his arm to pull down to get
his neck and then the other guy in front
of him pulled him down and
I couldn't get the neck.
Could you tell us what happened?
I mean, explain what happened.
All I seen was a guy walking out and you
grab them. No, if you're watching it,
okay, let me tell you what happens. I'm
there looking at a ring, right? Yeah.
And that guy sitting down earlier had
checked to see if the door was open.
He went out to spit and now he really,
he thinks the door's open,
so now he thinks he's just going to
get up and walk away with this ring.
This is where he makes his little move
and then they lock the doors and then I'm
standing there, I'm like,
what's going on? And I'm like,
he takes a swing at my friend's
father and then I go, no, no.
I tried to get his neck
and that guy pulls him.
You see there's a lot of opportunities
yet the neck there. So no, but I'm trying,
he's a big strong fucking guy too.
You got to go over the top.
I will look Tom just trying. But I
had three layers on. Got a jacket,
a sweatshirt and a long sleeve shirt on.
There is an issue and then a,
so then I try to go for the arm.
But everybody sees everybody's in my way.
So I'm like, give me the arm. Just let
me get the eye move, Dad, move dad, mate.
That's uncle David. And there I get,
I get the arm, the backward base.
Now I'm pushing the arm down and
you'll see I locked the wrist here.
As soon as I locked the army
says, he says, okay, I want
you to stop some living.
Right. There it goes.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Yeah,
I got the rest of the [inaudible]
Steven Seagal style. That was my friend.
Senpai shall look. Oh, there you go. Relax
or legit. He got up again. No, no, no.
This is just a different angle.
Different.
I want to know how far we was going
to make with a ring. You see, um,
see that wall where my cousin is hiding,
when he was trying to get out, he whacked
his head against that wall. Oh No.
And uh, and he could see her
open. Th th th the thief. Yeah.
So whatever happened to
him, he got arrested. I was
carrying, was this in Toronto?
No, in New York City. No Shit.
Right in the jewelry district. Wow.
So it's funny.
That's like ill planned out move.
Yeah. They know that people
grab things and run away.
Well there's that and he apparently this
guy had been coming to the store for
six months scoping, scoping the
place out. Oh that's hilarious.
Scoped it up poorly. That's
hilarious. Yeah. Just silly.
Do you have to go to court or anything?
I don't know.
I haven't heard anything since
and I just put them in the,
I all I was trying to do is hold them
there because all the doors were locked.
I'm like, it doesn't make sense
again to a scrap, but the guy,
if I could just put him in a choke hold
or, or a lock then till the cops come.
But the thing is like you could injure
him. If you enjoy him then they suit you.
Well yeah, not really. As ridiculous
as it sounds. It's rough work.
Well Russell is not really
a law enforcement officer.
I could see if you had,
nobody would have been
dangerous, everybody in the
store if he was running wild.
True. Yeah. So I mean look, he's lucky
he didn't crack them. Yeah. You know,
I just locked him up and I
said, all right, as soon as
I locked up because, okay.
I'm like, okay, good.
And then he had one knee,
one knee down and one leg up and
I kick that leg out so he would,
we'd be bombed both knees. Get
rid of his base. Yes. Right.
I was trying to move Wizbang Bang.
Who's the bitch? Got a question. Okay.
Now if the whole thing happened again,
how would you do things different?
I would have told everybody get out of
my way so I can get him in a choke and,
Huh. Okay. Would you just
put him to sleep? Yeah. Just
put them asleep. Lamb down.
Yeah.
Lay him down,
talk him in and he went back home and
obviously feel good about yourself.
Did you kind of run the whole
thing through your mind a
couple of times? Like Yo,
this could have happened or what could
happen after if he had a gun or if he had
a knife, but I'm like, if he had a gun, he
would have pulled it out right away. Wow.
Yeah. You know, he's not here
to surprise you with a gun.
He's here to scare you with the gun.
Well,
if there's all that many dudes on them
too, good luck pulling that gun out. Yeah.
Yeah. One of us would've got shot, but,
but probably not food or
something that if you,
you probably got real urgent if you
saw him reaching for something. Yeah,
it would have changed. I think needs to,
the head would have kicked everything.
Everything.
I know.
I watch while the coronial different
things you could do like a little loop.
We want to practice karate.
You ever want to do something different?
That's why I was asking you about
your Jitsu because you know,
when you're a world heavyweight
champion boxer after, why?
Like what other shit can I learn?
I kept arm locking her in England.
I kept hugging him, putting
them in like, um, you know,
great Bruce Lee Fan.
I love fighting movies and uh,
you know,
martial arts is always
been a part of my life.
And I say that because every fight
I fought before I fought that fight,
I watched the martial arts
movie. Really? What, uh,
Chuck Norris, Bruce Lee, that
kind of shit, leave venom.
All the real shit. Yeah.
So those kind of movies, Carter
Wong and type stuff, you know? Yeah.
I like that. And that just got me in
that mental state. Like, you know,
you watch him I today. Yeah. Do
you, do you ever watch it and go,
if this was around when I was
fighting, would I do this? Um,
the only thing I think about that
because, you know, like I said,
I was in the wrestling and I did wrestling
when I was younger and boxing as well,
so I didn't know they could combine them
too. So like got older, but you know,
my focus was more on
boxing. Uh, but you know,
if they got paid a lot of money I probably
would have done it, you know? Yeah.
That's how a lot of people feel,
I think. I think like right now,
the money's not quite there.
It's not quite,
it's for some people that Conor
McGregor or Ronda Rousey and,
but for the other folks,
it's not,
it's not enough to get a guy like Earl
spends to jump over there, you know? No.
And then I see a lot of,
I've seen some boxers actually good at
boxing actually just win the fight on
boxing because they're so good with
their hands and your stance has to be
different. You can't have your lead
leg out in MMA. That's the problem.
You can't stand the sideways. Yeah,
you gotta you got just square up,
your leg will get lit up.
I Dunno.
I stand sideways even in the fight
because I know that I stick that leg out
there for them to come, come
at and obviously, you know,
it's easy to grab a leg,
but to me,
I don't think fighting should
start that way anyway. Nobody,
when you start fighting,
usually punches are thrown quick
and it lasts a couple seconds.
Nobody really just goes straight
legs unless they say, okay,
I'm going to go for his legs and take
him down. Nobody in there kick your leg.
Yeah, they kill you. Can't walk
the kid leg kicks are brutal.
You have been like kicked.
Yeah. Yeah. It's rough.
A guy on the leg one time and I was like,
I couldn't move.
And I'm like still thinking
if we got in a fight,
kicked him in the leg and they
gave me a dead look like this.
I don't know what I would do. So,
and if it's a guy like your size,
like a Rico Verhoeven, like whose glory
world? Heavyweight kickboxing champion,
they just keep their hands up and chew
your legs up mean one or two shots of
your legs. And it's a horrible
feeling. It's like doesn't move. Right?
It's like it just gives out. I write
on the side of your knee. Oh, well.
Oh well, you know what?
You know he used to,
did you guys look like you've accepted
that? I's like I go mad. Yeah.
Someone kicks me in Mulligan
like, Yo, you kicked me in my leg.
I don't think anybody's kicking
you and your leg. And even,
did you ever see when Shannon and,
and try it out some kickboxing? No.
Shanna breaks fought. Uh, Tom
Erickson. Oh goes, no, no.
He fucked him up. Shannon got leg
kicked out and he said he, he, you know,
Chan and talks. He's hilarious. He
goes, champ, he goes, it hurts so bad.
But I tried to play it off champ.
He got hit with one leg kick,
then you got to hit with
another one. But he, he,
he touched him with like a jab to the
body and Tom Erickson got a little cocky.
Here it is right here. He, uh, he,
he fought when he was in
like this transitionary
period and they offered him a
lot of money. Like right there. He got
leg kicked by this guy and the guy,
Tom Erickson that he fought
is really more of a wrestler.
He kicked him twice and then Shannon t he,
he actually broke it down
for us on the podcast,
but he said his leg was hurting so
bad and he tried to go the guide into
thinking that he could punch with them.
See, they got hit again and he's like,
oh Jesus, he's letting him hit. I
would knock that guy out. Yeah. But he,
you think you would just let them do that.
But once you get hit with one
of those things like that,
it's so crippling to your leg. You
don't move around. You're right.
Cause like I said, you know, I got hit
there and I was like, oh my liquid move.
The thing is that you marry him just
locked up. Huh? You put Shannon to sleep.
It was a great fight to Erickson tried
to box with it for some strange reason.
He got into this crazy idea at like right
there, boom. Clipped good night. Yeah.
And that's it. He's got the
one shell champ. Chill boxing,
kickboxing, because they're wearing
gloves when no shoes, no shoes aren't,
aren't you suppose?
Isn't Shannon Briggs supposed to at least
kick a couple of times? Well, you know,
if he knew how to, but I think he
went into their thinking, you know,
I'll just crack them with a punch and
knock him out. Which he did. You know, he,
he ate a couple of leg kicks, but it's
hilarious when you hear him break it down.
He's, how old are you now? Owe me. Yeah,
I'm under a hundred under a hundred or
under a hundred but you can't be any more
than like, what are you? 45
47 hold. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. Are you older than
that? 51 want to say you're a great guy.
You're a great, you don't want to
say people have internet out there,
so they'll just look. How old is
he? 53 you look great. Thank you.
You do right, doesn't he? He's always look
good. But when you were like, you were,
you're one of those guys
who did the smart, you were
tired and you just retired.
Yes. You know, which
is, I respect so much.
We were just talking about
Marvin Hagler the other day.
[inaudible] when Marvin Hagler retired,
he's like, goodnight. Take care of buddy.
Lost a controversial decision to
sugar ray Leonard. He said, hey,
I'm going to go do some movies. And
that was it. He just never came back.
It's so rare that a fight or
does that well, you know what?
Marvin was disheartened
like a motherfucker for
boxing though. He hated it.
He was like,
I'm out.
Yeah, yeah. Um, you know,
w boxes go through so much and uh,
it's like when they know,
when it's time,
when a box that says it's time to quit,
they know it's time because they've gone
through so much and they realize that
it's a lot of hard work for me.
I've been boxing since I've been 15,
so you know, in training,
hundreds of hours training,
hundreds of hours working out Restin uh,
working on a technique, sparring, all
these different things. After a while,
you know, you have to read, you reached
that height where you say, okay,
that's enough. And
sometimes you know, people,
managers and trainers and promoters,
they don't want to tell the box if that's
enough because that's how much they're
making money off of that box every time
you stepped in the ring. Right. So, um,
did you have a conversation with
Emmanuel Stewart about it? Absolutely.
And who made the decision?
Did you guys make it together?
Uh, I made the decision he wanted
me actually to go on. Really? Yeah.
Cause I want it to, Tyson was my
main nemesis. And, um, you know,
he's a, he's a boxer that I definitely
wanted to fight before retiring.
And A, I didn't know if it
was going to happen or not.
So I actually stuck around for a couple
more years for that fight to happen
because I didn't want,
throughout history people will be saying,
oh Tyson with the one or Lewis was the
one I wanted them to know who write one.
Right. And then after that, after the
Tyson fight, you know, Manny said, listen,
Chris goes around,
that's the new generation.
You can beat the guys from this generation
and the guys from the next generation.
I'm like, yeah, that sounds good.
So he kinda talked me into doing that
fight cause I wasn't really going to go do
that fight. And then, um, you know,
that was a year after Tyson and I didn't
really want to box him straight away.
I want it to bug somebody else because
the main nemesis was Tyson. And you know,
once I, once I beat Tyson, you
know, I could relax a little bit,
a relaxed for a year and then getting
back into boxing I box Klitschko was my
first fund,
which was a mistake.
Took the fight 1717 days notice at
my worst I beat him at his best.
Why was it such a short notice fight?
Because the opponent that I actually
picked to fight didn't fuck,
didn't want to fight me.
He actually said no,
it was supposed to be a Johnson
from, oh yeah, Kurt Johnson,
Johnson, Nova Scotia from Nova
school. You were doing him a favor.
I think politico felt that he was
doing him a favor. Listen, take.
Let me take the fight. I've been trained
in for two years for this guy. I'm ready.
And then we'll give you
the first shot after I win.
That's what was promised to him. Battalion
has such a weird style, didn't he? Yeah,
he did.
And that's that kickboxing style coming
into play a little bit because he would
throw a punch and lean back like this.
And that's the first time I've
actually seen that style. And you know,
if I didn't reach out with my
right hand as far as I did,
I would never have caught him with that
cut and it was that long right hand that
cotton just at the end of my punch when
he leaned back and he couldn't lean back
anymore. That made is I cut. Yeah.
He was a very strange fighter
in terms of his style,
just the way her hands were always
down is a very weird way of moving.
Very Unorthodox because he was such a
big guy. He was six foot seven. Yeah,
there was. It was probably the
biggest guy you fought, right? Yeah.
Could you take it? Have you ever shot,
you're never far guns I listed yet.
Michael Grant was big guns. All of
this I I boxed in the limb. Okay.
Luis Gonzales that was named, right? Yeah.
Cuban guy. Yup. They are looking at like,
look how weird the way he fights is
just such an awkward way of moving.
He hit me good with a
right hand and I held on,
I see me holding him around the neck.
That from Mohammed Ali.
He said if you hold a
gun Chi around the neck,
you can tell when he's going
to move. Mm. Wow. Well he was,
he was good in the,
in the first few rounds
after the first three rounds,
what people don't realize about this
fight. I wasn't fighting for, uh,
for 12 rounds.
I was fighting to knock this guy out.
Okay,
because you had it in your mind.
Yeah.
Like this is the first time you ever
see me going forward in the fight.
This guy's bigger than me. I'm coming
forward and I'm throwing punches.
He's catching me.
But those were the early rounds.
Although he's two inches taller than you,
you look bigger than him.
He just like fellas ugly. Physically,
you're wider, you know, when,
when you look back on your career,
like do you have like a most satisfying
victory? Yeah. What is it? Ah,
seem Rockman I was going to say that.
I was going to say the rematch the first
or the second. The second one is Christ.
When a guy, when a guy beats
you like that and then you know,
you could have beaten him or
you should have beaten them.
Is that what bothered you
so much? Um, no, you know,
it really bothered me is the fact
that I gave them an opportunity.
I gave him a fight when,
uh,
I'm basically waiting for
Tyson and I have to keep busy.
I'm looking down the list of who to fight.
He's number seven.
I realized that he's durable is nothing,
not one of these guys that got knocked
out easy. So I wanted to give my fans,
you know,
a proper fight box,
the best guy out there and not bucks an
easy guy that's easy to get knocked out.
I don't want to go home in two rounds.
So,
and then another reason a
lot of people don't know,
I went to Africa to fight because
Muhammad Ali went to Africa,
he fought in Africa. So I wanted
to do that. I want us to be,
I wanted to fight in Africa.
If I say I'm a world champion,
so I need to find all the world.
So that's what made me go to Africa.
The only thing about Africa is I didn't
know that it was such a high altitude up
there and for me to have a fight,
I should have got there a lot earlier,
but I was doing ocean's 11 at that time.
And you say you were doing the movie?
I wasn't doing the movie.
I was sitting around half the time
waiting for them to change the lights,
then go out and go up there for two
minutes and then go back and sit there for
another two hours while
they changed the light.
So we training at all when that was
happening. Yeah, I was training,
but it wasn't like it wasn't
the conditions of training.
You know, I needed a bag,
I needed sparring partners
and we up there a lot sooner.
So you're just kind of traumatize.
Yes. How many thousand feet?
Was It above sea level? Higher than
a big beer? It was Cape Town. Right,
so more than six. Wow. I
didn't know that. Yeah,
it was kind of weird because when I
started working out I was like throwing
punches.
Then I found myself going,
so I had to take two steps
back and I'm like, oh no, no,
don't tell me this fight is going to be
one of those fights where I have to take
my time. So I basically went out
there taking my time. I realized he's,
he's dealing with the same
thing I'm dealing with,
although he was there a lot earlier,
but you know,
I had a couple of things going wrong
boxing at four in the morning. Uh,
they couldn't find a big enough ring.
Then they,
when they put the ring together it
was like a 18 by 19 so and then the,
the punch that actually hit me, I
actually thought I was going to block it,
but it came around this side.
I'll put my hand,
I put my hand up to block it,
but it came around and hit me.
One of those things where a man through
a terrific punch with my chin happened
to be in the way of,
what is it like when that's
over and you're sitting
there and you know you lost,
but you know that under the
right circumstances this
guy is not at your level.
Uh, in fact, you know, my problem was
solved before I got out of the ring.
I knew what I did wrong, which was the
greatest thing that ever happened to me.
He's like, Oh, another day he wouldn't
throw a lucky punch like that.
It wouldn't hit me and he wouldn't
have a ref that, you know,
was on his side as well. How
was it rough on her side? Um,
when I say the refs on his side,
you know, I got it a little early.
I got knocked down in the second round.
I'm the, I'm the champion. Right.
At least giving me a chance, not waive the
fight straight. Right, right. You know,
you've seen, you've seen the Deontae,
a Tyson fight. Like, you know,
if that was the ref,
he counted them out straight away.
That's what it stopped it at
the press conference 12th round.
That right left Deontae landed the
fact that Tyson got up and then one the
remainder of the round.
That is crazy. Yeah.
I am so frustrated that fights not
happening again, man. Every, you know,
I'm looking at the heavyweight
scene and, um, I'm looking at,
obviously I'm Joshua Joshua
from England and you know,
he had the opportunity to fight the
Auntie and didn't take it. I'm like,
if that was me,
I would've took that chance because you
never know what happens down the road.
Likes what's happening
now. And um, you know,
to me it's being put on the shelf now.
We asked to box somebody that
nobody really wants him to box.
Who's he fighting next? A baby.
A baby. Middle, a big baby.
Miller, big baby, you know,
big baby millet. I haven't seen too much
of him. I don't know too much about him,
but you know, he's talks a good
fight. I knew, I know he weighed,
weighed over 300 pounds at one
time and, and yeah. And uh,
you know, now he's got an
opportunity to fight the Joshua,
so he's taken full advantage of
it. Like he should. But you know,
I don't see anything in his history
to show me that he can beat Joshua,
move you beacon. He can, he can bag now
he can bang. If you're there to Bang Josh.
Joshua has got feed, he's going to move.
He's not going to stay there and bang.
Yeah, he's going to be a smart boxer
in this fight, allegedly. We'll see.
Right. I mean, you never
know. Yeah. I mean this,
this isn't one of those things where
I think this is where Anthony gotta be
extra careful because Miller going to
try and twice as hard and if Joshua
doesn't train,
like he's fighting Deontae right.
He's gonna he may take it for granted,
make a mistake
and you can do that. I've done that.
I've done that. And it's nothing.
It's nothing that he's done on purpose.
It's not, it's like it's a mental thing.
Yeah. It's a mental thing. Like when
you were fighting my Ravitch. Yeah.
That guy wouldn't go home.
We wouldn't go home, go home.
He gave me a lot of trouble. I was at
that fight, gave me a lot of trouble.
Um,
Lennox box,
this guy around the ring for 12 rounds,
like literally the guys heads snapping
back and this guy's not going.
He was going nowhere. That
is, that's gotta be a weird
feeling too. When you know how hard you
punch and you see a guy just eating them.
Like some people just are built
weird. They just can take a shot. No,
I learned that coming up.
I learned that like, Yo,
some guys that are tough to the
head or week to the body, uh,
some guys are tough to the body week to
the head and some guys are just made out
of rocks.
Yeah.
It's almost like a ignorant bliss.
It just don't know they're
supposed to feel bad.
I don't know. I mean, I really
think it's a physiological thing.
I think some guys can just take a shot.
Uh, they just, they just built better.
Sometimes.
I've been in fights where I've gone in,
the man's hit me on the Chin first couple
minutes and it's like he just glanced
off my chin.
I was like an eight har ain't gonna
Punch up and it didn't hurt me and it was
like, what happened to a punch? It
was so hard. It hit you on the chin.
Everybody was saying, Yo, did you see that
punch? He never felt him. I'm like, no.
And when I look at tape of it,
it's like, wow, I did get it. Hmm.
Is it because like are there a bunch
of factors like how much you got hit in
training, how well you feel coming into
the fight where you're at in your career.
And there's a lot of factors. Like
for instance, let me give you a good,
we could factor,
if you have a box for two years and all
of a sudden you step into the ring and
it's a title fight and you box,
you got the first good hit you get is
going to concuss you really because you,
you haven't been getting those
hits for that last two years.
Now this man hit you
with a two years, uh, um,
and you're getting used
to it and you have,
you felt it and you've gotten over it.
You need to get over that hill.
Is it a mental hill? It is a mental
health because even for me, for me,
when I haven't fought for awhile, you
know, I call out there until I get hit.
Once I get hit that wakes
everything. I'm just like, Yo,
this is not supposed to go like that.
You're not supposed to hit me.
I'm supposed to hit you.
So I get, I get going.
So the hot steam Rockmont
fight after it was over,
were you worried that you were going to
get, we're not going to get a rematch?
Yes, I was very worried. In
fact, we chased them two,
three courts around the world and the,
he didn't want to fight me. And I,
you know, if I was in this
position, I wouldn't want to
fight me that because, uh,
you know, I'm coming back for revenge.
Plus there's a big money fight out.
They would Tyson brunch. He, so, um,
so happened to say after the fight,
no more Louis Tyson,
no more Louis Tyson and
he actually left um,
South Africa without visiting Mandela.
Like why you go African of a Mandela?
I did. He just wanted to
get out of there. Yeah,
he just belt and that $7 million
that he got off of Don King.
So the fight got made again because
after the third courtroom the judge says,
whose signature is this? How it seems
that it was his, you signed it? Yes.
Well you got to give him the rematch.
This is,
you signed it to give them a rematch
so you have to give him a rematch.
So he didn't want to hear that. So I was
happy. So the, and how long did it take?
Two years.
And then was all that,
all those brawls in the,
remember the ESPN studio when him and
Rockman I got into a fight over a table
and everything. Yeah. The Alex was wearing
this big Steve Harvey suit. Did you
let me tell you it wasn't
Steve RBC to cause I had this,
I'm going to have the
slipper shoes in the world.
I didn't come here to fight
that too. Like, you know,
do press slippery shoes are the worst.
If anything goes down.
You got those leather
shoulder. Oh my God. On carpet.
That's where you got to know,
learn Jujitsu.
Now when you were in that time period,
I don't remember.
Did you have fights in between? Uh, yeah.
How many fights did you have after a
rock? Oh No. It didn't have no fights.
No fights. No. No. I just trained
for Rockman. Just waited. Yeah,
so it took you two years. Two years. That
must have been so frustrating. It was.
It was because you never know if you're
going to get the fight or not or you
know,
these guys are running from you.
They signed to fight a rematch because
you know now they didn't want to sign it.
I remember when that right hand landed.
I remember when I was watching it at
home and I threw my arms up in the air.
I was like, Oh shit. I went to sleep.
Let's,
let's check this out man.
I mean for a long time come
and you're waiting for it.
You know,
for this,
this flight Rockman couldn't catch me
cause my speed was different. You know,
in South Africa it was a lot slower.
Now he got kind of a little
frustrated because he couldn't
get to this. Boom. Yup.
Oh Man. No. Over the top of the
shoulder. Let them counts though.
Oh,
that was a phenomenal player.
That was probably one of the most
satisfying one punch knock outs I've ever
watched because I knew what you had gone
through and I knew like everybody knew
you were one of the greatest of all time
and to have you get chaos like that.
First of all,
it made it endeared people to you in a
way because it shows your vulnerability,
but also your character and your ability
to come back, which is not easy. Man.
When you get stopped like that,
like psychologically,
it's got to be fucking with your head.
Let me tell you,
the first time I lost everybody was coming
up and shaking my hand and said, well,
what are you going to do now?
I'm like,
what do you mean what am
I going to do now? Yeah.
What you gonna do now is I'm going to
go back and when my championship I said
okay, you know, they didn't think
it was going to be possible,
but I'm thinking Muhammad Ali
gained the championship three times.
Yeah. So I've only lost it
once. I can do it again.
It takes a special person to
do it and I can do it. Do you,
do you feel like there was
like two stages of your career?
Like Pre Emanuel steward
and post? Yeah, absolutely.
There's two sizes of them too.
Then if you look at it serves like he
went from like a, like a, a skinny,
a skinny kid to a man. Like it just giant
fucking man out of nowhere. Yeah. Um,
the PRI, the PRI manual stew
was obviously, you know,
me learning how to be a
professional learning to fight pro.
And then once I got to a manual,
we just like, Yo, he said, hey,
you're a great fighter. You
know, he used to move around La,
we've got to bring that back.
And I'm like, okay, cool.
So the movement and he brought back, he
taught me a couple of uh, Kronk tricks,
you know, that check hook and different
things that the Krung fighters do,
which works well. Um, and uh, you
know, he was easy to understand.
Then what I liked about him, what he
said I can do, I could accomplish.
He just told me what to do. I'll
do it. Yeah. If he said, Lynn,
we need to win this room and I'll
win that round. You know what I mean?
You had that kind of
relationship, right? Yeah.
He was really one of the great
masters. You know, there, there's,
there's certain masters when it
comes to like boxing training.
Like when you would hear
him discuss fighters,
like I really loved hearing
him do commentary as well
because he would discuss
fighters and what they need to do
and he was always just dead on.
He just knew things.
He understood boxing so comprehensively.
He just knew what a fighter needed to do.
So I was so excited when he started
working with you because it was like,
well that's, that's exactly what Lennox
needs. So it was HBO because you know,
it's funny, I'll do fights on HBO and
they will say, oh, he's doing this,
he's not doing this.
He needs to do more.
And he's a total nut job
more than Emmanuel started
working for me and he's like,
oh, he's doing the jab was doing well.
I was like, Oh, this is what you need.
You need a great coach at time. You're
going on TV that the commentators respect.
Then they'll talk good about the boxer.
But if you're not a good trainer is like,
what do they need to talk about?
They took a lot of shit and boxing
commentary. Oh yeah, they did.
They let you know whose side they're
on. They always are. You know,
you could talk about how they're guiding
your brain to watch the fight. Well,
they also, they'd talk a little shit.
It's more like sports commentary,
like a mixed martial arts commentary.
Yeah, I don't, I don't do that.
I don't really talk shit
ever. I mean, I occasionally,
if something's egregiously bad
I'll talk about that. You know,
there's real issues here, but
I tried to, I tried to just
write a comment. Both of them aren't, I
try hard at that because I wasn't always,
you know, I've, I've had, and I
learned how to do it on the job.
Nobody really knew how to do.
There wasn't a lot of people doing
it before I started doing it.
What sucks for you because your
findings with all the fighters,
it's hard when you watch a friend of yours
fuck up another friend of yours. Yeah,
that's hard.
What about a friend of you as a student?
Something wrong that needs to do
something right? Do you tell him?
I tell him privately, uh, Mo, CIF
from, for me, I would like to,
I wish I was like that. I wish
I could do that, but you know,
people want more truth out in me,
so I try and bring it across in the
software and not make it too harsh.
I would bring, I would say there's
issues like I see something,
if I see like a vulnerability, I
will, I will, I'll discuss that.
But if there's something that
someone needs to work on or do,
I'll try to pull them aside, you know? But
most of them know, you know, just there,
you know, like MMA fighters,
I'm sure a lot like boxer sick.
There's different kinds of humans and
some of them are just fucking wild.
And those wild ones, you know, a lot
of times they never become champion,
but they're the most exciting people
to watch. Like, like Micky Ward,
like making words, fights with a Touro
God. There are some of the greatest,
cause they were,
the way they matched up some of the,
I would never want one of my friends to
fight like that to lunatics and one rain.
I'm like, God man, those
fights where chaos though.
Everybody knew that those guys were,
they're never going to be made whether
they're never going to beat the best guys,
but God damn,
they were fun to watch some of the crazy,
they were like raising generations.
Uh, uh, prior. Arguayo almost, almost,
except they went back and
forth and back and forth.
You know who, who was it that, uh,
had an arm injury and still boxed?
Micky Ward?
No, it wasn't at Bernard Hopkins when
he fought Antwan Eccles. He, uh, I,
I might, I might be wrong. You mean a
blood got permanent, like a broken arm.
Someone got their arm broke
in or pulled out. That was a,
it was Antwan Eccles. It might've been
against Hopkins or was against somebody,
but somebody,
the guy who picked him up and slammed
him and he dislocated his shoulder and
then the ref was like, should I stop
the fight? It's like, no, no, no.
And he knocked the guy
with the left hook after,
but it just can't be
done with his left hand.
He's got slammed and they stopped the
fight. Then he came and won the rematch.
Remember that? Uh, yes, but
I, I recall, I recall them.
Guy would knock him out in the next round
with his left hand only was at Hopkins.
It might've been Hopkins Eccles.
If, and I'll tell you what,
one of the hardest fights for me to
watch was a Hopkins versus Joe Smith.
That was,
that was a bummer down and fell out
of the ropes and landed on his head.
I was like, man, that is just,
first of all the fact that there was
no padding on the ground. This is God,
this is Bernard Hopkins is one of the
greatest of all time and this is how this
is set up. You know, and they don't
use, they don't put it on the ground.
They need to have something.
They're like, no, it's an apron.
Tables have to put more people around
the ring. So anybody's comes flying out.
Yeah. Well that's how they
do in Japan. I can pride,
they would have guys like waiting by
the side of the ring to stop guys from
falling around the right
cause they would use rings,
which I don't recommend for
MMA cause this pros and cons.
The pro is that the cage,
the cage kind of like you can kind
of hold a guy again against the cage.
He can't really hold the guy very
well against, uh, against the ropes.
Here it is right here. See
He, I mean like you fell boom,
like right on his head, man. I mean,
I think that's concrete yet is he went
through and somebody bumps you up to
fights over. Yeah. You're not,
you get disqualified the minute somebody
helps you back into the ring. Oh really?
Yeah. You have to get up on your
own and get back in on your own.
Little interesting details.
Shows this light of ruined the
fight for him if he was okay. Yeah.
Like if he was okay, if he fell and then
someone helps them get back up the tech.
Oh, that's interesting. Yeah.
Somebody be, Sean, don't touch him,
but nobody knows if he's all right or not.
Right.
Especially when you see him land on the
shoe in nature. They're running help,
but it's also he's 50 or 51 yeah, it
was right. Yeah. Let's see. 51 yeah.
He was not young in that fight.
When you see a guy like him,
like how the fuck does a guy like
that defy the odds and defy time?
I mean it's just a skill level experiment,
experience intelligence and Neural Hopkins
is an intelligent, funny. He's like,
you know,
you watch him fight smart and doesn't
spend one day out of shape and eat clean
doesn't party. Yeah. He still to
this day I follow his Instagram.
He's always training. He's
always exercising. Still
look slim still looks good.
He's got a true focus. Yeah. Yeah. It's
interesting that that he became that way.
Like in his estimation because
of prison time, you know,
going to prison turned him
into a disciplined man. You
know, like realizing like,
like this is rock bottom.
I fucked up. I need to,
I need to get my life in
order and did and you know,
imagining the people out there
that committed a crime spend three,
four years in jail because of some
stupid crime they could spend that time
training and being the
world champion at something,
at anything which just just develop,
use that time to develop yourself.
Develop your mind. You know, I
mean, when, when Hopkins was,
they were already writing him off
when he fought Felix Trinidad,
remember that everybody thought the
Trinidad was going to run him over with a
shitty pulled in Puerto Rico in the,
and I'm like,
oh my God. He looked and he had to make
that like six or seven foot jump. Yeah.
Till the ground. And he was scared. He
was gonna break his legs. Hilarious.
I forgot about that. That was crazy.
They chased him out of the stadium. Yeah.
Well I'm sure if Tito had so much on his
mind in that fight, so much emotions,
you know,
and then that was the mental warfare
that Bernard won't run into that one for
sure. But then also he was just too
good. Yeah, he was too good. I mean,
he was just, he was too
big. He hit too hard.
Like Trinidad really was a
lighter weight fight it than that.
It was a junior middleweight yeah. Brona
did that same thing. Almost got fun too.
Yeah. I was like, yeah,
exactly. Threw it down. Oh Man.
That was crazy. Yeah, that was
crazy. And you know, this was a kid,
I was like 36 at the time. Look at him.
They're all swinging at him and shit.
I that jump jumpy had to do,
was trying to get out of there for real.
If he just turned,
they would have stopped. If he turned
them like they would probably be like, oh,
what am I doing chasing a tiger?
He didn't chase it. Tiger.
And you catch it. You got a
real fucking problem, you know?
Did you ever have any thoughts at
all once you'd finally retired?
Like maybe one more. Did you ever have
any thoughts like that? Well, you know,
I told people like, I'll take, I'll take
my pajamas off for a hundred mil. Mm.
So she serious come with
the baby, show me the paper.
But who will have to be
against a Aaj maybe enticing.
But when you had beaten Tyson,
you'd beat Tyson.
That was kind of at the end of his stage
two, right? Yeah. It wasn't the same guy.
Like, I've, I, I looked at
Tyson's history, you know,
he's coming from the same history
that I'm coming from, you know,
and he spent some time in incarceration
while he was incarceration.
I'm still out there
fighting and training hard.
He didn't have that in there. So when,
when he came out, it's like, you know,
he's trained again. He's doing what
he, what he knows not what he loves,
what he knows dusk,
what's going to make him some money
that's going to put food on this table.
So it's like I look at
old time fighters and say,
what made them stay in boxing so long?
That's the only thing they knew, right.
Um, they didn't, they're not going to
be no singer or a dancer or whatever.
They only know boxing and this is where
they get their money from. So they,
that's what, that's what
forces them back into the ring,
especially,
especially olden days.
And that's why they were called prize
fighters because they wouldn't make enough
money to make a living
unless you were like a huge,
I get Jack Dempsey or ray robins,
ray Robinson for way, way,
way past his prime again, cause they
were making good money at the time,
but not the money that they would
have been making if it was today.
Well there was no, I mean, you know,
you had to go see it live, you know,
like how much you get paid for the radio.
Who was the fight on the radio?
Was it Jack Dempsey? Gene tiny. That was
the first million dollar gate, I think.
So it was one of those,
Ray Arcel did that fight I think and that
create what does $1 million back then?
That sets a lot of money back then
it was in the 1920s. Right? Yeah.
Gene Tunney Jack Gene.
Gene Tony. Yeah. Um, when,
when you,
Tyson was in jail,
he must've been doing something because
he came out jacked. Like he looked good.
Like he came out looking different than
he ever looked like six pack fully built
when he fought. Peter McNeely. Terrifying.
But like physically he
looked really good too.
Like you look better than he
ever look more ripped than ever.
So when he went in he was a little chubby.
Yeah. You know, what is it doing there?
Yes. Nothing else. That's weights.
Fuck dudes. That's why here, you know
how many dudes before it's enough. That's
how much time you're in there for it.
Yeah. That was him when he came
out. Yeah, he was shredded.
It was so much more muscular.
So he's probably,
he probably couldn't do any sparring.
I doubt they had a heavy bag,
but they probably had a weight
room, you know? But you can fight,
you can fight in prison. And he was like
28 29 there. It depends on what prison,
right? No, I'm saying even fight.
Just fight. Fight people. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. You know, somebody would have tried
to start some shit with, oh, I'm sure.
I'm sure we're not on guard
even, you know. Yeah, I bet.
I bet he had to listen to a
lot of shitty things regard.
It's funny when I seen him be arrested,
taken from the courtroom and they got,
they must've got the biggest guy they
could ever get to go put handcuffs on him
or something like that.
Um, anyway, situation that.
Yeah. I hope a lot of
people stay away from, yeah.
When he went away did you feel like,
dammit,
like I'm going to miss out on that
fight that I want yes. Straight away.
And he's like, oh no, I'm going to
have to wait and delay my retirement.
Oh,
so you were waiting,
you were considering retirement even
before he was incarcerated? Yeah. Wow.
Interesting. Chasing the bull
fight, both fired chicken bowl,
you know, you figured
that um, chicken bowl,
so she couldn't call them ridiculous,
but she can go and try to pick
a fight with me the other day.
They didn't really do the other day
he did. Yeah. Where, um, out of fight,
it was like in la where they called
all the great ones on jury Cooney, me,
uh, foreman Spinks was
there and what was he doing?
He wanted to stand beside me and
take a picture. I'm like, dude,
you can't stand beside me.
Costs down. We're all wanting
to stand. I'm like, dude,
you're going to have to move.
So Gerry Cooney kind of helped us
out there while I'm saved them.
Cause he can smell. Yeah. He can't have a
rough time. Yeah. The difference between
a guy like you who gets out, who speaks
perfect and a guy like him, he's,
he's the the warning, you know, that's the
warning to the young fighter. You know,
you see the, the older
guy who, you know, I,
I saw an interview with him and it was
one of the saddest things I've ever seen.
It was horrible because I go back and I
think about those fights with Holyfield
was fucking crazy wars insane. And
you know, he paid that price man.
He paid that price and you can hear
it when he's talking now. It's rough.
It's hard to listen to it.
The good news is now we're on the other
side of fighters coming out that punchy.
I think with all the rules and
changes that have been made,
what change you won't,
you won't meet as many punchy guys
as you met from back in the day.
Like you listen to personnel,
you listen to Riddick,
you listen to Meldrick Taylor.
He in a lot of guys personnel bad now
he's a little and pronounce it even got
hit that mark. But I think for now
this is probably more from a, you know,
cocaine makes you slurry work.
I Dunno man.
You know you're do enough shit in
your life. He drinks, he drinks a lot.
I wasn't drinking.
I got drunk with porno ones.
One of the things that they
say with older fighters is,
and even older football players is they
become addicted to alcohol because like
they're, they're searching for something
to try to like recalibrate their brain.
You know? I mean there's a scientific
explanation to it that people talk about.
People with traumatic brain injury often
become alcoholics. It's like they're,
they're trying to get some sort of
a dopamine rush out. Could also,
you could also use the alcohol
as a justification as to
why you're slurring your
speech. Well, I know a dude who's a MMA
fighter who has, he's, he's punching,
he's had a bunch of shots and this
motherfucker will have one drink and you
can't understand a word he's saying.
It hits them so hard, so hard.
It's like, it's, it's confusing. It's
like, how would, how are you that drunk?
And then you realize,
oh, he's, this is both things.
It's both things. It's,
it's the brain damage
and the alcohol combined.
Just the wheels come off the carry. It's
bad. Yeah, it's, it's awful. But you, you,
you've made it out perfect. Matt,
you've made so far so far, so far.
Years will tell. Yeah. Do
you worry about that? Um,
not really. Um, like, uh, I try and keep
my mind active. I play a lot of chess.
How often you play chess? Every day.
Really? Yeah. Do you play online?
Competitive? I play on line
because whoever, whoever
jumps in the battle. How good.
Are you? Pretty degree. Yeah.
It's pretty good. As a bully.
He you he is, no, he,
he used to get mad at me cause I'd
go to his house and he'd be like,
you want to play chess? I go, I don't
know, just play. When I got to play,
just beat me up and were like,
get out of here. Just move.
Bringing somebody to complain to you. A
study chess. None as much as I should.
Uh, I just played often. And uh, you know,
when you play offering there,
you know,
people will come out with the
same moves and it's like, oh,
I've seen this movie before.
I know what to do. Right.
Uh, but you know, it depends.
There's people that use
the ponds to, to, to wage war user, um,
the nights or the bishops in combination.
So it really depends on what type
of player they are. I'm a you right?
I'm a bully play.
I like playing the Joe
Rogan of pool of chat.
Well listen,
I can my defense Lennox to challenge me,
I was too late or just for people don't,
um,
don't challenge anybody on their
own table. Lennox challenge.
Giotto came a pool before the podcast
and Joe fucking cleared the table before
Lennox could get one shot.
Yeah, it was good. It was a,
that was the warmup where I won
the second game too. So yeah,
he doesn't need the second game as well.
I'm still warming up. I would go back.
He's got the time deficit.
That's a crazy game though on that table
because that table as four inch pockets.
That's my practice table. You a four
inch bucket. Hey, wait a minute. Whoa.
You putting it? Uh, I have a regular table
at home. Well not a regular tape. It's a,
diamond's got four and a half inch
pockets. It's still a little tired.
Normal Po Po.
Like if you go to a pool hall,
they'll give you a five inch
pocket or a five and a half inch.
But I got to pull too much. This
guy fucking, I got the best.
This table, you can't mess. And it's, it's
dirty right now too. So it's, it's even,
it's even like the cloth slow.
So balls don't drop unless they go right
through the same type of coffees up.
Yes. That's the most, that's the
best one. Yeah. It's the best. Yeah.
It's a great table. That's a
1972 pool table. Oh really?
Some guy had it in his basement forever.
And uh, my friend Dani sold it to me.
Yeah, the guy just had it sitting in
his basement. It's in perfect condition.
It's a basement find. Yeah, man,
that's a hard table to get know somewhere
in California. I love about that table.
Well, guess what, what,
you don't want to have to walk around
and take the buckets of balls out of the
park. Yeah, yeah. That's annoying. Yeah.
It's like ball return. They're all there.
Boom. Yeah. Those, those holes. When I
got those, I got those. It's annoying.
But you probably have like a decorative
pool table came with the house.
You have a beautiful house.
You've been invited many times.
He's been to my house when
it was with my parents.
He never came to my house as
a, as a solo man. Now, um,
when you play chess, um, are
you like, do you get ranked?
Are you a yeah. What it
is, is your, your um,
your points go up.
So I'm at 11 on 11,
7,000 1100 right now. Sorry. What is that
like? Whoa. The rankings are like, if,
you know, if you're up to
14, you're a master for,
so you're closing in on being a master.
Well, I wouldn't call me a master yet,
but you know, obviously if I get that I'm,
I'm trying to get as high as possible,
but if someone talks shit
and they're like, Lennox,
I want to please was something, not pull
some chats, you'd be like, oh, okay. Yeah,
because straight away, what's one of
the most mentally intensive games?
That's probably one reason
why you stay so sharp.
I would imagine there's
a time restriction.
10 minutes till you played
that we hit the slap the clock,
10 minutes for a move for 10 minutes
for the whole game. For the whole game.
Oh Dang. Whoa. On the, on the, um,
it's a fast game on the computer. Once
you've made that move, the time goes over.
It just resets. So it's good. Now,
do you ever go like to Washington square
park and play those dudes done? Really?
Yeah. Yeah. That's, that was,
that was fun. They talk a
lot of Shit, Huh? Oh yeah.
They're good too.
They're good.
The guy that was playing was talking a
lot of shit. Yeah. Yeah. Did you beat him?
Um, no. Wow. You should have hit him.
Why did you have to ask that question?
It was just fun playing
him when he's doing,
when you're gonna be a winner all the
time. Those guys are masters. It's true.
They got nothing else going on. Well, I
mean, that's all they wanted to. I mean,
when you get really good at chess,
and I'm not really good at chess,
but I have friends at are they explain
to you like it becomes your whole life.
Like you start thinking like as
you're walking in the street,
you're thinking about chess.
He just,
it becomes a thing where it's just
everything. It's all, it's, so,
it's such an intense game.
I played like four games a day.
Wow. Online. Tim, what's your
online name? Um, let me see.
Do you use an online live? Yes I do.
They don't use your real name. Right.
I'm going to get it
right now. It's um, oh,
I made this name a long time
ago in Washington square
park of that playing some
masters that MC supernatural.
Those dudes love that game though, Matt.
I mean there's those guys who were there.
If you go there and there'll be there
every day, they fucking live for it.
You know, it's um, it's one of
those things I really admire.
I really admire people that get it
get really, really good at chess.
2000 Inter 2000. What
does that mean? Well,
it was supposed to be Interpol team.
Tell hold 2000.
It's like the name Interpol. It sounds
official when when people were playing,
playing is integral.
I think this is the government
I'm planning at CIA.
So if you're out there and
you're playing into 2000,
you're playing Lennox motherfucking Louis.
Yeah. I was going to put my real name,
but yeah, I don't want everybody
to try and beat the champ.
Well now they're going to turn this
retired right now. Let it be known.
The Lennox Lewis is one of those dudes
that walks around with no case on his
iPhone two and it smashed, it
smashed. If I tell you what happens,
what happened? I was doing something.
Then all of a sudden, you know,
my wife said do this. And I went,
Ooh. And it flew out of your hand.
You have the biggest hands of any human
being I know. And A, and there's no,
there's no phone that's gonna be
big enough. Lets you carry an iPad.
Well let me tell you,
I don't know who makes these iPhones,
but they may come to slip
out of your hands. They do.
They really did like put something
on that. That's grips have a case.
That's the first thing I did was
put a case on. Right. And then, um,
I forgot what I had to do.
You have to take it off to charge
it up or something that yeah,
got the wrong case.
You have the wrong case case.
Whoever you sold your cases an Asshole,
I guess it doesn't have a thing where
you could just stick a hole in that,
look at it. Never run jre case.
Look at these guys challenged.
They're all challenging
me. Are they now? I go,
a boy called this game right now.
They're going to come after you now
though. They find out they can play.
I liked that they're doing it while
we're doing the podcast live. Hey look,
he's going to get obsessed. The wheels
are spinning. The competitive drive.
Let me tell you, my wife gives me
problems on this. He says, you know,
he's playing chess.
They women don't understand that
you playing chess and focusing on,
I'm trying to tell her, listen,
I'm up to this score point.
Don't interrupt because it affects
my score, but I need you now.
I need to do we need to do this five
minutes please. Five minutes. You know,
she's looking at me weird, but
she's gotten better. She's actually,
are you playing chess? So and then she
leaves you alone. Yeah. Oh, that's good.
I think because I got mad
a couple of times probably.
Yeah.
Big bully with his wife Jean.
Play chess with people other than Lennox.
No, I can't play chess. I don't know.
I can't either. Maybe you and I played
together. We should really learn the gap.
You're learning together.
I want to video this game. Do you have any
fucking disgusting? Well, you know what?
You could coach the game. No, this
is the first time I was, I was,
I would ever see a chess game
turned into checkers. Hmm. Oh Man.
It's like I said, we're fighting. How,
how do you play this game again? How rude.
All this coming from
man doesn't really know how to play pool.
Oh,
shots fired. Shots fired. You're right.
You're right. I played billiards.
Billiards, three cushioned
billiards. You know what that is?
One, two, three.
Hold at. The now has no holes. Is that
the one that the bumpers? Yeah. Well,
the whole table, so you have to touch it.
Yeah. Yeah. Russian aggression, isn't it?
No, but I mean Russians play it. It's
a big, it's real big in South America.
It's real big in Mexico. It's real big.
And parts of Europe real big in Asia.
Yeah.
It's a different game.
There's a to two different color balls
and like is he the two white balls and a
red ball or two red balls and
white ball and you've got to,
or sometimes it's a yellow ball,
red ball in a white ball and the idea is
you make contact with one ball and then
you have to hit three cushions and then
make contact with the second ball. Wow.
Yeah, it's very complicated to watch.
It's, well if you know how to play it,
it's good to watch.
But if you don't know how to play it,
it's to thing about what I like about
pools. I like when the ball's disappear.
Like you make a ball goes away, it goes
in that hole by bitch, you sink the ball.
It's like a, it's got a
finality to it. It feels good.
But with that it just clicks. It's
like just Ding, Ding, ding, click.
But the people love it.
Love it.
It's a very intellectual game
cause it's all about geometry.
It's all angles and spin and you know,
I'm not good at that either.
It's tricky. It's a tricky, I'm not
good at it. I know it a little bit.
We're about table tennis.
I can't play.
That will test how you fucked me up high
and coordination. Oh yeah, I'm sure.
Yeah. Yeah. One thing I learned is
that you can't do too many things.
It will fuck you up. Like I've, I've, I've
a real problem with quake. You know what?
Quake is like video game. Jamie's
been fucked me up lately. Quick. Yeah.
We play, we got a computer room
set up in the back. It gets tense.
Yeah. We'll just wait.
What is this? Quake.
What does the Three d game
where it's a computer game.
You have all these weapons. You run
around picking up weapons and you're,
you're on a map.
So it's just like every map is different.
But you can do this in real life too.
I don't know why you're playing.
What do you mean hunting? That's
in the forest. That's different.
I'm looking for meat. That's a
different thing kind of me onto for elk.
Mostly elk and deer. Yeah.
Nice. Yeah. Do you cut it up?
Same spot. Well you
butcher it. Ew. Ew. Ew.
Quarter it up while it's there.
So you can carry it out,
but you don't really like,
you want to protect the meat,
so we really want to get it out of
the woods first and cool it off.
You want to do, what do you do with all
the leftover leftover? Like what leftover?
The limbs and stuff. Leave
him. Leave the bones.
You don't bury it. All the animals
will eat them. Oh, okay. Yeah.
If you leave the bones behind that,
nothing goes to waste in the forest.
If you shoot an animal in the
forest and leave the bones behind,
so I'm just gonna eat it. If
they don't eat, they'll eat
most of it, you know, they,
they find it. Bears will find it. The
ecosystem will take care of everything.
Rats, everything. They'll,
everything will take care of it. Now,
how do your children feel about you
doing those bad things to this alimony?
Listen, as big as you are, you have to
eat meat. There's no way you're a Vegan.
Yeah.
Then my kids have used to it because
I've been hunting since they were little,
so they've eaten bear and deer and
elk. They eat it all to cook. Yeah,
all the time. That was bad
taste. Here's a question for you.
Do Wash your meat there?
Wash it.
Didn't like my deck is
no, going back to that. It's funny. A lot
of people take it that way. It's like,
you know when you're cooking it's like
you're taking the meat from the butcher
is you don't know where it's been.
The worst kind of rinse the chicken or
whatever or put some Vinnie grove written
it like that. So that's what me and my
wash it. Well, when you're cooking it,
you're cooking the outside and anything
that might be bacteria is going to get
killed.
The real issue is when you have
an animal that has parasites,
that's the issue.
So what if you're like cooking a deer?
You don't have to worry about
that because tears are herbivores.
Herbivores don't really have
parasites, but um, you can get,
they can get some this,
some worms that they do get,
but most of the time,
like some pork isn't pork.
Definitely cat and the park, you get
trick analysis. That's pretty serious.
That's pretty serious shit.
I do enjoy me some pork though.
You heard me man, the
devil's beast. Lennox. Hmm.
This is why in bread and wine
you don't need the park? No,
he used to be a rustic Kendrick, you know,
chicken jerk chicken all day.
That jerk chicken and talking
to them for some oxtail outside.
Find a real good Jamaican restaurant. Is
there one in la? None that I've found.
I've been here 13 years
and I can't find it.
No one where they have good jerk
chicken. Uh, swingers, you know that uh,
that oh the camping or Beverly
or somewhere. Wherever it is.
Is it Beverly up there? Yeah,
they have to check it out.
[inaudible] you doc, maybe you, your,
your standards are higher because
you're actually Jamaican. Right.
But for me it's tasty. I might be
off the, have you been to Jamaica?
You need to go? Yeah. Okay.
I think you would look at it.
They're very important to go to Jamaica
because everybody always tells you
different stories and stuff. But it's
a, it's a paradise over there. Yeah.
What do you like most about it?
That you can see different colors.
You know, cause I spent a long,
long time in London and when I left
London to go to Jamaica I was like wow,
all these different fiber and colors,
even in the water colors
in the trees and the,
when you're driving around
London it's gray. Gray. Yeah.
You know, different cities,
they're grace. So I like, I like
contacts with contact with plants,
vibrant energy. Yeah. So you
know, that's an interesting thing.
You know a lot of people do forget
that you were from England, right.
And that there was a stigma with
English boxers for a long time.
And you, you broke that you were the man.
But because of the stigma, because the,
I heard that was um, uh Oh,
British boxers or of horizontal.
Yes.
Well they were more vertical.
They would stand straight up and they
would have like that European style,
but it was like Henry Cooper,
remember when Henry Cooper drop
Muhammad Ali and then they cheated,
cut his glove,
the glove.
I mean he was sort of one of the last
great English boxers before you came
along. And then for a long time
there was guys that were pretty good,
like Frank Bruno pretty good.
But then they would get in there with
guys like Tyson and they would always wind
up losing. So everybody had
these, like, this is our guy.
This is the one in Frank Bruno.
Damn. Did he looked apart?
Was there ever a man more jacked as
a heavyweight boxing, no fat on him.
Jesus Christ, he was a Goliath. He
was carved out of granite and Oh yeah.
I mean nobodies. There's never
been a better built boxer ever way.
You'd look at Frank Bruno and you go, how
does he not kill everybody? He's so big.
Let me tell you, you should see Frank
Bruno now. I would still chisel.
Really phenomenal.
Genetics must be phenomenal.
Genetics even at the age who'd
like 65 wow. Think of Anders.
Same thing. Oh yeah. Well, yeah.
Well Vander, you know, people forget,
he started out as cruiserweight. He was
a much smaller guy. Light heavyweight.
Actually. Was He in the UFC? I mean
boxing it and then when the, oh no,
it was out in the light heavyweight
title from Dwight Muhammad. Calm.
That was no, as I was cruising,
which is a hell of a fight.
There was a hell of a fight that was,
that was like his big fight like to,
to prove himself as a professional
because Kali was tricky. Five, seven,
200 pounds. It was weird fighter man.
Well that was the American Olympic trials,
right? Well, no, that was the,
he was uptight. There's no fight.
That was for the cruiserweight title.
No, I hadn't been. Eddie Davis was,
let me tell you, he had
login it. Frank Bruno,
he got to see him with his
shirt off is still cut,
but you could tell skinny ass legs.
One leg kick. He's got a problem.
Damn though he does look very good.
I one time he had big legs. Yes.
Go see Frank Bruno back when he was in
his prime as a boxer. He was gigantic man.
He was a, a sculpted as a boxer ever
gets. He really, he really wants,
it's not even a good picture now. It's not
one of the best. Yeah. He was so jacked.
Yeah. Well, coffee was a, a
crate. The Camden Buzz saw,
he was such a crazy fight it because he
would pull his shorts up here. Right.
And he was five set of,
tucked down super wide and he would
fight with that Philly shell and come in
real low. You know, he was a varied here.
That Archie Moore style almost
very difficult guy to deal with.
Don't see those thoughts anymore. No,
no, no. When you watch boxing today,
who really stands out to you?
Um, you know, all the, all
the champions right now.
They didn't get to be champions for
no reason. And uh, you know, each,
each one of them have different
qualities. Um, you know, even, well,
let's look at the heavyweights. All the
heavyweights, the top three heavyweights.
Right now they're all over six feet,
five and they all have a different
style, which is good because, you know,
it reminds me of when me and the
Holyfield and Tyson will run,
we all had different styles, which
makes great fights. Now it's to guests,
which thought I was going
to beat which style?
You never know because they're all
similar, you know, they all go,
all three of them have knockout
pretension and uh, you know,
they're boxing to win.
So what we want to see,
we want to see who would win out of them.
Deontay wilder to me is the most
perplexing because he hits so hard.
It's almost like he's
got magic in his hands.
He makes guys fly across the ring,
but he's only 209 pounds and
he does it off balance. Yeah.
And he does it with Polk legs in the air,
the Olympic team and want a gold,
a bronze medal, a year and a
half into boxing. Oh yeah. Yeah.
That's my problem with the new,
the new division is that they
don't have the amateur pedigree,
but maybe the owner
needs to tease is great,
but our t's is much older than he says
he is. Is He, and what does he say?
He is 40 something like 40 or 41. How old
is he? I'm hearing the stories at Ortiz,
like 49. How do you know? Um, somebody
tell me about from the amateurs.
I remember seeing them in the amateurs
and the eighties and they're like, what?
They would say that about Cuban stuff?
Yeah.
Cause they say that same shit
about Yolo or married on, he says
he's 39. Yeah, he just fought on
the weekend or two weeks ago. Right.
A couple of weeks ago in one stop it right
now. I think it was a decision, was it?
If it wasn't that it was a late round
stoppage unless he just fought again.
He just fought like last weekend or two
weeks ago. Two months ago to no, no,
he just fine. No, that was a stoppage. And
this fight just happened. So he's very,
he's been very active. He's trying to
come back. What do you think about that?
Like how active you think
of boxer should be? Um,
what it really comes down to,
you know, this is how it goes.
If you're starting boxing,
obviously you want to have as many fights
as possible to, you know, seasoning,
get that experience level.
So as much as possible,
it's usually four fights a year.
And then as you get better,
it drops to three fights and then when
you're the champion that drops the two
fights. So, um, that's, that's the
progression of, of fighting. You can't,
like for instance, how many fights
did Deontae have this year? Maybe two.
Brian, you know, before when
he was starting out, he would
have like three to four.
Yeah. He's very angry that this rematch
is not happening. And I side with him,
it was a Tyson or pulled out Tyson got
a deal with ESPN. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
and it's, it's a, it's a big deal because,
you know, talking about chess match,
I think that's,
he's pulled off the greatest chess match
move there is first he comes over from
England. He wouldn't, he
takes the challenge if with
Deontae, uh, Joshua didn't,
he boxed,
he had a great fight.
Now he's put himself right up with all,
all three of them are on the same line
to me. And then now for the rematch,
they want to,
people want to see Deontae and they
want to see Tyson fury again because the
first fight, it was exciting. Uh, Joshua,
who's he fighting? You know,
he's going to fight but big baby,
but nobody knows him.
Everybody knows John.
Take boxing fans now everybody
knows Tyson. Everybody in that,
especially after that fight because it
was such a spectacular fight that knock
down. Oh my God, the first
knock down was great.
The second knock down was preposterous.
So the fact that he rose like Lazarus,
I mean it was crazy.
And then one the rest of the round,
he gets tagged a few times and it
starts boxing and then even tag Deontae.
I still had him winning that fight.
It was close Tyson I think by around
I think boxing one that night.
Every, yeah. Both guys
looked great. And uh,
box 12 and maybe like assigning
fight that the rematch,
obviously everybody wants
to see the rematch again.
So when the rematch happened that that
put em from Joshua on the shelf in my
eyes. Now it's putting them on
the shelf a bit longer. Yeah.
With this ESPN deal.
And you know,
Tyson fury is boxing in front
of the public. Yeah. Uh,
Anthony, Joshua and Deontae
there pay per view. Right? Well,
who are they going to fight? View?
Nobody wants to see no silly fight.
They want to see what the
fights. Yeah. You know, it's,
it's a great move by Tyson fury.
It's a great mobile. The first fight
that, that the fight ended in a draw it,
right? Yeah. Yeah. So in the
draw, Deontae keeps a title,
but it least Tyson walks away like
saying, look, look, I won the decision.
I feel like I should have won
the decision. There's a dispute.
There's a debate about it, but
everybody wants to see that fight. Yeah.
I'm going to draw is not from
the reasonable, but kaizen
could lose to somebody.
Yeah. I've been mucking around saying, oh,
I'll fight this or it won't find it till
next year and somebody might lose this,
what happens?
And now none of them can fight each
other because if Joshua fights fury and
loses to fury,
Joshua was star goes down.
They've sure Joshua Fights Deontae and
beats Deontae the Tyson Deontae fights.
Not that exciting. Right. But
if Joshua wants real respect,
he's got to fight either fury or
Deontae fights. Those are the big fight.
Obviously. Gets respect.
He's the heavyweight champion
of the world. But split,
you know, that's a weird thing
too. I'd like to see Joshua Ortiz.
I've been interesting fight.
There would be an interesting cause our
teas can box and hit what that was what
showed how God damn powerful Deontae is
that or was winning that fight and then
I was, I think it was the 10th round and
they go to the seventh or 10th I don't
remember. But I remember when
he caught him, I was like, God,
that guy even late in the fight,
that guy carries no power or
tease his past his prime. Let's,
let's slow down there
Louis. Yes. Prime time
is a good fighter. But you know, give him,
give him, give him like 10 years. Yeah.
And he would, he would have beat these
guys. He would have given them a good,
good fight. But right now he's, you know,
he's obviously older and
he's an old fighter. Yeah.
Well they caught him doing some steroids,
which is a lot of times guys get older,
they try to, yeah, you need it chews
up the old body. Yeah. So you know,
when you reached that point where you
need steroids mentally, it affects you.
Yeah. No. You go into the ring and it's
like, you know, you're missing something.
Something that was there in the
past and it made you feel good.
Now I don't feel as good.
Brian, when you were fighting,
did anybody that you were finding, did
you suspect that they were on something?
Um, yeah. Oh, a couple times.
But the good thing is that I
know is I realized they're right.
Steroids can never get this.
A strong your chin.
Chin. Yeah. So you can take
as much dirt as you want,
but I'm not hit you on the chin. Right.
You can't put muscles on your face. Yeah.
Yeah. And then you know,
these body punches, you can't,
you can't protect around here.
So they will affect you as well.
So that's where you, you
know, when you, when you hit,
when you hit and guys around here,
body punches and you hit him on the chin,
it doesn't matter.
But don't you think that it does
make some stronger physically?
It gives them more vitality.
Might make them able to absorb more
punishment for a minute. For a minute.
Just for a little bit.
Yeah, for a little bit.
Who Do you suspect was on
something when you follow them?
Um,
don't want to say you don't
want to. Yeah, go ahead.
I think it was the first guy.
It's as far as I'm concerned,
was the first guy on steroids back.
They look at the fucking size of that
guy in the, in the late nineties,
especially when he fought Lennox.
Have you ever asked him if
he's been on steroids? No,
I've never actually
hung out with a vendor.
I might've make your
victory party 20 years ago.
You didn't hang around with the
guys that were like into it. Mark,
whatever his name was,
he was the first guy to have a strength
and conditioning coach and a and all
that kind of stuff's Dietitian.
Spanx did when he fought. Um,
when you fought Larry Holmes,
he same guy shall stone Mackey.
Shell stone got him in shape for
Larry when he was coming up from light
heavyweight. Yeah. That's the same guy
that Vander used. And they were doing,
it was really interesting because at
the time the conventional wisdom was at
boxers should not lift weights and Avandia
was lifting all kinds of weights and
he put on all this muscle.
But really he was only about 200
205 pounds when he first fought fog.
Heavy traps. Oh yeah. Jesus Christ.
He was built, it was built. It was PR.
Perfect body.
Yeah.
Yeah. Look at this. Ooh,
that's not steroids. Steroids,
but not necessarily.
Definitely can get that big without it.
I mean,
there are guys alleged,
yeah, alleges a good word,
but it's also possible to
get that big with steroids.
But it's not just steroids too. It's
EPO. There's a look at that one up there.
Yeah. But this is in the
night, eighties and nineties.
This is the good stuff wasn't available.
Well
back then, was it? Oh yeah.
What are you kidding me, man?
Those Russians had everything back then,
man. I mean, the eastern bloc women,
they made world records.
That was when he was a, uh,
that was when he was a cruiserweight.
Look how thin he was. Yeah.
But you can't call them
women if they had mustaches.
They penises fake beards and
fat dicks. They were, they were,
they set records. That's still
to this day haven't been broken.
And because they really were not women.
I mean there were women with massive
amounts of male hormones in their body.
Flo Jo. Yeah. She,
she's I think still sets the record
right now for what, whatever it was.
And she was also someone that was
accused of doing things. Yeah.
I mean look, track and field according
to victor contact, um, who uh,
was the balco guy. I had him on my
podcast. He was the guy that got um,
the clear to Barry bonds and all
those castles undetected supposedly
undetectable steroids. He said track
and field is just a dirty sport,
just like Tour de France.
Like just like cycling.
He's like disappointed dirty sport.
You got Carl Lewis trying to
call out Hussein bolt now, right?
What are you showing us champions
at the top 100 meter times.
All the names crossed
out. Oh Wow. Steroids.
God Damn.
Well,
that's like when a Lance Armstrong won
the Tour de France and they took his
title way.
If you had to give that title to someone
who didn't test positive for anything,
you had to back to 18th place.
Wow.
That was a dirty sport. You know, Bill
[inaudible] said it best. He's like,
yours are psycho was better than your
psycho. They were all, you were all dirty.
There's a dirty sport. He was just better
at doing that sport while being dirty.
Yeah. If everybody's dirty,
then it's fair. Well, he,
he won while everybody was
cheating and I mean, did he have,
so is it still cheating if everybody's
doing it? It is and it isn't. I mean,
it is definitely cheating, but
everybody's cheating. Yeah. It's weird.
It's not good. See, you know, they
went off to the wrong thing. You know,
people were looking for drugs to help
them get stronger when it's natural food
that makes you stronger, this is what
you put into your system. So, you know,
I know what Jamaican food is great. You
know, yams, the plan, Tim's everything.
Bill Umif, bully beef. You know what's
better than that? That's the steroids.
Steroids are way better.
They work instantly,
but if you just stay on them like
guys like Lance Armstrong, I mean,
they proved it just you.
You almost can't do toward the France
the way they were doing it without some
sort of chemical help. And then I,
I've heard it argued by physiologists,
they say it's actually better for your
body to be on steroids while you're doing
something like the Tour de France because
you give your body a chance to recover
because they're doing so much work over
the course of this race that without
having some sort of chemical enhancement
of your ability to recover you,
you just not going to be able to do it.
Help your body can't do break down.
You get that Rhabdo my locis that
those crossfit people get, you know,
that's when your body starts breaking
down muscle tissue and it becomes toxic.
Oh yeah, yeah. Pollutes your, we do that.
They work out so hard and
that people have died of it.
Fighters have died from Rhabdo my locis.
Wow. It's a, it's from overtraining. You,
you overtrain. You know like some, you
know, which is a big issue with fighters,
right?
Like they,
some fighters can train too much and a
good trainer knows how to pull you back
and so that you're peaking
when you get into the ring,
but sometimes people
are so mentally strong,
they push themselves through even when
they're exhausted because I think that's
the way to victory. Hard
work. What's up Jamie? Yeah,
you're pissed comes out looking like
coke comes out looking like Coca Cola.
That's what rhabdomyolysis piss
looks like. Yeah. Wow. Yeah. That's,
that's a sign that your
body's breaking down.
Your muscle is all your, your proteins
in your body are breaking down in.
Your body's getting poisoned by it.
People die.
A lot of crossfit people get it.
What is your kidneys?
What are you doing this situation?
Do you take a rest,
a leave of absence or do you go see the
doctor and they can give you some pills
to put more things that
you need in your system?
I think you have to go to the
doctor almost immediately.
I think they have to do pretty much
your body goes septic on you. Yeah,
it's very dangerous. And the, a lot
of these crossfit people, you know,
because it's a competition and you're
competing against all these other people
and you're doing these massive
repetitions and some of them is,
I'm not really conditioned for
it yet. So their bodies, just,
the muscles not really acclimated to this
kind of workload and it's shit starts
breaking down. Wow. What do you
do these days? Like exercise?
Cause you still look great. Yeah. I ran
10 miles this morning. Wow. Yeah, man.
What'd you go? Huh? You mean
them where I went on the road.
But what'd you run on the beach. Oh,
okay. Woke up, took a shower. Nice.
So you're still dead?
Yeah,
I feel like I don't know you anymore.
You guys don't even catch the joke.
I ran 10 miles and I woke up
and took a shower. Oh, okay.
Oh, I see. I said I that meeting. He's
supposed to know that, but listen, listen.
All right. That's a bad first of all,
sit down. Tell him, tell him, you know,
he used to do this shit to me begging the
day I'd be at his house. And uh, and uh,
I was like, I'm in his basement ago.
It started to rain and go, listen,
I've got to go outside and close
my sunroof. And he's like, no, no.
Hold on a second. I'll tell you a
story. I got Lynn, let me just go close.
My fucking son was like, hold on, let me
just tell you a story. And I'm like, dude,
it's raining.
I,
my sunroof was open or you're going to
pay for my fucking car to get fixed.
He's like, hold on, Yo, there's this
guy, right? And I'm like, come on.
I mean his fucking long story and it goes,
he's trying to get out this window on
that and I'm pulling his leg and I'm
pulling his leg and I go, oh, honey goes,
just the way I'm pulling your
leg right now. And I'm like, ah.
Do you ever do yoga?
Yes. Guy, get into yoga.
I actually hurt myself doing yoga so
much harder than it looks different,
flexible. Like, if I stand up,
I can put them both my hands on the ground
like that. Wow. With my leg straight.
But uh, somebody told
me, Oh, you know what?
You got to move your bum cheeks a little
back and that helps you get down a
little more. And I'm like, okay.
Cheeks a little black and hot.
After a couple of days it's like,
you know, I'm walking around the fan,
I hurt myself and it goes yoga. Yeah.
Say Yo, I heard myself too. I'm like,
I didn't know you can hurt yourself in
yoga. You can hurt yourself in yoga. Yeah.
My doctor told me a lot of
people come to him with injuries,
back injuries from Yoga.
What does that mentally saying that you
can do it when your body is saying you
can't or just doing something wrong.
Just doing something wrong.
Especially if you do it too hard, too
quick. Like yoga is like anything else.
I mean, it's exercise. You definitely can
hurt yourself. Do you do the hot yogurt?
Cold Yoga? I haven't tried the hot
one. Uh, I want to, but I do. I do.
Koleos I like hot because a,
I think we're losing now.
I it's also torturous. I liked
that aspect of it. And also they,
there's a Harvard study that's going on
right now or they're trying to find out
if there's the same benefits that you
get from the sauna you get from doing hot
yoga. When your body gets
really overheated like that,
it produces heat shock proteins and it
alleviates a lot of inflammation in the
body. Wow. That's why the sauna so
good for you because a you're dropping.
Yeah. Try Sauna. Your body gets,
you get in there, your body.
It's like what the fuck is this?
And so it produces these sidechains he's
he chocked proteins and it's fantastic
for people just for, oh my hands
don't hurt when I'm in the sauna.
You should get one in your house man. I
got one. I got a stone at all. It's nice,
right? Yeah. Every day, man. Dude,
you should be in there every day.
Especially cause you're doing Jujitsu now,
you know after training.
Fantastic for you. Really Tub with Epsom
salts. That's good too. That's good too.
I don't think that works. Epson salt makes
it, it makes it feel good. Going to bed.
Yeah.
I go to sleep and you know, aroma therapy,
that type of thing. It smells good,
but it's not that. It's there's
magnesium in it. No Epsom salts.
Your body absorbs magnesium through your,
through your skin.
It's one of the best ways for your body
to get me magnesium is actually through
Epsom salts. Yeah. Okay. I'm going to take
more of that. Yeah. I have a float tank.
You ever do a float tank? Is that the cold
water one? No, no, no. That's uh, it's a,
a tank of water that's
heated to 94 degrees,
which is like the surface of your skin
and there's a thousand pounds of Epsom
salts in there and you lay in it and
you float you like, like your body.
Half your body is above the water and
then he closed the door. Total silence,
total darkness. And it feels like you're
flying through space. It's beautiful.
You would love it man.
Especially being the super,
tell me about this one for years. I got
one right here. I know anytime you want,
but it's the kind of growth,
somebody else's? No, no.
There's film. First of all,
it's only me. I'm the only one that
sits in it and I know how to say
this is a massive filtration system.
It's like this kind of
commercial filtration.
I just drop in and by John
was going to go floating man.
Just just text me and I'll have Jeff
come by and open it up for you or do it
while we're doing the show. Yeah. Yeah.
You gotta be naked and they don't,
don't have to worry about
of home. Be Floating. Yeah.
That's the one I show you the whole
system and there's a ozone system that
purifies the water. It goes through
this commercial filtration system.
It's heavy duty stuff,
man.
It's pretty intense because they started
these flotation tank centers now. Yeah,
they're everywhere. Yeah. You were talking
about this for the past 10 years more.
I had one in 2002 I remember you telling
when I went to your house back in the
day when you're doing that, when you
were doing this podcast out of the house.
Yeah. I had one in the basement. Yeah.
Yeah. What about the ice one? Oh,
that's great. Yeah, cryotherapy is,
this is a place down the street from
here about a couple of miles away.
250 degrees below zero. I thought
you would have had one of those two.
That's like, you have to get
like nitrogen tanks and shit.
And I worry about that stuff exploding,
you know,
some shit going wrong and you getting
maimed, you know? Yup. So do you,
uh,
do you enjoy doing commentary to yeah.
Um, I love, I love giving
my opinion. You know,
people will say I've got an unusual,
um,
opinions. They've never heard that
before. I never heard it put that way,
so I can give you from a fight
five. His point of view, um,
have been in boxing for so long.
There's different experiences that I've
gone through, so I'm happy to share them.
But you don't ever work out
boxing wise anymore. Yeah.
But you don't hit a hit a bag.
My son's 15
then, and I know he wants to buck,
so anytime we get a chance, you know,
I'm always training him.
How big he now
six feet.
Jesus has told them the new Tyson son,
Tyson son is 16 oh, Miguel. Yeah.
Tyson son was saying that he wants
a box to Tyson's. Like listen, no,
Miguel was not built like that. But
he's also saying, listen you, you,
you grew up soft and you
know he's saying like,
you don't want to meet someone
like me. You know, like the
way he was. Yeah, I know.
Mike, do you want to meet
some? And I'm all like me.
You know like when he was fighting like
he like he thinks of what he would have
done to his own son's like,
oh don't do that.
Like he was talking about it
on the podcast and his son,
Miguel's are really talented kid.
Like musician wise can play like seven
different instruments in Spanish.
Wow. The kid's really, and
he's a really smart, nice kid.
Well Tyson is a smart guy. He's not
like he, I think people mistake tied.
Some are big dummy. He's
very, very intelligent.
Well read the boxing is in
at least some levels of very,
very intellectual pursuit.
There's,
you have to have a strong mind to
be able to dodge those punches,
get in and get yours in that you have to,
you have to be able to sort out that
problem is a problem in front of you.
The problem is another man who's the
same way as you, the same size as you.
He's got gloves on just like you do and
he's trying to do what you're trying to
do to him. And you have to do that
within seconds. Yeah. Boom. Yeah.
Punches thrown at you. What do you
do? What's, what's the rebuttal? Yeah.
People don't understand.
They think just because someone doesn't
have the best vocabulary or because they
don't have a,
a comprehensive education that they're
not intelligent and that's a big mistake.
No. Twice Tyson's intelligent. Uh,
I remember going to the
Catskills when I was, uh,
I won the world junior championships
in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.
And I remember the American
team was saying, oh, well
you never fought the best.
I'm like, I didn't fight
the best. I thought American
sent them best team. Yeah.
But one guy, he doesn't like
taking plans in this manager,
don't like taking plans either.
So I'm like, who's that?
And they told me it was Mike Tyson
custom model. So me and my trainer,
we left Canada and we drove all the
way up there and while we were up there
raise your brother was up
there and they said, oh,
raising really came to inspire with
us. So okay, I'll start with the,
I'm here for four days.
So first time Tyson actually met me,
you know, he was Nice Guy, really
nice guy, took me in his room,
showed me some old flicks that I've never
seen before of old time fighters would
tell me about each fighter, like he
studied them and then um, you know,
this is where he got his old star is
his style of fighting from. And uh,
first day in the first day in the gym,
Bell went,
he came across and he was trying
to kill me. Like, you know,
I did my Muhammad Ali thing
obviously stayed away from his power,
but the first day was really hectic and
then the second day was a little hectic
and it got better as it went along in
the last day is I got actually the better
of him the last day and I
remember custom models and Mike,
you're going to meet him some day,
don't you do that?
And that always echoed in my
mind that will we ever fight?
Will we have a fight? Cause custom
model said that we're going to fight.
Why did it happen? And there's
footage of it. Yeah. Wow.
Lennox has the footage of it.
Footage of the training centers.
Barring how old was Tyson at
the time? Tyson was like, uh,
he was about 52. No, no. How old
was he at the time? Oh, at the time.
15. Um, he was, he was younger
than me. I was on Sunday.
He's about 17. Wow. I was 18.
No, he was younger than
that. That must have been
[inaudible] 84 is before the, uh,
empire state games and everything.
Can you,
would you want up there before you went
to the 84 Olympics? Yeah. Yeah. Well,
it must have been crazy though,
knowing that, you know, you,
you guys were going to be a part of boxing
history and knowing that all the way
back then and being a teenager and
standing in front and here in custom model
scream that out.
That must have been intense.
It was intense because custom
model wasn't that loud when he was,
when they, all of a sudden he became
loud. It was like everybody listened,
you know, and then, you know,
there's certain ways that you would
get across to people and some,
some people take you
have to shout at them.
Did you ever wish that you
fought him in his prime? Um,
in essence I did fight him in this
prime and you know, when you say prime,
I was in my prime too. You know, it, you
will definitely in your prime. You were,
you were, but I feel like his
enthusiasm had waned before then.
You know, um, I, you know,
this is my perception,
how I look at that whole thing is
Mike Tyson was an early bloomer.
I was a late bloomer. So, you know,
when, when both of us meet, you know,
there's never a perfect time. Perfect
time for us is when we meet in the middle.
Right, right, right.
And, you know, if he won,
maybe people would look at it differently.
Right.
It's because you beat them and beat them
so soundly that people look at it like
maybe his, his time had
already been gone. Yeah.
Lenox turned pro after Mike had already
had a defeat. Wow. No clubs turned prone.
89. Wow. I never even thought of
that. Mike lost in January of,
this is all stuff in.
Okay. Kevin Rooney. Wow.
That is crazy, man. God,
that's crazy. Go back then too.
We had a big neck. Yeah. He, well,
he was always doing those neck bridges,
but he also just had freak genetics.
I mean, just phenomenal genetic
specimen, you know. Uh, I had, um, uh,
Teddy Atlas in here and Teddy House used
to take Mike to the smokers when he was
13. And he, teddy was joking
around about it. I said,
everybody always lied
about how old people were.
They would tell you the kid was 16,
when really it was 20.
They always did that and he said, uh, he
goes, uh, so, uh, how old is this kid?
He was 13. He goes, what does he
weigh? He goes, 190 pounds. It's like,
what the Fuck Teddy? Come on. He's
like, I'm telling Ya, he's sick.
He's fucking 13. What do you want? So,
you know, nobody would believe because he
was such a specimen. I watched that one.
Teddy was great man. Do you think
he should have stayed with teddy?
Should it stay with Kevin and Teddy?
Well, he definitely, how, you know,
he was so wild. Like how, how could
you tell him what to do back then?
That was part of the problem. I mean,
he was never, no one ever prepared him.
And this is one of the things that we
discussed on the podcast was that he was a
12 year old, 13 year old boy
and he was getting hypnotized.
He had came from a terrible
background. It was, there was no love,
he was abandoned and all of a sudden
he's getting love and attention for
something. And this one thing
was this man who was telling him,
you're going to be a great fighter,
you're going to be a world champion.
And he would hypnotize me saying,
you don't exist. The task exists.
You know you're going to work
the body and destroy this man.
And he would tell he would
put these thoughts in his
head and Mike couldn't wait
to just get out there and fuck people up.
Cause that's where he got the love.
That's where he got the attention from.
But he never turned,
never told them how to shut it off.
He never,
I mean he didn't have time to
work with him cause he was,
he was on his way out and he
was dying when he met Mike.
And so he only taught them how to destroy.
He never taught them how to cope.
He never taught them how to understand
that there's going to be a lot of shit
coming your way and you've got to know
what that is and don't get caught up in
that hype train. Don't just don't get
wrapped up in Hollywood. And you know,
he wound up marrying robbin
Gibbons and you know, all,
I don't think cus foresaw
all that other bullshit. No.
How could he of course was the run.
Mike would be totally different.
He would have been a different man
if costs lasted another 15 years.
Even if Jimmy Jacobs had lasted
another five years, maybe. Yeah,
maybe that would have helped.
But I mean it's like once
you're once removed from cus,
it's like Kevin Rooney was
once removed from cuss. Right.
And then Teddy Atlas was way more of
a hard liner, you know, Teddy Atlas,
you couldn't put any bullshit with,
you know,
and like those other guys are
just got to go, ah, you know,
when he got to Aaron snowball and all
those guys was with them rich and Ghia
Ketty they just didn't, they, they didn't,
they could've never brought
Mike to the dance. Right.
They got there when he was already at
the dance and they just trying to like
maintain things and he's not
listening to anybody. Mike Tyson,
they also weren't boxing people
as far as I was concerned
when he was up with costs use.
It was in a good situation.
You know, there was a lady in
the house cooking meals. Uh,
they had custody of being a father figure,
talk to him every day.
And that's what young kids
need. They need that, you know,
to be spoken with by older
people. Yeah. And you know,
a lot of young people nowadays are not
even respect him, the older people,
but they can get in a lot of information
from an older person. You know,
how do you deal with this
situation? Well, you know,
you hear from an older person that kind
of makes your mind thinking and said,
you know, you're right. It works for them.
So anytime I get a chance to
talk to kids about, you know,
their life and where they're going,
or it's take that opportunity.
Well, you're such a great example of
a guy who has done incredible things,
but you've come out on the other end with,
with wisdom and lessons and honesty,
and you can talk about things and
people will listen to you in a way that,
you know, a lot of kids don't
want to listen to someone.
We ain't done shit. Right? And he talked
to some guy who's just some boring dude.
Do you want to give you advice?
Like, Hey, fuck face. I look,
get your own shit together. Tell me
what to do, bitch. But what do you,
Lennox Lewis, he talked
together go, oh, okay.
Mr Chess master world
heavyweight champion,
and he was in Jamaica. Now you got
a box in school then Lennox Lewis,
League of champions. Woo. Yeah.
It's for young kids that, you know,
learning how to box teach.
We teach them on the box and we'll
teach them life skills as well.
Because what we realized that, you know,
a lot of the kids just want to talk,
you know, there's nobody around them
to talk. Nobody listens to them.
And when they hear all the kids' stories,
they feel a lot better. It's like, Yo,
you know, I was going through that and
I liked how he dealt with it. You know,
it's like, yes, this is what,
what's missing nowadays,
the relationship with kids, you know, uh,
talking to them, just ask them out there,
I have some board, they're
doing what do they want to
be. Right, right, right. Yeah.
And then have some place where they can
go in and have something that gives them
a sense of value, you know? And that's
what a lot of sports does, di do,
di to children gives them, you know, you,
you realize if you work hard and you try
something and you study it and you get
better at it, you feel good.
Like you accomplished it.
You got through whatever the sport is.
A lot of,
a lot of the kids that come boxing,
um, I've never tried it before,
but once they try it, it's like wow.
They learn new things about themselves.
Even the training of boxing, you
know, the fact of us run a mile,
they never ran in their life. Now they've
run half a mile, didn't make the mile,
but the next day, next day they want
to try them out. And then he just,
it shows them that if you keep working
at something, you'll accomplish it.
You know, don't give up. Don't over
sudden you tried it and it's like, hi. No,
it's not for me. Keep
trying it. You don't know.
It's not for you until you keep trying
it and then realize it's not for you or
for you. What are you gonna do if
your son wants to fight? Let him,
yeah. I think your perspective would be
very different than Mike's. Yeah. From,
from me. You know, I'm not
forcing my son two bucks,
but if he wants to try it,
let him try. His father used
to box, so why not? Why not?
Try something his father did, maybe has
the gene for it. You know, right now my,
my play plays basketball. He wants
to be an actor. He loves boxing.
They couldn't do anything he wants,
you know,
all my kids are talented and I see the
drive in them that I have and their
mother has. So I know that they're going
to be successful. You know, they've,
they're,
they're basically,
I'm trying to help them to
become successful in the
future and giving them the
tools to become successful in the
future as well. Good for you, man.
Lucky young man. I mean, you know,
and young women too. Yeah. Well,
but a great situation to be your son,
you know what I mean?
And your daughters as well, but for
sure. But I mean to be your son,
if you really do have a desire to box,
would you start training them? I'm trying.
Oh Shit.
I'm saying saying
it's like, you know, um, you know,
I was talking to George Foreman
the other day and his dot.
One of his daughters were fighting
number in her name. George.
She's Georgina or something.
Right? Some crazy shit.
He's got like eight Georges in his house.
I said, and I'm watching her finals,
but they know by the tone apparently
which one it is in fluxion on the Jew.
I'm watching her fight and I'm like,
George, you need to tell us some stuff.
I know there's some good things you
can tell her or even get her a proper
culture or you know, help her.
I don't want her to fight. Wow.
Solely at to say, yeah, but if you don't
want her to fight and she's fighting,
you're not going to help her. She's
going to get hurt. So you might as well.
I think she stopped already. Anyway.
My approach to raising kids is I don't,
I don't have any input under
what they do. I want, I don't,
it would never tell my kid, I don't want
you to do that cause it's not my life.
It's their life.
I give them guidance if I can,
I'll talk to them about what
they're doing, if I can,
but they also have to go
out and do it themselves.
I really firmly believe in that.
Like you gotta go do it yourself.
But if you want to do it,
that's your thing.
I tried to convince my daughter to want
to do Jujitsu. I really, I do. I said,
sweetheart, I'll get you a
pink gee, if you my teeth.
My kids were doing
martial arts for a while.
My middle daughter was doing Jujitsu
and my youngest daughter was doing MMA,
but she got bored with it after a
while, which was cool too. You know,
like a 10 and eight. You know, who
knows. Maybe they'll come back to it,
but you know, I kind of
whispered it to my son right now.
You need to do some wrestling,
get them in Jujitsu.
I'm telling you, just thank
you. Should fight MMA. Uh,
you know, I don't know what the future
holds. He may fight MMA. He's kind of,
he doesn't, if he's going
to fight a shoebox, why?
Just because of the money factor. Yeah.
You know what I mean? Honestly, I mean,
if you're a heavy weight,
you know,
if you're a heavyweight and
make a lot of money, yeah,
we sure certainly will basically give
you a Lennox, his brother Dennis,
they're nothing alike.
Lennox is bones mean goddamn butter heavy,
like a child holding a fist that pretty
big fists, but yours are gigantic.
Then you know, huge, huge human being.
You know your kid's going to be a
heavyweight. Oh, he's going to be a heavy,
he's already,
he's six foot and he wears size 15 shoes.
He doesn't need to fight. Just keep
a pair of, of shoes by the front end.
So I think he's, he's to outgrow
me. That's like a puppy. Yeah. Yeah.
He's always going to be enormous. A great
day. Why do kids outgrow the parents?
I don't know. I think it's food. I think
they get better food than us. Yeah.
I think you know, you think about like
how much protein children have now,
if you ever go back and look at how
big men were during like the civil war
period,
there were tiny like a hundred pounds.
There are tiny little people
because nobody had good food.
Like everybody was like barely surviving.
Everyone's scrape those
divers bread and water times.
The people that made it across the West.
You ever see photos? A little folks.
It was skinny,
rickety looking people just tougher and
tougher than we could ever be. Oh my God.
They were a little wolves. They're up
in the early in the morning working.
They had to survive. Yeah. It's just,
but now today kids are getting, you know,
massive amounts of protein and they get
vitamins and vegetables and you know,
drinking all this milk and food's
got shit. Oh yeah, there's that too.
There's that too, but I just think it's
just an abundance of nutrition. I mean,
when people were smaller,
a lot of it was because of malnutrition.
Like look at a Asian folks. Like a lot of
Japanese folks used to be much smaller.
Now they're pretty fucking big. You're
getting some really big Japanese fighters.
Like they're larger because they're huge.
They're eating better. You know what?
I wanted to ask you please. Conspiracy
theories. I know you have some. Yeah,
I got something I thought I was listening
to you about was something about
Martians the other day that was
a positive challenge. Jones,
Alex and I saw an amazing NASA shirt I
was going to buy for Eddie the other day.
Yeah. Alex wore a NASA churches
to for watch the, yeah. Yeah.
I believe she had that.
Even Alex thinks is ridiculous.
Like what quits conspiracy theories do
you want to know about it? No, I'm like,
let me hear some, well, I, I believe
less than, less than I ever used to.
Population control. Do you believe
that? No, I don't believe that.
I don't believe there's
any concerted effort. Um,
like where there's a bunch of really rich
people that have decided to euthanize
a bunch of people to keep the
population low. I think that is,
that's paranoid. I think that
there's probably some people that go,
you know what? We would be a lot
healthier if there was less people,
but there's no,
there's no obvious effort.
The population keeps fucking growing.
Imagine if you are the all powerful,
all knowing people that were running
the world and you're doing such a shitty
job of population control.
Yeah.
I don't know how you're going to
control the India and China. You're not,
you're not.
You're not.
You're not going to be in these fucking
dirty villages and trying to stop being
not doing it anywhere.
And even in this country,
people are fucking like wild animals and
just coming next month I got three kids.
Yeah, like look, it's just the way
it is. Mad People like to fuck you.
Like to make people in China.
You're only allowed one kid. No,
I think they lifted that.
They've left, lifted,
lifted that because a lot of people were
drowning their daughters. They were,
there was horrible shit. You're
killing, I mean there's the,
this is the rumor was that people were,
they wanted a son and if they had
a daughter they would, you know,
the daughter was like the law,
the law, the lose for you.
And to me a daughter is a win because
there's so much easier to deal with.
Really. I find with my daughter and we're,
we're like this. Yeah. You know what man?
I mean, just be happy. I've got
a guy come, a boy coming next.
You got to have a little Joseph Lennox
Lewis. Peter's come in next month.
I'm Joseph Lennox Rogan Peters.
He's going to be amazing.
I'm so happy that you gave him
my name. Yeah, that's beautiful.
Keeping that first is going
to give me a middle name,
but I didn't want to do that to him.
So what's your middle name? Whoa. Yes.
My middle name is Claudius. Claudius.
It sounds like a Roman emperor.
Absolutely
beautiful.
Hey Man,
I know you're supposed to get out of here
at two o'clock do you have a hard out?
No, no, you can stay. Yeah, absolutely.
Beautiful. Let's keep talking. Yeah.
Yeah. So back to your
question, I don't, yeah,
I think there's definitely some people
that are influencing the way the world
works for sure.
But I don't think there's anybody that's
really trying to control population or
what about this one?
Okay.
Do you think the Russians put Donald
Trump in the president's chair?
I think the Russians absolutely want
to. Donald Trump to win. Absolutely.
And I think they definitely undermined
our democracy through various methods of
manipulating people through social media.
In fact,
I have a woman coming on very soon.
When is Renee [inaudible]? This week.
Next week. And she's on next week and
she actually studied it and wrote,
wrote this very
comprehensive report about,
it was on Sam Harris' podcast and detailed
millions of interactions with Russian
bots and Russian fake accounts and that
these troll farms that we create memes.
And they did,
they did a bunch of different things.
They didn't just try to pump Trump up,
but they also tried to get
people against each other and,
and cause all sorts of civil,
uh,
arguments and all sorts of a armrest.
Yeah.
All sorts of unrest online.
They organize these, um,
meetings like they organize one pro Texas
meeting across the street from a pro
Muslim meeting.
I did it on prime all through Facebook
to get these people to fight with each
other.
They're doing these things to try to get
people to take sides and to get people
to be angry at the other side. They did
a lot of shit like that. Real sneaky,
sneaky stuff that we probably do
in foreign countries all the time.
And you know,
we're mad that they're doing it to us
because now they're doing it through
social [inaudible].
Well, if you think about when we were
growing up in the eighties seventies and
eighties all the imagery we saw,
the USSR was very dark and gray and it
was very barren and it was destitute and
well some of it was true though.
Yeah.
We saw and then all of a sudden that
lifts and these hot fucking Russian chicks
show up and like what were
these bitches the whole time?
Where was she in the propaganda? So
true. You never saw the hot Russian lady,
some of the hottest women on the plan.
They used to show us these big manly women
will do one and now you're like Whoa,
whoa, hey Lou. Yeah.
Yeah I have two friends in are married
to a Russian ladies. They're very happy.
No the question cause cause you were
American. Everything. I'm not American.
So is this wall ever going to get built
towards that? What's the situation?
I think it was more of a campaign
rhetoric thing. You know,
build that wall, build that wall.
He's kind of staying with it.
He wants to Porter's, I think he's
got a kind of do something right.
Once you say that you're gonna build a
wall, you got to kind of do something,
but they ain't shit been built and
we're two years into the president.
They haven't built shit.
I was a year left in the year and a half
left in the presbytery has some wall.
There's some wall that's up,
but there's also some big as gaps and
the idea that they're going to stop drugs
from coming over from that wall.
Now the wall looks like Leon Spinks
his mouth. I don't have a badge.
I forgot about Leon's spanx.
I remember my
parents were hippies,
right?
But when Muhammad Ali lost to Leon
spanx and then there was a rematch,
we watched it on television.
Everybody, everybody wanted Ali to,
when people forget that Ali wasn't just
a great boxer and the heavyweight champ
of the world, he represented
people that were against the war.
He represented people that
were against all of the,
all of the discrimination and all the
racism that people experienced in the 50s
and the 60s he was a different
thing. He was. He represented that,
the hope of this new generation,
that this athlete would take a stand.
And he said that no Vietcong ever did
anything to me and I'm not going over
there and fighting anybody.
And they took away his ability to earn a
living for three fucking years primary.
And he was a hero, a real social.
He could've, he got to given in,
he could have given and he could've got
a cushy job like Elvis or some shit,
you know, and they would have had
them go over there and you know,
just just to make it look like he
was doing something. He's like, no,
no fucking chance. You know,
he stood up for it and my,
my parents were hippies wanted,
wanted to him to win. I mean, my,
my mom didn't give a fuck about boxing,
but when I was,
when I was a little kid, I remember
watching us on TV thinking, this is crazy.
My parents want to watch a boxing
match because what he stands for,
my dad felt that way about
Joe Louis Robinson. Well,
when Joe Lewis beat Max Schmeling oh,
he didn't match. Very similar thing.
He was beating Max Schmeling for
the world, like it wasn't, I mean,
I feel terrible for Max
Schmeling because I mean,
he was probably just
caught up in all that shit,
but Max even said he wasn't part of it.
He was just,
he was just a pawn in the game.
Yeah, I'm sure. Yeah, I'm sure.
But what about Jack Johnson?
That's my favorite.
That's the craziest in Lennox
Lewis. Jake Johnson, my favorite.
That's the craziest of all stories, right?
It was managing and he was incredible.
I must've experienced in the shit he
said back then. He would slick talk.
You bad. My favorite one, there's
a meme, a photo of him in his car.
I don't even know if the story's
true. I don't know. Change.
I'm coming back tonight. Same speed. Yeah.
He got pulled over going 50 he had
to give the guy $50 that was the fee.
Gave the guy a hundred he goes,
what's this for?
Is I'm going to come back
later that night. Same speed.
Then there's the story of him getting
in a taxi and get in the backseat of a
taxi and the guy goes, I don't
drive. Niger's. And um, and he,
and he reached over,
pulled the gun to the back seat,
got in the front and drove himself to her.
He had the guts and the guy's like,
where's my fair? Cause I drove myself
and he got out. I wonder if that's true.
You know, he could just
roll in his book. You know,
he wrestled this video of
Jack Johnson wrestling.
He had like a 13 inch wrist. Here's
a gigantic human being for the time,
but I think he was only six
too, you know. Yeah. But it was,
they called him the Galveston
giant. Yeah. And people,
a Gq magazine rated him as best
dressed athlete of the century in 2000,
um, just wrong century. Uh, well, uh,
you know, the 20th century hundreds.
Oh, right. Get it. Oh yeah.
In 2000 they did it. Yeah.
The whole 20th century. Backtrack.
Yeah. Well, you know, I mean,
I don't think any of us could even imagine
what it must have been like when he
won the title and the kind of hate that
he got all the people that wanted him to
be killed. The shit he did
was so gangster. Oh yeah.
He would hit you and see your knees
buckling hold you up and say he would say
things to the guy's not
yet, sir. Not yet. Not yet.
You're going gonna have
a longer night than this.
He would just torture these guys,
this guy and those boxes.
Did you ever see his fight with
Stanley Catcho? Yeah. Yeah.
The boilermaker Stanley Ketchel dropped
him yet it was supposed to be, uh,
uh, exhibition, an exhibition.
Mountain stand. The catcher
was a middleweight, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay. And then
his teeth got stuck in his glove.
He smashed him. Wow. Yeah.
He had a fascinating style when
they had those little gloves. Well,
you guys don't realize that was going
to say the little gloves horsehair
different worlds closer.
A hard your fucking hands real easy too,
but they heard more. I'm going
to add, added that. Yeah.
It hurts. Well, it's like,
am I make gloves? Yeah. And I may
fighters find out the hard way.
Like you can't just,
you can open up with boxing and not even
worry as much about what you're hitting,
but you cannot do that if you're
fighting bare knuckle this.
Have you seen that bare knuckle boxing?
I was just going to say,
what does this bare knuckle resurgence?
I think these guys are tough. Yeah.
The desk. What? You got pro boxers going
in it now? Yeah. Uh, who went in it?
Somebody, a decent name was in it
recently, but a lot of UFC fighters. Yeah.
There nobody has a rover.
Yeah.
They've gone in rugby or football.
Right.
Rugby guys are tougher than the
football players. 100% yeah. Yeah.
The Italian guys in it to,
I saw him doing the bare knuckle thing.
Italian guy. It was the UFC fight in
front of the building. No, no, no.
An Italian American. She'll
feel baroni bare knuckle. Yeah,
he did one. Yeah. Yeah. Quite
a few MMA fighters. Melvin.
Gloria did some, yeah, it's a, you know,
but it's sort of a last resort kind of
thing. Trying to pick up a paycheck.
You know Chris Lidell did it.
It's just a hard way to make a living.
Some of them about 20 to have
CT scan knocking at the door.
He's just saying the time. Tell us
mother fuckers sit down. It's your boy.
Who My guy. Yeah, he's not going
to Eddie the Mexican. Yeah. No,
he's good to fire him. He's trying to
get into the other guys talking to him.
So Lennox is fellow is talking
to your fellow? My assistant.
My assistant knows better.
Well, people get silly. It's
like a good million though.
Once you enjoying this meal,
you just want to finish it. No.
What did they have you doing after
this? Uh, just more interviews. You,
they kept me busy, boring ass
interviews. So what are you promoting?
Promoting the fights. Which fights?
We haven't talked about any of them.
You couldn't promote a foreigner to be
neat and context talking about Chason get
the fuck outta here.
You get the fuck Outta here.
Tell your boy I'm good. I'm good
at it. You don't worry about me.
I've already told them I don't have
to be somewhere to four 30 that's,
I'm going to put some two way glass there.
We could see out and they can't
see in. That's a good idea. Yeah.
Silly boy. Try Interrupt podcast ready?
Jesus said it's Shawn Porter. Yeah.
In this weekend.
Who was he fighting?
A you guys from Cuba. Oh, they said
you guess I'm like, I, I'm know who
it should be a good fighter. And
this is on, this is on Fox PBC. Oh,
nice. Yeah. Porter's a
champ right now. Right?
He won the title from
Thurman, didn't he? Yeah.
And the or did he want
it from Danny Garcia?
Danny Garcia.
Don't you watch boxing, aren't
you a box? Of course. Jesus.
I'll tell you anything
about the heavyweights.
Are you doing commentary on us
last week? Danny Garcia? Yes.
So you're doing commentary on this for
Fox? Yes. Nice. It should be a good fight.
It should be a very good
fight. Yeah. Yeah. There's a,
there it is right there. Oh,
he grew his hair out every,
every time. Sean Pores. SMURF.
Oh, it's Lennox. Every
time Shawn porter fights,
he's always uh, uh, the
series Brah you know,
this guy reminds me of the
old time fighters. He the
way out of this guy fights,
you know,
it gives you a lot of pressures on you.
Somebody you help him tie
his tie though he doesn't,
he doesn't mind taking the shots
too punchy. So he mixes it up.
That's this Saturday
night. Yes. Nice. Um, yeah,
there's a lot of great fights
coming up. The uh, Mikey Garcia,
Earl Spence jr excited. That's
what, that's a very good fight.
It makes me nervous though. It makes me a
nerd. Why and why? That's a great fight.
What he wants to see. It's a great
fight, but as I'm a, I like Mikey Garcia,
but to me it's like, I like both of
those guys. I like them both I think.
I think Mikey's plus in
this fight is that spent,
hasn't had pressure like this and Mikey
doesn't tank out on anybody. Yeah.
He's not gas out and he's not
afraid to mix it up with you.
What about the size difference?
That's what I'm worried about.
It's the size difference,
the weight difference. I
mean, I would have preferred,
mine is called one more fight before
he fought Spence. But no, he's,
they know what they're doing. He's ready.
These whole families. Um, I mean, yeah,
he talks in specialists and I trained
with his brother before with, with Robert.
Oh, have you really? In Oxnard. Yeah.
Really? Yeah. No Shit. Yeah. Okay. Great.
Gym Jujitsu with John Jacques
Machado. Your boxing, Robert
Garcia and Loma Chanko.
Was there a training one
day? I went damn. Yeah,
Teddy's up there right
now working with that.
A light heavyweight Russian character.
Oh, the uh, the Uzbek gay kids.
Amazing. Yeah. Yeah,
yeah. I trained with
a trained over at, uh,
Goossens Jim over the Christmas holiday.
How did you relate? Boxed in two years.
Oh my God. I suck. My fucking hands
are, and I'm like, God, fuck this sport.
It's what your, your hands and
my hands were hurting after that.
Did you wrap them?
I wrapped him.
I might wrap them too tight
and you got soft hands.
Don't make me square up. Kid took it.
It's been two years. I was like, ah,
I don't, I do this and got to
do it slow. You know, it was,
cause he knew I used to train
back in the day, so I was like,
I want it to look good. And I'm
like, ah, okay, let me help you
do, let's see. This is where
the martial arts comes in,
but get this thing of sand,
ah,
and you just start punching it.
Toughen you up a little
bit tough and you won't.
When I say my hands hurt, I meant like
the joints. My joints were hurting. Well,
you know what people do
you ever see rice bags?
They stick their hand up rice bags,
they do a lot of this rice bags that
apparently is very good for your hands.
I did that, but my mom got mad.
I was fucking up her. Right. So
what did you do about it?
Yeah. And I went home and just so
if you just get back to doing it a little
combat, you know, I figured that much,
but I'm like, bring a tennis ball
everywhere. I'm gonna stick with Jujitsu.
It doesn't hurt as much. Did you? Just,
it doesn't hurt your hands? No. Uh, my,
I wear those little Luda gear guards.
What Lou tell gear. Have you seen them?
They got these little finger
guards that they actually help.
What are their strength?
And it gives you say make a
two finger on a three finger.
I will no idea what the word, the three
finger. It's just like a little, uh,
it's like a little cut off glove for
your fingers. Really holds them together.
Ninja thing.
It's nice.
It give you more traction to cause
it's not necessarily, but it just,
it keeps your fingers together.
Piece from separating.
I'm fucking pop your finger out.
That's probably good if you're
a guitarist or some shit.
Probably my mom uses some too
forthright. I'll look at that. That's it.
That's the two finger joint. I use the
three. I've never even fucked with those.
Yeah, I'm old school bro.
I just take my shit up it.
But you're also fucking gorilla
strong. It's weird. Why is it weird?
Because it just, it's, it's like playing
with a fucking silver back gorilla.
Even when I watched your role was John
Jack that day. I was like, you go,
you want to roll? I go, no I don't.
I'll do it now. But then I'm like,
no, but I've been doing
it a long time, man.
I started Jujitsu in 96 [inaudible]
rolling tomorrow. Right. I'm calling them,
calling them now.
We're going to probably roll around not
eight 30 in the morning if that's cool
with you. Yeah, that works.
Yeah, we could do that.
What's different about
Jujitsu and wrestling? What's
the, what's the difference?
Depending upon whether or not use
the Gooey, the gies a big factor.
Cause you could grab a
hold of that and it's all,
it makes you more defensive minded
because you can get caught in things.
He ain't cotton submissions easier, but
submissions are the big thing obviously.
But I do a lot of Gnocchi.
I have a black belt Nogi Jujitsu,
engage you to two pro.
I actually prefer
no, Gee, we don't want to do tomorrow.
We do whatever we do gay. I don't care.
I just don't use it. I just don't use the
key. You know, I let people grab mine,
but I try to use armbars and chokes
and things that I would do Gnocchi.
That's how I trained from Geeta Nogi so
that I could do both. I just decided to,
I'm just going to train in the gay,
like I don't have one on like let
people grow. I'll be, I'll be,
I'll recognize that I have it on so people
can grab me, but I don't grab theirs.
I just use over hooks and under hooks and,
okay.
So I was trying to make a joke out of
Nogi. Oh, somebody gave him the key.
Josie Gaylord.
It is definitely a slower game.
Like older dudes in particular,
they seem to like the geek because they
can kind of control you and it's good
for you and it could also be used
against you, which is bad. Well, it's,
if you have a winter coat on,
man,
like I always said that the worst thing
to do is get in a fight with a judo
black belt when you got a winter coat
or a sweater lecture. That's good.
Yeah. Yeah. We're looking
at you. It's all gravy.
Yeah. You, uh, you got your blue
belt now, right? When you, uh,
when you think you'd get a purple
belt and you're on your way, right?
I've got to get some stripes. I
talked to JJ about it ago, dude.
I'm trying to train more so I
can get a stripe because yeah,
you're due for a stripe. I go, well,
how am I going to fucking train more?
So I think I have to strive. I don't want
the stripe. I want to earn the strike.
How are you doing things other than
your Jujitsu training in terms of like
physical training? Um, maybe
a little dumbbells and, and
Yoga Ball. It's about it.
Yeah, that's it. Yeah. She get a
trainer. Get someone like it'll,
it'll make a big difference.
It's like, think about your,
your body is like a race car,
right?
If you could just lift weights
and your race car would go faster,
wouldn't you do that?
If there was a thing you could do,
you can your raise my little dumbbells,
but dumb bells.
But my elbow farcan hurts lately.
So like quitting is talking about,
this is the thing I was talking about
either with tennis elbow, right.
I was having a problem with my elbow.
You'll, you'll hold it like that.
Like you twist it like this and then you
untwist it with your arms so you hold
it like this,
twist and then untwist it.
He'd do it slowly and it
works on these tendons,
the same tendons that you get wet,
but it's just so shitty. How I got it.
Fucking sleeping. Could we have
him try that right now? But see,
God damn. It's a lot heavier
than it looks. So you twist
it and then untwist it.
Yeah, like, like twist
it like that. Right.
And then leveled out and then
slowly untwisted that's good.
Yeah. Just to do it over and over
and over again a little bit. That's,
it's far more dense than it looks.
It's great for your tendons.
It's specifically works this part of
your arm like down in here and they just
look at, you're jerking
off Lynn. That's good too.
You know what else is good?
A roller.
You know like when you have
one of those foam rollers? No,
a chord with like a weight of the bottom
of it and you've got to roll it with
your, Roy used to do that and
box. That was during the day.
Those are great people just
used to fabricate them in the gym. Yeah,
like a stick or a row. Those are great.
Yeah. I haven't one of those
out there too. It's just that's,
that's one of the best things
for your forearms, right? Yeah.
For your forearms and gripping.
Just have that kind of strength.
Good.
You'd be awesome at Jujitsu.
I guarantee you because you're a chess
player and she just is very cerebral.
You know? It's very, it's like it's, it's
boxing. Obviously he's very cerebral too,
but there you're limited in your weapons.
You'd only have a certain amount
of angle she could punch from.
Where did you Jitsu?
There's an endless combination.
You get some time to think some to in
certain positions of the teacher that did
I kido, yeah, that's what he did to that.
Do the half and half, half a k
don't have to Jitsu on. He gave me,
he did something to me and I realize,
okay, I got to watch out for that.
That's where you know the person
manipulates your bone and then drops their
whole weight on it. Yeah. Yeah.
That shit could break your hand.
If you don't go with it.
It'll break your hand.
Fred's Fred's and push out
as I shit the people. Yeah.
Marcello Garcia is tat people out like
high level people with risks locks in
Jujitsu tournament.
John Jack was showing me like how to risk
like a guy while you're done like damn.
It's like, it's not nice. Don't do it
to people, but you can do this. Yeah.
There's some nasty shit. The thing
is like there's no end did you do to,
there's no end. There's no like these
are all the moves and that's it.
But people keep inventing moves.
I just found our new move yesterday.
One rubber guard assassins
on uh, Instagram. Right.
They've figured out some crazy Kamora
that you do from a closed guard that leads
to a triangle.
I'm like,
what got somebody has to let you do a lot
of those things to some of them. Yeah.
But sometimes people don't
know what you're doing.
They don't even know you're letting them.
I'm always concerned about
rubber guard with the knees,
like fucking up your knee joints cause
you've got to be very flexible to get
that rubber guard in. Yeah,
just stretch. Yeah. Yeah.
Stretch rubber guard.
I don't know what that is.
It's where you put somebody in between
your legs when you described it sounds so
gay. Uh, you put a,
put somebody between your legs and
then you pull your leg over their head,
but their head has to pop through so
you're now you're controlling them.
You can hold their head this way.
It's a lot of fucking rubberiness.
Yes.
That I don't have the ability to do.
It was invented by my friend Eddie Bravo,
but there was some guys who would
play high guard before that.
He just put it into a more, there it
is here. That's a good example of it.
That's what it looks like.
So he's pulling down using his his leg
and his arms to control a guy and wraps
them up and while he's down. Yeah.
Well yeah, so he's on the bottom.
It looks like a Gracie move. It is well
to Jujitsu moves. So it's a bravo move.
All Jujitsu essentially. Sadie
right there. Yeah, there is.
Eddie and Joe came up under my teacher
and then Eddie took it to another level
from there. Well Eddie just branched
out and you know, went into Nogi.
He's much more [inaudible].
He has a black belt, the
as well,
much more concerned with Nogi techniques
because he wanted techniques that would
work in mixed martial arts.
So it mixed martial arts,
you don't have the collars
to grab the sleeves to grab.
So he wanted to invent a
system that you could use a f,
especially when you have the ability
to fight off of your back is very,
when you fight, that's Ben Saunders,
who's like one of the best at it in MMA.
And if you get wrapped up,
you're on top of a Dooney.
He wraps you up with his legs like
that. It's very, it's very demoralizing.
You get so trapped in human nature tells
you when you're on your back and his
guy on top of you, you're in
trouble. But in Jujitsu like, Nah,
it's fine if you've got a good
guard like John Jock. Yeah. Yeah.
Wow. I have an interest in that. What do
you live these days? I live in Canada.
You still live in Toronto? Yeah, I
was in Jamaica for a minute. Yeah,
you were living in Jamaica for me.
Yeah. That was fun. I love Toronto.
It was one of my favorite places
on the call. You first met him.
I introduced you to him. I was telling
him earlier at the nightclub. Yeah.
I took Joe nightclub to meet Lennox and
I remember that meeting though. Yeah.
That's when the,
what's the thing was playing scratch.
Scratch was playing and
everybody was there.
Toronto is just such a perfect city.
It's like the people are nice,
but it's urban, like it's very
populated. There's a lot of people,
but they don't have that asshole
vibe that like New York has.
I think it's the fifth largest
city in North America. Is
it? Yeah, let me tell you.
They're building like mad over there.
All the condos made out of glass,
renters market. Uh,
but tiny little places.
But there's so much cool shit
there and now that weed's legal,
it's probably booming in Canada,
but he was never really an issue there.
If you got caught with it,
like just give it to stop it.
But now it's like you'd
go to their stores,
you know the stores on the street like
yeah,
I think
we saw some stores,
they're opening like
about 25 or 50 in Toronto.
So the government's giving
them great place, man.
I did that place that you do that a
the score. Shannon does center. Oh,
Scotia Bank and call at Scotia Bank.
I just did it in November.
He came home and then you were there I
think a month before me when I got yeah.
Yeah,
that was there before my Netflix special
came out and it came out in October.
So I think I was there around that. Yeah.
Yeah. I fucking love it up there man.
That's probably one of my favorite
cities to visit. Come on back. I love it.
Massey Hall. Love that. Put that
together. Yeah, that was fun, man.
You and me and a big J. Oh, that's
right. That's right. That's right.
Yeah. That was a good time, man. The
UFC is, they're always great too. Yeah.
Good support. They love it up there.
Yeah. Well it's just Toronto. Just such a,
it's such an unusual city. Like Canada
in general. Like I'll ask you this,
why people are so nice. There's so
much nicer than Americans. It's a,
I don't know. It's different.
There's nice American. It's nice.
You're saying they're more polite,
more polite. Yeah. I find that too,
I think are
nicer on as far as, um, have you
been to New York lately? Yeah.
I love it. Here's the
thing. Canadians are polite,
but we'll talk shit about
you and you're not take that,
but take that over.
Being rude.
But Canadians can also get freaked
out by people being a foreword,
which Americans are considered
very forward. And you know, it's,
it's an outgoing thing. So where,
where is an American be like, Hey,
yeah, I want to ask you something.
Eh, Canadians were like, whoa. Why?
Why is this person so aggressive? I'm
like, where's the Canadian? Be like,
excuse me. I'd like to ask you a
question. That's true. That's true.
It's very similar, but just
different approaches. Why, you know,
as far as like standup comedy is there,
how good is the,
the community in Canada?
Is it like the community in America where
there's a lot of up and coming people
or is it, is a lot of comics in Canada,
a lot of great ones come out of Canada.
Um, the problem is there's
no, um, the money's not there.
So no matter touring around like
the clubs, once you get, you know,
the clubs tap out at like, maybe
you'll make, let's see what,
that's six shows on a weekend. I had a
good headline there. Can make 1200 bucks.
That's it. I mean, that's pretty
fucking insane. Yeah, it's rough.
Especially if they're selling
out and making drinking.
That's the problem is that the club it,
I liken it to the UFC almost to a
certain degree. It's not about the comic.
It's about the name of the
club who like Yuk, Yuk, Yuk,
yuks and it doesn't matter who's there,
it's about Yucky. The UFC is about UFC,
doesn't matter who the fucking fighters.
They used to have that attitude at
some of the clubs in La. You know,
that was one of the reasons why they had
that big comic strike way back in the
70s yeah. It's because people
felt like the, you know,
the comics were the ones who
are providing the art form,
but the clubs are the ones who are making
all the money and they were like, hey,
you know, you are you, you're at the
improv where you were at the comedy store.
You know,
the pay scale at these clubs is the same
as it was in the 80s which is fucking
horrible. Like I take people
out on the road with me and,
and the clubs will pay 50 bucks for an
emcee for the weekend and 100 bucks for
the feature. And I'm like, that's
fucking nuts. That's what it was.
I started in 89 and that's what
it was back then. That's crazy.
They just never like that.
And I'm like, that's terrible.
Like how are these kids
going to make a living? Well,
in a way it's a lot like boxing.
Cause like when people think that
boxers make millions of dogs cause Floyd
Mayweather and make $100 million
in a fight. And that is true.
But if you look at the undercard,
like there's guys that are
fighting for chump change. I mean,
and they are going through a long camp.
Do you remember your first paycheck? Yeah.
What was your first boxing paycheck?
5,000 wow. That's because I'm coming,
I'm coming down to the Olympics baby.
Yeah, that's true. But even still,
that's $5,000 for a
fucking professional fight.
But you also had signed a multi
billion dollar deal. Oh yeah.
He's going to add up after a while. Yeah.
I mean you're a, you're an exception.
I mean there's guys fight not there for
like 800 bucks. You know what I mean?
100 try 500 300 yeah. Yeah. So you know,
another thing that disturbs
me about MMA as opposed to
boxing is the a win lose bonus.
I don't like that.
I think fighter,
I think a fighter should get paid
what they're supposed to get paid.
No one's trying to lose,
and if you're trying to lose,
you're never gonna be able to
compete at the highest level anyway.
These guys are pouring their heart and
soul. They're giving their body, they're,
they're,
they're literally sacrificing their
health and they might get fucked out of a
decision and because of that,
they lose 50% of their money.
So some incompetent judge,
which inboxing is everywhere.
I mean the late bird, how dare
you, you just, well, there's a,
there was even worse than her.
There's people that don't even do it
anymore because they get chased out of the
game every time I listen to the eye.
That's when you know
you're a fan of the sport.
When you hear the judge's names go, fuck.
Not that guy. There was a lot of them,
man. There's a lot of them. I mean,
imagine if 50% of your purchase goes away
because someone doesn't know what the
fuck they're doing. The win lose bonus,
they're guaranteed a certain amount,
the guaranteed a certain amount, but
that's to show like say this, right?
Like say maybe you would get 10 and 10
so you get $10,000 to fight and 10,000
more if you win.
It's crazy.
It's oftentimes 50% and the idea is that
you're going to give these fighters and
an incentive to put on a better show.
But I think,
I don't lie and then fight of the night,
I don't like when people
fight any different than the
way they're fighting when
they're fighting the best
and the smartest. Right.
I think you should fight intelligently.
You shouldn't engage in a wild brawl
because you want some performance bonus,
you know?
Because like they'll give out performance
of the night or knock out of the night,
can you,
can you lose and still get the,
the fight of the night bunk Serone
he's got a ton of those phones.
Got a ton of bonuses.
I mean that's him though.
He would fight that way if you gave him
a guarantee. Oh yes. It's a free sample.
If he knew he was going to make a half
million dollars a fight, no matter what,
he would fight exactly that way. That's
how he fights and I think that's how,
that's how it should be. He's an anomaly
though, because he grew up with money,
didn't he like the decent? He grew up
with a decent lifestyle. Terribly poor.
He wasn't wealthy.
I have fun.
I had money and they could grow up
with with a decent amount of money.
That's the way I was sold at.
I don't believe so.
I don't want to speak out of school. I
mean neither, but I have always been,
he's fought Bj Penn.
Did you know Bj Penn is a legend.
Bj grew up with a wealthy family.
They're wealthy. He just was a fighter.
He finds it, saw somewhere. He's fine.
He's gonna fight. Click Weda. Yes.
That's a fucking odd one. When
he retired, he did. He got bored,
so I still wants to do it.
He actually lived very good and this
last fight up until they told him he got
very exciting fighter back in the day.
There's still a wild man.
He's still a while,
but he got leg lock by Ryan Hall,
who's just phenomenal Jujitsu
player and he, he caught him with a,
he did a, uh, uh,
Amun Ra role and caught him at a leg lock
and just fucked his leg up and Minari
role. Yeah. You're talking about,
it sounds like something you eat it
him and our role,
um,
him and Ari is this a very famous Japanese
fighter who was a phenomenal leg lock
artist and does actually two moves.
There's two,
there's the MNR role and
there's an immune Ari,
which at MNR he comes from a Omoplata
and Omoplata is a shoulder lock.
I think it's a Portuguese word.
I think that's what they call it.
[inaudible] it's from your leg
gets a, yeah, it's a shoulder lock.
And then the inventory is,
while you're locked up in the Alma Plata,
you grab like a grip underneath the guy's
Chin and Yank them back. It's a nasty,
now I'll show you tomorrow.
I hope not.
I really hope I can just
have a friendly role weekend.
But if you catch yourself in a
normal plot that it's common.
You don't, you know what's funny is when,
uh, uh, I'm a big fan of the NRM choke,
which I know is your favorite head
and arm. Yeah. And uh, and then
yeah, and then, uh, you're on jack now
calls of the Joe Hogan. Some would do it.
Can the Joe Hogan and then that's
your move. You've actually,
that's now your move at the gym.
Well, you know, sometimes you
have like techniques that you, uh,
you hit so often that you just know when
they're there and you can close them up
real quick. Yeah. That was
my shit.
That's what I've been ever since then
I've actually been working on that.
Well, you know, somebody,
you guys did it to me and it's
such a suffocating feeling.
And when someone's on top of you
and you got your arm pinned here,
that neck arms across your neck and
you like it a and you make that noise.
Funny enough, it's a horrible way to
get choked out. The esteem and luck.
I like when guys get locks named
after them. How do you get out of it?
You have to put your hand on your ear
like you're answering the phone. That's,
that's one.
Then the first thing is you're trying
to create some space here so that you
don't go to sleep.
You gotta,
you gotta give into the fact that this
guy's choking this side of your neck for
sure. So the arms coming under
here and it's wrapping around here,
and if you just go like that
and it's down or like that,
it's going to get smushed. You're
getting, you're getting smashed, right?
So you got to bring this thing in here,
it trying to create a little bit of space.
Then you hope this motherfucker gets
tired of squeezing your neck and then you
try and get in here and create a little
bit of space. That's what we tried to do.
Just give me a little bit of space
at a time. Little bit of space. Just
get a little bit of space.
It's all just a matter of little inches,
little tiny micro movements.
But when someone has your arm wrapped up
like that and they have that arm across
your neck and it's crushing you with
their body weight and then they get their
knee on your solar plexus and
flat and you out and squeeze down.
It's horrible.
Are there funders and other countries
that don't go into Lma but they're
unbelievable fighters but they're not
trying to show anybody that they're
unbelievable fighters. Oh,
like Kung Fu guys? No, no.
Those guys all get fucked
up and they try to,
they think they do it because you start
believing it and you have your students
and they believe you're the master and
Shaolin Gadhia tried entering a bunch,
a bunch of those videos, that guy,
he would wear the Orange Shaolin suit
and he would win and like these really
hokey fight competition.
Then you get into the big ones and you
just get the shit beat out of him. Yeah,
he was kickboxing. Yeah. He
actually has some skills.
Like he didn't used to watch a
show that he could do a little bit.
But what I'm talking about,
it's like these cheap masters,
like a lot of those numbers are the ones
where you put a seems real are those
are so sad. Yeah. Yeah.
Dope. Yeah. Um, uh,
Mick Dojo,
what is the,
the mic Dojo life on Instagram
has a shit load of those.
It was making me laugh. There's so sad.
That's what you put you put seems legit.
Yeah.
Well a lot of those budget is fuck.
They'll go and fight a real fighter and
they think they actually know how to
fight and they just get cut costs. They
just get smashed open cause you know why?
Why don't they don't get hit? Yeah.
They don't get that. That's why.
That's why I love boxing. Boxing. You
spar all the time. Yup. Hit all the time.
So you know, in a real
fight, boxers of being hit,
you know guys up do Kung Fu and all
those things, they don't get hit.
So when they do get hit in the real fight,
it's like it messes them up. It's like,
no, I do not see this coming.
Yeah. Practical application.
The difference between
practicing and you know,
thinking there's so many of these,
there is this guy doing,
I haven't seen this one.
This is a new one.
I just picked one that
that guy in the black,
he looks like he's going
to fuck this dude up.
It's a very like gay looks like the
carpeting and my bedroom. Oh my God,
what are these guys are, oh, see
that. She did just see that. Oh,
I wonder why they were in such weird
gies and everyone can everybody clapping.
Many black belts are in that
class. God days, silly Fox.
They really believed that.
I bet that guy could get them
to suck his dick the same way.
I know people who really believe that
their teacher can do that stuff, so
they're called priests.
How dare you. Yeah. It's,
it's weird that those people are still
around in the day of video cameras that
you can still have this. But yeah,
what you're saying is probably like,
even when you were saying that if you
hadn't fought in two years and then you
would get in there and get hit, you're
like, whoa. Okay. Okay. Let's see.
I seen Keith Thurman do that
really old in his last fight
in Lopez is in a banger by any means. He
looked a little little off though. Yeah.
But Keith Thurman had to suffer through
that one little concussion concussed,
I should say. And he was all right after
that. If you hit him with that same shot,
he would have took it even better.
Yeah. Because he got over the hump.
I still get that fight to Lopez though.
A lot of people did. Yeah. Yeah.
It was a close fight and you know, it
was Thurman's big comeback fight. I mean,
how long had he been out? Two years at
least. Was He injured? He was injured.
He had some sort of shuttle
operations elbow or, yeah.
So you know, but that's also one of the
things that makes it so interesting,
you know?
I mean,
when and when a guy does come back
from a devastating loss and he'd go,
okay, like, like Manny Pacquiao
when mark has knocked him out out.
Ooh, I mean crazy. That was a
bad one. That was a bad one.
Yeah, that was a bad one.
That's going to cause some slurring
later. Maybe it's like, you know,
you make a move,
it's a good move,
but then you've moved into the man's
power punch and he hits you and you know,
there's no second chance with
that one. Yeah. And uh, mark has,
I mean he's a, he's an interesting
case, you know what I mean?
He's a obviously a very, very
talented fighter, but as he got older,
he got like physically stronger. He
got bigger and stronger. You know,
Mexican supplements can
meet a lot involved.
Clem mood around meat monkey
juice. There's a lot involved
there. Right. I mean,
and he actually was working with Manny
Pacquiao is old strength and conditioning
guy and man, he was the guy who was
always accused of doing stuff. Oh,
you're talking about Alex or,
yeah,
I mean Manny went up eight when you had
house or he is a trained me before. Yeah.
When I was doing my special three
years ago. Look at them jacked.
Does he still fighting? No, he's retired.
My cousin's done. Yeah. Good for him.
Cause they're talking about Floyd.
They're doing a,
they're talking about doing
a Floyd Pacquiao rematch.
I'm not really excited about that.
You know what I'm excited about?
I want to see how much money
Floyd Mayweather can make.
I'm excited. I mean, look,
the fucking,
the fact that he talked to everybody into
that Conor McGregor fight and he made
more than a hundred million dollars.
Isn't that tension kid fighting again
and he's fighting somebody else? No, no.
Zwickau yeah, he's a, he's a bad ass.
Ain't nobody's supposed to be fighting
another, uh, another boxer. Yeah.
I think you're right. Probably
a lesser one. But you know,
tension is 126 pounds.
Yeah.
So we should find somebody that's mean
the fact that he fought Mayweather at all
and people are like, oh it looks
like it was a fake fight. No,
that's what it looks like
when 126 pound fighter fights.
One of the best boxers of all time.
Yeah, that's what it looks like.
They don't look fake.
He did fall very dramatically cause
he cut his fucking praying rattled,
you know? Oh it's daunting. Oh my God.
They can't make that
weight anymore either.
Drawn to kind of make
the weight he's at now,
but they don't have them make
weight. That's the thing.
They just have them fight.
I mean Floyd didn't make any fucking
wait did he? What'd you like?
Do you like the way one fc is doing their
weight thing? Yes. I like the clot. Yeah.
For people don't know. They don't let
them cut weight. They, they, they,
they do hydration tests.
So there's no dehydrating yourself.
So if you weighed natural,
you walk around 185 pounds,
you're going to fight it 185 pounds.
You're not going to fight at one 70
or one 65 like a lot of these guys do.
That's good. Yeah, I'd love,
yeah, that's good because, uh,
the hydration aspect of even in any sport,
taking that liquid away from the
brain. Yeah. Your body needs liquid.
Yeah. It's a vibes on liquids
and it makes your bones brittle.
It's terrible for you in every way.
It's terrible for your performance,
your internal organs.
A lot of guys have kidney failure
when they're cutting away for Wayne's.
That's the beautiful thing
about you being a heavyweight. Right.
I didn't have to take off my clothes.
I can weigh whatever,
but there was always that fighting weight
where I would be perfect that Manny
was good at that. Yeah, I'm
sure way. Okay. Don't move.
Don't move from there to 42 35 to
35 was a perfect knew you were on.
Yup. Yeah. Now what kind of,
what kind of nutrition did you
follow when you're fighting? Did you,
did you take specific vitamins
or any specific things? No,
just a Jamaican food. Jamaican
food. Yeah. Uh, Angelo,
Dundee asked me that same question.
Yeah. I said, what do you eat? I said,
my mother's food. He said, if it,
if it ain't broke, don't fix it.
That's a perfect Angelo Dundee quote.
Yep. Yeah. He's another one man.
Remember that in there with the sugar
ray Leonard Against Thomas Turns.
You're blowing at kid and he gets,
she should write a letter.
I get fired up and he goes out
and stop some of the next round.
If there was a lot of good trainers back.
Georgie Benton Benton.
Yeah. Bless his soul. Good
for good train as well.
It's so important for a young fighter
to get hooked up with the right trainer.
Right. You know, we got
on that for a second.
I think part of the problem with
a lot of young kids right now,
they need to get good trainers.
Yeah.
Good trainers really help
your game because even helps
you with the, with the, uh,
TV because,
um,
I was saying today that when
a man came into my corner,
HBO started talking about me
better before nothing was like, oh,
he doesn't throw the job and off he
looks like he's tired. The fight.
When I went with Manny, they
were like praising me. Oh,
he's doing good now, Matt.
He's my knees behind them now.
He's a trainer of champion.
So training really helps you your game.
Where are you with Mandy when you fought
Mercer? Yes. That was a war. Yeah.
That was actually, no, I wasn't,
I wasn't the immersive fight he actually
taught Mercer helped me out because um,
before that fight,
I was always fighting guys that hooked,
hooked around body shots and hooks.
So I kept my hands like this
other side of my face. Then that,
and then I went into that
fight, got a fat lip. I hated,
I hate getting fat lips in my
fights. It's like, you know,
hey you did you win the fight?
Yeah. It didn't look like you.
You got to get a fat lip from,
you know.
So I kept on walking around with a
fat lip and then I got, you know,
I got a good picture of,
you got a good picture of you and me and
Lloyd and you got a fat lip and right.
That's the, when he fights from like
[inaudible] 97 and then then man, he said,
you know what you're doing wrong.
He said,
you need to put your hand in front
of your mouth. I'm like, okay.
So even if a guy throws a punch,
which slides it doesn't slide through,
it's going to hit your hand.
And he said,
you can move your hand two inches to
protect yourself from a hook, can't you?
And I said, yeah. Oh, okay. You're right.
No more fat lips. Well, I used to
getting fat lips book. Everybody
look at you funny. That's hilarious.
Well, but having a great trainers, it's,
it's, it's so important in MMA as well.
I mean it,
and there's not that many of them.
It's like you really have
to find the right ones.
You got a good trainers to just former
fighters now. Right? Well there's that.
Yeah, but you know,
someone has to be a real,
you can't just be a trainer or
just be a former fighter. Rather,
you have to be a student to
really understand the game.
Like a manual was only an amateur fighter.
Right. He never fought professional.
And he was one of the greatest
of all time. Unquestionably.
Everybody respected him and so soft
spoken, you know, and just, but just knew,
just knew how to raise fighters.
And you think about all the guys,
Jeremy Mclellan, Tommy Hearns, all the
great fighters that came out of that camp.
The only problem I have with, you know,
old time fighters is like, you know, some,
some old time fighters were bad fighters.
Now,
right now the training a young kid the
same way. Right? Not, it's not positive.
It's like a teaching them the bad tricks.
Yeah.
But then there's guys who are better as
trainers and they were as far as like a
roach, 100% yeah. Like
Freddie Roach is recognized.
One of the greatest trainers for
sure alive, but as a fighter,
it was a journeyman.
Kevin Rooney was a good trainer and his
dad and he got knocked up by her quiet
one second round. Well, he
was a good trainer with Tyson,
but he never really developed
town outside of the,
it's developed a lot of alcohol.
That's what so,
so he don't hang around with Mike and
he's got hires on a leash and then buddy
had a good run for a minute. Buddy.
Mcgirt he's still training fighters.
I've tried to buddy before.
Yeah, he was a great fighter,
but he was a great fighter.
Yeah. Great Dude. Yo,
you haven't trained with
me at [inaudible]. Uh,
uh,
listen man,
your phone keeps blowing up and you were
supposed to be out of here an hour ago,
but I appreciate your time, man. It was
an honor to sit here and talk to you.
Thanks for having one of my favorites
of all time appreciated, Russell.
I like you too. Thanks man. You're my
favorite guy to get choked off, sweetie.
We're going to have some fun tomorrow.
Jesus. Lennox Lewis, ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you everybody.
That was great.