Wow.
We're live. Good googly Mowgli. Jeff Ross,
push that fucker up to your face and
say hello to the world. Hello world.
Are you taking off the, you know, know
headphones or you grab all your Rabel.
You don't give a fuck. You look
great. You look great as well.
Fellow black belt in Tae Kwon.
I saw a picture of you
and you're a little kid.
Somebody posted it up on my message board.
He wouldn't be like the youngest black
belt in New Jersey or something crazy
like that. Yeah. Second. Yup. Second
in the country. He fucking savage.
You were dropping some, uh, some
knowledge about all of this. Uh, we,
we started the podcast up quick. Look
at that. Look at that fucking wow.
That's bad ass little kid. I never knew
that. I'm a 10 and a half in that picture.
Right. Chop and pitches. Am I
still a blackbelt Joe? Technically,
if it doesn't fit around my waist anymore,
you are s you have earned it.
Whether or not you were at black
belt level or not, that's debatable.
But you have earned your black
belt so you are a black belt.
It's like the marine. I love that.
Once you go black, you never go back.
Um, we were talking, we started the
podcast up abruptly because, uh,
we were talking about, um, how do
you, wait, one question for you.
How do you think being a black
belt is affected your comedy? My,
I don't, I don't know. None. Not at all.
I don't think I would have the confidence
to talk shit if I didn't get a black
belt early on. Really? Yeah. It probably
helps something come on of course. Sure.
And that way out about it.
Well definitely helps.
Like you not be worried
about confrontation as much?
Well, at least. Yeah. Oh,
for sure. Like having that, uh, what do
they have around Israel? Cone of silence?
No, the uh, the Dome,
something they have a dome is
like a defense system. Oh, I see.
Right, right, right. So you
have a defense system in place.
It might be a little rusty and a
little, you know, in need of some tuna,
but it's there. Well, anybody
that would, most of the time,
anybody that would hackle you
or think about attacking you,
usually they're so fucking stupid.
Like the vast majority of
hecklers are so God damn dumb.
But I've been around so many
people that can kick my ass.
I'm don't feel very confident
it'll work in for the UFC.
I'm just constant around people
that could just fuck me up anytime.
I've just don't feel very confident.
I like with regular people maybe,
but to some to humbled by my job
with a bunch of fighters. Yeah.
What have you been doing with them? Joe?
Daddy Stevenson. Yeah. Joe Stevenson
Mentor and like fighting
coach for the show kingdom
MMA fighters and underground scene.
That's a direct TV show, right?
[inaudible] on that
towns on it. Yeah. Yeah.
That's cool that directv is doing
their own programming. It's nice.
It's like there's so many different
avenues for programming now.
It's pretty fucking bad.
Make show and then they show the show and
now it's on iTunes and I'm on the next
season. It's a cool thing because it's
fun to see the fight world get dramatized.
It's like Friday lights
for uh, for fights. Right. Are there good
scenes though? Like very aggressive. Yeah,
of course. As a fan you're going to,
fans would roll their eyes and go,
how realistic could be,
I've only been to one fight.
It was the one you and Ari invited me to.
Which one was that?
You mean Coover few years back
and a have to think of who was,
might've been turned. That sounds like,
I think it was Jon Jones, was it John?
John Kerry, John Jones and
Gustafson. Was that Vancouver?
My jaw was dropping at the
blood. It's crazy. Never been.
So now these fight scenes
we should at night.
So it's very realistic and
it's surprisingly authentic.
It's all real fighters and boxers
fighting the actors on this show.
Nick Jonas music superstar.
When the Jones brothers on the show,
not one of the Jonas brothers,
like the guy who's got the number one
music career right now is also playing a
fighter and he's a total bad ass. And I
know it sounds crazy, but he's ripped.
He's in these scenes for six,
seven hours a night, two,
three nights in a row shooting these,
just the fight scenes.
Then the next day or all day he's got
to do like actual dramatic acting.
But the files are really well
done. They're, they're raw.
People get hurt. There's a lot of real
blood mixed with the acting blood.
You know right here. Look at his
fucking Stud. I'm telling you man,
I was so impressed.
Looks like Tj Walberger I play a sleazy
promoter that hires him even though he's
uh, out of medical leave from
fighting. It's a handsome bastard.
Does he actually know martial arts?
He is very believable as a fighter.
Like some of the fighters said he's as
good. Joe Daddy actually told me this.
I don't know if I'm supposed to,
but he thinks he's as good as some of
the fighters that they have come train
them. Really? That if he was fighting,
he would beat this guy for real.
Like he was doing the senior of the night.
And that's what Joe Daddy,
that gay scene right there,
right there that's going on right there.
That looks like,
I dunno what's going on,
whatever. By the time they get
under hooks to fight him off,
get that right under hook. It's a very
intense show. There's a lot of tears.
And is that a drugs and fucking,
are those tattoos on his arm or is he
just like really in a tape? What is,
what is that? As soon as thing bro, like
duct tape up before I leave my house,
Bro. I think he's taped up.
It's a bad technique, right?
They're getting a little upset
about being naked. Choke technique.
What's he doing with his right hand?
Why isn't it behind the guy's head?
You are not watching a sanction
clip from the show. I'm watching.
This is what I do when I'm fucking,
I think you're watching this John Long
wash to start questioning your sexuality.
Alan,
you catch have done that,
but I don't quite sync the choke in.
You've started fuck staring at Nick
Jonas getting choked out for almost three
minutes now. Hypnotize. It's like one
of those fucking clocks. Tick Tock,
tick tock.
Hamu
I'm getting so if you
ever been hypnotized, no,
I got hypnotized reasonably for the first
time ever. Was very interesting. Yeah.
This guy who uh, Vinny shoreman,
it's been on the podcast,
he hypnotize a lot of fighters,
da. He's like kind of a mind coach,
knows a lot about like uh,
how to uh,
eliminate barriers that
people have set up.
I could send them to you buddy
kicked this fucking cigarette habit,
get you on the road to recovery.
But um,
it's very interesting because when you
get hypnotized you're aware of what's
going on.
You're totally aware,
but you are definitely in some sort of
fucking weird dreamland. Very strange.
Where you completely sober? 100%.
Yeah. 100% sober sitting on the couch.
Was it just the adventure where
you're trying to cure something? Why?
I'm curious cause I wanted to know what,
cause I know a lot of fighters have
used it and had very good results.
Like it's alleviated a
lot of anxiety with them,
giving them a lot of confidence and
they've attributed to a lot of their
positive performances. It's not foolproof.
Better man always wins every time,
you know.
And sometimes fighters who don't have
a mind coach will still beat fires that
have a mind coach.
But I think all things said,
if you add all the different things
that a fighter has to be aware of,
you have to be in shape. You have to
know your techniques, you have to be,
you know,
motivated.
It's a lot of stuff going on in a
fighter's head that it has to be lined up
properly and a mind coach,
not a bad idea.
Having someone who can hypnotize you
and give you a tenants to live by and
pathways that you could
follow that are positive.
I think that's fucking super
important for, for anybody,
for fighters, for anybody.
So I just wanted to try it.
I wanted to see when I see if what
it does for fighting can actually,
you'll actually do for stand up.
Did you trust this guy?
Did you notice hypnotists?
Like he didn't pay any crazy things
that you make chicken noises, but no,
no. It was just, uh, I mean
I wasn't, it wasn't like, you
know, take your pants off.
Suck my deck. It wasn't
like Addie. No, I know.
It wasn't because I was awake
the whole time like you're awake.
It's a weird feeling man.
It's like you're, you're,
you're listening to him but it's almost
like you're in a room and he's coming in
over a loudspeaker and your, your eyes
are closed. That's what it feels like.
It's very strange. Very
strange there. Anything you
can compare it to? Is it yoga?
Is it like, no, it's
like a little bit like a,
something that might happen in a sensory
deprivation tank because it seems like
you go into this weird alternate state
and that's a sort of how he describes it,
that you're,
you're actually entering into an alternate
state of consciousness and like I'm a
different mind state. Very,
very interesting stuff.
I was always curious because you
ever seen a r rated hypnotist?
The guys that are really good, you ever
see Frank Santos wasn't, he was on,
I remember him in Boston. Yes.
She's the best. Who's the best?
That guy can seem creepy to me.
Like he had the hottest wife imaginable
and he looked like a frog and he knocked
it out of the park.
Who's a great guy though.
I just kept looking at her trying to
think of whatever the that say the code
word was,
snap her out of it.
Just tickles randomly Graham crackers just
to see what she's like, why don't you,
I'm married to who? Wait, wait.
I was at a corporate
party. What happened? No,
I'm married to a hypnotist.
He would have guys come in their
parents all the time. He would a,
this is back when Madonna was hot.
It was like the 1980s and
he had some guy and he,
the guy was like doing pushups
on stage and he told them,
now Madonna's underneath you and she's
naked and you're having sex with her and
you could see the guy literally thank,
he was having sex with Madonna
and he would come, Jesus,
are you going to go back,
have more suicides like sessions
and like tried to do it again.
I would definitely do it again.
The hypnotizing thing,
I think I would do it again.
Vinnie lives in England,
so he's only a here occasionally.
But uh,
if I found someone that was good
that was in this area, I would do it.
I think there's something videotape
it though. Right? So creeped out.
I'm not scared. Yeah, I'd
be her scope. That shit.
At least I have to suck your Dick.
Blotching did it from their phones and
their car fall asleep at the wheel and
drive out in the trap. But they all
fall asleep along with me. Wait,
why haven't, why hasn't it like a TV
show? If hypnotism does exist or like,
and it's true, why hasn't a
TV should done that? Like,
like have like a 15 minute opening where
they just hypnotize everyone that's
watching it. It's good. Yeah.
Actually you should do it.
That's how the Jonestown massacre started.
You know what?
Skype hypnotizing is a way a cult.
You could get a group of
people to sacrifice to a crime.
He does stuff over Skype.
There's probably laws,
there should be anti hypnotism laws
for more than small groups of people.
I don't know if it works like that.
What if Hitler was just a hypnotist,
that those big crowds, he's like, fuck it.
Don't you think that when you're staying,
you're onstage and you're killing when
you're locked in? Don't you think?
That's kind of a sense, like sort of
a massive gnosis and a lot of ways,
don't you feel like that? Like that?
I never thought about it that way,
but I could see that.
You know how like when you're in the
middle of your material and you're locked
in,
you're tuned into the audience,
the audience is tuned in to you and
they're kind of thinking like you're
thinking.
I feel that way when I watched somebody,
if I watch somebody really good, so I'm
like, I'll watch bird the other night.
He was hilarious. And I feel like
when you watch someone is really good,
you're tuning in to what they do. Like
you're, you're, you're in their head,
like they're in your head, I guess more.
And you're like, you're just kind of a,
like an empty vessel and your brain
is filled up with their ideas.
And when someone's captivating,
especially like d as the other,
I had this fucking Cosby
bit that was killing me,
fucking killing me.
And when he's doing it,
you're thinking the way he thinks.
Like your eyes are open,
you're anticipating
what he's going to say.
You don't have any room in
your head for anything else.
Like you're thinking the way he's
thinking. Got, he's inside your head.
He's hypnotizing entire crowd.
He's taking you for a ride.
Even if you didn't believe weren't
with them. Now you are. Yeah.
He's taking you for a ride.
He's taking you for a ride and a lot of
ways he's on the same ride. You know?
I always feel that way too. Like a
lot of ways, I've always said this,
that when I'm at my best,
I'm as much of a passenger
as I am a driver, you know,
I kind of have to make the turns and
steer the car and figure out which way the
bits are going to go.
But when I'm locked in,
I feel like I'm just riding it like it's,
I just have to get out of my own way.
You know?
Until you feel like that
I can understand being on a role and
not thinking how's this going or what
should I do?
Just talking your as if you're talking
to your buddy in the back seat of your
car.
Well especially your style too
because you like to fuck with people.
Right and so when you're fucking with
people you're coming out of nowhere.
I mean you just pulling
them out of the universe.
Yeah.
I remember hearing once how important
there was an article a long time ago,
maybe it was in a book about late
night hosts and you have to listen.
Just as soon as I stopped trying to
think of jokes and just started to listen
and trust that whatever I said
would be entertaining in some way.
Eventually if I just stay in it and
just listen to the other person. If,
if a funny character is presented
in front of me, if someone's boring,
you might have to try to write a
joke on the spot and your head,
but if they're an interesting person you
could just talk to them and eventually
it's going to land on something funny.
Yeah, that is a problem with some comics
is that they're so in their own head.
They don't listen to the
person they're talking.
I had a lady on stage in Chicago and
so speed roasting the crowd and Gosh,
she was like a really round person with
a crazy yellow Mohawk way over the top.
And she was tiny little thing
but built like a little mailbox,
the big mouth, just a funny,
funny body. And she came on,
just threw herself up on stage one
or to be roasted. And I was like,
uh, you said a lot of, a lot of people,
I think I said a lot of people couldn't
pull off that outfit and you're two of
them.
I don't know what the Shit,
I'm relearning a crime with a fond memory.
He came to you out of nowhere.
Uh, I got to remember the joke.
We came to you and they're like,
yeah, you're just listening and boom.
That's the home run that people remember
because it wasn't thought about ahead
of time was just listening to the looking.
And you know,
when you're roasting people listening is
also looking like taking a good look at
assessing exactly what's
been put in front of you.
Do you,
uh,
when you were doing the prison thing and
you talked to the guy and you said you
look at a combination of a
child and a child molester.
Yeah, yeah. They're rare
personal click a child,
not a child molester at the
same time. And he did, you know,
it wasn't like Fidel. He
did. Yeah. Nailed it there.
I just say try to say out loud what
people normally would say behind people's
backs.
Hence the karate self defense.
I do remember early instances of hecklers
before I knew anything about roasting.
I was just a comedian, you know,
usually emceeing, uh, you know,
on the road or a jersey,
you know,
or you had a lot of characters
and in the audience.
And I remember a few times people taking
swings at me or just walking on stage.
I was working with rich vos
at a firehouse. You know,
I'd only been doing comedy a year or
two and I opened for him at some sort of
fundraiser to firehouse.
And Ah,
I was about five minutes into
my routine Saturday night.
These firemen are in their firehouse.
There's, this is, you know,
this is before there were any rules
to anything as far as you know,
uh, and just, just, they kept telling
me, make fun of Larry, make fun of Larry.
He loves it. Make Fun of Larry and I
don't know who Larry is and you know,
of course Larry turned out to be the
biggest asshole on the planet who doesn't
love it at all.
And he literally was gigantic and walked
up on stage and took the microphone out
of my hand, put it in the mic
stand and said, you're done.
Wow.
The audience laughing before that.
I don't remember. I'm sure they
weren't laughing enough. You know,
I just remember it being so
hard and it just builds up your,
you have to have thick skin and
you got to be able to like stare.
You got to have confidence that you
know, you're, you're in the right.
Well, you definitely would get
a little bit more confidence.
Haven't gone through martial arts cause
you've, you've done some difficult stuff.
Been involved with a
little bit of conflict.
I mean I did karate
tournament as a kid and
it's like you never feel more
alive than when you're competing.
And I love when comedy
has a little tension to,
it doesn't have to be
all about what I think.
I sometimes I remember getting it as
heckling became more and more pro in the
audiences. You just more and more
you heard people heckling and uh,
there were famous instances of hecklers
and audiences and stuff like that and I
said, fuck it. People are going to
videotape to shows. It's so annoying.
Why don't I just go one step further
and put the audience on stage? Well, I,
so that's when he started speed roasting,
interactive.
I wanted my show to be more interactive
and I, I'm still partially like that,
but I think the audience is a big part of
the experience now. We'll also for you,
because that's your, it's
your style. Like, you know,
maybe that wouldn't work for some guys,
but you it just fits. Yeah. So you do it.
Yeah. And I grew up at a catering
hall. I like talking to people.
I like knowing why they're at my show
and [inaudible]. Yeah. My grandparents,
my uncles, my cousins. Me. So you
just always around people. Uh,
food people.
He dancer tons with stars.
You were telling me that you got your,
I fucked up and dance with the star.
Had a scratched cornea on
the last rehearsal on the
first day of the live show
and went to the hospital and
danced. Anyway, it was just,
I got the lowest scores since,
since,
I dunno know Larry Flynt wheelchair
flipped over and season two.
So you just couldn't see. Oh, you had
an eye patch while you were doing.
Wow. Do Lucky. You'll fucking
look pretty thin there. Yeah.
Well there's a lot of way doing that
show. I lost about 20 pounds. Yeah.
How much is your ego away the year he
goes off five pounds for sloths. That too.
But I look good. That's editor.
She's awesome. Yeah. You.
You have to practice every day
for that shit. I practiced.
I was in the best shape of my
life. Yeah, I did a all day.
I did a dancing scene with Leslie
Bibb in the movie zookeeper.
We had to do this fucking crazy dancing
scene, so we had to take dancing lessons.
It's hard. It's fucking hard to do.
And here's the thing, I don't like it.
I love it. I didn't want to do it. Do you
pull it out? The roast battle? We have a,
no, I don't want to do already on the back
bar. Really at the comedy store. Dance,
dance, dance like 30 people to me. Why is
it 150 degrees in here? Any reason? Maybe.
Let's see if there was an ac things
work. It's hot as fuck in here, isn't it?
I do the whip. I'm sweating
too. Then ne Ne. What does
that, it's a new dance craze.
Oh, whip and the DNA name.
Do you know what it means?
It means when you break your leg and you
had a cast on and you take off the cast
and it stinked like the stinky leg.
So what it means. The kid had it here.
All the kids are going crazy. You ever
heard of stinky leg? What do you do?
You not even on the mic and
you're not making any sense.
Go put the AC on and come back and we're
formulate your thoughts while you're
out there.
That's Brian two hits and that's what
happens to hits and he forget. He just,
he just doesn't make sense to anybody but
him to him. It's totally making sense.
It's just so fun. Thanks buddy.
Nice studio. Glad to be on the show.
It's comfortable, right?
First Time. Finally Dude,
I've been asking You keep saying no.
Well you know,
I'm just happy to be here. I'm happy
to have you here man. I get to see you.
We've been friends a long
time. Long fucking time. Back
before you were Jeff Ross.
That's right. I knew you would do
different numb diploma. Lift Schultz. Yes.
Back Up. What made you change it
to Ross? It's enough. Enough. Well,
technically Ross. Well Ross is my middle
name and I'm still Jeff. Flip shoulds,
what I call your driver's license.
Certain things, taxes and shit. And
I was on star search.
That's why I changed it.
And Ed Mcmahon kept
mispronouncing my name.
This is my first time on TV and I was
so, it just threw me, I was so new,
I didn't know he just couldn't handle,
please welcome your challenge or Jeff
Lifshitz and it's just come out from my
three minutes, like all frazzled,
trying to make my family proud.
I'd never been on TV. So now
their names wrong, you know? So,
and then you also had to use a smaller
font on the screen when they introduced
me and it made me crazy. Jeff Lifschultz.
It took up the whole, Oh right.
So on the flight home,
after I lost,
I said I gotta do something and I just
started using my middle name Ross named
after my great grandmother
Rose Lift Schultz,
who was the greatest cater in New Jersey.
And it all comes full circle.
Well it's good too because it's
the same letters, Jeff Ross,
the same amount of letters, foreign for
Bam. And that only started in solid. Yeah,
it feels good. Solid. I
like it. Hey man, it works.
And by the way, when I was bad, when I
was a kid, they called me that anyway.
Jeffrey Ross. Javier. Oh really? Yeah.
Oh well that's perfect then. Yeah.
What made you decide to
do this thing in a prison?
Because that was a fucking
risky, ballsy move. You know,
we talked about it and like Paul
Rodriguez had a special that he did in the
prison, but uh, quite honestly, he looked
a little nervous. It's back in the day,
it looks a little nervous. This
was many years ago. He did a,
an HBO special live from that prison
critique that he looked nervous and a
prison. Of course it's because
you didn't look nervous.
You watch carefully enough
because I was fucking,
I can hear myself stuttering and
I can see my sub shaking. And,
but you were pretty remarkably relaxed
for the fact that you were roasting
prisoners. I mean, you were having
fun with it, man. It was fun.
And you even speed roasted them on stage.
So you turned your back to
these fucking guys. Like,
did you know who they were or
what they did? No. No idea. No,
but I, I thought it would be disrespectful
not to do it. Like a doing normal show,
right? No, no. I didn't
know a lot about them.
I just tried to be in the moment and
learn about them as I went along and I
learned a lot. Well you wrote
something, was it for huff post?
Is that what you wrote it for?
And I read it and then I
retweeted it because it was,
it was fucking really powerful man.
And that's one of the things about
their is I went to a Texas jail to Rosia
inmates.
You here what I learned about
incarceration in America
and then in the corner is
a girl arrest. Um, but it's also,
it wasn't just that, it wasn't
just this, this article too,
but also the little pieces that you had a,
in the videos where
you had like the stats,
like one out of every 100 Americans is
in jail and there's more black men in
jail right now than there were slaves in
the 18 hundreds. Right. Fucking a man.
It's an emergency. It's an embarrassment
to America when you think about that,
if that many people are in jail and
you know it is one good piece of positive
news I saw is that they're commuting
some sentences of nonviolent
drug offenders. You know,
it'll only be in the hundreds,
that 65 so far,
which is done or what I saw the other
day in one article at least. Yeah.
So maybe there's some hope that, I
don't know. I do feel like the show,
the roast helped people talk about it
in a way that there's a little more
accessible because it wasn't
something I knew a lot about.
And as I started writing,
I really just wanted a roast criminals.
I thought it'd be funny.
And as I started writing the act,
I did a stand up act for months in
rehearsal in just to acclimate myself and
then have an act that would kill in
front of people that are locked up.
Right now.
I learned so much and that's what I think
is the greater good for me is that not
only that I make them laugh, but I
got something out of it too. I mean,
it's embarrassing that we have more
people locked up in America than anywhere
else in the world.
And we're supposed to be a free country.
And the reasons why they're locked up,
that's what's fucked up.
And the also the idea that like
someone in his world can't fuck up.
You can't make a mistake.
And if you do make a mistake,
then you get locked in a cage.
Especially a mistake if you're thinking
about someone who's coming from a really
poor background who needed money,
took a chance and sold
some drugs and that's it.
And then you're locked in a cage.
And that's,
I'm sure a lot of the people
that you were talking to,
a lot of people that you were looking at,
they were in there for some
sort of nonviolent truck crime.
It's a big percentage of our,
our, our prison population.
And when we were in the parking lot
of the comic store, we had that,
a conversation about it. It's,
uh, it's pretty obvious that,
I don't know if it changed it.
Could I say it changed you or it
certainly affected you in a big way, man,
you were,
you were really taken aback by it.
And just the sheer numbers
and the experience itself.
Everybody in there is a human being.
You know,
you look at those orange jumpsuits on the
news or on lock up and people are just
getting tossed around and pushed around.
There's parts of jails.
And even I didn't get to shoot in,
you know,
there's in the 70s hundreds of thousands
of beds in mental hospitals just closed
down.
This is the way we run mental illness
and America changed in the 70 so now the
jails will become
de facto mental hospitals and these
jailers have to babysit people that are
crazy.
And that's not what the job is.
And these places become very complicated
to run and we just lock these people
away. They come back over
and over and over like human
dust. We forget about them.
If you lock them, put them over there.
We don't have to think about them,
but the food sucks.
Solitary confinement is barbaric.
You know,
we should just sort of be talking about
that should be the biggest thing they
talked about in that Republican. I hardly
heard anything about prison reform.
It seems to me like this is an emergency.
It does seem like that.
Did you hear they put Chelsea manning
and solitary because her toothpaste was
expired. They can do whatever they want.
It's like, I wish I was making it up.
Jamie. Pull it up. Why? What
was the reason for that?
Not supposed to have expired toothpaste?
She wasn't brushing her teeth enough.
It was just one of those
things where they just, they
had a violation. They fucking hate
this girl who used to be a guy.
If you don't know the whole story,
she is the former formerly artist,
formerly known as, what was it written?
The middle of the original name?
Bradley Manning. Yeah, Bradley. And uh,
he gave all the files to wikileaks
and a look at this wikileaks source.
Manning convicted over magazines and
toothpaste. Well, what does it mean?
What does the article say?
They're convicted of
violating the espionage act
and prison for providing classified docket
stop guilty on four charges to inmate
tweeted. I'm receiving 21 days of
restrictions and on recreation,
no gym library or outdoors.
Manning tweeted those four
charges included medical issue,
prohibited property,
disorderly conduct and disrespect.
Can't break the rules in medicine.
Charge came after officials discovered
expired tube of toothpaste in cell.
That's the medicine charge.
Wow.
So they're just fucking
weather contraband.
Karma came in the form
of books and magazines.
There's just a copy of Vanity
Fair magazine featuring
Caitlyn Jenner lol and a
copy of Cosmopolitan magazine featuring
an interview with manning. Oh Wow.
She's not allowed to have
an interview with herself,
but according to Chelsea manning.org she
received the reading material legally
through the prison's open mail system.
Yeah, they're fucking weather, dude.
They're fucking weather. They
can. They're fucking criminals.
Just lock that person
up and take away all,
all the rights, all, all
that's any privacy, the,
any ownership they have over their own
body or even what they want to read.
Imagine that Vanity Fair's fucking
contract band. You can get,
you've locked up in
solitary for a vanity fair,
fuck sick. It's sick. And you know,
look at that whole thing, the way
it went down. That poor guy, um,
uh, Julian Assange, he still
locked up in that fucking, he's,
he's still in that house, in the, uh,
what do, what do you call those things?
Embassy. He's still in the
Ecuador. Ecuador's embassy,
something like that. Uh,
in London, like you can't leave if
he steps foot out of that building,
he's fucked. So the dude's not getting
any vitamin D, he's not going outside.
Super unhealthy.
It really is unhealthy.
Like you really need to be outside
poor fucker. You can't lose,
you can't walk out the door. Yup.
Exactly. But you know what they're saying?
They're saying it.
They,
what they're saying is that it's a sex
case that he had sex with a woman and
then in the middle of the night, uh,
he stuck it in again without a condom.
It's called surprise sax. Like they
were cuddled together naked and, uh,
he didn't put a condom a second time.
And I don't even know if the woman
is pressing charges. I mean I don't,
I don't know what's going on.
But they were trying to extradite
him for that like, right. Yeah.
That's what you're doing. Yeah. Right.
Like that's why this guy locked
up in an embassy to manage.
If every time a guy tried to cuddle
with a chick and sneak it in without a
rubber,
that guy will get locked up in an embassy
and behold up there there'd be the
secretary of state. That'd be
it. Every embassy in the world.
You one of those surprise
sex, enthusiastic. I love
slipping it in it for $30
that's a,
it's not in tactically rape because I
guess she was asleep and they had already
had sex and they were,
you know,
cuddled together and this little
spooning type position, you know,
Dick to Vijay Jay right from behind.
I don't know.
I'm just making it up cause I
don't really know what happened.
Nobody knows what happened. He says
it's all bullshit. And, but the,
the idea that they got this guy locked
up for that and that's why they know it's
not, it's Wiki leaks. It's the
fucking information they released.
That's what they're trying to try to get
them on a loophole. And we all know it.
It's going on right in front of our eyes.
It's fucking crazy.
It's just right in front of our eyes
that Ashley Madison finally got leaked,
uh, yesterday. So whoever did that,
I'm sure he's going to be the next one
of these guys if they find out who it is.
But that could just be a hacker though.
And I could just be like the,
the fat burning people,
they just tap into kind of fucking mask,
cock blocking that job.
Ashley madison.com. So are getting
laid there. Like fucking thumb,
not getting laid. Nobody's getting
laid. I should tick it's out.
I saw it too. And it was scary as it.
Not only does it have all the names,
it has like all the information. So they,
they leaked the credit card information.
They leaked everything.
So did they lead who they had sex
with or who they think that, yeah,
cause you make an appointment with
the other person. So like there's all,
everything in there,
an appointment,
you're pretty much buying an escort,
but it's not an escort.
And so you're using your service.
Did you hear about that Uber for escort
APP that they have in Germany and they
were like a Uber for escorts.
It's like, it's, you know,
it's like, like using Uber,
except you have the escorts. You just
fucking look at your phone. You say, Hey,
I want to get my dick sucked when you
put the thing up there and then really?
Yeah. And then Uber, Debbie's on
her way over, you know, Bluer.
That was hilarious.
When you call it the lesbian and the
crowd for being looking like exactly like
Justin Bieber.
It was perfect in the women's jail. Yeah.
The women's jail was an interesting one,
man, because they fucking laughed
hard day, laughed harder, needed it.
They did and they needed it in a
whole nother way. Then the guys,
what did it feel like?
What is the difference tune?
What does a woman's GL feel like
as opposed to a male men's jail?
Cause you don't feel it's like physically
threatened, right? It's a little bit,
a little bit right. I'm sure.
I mean it was fine, you know,
but I wasn't thinking about my own safety.
I was more thinking about how to make
this the most like at night my instincts
were to make it like a nightclub. Treat
the women as women, not as inmates.
Right.
And make
it the same way. I would add an
comedy club and that's what I did.
And they were shrieking with the light
cause no one had spoke to them as women.
They're always as yelled
at in order to around and,
and that came through that they really
needed a laugh and to just be girls,
women ladies for an hour and
they wind up being so great.
It was a warm up for me for the next
night when I did two shows for the guys.
Oh see do the ladies first.
Yeah.
And you said you had a real hard time
trying to find prisons that would let you
do this.
Yeah.
I W we reached out to 150 or so
until finally we found one in Texas.
That one, one. Wow. And whose decisions?
The warden's decision.
There's a few people who have to agree.
Wayne Dickey as the jail administrator
at Brazos county jail and he stepped up
and had confidence in his institution,
in his facility and he wanted her,
he wanted everyone to see his staff and
how great they were and to see how, uh,
his inmate behavioral programs worked
where he incentivizes the inmates.
How does that work in good behavior and
they get rewards if you do your time
without messing up. There are huge rewards
on, one of them was coming to see me.
These guys had to behave for one
month in order to see my show.
And then I took that as a huge
compliment that so many people,
uh, did that not everybody,
but most of the jail,
more than half came to my shows and they,
they were appreciative
and I felt that too.
That's why the show came off because
not only were they good sports,
but they knew what they were signing
up for ahead of time because they had a
month to notice that I was coming there
to roast them and I s there were posters
around the jail and said, you
know, if you can laugh at yourself,
you're one step closer to freedom.
And they came and when
I asked for volunteers,
guys were running down from the balcony.
They're not allowed to
even be in the same room.
It was a communal experience for the
different sex and gangs and types of
people,
you know.
It was all dudes and squeezed into
this one room with the most dangerous,
closer to the stage by the door and the
least dangerous packed into the rafters.
Wow. So if there was a problem, they could
handle it. The jailers can handle it.
It was very calculated. And as far as
the safety of how it would go down,
did you get your front kick ready? I was
someone I was charging stayed in it, man.
I was,
I didn't want anybody near the stage.
I wanted it to be the
most like a comedy club,
I can make it for them.
So that was the only time that they were
ever jammed into a room like that. Yeah.
And you know that's a
real security concern.
That takes quite a bit
of planning to take five,
six pods of dudes and
put them in one room.
They can overpower the jailers,
they could over do whatever they want.
There's cameras in there. I'm in there.
So there was a huge trust factor. Wow.
That went on between the jailers
and the inmates, myself on my crew.
So what kind of security that they have
in place in case the shit hit the fan.
I did ask about my security if I had
any special person or a way out and they
said absolutely not,
which I couldn't believe at first.
I think I took them off guard.
They just didn't get to that.
But their assumption was beyond me
was there will not be any problems.
So I am no more special than anyone else
in that room be the way they set it up,
which I respected.
There was not going to be a problem.
Where did you come up with this idea and
what made you decide to film a special
this way? Um, who, well,
I wanted to make it
purposeful.
I wanted to learn something.
I wanted to initially think of
the funniest thing, which would be
okay.
Crime in America.
And I talked to a lot of people.
I'm friends with Tony Hinchcliffe,
Mike Ferrucci,
George Ryan Blatt, my cousin, Ed Larson.
We just brainstormed and tried
to think of the funniest,
craziest Shit we could do.
And somehow roasting criminals.
Yeah.
Seem like a hilarious way for me
to do what I do face to face you,
you know,
roasting concepts as one thing or
roasting people from behind a desk has all
been done and,
but go into it like getting into
something, immersing in an environment.
That's my specialty. I love that. To
me it's like a corporate gig. You know,
you're writing a special
act for a certain night,
then you're never going to
do it again. Right, right.
And I love that it's a roast.
So that's what you like about roads.
You like preparing for roasts?
Like I've seen you at
the S. Dot. The clubs,
the Improv and the store
getting ready pages and notes.
Like you liked the whole event.
Like there's an event coming up.
I liked the writing. Yeah. The
event is the is the payoff,
but you have to enjoy the process.
Say I like writing the jokes.
So you just like a subject to focus on.
Yeah,
I liked that.
I something that I love
that I'm interested in or
curious about are a fan of,
you know, it's gotta be something meaty,
you know? I mean I can riff if I don't it,
but if I'm invested in it somehow,
like with the jail,
I thought like,
how did I like smoke so much pot and had
so much fun in my life and never get in
real trouble. I sold weed in high school.
Like this could have been me. Yeah.
You know,
this could have been me.
So I got curious and as I get personally
curious and invested in something,
I can start to see, find the
hypocrisy that go into it. Hello.
How
the humanity can be lifted out of it.
And I started to see that this is a sad
place and it's kind of like doing a Uso
tour. And I told that to the
jailers when I met with them.
I had to go down there and ask permission
a couple times and they had to trust
me. You know that I wasn't
there to humiliate anybody
or expose anything that was
not just, I don't know, I
wasn't, I didn't have an agenda.
What it's going to make it real.
I was really just going
to go there and see what,
see if people had a sense of humor.
It was simple. And as I got into it,
I realize how lucky I am that
I never got in real trouble,
that I never got busted for anything.
And then if I had,
I'm not sure I would've survived. Well,
especially if you were selling pot, right?
If you were selling pot, you could
have got caught and you also go to,
got talked into selling more pot.
We've ever heard of those stories,
like DEA agents go undercover and
they'll talk a kid into a glisten.
I'm going to put a deal together.
You know, if you're a part of this,
there was a story that they did in
rolling stone about a DEA undercover agent
who talked this kid into a big cocaine
deal that wasn't real. It wasn't real.
There was no real cocaine,
but he talked this kid into selling it
and this kid is in jail for life now.
Kid was just a low level dealer. He was
selling, you know, a little bit here,
a little bit there and nothing big.
And this DEA guy essentially talked to
him into doing some gigantic deal that
put them in jail for 25 to life. And
that can happen to anybody. You can.
I look,
I've made some big fuck ups in my life.
I've been an idiot many times in my
life. I've, I've, you know, there's no,
I don't know, a single person who hasn't
made mistakes. We all make mistakes. It's,
but it's whatever the environment is
that you're growing up in dictate how bad
your situation is, whatever, you
know, whatever you were exposed to.
And that might be a factor
in the level of your mistake.
So the dumb mistakes that I made
with a pretty uneventful childhood.
Nothing too serious. Good parents,
nice folks. My mom's a sweet person,
you know, love my sister. It's like
pretty easy life growing up in Newton,
Massachusetts. Not Hard, not hard at all.
I imagine just a much more chaotic
situation with the same person living in
Inglewood, you know, whatever. Watts,
Detroit in some fucking hopeless
place where you can't get out.
And then next thing you know,
you're in fucking jail.
You're in jail and you're going
to be in jail for five, six years.
And during that time you go from being
21 to 26 and now you getting out and
you're fucking, you're a man and you're
a convict. You can't get a fucking job.
And you're just trying to figure out
how scratch and survive. It's fucked.
It's fucked.
You know,
it's fucked that there's so many people
out there that just don't get a chance
or whatever chance to get, you know,
and it's, a lot of people go off,
you just follow the law, but to get
the fuck outta here, that's nonsense.
Especially when it comes to selling
drugs just doesn't make sense.
It doesn't make any sense
of these kids just doesn't.
And then I saw guys 18 1920 years old,
been already been in one, two, three times
and imagine what their parents are like
imagining what their neighborhood was
like.
Imagine what their uncle was like,
whatever the fuck they encountered from
the time they were a baby until the time
they're a prisoner.
And then the fucked up thing is you just
become kind of a human battery because
all you do is you generate
money for private prisons.
Every one person that goes into those
private prisons is worth a certain amount
of money for those companies and
they sell that. That's what their,
that's their business.
Their business is making money,
extracting money at a prisoners and
there's a whole system that's involved in
doing it all the way from the guards,
the guard unions make sure that they
keep certain drugs illegal and make sure
that certain laws stay on the books and
certain penalties are still in place.
It's fucked, man. It's fucked. You know,
I had this guy on the other day we were
talking about and he was saying that one
of the only things that keeps it from
getting even worse is that the private
prisons and the the guard
unions don't get along like the,
the guards want certain things at the
prisons don't because the prisons don't
want to pay the guards. So there's the
fucking, there's a little internal struck,
but if they work together it
would be even worse. Terrible.
You could have been a prisoner. You
could have totally fucked up. Huh?
I was in prison or jail at I. That's
where I learned what hooch was. Well,
you went to jail for something you
didn't even do. You got, you got,
you are at all the dudes I've ever met
and of all the guys that I've ever met
who have run across crazy women that
get really fucking angry at you when you
break up every fucking girl you've ever
dated since I've been friends with you,
they get furious at you when it's over.
Where they want to kill you. Yeah,
I've seen it in person. I just not,
it's not just granted you
inspire that in some men as well.
I just date those crazy bitches.
I don't know what I really,
uh,
I think I mentioned whatever
attract my attraction.
My smell that I like on women is ones
that are more entertaining than boring,
I guess. Well, you liked those
dirty girls to a lot of times,
dirty girls that are involved in
naked things. No, those girls wilder,
they're more fun. You know, I was
thinking like, I want to meet a girl that,
that every time she goes to Vegas to
hang out with her friends like that,
she sends me a photo of that.
I'm not looking at the wallpaper and
then comparing it to like Dan Blitzer in
Instagram photos, you know,
like I'm like, wait a second,
it looks like the same cup on his
nightstand damn bills area, whatever.
I just found out about that guy.
Like I,
I'm like the last person I just went
to his Instagram and she's like, wait,
this is what everyone's
been talking about.
That's amazing that he's made
millions of dollars playing poker.
Apparently more than a hundred
million dollars playing poker,
but he got all his money from his dad
to his dad was a some famous character,
so he's like been rich.
His life doesn't
give a fuck. Hey, it looks like
here's a lot of fun. What Jamie?
Where's those as well? I would lytros
we'd give you some of those night crump.
Nitros nitros no,
nitro coffee. Caveman
coffee. Those nitrogen native
brewed cold brewed coffees.
I'm addicted to those little things right
now. They're awesome. You ever have one?
Do you drink coffee? Sure. Get one for
Mr. Ross. Mr. Ross would like a night.
What? Cause be drinking?
Fuck fucking Jamie.
He drank all of them. I had three
of those. You fucking savage.
Give him the real one and get me a
uh, a bottle of water. No, no, no.
It's okay. That other stuff.
Same Shit. Just fucking around.
He does drag him everyday. Those savage,
you got to order something, Jamie,
if you're going to drink them every day.
You got to order.
I'm okay fucking animal.
Thank you sir.
Do we have any cold water's in there.
What did you think about the
whole fat Jewish thing? Yeah,
that's what we're talking about
actually. Before the show, um,
you were saying that you think that
the networks need to loosen up on the
Internet needs to tighten up.
What'd you mean by that?
Oh, I was just saying, I was
just talking off the cuff,
but thanks buddy.
You know,
we're talking about this guy who goes by
the fat Jewish on Instagram and I would
follow him in. I'd see funny stuff on
there. So I kind of knew about him.
I didn't know a lot about how
he collected his material.
I guess I didn't think about it.
Like most of the 5 million people
who follow him, they don't care.
They just want to laugh. They're not
thinking about anything, you know?
And then I started to see that he was
collecting whatever he thought was funny.
I'm not sure, I don't
know a lot about it, but
he makes me robbing people's names out.
He wasn't just collecting things.
He was actively trying to make sure that
he didn't show who created it and he
just put it on his page. So he didn't
give credit to the people that made it.
That's what the big problem was. Everybody
read tweets, things you retweet things.
I read someone,
one of our friends said something funny.
It helps them when you retweet it and
it shows first of all entertains that
people that get to read it on your
Twitter feed and it gives that person to
credit. It's a great thing. There's
nothing wrong with re tweeting.
I think if he did that,
he would have the same amount of people.
If he really was a true aggregator,
like huffpost,
they credit everybody that they use.
Yeah.
So what I'm saying is this
is an aggregate, the Internet
my entire career, like
I've never made money off all the millions
of clips that are out there. Right.
You know, millions of views and
people are always shooting comedians.
Comedians get annoyed, you
know our material. You know,
you see a lot of comedians
when it's shut down,
phones at their shows because they don't
want their half written jokes on the
internet or they don't want their fans
to see their material without having to
pay for it either.
Live at a show or buying
their specials online.
So I go, it seems MTV seems
restricted all the time.
So maybe what do mean by TV's restricts it
all the time?
Well, you know, you have in the
networks are trying to be edgier,
but there's still bleeps and they're
still censorship and there's all sorts of
regulations. But with the Internet,
everyone always explained it was a wild,
wild west, you know, and you
can just do whatever you want,
like all the time you'll see people will
make videos and comprehends and they'll
edit famous movies and you just use
whatever footage and no one ever cares.
Then now people are starting
to care a little bit.
They're looking for ways the last five,
10 years to monetize the Internet.
And to me it's coming very close
to being how we watch everything.
I hardly ever watch TV
anymore and when I do,
it's a big live event. In the end
they're just all starting to become does.
No more of the Internet.
There's no more TV,
it's just programming and it's different
brands and you go to those brands.
So I go at some point,
the regulations for the Internet and
television should be the same and they
should be, they should get
together and it should just be,
do you mean it's once a set
of standards for now on,
but what do you mean by standards?
Do you mean as far as
for, as far as, um,
the music rights and how it all goes
down and the stuff we have to, you know,
the residuals and those sorts of things
and how the unions operate on the
Internet as the actors and directors
and writers unions, you know,
the fees and the rules
for the internet or,
or different payment minimums
are different from the
Internet and television.
Right now I'm in the
writer's guild and I dunno,
I mean it's all the
same now at this point.
And I feel like the Internet needs to
step it up and they should be crediting
stuff and
paying for rights.
And
to some extent I think it's happening.
And I think that's good.
I think you're right. I think the, for
a long time it was innocent. You know,
like someone would post a funny meme
right on their Instagram and no one cared
because it was just, just
people being funny like, God,
this is, this guy's funny.
But then when people started making
a lot of money off of it and then you
realize, well what made that guy
famous? Well he's just an aggregator.
All he's doing is collecting all the shit
that's online and instead of the row,
the actual writers of each one of those
individual bits getting some credit,
all the is going to him.
So now what he's doing with this guy who
calls himself the fat Jewish is doing
is he just puts the guy's name at the
end or the girl's name at the end.
So he steals her picture, puts it up
on his site. And instead of saying,
this picture was made by Jeff Ross,
the real Jeff Ross,
it now just has an un [inaudible],
just a tag, you know at.
And then whoever's name it is with no
mention of where you know that this person
created this originally, it just,
they just throw their name up there,
which is stupid.
Like,
all you have to do is this hilarious
meme was created by boom and then that
person gets credit.
That person probably happy,
they'll get a shit load of fucking,
people will come to visit them and sign
up and follows. He's not doing that.
And I did notice he sorta does it at
the end of whatever the new comment is.
So it almost looks like the person
who wants to give credit to,
he's actually giving credit for the
comment. Not In some ways. In some ways,
yeah. It's just not, it's not an
open, you know, it's just like, it's,
it's reluctant.
It's a reluctant credit at the end.
What else is he funny? I haven't seen, I
don't know. I mean, he's a good marketer,
obviously. He's really smart at putting
it all together. He's eating, he's not,
by the way, he's not even giving
proper credit on a lot of them.
I've noticed like he's, uh,
he's, he's saying that accounts,
like he's saying that
that person made this,
but then you go to their account and
they don't have that on their Instagram.
There's a few instances
where he's crediting these
people that didn't make it,
aren't even active.
Like one of the people ha even used
their Instagram for like 12 months and it
was just like if you went
go through all his photos,
it has nothing to do with what he like,
why he credited.
So it's weird why thing he's doing that.
Um, what the Internet is saying. Uh,
allegedly I gotta protect myself.
I talked to my lawyer yesterday about
all these. Really? Yeah. Why? Uh,
just cause I don't want to get s get in
trouble or anything like that. You know,
we need to have somebody that's Jewish
and the first thing you think of that
you're going to get sued.
If you could talk about how's that?
She'll tell you, sit next to
this guy. Kidding. But Damn,
man, I German, you know.
No, no Irish. Brian was Shelly. No,
you wrote on your page this fat German I
know is going after this fat Jew. Yeah.
Uh,
but now what was I talking about?
You tell me. What was I
talking about? Who Cares? Yeah.
You were talking about him not giving
credit to Internet is saying is that he's,
uh, that he has a lot of these interns
supposedly that are half the accounts, uh,
that he, uh, credits.
So he has his intern take it from somebody
else and put it on, on his account,
and then he credits his intern
so that it's still in the family.
Like he's not gay. You
know what I mean? Yeah.
It's kind of like a loophole that's a big,
allegedly you don't have any,
well this is just what the
Internet, Internet, which forum?
There's Reddit, Reddit, Reddit,
a forum. I, there's, yeah,
I think both of them are on reddit and
there's another website that's doing it
also, but if you just Google him, uh,
there's a lot of message boards that have
been talking about him for years, uh,
and breaking down everything. He's
stolen and, and, and, and it's, um, it's,
it's very interesting.
Did he call himself a curator or
something on this Instagram pages?
Me Sort of saying this is what I do. Is
that what he's saying? I Dunno. I Dunno.
Um, we should say though, because
somebody posted this yesterday that, um,
you know, we were talking about that
girl, she's really funny. Um, that, uh,
we were saying, what was her name
again? Pistol. Sherman. Yeah.
Um, people so that she has, uh,
uh, misappropriated people's stuff
as well. I don't know how that works.
So yeah,
I don't know if it's true or not.
I think she is a,
I think she's kind of admitting that she
has definitely put some stuff up that
somebody sent her that
she thought was funny,
but I think she said 80% of this stuff
is hers. But you know what I mean?
A lot of people,
they're just finding memes that are
funny and they put them on their page.
It's kind of innocent in some ways.
Right. That's what I mean, the Internet,
I don't know.
It's for amateurs or something.
Still we've got to figure out how
to make it, but how do you, I mean,
jet Brian Rather did a great
job of actually finding the,
the original image and finding the time.
The original image was posted in the
day and that's how he credited people.
And that's how he actually discredited
a couple of people that originally were
trying to claim that they
came up with it first.
But it was proven that somebody else had
it posted the exact same image to the
exact same tax before them.
Yeah, it's kind of sucks cause
if we want reg regulations,
if we want to make change how it is now,
what it's going to happen is it's like
when you have a youtube video and it
detects that there's
copyright and material in it.
So now anytime we want to post
like a photo on our Facebook or,
or tweet something,
we're going to have like a block
and we kind of don't want that.
You can't fuck with the Internet, man.
They find you. They find you. When you,
when you tried to sell them a
plate of bullshit, people find you.
They just figure it out.
You can't get away with it.
You just can't do you see the aspree
thing [inaudible] look at this.
Dave Asprey put up a photo
of his stomach of a fake,
a fake photo of stock photo of
someone else's abs shredded and said,
you know,
this is my stomach after a 4,500 calories
a day and no working out and it's just
a stock photo.
It's a stock photo and he's trying to
say that his bulletproof diet gives you
that. In his defense, if
you click on the link,
there's an actual photo of
his actual abs that Jamie,
thanks a photo shopped allegedly Jamie,
thanks for allegedly Photoshop.
You don't even need to say it. Let's not
even pull it up, but it's the same thing.
It's the same thing. You can't
fuck with these people if you're,
if you're blatantly bullshitting
and stealing, they cannot find you.
That's the, that's really funny
though. Like, like I said, he did that,
like I put working out and just post
like that guy has muscles everywhere.
If you,
if there was really a way that you can
get a body like that guy's without ever
working out, you would have to be
some sort of a genetic manipulation.
You have to be some experiment.
That's, that's not just apps.
That guy has chest muscle,
shoulder muscles.
It's a guy that trains
probably on our daily basis.
The fact that he would put that picture
up. It's just so crazy. It's funny.
He's so crazy.
Just so it's so fucking nuts.
People were out of their goddamn minds.
They really are. And the Internet, it's,
you know, it's kind of fucking expose.
That shit just takes a matter of time.
You got to go see shows.
Live
standup you mean? Yeah, the less
jokes on the internet than I used to.
I put less jokes on Twitter than I used
to because I want my best material for
when you come see me live and that's
much more unique and exciting experience.
People get mad sometimes if you
talk about something on the podcast,
even if you bring up the subject and
then have a bit about it on stage. Oh,
you were talking about doing on the pond
curves like do you not want us to talk
about funny shit on the pod passed?
Can you,
can you allow us to come up with ideas
spontaneously on the podcast and then
talk about them on stage as well? You
fucked. Yeah, I've done that before.
That's just, you know, they
want to know that. Well,
they just want to fucking let you know
that they're listening to the Rudy.
Don't you think though that it's good
though, that they keep you on your toes?
I think even with the hyper criticism
like each, you don't want to dive into it.
Like you don't want to just do a
Google search on your name final.
All the people talking shit about you.
It's not good.
But knowing that they're there probably
gives you an edge. It gives you,
keeps you sharp. I can see that.
I think so. Keeps you sharp.
I try not to read the bad comments.
I try to stay away from the haters and
stay positive. Well, you try hard though.
When you work hard at what you do,
it's not like you're slacking off and
someone's coming along and calling you on
it. If they're saying something
mean shit, they just don't like you.
They might not like your style.
There's going to be people that like
you know him or like anybody, you know,
they like a certain style and they don't
like your style or they do like your
style. You don't like somebody else's
style. They're not right or wrong.
They just have their own taste. No,
they're wrong. Everyone likes my style.
Would you read it though? Some of them
are so fucking mean. And why is that?
Just because they want you to notice them.
They want to make it a lot of people
sometimes. Yeah, they're outlet.
Just rude and mean. It's mine. Why would
it, what am I argue with them? I don't.
I ignore them. I don't
want him to block him. No,
because then they know you saw it. Well
cares. Why do you care if they know?
I don't want them to put that. Just want
them to float in the sea and not do.
But you did see it.
Yes.
So why acknowledged some piece of
shit then he can just keep doing it.
You're going to get Twitter bomb now.
They gonna bomb you real Jeffrey Ross,
bring it on.
I'm ready.
What are you going to tell
me? I don't know. Already.
Fucking know, you know, fucker.
What are you going to tell me? Real
Jeffrey Ross Christ are so aggressive.
Come on, bring it on. You think? I don't
know. I look like Bruce Willis drowned.
Bring it on mother fuckers.
I'm ready for some.
Bruce was wishy looked like you
write down on my Twitter right now.
Bruce Willis looks like shit. He
wishes to execute now. Poor bastard.
I just spent a week at the beach. This is
his tan as I'm ever gonna to look good.
I feel very healthy. You look vibrant.
Thank you. We're gonna say I've, uh,
I've toned it down more
on Twitter than I used to.
Like making fun of people or like
attacking people. You know, on Twitter,
I used to be, I think, you know, back
in the early days of your
message board and stuff,
we used to have like kind of fun,
like having online battles with people.
You know, Moore's Florence flame
wars, that's what we used to call it.
We so called flame wars. Yeah,
those were fun. They were fun.
But too many people jump in.
Now there's the other thing is it's not
just two people going back and forth.
It's a bunch of people that would decide
that they're on the other guy side or
this guy side and jump in.
Like you get a lot of that now.
There's a lot of what you see online
when there's any sort of a debate about
something as pylons,
you know,
there's a bunch of people pile on
one side or the other. You know,
I tweeted something the
other day and this guy's a,
he's up for,
he might go to jail in Canada because
he's been tweeting at this girl and
apparently there was like some agreement
that he wouldn't tweet at her anymore,
but he used to,
he used to be on her side.
I think he actually even
did some artwork with her,
but she's like this radical feminist and
you know, and she took them to court.
Like she, she called the police on him.
This guy was harassing her like she,
it was even sometimes she would write
something about him and the fact that he
responded to her about him,
she was saying he was harassing her,
which is kind of hilarious.
But all I did was there was
an article and a video and uh,
I retweeted it cause I was
like, oh, this is interesting.
The exact title of the video is what came
up on my tweet in the exact same order
because I just went to the youtube thing
where it says share. And I tweeted it.
I didn't put any commentary, I didn't
have any editorial control over it.
And so many fucking people were angry at
me saying that I'm a misogynist and why
would I post this?
And like it's a woman in the video,
an older woman in the video
is talking about this case.
So it's a woman's video about a woman
who's suing a man and the man might go to
jail because the man was tweeting at a
woman who didn't want him to tweet at her.
This is like, this is crazy. But I looked
at the comments, I was like, Jesus Christ.
Like the fucking mean.
People piling on an angry
at me that I tweeted this.
I guess you could kind of think that maybe
this is my opinion instead of me just
sharing something, but I share shit.
I don't believe in at all. I share it.
I'll share some flat earth shit or some
big foot shit or any I share nonsense.
I'll, I'll retweet people that think
the earth is less than 10,000 years old.
I do that all the time. This is one dummy
that I fall. I retweet them while I'm,
I don't retweet them anymore because I
don't want them to know that I follow.
I do. I do read his shit.
It's just so ridiculous.
Some of his stuff is soak. It's all
anti. Oh, it's either he hates Obama.
I wish I remembered his name.
Joe Summon up something starts with C,
but he's like one of the dumbest religious
guys online and everything is like
either anti-Obama or anti
evolution or anti, uh,
the earth is, you know, four
point whatever they think it is.
4.6 billion years old.
He's convinced it's less than 10,000
years old and he's a real guy. It's not,
it's not, it's not a parody
account. There's this MTV celebrity,
I don't want to say who she is,
but she's always
on TMZ and it's always her being like,
like,
don't you know who I am and
getting arrested and like,
like she's just like this like,
like privileged white girl
celebrity from MTV. And I,
I tweeted her something cause he was a
recently she hit a cop or something like
that and she's just that they're drunk
and they're just recording her outside of
a club handcuffed.
And I tweeted or something and it got a
lot of retweets and last night I was at
the thing and she was there
staring me down. I'm like,
this is it. I can't do this.
She's going to attack me right now.
And I was,
that's one of those things that are like,
I wish I never tweeted that.
Cause now she knows like as an enemy.
Yeah, she's an enemy for no reason.
Like it was just me. Like, dude,
I should have said that. You know,
to myself instead.
Right. Tweeting it. Yeah.
You that you could definitely
create little enemies, you know,
by tweeting something that you think
is going to be funny again to get a big
rise. Right. And then, you
know, you realize, especially
if you get high, right,
you get really high and you go, why
am I doing this? I'm creating enemies.
What am I doing? Joe's, wait,
I was put it in my notebook and wait
till the morning. That's a good move.
But sometimes you gotta be on the ball.
You've got to be the first one to attack.
Yeah. Those days are over. Who
Cares? I took two hits today.
I went to yoga and it was breaking
down my whole life in that yoga class.
Oh my God. The things chat about
things I don't get upset about.
Just I need to be nicer.
Just calm the fuck down too.
Worked up. I get to, I think I'm
doing too many things in my life.
I really think that
that's what I'm thinking.
I'm thinking I'm under too much pressure
and stress and even though I'm cool
about most things,
like there's certain times where I
have a perfect reaction to something.
Like I always bring up this
time, whether the guy hit me, uh,
on the highway and my,
uh,
my car fucking texting rear
ended me smashed into me.
But I had gone to yoga that day just
from uncle, a little rainfall felt great.
I was loved, I loved the world.
I got out, I was fine. I did,
I wasn't hurt and I wasn't even mad at
the guy went over to him, I go, you okay?
And he's like, I'm sorry.
You know, I fucked up. I go,
it's okay. We all fuck up.
And then I go, do you have a license?
Cause I don't have a license.
He didn't have a license, he
was illegal. He's from May call.
And I thought about it, I said, all
right, I'm outta here. And I just bailed.
And I said,
I'm not,
I don't want to call the
cops cause I don't want them
to go to jail because look,
his car's fucked. His car was
fucked. Anyway, his car was totaled.
He had a civic and he, uh, he, you
know how sometimes you hit the brakes,
your car goes down,
like you go under the car.
So his car went kind of under my car,
lifted my car up and sent my car flying.
So my car,
what did not have that much damage?
It was only a beam that needed to
be replaced in the back bumper area,
but which was all plastic.
So they just put a new piece of plastic
and they replaced the beam and it was
good to go. I had it back in
a couple of weeks, but, uh,
I've thought about this total
and you would've ruined his life.
And he told the cop, no, I would have
had to, they would have had a tow me,
so they would have known. But I thought
about, and I was like, this guy,
you know this guys, he's got a shit. Roll
the dice. He got to shit, roll the dice.
He made a mistake. I'm not hurt like
I'm okay and I can pay for this.
I can figure it out. Like, I'm going
to just get the fuck out of here.
I just said I'm just gonna go.
All right man. Nice to meet Ya.
Took a picture of his fake license.
Yeah,
just in case some weird shit happened
and he said I did something and you know,
you never know and just get out of there.
Apparently he has insurance. I might be,
I might actually get paid for this,
but the point being that
the way I reacted to it,
I wish I could react to
it like that all the time,
but I don't know if I would like,
if I'm stressed out,
I got a bunch of shit going
on and there's blood fucking,
you hit this boiling point where you
come in on a four or five instead of at a
zero. He coming in hot already, you know?
And I was thinking about that while
I'm a in Yoga class. I was like,
there's times where I'm,
my reaction to the thing is not entirely
warranted by the situation itself,
but it's more dealing with
all the different shit that
I've got going on in my
life. It's too many. I have too
many things. This is what I think.
Okay,
this might be crazy,
but I think this is part of the problems
with police brutality and some of the
mistakes of cops have
made is they come in hot,
their job is tough and other stuff's going
on and then you'd come from one thing
to another and they warrant different
roles and disciplines and,
and danger levels.
But they coming in not knowing or,
you know,
fired up their blood pressure.
I've talked to cops,
especially in New York and Chicago where
they're on blood pressure medication
and their families are stressed
out and um, their, their,
their job is more intense
than it ever has been.
Oh, it's an incredibly intense job.
I couldn't even imagine it. I mean,
do you know cops?
Do you have any friends that are cops?
I'm getting to know more and more cops.
I've known cops all my life.
My karate teacher was a cop,
so is mine. My original cried teacher
was Joe Esposito, Newton, Massachusetts,
Kelly, Newark, New Jersey.
A lot of cops learn karate.
Italian cops. Exactly right.
Isn't that a, it's just,
it's,
I just think that the job of doing a cop
doing police work is probably not only
is it not for everybody,
probably too easy to get,
it's probably too easy to be a cop.
Like some people,
they don't have the
right mentality for it.
I want a roast cups from my next comedy.
That was a great idea.
That's a great idea.
It's not easy. Oh really?
I think la would let you, yeah.
Burbank, Burbank. [inaudible]
tell the story, but maybe,
I don't know. I might do it,
but I might do a bunch of
precincts. Yeah. Coming in hot,
so I figured that out in Yoga class.
I just figured out I need to do yoga more.
I'm going to do something every day
before I go out and face the world every
day.
Blow offs and stress.
I spent some time and at the beach lately
and that can also help, but that's,
yeah.
Why do you think people at the water
or so mellow Paul Beach Communities and
mellow? It's just so relaxing,
man. It, it's also humbling.
Did a week at the Jersey shore and
a few days a Malibu and it just,
we had some shit fixed
and our kitchen and uh,
so I rented a house for a while in Malibu.
I would never, I would never buy it.
I don't think I'd buy a
house like on the water.
I think it's fucking crazy that waves come
in. You never know when again, come in.
Yes, we went out. I went out at
night by myself down to the water.
It was scary, dark, scary.
I felt like you're having a trust
with the ocean at any minute.
It knows they could just swallow you up,
but instead just creeps up to
your feet and just says hi.
Well I was Pam at any second steamrolled
highways that had two floors and one
four was above the water looking down.
But the first floor was like the water
would go right under the fucking bedroom.
Like you would see the waves come in
and you would hear them crash underneath
you.
And it was dark.
And I'm looking out this window and I
was high as fuck and I was looking out
this window. It's like, oh my God, this
is crack. Can't sleep here. I was like,
this is nuts and I know that this fucking
building's been here for who knows,
10 years,
whatever.
I don't know that a lot of the house has
been there since the 50s his pictures
this like there's a one of
those restaurants down there
that has these old black
and white pictures on the wall, but
when you, when you're there at night,
it looks like a monster and the day it's
like this beautiful friend in the day.
You look out there like I'd have breakfast
and I'd sit down this little table,
look out the window and eat eggs.
I'm like, God, this is amazing.
Look how beautiful it is just to
be like next to this alien world,
this beautiful alien world,
and I'd see sea lions or seals or
whatever the fuck they are and birds.
Occasionally you'd see a fish splash
around, but like this is so beautiful,
but at nighttime, goddamn
terrifying, but it's humbling.
I think that's one of the reasons why
people that live in beach community is so
nice because you just look out and
just smacks you in the face with you.
Ain't shit is so like that.
I was thinking you get as holding a
glass of sparkling water like Perrier or
something out on the beach by myself
and I was half done with it and I just
tossed it down into the ocean.
You just think that's,
it's such a great equalizer is fancy
cup of Perrier thinks it's so fucking
important and high and mighty. You just
drop it into an ocean. It's nothing,
just nothing. It makes no impact. Nothing.
All beach communities are filled with
mellow people. Right? Pretty much.
Never heard of an aggressive
beach community, Long Beach. Nah,
that's like snoop Dogg's, naval
architects, builders, contractors
could spend 10 years building a skyscraper
and most beautiful people will never
stare at it. And the way they stare at
the ocean, which is in the air, floating,
splashing. Well, it just gives
you this feeling of like this.
It's a totally different world in
front of you. Alright, Jersey shore it.
No one's cool there, right? Like that's
not even paying attention. The water,
they're just doing steroids
and fucking fist pump.
What happened to that?
How come that show went away?
I don't know which ever bring it
up under the car. Hurricane Sandy.
That's what did it. Oh yeah,
that's right. Did it? No.
Yeah. That beech is fucked. No,
people just got tired.
They just got some back.
I was just down at the Jersey shore.
A lot of construction happening,
lot of activity, a lot of people out
having fun at the boardwalk, so it was,
it was great. I can't wait to go
back. I used to do gigs out there.
I used to do gigs for Bob Gonzo
stationed down there. I don't even do it.
I didn't get on stage once.
It was,
the beaches are beautiful
and the weather was perfect.
The water was just as warm as it is here.
Don't people have a bad opinion of
the Jersey shore though? Don't they?
Think of it as you go there. It's
just a bunch of Orange Guido's. Yeah.
Fucking shit out of each other.
It's not like that. Maybe. Maybe.
It's evolved or maybe that was just
a show showed it in a bad light,
but it was great. There's that showed
this old house, they just did it.
They did a long special about rebuilding
the Jersey shore and it's really
interesting. I didn't I, that's what
I thought also is just like this,
like myrtle beach spring break thing
the whole time. He didn't know.
It's very beautiful there.
While my uncle lives there,
my uncle lives on Jersey
shore. He just sent me a some
drift. What? He's an artist.
Some shit like the Hamptons
or any fancy beautiful beach.
It's back.
It's done sending them back.
It doesn't already have a place
down there. I was there last week.
I sent the picture you guys together and
he has a beautiful a house right on a
lake. I mean he has to
dream. He has a late,
you walk into Artie Lang's house and the
Jersey shore and if he didn't tell me
he lived there, I would think like Mary
Lou Henner live there is something,
it's immaculately decorated,
perfect nautical theme,
the white pillows everywhere. There's
no chance. And he's like, yeah,
my sister's a designer.
She did everything.
So does he stay there all the time or
sometimes I think he's there most of the
time and he has his whole man cave
with all this Thurman Munson themed
memorabilia and he's just the best.
And he's got a place in Manhattan too.
Is that how he does?
I think he lives a place in
Jersey. Hoboken, right near
Manhattan. Oh that's right.
Yeah. Already can't leave New
Jersey. That's hilarious. No,
literally has like a
bracelet on his ankle.
He got, he got visibly upset when I
told them that I don't follow sports.
Like you could see, he was like,
like I was less of a man in his eyes.
Really? Yeah. Yeah, I could see it.
There's guys that are fucking
crazy sports fanatics. We tell him,
you don't give a shit about sports.
The only thing that saved
me is I'm actually a sports
commentator, so I'm Kinda,
I kinda, you know, I fall into the
Hippie, hipster, whatever category that
he would hate the most. But it was,
he was disappointed in me as
a man. Really? That's strange.
But I guess he does love sports,
man loves it. Well, yeah,
that's ports show that he was doing
for a while with Nick Depaulo.
I'm getting more into it. Sports, doing
a fantasy football app. Get the fuck out.
Draft an APP comes out in a few weeks.
Really producing an APP.
I'm like the voice spokesman of it.
Look at you funny videos.
That's a good idea. Play fantasy
football and talk shit. Or your friends.
Do you know football? Do you
understand it? Of course.
I played high school football. Yeah.
What's that guy's name with a giant arms.
Jamie know that Popeye. What's
his name? Ron Land. Do you know?
He is a picture. Do you know
who he is? I think Ron Landry.
You obviously don't know
like Jamie knows it.
Maybe you need a man like Jamie on
your team. Yeah. Oh yeah. He's not.
This fucker knows a lot. Look at this
guy's arms. He showed me this yesterday.
Get the fuck out of here.
What is that?
He said the dude's been busted a few
times for steroids. I said, no way.
He's obviously had no shirt on
over that thing. He just does it.
Shirt scared shirt just
goes over. Okay. Okay man.
Jesus Christ. Scroll, Scroll up. What does
that one with him holding the camera up?
He's got the phone up to the far right.
What the fuck is that?
Jesus Christ.
That is an enormous human being.
Didn't even make people like that a
hundred years ago, but he's a safety too.
So those guys are tended to be a little
smaller than like a linebacker alignment.
How much does that guy way about how tall
is he rather? Uh, I'll find the stats,
but yeah, find a stats if, but if he, it
depends on, I mean he could be like five,
seven and he'd still be 230 pounds. Wow.
Built like that. He's a fucking giant.
He's beautiful. You like
it? Six feet tall. Two 20.
It's just an ape filled with
fucking testosterone and fury.
God Damn,
that's an athlete.
That's about as strong an athlete as you
get human bins there. He like, you know,
great slave auction are back in the day.
Look at them that way. But we're all
apes. I'm an eight year an ape waves.
It's what humans are just saying.
The way you break down a person's physical
appearance. That's what I do. I'm an,
I'm a sports commentator.
If you remember full stick testosterone,
that guy's a fucking dat is a silver back.
That's a silver back gorilla.
Yams on that guy.
I mean you'd never had a human being
that was built like that a hundred years
ago.
This is an entirely new era of humanity.
Like you look at those Greek statues,
those were exaggerated and that was the
best they could imagine in their head.
Those guys are pussies. Every one
of those key Greek guys was good.
It looks like they barely work
out. You know like the, the,
the biggest stud Greek statue.
Like how's it compare to this guy?
Not even close. Yeah.
Show me a Greek statue.
Show me like the best Greek statue
with the most muscular of all the,
the Romans or the Greeks.
Shit. Some fucking animal.
I want to see what it looks like cause
I guarantee it didn't look nothing like
that dude. They just didn't even know the
people are capable smuggling these. Wow.
That's actually a pretty big,
that guy's pretty yoked.
He's pretty studly except
for his little cock.
I wonder if people really did have little
dicks back then or if they just made
them have little dick so that everybody
looking at the sculptures didn't feel
bad because like look at that guy's dead.
That's an enormous man
with a fat guy's Dick.
That is what like a mushroom
cap and the guy looks huge.
It looks like the hulk.
I take back everything I said.
I take back everything I said though.
Cause that guy's giant. Look at them.
Does that real? The guys back?
Is that real? Come on. Yeah,
they were really fit, man.
That's real from a computer.
That doesn't seem real to me.
For some reason that we're looking at
this guy's back that is insanely muscular
and it's a sculpture,
but his ass cheeks are a little too big
and he's holding something in his hands
or you get to play your Nick
Jonas Gilfoyle rent. Come on,
look at the muscles on that guy's back.
He looks like Vandelay Silva when
he was fighting in pride. Yeah.
See that guy. That guy's a pussy.
Okay. It looks like a big condos. Yeah.
It looks like you've never
done a squat in his life.
None of these guys who make
the NFL. No, no fucking way.
Not with the athletes they have today.
I think we all agree that the NFL athletes
are the most impressive athletes in
all sports. Right? Can we agree on that?
As far as like horsepower
about what they can do,
the speed coordination,
right. W we all agree and I,
you know,
obviously I work for the UFC.
I think UFC athletes are
incredibly impressive,
but as far as like what
they have to be able to do,
UFC athlete has to be able to fight.
If it's championship fight,
you have to be able to fight five rounds,
five minutes each round.
You just can't do that. If you're built
like an NFL player and you just can't,
you can't do it. It's not possible.
So that is a bodybuilder though.
That's totally different. That's
modern. That's a modern bodybuilder.
Like that guy, that guy could never
fight in the UFC match. She would never,
I mean, unless he won in the first
30 seconds, which is possible.
Does the only way he'd be able to do it,
he just wouldn't have the juice.
Does no way. You'd have the
capacity to fight for five frowns.
There's just no way.
Muscle or current statutes like new
statutes that are made today of naked men
are their cocks the same size. It's a very
good question. I'm so glad you're here.
Let's go look.
Let's look for giant Cox on naked.
Homosexual.
Least a lot of rumors times are changing.
We just a lot of rumors, but what do I
look for that new? That's black cock.
Cause Google. Yeah. This duplo
olive garden. Black Cock. Seven
eat anything around here.
Jerky. We got some Cherokee. No.
What you want. Oh wait,
we give you some food.
But if you talk into the microphone way,
he never one's going to be mad at you.
Oh,
I won't.
Jeff Ross trove through
traffic. Did you Uber. Uber.
Did you have a feel uncomfortable at all?
Why did you ever get a an
uncomfortable Uber driver? Oh, I,
it's only annoying when they're, you
know, they want to talk to you about,
you know, they want to come
into the show like, well, like,
yeah.
I only hate if you're on a date because
then you have some other dude's just
listening to your [inaudible]
bullshit. Oh yeah. You're
trying to get some thanks dude.
Those cashews are very yummy. All that
stuff's good. Those bars are great.
It's pro bars. Those are the best.
I won't make any noise, but if I do,
I'm so don't worry about it.
Don't mind having a good time.
Enjoying the vibe.
Um,
you were at the roast battle pretty much
every week when you're in town, right?
Yeah.
That was a Jim Carrey last night.
That was the first place that I
went back to when I came back to La,
came back to the comic store.
The roast battle was one of
the reasons why I did it.
It's a movement is a movement,
right? It feels like, it feels like,
like I was talking about this
on the message board today.
Someone was bringing up, uh,
I, it might've been trolling,
I might've got sucked into a troll.
It's actually about the old days.
Guys used to, uh, borrow each
other's jokes and you know,
it was like a tighter community
back then. It was like, man,
I don't know about all that,
but I think this is the tightest
community ever for standup.
I think this is the best
time ever for standup comedy.
I really do as far as
like, I love that. Yeah.
It's like you love what you just did.
Montreal all comedy
festival. I'm hosting odd ball starting
next week and I love comedians.
I do these festivals because I
love being around comics. Yeah.
It's like a religion.
I feel like it's a real,
I feel like I'm a comedian before
I'm anything else. Yeah. Yeah.
I agree with you. I just want to see
comedians hang out with comedians.
I remember going to a Christmas
party once at Al Roker his house,
if I should tell this, but go
ahead. And it's very fancy.
Upper East side Christmas party
for charity fundraiser thing.
And I walk in and there's like a,
you know,
people in Tuxedos taking your coat when
you come in and very handing out hors
d'oeuvres and big
beautiful home fireplace,
Christmas music. And I look over at the
people that coach people. It's like two,
three people just sitting
there and Chris Rock.
Like he would rather talk to the coat
check people. Then these fancy people.
He was so bored. And then, and then I
walk in, he's like, he ran over to me.
He's like, oh my God, a comic. I can
talk to a comic. This is so great.
It just comics need to talk to comics.
That's how I felt last night at this
party. It was just like Samsung. Yes.
I went to this cool Samsung Party
where asap rocky and performed it.
And that was really cool.
What does that asap rocky is a musician.
He's good. Yeah. Yeah.
Well I live a bad pitches.
That's my fucking problem.
Really. I love bad bitches.
That's my fucking problem. That's what's
the Jeffrey Ross team song. But uh,
it was, you know, Super Hollywood Douche,
like I hate those kind of people. Uh,
it was like in a studio lot where I
think right next to Oprah is building a,
so we don't know what studio.
That was some weird studio lot and it
was this humongous party was awesome. Uh,
Samsung was showing all
their new phones and uh,
I didn't want to talk to anyone because
everyone was like beautiful models and
just like, you know, I was just
sitting there like, this is gross.
Then I see Stephen Glickman, uh,
across the the room. I'm like,
I love you.
And I'm just like giving them
big hug.
It was like the best day of my life just
because I saw a comedian that I knew.
Yeah. I've been in that
situation before. It's cool.
Those situations are cool when you,
you know, you have that camaraderie,
you run into someone that you
know. Yeah. The old days baby,
I used to do a news radio right next
to what Greg Geraldo had a sitcom for
awhile and Geraldo Sitcom lawn.
Yeah. They'll be right next door.
And uh, I'd go out, hang with him.
We just hang out in the parking lot and
shoot the shit. But it was always like,
you're not even in an actor,
a comedian. Look how x, right.
We talk about it and he talked about
how frustrating it was. Cause you know,
trying to do is show his way, all the
producers and every, the, you know,
the network and all that jazz that you
have to deal with and trying to put
together a sitcom. It was like, you
know, I just run in Emory. Yeah.
There was a few guys like Lanny Clark,
Lenny Clarke was also on the
set on the a lot rather than,
cause he was on that show with John.
What the fuck?
I want to say Lithgow, but
it's not Lithgow. It's the
other guy. Larry cat. Yes.
Thank you. He was on that show
with John Leora cat to John,
I guess it was called the John Leora
cat show. And uh, I used to, uh,
run into Lenny, you know,
just run the Lenny. Hey, what
the fuck? How I yeah, yeah.
I'm doing this fucking show.
This cranky bastard was Lithgow.
What's fucking scream at everybody?
We'd watch the close circuit monitors.
Lithgow would get mad. Remember?
You're fucking crazy and shit,
but you know,
you're running into a comic,
whether it's at the airport or anything,
it's, it's a, it's a nice thing.
We're always on the move comics in
an airport on a Sunday or a Thursday.
Yeah,
that would be a good show.
Just comics running into
each other at an airport,
a podcast.
He just gets randomly connected with
another comic that just happens to be at
the same airport.
Well, if you did that, you know, like
for real, if you want to do a show,
say like Dallas is a big port,
there's always big ports and you set up
a podcast studio in that port and said,
you know,
we'll be here.
We're going to be here from 9:00 AM to
3:00 PM let us know if you're coming
through. And you know, maybe
you could schedule your layover,
you could create a studio in
one of those like lounges,
like the American airline
lounge and then you can help the
community. And he's like, yeah, hey
comedian. Stopped by, you know, the,
the comedy louder and celebrities and
wants you to do by Kate, by tournament,
by my gate. 67. A like, you know what, you
could do two. You could have one of those,
you know those massage places
where they rub your back.
You have those let you sit in those
chairs that your face goes first.
You could do that. Like we'd sit
next to each other and get a massage.
Talk some shit. How the microphone
looking up at us. How's uh, those uh,
Asian ladies a rubbing your back.
Just make it great idea.
It's not a bad idea to just have
people lead that are out on a Gig.
Right? Where are you going? Here's
the idea. It's okay. You do like,
you do like women have like a little
spa where they get their hands on it.
Just do for guys like guys spa.
Yeah, but you don't want to get,
you want to get your hands done.
No, you don't have to maybe do that,
but others toes done. Did you
get it? You listen to them.
You're going to ever play some ping pong.
That wouldn't be bad.
If there's a spot where you could go
and hang out like a bar, like a little,
you know the comedy store
has that private bar.
If you could set something like that.
I danced there last night that you dance.
It's so fun there. Yeah, got chew. Don't
worry about it. He's like hold him,
but he's doing very well done and then
I to gold this long without knowing
what's not about. When I get off
stage, I'll do an hour, hour,
15 minutes when I'm headlining
and I literally will have,
they'll still be clapping and I'll already
be halfway through a chicken salad on
pita bread. Really? And if you have a
second show you'll do that. You'll eat in,
which I always eat before the first show
we did between the second show was free.
I just need food all the time.
I can't eat before I go on stage.
If I do it slowly go on stage.
If I'm hungry, I lose my
mind. Really. I'm too mean.
I lose. I just wow. Jeff Ross, all those
little cranky I, it's not fun for me,
but I think it's still funny for the
audience cause I used to have an old
girlfriend.
He used to say the crankier I was the
funnier it was like if I got really mad he
would just be so fun. That's what she
likes. She likes getting dirty. Yeah.
That's all. Yeah. I,
I try, I try to eat before and
I just fall asleep. I like,
I mean I feel like I'm really tired stage.
You've got to digest that stuff.
Like you would never eat before he fought.
Even never like have a sandwich
and then go fight ever. So like,
because you wouldn't have all
your resources, your, your body,
there's a certain amount of your body that
would be breaking down your food. Huh?
I guess, but not quite the same
as telling jokes for an hour.
Not quite the same, but the energy
level won't be the same. Your,
your energy level, like you, you won't
have as much resources dedicated to like,
have you ever gone on stage dehydrated?
That's a problem. That's bad.
That's harder for me. I did just been
drinking too much coffee. I haven't slept,
haven't had enough water.
I was in planning land all day once
all day in the summer, like July.
It was bad.
It was fucking hot as shit and I was
there with my kids and we stay the night
there.
You know,
you get a hotel room at the Disneyland
Hotel and the whole deal and you know
you're,
you're fucking going through the park.
It's hot as shit as a million people.
You might not drink enough water.
And that night, man, I hit the wall.
I did two shows and the first show
I pulled it off at the second show.
My fucking head was throbbing
and I was thinking of stuff like,
I'm really dehydrated here.
This is not good.
It's probably one of the worst ways
to be on stage. It'd be dehydrated.
He brain just doesn't work right.
She doesn't fire.
I told him I had that in Iraq.
I got dehydrated and couldn't after a
bunch of shows and traveling and not drink
enough water and over caffeinating to make
up for not sleeping and being nervous.
That was what happened.
At sent me to the infirmary,
to the medical tent in the middle of,
I think it was Alice sod or Falucia
Jesus Christ with an ivy bag.
How many times you've been over
there? A couple. Yeah. You like it?
I'm not sure what you mean.
Well, you were saying that you,
it was pretty straight forward question.
I love going to Iraq.
It is so much specially around my
birthday and when I can really party.
You were saying that the great
clubs and Todd you were saying,
you were saying that doing the prison
was a lot like doing a u s o Gig in that
you're bringing laughs whether
normally aren't any and it's, you know,
politics and all that and whether
people deserve a show and all that.
You can just put down the side
for a second as a comedian
just going in and that
challenge of making people laugh that
are miserable. I love that. You know,
I feed off that and we're trying to
make my mom laugh when she was sick and
stuff. You know, just the,
I love that challenge of trying to break
somebody who's just a little frozen.
Mm.
You like a little little,
little run up hill.
Yeah. Jeff Ross. Yeah,
I remember being an early in my career
seeing him Buddy Hackett perform.
I didn't know him, but I knew his
son, Sandy and sandy let me come, uh,
by myself, the end of a run in Atlantic
city and buddy was there the next day,
so I stayed an extra day to see the Buddy
Hackett shell this like kind of a late
afternoon, early Sunday show. And I
remember buddy right out of the gate,
saw some lady taking notes.
She was a reporter and he didn't know
about it ahead of time or whatever.
He called her a cunt.
Right.
And literally the first 45 seconds of
walking on stage and just the whole
audience taken. Yeah, she was
mortified. She tried to say,
I'm from the so and so Harold did that.
He just wouldn't hear it.
And he just called her content.
He just put a really weird vibe in the
room right out of the gate. And, you know,
eventually the show went on and,
and it was amazing and I,
but literally a decade later,
but he became a very close pow and I
could ask him anything and I said that
you'd never remember this man.
But like 10 years ago in Atlantic city
at the Trump hat, castle, whatever,
some lady, you know, he's like, wow,
I go, I go, why would you do that?
Like right away, just for no reason.
Just what was,
how could you imagine what might've
been happening in your head buddy?
And he's like, he's like,
oh, I do that all the time.
I like to dig myself a hole
just to make it interesting
just to see if I could dig myself out of
the halt. It does make an interesting,
do you do that with new bits? I'll do
the new bits sometimes. How do you mean?
I keep myself like a pause and a new bit.
I'll give myself like a
fucking dead end where I've,
I have to come up with some way to get
out of it like a low myself. Anyway,
sometimes you, Tommy
Sigora says this best, uh,
the best, uh, description of
like when a bid is not that good,
but you kind of jazz it up and
make it good. You try too hard.
He calls a dance moves, you know,
like I'll have a bit, and I, I,
the way I used to say,
I said I used to call it English
like English and acumen along. Yeah,
it's spinning around too much. I might,
those balls are spinning around too much.
It's too much English on this fucking set.
It's just too much nonsense and jazz,
you know?
But Tommy had a better expression,
dance moves and that's what kind of what
it is sometimes like sometimes a bit,
it's not that good. Like it's,
it starts out kind of good.
You have an idea and you're trying
to figure out which way to take it.
But sometimes you jazz it up too much
with the performance but not enough with
substance and you just kind of
try to figure out what's the,
what's the line between those two things.
You know,
how to hold you up sometimes when
you know you got something and you're
developing it and you have a couple of
tent poles that maybe you won't need once
the whole thing's bills. It's
like a, it's like a scaffolding.
Yes.
That's how I describe it.
The same way I was having a conversation
with Tony Hinchcliffe about this,
cause it was a subject that,
it was a little kid,
he was doing a subject that
was kind of mean and I said,
you're dedicating a lot of time to this
bit that I know you don't really think
like this. Like you don't mean this.
Right. And he goes, no. I'm like,
well what if somebody has this disease
is in the audience and they hear this or
someone who knows somebody.
I go,
you're taking all this time and creativity
and you're putting it together with
something you don't necessarily
believe in. And I said,
you got to think of a bit as like
a subject is the scaffolding.
And then inside that scaffolding you
put all your material and that's what
you're doing. You know? And
when you create a new bit,
sometimes you do have those dance moves.
Sometimes you do have those and sometimes
I'll just chop them down and leave and
I'll start it out good.
And I'll just hope there's a pathway
that opens up in my brain when I'm in the
moment and contemplating the bit where
I know there's a lull there and I know I
got to dig myself out of the lull.
Maybe I'll find it and I don't find it.
Sometimes I don't find it.
You know,
sometimes like sometimes you'll do a
bit three, four times and you're like,
I'm ready to abandon this motherfucker.
And then boom,
something pops up and you're like,
oh, this is it. All this is it.
You go back to it. Yes. Or you go back
to it. Yeah, he take a little time off.
Put it aside.
You know what else I noticed?
I don't think this happens
as much anymore, but
you'll have a bit that you're
not. When I was beginning, this
is good for beginning comics. You
have a bit that's okay. And you know,
he kind of like it but
it doesn't quite work.
And I went back to old notebooks or
it just came back to me one night. Um,
and when you become a better performer
and you can sell them more different type
of bit, it's more in your new voice
or your can just sell it better.
Or you know the English better like you
say and you can go back to an idea that
you, you weren't ready for.
Yeah. Like maybe you didn't
see the the way out, right?
You didn't see the pathway fit with your
bullshit act that you were doing when
you were starting. Yes. I like,
how are you doing this right now
with a fucking mouthful of food?
Like a squirrel,
but you're completely professional.
You tuck it all the side Shit, monks
style and you didn't chew once on the mic.
Brian Cowen can learn from you.
I've been doing this awhile.
This is my first podcast. Joe
Rogan. Do you have a podcast? No.
How the fuck is that
possible? I, I don't know.
I could barely work a garage door opener.
This would be really hard for me.
Just get somebody like Jamie or Brian
to do it so I don't have a fucking
remodeled garage that I can put up.
Three pictures of Elvis.
Jimmy still trying to figure out
a Rosa Rosa parks. Really? Yeah.
Okay. She was hot. No, no.
Casey. No, you're just
crazy. Now we know your type.
Let the record show al Qaeda has the
same decorators is the Joe Rogan studio.
Really just in the Rosa
parks saying pictures of,
I found out that Hendricks is not the
real fucking Hendricks mugshot from
Toronto. Yeah, sons of bitches. Wow.
They sold this to me and Hawaii too.
That's a iconic Jimi Hendrix
photo that they stuck on.
The actual writing from when his
mugshot was, I bought the real mugshot.
Jamie, do we have it in the
back? Don't worry about it.
I got the real mugshot from Hendrix, so
that will be replaced with the real one.
Interesting. So they, my new studio,
I'll take it. You can tell you actually,
this is all very cool. Thank you. Um,
do you know a youtube star or have you
ever heard of a guy named Joey grass
stuff? Uh, grasp this guy right
here. Uh, this guy right here? No.
Uh, so he is like this really super
popular famous Youtube Star I guess.
And there was this guy named Brock Baker,
a really funny comedian and writer here
in Los Angeles and he makes these really
funny videos called angry man.
And he did this thing and he talks about
this youtube star because he has a book
out.
And if you read the back of the book,
what it says on the
back of the book cover,
it is one of the most
creepiest things ever.
The guys 24 and all his fans
are like young kids, like,
like eighth grade to like
13, 14, 15. You know,
kind of like the twilight or kids. That's
his fans. That's his fans. And He's 24,
uh, if you've read the back,
Jamie, do you have it pulled up?
Because it'd be funnier if
you check this out. Read this
right here. It's not what you begin that
matters. It's where you end up. Go ahead.
All right.
24 year old Joey,
whatever has captured the hearts of more
than 4 million teens and young adults
through his playful,
sweet and inspirational youtube presence.
Not to mention his sparkling
eyes and perfect hair.
This is like a book about him and he
has his on the back of his car anyways.
Uh, Joey wasn't always comfortable in
his skin and in this candid memoir,
he thoughtfully looks back on
his journey from pain to pride,
self doubt to self acceptance.
That's an important message.
If you just Google this guy's name,
the images that come up is some of
the funniest shit ever cause he,
he really does. Like, he's in love with
his hair. So you just made another enemy.
Just like you said, you're going
to run it in the next Samsung par.
Are you going to see this fucking guy?
He's going to want to feed you your teeth.
It's so funny though. I, I,
I dunno, just look at the
youtube videos. It's hilarious.
He's really addicted to his hair,
what we talked about earlier and just
write that down and think about whether or
not you want to talk about it.
Right. Make making fun of it. Oh,
yesterday who are really likes his hair,
but all his pictures on Google are just
perfect hair like this. Okay. Crazy.
Johnny Bravo here. Nevermind.
It's okay. Good. Look at,
it's funny. I'm not going to,
but thank you for your suggestion. You're
going to look at it later. Jeff Ross,
what do you got going on man? Besides
odd ball, you got some gigs coming up.
University Rhode Island's coming up. I
think you're doing, that's interesting.
You can do in college is still what?
This fucking big backlash lately the
kids are saying that everybody's too
politically correct to do colleges.
Yeah.
Well Seinfeld doesn't want to do colleges.
Christopher Nolan and I find a
really cool college. Do you think so?
University of Rhode Island's a good spot.
What's a,
did they let you do anything
and get away with anything?
They haven't been given any restrictions.
Do you feel like kids are a little
bit more sensitive these days though?
That's the big people I like.
People are more sensitive.
Do you think they're more sensitive or
do you think they have the opportunity to
complain more? Both. I
think it's become, you know,
the egg before the chicken and
the egg because I don't know,
how's it?
I think people are just looking for
things that everyone feels like a victim.
Everyone's sounds like
a victim all the time.
I feel offended or I don't have my head
to see this or I'm glad to hear that are,
you know, they found another
guy faking black [inaudible] no,
I've seen that in other guy.
Part of the black lives matter that
I feel like people have been
doing this forever. Yeah.
But these are like activists that are
doing it, which is kind of adorable.
It's on Breitbart,
young man named Sean King.
There's another fake black guy,
you know the Rachel Doles all.
She claimed to be black,
but she was actually white and she
said she identifies with black.
You know that they found another dude who
does the same thing and he's a part of
the black lives matter. Oh God. Really?
Yeah. Yeah. It's interesting.
I mean he looks really,
really white and,
but he has that kind of creepy mustache
to some black guys can pull off.
There's his dad. His mom is white as well.
There's photos of him as a young kid,
totally white,
but talked about his struggles of
being an African American. How's,
he was always bullied and throws a lot
of pictures up against that are black and
white. And here's the thing, you know,
there's nothing wrong with being a white
guy that works for black tweeted lot of
my blackness. Then yours,
Daddy said, oh my God, awesome.
He's got black sunglasses on or glasses
and agriculture. What does that,
does that mean? Oh, I
hate those Goddamn popups.
I feel like I'm color blind.
I don't even see,
I don't even assess people's
race right away. Me Neither, man.
I'm fucking completely colorblind in
the human and natural progression of the
way people think. Just weird, weird people
like this are going to crop up. Whoa.
This guy that I really like,
Milo Yiannopoulos,
I'm not exactly sure how to say his,
his last name correctly, but it's Nero.
Any r o on a, on Twitter and a,
he's a fucking funny writer man.
And he's a really good speaker
too. He's hilarious on these. Uh,
he does his interview shows and he's,
uh,
he's always like saying logical things
and having logical arguments against
feminists. If you, uh,
if you like Google some of these Milo
Yiannopoulos and they can't fucking say
anything about him because he's gay
and he has blonde hair and he's super
articulate. So because he
doesn't look like, you know,
like one of the guys from Jersey
shore, he's not like, you know,
a lot of these guys that are representing
men's rights, they, Kyle look douchey.
You know, they kind of look
like Bros. He's gay. So because,
and he's open about it and he's fabulous
and he's got a great vocabulary.
But when he's,
when he's describing or when he's giving
these arguments in debating rather
these women,
he's crushing them cause it's like it was
talking about diversity in science and
he's like,
well the cold hard truth is,
it's not that women are
discouraged from doing science.
This is a lot of them
aren't attracted to it.
Men and women have different states of
mind and boys and girls when they're
young, if you give them
like equal access to toys,
boys naturally will gravitate towards
like trucks and cars and girls were
naturally gravitate towards dolls. It
has nothing to do with it. Yeah. Here's,
here's one of them on Sky News.
Why men are better at chess,
listen to by look at them.
You feel about being different because
of your hard wired differently.
So it's not something you've
have a failed to hear before.
It just seems to keep cropping up.
Is it necessary?
It's just, it's ridiculous.
It's his 50s thinking, you know,
I mean it's just so ridiculous.
This biological determinism,
frankly, you know, interests
and talent and you know,
passions for particular topics,
subjects or arts,
whatever. Like they're not
relegated to either gender,
but unfortunately because of
some stereotypical thinking,
often one gender is encouraged to pursue,
you know,
a sport or an art more so than the other.
And my colleague at the Telegraph,
Radica Sigourney,
she wrote a piece just this
morning speaking to, um,
like young girls who play chess and
actually what she found out that they're
dropping out at the age of
12 probably because you know,
they're not encouraged or you know,
there's,
I don't want to me telling them that
it's not for them, it's not called,
et Cetera, et cetera. So you know,
this hardwired brain staff
like is it's retro sexism,
Barlow, you're not plus
bashed, smiling, laughing.
Ben and women are wired differently,
have different skills. No,
it doesn't matter in the sense
that they are equal but different.
But it simply isn't true to say that
there is no difference whatsoever between
the attitudes of men and women.
And it is without question true that
there are some biological differences
between men and women.
And we know that from our anatomy.
But we also know it from experiments
that we do on young children.
Before they've had the
opportunity to be socialized,
the sorts of toys that they go for.
And that holds true.
Actually for them it's the
animal kingdom as well.
Some of the reasons why girls drop out
of stem subjects at college and, uh,
chess clubs is because they keep losing.
And one of the reasons they keep losing
is that it does seem to be the case that
chess as a game plays to some of
the male intellectual virtues.
And when Simon Baron Cohen
talks about this, is he,
the way he describes it as men are good
at systematizing and women are good at
empathizing and there is some reason to
suppose that that may have some basis in
biology.
It's very trendy these days to say
that everything is socially determined,
but that's not what the science says.
And it's not either what common sensors,
because if it were true these days,
there would be a lot more
representation of women in the sciences,
in astrophysics, in philosophy,
in mathematics, and in chess.
But there isn't so ready. Does
that, does that make sense? That's,
that's done. That chick should just go
home. She just pooped hers just go home.
Cause it's true.
That's the idea.
It says is that saying that men
are better or women are better,
but the idea that there's no difference
between us and biological determinism is
bullshit.
It's just ridiculous.
So that dude is hilarious and
he's the guy who busted this guy.
He's the guy who I had the article on
Breitbart about this guy who's actually
white, pretends to be black. He's
great though. I love his writing.
I love listening to him talk. The
guys just, he nails it every time.
It was hilarious. Yeah. Yeah.
He'll be on soon. He's going,
he'll be on here and a couple of
weeks working something out. Hmm.
Jeffrey Ross is here now though
and now he's had some food.
Expertly eaten off Mike and Nobody
would know anything if you didn't call.
I been all carved up and
rejuvenated and what you did,
I love how you handled it.
Did it professional,
got to watch some fucking bullshit
about shit. I don't care about you.
Care about fucking knew.
What do you think about Trump?
I feel like he has a Charlie sheen
writing is material. We're nature.
Nova loses. I need to be aware as, yeah.
If he wins. I said this at the comedy
store last night. If he wins a,
it's proof that there's an Illuminati
in this country or he's a part of it or
he's a part of it. But that seems unlikely
that he's a part of the Illuminati.
Yeah. Why would they want to billionaires
and the Illuminati? He's rogue.
He's on his own. He's fucking crazy.
I've roasted them a couple times. Yeah.
He's a good sport. He doesn't
show it, but he is really,
what's he like as a person?
Uh,
he's engaging and he likes to ask a
lot of questions about Mexicans. Nah,
we were on a pleasure trip.
Got Into Mara Largo on his plane.
Me and Bruce Smear Knauf really quite
a while ago. Nice. Be Back in the day.
I haven't heard that name. And forever. I
was very generous. He, Bruce Knauf. Yeah.
The proofs and I on,
on Trump's plane.
I remember the Donald in the nineties
yeah. Something like that. No,
early two thousands I
think. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
So you're chilling on his plane.
We go down to Mara Largo you
have in Palm Beach, Florida,
Donald Trump's golf country club facility.
They're very fancy,
very beautiful.
And he gave us a Cadillac Bruce Tonight
at tool around with for the weekend.
I did a show on the Saturday night.
Donald brought me up himself.
Really? Not An easy crowd,
I wouldn't think so.
You know, very formal,
you know the whole thing.
Bunch a creepy one percenters on Adderall,
but a very,
very elegant and in the end,
very appreciative crowd.
And I roasted them at the friars club
once when I roasted them on comedy central
ones.
I remember him not laughing at all for
like three comedians and I went up to him
and during the commercial
break and I'm like, Donald,
you have to at least smile so we have
something to cut to other than other
people laughing at you. And he's
like, oh, okay. I get it now.
I think sort of smiling and enjoying
himself a little bit. That's hilarious.
That's a what? A what a
weird guy. He is, Huh?
He's in a strange there is right there.
Nice and orange.
Yeah. What's the orange all
about? He wears a lot of makeup.
Is that makeup or is that like
Spray Tans Shit from my HDTV,
I'd always looks like caked on makeup.
He's got the original kissy face.
Go back to the lessor to push,
get a plus on sourpuss but
there he doesn't have it.
So what does he do in the how?
That's powder Donald Trump.
You think it's possible that he could win?
How close do you think he's going to get?
Oh man,
he's, he's kind of a shoe in
for the Democrats is what he is.
What do you mean?
Because a lot of people that would vote
Republican are going to vote for him if
he stays in. If he stays
in, it's gonna make thing.
Especially if he goes independent,
which is totally possible. Right?
If he goes independent, he could be Ross
Perot in this motherfucker. He could,
a Ross Perot sunk the ship of Herbert
Walker Bush because everybody was torn
between who to vote for.
There was a libertarian people that
would have maybe possibly voted more
fiscally conservative.
So they had gone with the Republicans
and instead they went with Ross Perot
cause he was laying it down how the
taxes were and what the fuck was actually
going on. Whereas, uh, that, that
like opened the door for Clinton.
What do you think about
Bernie Sanders? Uh, like, um,
like what he's saying about education
and all I fucking hate when people say,
you know, yeah, that's great.
Good at fucking people.
Be Nudge gay on my tax dollars.
What about more tax dollars?
What about war that you know,
how much more it costs to go to war than
it costs to educate people? You know,
don't you think it would be better if we
had less people that were uneducated in
this country or if we had less people
that were leaving college in fucking
massive debt? If you're a kid,
okay, if you're 18 to 21 years old,
which is most people that are in college,
you don't need to be saddled down with
hundreds of thousands of dollars in
education debt. That's
fucking gross. It's gross.
And it's stupid and it speaks to
poor management of our civilization.
That's what I think about our situation
in America when it comes to colleges and
the amount of money that
kids get straddled down with
saddled down rather with
debt, they're fucked. You
know, especially if you go,
if you talked to someone who goes to
medical school, Jesus Christ, right?
My friend was,
he was hundreds of thousands of
dollars in debt before he, he,
before he left a medical school,
hundreds of thousands
of dollars just fucked.
Like it takes you forever to make that
money because you don't just make the
hundreds of thousands of dollars.
You gotta make a living too
and incentivize you to deal
with the system the way
it is and not adapt to some new, yeah,
health plan in this country, whatever.
You've just got to get your nut while
it becomes a game becomes a game.
Just like the cop thing, we're
talking about the comp thing, cops,
it becomes a game of convicting people,
going after people, convicting them,
getting the win, getting the
victory. Well with doctors,
it becomes a matter of getting
people to have surgery. I had um,
a friend of mine telling me he
started when he was 16 years old,
he was working as a like a
like some vacation resort,
you know, he's working on,
it's like somebody who works at the
resort and he said he overheard these
fucking doctors talking about talking
someone into getting an operation and they
were going chit chain. They were
just talking about how the, you know,
I talked him into getting this
and that means I get this,
like they were talking about it like a
guy who was talking about selling Chevys.
It's like [inaudible] these all
doctors that they were together.
So just like comics would get
together and shoot the shit.
Doctors get together and shoot the shit.
What did you do?
I told him I got a fucking fake knee
given each other knock goals, any goes.
It changed forever the way I thought
about doctors. He goes, I, I left.
You know what didn't work there anymore.
I never thought about doctors the same
way because of that conversation those
guys had. I would've never been privy
to that in any of the circumstances.
But a few guys sitting around at a resort
having a couple of cocktails, again,
a little loose with the lip, he found
out what they were really all about.
It's because they're fucked. They're
fucking, they're, they're, they're fucked.
Not just with the amount of money that
they have to pay for their education,
but also malpractice insurance is crazy.
My cousin is a surgeon. He was in
practice in New Jersey for years and said,
fuck it. I'm going to work for
an emergency room where I share.
And it just took a lot of pressure
off him in his life and I think he got
happier and probably became
a better doctor. Yeah,
well that's what I think a lot of
responsibility, a lot of red, you know,
constant work to run the practice,
act yourself.
It is. It is. And you know, people
do do need to be protected. I mean,
there are doctors at fuck up.
We showed that lady who got her feet
fucking amputated in her hands amputated
and they fucked up.
But she,
they'd literally amputated the
wrong person's feet and hands.
He's fucked up.
You see this Sarah Silverman, uh, Bernie
Sanders video. She did a speech for him.
It was really powerful and it,
and it's really cool that she did that
because you know, uh, Bernie somebody,
I think a lot of people, younger
people, uh, would like also like,
cause I'm Facebook, a lot of the
younger people I'm friends with, uh,
or always posting burns.
My friend's a little kids, man. The fuck's
going on talking to six year olds. No,
but did you see the uh,
the giant rallies that he's put
together and including one in la?
There's like 18,000 people. So you have
them in la. That's great. Well the,
he gives you a hope that there's some,
someone that represents
a more open minded,
a more current point of view,
I think. And I think, you know,
there's this fucking like Ted Cruz and
all these people that are running and
they're like, you're like, Ooh, I like
is you like you look at them and you go,
this guy can't win Kenny, can
he win? Lucky you seek guys
like that and you go, oh,
come on Bri. Is this real like Chris
Christie? Is that Breal it? Can he really,
when you get more standoffish
and scared by it than anything,
he had to run because of all
the scandals he had. Otherwise,
what made him seem guilty really,
but I think,
I think he had had to run node or
to go, everything's fine. Yeah.
That's an interesting way of looking at
it. I'm from New Jersey, just me too.
I was born in Newark, me to
shut the fuck up. That's crazy.
When we born 65 you're older than me.
67 August 11 September 13th Jesus Christ
basically two years apart from each
other, pal. Here we are. Same Hospital.
Maybe. What hospital? Beth Israel.
Is that the name of it?
I don't even remember.
I was hoping would say something and
I go, that sounds like mine. Yeah.
I'll have to ask my mom. You guys
didn't go like know each other at all?
We met each other in New York in like
1990 maybe 91 when did you start?
What year did you start doing
stay? A April fool's day? 1989 wow.
Yeah, I started um, in 88, August 27th,
1988 stitches Boston
and uh,
I made it to New York somewhere on 90 91.
It was probably when I met you back it
up at catch a rising star. Ah, it didn't,
we meet at a Boston comedy maybe.
Probably met hosts there and do spots.
There is a great little spot. It wasn't,
it was good. That was a great little spot.
That was one of those really tiny rooms.
Like that was a 90 cedar like maybe
didn't even see 90 probably something like
that. Maybe a little more in the villa.
They say 120, but I could be a crazy,
let's say a hundred. Yeah,
it was a great little spot.
Charlie Barnett,
there's a cool article about him
in the New York Times last week.
Trolley Bailey who died of
AIDS. Sad, sad, sad story.
But
he was the king of the park in Washington
Square Park and he would go on at that
Boston comedy club and the comedy cellar.
Well he would do a lot of
sets, uh, out on the street.
When we do shows in the street,
he'd throw his hat down and uh,
Dave Chappelle used to like,
he learned from him. Right.
Chappelle used to do a lot
of shows like that where he,
I saw him do it in Montreal. We did a
show at club soda. I Remember Club Soda.
It's still there. Yeah, it's a call
that something different now, isn't it?
I think so. Anyway, they did a,
we did a show at club soda and then
outside Dave just starts just like gather
round, gather round, and
he starts doing standup.
Got All that from Charlie.
Yeah.
Dave and I both lived on the sides of
that park and we used to watch Charlie all
the time.
And then I think when Charlie passed away,
Dave kind took over that mantle in the
fountain on the weekends and sometimes
during the week and he really found
his voice I think in that park.
So you guys used to go and watch Charlie
perform in the powers and just hang out
with like, it was great. It was, you know,
you had to get your work done back
then we lived in small apartments. He,
there were no cell phones and you weren't,
you had to do whatever you were going to
do. If there was an email or phone call,
you had your phone in your house and
you went and did all that and you left
messages and got messy and you went out
and when you were out you were present
in the moment and you are
loving every second of it.
Dave and I would hang around Washington
square park and try to talk to Nyu girls
who are studying and whatever we could
do and find some weed and we would
brainstorm and write jokes and we'd eat
lunch in the park and listen to music.
There was always a,
the acrobats were in the park and,
and masterly karate,
he comic would come.
And Charlie Barnett,
this guy that was just hilarious would,
you know, like you said, he would
jump up on the fountain show time.
It's showtime and all
jokes are real simple
and he could work the crowd. A
homeless guy walks by, he had a joke.
Japanese tourists walks by. He
had a joke in mimic him, you know,
and you know, uh, it was
a great show for anyone.
Eight to 80, rich or poor. Even
if you don't speak English,
you're laughing at Charlie. He
was so physical and funny and, and
it was a great time. I remember
there were riots in Los Angeles.
It might've been Rodney king and we
got warnings in New York to be careful.
It might be riots in New York and
trolley. Walk me home. He's like, yeah,
I'm going to have your end word walk,
walking home.
Just really endearing. And I loved him.
He was what? He was supposed to do,
siren live. But apparently when he got
there they realized that he couldn't read.
Yeah. It's kind of a crazy
story, you know? I mean they,
he was like a hot comic.
A lot of people wanted him to do things,
but he didn't know how to read.
I don't know. He was super,
super funny. It's interesting
that he had that style, you know,
that style influenced a lot of people,
that style of like doing street comedy,
you know,
just gathering a crowd out of nowhere.
I never had the guts to
go on outside like that,
but Chappelle watched them and watched
them and watched him and Charlie sort of
bringing them up every now and then he
let them do a few minutes and eventually
Dave, that just became one of his
chapters. It was amazing to watch.
Charlie was loud and his
jokes were really short.
Dave was more soft spoken
and his jokes were longer.
To see that in the park was fascinating
because the park had to come to Dave a
little bit and you've really saw at
least I really saw having hung out there
every night that every day.
You know,
sometimes Dave would do a few couple of
shows on a Sunday in the park and he'd
make real fans and he got a real sense
of who he was right there doing that.
I mean it was magic to see uh,
a young genius in the middle of the public
just being him and having the public
come to him gravitate to him.
Uh,
it was once in a lifetime thing to say.
That's cool.
I got a chance to see him perform
at catch a rising star when he was,
he might've been 18 thing.
How old's Dave now
don't ask.
Look on the fucking computer cause
you got a computer in front of 45.
How it is stage of Hill.
Okay, so he's six years,
seven years younger than me.
So that doesn't even make sense.
So cause I was only like 23
how, how's that? Is that true?
Maybe he didn't get that right.
41 that doesn't make sense.
He's 42 because he was born August 24th,
1973 and
I was born in 74 and I'm 41
means he turns 45 days from now.
This is the 24th, 1973 though.
He's 42 next week. Next week.
Next week is 42.
He got mad, dammit. My
math skills. Uh, so,
uh, so if he's 42, um, I must fuck man,
that doesn't make any sense.
I guess maybe I was too.
So He's six years younger
than me, so I was, man,
that seems weird because that
was really early twenties.
I was like 21 or 22 at the most.
I was 24.
I was doing comedy is high schools too.
Yeah, I guess he was 18 and I was 24.
That, that makes sense now
that I think about it. But, uh,
I got a chance to see him at catch
a rising star. I was like, wow,
what a precocious young man.
He was like so advanced for his
age and it was a a lot like, um,
uh, Tony Woods. I remember Tony
Woods or also from DC. Hilarious guy.
I think Tony and him
probably work together
together. I think they will fully
admit that he was influenced by Tony.
Tony. They were, you know, they were good
buddies. I think they still are. Yeah.
Um, you always had this love for
the older comics, like always.
I remember that like you were one of the
first guys going to the friars club and
I was like,
look at Jeff and his fucking twenties
is hanging out the Friar's club.
I a love for all comics and that's where
the older comics were and they had,
they were smart.
I learned a lot just about how life works.
Not just show business.
That's obvious.
You get to talk to an older
comic about show business.
But I would talk to Buddy Hackett for it
hours about guns and pussy and politics
and travel and food and booze.
And he knew everything.
Isn't it weird that there's a club Friar's
club like dead dedicated Comedians,
club
comedy show business? I see politicians
and musicians, they're agents, lawyers.
Is that still going on?
Thriving?
The Friar's club on 55th street between
park and Madison in New York City.
So it's not just comics? No, it
wasn't always just comics. No,
it's well known for the roast
comics are identified with it,
but it's a fraternity for show business,
basically a show business themed club
and it's in New York and in La is the one
and only in New York. Only in wasn't la
for a long, long time, but not anymore.
When did it, uh, when Milton Berle
died had kind of died with him.
What year was that?
10 years ago I think.
Hmm.
Wow.
You ever meet Bob Hope? I never met Bob
Hope. And that's, uh, I met him once.
What was that like? I was just a
kid, but he was very nice. He, uh,
he was golfing and I was at
the memorial tournament and uh,
there was this huge crowd of people
and he was just walking by and he just
looked over at me for some reason,
just walked up to me and goes, hey kid.
And he signed my, uh, uh, like the
little paper thing and then just away.
Didn't take anyone
else's like photos or a sign,
anyone else's shit.
I didn't even do anything different.
Like he just came right up. It was weird.
Well back in those days there was not
that many photos because you didn't have a
camera on me when I met
Bob hope everybody's got a
camera on them now I'm at
honey young men,
Henny Youngman when I was a little kid
and he gave me a card and I still have it.
I mean I kinda like that charity
in your pocket. You just pointed.
You would just reach for your wallet.
Do you still have it? No, I do,
but not on me. It was a music note
with his name, with his autograph.
He played violin and his, actually,
he had a music. Take my wife,
take my wife please.
He was a funny guy. He,
his picture is still hanging up at
the friars club by Leroy Neiman.
A beautiful painting. There's
no, it's like a living,
breathing museum of show business
places like that in la anymore.
No. Too Bad, Huh? Yeah.
Or they're that many old comics
that are still kicking around.
Well, you know there's always
an an old comic. Yeah. Yeah.
He might not be from the Dean
Martin from Fryers, you know,
Co celebrity roast era,
but there's always a new old comic.
Have you ever seen some of the memorabilia
they have laying around at the store
from back when it used to be Ciro's
and Dean Martin and Jerry Lewis used to
perform that haven't,
oh,
you got to go into the office and see
some of the cool posters and that old ciro
sign was Bugsy Siegel's
joint. Pretty wild. Fuck all.
That's why everybody thinks it's haunted.
They think so many people were killed.
There is a tunnel in the back of the
comedy store that did they close it off as
it closed off?
Yeah, it's closed off by
concrete I think. Right?
Something,
I dunno,
but there was a tunnel that went from
the comedy store up the hill to a house
that like people could escape through
where they could fucking move shit too.
You know,
the comedy store is just
filled with catacombs and
says fucking so clustered and
confusing. If you don't know
your way around that place.
Of your some cop and we'll confirm Meyer
Lansky and he fucking just skirts out
the back and I've seen both the hill and
stuff. That's what it looked like. Wow.
Go big screen on that. Fuck man.
Look at that. That's the main rule,
man. Holy Shit. How weird is that?
Because you kind of
recognize it a little bit.
It's like Jessica Rabbit should
come out and start singing,
which probably would be dead back then
or some facsimile. Whoa, look at that.
That's what the stage looks like.
Maybe that might not be the
same place that seems off,
but the other one was
Ciro's, right? Yeah. Wow.
Who was the girl? A stripper stripper.
Lil Saints for, what was her name?
Let's see here. Lili St Cyr. See
why are, how do you say that?
Performing at Ciro's nightclub.
A stripper at Ciro's. Wow.
How weird.
Great. What are these old ladies
watching this? It looked like,
scroll down and look at the photo down.
Look at that.
That's the fucking front
of store, man. That's
nuts.
That is not God.
It looks so similar to where
it looks like that car.
That's a cool old car. My those cars
are worth a fuck load of money. Now.
That house isn't there anymore.
Right.
That's where the hotel is to the
right of it or chop their pitch down.
But that's definitely the store.
Like the patio there. Still intact.
Look at the sign. Sammy Davis
Jr. Wow. Who's that guy?
Will Mastin? That was his
dad was it? Yeah. Really.
His uncle, that was his uncle he
worked with. Wow. Look at that.
Everybody pulling in the front.
Fuck. That's crazy to see.
It's crazy to see a plug. That's
the fucking back parking lot, man.
That's the side area.
Jesus Christ.
That is so weird. It's so weird
to see that place like that. Wait,
so that's where the belly room
is, right? I think, isn't it?
Yeah.
I mean doesn't that look like the corner?
It looks totally like the corner and so
I guess there's a sign in the front or
was it the front of the building know
that has to be mark as a front of the
building. Yeah, that's up front. They
just, it just looked way different.
It was just set up way
different. Wow. It's amazing.
There's so much history in that place,
that place it feels like like comedy,
musical chairs too.
Cause it feels like the music's going to
stop and everyone's going to be really
sad because when Mitzi dies, who knows
what that place is going to become?
What is it? Who is that guy?
What the fuck was that? What was,
what the hell is that?
What is that guy doing when his dick
as he thrown a girl up in the air.
Okay.
He's got his hands over
his Dick Doing Voodoo.
He's barefoot like guys barefoot and
he's throwing that woman in the air.
Wow.
It's crazy.
I wonder if anybody's ever
done a documentary on Ciro's.
New York doesn't really have a club like
that. Huh? They don't have an old club.
Like what's the oldest club in New York?
Comedy cellar.
But that's like the 80s right?
No settles seventies that's pretty old.
So seller is the oldest place you think
so a comic strips have been here a long
time, but nothing is like, this catch
was great. That was a great little room.
That was a great little spot,
man. This is freaking me out.
These photos of Ciro's you,
you go back and forth,
you go back and forth from New
York to La and New York and La.
I'm bi-coastal so you just have fun.
Just do whatever the fuck you want. Well,
I mean kind of live in a dream Jeff Ross,
things are good but you kind of live
in a dream, you know the way you do it.
It just,
I see you dick and pictures like there
was a picture of you the other day with
Ray Romano and the seller and then boom,
all of a sudden you're at the store.
You know like you would just hop back
and forth and Ari's doing that to ours.
Your peers doing that too? I
like it man. I like, you know,
you make the world smaller and I don't,
I'm happy
in both places. I like to move
around. I like, I like life on both.
I don't know.
Where do you like performing better?
I don't know. I don't, I guess
generally I like New York as a city,
but I have all my friends
out here and I don't know.
Do you keep an apartment out here?
I have a house here.
So you have a house here in a place
back there to get she fucking animal.
I like it. Whatever happened to the burn.
What happened? Comedy Central One. Yeah.
They didn't make it after two seasons.
That was a fun show. Yeah. So fun.
Fucking love that. But you'd be tied
down then you have to stay here.
That's all right. That's not what a
dinner for that and all my buddies,
they're working. It was awesome.
You got anything going on right now?
Working on the next special and when
a roast cops, right? He told about,
talked about that earlier.
Hosts the odd ball tour with Amy and Aziz
and among kingdom couple of new ideas
coming up. Things are good, man. It's good
to see you buddy. It's just so much fun,
dude. You seem like you seem
overwhelmed. What do you mean?
He's just very low key? Very low key.
She ever meet Steve Martin? Uh, no.
Never met Steve Martin.
Is there a comic that you want to meet,
do you haven't met? Oh boy. I never
met Woody Allen. That would be cool.
What do you think that conversation would
be like? I had to keep it about comedy.
Yeah,
you'd have to.
If you ventured into girls that
would get a little weird sweaty.
It'd be a fun conversation.
You think so? I think he would.
We would open up to a comic before
he would open up to anybody else.
Don't you felt like you'd just tell Woody
Allen everything? Me? Yeah, definitely.
Pull them aside
and be like,
he'd be very open minded
maybe. Who knows? You know?
It's all depending on who you're listening
to. If you listen to me or feral. No,
not so much, you know? But he's
obviously a creative genius obviously,
but you know,
I got to know Mel Brooks.
That's my other one
where that's a big one.
Spend a lot of dinners at Caesar's
house. Listening to Mel. Really?
Oh yeah. Wow. That's huge. That's
gigantic. I asked my uncle Murray,
he's coming out to visit a
couple of years ago. I said,
if he could meet anybody. He never been
to la. I've been all over the world.
He's a purple heart, Silver Star
recipient, World War II army medic,
helped liberate a concentration camp,
dined all over the world,
best restaurants in the world
was a caterer, had a great
life, outlive two wives,
loved them both. He's never been to
la. I said, what do you want to do?
If he could meet, do anything, what would
do? He's like, I like to beat Bill Brooks.
I was like, well, what's your second
choice? Because that's not happening.
And you know,
he's coming and he's coming in and
it's getting closer and so fuck it.
I write a letter to mail
books. A letter. Yeah. Wow.
And I knew where his office was and I,
I knew Mel a little bit because I
had sat with sit Caesar's house for
different holidays and birthdays and
he'd always pop in with Carl Reiner.
Even when sid was frail and old,
Mel and Carl would make a big entrance
male with lean white innocence
wheelchair.
Mel said,
it's Mel Brooks and Colorado
and you see scintillate up.
It was great. And you know,
it was like 4th of July
weekend a couple of years ago.
And finally I'm like fuck my uncle's only
here for another couple of more days.
We're having a great time.
We went to Fred Willard and Mary Willard's
fireworks party and I took him to the
Polo Lounge with Bob Saget and we'd
been having so much fun and he saw Renee
Taylor gang is cone Chinese restaurant.
He got a picture and you know,
my uncle is having the best time
but man he did say, you know,
months ago that would be the one thing
with the Creme de la creme would be,
you know, just a handshake
and a photo at Mel Brooks.
So I'm a little embarrassed.
So I go into the bathroom and I called
Mills Office cause I don't want my uncle,
they hear me even though
he was 90 you know,
and I'm like I just make sure he got
the letter, you know, following up.
I'm just like being as humble and yeah.
Yeah.
Mel's been out of town off.
I'll, I'll, I'll see what,
I'll see if I can get an answer at.
Boom.
I have to go to emergency dental
appointment. I think a filling fell out.
So I took my uncle to the
dentist with me. I'm done.
It's 10 30 now. I'm like, how do
I kill our last day with my uncle?
I love my uncle Murray. He's just
the family. Ballbuster mean Marie.
We called him and he just basically made
fun of me as a kid and taught me how to
take a joke, like a real Jersey
guy, you know, lifelong caterer.
Just super funny. And we're
up, I'm showing them, you know,
Mulholland and this and that and we're
right at the top of Laurel Canyon and
Mohan and my cell phone rings hold
from Mel Brooks. I'm like, Oh,
this is where he's calling. Like,
there's going to be no service of here.
This is terrible. Like
this is, Mel gets on.
And he's like, he's like, um,
basically. So what's going on?
What's happening? And I'm like, oh,
we were trying to talk and drive down
this hill a once. And I'm like, well,
you know, I think he would be
so nice of you and my uncle,
he just loves you and visit
whenever I can say I think you guys,
you're both World War II veteran lawyer.
We have a lot you'll have,
you might have a lot in common.
And Mel goes,
the only thing I have in common with you
and with your uncle is that I'm a nice
guy.
So come on over.
It had hour and a half over to my office
or the barber shop, I don't know yet.
I'll call you back click. I go down
the hill and we're both in shorts.
So might were panicking.
So we're racing down Laurel Canyon and
we run home to put long pants on and just
comb her hair or whatever.
I was coming from the dentists,
he knows just sweat and on my
uncle is like, he doesn't ever,
he'd ever waits online. Like,
you know, he has certain real,
he's like a very proud stubborn
guy, you know, seen it all.
And he's like nervously rehearsing
opening lines to say to Mel Brooks.
I say to him, he's like, how's
this? He goes, well, I'll
go goes houses. He goes, ah.
He goes, uh, it's good to meet the king.
It's good to be the king is mill's famous
line. Right. And a I'm like, I got it.
That's good. That's good. I'm there is
to my uncle Dave. Anything a second time,
you know,
and uh,
we get there and we have this parking
spot on the lot right next to Mel's
parking space and it's beautiful.
It's where they shot gone with the wind.
It's like this beautiful
movie La. My uncles, you know,
he,
okay.
He has very bad knees,
very,
very weak knees from walking
across Europe and World War II.
He can barely stand for
it was a very strong guy.
Worked his whole life and as
a cook in his catering hall,
but now he's old and he can't
w Mel's office for some reason.
Who's by the way,
is only a year younger.
Two years younger is on the
second floor of this building.
So now my uncle who can really,
yeah.
Flies up this flight of stairs
into bell's office. He assisted is there,
you get a year drink. Sure. You know,
my uncle,
it just like get the fuck could zone at
Mel's Duller opens and they go in there
and they promised me, you know,
five or 10 minutes with Mel,
these two guys are in there for 75
minutes. They know this same guys.
They were both in Patton's army.
They knew guys from New Jersey,
they do guys from New York.
They are laughing, you know,
uh,
my uncle says I've been a fan ever
since the 2000 year old man and Mel,
Mel says it's the 1000 year old man,
don't make me older than I am. Yeah,
they're just laughing and I'm
just staying out of the way.
I'm giving them both a couple setup
lines cause I kind of know both of their,
you know, where they're going.
I'm trying to be helpful.
But they've tuned me out for
over an hour and they hit it off.
And Mel signed a bunch of,
gave my uncle his DVD set and
signed it to my uncle and, and,
and Mel walks us out himself and we
took pictures, a great picture. I'll,
I'll Instagram it this
week or something. And, um,
the door closes and we're walking down
the hall and my uncle who's never at a
loss for words, he just,
he's bouncing these like,
wow. Wow. Wow, wow, wow. Okay.
Like a little kid coming off a
rollercoaster, uncle Murray story.
Uncle Murray, he passed away. Rest in
peace. We're not going to top that.
So it was wrapping up right here. That's
awesome. I love it. Yeah, it's cool.
That's a great thank you Mel Brooks.
And then I see Mel, uh, uh, you know,
I thank him. I thank him. You
know, he always mentioned,
asked me about uncle marine and my uncle
Murray family passed away and I said to
Mel, I said, listen, if it Mel, if any
of your uncles ever to meet me, I'm happy
to oblige
the wheel.
Jeffrey Ross on Twitter and on Instagram.
Thanks brother.
That was awesome. So that was good fun
buddy. Thanks for having me. Your show.
He's always around.
He could see him at the store or you see
him in New York if he's in a Rodeo on
Tuesdays roast battle on Tuesday. Humble
tour university, Rhode Island. Ah,
come see Brian Red band tonight at
the sold out ice house show bed.
Nice. Yeah, we're going to have some
fun tonight at the Ice House. That one,
Tony Hinchcliffe,
Joey Diaz and Brian Cowen.
Good fucking googly Mowgli.
Uh,
this weekend I'm at the
store on Friday night.
I'm doing the late show in the belly
room with me and the Golden Pony,
Tony Hinchcliffe. That should be
fun. Uh, that's a Friday night.
10 30 at the store, and I'm at the store
all weekend too. All right. You fucks.
Love the shit out of you
people. See you soon. Bye. Bye.
Hm.