Five four,
three,
two,
one.
Fuck it.
We'll do it live.
We'll do it.
Josh [inaudible].
Today's a sad day in las bill o'reilly.
Oh,
am morning at you.
Morning Joe.
I feel like I should be,
but I'm not a ton of loot.
What's that?
I said he made a ton of lewd.
Wow.
I mean since 96 when Fox News launched
and he was like the big,
I'm just making it up,
but that's when Fox News launch.
Let's check at Jamie,
is that when Fox News launched 96
[inaudible]
uh,
he has pulled in so much money for that
network and for himself.
He was one of the bunch of bulls.
The main guy,
he really was the main guy in
broadcasting.
They're going to find another old cut to
fill a spot.
You're going to have to,
that's what people look at.
That October 7th,
1996,
ladies and gentlemen,
you'll welcome America.
You'll wear that.
He was on like a hard copy or something
like that.
Right.
I don't even know.
I was too young.
I wasn't even here in the states.
Oh yeah,
I was at school,
child in Australia and was a child.
I don't remember him from anything else.
I just remember him being on o'reilly
and watching it and going,
what is it?
It's like that longing for in the Stall
Gia thing,
you know,
you see an older gentleman in a tie who
just sit well and that's the way it is.
The tide goes in,
the tide goes out,
can you define it?
What in the fuck is this guy doing?
And that was when he was talking,
he was talking to an atheist,
wasn't it?
Who was he?
Was it?
Oh,
I don't remember.
It was like maybe it was ricky Gervais'
or some,
I can't remember,
but he was saying,
well maybe it was sam.
Could it have been Sam Harris?
I don't know who it was somewhat.
Some atheist was saying like a w was
saying,
what do you,
he was like,
Bill was like,
I've got the absolute number one reason
why you have to believe in God because
tide goes in.
Tide goes out,
always been that way.
Always will be that way when one goes
round or just spins around.
How do you explain that?
If not God,
it was just super obvious that he was
pandering because the guy went to
fucking Harvard.
Okay.
Bill O'reilly's not a dope.
He might be a Douche bag,
but he's not a dope.
He's not.
I think religion makes people dopey and
ways that they don't and they don't even
know about,
I don't even think he's religious.
I think he's barely religious.
I think he's religious enough to get by
with the job.
I said,
do you think he's in since he has been
in some see 100% because I think he's
one of the,
look,
I don't watch the show a lot,
so I'm not sure.
But I,
he's always struck me as one of the more
straight shooters.
I think he is.
He's smart but not wise.
Yes.
Uh,
you know,
he feels what he feels in his gut is
more important than what the data tells
him.
And I think he falls for a bunch of
fallacies that a lot of people fall for,
especially if they're religious.
Like the idea that there was a certain
order to the cosmos and how could we all
have come about?
How could this whole thing around us
exist with all these butterflies and the
moon and the tide comes in and the tide
goes out and does his,
me and Joe,
these spiritual creatures,
these beings sitting opposite each other
on a,
at a table
in Los Angeles right now.
Some people just find that to
inexplicably to explain without a deity,
so they're like,
all right,
there must've been a big guy who did it.
It's even dumber in my opinion,
to think that one dude engineered this
whole fucking thing.
I mean,
wouldn't,
wouldn't you just think that,
oh wow.
There's some crazy super complex system
that sort of works in some odd way where
it balances itself out with Predator and
prey and food and water and fire and
dirt and all this stuff together,
and then you realize that it all has to
form out of the the,
the,
the actual elements that come from an
exploding star.
It's magnificent.
Just the actual,
this,
the full realm of things that they've
absolutely proven to be true in terms of
like scientific discoveries about the
universe and the,
yeah,
just the very elements that constitute
human beings and everything.
You see this table and laptops,
it's amazing the idea that one dude and
sitting there up in his class
and of course moderate religious people
will say,
well,
of course we don't believe in that kind
of a god.
We don't believe in a God with a robe
and a beard sitting in the clouds.
We believe in a more sophisticated
metaphorical version of God.
Yeah,
but you still believe that whatever
consciousness created black holes and
the whole cosmos gives a shit whether or
not you beat off well also that it has
to be a one.
Yeah.
Hey God,
a thin one thing,
unless you're a Hindu,
in which case I've got an elephant got
over here,
I've got to emission whoever.
Here I've got a multi armed monkey
and you got a lot of Hash Hash to say
those things.
I mean,
one of the things that's interesting is
I think at any given point in time,
people just assumed that the universe
was created by whatever thing happens to
be around them.
It was on the podcast head that that was
a great upset.
I had him on my podcast with,
uh,
no,
I had him on point of inquiry actually,
which is a different podcast than my
normal one where the people,
like the week before he was on yours,
yours was way better.
You can talk about a lot of shit in
three hours.
Joe,
you kind of took that theme and that's
why I like doing it.
Yeah.
Broke
my brain with this one thing he said.
He explained that when you talk about
the universe being 14 billion years old,
you're talking about the observable
universe and he's like,
the problem is space moves faster than
light.
The universe is moving faster than the
speed of light.
So what we're seeing is what we can see
from 14 billion years ago because,
but that doesn't mean that's all there
is,
right.
He goes,
space itself is bending.
But what he's saying is space itself
beyond that could be infinite.
It's just moving faster than we can see.
He just spread my brain.
Yeah,
exactly.
So,
but he was saying,
it's like when you're talking about the
observable universe being,
I think it's 13.7 billion years,
almost 14 billion years old.
That's just how far back we can see.
He's like,
but before that,
like when you go back further.
Yeah,
that's right.
It's just that we can't see it because
the space itself is moving faster than
the speed of light.
That's right.
And you're also,
what you're looking at is not only the
edge of the universe,
but the edge of time.
Yeah.
Because it's not even the edge.
What he's saying is it's,
it's very likely that not only is it
infinite,
but there's an infinite number of
possibilities beyond it.
Yes.
And those things beyond it may also be
right alongside us.
I mean,
in terms of the other dimensions and
things like that,
like he didn't even get into all of it,
all of that stuff.
But if you believe in string theory and
quantum physics and if you believe in
math,
then you sort of have to,
well quantum physics and string theory
to a dope like me is one of those things
where I have to contact your word for
it.
It's almost like before the,
uh,
before the Lutheran Times,
before the Bible was translated and you
have to rely on the priest,
just trust the price.
I'll just you and your knowledge cause
he knows Latin and he speaks Aramaic.
You know it's going to read this shit.
Yeah.
Who told the priest?
Well the pope who told the Pope don't
ask questions,
but when you go into this food,
that's why it's so important to,
to appreciate like when people are
science deniers,
it's so frustrating because everything
you use,
everything you enjoy,
everything that you in terms of
medicine,
technology is based on the work of
countless people who have worked
generations after generations on the
innovations of the past.
Like the people before them invented
some shit.
They improved upon it.
They figured out more.
They studied the calculations of those
people,
they added to it.
And then you get to 2017 so whenever
someone steps in with an incredibly
limited understanding of science or of
what we're,
what we're dealing with in terms of the
universe itself and says,
Whoa,
tide goes in,
the tide goes out.
You can't explain it like you mother
fucker.
They've been explaining the tides
forever.
What are you talking about you?
I think what he actually means is Yukon.
Explain why there is.
Why there is something instead of total
chaos and anarchy.
I think you can get sold credit.
He's a douchebag.
He's,
I think he's pandering.
I think he was just trying to,
I think he knows there's a bunch of old
dummies out there,
crocheting,
you know,
with three teeth listening to his stupid
fucking shit.
I don't think that you can be highly
intelligent and religious.
Yes you can,
but you highly effective at individual
pursuits.
Now when you talk,
when you say highly intelligent,
as soon as soon as someone is religious
in terms of like if you believe in
preposterous notions,
like there's a guy who came back to
life,
he turns water into wine,
he walks on water.
If you believe that you're not
intelligent,
you're just not well,
I don't believe you're intelligent.
I think you are intelligent in
individual disciplines,
but obviously if you believe something
that makes no sense whatsoever,
you believe that someone was magic.
Someone defied physics.
Someone had superpowers.
Someone was a person who could bring
people back to life.
Someone could come back to life
themselves.
There's no evidence.
You believe this on the flimsiest
fucking evidence that wasn't even
written down until 70 or 80 years after
that dude died because Christianity
didn't even so been worse than that
because the old testament is far older
than totally notion of Jesus,
but that's not it.
Hang on,
I,
I do quibble with the idea that this,
that you can't be smart.
Stephen Colbert was one of the smartest,
the word smart.
This is what the problem is like would
define smart,
what you believe.
Stupid Shit.
Are you smart?
You are implying that the reason why
bill o'reilly talks about tide goes in
tide goes out is because he's pandering
to people because he's,
he's a Harvard guy and there's no way
that he would be dumb enough to believe
that no,
I'm,
I'm complying that because I looked at
the way he said it and I know what he
does and I think he's manipulative and I
think what he's doing is playing to his
base.
I think there's a lot of people out
there that want to see some smug liberal
atheist get taken down a notch and bill
just the guy to do it and talk over him
and he's a big giant guys.
You can yell and get all aggressive.
We went on,
I don't understand is like steven called
Bay is obviously a very smart guy.
He's a Catholic.
Andrew Sullivan.
I know if you know him,
the blogger a,
he's a friend of Sam Harris's like he's
a Christian and good luck.
These people find ways of
compartmentalizing logic I guess.
So like as you say,
they believe in something that is
totally crazy.
I mean the idea that you can say a
certain number of Latin words over a
over a cracker and it'll turn bodily
into the flesh of someone who existed
2000 years ago.
It's crazy magic talk.
Well,
it's crazy talk,
but there are people that are religious
that are extremely intelligent and I
agree with you on this.
Like Jordan Peterson,
who's a brilliant man who is very
religious in the sense that he studies
religion and he believes there's some
fundamental principles that are involved
in religion that are in extra bowl to
the human condition.
And I think he think he thinks they're
important to our society and to civility
and ethics and morals.
I don't think he believes people walked
on water.
I don't think he believed someone came
back from the dead.
I don't think he believes this stupid
shit and I don't think the stupid shit
is even the original story.
The huge problem with religion is
translation over time.
That's one of the biggest problems.
The oldest version of the Bible that we
know of is the Dead Sea Scrolls.
They don't even use that because it's so
fucking crazy.
If you listen to some of the
translations of the Dead Sea Scrolls,
are you read?
Some of it is unbelievably crazy.
I mean it sounds like science fiction
stuff.
And if you go back to that version of
it,
I mean you're talking about stuff that
was written on animal skins.
They used to do they,
they,
they did DNA tests to make sure that the
pieces that they got,
you don't,
you know the whole story behind the Dead
Sea scrolls basically,
but you found them in Cobra on the
scrolls were written on animal skin.
So the,
they were broken up.
So the piece them back together,
they had to do DNA testing to make sure
that the piece
of skin came from the same cow.
And then they had to try to figure out,
okay,
where does all this shit go?
And then how to,
how to put it into place.
But they don't even use that version of
the Bible.
And even if you use the Old Testament,
people say,
well that's the Old Testament.
We don't really,
we go by the New Testament,
which is even more preposterous because
the new testament was written by
Constantine and a bunch of bishops and
men decided what to leave in and what to
take out.
They decided
of course,
and that the whole chunks of it a
contradictory as true as well as the
Bible,
but I mean we're just talking about the
bio for now.
Constantine wasn't even religious.
I mean Constantine wasn't even a
Christian until he died.
He was converted on his fucking death
bed.
I mean he just did it so that he could
unite Rome.
He knew what the fuck he was doing.
He was getting all these people to
operate together.
Does this mean there's No God,
absolutely not.
Does this mean that I have in the
answers that you don't have?
Of course not.
I'm just saying people are full of Shit
and that story sucks.
It's that simple.
Why they may.
I think what we do too much of is
confusing.
Two questions,
one of which is,
is there a god without defining what God
is and the other of which is,
is there any reason to believe in a
particular faith or a particular
denomination to be a Christian or a
Muslim or a Jew or whatever
done in further than that people don't
know.
And anyone who says they know that's not
telling the truth.
Yeah.
We're not talking about,
well,
we do know that carbon comes from stars
when they explode.
Yeah.
Well that can be scientifically
explained and proven.
We're not talking about that.
We're talking about,
do you know whether or not Jesus was a
man who came back from the dead and turn
water into what you do not know?
One
it is.
I know with as much certainty that he
didn't do that.
I don't know anything about the past.
But you don't hear.
You honestly don't.
You don't.
Well,
how do,
how do you know what Napoleon did?
You don't write well,
we know historical records.
We know the stories of people from back
then,
but the idea that
this one guy did things that no human
being could ever do today.
Yeah.
Defied logic,
physics,
the laws of nature,
the laws of life and death,
all the different reality.
The reality is that we accept today in
terms of what's provable,
what we know about biological life.
All that stuff was violated by this one
guy.
Yup.
Could have happened.
They could have,
it could have in the same way.
I'm like close might not have happened.
No.
It's way less likely than that.
You reckon it's more likely that Jesus
was divine?
No.
The opposite.
It's way more likely to called the
Holocaust didn't happen then that Jesus
did all of that shit and I think the
Holocaust is 100% real.
He sounds like me too.
I mean that's,
that's kind of my point.
There is a religious people put an undue
burden on on nonreligious people by
saying,
look,
who's to say?
I say there's a God.
You say there's not a god,
it's a 50 50 toss up.
I'm just going to believe in Christian.
I've heard call bear say this to Bill
Maher on his show.
Look,
I'm a Christian.
I've got nothing to lose.
If I turn out to be right
and Christianity is true,
whoop de do I get to go to heaven?
If I,
if it turns out that Christianity is
wrong,
then I just die.
But at least you know,
give it a chance.
This is Pascal's wager,
right?
This is this idea that you might as well
be religious because hey,
if it's true,
you've got an attorney of goodness,
but here's the thing and you avoid hell
fire.
Yeah.
Can't be true because no one knows like
no one has died and giving you the debt.
No one's died with a VCR or you know,
a vhs tape recorder and comeback with a
knock here,
put this in the machine and play it.
This is heaven.
I've shown you,
but it's not even a 50 50 shot is what
I'm saying.
It's not like black.
Bertrand Russell kind of demolished this
idea with his teapot analogy where he
said like,
okay,
I'm going to claim that there's a teapot
circling in orbit between the Earth and
the moon,
and now if you deny that,
then hey,
it's just a 50 50 shot.
Maybe it's there.
Maybe it's not there.
Who's to say,
obviously you would say,
no,
I think it's not there because if
there's no evidence that it's there,
I'm not going to just going to believe
you because you say it.
And similarly if you say,
oh,
this guy,
Jesus,
2000 years ago,
he turned water into wine.
He walked on water and then he was the
son of God and that God requires you to
believe on him.
Otherwise you're going to go to hell
forever and you say,
why should I believe that?
And they can't turn around and say,
hey,
it's a 50 50 shot.
It's not a 50 50 shot.
There are good reasons for believing
things and bad reasons for believing
things and religion almost always only
offered bad reasons for believing in it.
Well,
as soon as you start talking numbers,
percentages and stuff,
like you're just making those numbers
up,
right?
50 50 where are you coming up with that?
How about a 50 50 shot?
This is vegas odds.
Like what is this little group?
A lot of religious people.
It doesn't mean,
here's the thing.
If people are listening to your getting
fucking pissed,
it doesn't mean there's not a higher
power.
It doesn't mean it's not an order to
this university signs that it's super
likely that if there is something that's
unbelievably powerful and there's some
law that keeps the universe together and
some force of good that's trying to
guide us in this.
There's some,
you know there's some beautiful
inclinations towards that direction.
What I'm saying is I guarantee you that
the people who lived 2000 years ago who
wrote this shit down on leather with you
know,
ink that they met at a plant,
they didn't have all the data.
They just didn't know.
They just didn't,
they didn't know July theory of disease.
I mean they didn't even know that the
Earth's spinning around the sun.
He showed the people who understood the
most about the cosmos or some shit
today.
I mean the reason why they didn't want
any pork is because they figured out
trick analysis.
They're like,
oh listen,
if you need these fucking pigs,
ma'am,
kimber getting sick left and really got
to stop doing that.
As for those things that crawl off on
the bottom of the ocean.
Yeah.
Give me any of that shit.
Exactly.
Well the got hooked up with red tide.
They're like,
look,
yeah,
we're dying.
We've got to stop eating shell fish.
And there's a lot of like real logic to
the Wa the the reasons why they had laws
and it makes,
makes sense.
But the real issue again is the
translation.
It was that the ancient Hebrew
version of the Bible,
ancient Hebrew,
the words also double as numbers.
Like do you know that letters or numbers
in ancient Hebrew,
right.
Their alphabet,
they don't have numbers.
So the letter a is also the number one.
So words have numerical value,
like the word God and the word love,
they have the same numerical value.
All that was lost in translation when
you translated to Latin,
Greek,
eventually English,
all that Shit was lost.
Like it's the,
the ancient Hebrew version of it.
Like if you ever read like some really
goofy translation of English,
Japanese.
Yeah.
And you're like,
what in the fuck are they saying?
Or if you translated English into a
foreign language and then translate it
back from that foreign language into
English,
if it comes jibberish.
Well,
one of the things I love about instagram
is it has a translation thing that I use
a lot of times that follow out of
Russian fighters.
There's a lot of a Russian MMA fighters
and I follow their pages and I'll go,
okay,
let's hit the translate and now hit
translate.
I'm like,
Jesus,
it seems especially hard for some
reason.
It's got to lead.
We had pronouns and things are always
saying good.
This is the best fight.
The well,
it's also like their language looks
different.
Yeah,
no,
it's totally in cyrillic.
If you had the,
uh,
the claim that the 72 virgins in the
Koran or actually 72 raisins,
no,
but you know what?
That wood is almost the same between
reason and virgin.
No,
the expression 72 is like a fuck load.
That's what it means.
It doesn't mean 72 virgins,
but it means like there'll be 72 and
you're like,
wow,
that's,
that's enough.
That's enough.
We're good.
I would not need more than 72 virgins or
raisins.
It's to help me happy bringing them to
life.
It's probably not even the number 72
it's just like our translation from
Arabic to English to screws it up and
then someone probably came up with this
numerical value a long time ago and they
stuck with 72 so I believe in science,
paypal.
So talking about bill o'reilly,
do you think he should have been fired?
I don't know what he did and I know I
don't know what he didn't do.
You know?
I don't know.
I know he's definitely done some gross
shit in the past.
Like there's the audio of him calling
that check and say he's going to take a
loofa sponge Loofah,
big,
big olive bill with his luther in the
shower.
I don't know.
You know,
who knows?
I would imagine whenever you hear a
story about a guy like that,
that's,
some of it is probably fabricated.
I know.
I just don't imagine that all the people
that say things about him or all telling
the 100% truth,
I wouldn't matter.
Imagine that would be true because
people are just not like,
once it gets beyond a few paypal,
then you think that the preponderance of
evidence is that they're probably,
yeah,
I guess you can't say they're all
telling the truth,
but it's hard to take their word for it.
No,
you don't.
You definitely don't.
If they're a six,
seven,
eight people,
definitely stories.
You definitely have to go.
Hmm.
But you don't have to take all their
word for it because first of all,
you don't know those people.
You'd have to know those people.
You'd have to really know if they were
honest.
You'd have to really be there.
You got to to know what really is so
fucking hard man.
Because first of all,
people,
not only are they full of shit,
but their memory sucks.
People's memories.
Like if you,
I'm sure you've had a conversation with
someone about something that happened
that you witnessed as well and you both
have totally different memories of
memories that terrible.
But I've come to accept that though for
myself over the last few years,
like I used to like clean the memories
and then try to argue them.
But I think it's been scientifically
proven that the human memory is one of
the worst pieces of evidence that you
could ever call upon.
Yeah.
The justice system is dining to de
prioritize it as well as it should do.
Because in the past,
like I witnessed,
you know,
accounts in courtrooms have been very
highly prioritized.
Like they'd been very highly valued and
prized by prosecutors.
Wow.
Well,
I mean this person points out the WHO
and the,
you know,
do you see that person sitting in the
courtroom today,
madam?
And she points their finger and well,
it's a slam dunk.
Of course that was the perpetrator.
Now we realize people are memories all
the terrible and wrong all the time.
We're really susceptible to suggestion
and influence and all that sort of
stuff.
But I think you kind of remember whether
or not your boss who's a television star
put his hand up your skirt.
Very likely,
probably.
But there's also someone who could be
seriously deceptive and very ambitious
and realizes that bill o'reilly's kind
of a Twat and this is what I'm going to
do.
I'm going to get close to this old cut
and I'm going to get this guy to get
creepy with me.
And then I'm an exaggerate what he did
and I'm going to profit off of it.
Yeah,
I mean,
do you,
you don't understand that they've paid
fucking millions of dollars to people.
So there's a real industry and getting
bill o'reilly to get creepy with you.
Like I was a chick,
like,
especially if I was like a really
unscrupulous chick,
he tied my knee.
That's half a million.
He wants to confide.
That's a million and a half.
This guy's a Douche bag,
but this is what I'm gonna do.
I'm just going to like kind of give him
like a semi green light,
you know,
just a little bit.
I take it back a little bit,
take it back.
And the problem is though,
that this kind of skepticism towards
women's stories about sexual assault
has,
is what has pr permitted?
People like him to get away with it for
decades and centuries.
Right?
Like it doesn't agree with you.
I take your point that it's hot
happening.
You know,
it's just a,
he said,
she said,
I don't think that's what I think power
has gotten,
allowed them to get away with it.
I think fear and power,
the fear of this powerful man,
I think that has been the doesn't work.
You're not being believed part of that.
Maybe I think the repercussions that
he's going to ruin your career,
that he's going to,
that he has influence.
And also that if you just play ball,
you'll get something from it.
You know?
I mean,
I'm not,
especially,
I'm not talking about an individual
person and saying this individual person
not telling the truth.
What I'm doing is just making
hypothetical's.
I'm just saying if I was a check and I
was,
uh,
an unscrupulous sort of social climber
and we all know that they exist,
and I was the type of person that really
wanted to make it in this business,
and I was like,
look,
I'm working for an asshole and I already
know this five chicks we got paid.
They've already paid out 13 million
bucks.
I'm going to,
I'm going to and move in on this.
I'm interested that that route that
turned on him.
Then Rupert Murdoch turned on him and
kicked him out when he's still making a
ton of money.
He's still the number one cable show.
Right?
Or he was,
well,
maybe Tucker Carlson had a meeting with
him,
pulled him aside.
They listen.
Fuck God.
That tide comes in and out.
Jesus fucking
speaking of someone who will say
whatever they think their audience wants
them to say,
Taka.
That's,
he got right there with his stupid old
bow tie.
He doesn't have a bow.
Tiny one.
It's no,
he got rid of it soon.
It's a straight time.
Yeah.
Both ties to gay.
Exactly.
Don't be associated with that.
Or clowns or you know,
someone who's got like a camera in it.
It's,
I'm amazed that he's had his renaissance
taka like he was there was that classic
John Stewart moment when he used to host
crossfire.
Chuck Tucker Carlson and John went on,
he was like,
you're a grown man wearing a bow tie,
stop hurting America.
The Johnston in that regard where he was
funny on his show when he was doing a
scripted monologue and talking to people
who was gracious but did view,
if he came on your show and he had an
issue with you,
you would find out how fucking smart and
mean he could really go after you.
Absolutely.
Which is,
which is good cause I mean Taco.
Yeah.
Would it be to think about whether or
not bill o'reilly believes what he
believes?
I don't think tuck a nose.
Like taco has this constant faith.
He has this have,
you know,
if you're listening to audio podcasts,
you can see my face,
but it's kind of furrowed brow and like
mouth breathing,
kind of like,
you know,
he,
he plays the role of like the bemused
clown who doesn't know who's just,
I'm just a common man from mine,
just middle America.
I don't understand what you're talking
about.
And he's like very,
very,
very riding the fence,
very kind of riding the fence.
Very like never quite having an,
I'm just missed a common sense.
Like I'm just saying it like I see it
anyway.
I don't know.
I would assume that a lot of these women
were telling the truth.
No one.
I'm not,
I'm definitely not saying that they
weren't telling the truth.
What I'm saying is,
I don't know.
I don't know what happened or what
didn't happen.
I don't know whether he should be fired
or shouldn't be fired.
You mean?
Uh,
I think he feels that he fills a niche.
Right.
And if it's my company and you have to
worry about this guy representing you.
Oh,
okay.
I see.
Where you wouldn't want that guy
representing you because he's
problematic and people think he's a
creep.
But he could just go do his own shit.
Like Glenn Beck,
he little Horn antic of course he wish
or something and he's not going to go
away quietly.
I mean it's an interesting,
it's an interesting question about what
happens to the right wing media now.
Cause if Roger ailes is no longer at Fox
News and Bill O'reilly is no longer at
Fox News for the same reason,
for the same reason,
but exactly both guys the same.
The plays into the same narrative
doesn't let of dirty old white guy.
Just a fuck fest going on over there at
Fox News may him just young women.
It's like an old,
like an old porky's movie or like one of
those 1970s national lampoon films with
women with their tits hanging,
hanging out.
People are to the dorm tweeten and
Hannity now your next handed it.
Yeah,
exactly.
You're going after him now and
Breitbart's had its dude Steve Bannon
sideline in the White House.
So if he can't get along with trump
anymore,
is that true?
I don't know.
I don't,
I'm not friends with him.
I love rumors.
I don't call him up.
Hey Steve.
Hey stevie,
Stevie Bay.
How you doing?
How are you doing with that?
With Donnie these days?
How are you guys still close?
Jared is running the show now.
That's right.
And I think he had to make a decision
and he kind of sideline to the,
the white nationalists a bit.
Any kind of empowered the old school
Republican orthodoxy.
Gee,
you'd be pissed if you were a trump
voter,
wouldn't you?
Did have a Jew running shit.
Well not just to have a job.
Doesn't help.
Joe's doesn't help.
But no,
I just mean like so much of what he sort
of ran on was like,
it's going to be different.
It's not going to be the same old
politics and now you know we're going to
repeal obamacare.
Well that didn't work out.
That's just going to be tax co.
Now he bombed Syria where you weren't
supposed to be bombing people.
I thought we were going to get out of
all these foreign wars and shit.
Don't care like that
many people,
they,
they have this cognitive dissonance that
they have in addressing his actions as
so they're,
they're the support of him.
They're so happy that they won.
They would,
they would never want to take away their
victory.
Like the people that are happy that
trump is in office are so happy that he
won and they won with him.
That any little thing that happens,
they just come up with some sort of a
way to rational
some of them do.
Some of them do.
I start a story the other day about a,
about a county in Pennsylvania or
something which is,
uh,
which had voted for Obama twice and then
voted for trump because they thought
they were going to get changed and
they're all just like,
well,
he just seems like a regular Republican.
He's going to try to attack cut taxes
for the rich and go,
go to war with foreign countries,
isn't from what this is and what we
bargained for.
But it'll be interesting to see whether
or not they flip back and four years.
I take your point that they're just
really happy that hillary is not the
president.
There's a lot of people that are really
happy.
She's not the president.
I think bill's the biggest,
I think bill's super happy.
It's like fine.
I didn't want to have to go back.
I don't know.
There was a law.
The tail in that house.
He gets plenty of tail.
Yeah.
Betty downside side.
Did you see all that Sheila Riley
political system in the wikileaks memos
about the Commonwealth.
What was talking about him banging
hookers on the side was like talking
about how bills at home banging bimbos
and there was some thing about me,
Colin Powell is just fucking blitz it in
emails.
They talk shit like just like regular
people.
Yeah.
Don't put it in an email very well and
we learned nothing.
Don't send it to fucking anybody who's
got an insecure server.
No.
Well just don't write it down at all and
not even get kind of rarely talk now
anyway.
Cause that means that you're going to be
spied.
Yeah.
How are we going to have a private
conversations to just to just pull shit
on people just let it fly.
This like what we've said here,
cause usually have been in a,
in a private email.
Yup that's right.
Questioning whether or not bill
o'reilly's intelligent or whether or not
he really believes that or whether or
not in a religious people are actually
intelligent,
which I f you know clearly there there's
a lot of religious people that are
intelligent and I mean part of the
problem is that people give too much of
a crap about things that people have
said in the past.
I mean we've spoken about this before in
relation to political correctness or
something or like using the wrong
language.
I think as more and more of what we say
gets intercepted or at least in
susceptible in emails and also in phone
calls and so on and we're being spied on
all the time and things can be leaked
and things can be hacked.
People are just going to have to chill
the fuck out a little bit about people's
past.
Otherwise we're only going to end up
with the most boring anodyne and people
in positions of power because it's only
going to be people who've always watched
exactly what they say,
who are able to,
who have never kind of triggered a trip
wire and who have never gotten people
angry and just sense trumps the big
victory for that.
That's right.
You see what I said after trump was
elected that political correct.
It's just took a missile to the Dick.
Absolutely.
This is just,
it just shows you,
you could be out there and grabbing
pussies talking crap fucking people,
man.
It's okay.
Like it's,
it's not,
it's the world has changed in that
regard and part of the,
I mean part of the problem there is that
the things that he,
some of the things that he says really I
ad like,
I don't think that it's appropriate to
be to,
to talk about women the way that he
talks about women.
I don't think it's appropriate.
Basically.
Basically the problem with that is he's
talking to a dude and trying to make
them laugh.
Yeah.
I mean,
he's having a private conversation with
a guy and he's doing what he called
locker room talk.
Guys Talk Shit.
And they say things they don't really
mean and he's,
what he said was,
and I'm not,
I'm not an apologist,
just let me get this out of the way.
What he said was,
you can just grab them by the Pussy.
They let you,
you can do anything that you want when
you were a big celebrity.
He just grabbed him by the pussy.
Like what he's saying is not,
I grab women by the Pussy and sexually
assault them.
Well,
he's just being totally outrageous.
It's like a punchline for a joke.
He's exaggerating the reality of the
situation.
He's saying he's so famous saying,
when you're as famous as me,
you can do anything.
You can grab them by the pussy thing.
He's trying that you,
he's saying they let you meaning
implying consent.
Right.
And I say he's not talking about sexual
assault.
What's,
so when people were saying,
you know,
he's doing sexual assault.
No,
he's talking about girls that are in
thrawled with the fact that they're
around.
This guy was his fucking name on
skyscrapers and he flies around with a
jet with his name on it.
And if you're that type of woman and
there are that look,
there's that type of men.
There's that type of women were not,
it does not a gross generalization about
men or women but guaranteed your son
some women that when they're in the face
of a guy like Donald Trump,
they react that way and they let him do
anything they want and they love it.
Yeah,
there is that possibility.
There is that possibility.
I also thought that the phrasing of that
term was,
it was kind of funny like yeah they let
you grab them but like how
do you grab it to see exactly like where
do your fingers go?
Like,
well,
when does this some who's doing like,
so what?
It sounded to me like with someone who
is inept sexually,
which by many accounts he is like,
there are lots of accounts of like when
he was married to or dating the most
beautiful people,
he'd be downstairs eating Cheetos,
watching late night news,
cable news while they were upstairs.
Like not believe that will because well
just,
just compare it to whether or not it
comports with what,
what else do you know about him,
which is that he's very image focused
and cares a lot about being thought to
be the best at everything and the most
glamorous and the richest.
So it's,
you would imagine that it would be
consistent with his personality,
that he would want to present a front of
being more of a slayer and more of a
sexual demon than he actually is sexual
bands.
It's a great name for a band.
It's the sites.
So the grab them by the Pussy.
It sort of reminded me a little bit of
the way that 15 year old boys would talk
to each other.
Yeah,
Dude.
Or two
guys say ridiculous things that they
don't mean you get other people to
laugh.
I will,
I will grant you that.
Girls do too.
I mean,
my point about political correctness is
that I don't think trump has is our
best,
uh,
ambassador for the anti political
correctness brigade.
Like,
and part of his rise,
part of the backlash is a backlash
against the,
you know,
we've had so many conversations that we
all know it by now with we're bored of
like people who go,
who absolutely lose their,
you know,
just go crazy because you use the wrong
transgender pronoun or something like
that.
You know,
you say he instead of she or whatever it
is all these times or microaggressions
and stuff like that,
or all of that kind of bullshit,
I think gave rise to an environment in
which people are so frustrated with
political correctness that they
unleashed.
And it was like a pressure cooker
exploding and,
and the trump hair went everywhere and
just trump,
he's the,
yeah,
exactly.
But I don't think it'd be,
you know,
things would have been better if we
hadn't gotten to that place.
And we could all just take a chill pill.
I think we need to learn,
you know,
and I think we need to make mistakes so
that we can learn.
One of the things that's really
unfortunate is that he doesn't tell the
truth and that he's the president and he
shows that you can just not tell the
truth and be the president.
Yeah.
About all kinds of things.
The alternative facts analogy,
you know what I mean?
I'm trying to grapple with this on my
podcast.
Um,
because I think it's,
I think what's,
what's dangerous about trump is that is
not just that he,
he doesn't tell the truth because lots
of people point out,
many politicians don't tell the truth.
It's that he doesn't even care that he's
not telling the truth and he doesn't
behave as if there is such a thing.
Really as truth.
Like the other day he talked about the,
the warships that were heading for the
Korean Peninsula.
Did you see this,
this story?
He said that we've got this aircraft
carrier,
which is going towards Korea.
It was going in the opposite direction
to Australia to not attack Australia.
But do I have a military exercise with
the ozzies and now and then Sean Spicer
got there,
you know the press corps went crazy and
the White House correspondence and Sean
Spicer was like,
well I agree.
He was saying that it had been heading,
it was going to be going to the Korean
Peninsula but it was just do on a DJ.
So he wasn't saying the actual direction
of the aircraft carrier.
He was saying that it was,
he was talking about the overall
strategy of what and like poor old spicy
is out there trying to make trump
statements comport with something with
reality in some way.
But trump is just an explosive like
vomit machine just tweeting out stuff
that doesn't even have to map onto
reality at all.
And he always seems to take pride I
think in the fact that he can say
whatever million people at the
inauguration.
When I started talking the rain stopped
and the sun.
That was pretty good.
Are you working on that show?
No,
I like the impression that needs work.
It needs a little work,
but everyone's got their trump.
But you know what I mean?
He,
he will say things and then almost take,
I feel like he gets his Joel,
he gets his rocks off through the sheer
audacity of being able to say whatever
the hell he wants and just make his
opponents go crazy because they don't
even get to a game of whack a mall then.
Right.
It's like,
well,
you said,
that's true.
So he's acting as a politician for the
first time in his life and he's 70.
So for his entire life he's been this
braggadocious guy who is exaggerated
facts and built up this amazing persona
and exaggerated wealth and he's
obviously very successful but
exaggerates that success.
So like the thing about him winning the
inauguration,
remember that really interesting
exchange that he had with a reporter.
It was young reporter and he was up
there saying,
we won by the largest margin now blah,
just margin in the electoral college.
That's not true.
And he said,
well,
the law just for,
um,
Republican,
a Republican.
And that's also true.
So he said,
George H.
Bush or George Herbert Walker Bush had
much larger margin.
And so he explained to him,
well,
you will agree that we won by
substantial number.
Yeah,
well you are the president.
Thank you.
He was like,
good,
I want tic TAC toe.
Exactly.
It's just,
it's just he's not a politician and
that's what people like about them,
you know?
But then he starts doing all these
different things like,
you know,
he's trying to get all these different
plants to reopen and give Americans jobs
and they talk about all the jobs that
have been created and people get excited
and they signed this new thing
yesterday.
Uh,
you know,
American made American sales and try to
encourage people to buy and make
American and,
and then trying to get rid of foreigners
that are sneaking over here and doing
bad things and you know,
the base,
the people that have been clamoring for
that kind of response get very excited.
That's cool.
We'll,
we'll,
we'll deal with the lies.
The lies are fine.
As long as he opens up that Ford plant,
they'll,
the lies are bad.
But look,
he got those,
a Guatemalan terrorists,
drug dealers out of Chicago or whatever.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
And I think the,
I think that there's a feeling that the
whole people who regard themselves as
being custodians of the truth,
a Hoity toity out of touch,
a Leitz who've been shitting the trump
support,
the honest,
hardworking trump supporter for so long
that they deserve to be slapped in their
face with a little bit of untruthful
truthiness.
Sure.
And the judges and the academics people
smarter than you.
Yeah.
People more educated than you and her
spitting social acts and it makes you
humiliated.
I feel dumb.
Yeah.
Like the tide goes in,
the tide goes out to explain it.
It's kind of the same appeal.
Yeah,
that's right.
That's right.
I mean that people do love when liberals
get their comeuppance.
Liberals are really classically
associated with education,
higher education,
bigger vocabularies,
universities.
Funny things about trump that he's the
anti elitist as if the,
as if it is non elite to be a Manhattan
real estate billionaire.
How has that,
how has that,
the anti elite,
you just have to say anything.
When Rowan,
George Bush pretended he was from
fucking Texas.
Lot of people don't realize he's from,
yeah,
he's from the northeast.
He went to Yale.
Yeah.
He all he did in Texas was clear brush
and brush it.
And when people are looking,
Yep.
Camera's rolling.
Absolutely.
Chainsawing down trees.
But it's,
you know,
it's the American way.
You pitch people an image.
I mean it is why they have publicists.
Why,
I mean when you say though that trump is
like he's not a politician and that's
what people like about him.
Yeah.
There's the worry is that when you're
president of the United States,
shit you say has any impact,
right?
It is an important position.
So things,
things that you say can be
misinterpreted by the Koreans or the
Russians.
And there's a,
like if you are the president,
you should know that people in the
executive branch,
such as the president of people in the
White House,
should not disparage people in the
judicial branch.
Right.
Because we have a separation of powers
in the United States of America.
So when he made those comments,
for example about the judiciary,
I think a lot of people think like,
oh,
why is everyone getting their tits on a
tangle about them?
Just because he said that the judge was
a,
you know,
implied that the judge was biased in the
trump university case.
It's because presidential candidates
shouldn't be shitting on judges because
otherwise you end up with situations
like you've got in Venezuela or now in
Turkey,
they've just had this referendum over
the past weekend,
which gave sort of quasi dictatorial
powers to Turkey's president.
Similar things happening in Turkey come
dictatorships essentially,
essentially.
And Russia has done that over the past
10 or 15 years.
And when you listen to people who are
experts in these things,
they always say,
I was just listening to Masha Gessen
who's really into,
you know,
Marcia,
she's a Russian journalist who lives in
the states now.
Fascinating person.
She'd be a good person to get to get on
the show.
And she was saying that the,
the,
the things that,
that nice and to dictators always liked
to do is take,
take down a peg.
People who,
uh,
who,
who rely facts for their living.
So that's journalists.
It's people in the judicial department
and his academics.
So it's judges,
lawyers,
academics and so on.
That's always what you see.
Like the Putin's and again,
the sort of bill o'reilly mindset of
like tide goes in,
tide goes out,
hey,
I'm just a regular guy.
I've got my gut going for me.
I don't need all these fancy book
learning.
It's just you and me.
Let's go to Washington DC and take it
back from those fancy elites making
America great,
right?
And we're going to do it just without
balls.
We're going to grab them by the Pussy
and we're going to drag this country
until the 21st century come.
What may you should run for office,
goddammit,
you're phone out of the country.
That's a stupid rule.
It is America.
Most countries don't have that natural
bone rule.
Most countries,
if you move to that country and you
become a citizen and you live there for
a certain period of time,
sure you can move from the highest
office to run for office and all
offended.
Would you run for office if it was
available?
I think I can run for office.
I think I can't run for president.
Obviously Arnold Schwarzenegger was
governor.
That's correct.
Exactly.
So I hereby announce my candidacy for
the governorship of California.
Joe Rogan even live here.
Dude,
I do now.
When did you move?
I move.
I've kind of oozed between New York and
Los Angeles over the course of the past
four months.
But you're an elite by coastal guy
wearing an accent.
You hear elite by coastal guy and from
another country.
Look,
if I was al Qaeda,
I know.
I would say the way to get somebody to
slip them in is not to get some brown
guy who looks like an Arab,
nosy,
handsome Ozzie.
No one's going to think that the an
Aussie,
especially a gay wasn't exactly.
That's right.
I'm married having twins,
Joe.
Oh my goodness.
How?
How's that work?
It's very complicated.
Do you have somebody that carries them
for you?
Yeah.
Does she live with,
you know?
Oh,
that's weird.
Yeah,
that's extra sheets,
right?
Yeah.
We're trying.
That's how you don't want to be
controlling who's just,
did you choose?
We used,
we used my edges because we used
because,
uh,
um,
cause you're the boss.
I'm the boss.
Exactly.
Are you the dad figured that out yet?
I didn't say we had twins yet.
They're in the oven.
I have a couple that lives down the
street from me.
They're gay couple and I've known them
for probably about 15 years.
And uh,
they have a child and I'm watching this
kid grow.
They went through the whole thing and
they went through the whole thing.
Their kids friends with my kid and has
been since it was a baby and he's about
seven or eight now.
And they went through the whole thing
where they had a surrogate,
the whole deal.
She carries it and then at the end of it
she's like,
I'm keeping this.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
They paid for the kids and that was
Kosha.
She won.
I mean she got it.
Do you know,
because you know that's unusual because
California is usually outside.
It gets not in California,
but you,
it tends to have pretty good,
uh,
pro family surrogacy laws by which I
mean it makes it hard for the,
sorry,
I get to change your mind at the,
at the end we'll they did in 2000 it was
like early 2000 Oh yeah.
That might changed somewhere in do
bloody Australia.
I mean,
let me whine for a moment about how
backward Australia was 10 or 15
years ago when I first started coming to
the states,
I was able to look down my progressive
knows at these fine United States of
America and think of it as being a more
conservative center,
right country.
But now you guys are legalizing pot all
over the joint.
You've got the gay marriage.
Australia still doesn't like a lot of,
I feel like a lot of interesting stuff
is going on in the states,
in on the progressive side of politics
and culture that Australia has just been
too slow to pick up.
So on the,
on the question of surrogacy,
there's this weird like alliance in
Australia that also exist in some
communities here in the states between
essentially extreme feminists and like
right wing Christians to say that women
should not be allowed to take money to b
Sarragut carriers from the Christian
riot.
They say,
you know,
we shouldn't let these fags,
be using women to about an hour to
create life,
God forbid.
And from the feminists it's,
Oh,
we have to protect women from being
manipulated and taking money for having,
for renting their wounds out.
But you want them to have the right to
kill a,
an unborn baby.
No,
no,
no.
It's not that.
It's what you don't want.
It's a medical procedure.
It's not telling you baby,
it's a bundle of cells until it comes to
batch of cells and then all of a sudden
until it gets a social security number.
Yeah,
not real.
So you want a woman to be able to kill
that bunch of cells,
but you don't want her to be able to
bring that bunch of cells into
existence,
then get paid for it.
In Australia.
You can't.
It's against the law to be pet to,
to pay a surrogate to carry your child.
It has to be a favor,
but prostitution's legal.
You guys are just confused.
We were confused.
Nation lost on the wrong side of the
planet.
Well,
you're a tiny land.
You know it's a giant chunk of ground as
big as the United States,
but a tiny group of people,
a bunch of Los Angeles.
That's right.
We're the same population as well.
Bit bigger than greater Los Angeles.
You're not counting Mexicans.
They don't know skins are over here.
They just don't.
They do and they do a census anyway.
Most people say,
most people say la is 18 or 19 million.
Australia is 24 but who's counting?
Listen,
it's hop greater.
La is connected to Orange County is
connected to the inland empire is can.
It's not like it stops,
you know like when you still chatting
Joe,
I'm with you.
Okay.
We agree about the lodge list of Los
Angeles County.
Your country is not as big as ours.
I'm just saying,
but it's the same size.
The same size.
Yeah.
If you,
if you exclude Alaska then it's the same
size as the United States.
You take ewas you know the United
States.
Exactly.
So it's got basically half the
population in California.
Yeah.
You have a tiny little spot.
I know it's in terms of human beings,
so we have some tiny,
where have you been to New Zealand yet?
No,
I heard it's awesome.
it's great.
I mean that is a small place.
It's gorgeous.
Beautiful.
I'm half
New Zealand.
Yeah.
How do you know like aren't on the same
shit he has basically.
It's like so half Canadian California
saying they're from Nevada.
Like do you even know?
Well it is a different country.
Georgia.
That one right?
It's another island.
Yup.
Go to fly over there.
You have a row to row 1200 miles.
Can you row 1200 miles?
Fuck yeah.
Polynesians can like that's true.
They can and did,
they did.
So they got to Hawaii.
Tanga used to control basically all of
the South Pacific.
They were,
they,
they were absolutely bad.
Atses see the size of those fucking
people.
Yeah.
They big the giant.
They have giant bones.
They,
how do they fit in the canoe?
They build big canoes,
Bro.
Very big canoes and canoe full of toxins
can,
if I pull a pantry,
350 pound tongue is big humans,
they probably really big back then too.
Even when people weren't as big,
they were probably bigger.
I think they've always been bigger.
Hello?
Americans are giving them a run for
their money right now.
And a stand I was,
he's starting to get fat.
Well it's food,
foods,
the high protein count.
I mean you've seen it in Japan as well.
You know,
people are just larger,
you know,
they're eating more food and,
and we're eating more sugar that too.
Well there's also the,
I had Gary Tobbs on who wrote that book
the case against sugar.
And one of the things that he was
saying,
it was really kind of interesting is
that when you feed people a higher sugar
diet,
the higher insulin count is actually
making larger people.
So he's talking about his kids and that
like you almost like wants to feed his
kids more sugar to make,
you know,
bigger athletes.
And I'm like,
that's crazy.
So big or not in terms of having more
body fat,
larger,
larger humans,
larger human,
like taller as well.
Bigger.
Yeah,
just bigger people.
Yeah.
There's some evidence that points to the
high sugar diet as well as the high
protein diet are contributing factors to
people being larger.
Could I just ate a lot of Donna's not
now.
Not too long to miss the budge.
Yeah.
How old would I had to be when I want to
be like a little kid?
I think you have to be like,
I love you got to have a couple of twins
fish out a fuck or sugar stuff.
Their faces full of chocolate.
Best News I've heard all day.
You just kind of get like to the wall of
diabetes and pull back.
Oh,
this'll be great,
by the way.
Always want to get real clear.
I don't know what the fuck I'm talking
about,
so don't go feed your kids down at,
and I don't even remember exactly what
Gary Topp said.
Jamie's Colin's a liability of being Joe
Rogan story.
The other day I showed you.
This is after the show.
Let's get [inaudible] spilling onto
Wisconsin highway.
We're headed for cattle feed.
Oh yeah,
they do do that.
They give it the cows candy.
Yeah.
That's just to fatten them up the
cheaper.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They do do that.
They feed cows candy to make them
fatter.
They've done,
they also feed them antibiotics just to,
just to make them bigger,
just to make them grow faster.
Oh actually the reason why they feed
them antibiotics is their bodies reject
the grain there,
feed them corn and things like that and
they develop abscesses and their books
to affections to fall.
Apparently it's for that reason.
And also it just has this side,
the byproducts that it makes them grow
faster.
Antibiotics,
antibiotics.
Yup.
Oh weird.
Yeah.
It's bizarre.
I don't try to take those things
anymore.
I know was I really need them.
Surgery when you get surgery should take
it.
Yeah,
that's right.
But you should be real careful about
taking them for like little colds.
I think I'm just going to take a z pack.
Yup.
Yeah.
You're going to make a super virus.
You fuck.
That's right.
And if you do,
then make sure that you take probiotics
and shit.
Eat a lot of Kimchi and sauerkraut and
all that stuff.
Here you go buddy.
Yeah,
I know.
I've been listening to Joe Rogan.
You know where I got that?
That inflammation problems.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's right.
She's,
she's good value isn't she?
She's a genius.
Yeah.
Um,
she's making a person,
I wonder if she's going to feed it
sugar.
How old?
How long?
How far along was it?
Third Person.
Third Trimester.
Okay.
Yeah.
I needed to learn all that shit.
I'm not good with like the numbers of
human physiology.
I didn't know what a trimester was.
It's difficult.
You're a guy cause I don't have a slide.
I don't have cycles.
I don't have the cycles of the men
steroid administration and the moon and
the tide comes in and the tide goes out
and the blood comes in,
into the band comes out.
It's impossible to explain and the baby
comes out.
Sweet baby.
Jesus is the only explanation.
Joe.
So explain to me what the law is right
now in Australia.
Like,
can you hire a surrogate or is it being
pushed back?
Well that's a state by state thing cause
the strategy of results.
So a federation like the United States,
which he used to be a bunch of separate
colonies.
So it used to be a bunch of,
you know,
penal colonies that Britain basically
after the American revolution,
Britain had no where to send its
criminals.
And it was a very,
very tough law and order states in the
17 hundreds in the UK.
Like if you,
it was three strikes and you're out.
That wasn't even in the start of it.
And it was incredible inequality.
There was no welfare obviously and no
food stamps and shit like that.
So people who were starving would steal
a loaf of bread and you do that twice
and they'd be like,
all right,
we're going to send you to the moon,
which is essentially a strategy.
Right?
So they went and found,
they discovered this great southern land
that had been rumored about and had been
kind of sketched on the edges by some of
the explorers from the Netherlands and
from France so far.
And they sent out captain cook to settle
it basically.
So they would have a place for creative
criminals to examine a huge,
vast sunburnt land for criminals to to
run free.
And now that they could no longer use
United States any of those colonies.
It's one of the most beautiful places in
the world and some of the nicest people
in the world lived there like they
fucked up.
They made it a better place than ain't
sent the criminals and the criminals.
Like,
you know what our problem was?
We were living in fucking England.
It never,
it's never sunny.
People are constantly bars or a thousand
years old.
Jesus Christ,
I feel so good.
I'm going to be a criminal anymore.
I'm going to go south and Oh,
oh please judge.
Don't send me to the other side of the
world to a tropical paradise when I
could be living here in London where
it's dirty and disease written and it's
rainy and drizzly and gray all the time.
But isn't it of bid?
How there's a balance to everything.
Cause when you go to Australia,
everything can fucking kill you.
Yeah,
that's true.
Part of the problem is,
but goddamn box,
jelly,
fish,
Brown spiders and Brown snakes and all
these different things.
It can fuck you up,
but you don't feel afraid of that when
you're in Australia.
Do you you get over that and 24 hours?
No,
not me.
I'm a POC.
Terrified of bugs and snakes and shit.
Cause I'm the,
I mean you do to typically that you're
much more likely to be killed in it on
the freeway here in la or by someone
shooting you in the states than you are
by appspider.
Biden say bless you.
Go near the spiders and the snakes,
which is what I would do.
Let me know the problem with me,
I don't approach them.
We'll have a buddy of mine,
my friend Adam Green tree was a big bow
hunter in Australia.
Yep.
So He's trying to get me to go hang out
with them and I'm always like,
hey,
yeah,
I'll do that.
And then they send me a picture of some
fucking spider that a vicious poisonous
spider eating a vicious poisonous snake.
The fuck do you live,
man,
this is insane.
Crocodiles everywhere.
They went hunting and they didn't bring
any water and they just figured they
would find water and they use water
purification systems and cleaned it out.
So they're drinking buffalo piss water
cause he's water buffaloes.
They piss in this water and then you
have these filter pumps and you pump out
all the toxins but it still tastes like
piss because you're essentially drinking
purified pests and um,
they were cooling off in this water and
they,
they didn't realize that there's
crocodiles in the area,
Shit.
So they easily could've got checked by a
crocodile crocodile slide into that
water and they just sit and wait.
But it's one of those things that you
just led about as a kid.
It's a bit like,
I mean people like,
it's like when you talk to Canadians
about the risk of bears and they just
sort of laugh it off because you learn
about how,
or like people from Finland about
falling through the ice on a frozen
lake.
These are just things that you learn
about when you're a kid and you just
take it for granted.
I know where they will be.
Crocodiles 99% of the time and I don't
go to those places and I certainly
don't.
Well sure,
yeah,
exactly.
Get ready.
Farmer will be be with a group of
people.
I mean in terms of the,
in terms of like how good it was for
convicts.
I mean people came out to Australia for
um,
you know,
Brits came out to Australia even if they
weren't criminals just because they
wanted a new,
like a new adventure.
I mean,
my,
and some of the states of Australia
actually we're free settler colonies
like South Australia,
which is one of the states was never a
convict,
a penal colony.
And in fact,
when Australia became a country in 1901,
they w in the constitutional conventions
in the eighties and nineties,
which,
which created a country out of all of
these previously separate colonies,
New Zealand within negotiations to be
part of that country as well.
And Western Australia,
which is the western half of the
continent was going to be a separate
country.
And the eastern half,
the eastern states of Australia and New
Zealand could have been a single
country.
And then at the last minute and New
Zealand jumped out in Western Australia,
jumped in and now you've got two
different countries.
But Anyway,
oh this massive huntsman spider in
Australia is what?
Yeah,
but huntsman's aren't,
they don't hurt you.
It gives a fuck.
Kill Them.
When you get those,
you get those spiders,
spiders inside even in Sydney,
but then on size harmful God damn giant
crab.
That's huge.
It's on a broom.
So it's not,
you can tell that it's big enough to
scare the fuck out of you.
If it was in your underwear,
you die.
Yeah.
You know New Zealand is a place that's
really fascinating because they brought
over all these wild game animals from
other countries to turn it into a
paradise.
And I think they did in the 17 hundreds
of the 1800 it would have been insane.
Hundreds cause I think it was only
settled by white people in the 17
hundreds yeah.
And now they're the run rampant around
the island cause there's no predators.
So they have these hordes of red stags
from Europe.
They're wandering around New Zealand.
We spoke last time about the,
about the attempt that New Zealand is
doing to basically eradicate all of its
predators,
all of its invasive predators who that
have come from abroad like New Zealand
because it was the last country to be
settled by white people by White Farnaz
that is who brought,
you know,
foxes and rabbits and whatever nasty
things.
I always forget exactly what called cats
too.
I can't even remember what,
every time I say this publicly,
someone from New Zealand,
he was like,
actually we don't have Fox News on
twitter,
so I definitely do in Australia caddy
and have the same issue.
You have the same issue in Australia.
Totally,
totally.
But in Australia it's too far gone.
There's no way that you would be able to
actually eradicate them.
Whereas in New Zealand there is like it
is,
it is a New Zealand,
his patriotic duty to murder as many
little mammals as they can because those
little mammals eat the night of birds
and eat all the native wildlife and
stuff.
So New Zealand is like my cousins over
there.
They set traps out in their yard and
every morning they go down like they
with bloodied hands pulling out the
caucus is of animals that they've killed
and they're like,
oh yeah,
this good job.
Good for you.
Well Australia a bit bow hunting
magazines show people holding cats up
like domestic cat.
I hold them and you gotta like an Arrow
through the heart.
And there was a guy recently who got
attacked on instagram because he's an
Australian bow hunter and he's out bow
hunting and he killed this cat and all
these people were freaking out.
That was some of these pat you piece of
shit.
And they're like,
actually you don't understand this is
the ruining the ground nesting birds,
all these different animals that live in
the ground,
that mean to the animals that have never
had a Predator to like that and they're
missed or do just getting destroyed.
They're a menace that as cats they get
out.
Yeah,
it's hopeless
on the question of,
isn't that beautiful,
nice shirt.
Reagan nose blow right there and you've
got a cold or is it just,
uh,
I left someone off fighting,
went off.
Don't take antibiotics and you can say,
I'm,
I'm almost out of it.
But I worked out today pretty hard.
Some fucking crazy,
bro.
What'd you do?
Lifting weights.
Kettle kettlebells.
You know,
I do.
Um,
what was I gonna say about Australian
animals too?
I forgot.
Uh,
it's,
uh,
it's amazing that there is imbalanced.
Oh,
that's what it was.
The,
you're a Tasmanian tiger,
which was an animal that was extinct.
Yeah.
Apparently there's a bunch of sightings
this thing and they're pretty sure that
it might actually still be alive.
I've read that.
I hope so.
It'd be,
there's,
there's this really depressing footage.
You can say it online of the,
uh,
of the,
the last day of a Tasmanian tiger eye in
a zoo,
uh,
just pacing back and forth and back and
forth,
wiped it out completely.
1930s.
Right,
exactly.
Footage it really early.
I mean,
they basically destroyed everything in
Tasmania.
They wiped out the,
the night of aboriginal through and
wiped out the paypal.
They wiped out.
I mean,
it was like,
you know,
Haley,
oh,
the British empire.
Let's make things better by killing.
Everything is interesting.
Do you guys change the British accent?
Just a little.
Whereas like most Americans can't tell
where the fuck you're from.
How do you not tell?
Honestly,
it's really,
it's the same thing.
It's obviously not in the,
it's been half up.
You're not from here.
I can tell the difference between
Canadian and American.
Well that's easy.
Done easy.
Cause you were American as soon as you
hear a boat.
Exactly.
But then they're nicer.
I mean actually that is less different
than the difference between British and
Australian.
Consider a place.
Can you tell us what's going on in New
Zealand and Arizona accent and a
California accent?
Don't know.
Neither one have one.
It was a trick question.
Come on with an Arizona accident.
What the fuck is in Arizona accent?
Yeah.
Now the only American accent so that I
can easily pick apart from the big city
ones.
Cause you can tell Boston,
you can tell in New York he can,
uh,
that's a bet.
That's basically it is the south.
See there's that midwestern thing where
like Minnesota and Wisconsin and have
that all that cane,
da Fargo,
that sort of Fargo.
We accent.
Uh,
and then you've got the,
yeah,
the west coast thing and then the,
but that Fargo thing is similar to
Canadian as well.
A little bit.
It gets a little bit confusing sometimes
when you're a foreigner,
like myself.
Friendly people that live in the cold.
That's right.
Yes.
They have to be like helping each other
out.
Sense of community.
Canadians.
It's sort of like aussies,
you know,
they were also big landmass.
Not very many people.
Mostly in hospital.
Most of them are huddled along one
stretch of land in,
in Canada it's the,
it's the border.
And in Australia it's the coastline.
Yeah.
I think they have less people than
California as well.
Yeah,
they have about the same I think.
I think they have a bit more than
Australia.
I feel like 50 million or something.
Yeah,
exactly.
Um,
I'd moved there.
Those are the two places I'd moved.
By the way,
if I didn't live in America,
like if some shit hit the fan here,
if California,
California slid into the ocean and the
big earthquake or something,
um,
I would either live in Canada or
Australia.
Those are two spots.
Hold Joe.
Are you aware of that?
To be cold on Vancouver?
No,
but it's rainy and cloudy and gray.
Beautiful Green on the three days a
week.
When it's a year,
when it's sunny,
it's beautiful.
People are cool as fuck.
362 days a year.
Horrible.
Don't be a pussy.
Chrisley so what?
Stay inside good strip down gets me
down.
Mr [inaudible] tell you when it is
something
I guess.
I guess I get seasonal affective
disorder because my sister in law is
from Finland and when I go to Finland
and it's gray and doc,
I don't feel good.
You get sad.
I get sad,
I get sad and I actually,
I don't mind the cold called and I'm
under really frigid freezing.
Karl lived in New York for 10 ish years,
depending on how you count it and the
and the winters out there when it's
crisp and bright and blue sky.
I mean you grew up in the north face.
You know what that's like when it's a
nice day.
I don't actually care if it's only five
degrees Fahrenheit,
if it's,
if it's like sunny.
Right.
But I don't like gloom New York and
Boston in particular.
It gets really gloomy in the winter.
I definitely think that affects people.
I definitely used to affect me,
but um,
it's not as bad.
Like Colorado gets super fucking cold,
but it's really sunny and Colorado
doesn't have any of that shit.
It's not,
I agree with you.
It's not necessarily the cold as much as
it is the lack of Sun.
We need clear scars.
That's Ryan's feel better.
Yeah.
That's what I don't like about London
and Amsterdam and said he's like that as
well.
Seattle,
Portland,
Portland Tomorrow Holla,
two shows.
Oh Great.
Nice city.
But again,
fuck you.
Portland's awesome.
How many days of the year does it rain?
289 days of sunshine in Vancouver.
That's what he's a pussy.
Shit.
What is Jamie?
What are you looking up here?
They comp results.
It does say there's 166 days with
measurable precipitations that does a
bat up at the top.
It does because we're rains part of the
day,
but hang on 299 days of sunshine.
That just might mean that at some point
during the day there was a bit of a
glimmer of some,
that's all I need bro.
Just set up a little alarm to go.
I know we're still on a planet.
I knew there's,
or a bubbles.
Good.
Uh,
have you seen about um,
about the election in the cool,
quite a few stories coming out of Europe
this week.
I did a story I did my podcast today
about,
there's the British prime minister just
called a snap election.
Try to reaffirm her mandate for brexit.
And the French had gone to the polls
next week and for the first round of the
presidential election,
which could see the far right leader,
Marine Le Pen Win in France.
And if she does,
she wants to crash out of the euro
currency,
you know,
break,
do frexit brexit crush any France leaves
the EU.
Then that actually is all live.
I like penetration can leave if that
happens.
When would France leave the EU?
I saw that there's massive antifascist
protest this week.
Yeah.
So the way that their electoral system
works is they,
instead of doing it all on one day,
they basically,
whoever can run and get on the ballot,
they,
there's like maybe eight to 12
candidates who are on the ballot next
week.
And then assuming that one person
doesn't get one of them,
doesn't get more than 50% of the vote,
which I almost never do.
That then goes to a second round of
Palette,
which is next month.
And that's the actual presidential
election between the two main
candidates.
And what it looks like is that the far
right leader who is softer than her dad
who founded the far right party was,
but he was like a Holocaust denier and
like serious antisemites and she's just
a,
an anti Muslim like anti-immigration
Nteu sort of like more right wing
version of trump.
Uh,
she will get through in next week's
election,
which means that she's going to wane
her,
I don't know,
the polls say she wasn't,
but the polls didn't say that brexit was
going to happen or that Donald Trump was
gonna win either.
So the question is,
will people stay at home?
Because the person who she's most likely
to be running against is just this kind
of slick,
nice,
handsome,
doesn't really believe in anything.
Not really a politician,
but kind of pragmatic.
I mean maybe that'll work,
I don't know,
but it's a bit of a worry if you care
about the stability of Europe and like
Germany and France not ever being in a
war again for them not to be knitted
together and into the European Union.
I do worry about it.
And then there was the Turkey thing that
we were talking about,
so we've got these three,
these kinds of pieces of jigsaw puzzle
that had been bashing around in my head
over the past few days about like,
will we look back on this period as just
a starting point to something even
bigger?
Like I already think that it's amazing
like that trump is amazing.
Like I mean if two years ago I was on,
when was I first on this show?
Maybe three years ago or something like
that.
You know,
if someone had walked in that door and
said to us,
okay,
in 2017 you are going to be back on the
show,
are you going to be talking to each
other?
And the FBI will be conducting an active
investigation into whether or not the
government of the day conspired with
Putin in Russia to spread misinformation
and illegally hack the emails of the
Democratic Party on,
by the way,
the president is Donald Trump
and we know that the hacking happened.
We know that the Russians hacked,
did hack this and did spread
misinformation.
But the only question is whether the FBI
is trying to figure out whether or not
there was active collaboration with the
government.
What do you think about that?
I mean we would be like,
that's a cartoon.
That's a fucking cartoon story.
That is cray crazy cloud cuckoo land.
And so that's where my head has been at.
But that would have been,
if we did have that conversation,
that would have been before the
nightclub shooting in Paris that have
been before the truck ran over those
people in Nice.
Yup.
Like the,
those are those terrorist attacks that
they have had over in France and in
Germany have scared the fucking shit out
of people and letting all those people
in from Syria with no vetting and
letting a lot of Muslims coming to the
country that may have some real hate in
their heart for this new land that
they've found.
I mean they've got some real issues and
that's when a person who's a fascist who
comes along who's like this anti
immigration,
you know,
comes from a racist background,
super right wing.
That's when those people take hold.
Well this is
what I always say.
I'm actually,
I'm talking to Sam Harris tomorrow on my
podcast and this is something that he
and I talk about a lot,
which is we have to find a new way to
converse about the problem of,
of Islamic jihadism without being so
full of shit.
If we,
if you are,
if you are a globalist and an
international list like I am,
if you basically believe
you're a globalist,
that's a negative thing.
I know I've only started using that term
lately because the old Wright thinks
that globalism is like this Jewish,
you know,
global conspiracy and I love,
I'm trying to take over the world.
I'm open.
I'm an open minded person so I think
what I would define it,
well I would it as being someone who
doesn't like borders and who doesn't
like nationalism and jingoism and
believes that we are all one and should
try to get along.
You don't want to hear Bro.
I hear new world order.
That's what I hear.
This motherfucker's new world order.
I can't hear you if we got him on the
show.
Is that what that,
was that an Alex Jones impression?
It was getting close,
wasn't it?
Alex Jones is a performance artist.
Is that what you're claiming?
You know what,
I ask people on twitter what I should
ask you and overwhelmingly,
overwhelmingly it's all like why does he
legitimize quacks like Alex Jones
creates a false equivalents problem.
Oh No,
no,
no.
Why did he interview so many bad act
actors like Alex Jones?
How many people do I interview?
Like Alex Jones?
First of all,
I don't interview anybody.
I'm not interviewing you,
am I?
Nope.
I'm not an interviewer.
Um,
I suck at that.
I've kind of interviewed Ron miscavige
yesterday.
I talked to people and I record it.
It's it.
I'm not a journalist by any stretch of
the imagination.
Alice Joe has been my friend for 20
years.
He's fucking crazy.
I showed everybody how crazy he wasn't
my podcast by getting them high and
drunk and have them talk about inner
dimensional child molesters.
If you watch that and you think I'm
legitimising Alex Jones and some sort of
way,
then you're just,
you're,
you're just,
you're looking at things in a very
cookie cutter,
wet.
You're deciding that this is what I've
done.
But a lot of people listen to you.
And so I think the criticism that these
people have is like,
people put faith in you and they assume
that if you don't raise a question
against something,
that that means that,
that you tacitly agree with what's being
said and that that'll,
that allows the physicians about Alex.
A lot of,
no,
I didn't listen to the Europe.
We raise questions,
but we were more bullshitting than
anything and having fun and he was
hammered.
I mean,
look,
people got a chance to see them.
They're actually using footage of the
conversation that we had against him and
his custody battle because they're
saying he was in Los Angeles on film
smoking marijuana.
He's a loose cannon and that's,
that's literally being used against
them.
He doesn't give a fuck.
Really?
They asked.
They asked him a question about his kid.
He couldn't remember.
It was op.
Sorry.
I had a large bowl of Chili for lunch
today.
I can't remember.
He's fucking crazy.
He's crazy and he makes ridiculous
amounts of money out stones.
He doesn't give a fuck.
He's a great guy.
I swear to God.
He's just,
he's just got a ridiculous platform and
he's kind of character,
but he's he,
that's who he is,
man.
You think he's a performance artist?
I think there is a part of what he does
that is most certainly theater.
I think anybody who doesn't see that
goes out.
Todd comes in and todd comes out.
That's bad impression.
You got to work on it.
It's almost as bad as my trump
impression.
Fortunately,
I never listened to Ellis Jones,
so I don't actually know what he,
I mean I see clips of him when someone
shares something with me online,
but like life's too short to listen to
Alec's giant.
Just best clips or when he gets mad and
then he apologizes.
I'm a Christian.
I'm sorry.
He comes to someone.
Someone said something about him
recently and he went all,
I never swear.
I never
swearing at 20 years of nurse Warren on
the air,
but this fucking fat like
crazy.
Fucking crazy on this one guy and then
he's,
I'm sorry.
I apologize.
I'm children listening.
This is wrong.
I mean he's fucking,
he's a maniac.
I'm not giving him,
I'm not giving him legitimacy.
He already has a massive platform,
arguably bigger than mine.
What I'm doing is showing you what I see
when I hang out with Alex Jones.
People are like,
why are you friends with Alex Jones?
I'm like,
he's a nice guy.
I like him.
Look,
I have a friend do I argued with for a
fucking hour yesterday,
thinks I'm pretty sure he thinks the
fucking world is flat.
Yeah.
That's another one that I got satellites
is Eddie Bravo.
Yeah.
He thinks satellites aren't real.
He doesn't believe in dinosaurs.
He thinks dinosaurs are bull bullshit.
He doesn't believe in nuclear bombs.
He's out to lunch.
It,
listen,
man,
you can't,
you can't even hold it to the fire.
It's,
it's ridiculous.
I don't understand his thought process,
and again,
I've been friends with him.
As long as I've been friends with Alex
Jones,
I'm awake closer with Eddie,
way closer.
Like Ed.
He's one of my best friends.
He's fucking crazy.
But if you talked to him about
conspiracies,
but if you talk to them about like mma
or he's a jujitsu genius,
I mean,
he's like one of the very best Jujitsu
instructors on the planet earth.
Without a doubt.
I mean,
this is,
comes back again to the like how we can
compartmentalize our minds,
right?
It's like a religious person who
believes in the story of Jesus,
but he's also otherwise super
intelligent.
That's a perfect analogy.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
and you know,
I don't know how people's brains work.
I don't understand.
I,
you know,
I've,
I've tried to study like people's really
irrational thinking and tried it,
but you know what?
I worry more than anything that worried
that it's contagious disease.
I think it is.
I think it is,
and this is why I'm a bit worried about
way we're at culturally at the moment
because I think that concern about
irrationalism being contagious is not
too dissimilar from my concern about a
disrespect for the idea of truth and
falsehood being contagious.
So you know it when I was talking about
the,
the this analyst,
this Russian journalist who was talking
about the ways in which Putin and Chavez
and Atawan in Turkey and the Hungarian
dictator,
what not dictated Hungarian president
who was becoming a quad.
I dictated the way that they kind of use
the muddiness of the whole question of
what's true or false as a way of
throwing sand in the gears of the whole
democratic process and sand in the gears
of people's ability to kind of analyze
the world and figure out what's true and
false and what's important and not
important that if all you're doing every
day is just tweeting out like a stream
of nonsensical bullshit that is neither
true nor false but kind of exists in
like this area of like you are trump's
ego.
Then I actually have found myself
becoming less convinced about reliable
sources of information and myself
becoming more to irrational
ideas.
Like I don't feel as confident anymore.
Like it's easy because there's so much,
you see so much stuff of like I'll tweet
out something that the Washington Post
or the Wall Street Journal or The New
York Times,
uh,
have published,
all of which I regard as being
upstanding publications where I have
faith that the journalists are doing
their best,
not always perfectly,
but doing their best in the long haul to
tell the truth and only report facts and
then people will say,
oh,
fake news,
fake news.
That is the bullshit.
And they'll link to something to Alex
Jones said is if there's kind of a kind
of equivalence between those two things.
And I have to remind myself to an actual
specific thing.
You're just speaking in generality.
People have linked,
people have told me that they believe
there's no difference between the
credibility of Alex Jones and the
credibility of the New York Times,
New York Times talking about the
interdimensional child molesters.
Not yet,
but let's give him time.
Joe.
It's a,
its early days.
It was administration times has fucked
up in the past.
Yeah.
And they,
they have strayed from unbiased
journalism,
which is an issue because as soon as you
start doing that,
as soon as you editorialize the news,
you open yourself up for people who
point out that you editorialize the news
and then point out the fact that you're
biased and they have but hold on,
they have been not that that's an issue.
And I think they realize that they,
that has been used against them.
And I think that's one of the things
that they addressed when they talked
about sort of reinvigorating the idea of
objective journalism.
And they started talking about that
after the uh,
the trump election after he was elected
president.
They talked about this a reinvigoration
and this sort of re re committing
themselves to,
to real hard journalists.
That's right.
I think a lot of people also had done
understand the difference between the
editorial page and like the opinion
pages and the news section is true,
but even the new section has been
biased.
You know,
there,
there have been storms in a couple of
occasions been things we have a blind I
think yeah they have.
But as soon as you just leave open that
potential,
that possibility,
then people go,
oh,
you're a bunch of left wingers.
Like a lot of people think that because
they got the election wrong,
that means that you can't trust Paul's.
He's another way in which in which they,
this kind of insidious idea that nothing
is trustworthy and there's no such thing
as the truth or facts or you'll version
of history is as good as anyone's
version of history.
This is another thing that Lawrence
Krauss was saying on my podcast by the
way,
which is he thinks that there's a link
between the kind of postmodern like
hippie 1960s like philosopher movement
of like,
Hey,
believe whatever you want to man.
Like there is no truth,
right?
Like truth is all salt socially
constructed and like gender is entirely
socially constructed and there was no
such thing as masculinity.
It's all just,
I don't know,
some kind of capitalist story that we've
all been led to believe.
So I like put a flower in your hair and
bust out of it and let your truth be
whatever that you want the truth to be.
He stays a link between that and what
you might think of as being something
opposite,
which is
the hard right kind of outright trumpy
sort of fake news phenomenon because
both of them make the claim that there's
no such thing as the truth essentially.
And your truth is whatever is true for
you.
There were a million people and a dog.
I didn't alteration.
Okay.
The warships were steaming towards North
Korea.
Okay.
Trump said it.
Does it matter?
Terrible.
This is true or not true.
What's,
let's unpack that one step at a time.
Um,
I definitely think that some of the,
as we said before,
some of the reasons why trump became
popular are these ridiculous assertions
that gender has no basis in biology.
That you can be anything you want.
You can be Fox.
Can you know that you can,
you know,
you can identify with being,
I mean there's,
there's people that are trying to figure
out whether or not trans racial is a
thing.
Rachel Dolezal was on CNN and she was
talking about the fact that race is a
social construct is interesting,
wasn't it?
It is interesting because people don't
want to accept that black people get
really mad.
They're getting really mad at her.
They also say the same thing.
Like I mean anytime worth their salt
understands that race is not a genetic
thing,
that this is a cultural construct.
And I mean I find it,
I find her logic sort of hard to flow in
to fault in a way is most sort of social
construct.
It's most certainly more solid than
saying there's no biological basis for
gender.
That's right.
There's more biological basis to six
than there is to,
you know,
there's more sex chromosomal issue.
There's an x,
y chromosome that males have and if a
male decides that he identifies with
being a female,
look,
there's a boy that's running track now
there's a new one,
cause they've had a few of these is the
one who was a girl that was a wrestler
that was taking,
she wanted to be a boy.
So she was taking testosterone and
crushing all these other girls in
wrestling.
She won the state title in Texas,
I think you mean he was a trans,
whatever,
whatever.
But now there's a boy who's not even
taking treatment who decides he
identifies as a girl and he's just
whooping everybody's ass and track cause
he's a fucking boy.
But no,
he's a girl but he's not a boy.
He's not a girl.
We have to find a way to like separate
the psychologic,
the psychology from the physiology,
especially in sports.
Exactly.
100%,
especially in combat sports.
And I,
I took a lot of heat because I was
saying that there was a,
there was a man who was a man for 30
years.
It became a woman and didn't tell people
that he used to be a man for 30 years
and beat the fuck out of two checks
before eventually came out.
And now when,
once your out look,
I say especially in professional sports,
um,
you have,
uh,
right,
like two to say no or to say yes to
compete against that person.
I think if a woman wants to fight
against a man,
if a woman's 130 pounds and she wants to
fight against a man as 130 pounds,
they both agree.
Do whatever you want.
I think you should be allowed to.
But I think that there's a big
difference between who has been a man.
Their whole life has said testosterone
flowing through their bones,
their blood,
their body,
their whole life,
and then decides they're a woman versus
a woman who was born,
a woman,
raised a woman,
and as a biological woman her entire
life,
a transgender woman just is not a
regular biological woman.
It's this,
it's,
there's a difference,
but saying that gets people so angry
saying that a transgender woman who you
can say as a woman,
I say that,
but saying that they're the same thing
as a biological woman is just not
factually true.
Well was a different,
they have different chromosomes.
They have a different structure.
The hips are built different,
the shoulders are wider,
the hands are big.
There's so many factors.
That's right.
This is what makes people so frustrated
about the whole political correctness
thing,
right?
That we set up trip wires and if you
trigger one of those tripwires by making
a claim,
like the one you just made,
which is that a trans woman is not
exactly the same as a cis woman and non
trans.
Well,
no,
I'm not using sis again.
Not going to do it.
Not Real.
What do you wanna call them?
Disease.
I'll go with Z.
Z.
Z is the z instead of she for a trends.
No,
it's not.
Instead of she needs a shit.
Sorry,
did I just triggered one on the
tripwires.
Did I?
It's non-gender base.
It is a non gender base.
It's he or she for people who don't have
agenda,
it's what the fuck it is.
And you sitting over there as,
as as a male.
It was an actual mail.
I'm a CIS male.
Yes.
Yeah.
Not an actual male biological male.
All men have penises.
I had buck angel on.
Oh yeah.
Who's a Trans Jans Jan who uses the term
biological male.
He says there's a difference between
biological man.
He was born a woman and then
transitioned to being a man and he says,
biological male,
and he says that Trans people hate on
him for using the term biological.
Well,
what does he mean by the term?
It was someone who has x,
y chromosome,
a biological male versus him who has x,
x,
y,
Z.
I see.
I thought you meant that he calls
himself a biological male.
People biology.
Yeah,
sure.
He's like,
you should,
you should be able to differentiate
without being prejudiced.
It's so,
I mean ha,
it's crazy.
Crazy town.
I just think that people should be able
to live however they want to live their
lives.
And so I don't,
you know,
I don't spend a lot of time thinking
about this,
but I just wished that we were all
generous enough that when people find it
a little bit difficult to understand,
you don't assume that they're bigoted
just because it's a new concept for
them.
Because,
and I think as you say it,
this is part of what gave rise to trump.
The,
I mean the,
the parallel that I was drawing a moment
ago between like post structuralist,
there is no such thing as gender and
trump's fake news campaign was not so
much that all the one led to the other.
It was just that both,
this is the point that Lawrence Krauss
was making both undermine the,
they both erode the idea of truth
and what's ironic is it,
it's almost exactly the same thing that
bill o'reilly said.
The tie goes in the time it comes out.
People push this way and then people go,
fuck you.
There is a biological difference and
then they pushed that way and then they
get,
they get transphobic.
I mean there's,
there's a lot of people to get upset at
ridiculous ideas and then they get,
they go overboard and go the other way.
It's so stupid.
Like Louis Ck has that bit of bad gay
people as well.
He's like,
I don't understand.
I don't understand why people get angry
at the existence of gay people even if
they're not in their lives.
He's like even better.
The,
the gay marriage thing.
Yeah,
exactly.
People get furious.
Louie says,
like I would understand if like there
were a couple of guys fucking on my lawn
and I had to like hose him down to get
them.
Or like gay people were just like
touching their dicks in front of my face
as I'm trying to eat my breakfast
cereal.
Right.
But as long as they're not bothering me,
I don't understand the point in getting
upset about their mere existence out
there.
Yeah,
and it's the same with trans people.
I don't understand why there's this big
thing about trans people.
I understand.
It's silly what I mean.
This comes to also like people who are
currently obsessed with political
correctness as being the biggest problem
facing America today.
I feel like have missed the boat.
They're fighting the last year's battle.
They're fighting yesterday's battle when
the actual battle to fight is the day
before yesterday,
his battle,
which is today's battle,
which is a battle against bigotry,
I think,
which is a battle against trump,
like battle against the idea of fake
news,
a battle against America eventually
having its own pew.
Putin likes strong man.
Anyone who's spending all of their time
doing all of their shows about how
terrible political correctness is.
And you know,
Milo Yiannopoulos should be able to say
whatever he wants,
which of course he should is not I think
as like well political correct.
Yes.
Is a response to people feeling that
there's an injustice.
People feeling that there is bigotry and
prejudice and so they go too far with
it.
They get ridiculous and it's also a
natural human inclination to try to
control other people's behavior.
People like to be bossy and they like to
be able to tell you what you can and
can't do.
They like to tell you what words you can
and can't use.
It's a weird thing that people do and it
may be a response to the frustration
that they feel legitimate frustration
from actual bigotry and it makes them go
overboard.
It makes them go too far.
Yes.
It's a lack of perspective on both
sides.
That's a giant issue with human beings.
Yeah,
and you know what?
I think it actually was like the past
few times that we've,
we've gotten together and shot the shit
on this show.
Political correctness and the extremes
of it have been a major topic of
conversation.
And I think justly so.
But I do think that last year with the
election of trump and the kind of
welling up of kind of subtly anti
Semitic coded racially coded language
during the,
the,
the election campaign last year.
Why do you claim rent antisemetic when
jared Kushner is like his main guy.
And I don't think trump has an anti
semite I don't think trump hates.
So is he
a nice romantic?
A lot of people who support trump.
Hmm.
Right.
But there's no evidence that he is
right?
I don't think so.
No.
I think he's just an old,
an old white guy.
I think he's an old white guy with
traditional ideas about,
about what made America great and those
traditional ideas coincide with an
America that was a lot wider and more
Christian than the country that we say
today.
I think that's the way it becomes
racially coded.
Never even been a religious person.
Really interesting.
Isn't it?
Talk about no children of God.
You should be forced to suffer.
Shut to feet,
such a fraud.
He's such a go and get your steak knives
and your trump university dude.
It's like,
you know,
he's a charlatan.
Trump steaks,
steaks.
Amazing.
Shizzy how fucking corrupt the religious
right off.
I haven't gotten behind him so quickly.
When he was,
he went down to Liberty University.
He gave a speech.
He was like,
you know the my favorite part of the
Bible,
two Corinthians pronounced two
Corinthians.
It's second Corinthians every evening.
Even if you just went to,
went to Bible school when you were a
kid,
you remember that,
so they know he's a fraud.
He was asked by an interviewer or what
his favorite part of the Bible is.
He was like,
well,
I'm not going to get into that kind of
personal,
you know,
that's personal.
He hadn't read the fucking Bible.
He doesn't pray.
He's got his own Bible going to answer.
I wrote it exactly.
This is where I'm at night in his
underwear and he talks and somebody
writes it down one day.
That'll be the Bible.
The Best Bible.
He'd been an amazing Bible.
So they're all corrupt and full of shit.
Uh,
the religious right for getting behind
him.
When they always talk about how
important personal faith is in that,
in their candidates.
What else are they going to do?
They go towards Hillary.
I mean,
what are we going,
sorry,
I mean during the primary,
but who else would they go with?
He's going to win.
They knew he was Ted Cruz didn't have a
shot.
He's too wormy.
People see him sweat too much.
It's too of weird.
Easily lost the election.
But what,
but what I'm saying is they would
rather,
yeah,
they would rather have Donald Trump win
the election.
Then have ted Cruz will lose the
election on with principles,
which is amazing because you now you see
people saying,
I wish Ted Cruz was in office.
Like there's a lot of people on the left
that would have been happy with Ted
Cruz.
Yeah.
No,
not me.
Well,
he's really anti gay.
He's very anti gay and he's very smart.
He's extremely,
you know,
he was like a champion of the Harvard
debating team.
Apparently.
I think it was Harvard.
I think he's gay.
I reckon.
You Reckon?
What do you think when you look at them?
You got Gaydar,
right?
Yeah,
I do have good guy being a gay man.
Can you pick out cajuns?
Yeah,
I'll if you're in a room.
Yup.
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm pretty good.
I'm pretty good at it.
Huh?
What do you think really?
He gives,
there's a,
on the,
on the conservative,
right?
There's a fine line between slimy ass
hole and closeted gay.
You know what I mean?
You don't think there's some connection,
some,
some like,
well no,
I'm saying they could rise or
relationship.
It could be,
but the problem is that they never
underlying root system fungus that sort
of connects.
They communicate via electronic using
fungal.
Yeah.
Deep under the surface.
Pray the gay away as possible,
but they often are.
They also like,
Ted Haggard is a good example.
Right?
You remember that guy?
Yeah,
he was,
he seemed gay,
didn't he?
He had a little like his sibilance swear
a little bit.
S E s s list bees and gay.
But I didn't get it.
I don't know cause I'm like obviously
not the most gay presenting person that
you've ever met.
So I think that work.
Yeah,
I don't know.
It's fascinating though,
isn't that present as gay?
Here's part of the thing about gender as
well.
This is the right is it brings us back
to Rachel dollars,
Ireland,
rice and stuff like that.
Like obviously,
so maybe there is some biological reason
why do to or attracted to dude's tend to
exhibit mannerisms that are more
commonly associated with femininity.
Right.
Maybe a sing song.
He voice I certain style of walking,
Swish sashaying a swishy sort of
my friends that I was talking to about
the coppell.
Very clear.
Male and female and the relation,
interesting.
One of them does appear gay.
Like if you got him to be like,
oh that's a gay guy,
but the other guy,
you would have to know him.
Right?
You wouldn't know.
And so,
but then so what I think if there's a
kernel of biology in that,
I think it's been ramped up aggressively
over the past century by people also
playing the role of gay in the same way
that masculine dudes play the role of,
you know,
masculine structures will play the role
of masculinity and girls will play the
role of being girly and in that respect,
people who point out the gender is not
the same as sex or right.
Like gender is a bunch of behavioral
tropes that we will act out.
And so it's interesting to me like when
you say,
why are Gay People Gay People Act Gay.
Part of it must be an act.
What was theirs?
Maybe to telegraph to each other maybe.
Yeah.
But there's also just this broad
spectrum of individuals is so different.
I mean there's,
there's,
there's masculine people that are so
incredibly different than other
masculine people,
Feminine Women that are so incredibly
different than other feminine women.
I mean just people were,
they vary very widely biologically,
socially they,
they vary by their own neurochemistry.
I mean,
there's people that are just almost
naturally inclined to be depressed.
There's some people that you could shit
right in their hair and they'd be
fucking happiest peaches.
It's just,
people are weird,
man.
I'm a pretty happy person.
Where do you think you lie on that
spectrum of happiness?
I'm pretty happy.
Yeah.
But I worked at it.
I'm pretty aware of the pitfalls of like
inactivity and I'm very,
I mean,
I exercise a lot,
but even how the ability to motivate
yourself to take action is also
something that you'll need to have.
Yeah,
I guess.
But how much of that is from learned
behavior?
How much of that is from what,
you know,
the way I grew up,
there's a lot of factors.
Yeah.
Yeah,
there are,
my parents did not exercise
at all,
like fucking zero.
When I was growing up.
Zero.
They would come home from work and drink
and uh,
I did.
I just was like,
I gotta do something with this body.
This body wants to go to war.
I gotta I gotta get out and run.
I gotta hit a punching bag.
I've got to lift some weight.
I've got to do something.
I was just always like,
ah,
like I felt like there was an engine
inside of me that was revving up all the
time and I had to go run it.
If I didn't,
I didn't get out there and push it.
I didn't feel calm and it took me till I
was like a teenager before I figured
that out.
And then once I figured that out and
once I started exercising,
it was like there was me pre working out
and then me,
it's like,
oh,
now I can think now.
And then I realized I was a kid.
I was under the influence of biology for
well,
yeah,
I mean you're lucky that you didn't
channel that into drugs or,
or alcohol or aggression drugs.
Flora question.
Yeah.
Violence is the real worry like that.
That's a giant issue with boys.
And you see kids playing and I was at a
party recently,
a little kid's party.
It was an adult party.
Children's Patty.
All right.
Little kids.
Okay.
And uh,
there was this one boy and this one boy
has these two parents that had kids late
in life.
And they weren't really paying
attention.
They were inside drinking and this kid
was fucking hyper aggressive running
around,
pushing kids.
He hit kids.
I've watched him,
I watched him a call,
this kid a loser and uh,
you know,
I had to have a conversation with the
dad and I'm like,
dude,
you're kid is really aggressive.
And he's like,
he's a good kid.
I'm like,
yeah,
I wanted it.
It's so hard because you want to say,
hey man,
you ain't even fucking watching your
kid.
You read your drinking.
I'm like,
look,
I,
I saw him push his kid and him illusory.
Like that never happened.
I'm like,
oh my God.
He goes,
I look,
I'm trying to apologize cause his kid
did something cause I'm trying to
apologize for his behavior.
I'm like,
you're not apologizing.
You're saying he's,
he didn't do anything.
I'm like,
all right mate,
look,
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that this is the case,
but this is what happened.
What is it with parents defending their
kids so much these days?
If say if a parent had come up to my
parents when I was little kid and told
them that I'd been doing something like
that,
it would have been the grownups
gathering together against the child in
order to kind of communally raise the
child.
Like,
Hey,
my dad would not have said that he
didn't do that.
He will come up to me and said,
did you do that?
This guy and his wife were both
drinking.
That could have definitely been a factor
and there was a factor in me not pushing
it because I didn't want,
because first of all he,
when a guy says to you,
that didn't happen when you know it
happened,
did you are two steps away from beating
the fuck
he wasn't there.
You were there exactly what happened.
How does he know that it didn't happen?
And it's such a weird thing to say.
We're two steps away from,
well he wasn't watching this kid at all.
Yeah.
And His kid.
First of all,
he,
they had to go to visit his kid because
this kid hit other kids on three
occasions and it's funny,
he has really good grounds for believing
that it never happened.
It's party over
a course of,
you know,
this is over a course of a couple of
hours.
This kid hit three kids and so when you
say to a guy that your kids really
aggressive,
he's like,
he's a good kid.
Yeah,
no he's not.
He's a good kid.
Oh,
he's a good kid.
You don't even fucking know.
Maybe he's a good kid who's being
aggressive right now.
It doesn't change what I saw,
but what I'm saying is kids,
especially boys,
they have this thing inside of them.
Some of them do,
some of them don't.
But you know,
we very biologically,
but some of them have this aggressive
tendency.
That's why boys like to play football.
It's why boys gravitate to,
or some boys gravitate towards
aggressive activities.
They got to get it out of their system.
You got to exercise with that kid.
You got to do something with them,
play catch with them,
run around with them.
Where I'm out there,
people are not meant to sit down,
it'll fucking classroom and just pay
attention all day to some shit they
don't want to pay attention to and then
go home and sit in front of the TV.
And what do they do with all that energy
that they put them on?
Adrenaline that kept us from,
you know,
kept us alive,
kept us from predators,
kept us from invaders mean that all that
stuff is biologically programmed in the
human animal and we ignore it.
You're leading very transphobic by
implying that there something male
intrinsically transphobic or is it
gender?
I don't know.
Gender Essential Ism.
I think that's what it's called.
Uh,
no,
I'm with you and this is a problem.
I mean this is a problem about the,
about fatherhood,
right?
It's something I'm thinking about,
uh,
about now that I'm about to become a
file.
I'm like,
how do I run around?
Take care of too.
Yeah.
And how do I also make sure that like
they grow up with good masculine role
models and people and then I give that,
enable them to be the best kinds of
human beings that they want to flourish
into.
And then you've got the whole question
of adderall and Ritalin and saw on the
these,
my neighbor did that.
My neighbor put their kid on Ritalin,
one of them
Prozac,
Ritalin,
something like that.
They had this kid and he wasn't a bad
kid.
He was just fucking ignored.
The same thing.
The wife,
the wife was always trying to get dick
from everybody.
She was like flirting and everybody,
she flirt with my friends,
flirt with everybody and the husband is
just fucking like dealing with this
crazy bitch for a wife.
He didn't want to be there.
He would work late and this poor kid was
just bouncing off the walls.
It's,
they put them on drugs,
dogs
as I am.
There's a,
an economist called Tyler Cowen,
I don't know if you know of,
of Tyler.
He was,
um,
he would have,
he's the kind of guy who now that he's
in his mid fifties says that he's sure
that when he was younger he would have
been medicated if it were,
you know,
if,
if he were a young person today and he,
and the point that he was making about
that was that human psychology is
complicated and there's no sort of Yin
without the Yang.
Right.
Like the,
the distractedness that he had was bad
if what you wanted was for him to sit
still in class and pay attention to
something that he wasn't interested in.
Yes.
But fantastic in a whole bunch of other
ways that he thinks were invaluable.
Yeah.
Right.
Well,
my best friend Sam and Australia,
who is a brilliant,
like soil scientist,
one of the countries and possibly the
world's best scientists in his field has
a phd.
If,
if we'd been growing up,
if instead of being born when we were
born,
we'd been born just 10 years later.
What would his creative,
what would have happened to his
creativity if he'd been medicated in
order to be able to get through class
because he was always
distracted.
Parents don't care.
They want convenience,
especially parents at work all day.
They work all day and they come home and
they want this kid to fucking behave
because they're tired and they want this
life that they see in movies and in
television shows.
They don't know what it's like to raise
a human being.
It's very complex and you know,
especially when you're sending these
fucking kids to schools that they
promote these rigid ideas of how
children are supposed to behave and you
know,
and tell you that if you don't follow
the rules,
you're not going to be successful.
I mean how many fucking stories have you
heard where teachers tell rowdy kids
they're never going to amount to
anything.
I had a teacher tell it to me.
I'll never fucking forget it.
Yup.
My head that as well cause she was just
so dumb.
She was so,
she was so dominant,
such a bad teacher.
And I was a terrible student.
I mean she was certainly frustrated ms
public schools.
Right.
But,
uh,
I said something and she was a black
woman,
had terrible accent.
She,
uh,
had a very bad ebonics accent and I was,
talking to my friend and she goes,
Mr Rogan,
would you like to come up here and do
both of these problems in front of the
class?
So I go,
would you like me to do both of those
problems?
And everybody,
everybody started laughing.
Harla kids were like,
oh shit.
And so she kicked me out of class for
that and I said,
all I did was talk the way you talk and
you kicked me out.
I go,
just because you're teaching a math
class.
Shinny,
learned how to talk,
shitting learned.
I taught correctly for our students and
she kicked me out and she,
I remember said,
go ahead,
laugh at Mr Rogan.
Mr Rogan has never gonna amount to
anything in life.
Yeah.
Unlike being a public school teacher,
but I rent,
it's nothing wrong with being a public
school teacher.
Just saying she didn't amend it very
much.
It's not true.
It's a great job if you do it right.
What I'm saying has influence over
people at school.
Teachers are worthless and should be
executed.
That's precisely the boy.
So rude.
First of all,
you're not even American and come over
and say that shit.
We have public school teachers.
No,
of course.
I love that she's saying that it's cause
she's a cunt.
She was not a nice,
we should be
sizing her not for her occupation but
for her constant.
What's a fucking horrible job man?
I mean I wouldn't want to deal with me
when I was 15 yeah.
Who the hell wants to deal with a 15
year old boy who doesn't want to pay
attention?
Who doesn't give a shit about math,
but you know she left a weak spot,
do you think?
Well,
it also the whole question of like how
of speaking?
Well,
as a teacher,
if you're an educator then you sort of
have to have your shit together.
In terms of being educated,
but then that also bumps up against,
are we being racist by implying that
black American English is less educated
than standard white English?
Cause some people argue that the,
that black English is just a dialect of
the language.
Well you could argue that,
but you know what the same would be held
if this was,
I mean this is in Massachusetts.
The same will be held if it was a guy
who was a teacher who had a ridiculous
Boston accent and I've marked his Boston
accent.
Like if he said,
uh,
you know something about pack you
fucking cat.
And I was like,
would you like me to pack my cat
correctly?
Kicked me out because of that.
It's the same thing.
A lot of stress.
They hit him with a bid.
You're mocking someone's inability to
communicate correctly and it because
look whether or not it's good or bad.
Like you might like saying both better.
You might like it and there's nothing
wrong with that.
Look,
if you're a happy,
successful person,
you don't like to say both.
You like to say both.
What the fuck is wrong with that?
It's just a sound you make with your
mouth.
Sure.
But if I can say it,
if I can repeat it and you,
you're so touchy about it.
You kicked me out of class.
We fucked up.
You fucked up.
You got a soft spot.
That's right.
She knows.
Yeah.
She feels,
she feels insecure about it.
Exactly.
How big lab on this one of my first big
laughs,
I was like,
ah,
I could mock things.
Yeah.
But it's just,
you know,
she just,
she's under pressure.
It's terrible job not getting paid very
much.
And you have to be a babysitter as well
as an educator.
Yeah.
Fucking horrible.
I mean there's,
I had Frank Rich on my podcast on we,
the people,
uh,
who was,
who he's an executive producer on the
vape and he was the co,
he was,
we was like the main columnist on the
New York Times opinion page for about 50
from maybe almost 20 years in the 90s
and the two thousands and he sort of
started the New York Times.
We can review section,
which comes out in the Sunday paper.
And these days.
And he had a piece in New York magazine
which was about how much empathy we
should feel towards uneducated people.
He was talking specifically about trump,
about like trump voters because like
since the election there's been quite a
lot of hand wringing among progressive's
about like we've been focusing too much
on these issues like trans rights and
gay rights and so on and,
and identity politics and black lives
matter and we've lost touch with the
working class base.
Like the Democratic Party no longer
speaks in a meaningful way to white
working class,
especially males and especially in rust
belt cities,
you know,
in the,
in,
in the Midwest.
And his point was actually fuck him.
You shouldn't need to pay attention to
them.
There were a lost cause.
They keep voting against their own
interest by voting for people like trump
and voting for republicans.
Don't try to win them over and stop
trying to understand them and wringing
your hands about why you've lost them.
It's an interesting episode.
If people want,
I mean obviously I'm grossly
exaggerating what his actual position
is,
but you should,
you can.
I can see it,
listen to the other side.
I could see how someone would take that
stance,
but I think there's just a natural
inclination to go left and right with
people.
There's a natural inclination to react
to certain right leaning behaviors by
going far left and the natural
inclination to go like,
like how many people grow up from really
a regressive religious backgrounds and
then they become like really saccular.
As they get older,
they abandoned the religion,
they become reformed Catholics.
It's really common.
It's really common to to see the
suppression of one ideology and bounce
in the other direction.
If you have a parent,
I mean there's a lot of people that,
you know,
they grow up and their parents are super
hippies and then they become a
conservative going to rebel against
their parents.
It's a really common,
Yup.
That's what I'm always thinking about in
terms of parenthood as well.
Like no matter what it is that I try to
fix in the way that my parents raised
me,
where I think they could've done it
better.
That's just going to swing in the
opposite direction and then my kids are
going to do the opposite
because they,
because you always think that your
parents did an imperfect job,
right?
Fighting yesterday's [inaudible] does an
imperfect job.
It's impossible to be perfect.
You're a fucking human being.
There's no perfect human beings.
They've never existed.
Jesus said the sweet baby Jesus,
the Dalai Lama's not perfect.
How about fucking Gandhi?
Gandhi used to sleep with a bunch of
girls naked in his room.
He was probably a freak,
like Gandhi was most likely a freak and
he just,
they just kept it under wraps because he
was Gandhi like,
do you know the story?
Used to sleep with naked teenagers.
Yeah.
There's also weird things about,
I mean human and also Mother Teresa have
weird things in their personal lives do
well.
I don't think it was sexual,
but I think there was a lot,
there were a lot of questions about like
her ethical dealings in terms of the
Mother Teresa Foundation and where her
money went.
And like what did it go too well for his
thought.
She didn't think that it was very,
she didn't think it was a good idea to
empower young women.
What have you.
W We found out that all our money went
to a warehouse filled with dildos.
Why thought fuck.
Like she did a lot of good but she also
bought a lot of Dildos,
fucking gigantic stacks of,
oh wait,
she could use the door kick start these
fucking Harley Davidson powered
vibrators.
I love it.
Uh Yeah.
Well I mean the people are not perfect
and most charitable organizations are
criticized for spending far too much on
infrastructure and you know,
the administrative costs and then you
find out how much money actually goes to
the charity.
Like you just have an organization where
you're giving people jobs and by the way
you also do some good.
Awesome.
Good.
It's interesting cause like whenever I
give to charity,
I always try to pay attention to how
many,
how many overheads they have and how
much money is being spent on Admin and
so on.
But then it was actually I think will
macaskill or someone who's involved in
the um,
like the,
the life you can save kind of like give
well movement,
which is like rational.
Is it practical altruism or rational
altruism with effective altruism?
That's how podcasts,
yeah.
Yeah,
he's great.
He was an,
and they were saying in actual fact it
does take quite a lot of administration
to make a dollar work.
Well of course.
So if you just look at the ones at the
charities with the lowest overhead,
then that it doesn't necessarily
actually mean that they're doing the
best work in the field because it might
cost 40 cents out of every dollar to
make sure that you're targeting the
remaining 60 cents in a way where you'll
get actually 60 cents of value rather
than a place that only has a 15%
overhead.
But then the remaining 85 cents are all
being on bullshit projects
that don't have any measurable.
And then success.
It's signed the complete other end of
the spectrum.
You have the Clinton Foundation,
which was a ruse.
I mean,
it was not essentially a prestige play
wasn't,
it doesn't exist anymore.
Does not exist any going under.
Yeah,
they're closing it down.
Hmm.
Isn't that a fact?
Pull up police pull that up.
I'm pretty sure they,
they said they were shutting it down,
but I mean Bill Clinton would take
hundreds of thousands of dollars and
speak at these charitable events.
Like people would jet,
they would spend a gigantic chunk of
their budget to have Bill Clinton come
and speak and he would take all of it.
He would take all the money.
He wouldn't,
we didn't think of it fast.
Yeah.
So he would,
he would take these gigantic donations
from people and then he would speak and
get paid hundreds of thousand dollars
speaking phase of crazy.
I mean,
even the fact that Hillary Clinton was
taking speaking fees from Goldman Sachs
and did not think that that would look
bad in,
she didn't give a fuck.
So stupid.
No,
I,
well,
I think now she gives a fuck.
Well,
you know what?
Bernie Sanders drilled that and I'm so
glad he did.
But look,
it's bribery.
It's a loophole.
There's a little bowl and it's bribery.
Nobody wants to pay to hear her talk.
Get the fuck out of here.
She's a terrible speaker.
She's not Louis C k.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean,
this is not Chris Rock.
We're talking about this is,
she's not a good speaker,
but the whole painted here,
this is the whole thing about these I,
late Clinton global initiative to
shutdown lays off 22 as donations,
but this is the Washington Times.
That's a,
that's a no,
no,
no.
Right wing rag.
How dare you check.
Um,
that's,
that's not the only place that I saw it.
I saw it in a lot of places.
They're shutting it down at the top.
The top click is snipes.
So that'll tell level.
That's the conspiracy theory of the
whole story about snopes though.
Do you know about the guy who runs
snopes?
Snopes is run by a fucking Kook.
The Guy,
the guy who runs snopes left his wife,
he started with his wife,
left his wife,
married a prostitute,
a prostitute as a website where she was
as recently as two years ago,
was getting reviewed for her prostitute
work.
She's asked court and there they both
have a clear left wing bias clear like,
like he's,
she's been involved in,
well,
I mean show me,
show me any snips,
pages that say that something is true
when it's not or the sites.
Not necessarily that it's true or it's
false.
There's these ambiguous areas where they
always lean left and that's what people
have said about snopes.
It's kind of tricky.
Okay,
but it's not,
it's,
it's simple.
It's not like this computer controlled
objective reality and understand Isley.
Politifact is also,
it also gets accused of being left wing
because right wing people who are full
of shit don't like being cold out on it.
Fake News.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's not,
it's not actually,
I mean I've,
I haven't seen anything on snips that is
uh,
that is questionable.
Even if the guy's an asshole,
this CNN thing,
when she pointed to the CNN reporter,
you are fake news.
Oh well this is,
this is that me of living in a
banana republic reminded me of living
under in Venezuela.
Fake News.
Yeah,
you are faking like just that statement.
What the fuck does that even mean?
You're not news.
This is a goddamn person to you in vain.
You are fake news.
Fake news also,
but so effective people loved it when
you're,
you know,
the thug life meme,
the sunglasses chopped down.
I saw that a bunch of those for him when
he said that you are fake news.
I mean did you guys were in the states
when you were like kids we like,
did you have like I know you why you
said you are,
but what am I like that kind of
bullshit.
Basically what he's saying like people
accuse,
no,
you like he was elected on the,
on the back.
He would be elected by very,
very narrow majorities in a few key
swing states that had been inundated
with bullshit stories on facebook that
were coming out of eastern Europe with
Russian funding and expand,
exploding all of these fake bombshell
expos.
A's is about how Hillary Clinton,
how the FBI prosecutor who was looking
into Hillary Clinton had been found dead
and all this sort of stuff.
There was actually fake news then the
way the term came into public public
consciousness last year.
And now anyone who criticizes the
administration,
he just does.
He just pulls a,
I know you are,
you said you are,
but what am I a trick and says,
Whoa,
that's not fake news.
Your fake news you face is fake news.
What did you think about when Julian
assange,
um,
implied that that young man who worked
for the DNC,
who was assassinated,
he was shot in the back.
They tried to say it was a robbery.
Like they left his wallet,
they left his watch,
they left his phone,
they'd left all his money.
That didn't take a thing from him and
they shot him at four o'clock in the
morning in the back.
Julian assange was insinuating that this
young man had been the source of the DNC
leaks.
That implied that though,
that show that Hillary Clinton and the
DNC conspired against Bernie Sanders in
the primary,
and you don't really hear about that
anymore.
I mean,
that guy's dead.
He's dead and there's no investigation.
There's no,
no one was found guilty.
No one was tried.
There's no,
there's no,
no one's looking.
That guy was killed.
Well,
I'd like to look into it.
I think [inaudible] has kind of lost
credibility by essentially becoming a
conduit for the Kremlin.
Like all of know wikileaks,
we all know that the,
I mean people insecurity.
So every,
anytime I talk about this,
people are going to respond and say,
Oh,
you're just buying the security
services.
Align years believing what the NSA and
the CIA want you to believe.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'm basically taking on faith the
conclusions of security agencies here in
the United States,
multiple to get more than a dozen
different security agencies also
confirmed by the Brits,
by British,
the British secret service all believe
say that they have good reason to
believe that the Kremlin was behind the
hacks and that wikileaks released was,
it must've been in cahoots with the
Kremlin because otherwise how it,
how did they release the DNC was there
could have been
many people that were trying to have,
but dealing with like can see
fingerprints on things.
They know how these things work.
They can see the back doors.
So do you think that Julian assange was
lying and saying that guy was a part of
the leaks?
I think could have been one of the
conduits.
I mean,
he could have been one of the people
that leaked it to Russia in the first
place.
Uh,
that's possible.
Yeah,
I just don't know why I would be
trusting Julian assange about any of
this because he says that it didn't come
from Russia.
Well,
the other thing that I would worry about
with Julian Assan,
she's at this poor fuck has been trapped
in the embassy in London for so long and
he can't get out.
I think his head is,
I think he'd be,
he's got a problem with his head these
days.
How could he not Pammie's back?
Pamela Anderson makes us sixth visit to
Lover Julian assange as she brings Vegan
cheeseburgers to the Ecuadorian embassy
for the wikileaks foundation.
What Pamela Anderson is banging Giulia
massage.
Odd,
powerful Julian massage.
Wait a minute,
hold on a second.
Julien is trying to free the world.
I love him for this.
Pamela Anderson reveals her feelings for
a sausage in rambling blogs on sex and
faking orgasms.
Baywatch actress and model 49 is said to
have been dating wikileaks founder has
been stuck inside.
He's been stuck inside the embassy in
Knightsbridge since 2012 with saunders
had been stuck inside
posters too big for him to get stuck.
And I'm saying,
well I guess he's done well for himself
for a Pale pasty Australian who's never,
um,
would you just say,
Jamie,
she's been visiting him there and
whatnot.
For how long?
I last couple of months at least.
She's like a pretty good when you cover
up and put her all in black,
how old would pedal or Anderson Beta 49
we just read it.
Oh,
I see.
Okay.
He's 45 she's 49 she's an older woman.
Dark and holder and comes around.
Doesn't that like a fuck?
Yeah,
I mean time wins and all of us.
Yeah.
I looked like shit compared to when I
was 25 there's nothing you can do about
everyone does.
Nothing you can do about it.
It just beats you directly.
We'll get to a point with science can
reverse that.
It's on the way 100%.
They've already done it.
And what people would pay to be able to
look and feel like they did when they
were 25 well,
you know that Peter Teal guys are
already getting done blood put into a
system.
He said,
I don't trust the guy.
Him and Julie and a son should,
should meet up and create some little
underground implants and trust him.
He's selling something fishy about him.
He's a big trump guy,
which in itself in and of itself is not
bad,
but he's such,
he's a very smart billionaire.
Trump guy.
Billionaire gay trump guy.
Yeah.
Weird.
And also that whole,
you know,
suing Golkar until it went under.
Well he's very,
he's a violative prick.
Well they had a common,
I mean they outdid him and then they
went after Hulk Hogan and then the guy
said that he would release a sex tape of
a child,
you know,
if he could get away with it.
You remember that?
Yeah,
I do.
And I,
it doesn't condone them,
but I don't like setting up a precedent
where very,
very rich people can just,
cause this wasn't the only thing that he
was suing them about.
He was basically just throwing lawsuits
at them that,
that so,
so fast that they couldn't keep their
head above and
they went down to our biggest,
I mean,
how can you eventually the person's
going to win a lawsuit.
I don't like the idea that media
companies can just be constantly sued.
They went after a creep.
I mean,
well,
they were creeps and they went after
him,
but they went after a rich guy.
Yeah.
Well,
we live in,
we live in America,
which has a first amendment.
They're supposed to be able to do that
without,
without being sunk.
But should they be able to reveal
details about his life that he doesn't
want public?
Let's let the First Amendment is,
you're allowed to a set of first
amendment that you're allowed to go
after.
Someone like say if somebody decides to
just go after you,
you're not even a public person.
Like keep me.
Is he probably as a public person,
how has he public,
because people know who he is.
I don't actually know whether that was
part of the,
um,
part of the defense is crazy shit about
you,
unfortunately.
Yes.
Because that's what freedom is.
Like.
I don't think that,
do you think that America would be a
better place if fantastically wealthy
people could,
uh,
launch an endless string of lawsuits?
Whether or not they're legitimate at
media companies that aren't like,
it's a good question.
It really depends on what that media
company did and why they did it.
I mean,
I'm no fan of gawkers tawdry like I
didn't consume any of that stuff.
I don't know.
I didn't believe in adding paypal.
I don't think that they were right.
But what it says about his character is
what I find troubling it much like
trump.
I just don't,
I basically don't like vindictive people
who the moment you cross them,
they then spend the rest of their lives
and fortune like coming back to hunt you
down.
I don't think that's a mature character
trait.
I see your point.
Um,
the question would be what if they cost
him money and they profited from it
financially and then he will not leave.
Cry me a fucking Ribeye.
He comes,
not the best example.
It's not the best example because you
know,
there's nothing wrong with being gay.
She had just been out in the first
place.
Right.
But that's his choice,
isn't it?
Yeah,
it is his choice.
And I don't really believe in adding
paypal,
but on the other hand,
like just grow up.
Like I shoot them over that and he just
decided that they were constant who's
got to go out and get sued them about
that.
But that didn't work.
And then he sued him about,
he sued them on multiple occasions.
If you've got infinitely deep pockets
you can ruin,
you will find a way to ruin people by
dragging them through the quotes.
She should have been able to bank roll
hall Cogan did you think Hulk Hogan had
a legitimate gripe?
Yeah,
I think so.
Right.
I mean cause wasn't,
wasn't that the case that he didn't
realize that he was being 100% of the
time.
Yeah.
You shouldn't be able to have a video of
you having sex with somebody that you
didn't know it was being taken splashed
all over the Internet.
Yeah.
And then profit from it and then profit
from it.
So the real question was should he have
been able to bankroll exactly.
That's right.
Yeah.
Or or or should they be some limit to
the number of like lawsuits because
again,
you would want people to be able to
bankroll cases that they care about
deeply but maybe not three or four
completely unrelated cases all against
the same side.
Right.
That's where it gets weird.
But isn't this the like life in general?
Yeah,
it's slippery.
Yeah.
There's,
there's,
I mean it's like we were talking about
with abortion,
like what is it?
Is it killing a baby or is it a medical
procedure?
Just agree that it's both that like
that.
Not to send why there is,
especially in this country,
like it's so,
so polarizing here.
Oh come on man.
I ain't know Dawson Dawkins and tweeted
something about it that there was
nothing that people like a human embryo
was a essentially the same thing as a
pig embryo was like ridiculous
comparison to abortion looks like
because the religious right.
We'll always be crazy about the things
that it's crazy about and people will
always get offended on twitter when
Richard Dawkins tweet something that's
unpopular.
By the way,
I have an interview with him coming up.
If,
if so if you don't,
let me just plug,
if you don't subscribe to way that
people live in search for we the people,
all one word in your podcast App,
uh,
I'll be talking to Sam Harris tomorrow,
which I'll get released in a couple of
weeks.
And don't shout at me for not releasing
it immediately like you did last time
twitter and we'll have some not to shout
and we'll have some good and that's
exactly right.
It's true.
I'm going to sue their asses and then
drag him through course.
Uh,
and I'll be talking to joe about the be
doing,
launching a little,
um,
ask me anything kind of dominates.
And so I had,
I did an [inaudible] with Dawkins had a
stroke,
stroke.
He's great,
he's fine,
he's doing well.
Well,
the stroke did not affect his,
his cognitive function.
It did affect his ability to sing,
which is interesting.
Oh,
that's interesting.
Yeah.
And it's,
so there are a few motor functions that
I think it's affected,
but it didn't.
Yeah,
as you say,
it didn't affect his cognitive,
so that'll be being released.
So,
so follow at WTP underscore live on
twitter and on the school they'll find
it.
Just find a way with paypal.
Anyway,
so what Richard Dawkins was saying and
his people are going to be angry at him
on twitter regardless of what he says,
but I still affirm that in the state
it's in the states,
the conversation around abortion is
uniquely different from the way that it
is in Europe and in Australia.
It's much more of a,
it's just much more of a full pipeline
issue and I wonder whether in hindsight
it wouldn't have been better for row the
way not to actually have been decided by
the Supreme Court that way.
What?
Well,
just because I know people are going to
have,
you don't have this as well.
You fucking CIS gender piece of Shit.
I believe.
I believe in what their surrogate mom
leave and abortion rights,
but I don't believe that it's that you
can find in the constitution of the
United States a right so inalienable
that the Supreme Court,
like where is it in the constitution.
The Supreme Court said there's a right
to privacy,
therefore there's a right to abortion
because we don't want to interfere in
women's affairs.
But that presupposes that the embryo
isn't a human,
you don't have the right to privacy to
kill somebody.
Right.
I mean,
if I go into a room,
my right to privacy,
it doesn't extend to me get being able
to get away with killing a baby.
The question of whether or not it's a
baby is the relevant question.
Right.
That's not addressed at,
you know,
in,
in row.
So I think that it should be legal,
but I think that it should be legal
through the legislative process.
I think that is a legitimate democratic
aspiration for people to be able to,
and if it means that it does,
it's not legal in Alabama because a
majority of people in Alabama don't want
it.
I don't think the founding fathers would
have a problem with that.
Well,
there's a strong amount of large amount
of people that don't want men talking
about this at all,
that they will follow.
You should be able to discuss this.
Yes,
this is the problem.
That is one of the main problems and
female issue.
Remember as well woman being upset that
a man with no stake in the game is
stepping up and saying that a woman
should or should not be able to have an
abortion?
Well,
why?
I mean how do I have stake in the game
of whether or not,
for example,
murder should be legal.
Well,
okay,
this is not that.
This is,
this is something different.
This is someone
in might be to you,
but it might not be to them if it's just
having like,
okay,
here's the morning after pill.
Is that the same as an abortion?
I don't care because I don't think
there's anything wrong with abortion.
It,
no,
I don't think there's any wrong.
Well,
the shutter is if it's a nine month old
baby,
the baby's in there and it's about to
come out the next day,
decided to open her up and stabbed in
the head.
This is what I'm arguing for is that is
a kind of incrementalism which you were
just alluding to.
Right.
It's not a black or white thing.
Why can't we?
Why can't we all appreciate that it's
both because it's become so polarized in
the United States that both positions
are bullshit and people on both sides
know that both positions are bullshit.
It's bullshit to say that it is just a
women's health issue and has no ethical
implications whatsoever.
Even if,
as you say,
you're talking about cutting a woman
open at nine months and stabbing in the
embryo in the head.
It's also bullshit to say that the
instant an egg is fertilized,
that is a person that should have all of
the rights to life than an adult should
have and then it's murder to kill a
blastocyst,
but smaller than the size of the head of
a pin positions a stupid,
this is an incremental situation.
Life evolves.
It grows,
a fetus grows.
It becomes a human being.
I mean,
Peter Singer,
the great philosopher,
also an Australian says that under
certain conditions,
infanticide,
the killing of babies should be legal
and could be ethical.
While he's an animal nut,
he loves animals more than,
but he makes a legitimate point,
which is that,
you know,
why does it make a difference?
One day after the baby is born,
I suppose you've got a premature baby
that's born four weeks early.
Uh,
in fact,
now we can already make babies survive
at right at right around the point of
viability,
which is where abortion is still on the,
on the fringe of.
So say you've got a 22 or 23,
24 week old,
a baby,
not,
not we called baby you timing from the,
from the moment of inception conception
that could live outside the womb.
Right?
But the moment it gets born,
it becomes murder to kill it.
But you
could have killed exactly the same
organism with exactly the same future
and exactly the same prospects and
exactly the same life if it was inside
the womb and of states.
Uh,
well on underbrush,
on Roe v Wade,
I'm not talking about late term,
I'm talking about the point of viability
beat Roe v Wade state,
uh,
the viability time.
Uh,
it's,
it's been interpreted as being like that
20 to 24 week.
But this is specifically say that I
don't,
I don't think,
I don't know whether or not that comes
out of the actual ruling where they were
writing it in Roe v Wade,
but I do know that that is the way that
it's been interpreted by lower courts
since then.
But,
but maybe they actually spelled out the
number of weeks.
Either way,
you know,
he's pointing to a,
to a legitimate conundrum.
It was sort of moral hypocrisy,
slippery issue.
It's not simple black or white.
Right.
And the idea that we shouldn't be
allowed to think and talk about the
moral quandary of this because we can't
have babies.
Well,
I'm not agreeing as silly.
I'm not agreeing to that.
No,
I know what I'm saying.
That is an argument that women want to
take it because they feel,
they feel like there's this unjust sort
of male dominance on the female
reproductive system.
Look when I see a bunch of white men,
white old men sitting in Congress making
rules against women,
predominantly young women,
predominantly young women of color who
are in areas that have less the least
amount of access,
which siphoned legally women of color.
How so?
Because safe legal abortions are more
difficult to obtain in places like rural
Alabama than they are in places like New
York City.
Yeah,
but there's a lot of white people,
Rural Alabama.
I don't necessarily think it's a racial
issue as much as the poverty issue,
especially like things like planned
parenthood and shutting down planned
parenthood's.
They're just going to affect people that
don't have much money.
Yup.
Who had disproportionately people of
color as well.
Disproportionately in terms of the
actual numbers of human beings are
intended to percentage wise a lot.
The actual emotional lives of human
beings.
It's not right,
but you can understand how it would look
bad.
If you're a black woman ad people of
color to that,
it accentuates the issue.
It makes it even more problematic.
It makes it more of a big left wing
progressive issue.
Right.
That can't be argued against.
Do you think the is discrimination
against people of Color?
Oh,
don't want to do that.
It's people,
but do you think that the optics would
look as bad if all of the old white men
who were writing the laws were black?
I think it all looks bad.
I don't think I would look as bad.
The idea,
hold on a second.
You're saying that if old white men make
these issues,
it doesn't look as bad.
Know what I'm saying?
It looks worse.
Bad as possible.
It looks worse than it was black and men
were making this issue against all poor
people because old white men just seem
to drip privilege because they use every
single checkbox they've got going for
them.
They both male,
they're white and they're all sure
argument.
Anyway,
they're tortured arguments.
Thomas,
you don't think it looks weird when
Clarence Thomas Votes against abortion?
Yeah,
I do.
so there you go.
But I mean,
my
point,
my point is simply yes.
Okay.
I take the optics as being a bad thing.
I think the optics are worse if it's
white people and if it's black people,
but I'm happy to,
I'm happy to yield that point to concede
that point if that's the sticking one.
The point is we have to be able to have
conversations about anything without
allowing our identities to prevent us
from being able to think.
To ponder that I came on this show was
because I was getting into an argument
with an activist about whether or not I
had a right to have an opinion about
whether or not Stephen Colbert had been
racist.
Right.
And she was claiming that I didn't,
I didn't have a right to have a
conversation about it because I'm a
white man.
Well that was just the way she tried to
get out of the argument.
You know the whole thing before that was
her not understanding the joke and she
didn't want to own up to the fact that
she didn't understand the joke.
And then when you sort of explained it
to her,
she was using the you as a white man
thing.
They try to deny your opinion,
don't you think?
It happens all the time.
I mean just exactly what you're saying.
I think we're,
we're both on the same page here in that
I think we both agree that you should
absolutely be able to have a
conversation about this.
The question is,
should a man be able to decide what a
woman can and can't do with their body
and should we be able to make the laws?
But you just smuggled in the term with
her body.
Well,
it is a baby.
If it's a blastocyst and it is in our
body,
right?
She's a blessing to her body,
So that is a decision that we're talking
about that.
So when it gets to be an embryo or fetus
along the way,
somewhere along the way,
it ceases to be just her body,
but an unrelated male human being.
When should that person be able to make
a decision and should a male human being
be able to make a decision at all?
Because if you can make a decision about
the embryo or a fetus,
can you make it about the blastocyst?
Like when can you decide and why should
a man be able to make that decision in
the first place?
Because he's got,
because he's got a brain as well and
we're rolling and you deciding trolling
someone's body,
you are talking about controlling a
body.
No.
Which a woman with a black side of her,
you tell her she can't take care of that
blastocyst and remove it.
She must make it viable and bring it to
birth.
We're talking about when a homosapien
comes into existence.
That's a philosophical and ethical
questions.
No,
it's not.
If you're telling me framing it as
being,
if you're telling a woman's body,
no,
because we're talking about the rights.
Giving someone a ride or stopping them
and controlling them.
Yeah.
If you're talking about a blastocyst
inside a woman's body,
yeah,
and you're a man and you decide,
you don't even know this woman.
You decide by your moral argument and
judgment she should not be able to
terminate that blastocyst.
Then you are deciding what she can do
with her body.
No.
You're deciding what she can do to the
blastocyst.
It's in her body.
It's inside her buddy.
You sure?
It's also inside her body when it's nine
one
it's all so you're,
so you're saying a man unrelated man
should be able to have input on whether
a woman should not determine it.
A blastocyst saying,
saying that the democratic institutions
of the state should be able to decide
that
mean talking about democratic,
we're
talking very specifically about a man.
What are you talking,
being able to decide if it's a
dictatorship,
then I don't agree with that.
I do believe that people should be able
to,
I think this is something that people
ought to be able to vote on.
Yes.
I personally again,
favor abortion rights,
but I don't think that the,
I don't think that the gender of the
person who is voted into power by the
voting public is relevant in terms of
whether or not the voting public thinks
that embryos are human beings,
but you don't think that?
I just think,
I don't think that embryos have a right
to life,
but I don't,
I don't think that it makes sense to say
that an embryo is just the woman's body.
We're not talking about an embryo.
We're talking about the entire process,
right?
The entire process of conception to
birth and that somewhere along the way.
What do you like and then you arguing
that if,
if there,
if there are males in positions of power
and congress that they should have to
abstain from ruling.
I'm sure shit in male justices on the
supreme court have to abstain from
voting on abortion cases.
I'm arguing that it's problematic when a
man decides who can not get pregnant,
decides when a baby is actually a baby,
so it shouldn't be allowed to vote for.
I'm not saying that I'm the same
candidates that are antiabortion.
Don't you think it's problematic that a
guy should decide whether it,
like say if you're a hardcore where I've
already said it looks bad,
optics is luck,
looks man,
but what does a couple of medic main
other than looks?
Well,
it's not.
It's a,
it's a huge issue.
It's not looks,
it's a huge issue that someone who
cannot get pregnant decides that another
human being,
that they're totally unrelated to can't
make the decision that five cells that
are bundled together must be brought to
life.
They think that those five cells are a
person.
Well,
they don't even know this.
I mean,
you're just a lot of cells.
They don't even know this person.
They don't know this for wash.
They have any power over this person and
why should they have any power or his to
determining what are they controlling a
person's body and when are they saving a
baby?
Well,
that's precisely the,
the question,
isn't it?
Right.
That is the question.
Should they,
should a male have the right to
determine whether or not a woman can
murder her newborn baby?
That's a good question.
I say no.
At least she consistent.
Yeah.
I don't think,
I don't think anybody should be able to
murder a baby.
I don't think a man should have the
right.
I think we,
society as a society collectively know.
You were just,
I thought you were just saying that
you'd,
you'd think that a man should not be
able to prevent a mother from killing
her baby.
No,
that's,
I said that wrong.
What I mean is no,
because that is what you're saying with
regard to the abortion.
You're saying that a man shouldn't have
a,
should not have the right to prevent a
woman from killing her baby.
Very.
When we interrupt each other it's not
going to work.
Okay.
I,
I know what you're saying and I know
that you're saying that we should all
have a stake in this.
We shall be able to discuss this.
I just think that when you talk about
like,
especially like a blastocyst eventually
becoming an embryo,
we have to agree in some way,
shape or form that you and I don't have
a stake in it.
We're not going to get pregnant.
No,
it's a a way,
it's a way
bigger issue for a woman than it is for
Matt.
Yes,
so we agree.
We agree that it's a way bigger issue
for a woman that I should be able to
discuss it.
I just think we both agree that you
should be able to discuss it,
should be able to debate.
Where I'm coming from here is that I
feel like we use identity politics to
deprive other people of standing to
discuss questions that are actually
universal because they're moral
questions.
And I think we all have one thing that I
tried to do as much as possible as
understand where people who I disagree
with,
uh,
coming from.
Uh,
and I know you do that as well.
So I am pro abortion rights,
but in order for me to understand where
people who detest abortion are coming
from,
it's necessary for me to make the sort
of leap of empathy and logic into their
camp and see things from the way that
they see them,
which is that the instant egg is
fertilized for them.
That becomes a sacred,
a sacred question of a new life where
it's no longer about the woman's body.
It's now a moral and ethical question
that we're all involved in because we're
all involved in what our culture is
allowed to do and who it's allowed to
kill and how it's allowed to kill them.
So it becomes a bit more like a death
penalty question where you might say,
well,
I'm never going to be up for the death
penalty because I'm never going to do
anything that would require that would
put me on death row.
So what standing do I have to be in
favor or against the death penalty?
That's sort of a moot question.
Like we're all in the society together.
We'll have to figure out what's right
and wrong and if we've got a brain,
we should have conversations about
what's good or bad and the fact that I'm
unlikely to be in a specific scenario,
it doesn't actually really give me less
standing to have a conversation about it
or even to write laws about it.
If people vote me into a position where
I can write laws about it.
Well,
I certainly think it does when you're
talking about a blastocyst,
I certainly think it does.
When you talk about the argument of
conception and when something becomes
alive.
So let me ask you this.
When do you think abortion should be
legal?
Do you think it should be legal up to
nine months or these things should be
cut off period?
I think it should basically be legal all
the way up to nine months.
And I probably agree with Peter Singer
that maybe,
maybe it's occasionally okay to kill by
Biz.
So you,
wow.
So you think that a viable baby inside a
woman's body at nine months old,
she's fully pregnant.
As long as that baby doesn't come out,
she should be able to kill it.
Well,
I'm saying even if it does come out,
maybe
because I'm evil,
that's
murder a baby.
Well,
religious people think that you think
that because they think that blast
assistant blastocyst about religious
people.
I'm talking about you.
Yeah,
I don't.
I think it's obvious that the process of
going from an egg into a Joe Rogan is
such a long and incremental passage that
I don't see any reason why 20 weeks or
22 weeks or even vaginal birth is like
the absolute moral cutoff I would watch.
What you think though,
that that's weird that you have this
like really rigid opinion on it.
I don't have any rigid opinion.
You could kill a baby.
You don't think that's rigid?
No,
cause I'm absolutely open to being
convinced out of that.
It's just I happened to read a book by
paid us sing or about that.
And so he sort of convinced me,
I mean what you would have,
that you should be able to kill a baby
when it's born.
Well,
that they would be systems in place that
would like,
that would help mothers.
I don't think that it should be,
I sort of agree with Bill Clinton's old
framing that abortion should be safe,
legal and rare,
right?
That you should have as many
opportunities for people not to get
pregnant in the first place.
Widespread contracept contraception,
widespread sex education.
Uh,
and that this should not just be a form
of birth control.
On the other hand,
if people find themselves in a horrible
pickle and that I know of how to get out
of it,
you think you should be able to hit the
baby with a rock?
I used to do it.
He has a gun.
I didn't really,
yeah.
I don't know,
Joe.
It sounds pretty horrible,
doesn't it?
It does,
but again,
you can't get pregnant.
I can't get pregnant,
so that's true.
Pete.
I could feel my kids three holes.
They're getting furious at us right now
for even discussing it because we can't
get pregnant.
They're wrong.
But you're right.
No,
I'm right that I should be able to talk
about it,
but I don't know what the answer is.
You definitely should be able to talk
about it,
but it should be able to kill a baby
with a rock.
Yeah,
probably.
Nah,
probably not.
When I talk about that,
I'll never be on death row and maybe
that's how I get on death killing my
children.
It's so evil and unsympathetic and
un-empathetic paying a blastocyst is the
same journal it is,
but you don't see that little fucker
last assistance as long as it would have
to have like reading glasses on.
Do you look at it at the head of it?
As long as you put a comforter over the
baby so you can't see what's happening.
I think what we're talking about is a
really complicated subject and I think
it's one of the reasons why people like
to box it and put it into this yes or no
black or white because it's so
complicated.
You really sit back and think that hey,
if you have an abortion at,
you know,
four weeks,
five weeks,
six,
when does it have fingers?
Yeah.
Why does it have a heartbeat?
When is it?
Okay.
And it's also incredibly fraught with
trip wires,
right?
I mean,
people are not going to be with me,
mason,
that you should be able to kill a baby
and people are not going to be happy
with you saying it should be able to
kill a blastocyst.
But I think more people will hate my
position.
Um,
if it even is a position,
well,
when does a blastocyst,
is it that the moment of conception,
like how much time do you have?
It's almost like a race to kill the
baby.
We need,
well,
some people don't think you should even
be able to use contraception.
Well,
that's right.
And also like this is one of those
things were a bit like pedophilia.
Uh,
it's,
it's a subject where it's not really
possible.
Like it's so it raises passions.
So immediately look at what happened to
Milo Yiannopoulos when he was talking
about his pedophilia stuff.
Right.
Well,
he was also talking about his own
personal experiences and framing
them in a positive way.
Yeah.
And even saying that he was a sexual
Predator last we said on my podcast when
he got on the other podcast when he was
on the drunken peasants podcast,
that's where it get got more weird
because then he started framing it in a
different way and saying that he thinks
that there is a lot of positive benefits
to a young man.
Like,
uh,
I shouldn't say young man,
a boy having a relationship with a man
sexually that can help them and that
there's positive benefits to being
molested as a young boy.
I think that's obviously a horrible
thing to say.
I think what was going on was he was
trying to rationalize his own sexual
abuse.
Hmm.
I really do.
I mean,
I think in no way,
shape or form is it comfortable for a
young boy to be sexually abused by an
older man.
And I think that in this process of
rationalization he's created this way
that's empowered him.
And he's also rationalize that he was
the Predator and he keeps saying that
and joking around about it,
but he was the attain those,
I think he's a victim and I think his,
his,
he's a very strong,
smart guy and I think a lot of his
intelligence as allowed him to use his
perception of that event to sort of
shape it into a way that benefits him.
Yeah,
right,
right.
I mean the,
I was on a TV show in Australia where
there was a question of whether or not
we should be naming and shaming sexual
offenders,
sexual predators or people who've been
convicted of sex crimes and in the
meeting before we went on air because
it's a live show,
I raised the point that like I think the
more sort of interesting and
controversial angle here is what a
bloody horrible nightmare it would be to
be born being sexually attracted towards
infants.
Right now this is in no way to diminish
the monstrosity that is pedophilia.
I think it's the worst thing that you
can do to abuse the trust of children
who are too young to know any better,
but it's surely no walk in the park like
the reason I'm not a pedophile,
it's not because I'm a good person,
it's because I have no attraction
towards children.
Right?
Imagine if the only way that you could
express yourself sexually and find
fulfillment in life was by torturing
another human being.
Like you're basically a form of,
I don't want to use the wrong word here,
but a form of,
it's a form of psychopathy in some way
in the sense that like a psychopath can
only get fulfillment by doing something
that's awful.
So the job is to try to figure out how
to stop the psychopath from doing
something awful.
I'm not saying that pedophiles,
the psychopaths,
but you can see the analogy where if
your only way of finding fulfillment in
life is to rape children,
then let's address how to figure out how
to stop you from doing that thing rather
than demonizing you as a monster,
even if you don't do it.
Yeah,
for me to even say that,
a lot of people are going to push back
on that as well,
and it's a very similar thing to where
I'm just trying to figure out in my head
what makes the most sense to me.
And as you say,
it's got to be some kind of a spectrum
of like it can't be black and white
either on abortion or on something like
pedophilia.
But the moment you start having
conversations like this shit's going to
explode because people are very,
very,
very strident.
Like you've got to protect the babies.
Like you know,
going to protect the children.
Yes,
I understand that.
But does that make it impossible for us
to have conversations about it?
Right.
That's the issue is should you even be
allowed to have a conversation about it
and should you have a rigid black or
white view of this and if you are and
well,
here's the real question.
First of all,
we don't know what causes someone to be
sexually attracted to children.
And we don't know how many of those
people,
but there's a significant amount who are
actually molested themselves.
I mean that's a huge factor in,
in child abuse.
So what,
what causes that?
I mean is it,
and here's how to,
and even more fucked up throughout
history,
some of the greatest minds have been
pedophiles,
really.
Sure.
Socrates,
Plato.
I mean you can go back through history.
They were all fucking young kids.
Well then you had the Greeks were like
that when the Romans many,
many ancient culture
that was,
I think that was adolescents though,
right?
They will fucking right
fucking 12 year olds,
like [inaudible] was talking about
pedophilia and where you're talking
about babies,
which I think is probably even more
rare.
Someone fucking young boys.
Yeah.
But it's,
it's a very bizarre part of our human
history.
Very bizarre.
And it makes you wonder how much of that
sexual abuse gets somehow or another
transferred from a child being abused to
that child growing up,
becoming an adult and becoming an abuser
themselves.
What it,
is it a cancer of ideas?
Is it a dizzy,
almost like a sexual disease that gets
spread from perpetrator to victim?
The victim becomes perpetrator,
makes new victims.
Well,
do you think it's the same act now as it
was back then?
Because it's more accepted back then it
back then.
So I wonder if,
I wonder if it wouldn't have been less,
I dunno,
maybe it's not less bad.
I'm trying to think.
I'm talking,
I'm talking now only about people who
are sexually immature.
Right?
So like someone who's like a 15 year old
catwalk model,
let's just,
let's assume that it's a woman who's
walking down the catwalks of Milan and
Paris and has what she thinks is a
consensual relationship with a 25 year
old fashion designer that's against the
law and it's regarded as being deeply on
ethical in our current society happened
all the time.
And other societies.
Yeah.
Um,
there's no,
I'm not saying that I think that the law
should be changed.
I dine,
I think it's good to have,
have laws against these things and I
don't think that it's ethically
defensible for people who are
significantly older,
um,
to assume that the person who is still
kind of evolving and still coming of age
is capable of giving proper consent.
Well,
it's illegal if to just three years
older.
That's where it gets really,
well that is weird.
That's chapel I think a week older.
Yeah,
exactly.
If they like 17 and 51 weeks and the
other person's 18 and one day it's
illegal.
That's stupid.
There's a Romeo and Juliet clause that
some countries have.
Like I think in the Netherlands it's not
against the law to have sex with people
even as young as 12 or 13 as long as if
you're 14.
Right.
Or like if you're like,
well what does the law to meditate if
you're 15 and your girlfriend's 14 does
that legal?
And I think it's the state by state
thing isn't it?
But that's a good question.
Is that what you would never be
prosecuted but the head,
there have been these,
we had cases where teenagers have been
prosecuted for high,
for having um,
like Dick pics,
all walls.
Not only their,
their boyfriends or girlfriends from,
I'm a big piece of they girlfriends
unless they're trans but of themselves.
And they've been prosecuted for child
porn because they're a child and they,
they holding pornography the whole bit
about it.
Yeah.
That whole bit about this colony.
Ridiculous.
Yeah.
They arrested her.
She was a sending boys' pictures of her
pussy and they arrested her for child
pornography.
She was 15 years old.
Yeah.
I mean that's a weird use of the law.
You know,
like if she's sending it to other girls
and boys that are her age,
it's not your business.
Who are you protecting her in jail?
No one.
But it's a,
it's a,
an ability what?
When you give someone a game called
arrest people that are doing bad,
this is,
here's the law.
If they don't,
they don't follow by the byline's.
You're allowed to lock them in a cage
and this is your job.
You're allowed to do that end.
I want you to rest a certain amount of
people per month,
otherwise you're fucked.
Yeah.
I mean that's the issue with quotas and,
and,
and police.
Yeah.
I mean it's almost like I come in,
but who I heard saying this the other
day,
that police used to go out and catch bad
guys and like solve crimes,
but now we've sort of outsourced it to
police the job of just making everything
kind of Nice.
Well,
police are glorified revenue collectors
and a lot of ways,
I mean,
why,
why are they giving people tickets for
certain traffic violations?
Yeah.
I mean the smoking a plant.
There's a lot of things that people get
arrested for where this,
they're essentially just providing money
to the system.
You know,
they're not,
they're not serving,
you're protecting.
It's funny.
It's one of the things where when I talk
to Americans about the best things about
America,
the number one thing that Americans will
always say is freedom.
That this country represents freedom.
But the actual daily experience.
Like I've lived in New York and I've
lived in Copenhagen and I lived in,
uh,
in Australia and like the daily
experience of like,
I was standing outside my apartment in
New York drinking an open beverage,
uh,
just watching the world go by and a
couple of cops came over and one of them
was like,
Yo Watson,
the glass,
what's in the glass?
And I was like,
just soda.
It was fuck soda,
And his,
his partner had to be like,
oh,
don't worry about it.
Like,
come on,
don't make a big deal out of it.
And they walked away.
But I was like,
go to a park in everyone's drinking
beer.
It's,
no,
they're not getting harassed by cops.
Isn't that a kind of freedom as well?
We're taking off their shirts and their
playing volleyball,
topless breasts hanging out.
You're talking about one specific area
because if you go to New Orleans,
people walked down the street drinking
all the time.
Yes.
And it's more free.
Yeah.
If you're in Vegas,
people walked on the stage second.
Yeah.
I mean,
is it better to live in Vegas or New
Orleans?
You know,
some people would say yes and other
people would say,
I don't want that for the children.
It's bad for the children that are
abort.
That's wrong.
I don't know,
man.
I,
I mean it's complex.
The,
all these issues are very complex.
It's like when,
when should you just let people run free
and ramp into the point where chaos and
suse and here's another problem then
that was talking about this with a
friend of mine the other day about North
Korea.
Um,
when people have become sort of
indoctrinated into a specific style of
life and behavior and then all of a
sudden you remove the rains.
Like when people who live in Kansas go
to Vegas and bay
as opposed to someone who grows up in
that environment.
Or like say we were,
we were looking at the North Korea
footage yesterday of them goose stepping
down the street and the giant throngs of
people who are following the orders and
doing the bidding of Kim Jong.
And we're saying like what would happen
to those people if you're a move this
military dictatorship gave them a
democratic life,
would they even be able to appreciate it
and understand it or are they so
institutionalized or they so
indoctrinated into this very specific
style of living in behavior that they
wouldn't be able to adjust?
Like I talked to Ron miscavige about
that,
you know,
who is he got out of scientology when he
was fucking 76 I mean stop and think
about that.
The guy got in in 1970 and got out in
2012 live the bulk of his life in this
really bizarre environment and now all
of a sudden he's a free man.
I think that's right.
And this is one of my concerns about,
about laws that prevent people from
doing things.
This is why I'm sort of libertarian ish
when it comes to non economic cultural
issues because I actually think you need
to inculcate in people and experience of
showing restraint on the bus by
themselves.
Because if the law is does it for you,
you,
you then remove the laws and all of a
sudden everyone goes crazy.
It's a bit,
you know,
you can imagine that if all of a sudden
street drinking were permitted in New
York that people will be vomiting all
over the place and like getting,
getting drunk because they've been so
used to so acclimated to never being
allowed to do it.
That now it's the forbidden fruit.
Go and just get smashed in the past
because that's what we can,
we can do now.
Well,
do you know about Amish Amish?
Yeah.
Rubber spring.
When they get to do that,
what was the hell's playground?
Is that the documentary in the Senate?
There's a great documentary about it.
And these,
these people,
they have this period of time where
they're allowed to do whatever the fuck
they want.
It's basically when they come maintains,
right,
they,
they let loose from the amish
communities and they were allowed to
indulge jay go hog wild hog where they
go,
they party fucking hard and then they
have to
figure out whether or not they want to
go back to being amish.
Hmm.
And most of them do.
Yeah.
Strange.
It's interesting that you used the word
institutions joe to describing like
North Korea because I think this is
another thing that I'm so grateful about
America for and why I'm sort of
optimistic that trump is not going to
destroy this,
this country that institutions like this
sounds like such a valley girl thing to
say.
I was going to say institutions like
really matter
but,
but it's,
but it's true.
You look at places like Hungary and what
we've just seen happen in Turkey and in
Russia,
in Venezuela.
And it's much easier for people there
who are corrupt or who would like to,
to,
um,
to bring people under their spell to do
so because there aren't these big robust
divided institutions like the press
being fiercely independent,
the judicial system being fiercely
independent,
uh,
Congress and the executive hopefully
hating each other just enough to keep
each other in check,
keep themselves in check.
And also just the,
the,
the traditions of American life where
there's,
there's I think more acceptance of
descent and of weirdness than there are
in those other places.
Like Russians are just very,
I don't want to generalize here,
but allow me to conformist people,
like they've lived under csas and
fucking empires for centuries and
millennia.
Like they like following strong men.
Americans aren't like that.
And some of them are,
there is this kind of militaristic
jingoistic side to America,
which is very kind of like salute the
flag and like say yes please.
Like you got to honor the honor,
the veterans and everything.
But yeah,
but yeah,
exactly.
Respect the office or like kind of
stuff.
And I think that way tyranny lies.
I think the best,
the best thing as a mayor that America
has ever kind of given the world is its
flamboyant,
boisterous sense of possibility and
craziness that expresses itself in
Silicon Valley.
And maybe Peter Teal who I might not
like,
but at least he's unusual in Hollywood.
You know,
even in Wall Street there are a whole
bunch of,
there's just an excitement in this
place,
which,
which seeps out in so many different
ways in America that I think to try to
corral it as a dictator would be like
herding cats.
Like it'll just never,
you know,
it'll never,
it'll never quite right.
Well we can only hope because if trump
has his way,
he would definitely try to do that.
He would try to get all these people to
do his bidding and figure out some way
to dismantle all of these different
institutions and make it much easier for
him to make America great again and just
fucking force that agenda through.
Yeah.
I don't,
didn't think he would think that he's
doing the wrong thing.
Woody.
I don't know.
Do you think,
I mean he said he admires Putin.
I mean,
which is very bizarre.
it's very bizarre.
And when he compared what Putin does to
what we do,
that we do terrible things to like,
whoa,
that's crazy.
That guy murders people on the street.
I mean he,
any political opposition,
he fucking kills them.
He kills reporters mean or somebody
does,
I don't know if it's him or somebody
does
right outside the Kremlin.
A W know on the main bridge leading to
the Kremlin at night and all of the
security cameras from the Kremlin
happened to go off and have their
footage missing just when the murder,
it's insane.
The amount of power that he wields.
His stunning.
Yeah.
If someone on the left in America said,
Oh,
who's who?
Who are we to say that Putin is a bad
guy?
I think of all the bad things that
America's done
just
right.
That's a kind of Noam Chomsky thing to
say,
America's America's chickens are coming
home to roost.
We did this in Vietnam and now so you
know when I better than Putin,
fuck that.
I mean,
it's the right that's supposed to
believe in American exceptionalism.
Just not trump.
Isn't that well,
he's got a very bizarre interests in
Russia and that's one of the reasons I
think why he was want to release his
taxes.
The real,
the real question is how much money does
he have invested in Russia?
Like how much,
how much financial influence do they
have on him?
I wonder if part of it is when he says
that he admired someone like Putin,
if it's just his sort of constitutional
sense that he kind of likes a strong
man,
like his isn't his whole life sort of
about I am powerful,
I am rich,
you know you're going to kneel before me
and people who can pull that off.
I think just resonate with him in some
way that's more so I've always found
like the how much money does they have
invested in Russia question somewhat
less interesting to me.
Then why does he want to suck Putin's
Dixon Ma,
you know like is it the whole mean
interpretation,
a convenient interpretation of what
Putin represents because he doesn't
really have time to look at all these
different things.
You know,
it was revealed the other day that he's
not really aware that Kim Jong loons.
Dot.
Kim Jong Il.
Did you see that?
It is confusing.
There are too many Kim's in the careers,
but you did not say that
there's like this ridiculous thing where
he was talking about this gentleman,
he was talking about Kim Jong and he was
referring to conversations that Kim Jong
Il has had with Bush and I mean the
whole thing.
I think there's too many things to focus
on and he's so fucking busy with himself
and his business interests and the
things that he's trying to push through
and we're going to Exxon mobile and all
these different subsidiaries that he's
kind of invested in.
He's got his fucking fingers in so many
different pies and he's also just not
interested in the affairs of state.
He doesn't care about foreign policy and
stuff like it's,
it's a little bit,
he doesn't like learning and stuff.
He doesn't like it.
He's not a good reader or what's one of
the big concerns is that he's not
concerned with foreign policy to the
point where he's putting off all these
things and letting the military do their
job in quotes.
Did you see the point that he didn't
even authorize the mother of all bombs
when it was dropped on Afghanistan last
week?
The military,
the option to do what they think is
right.
And that's what Eisenhower warned about
when he left on.
That's right.
But in some crazy way,
don't you feel more safe
with the military doing it then with
trump doing it in some way?
Yes,
absolutely.
Well,
I think there's a real argument that the
military has been,
that they've been held back to the Paul.
They have,
I mean,
look,
you're engaging in war,
right?
And that there's a real argument that
the people in the military make that
people die because they're forced to
take too many steps before they get
clearance to do something when they're
being attacked.
And so their argument is it's better to
let people who really understand war
engage in more,
but then there's the eisenhower argument
that,
well,
you're dealing with an institution like
the military industrial complex.
You're dealing with a l I can think of
it as an organism that survives on war
it,
there's a tremendous amount of money
that gets pumped into this,
this thing that this war machine.
Yep.
Right.
And then what does it want to do?
It wants to fucking use all the
statistics that a war.
That's right.
Have you noticed how the the military
contractors,
if you looked at how,
how delicately spread out around America
that like they have plants in almost
every single state so that there's
always a congressperson or a senator who
are the military contractors can call up
and be like,
well you,
you're going to lose like 70,000 jobs in
this little,
of course shit.
Potel it'd actually be more,
it would make more economic sense for
them to have consolidated their
operations and be making all the
submarines and warships in the same
place,
but they don't.
They make one widget in Delaware,
then make another one over here.
Another one over here.
It's very select got congressman.
Yeah.
No one's ever going to want that plant
to close.
It's like mudgee things that we've
talked about today.
There's super complicated and there's so
many different things to consider and
it's no real one black and white answer
when when you're dealing with so many
factions in so many variables and so
many things.
That's one of the reasons why being a
president is a preposterous idea.
Is it?
It's stupid.
It's stupid,
isn't it?
If I have too much power,
I mean you talk about black and white
and you like shades of gray.
How do you negotiate with the North
Koreans and the South Koreans and the
Chinese and the Japanese and the
Russians about what to do about Syria?
We'll show a Syria.
Yeah.
Shit.
I mean in some ways.
What did you think of the tree of trump
hitting Syria?
Well,
no one died,
right?
What he did was attack airfields and
blew up airfields.
It was a show of force,
you know,
is it the right thing to do?
Shit.
I don't,
I don't know.
Um,
I don't understand exactly what is
accomplished other than you blow up an
airfield and have to rebuild it.
I mean,
you show people that you can do that,
but we already knew you could do that.
You show people you're willing to act.
I mean,
back in 2012 and 2013 I thought that
Obama flubbed it by saying that we
wouldn't tolerate the use of chemical
weapons and then doing nothing when
reaction by the right and the left
people were very weird war back.
Absolutely.
I think they've relaxed a little over
that.
Yeah.
When will willing to to go in and get a
break.
Yeah,
exactly.
Hold on,
I'm going back in.
It's like,
you know,
when you go in the pool,
you swim for a while,
then I come back out again.
I want to get cool again without,
with a nice foreign war.
Yeah.
There was Vietnam and we didn't like
that and then we can forget it,
bad it long enough.
So we did it rock and we didn't like
that.
But now that's kind of fading,
receding into the,
into the distant past as well.
But I,
yeah,
I,
I actually interviewed Phil Donahue on
huffpost live because he was a very
outspoken antiwar critic.
And I was saying at the time,
like,
can't we be nuanced enough to make a
difference,
but to understand the difference between
the Iraq war,
a full scale invasion based on a
misunderstanding or a misleading
interpretation of what Iraq's
capabilities.
And it's mean,
it's,
um,
weapons program was,
and this Syrian problem,
which is a horrifying civil war where a
dictator is gassing his own people and
we didn't want to invade,
but drawing some kind of a line in the
sand and saying,
you can't do that in the 21st century.
You can't just be dropping gas canisters
on kids.
So they bleed out their eyes and like
cough up their own lungs.
That's not a way to behave in the United
States as an exceptional nation.
And we'll do something about that.
You're right.
That about it really had his hands tied
because he went to Congress and Congress
didn't give him the power to do it,
but I kind of felt somehow sort of
slightly vindicated when trump did it.
Like I was not one of the people on the
left who was like,
oh my goodness,
what's he doing?
I was like,
well,
okay.
I mean at least that's a,
at least it's something
I agree.
But it's also an incredibly complicated
situation because Assad is against Isis.
Okay?
Superficially,
yes,
but
he uses isis as an excuse to be able to
target all of his political opponents.
It's too much.
It's too twice.
It's two twice dead end.
There's no way to get rid of isis
without getting rid of Assad because the
locals in Syria who will lift height
Assad,
who would,
who are anti Assad,
they hate aside even more than they hate
isis.
So as long as Assad is there,
they're going to give isis their
sympathies.
So this idea of like,
I mean,
basically the whole isis thing I think
is just a smokescreen to allow Putin and
Assad to crackdown on dissidents.
But isn't it also like a lot of the same
issues that they faced when they
dethroned Khadafi in Libya you create
this to happen.
Exactly.
I think it's too late.
Failed State.
Yeah.
I think we've missed the,
we missed the boat in Syria or what the
fuck,
what do we do?
President Josh Zaps?
What do we do?
We build a time machine,
Joe and uh,
we go back to 2012 there's not much you
can do that.
And I did.
They probably wasn't even much we could
do.
Do you think you can imagine,
oh wait,
you should have like one president that
deals with just Syria.
Like that should be your 100% that's
right.
The idea of having a president that also
deals with Exxon Mobil and BP and then
also was talking to the coal people and
also is talking to the people in Silicon
Valley.
You know why you haven't administration,
right.
I mean,
so the,
the secretary of State is broadly
overseeing it and then they will have a
special envoy to the Middle East who
should be split,
who is basically as the president of the
president of the United States for
Syria.
Yeah.
And then Sean Spicer's in,
in charge of cleaning up lies.
I mean that's what he's using
alternative facts.
President.
Do you think that that the world would
be better or worse off if America had
just stayed completely out of the Middle
East from like the end of the Cold War
on,
I don't know.
And I don't know how you fix the problem
of military dictatorships.
How do you,
how do you stop that?
How do you overthrow them?
I mean the CIA has been battling that
for years.
I mean,
they will propping them up or propping
them up or propping them up and shooting
them down or you know,
trying to keep that issue over there and
keeping them from becoming big enough
where they spread to the point where
they become another Nazi Germany or what
have you.
It's a really good question and I'm too
fucking stupid to give you an answer.
I mean,
who knows.
I mean look,
it's just disturbing that something like
North Korea can exist in 2017.
I want to go,
I really want to go to North Korea.
I think it'd be fascinating.
Really.
Yeah.
Cause it's like the last kind of hermit
kingdom lift.
It's the last true Soviet era.
Communist dictatorship.
You can probably control.
Yeah.
I think you can.
I mean,
but the problem is you have to be kind
of um,
you know,
accompanied by a Chaperon who works for
the government who only shows you the
things that the government wants you to
say.
Henry Rollins went,
that's right.
He to died show.
Yeah.
That's so gangster.
He's so good.
I was in New Zealand actually listening
to your epis to that episode at the,
at the lounge in Oakland airport,
coming back to Australia a couple of
months ago.
And Henry was really inspiring to me in
that episode because it made me realize
like,
yeah,
just because I'm getting old and like
I'm going to be a dad and everything
doesn't mean you have to lose your sense
of adventure.
That dude is bad ass.
He's got a hundred percent sense of
adventure to the point where he won't
have a relationship.
He's like,
it's not,
it's not worth it.
It's just too much work.
But he's also an interesting case study
in giving kids medication,
a very early age.
He was one of the very early Prozac
kids.
Oh really?
Yeah.
They are Ritalin rather.
Yeah,
they hooked him up.
They hooked him up with Ritalin when he
was fucking five years old,
man,
from five years old to high school.
How does he feel about that now?
Terrible.
I mean he just described it like it's
horrible,
like he's white knuckled his way through
the day and the end of the day the
Ritalin would wear off and he'd be
exhausted and we'd go through class.
I mean that's a good chunk of his
intense personality and behavior has to
do with him being raised on speed.
Yeah,
just crazy.
It's funny how it has a different impact
on people who have add and then people
who don't.
Right.
It doesn't us.
Yeah.
Well what is add,
you know what I mean?
It's a real thing,
but how does it manifest itself in a
person and how does it manifest in a
person that is formed in this
environment where they're forced to be
in is a rigid,
controlled social experiment called
school.
That's right.
And why do we have classroom?
Why don't we,
it has to be 30 people and they all have
to be sitting in a row.
And then he said,
program you to have a regular job that
you don't have.
Yeah,
I don't have,
he doesn't have,
there's a lot of people that don't have
jobs where you have to work in a fucking
cubicle.
Well that's one thing that I assumed we
would have.
We would have gotten to today,
which I'm surprised we didn't,
which is like the rise of automation and
robotics and stuff.
I mean,
millions.
How many millions of Americans,
I think it's the largest,
the largest employment sector full
working class males is driving self
driving cars.
It just around the bloody corner.
What's going to happen to the millions
of Americans who make a living driving
trucks?
The big solution to that that a lot of
people bring up is universal basic
income,
but universal basic income,
uh,
you know there's,
there's people that have a problem with
that because they believe that people
are only motivated by want and then as
soon as you give them money,
then they're not going to just pursue
their interest.
They're going to lay around and do
nothing and just live off of that money
only.
Well,
the,
and this also the question of whether or
not that's right or wrong and comes back
to America's sort of puritan work work
ethic as well,
right?
The idea that it would necessarily be
wrong for a person not to be doing
something productive,
but like if the robots are doing all the
work and they're producing lots of
wealth,
then who cares if someone's doing
something productive or not.
Right?
We're worried that they're going to get
mad at the people like you that are out
there being ambitious and they're gonna
kill me.
Mercedes.
Well maybe I would sometimes not do
anything as well.
I'm Australian.
What criminals?
We have a saying that,
thank God we were convicted by Woo,
thank God we were settled by convicts
instead of by Puritans to well it's a
good point.
I mean we've,
we've fighting off the echoes of those
fucking ridiculous instincts from the
puritans Atlanta to here.
We're still fighting that off.
I mean that's a big part of what America
is.
Yeah.
I think that would be a big impediment
to universal basic income.
The set,
this puritan sense of justice that there
is justice and also
I think maybe people just want work.
They want purpose.
Like the people who were retrenched have
purpose as well as universal basic
income.
You would have to sort of program it
into the Zeitgeists of the culture,
right?
And give people what voluntary ways of
expressing themselves and contributing
that weren't tied to their income.
Encourage people to pursue actual
interests.
Like say if you gave people universal
basic income and encourage them to
pursue artistic venues or ventures,
you know,
whether it's a writing or painting or
whenever the fuck it is.
And you say,
look,
there's a lot of merit in that.
Like you and you can do this.
Your food is bought you,
you have,
you have a home,
you can eat and you can sleep.
You have a roof over your head now.
Do what you want.
What do you want to do?
I think it'd be a fence.
It's a fantastic experiment and I'm glad
that there are a few little
jurisdictions in Scandinavia and Canada,
which seem to be trying it out because
I'd be interested to know how many,
like there are,
you could,
you could imagine different groupings of
human psychology.
Like some people will be like,
awesome,
I don't have to worry about making
money.
I'm going to become the greatest
artisinal,
you know,
furniture maker that I can,
and that's fantastic.
And then at the other end of the
spectrum,
there'll be people who are like,
sweet,
don't have to work.
Like I'm just going to sit at home.
That's fine too day.
What else be that crime rates lower
because of that.
Oh,
I'm sure that's what we should be hoping
for it and the idea,
the real good argument for universal
basic income is that the money that you
spend giving people certain universal
basic income you would save money from
people going to jail,
juvenile detention,
medical issues,
all sorts of issues that come out of
poverty.
There's a lot of issues that come out of
poverty that are directly connected to
that.
Yeah.
This is one of the arguments for welfare
as well.
I mean people who say that it wouldn't
have any impact on crime.
I would just say look at the different
countries in the world that have more or
less generous welfare systems and the
ones with more generous welfare systems
do tend to be more peaceful places.
There might be other reasons as well.
I think they're correlated and I think
also one of the things that I try to do,
I really try to support people who make
things and make things by hand.
People companies that like make stuff.
I like when people make stuff.
I like when when people pursue like,
like this,
this tables,
I mean by an artist,
you know,
I like when people make handmade knives.
I'd like that stuff.
I think the more API,
I think people get deep satisfaction in
doing things like that.
You know,
like I'm Russell Bill,
the guy made that clock right there.
That's a handmaid clock.
That dude built that fucking thing.
That one.
This tgg studios.
It built that right there.
That's a handmade clock too.
I tried to support that shit as much as
possible.
I think that that is the future.
The there's,
there's,
when I look at that clock,
I know a guy made that.
Yeah,
that means something to me.
Yeah.
It's cool.
It is also a really cool looking at,
if you asked me to make a clock,
wouldn't know where to start.
Well,
you would figure it out.
I would if you gave them the books and
all that stuff,
but you might,
it might not be a clock for you and
Maggie.
Yeah,
that,
that Buddhist sculpture.
Somebody made that and send it to me.
It's great.
I mean there's a lot of things that
people can make that other people would
enjoy.
And I think our teasel goods and
services and things that people do that
are hand crafted,
they have a special meaning to them that
people they value.
I wonder if there's something that's
mass produced.
I wonder if enough people can find self
expression through that to counteract
the uh,
the job losses that are resulting from
and will continue to result from
technological advance.
Well,
I think that with universal basic income
is possible,
but I think making things is not
necessarily the only way to do it.
I mean it's,
it has making art,
being creative,
encouraging
people to think of that as an actual way
to live.
Yeah,
that's a big,
that's a big impediment and a big hurdle
to get over it.
It's like the North Korea thing that you
were saying,
like if you got rid of the North Korean
regime,
would the people who lived under it have
the scope,
have the just a mental scope to know
what to do with themselves?
In some ways it's a comparable question
with capitalism,
right?
If you took away the capitalist
incentive to work and suddenly all of a
sudden everybody was liberated and had a
basic income that that gave them all the
sustenance that they need.
Would they have the horizons available
to them?
Having been raised in this idea of like,
you gotta get gotta work,
I gotta climb your way up the ladder.
I got to get a nine to five job,
go to college,
get an education,
you know,
please the boss,
get your promotion to have all of that
suddenly fall away and be like,
you know what?
Just go and make clocks.
But Cy,
you anyway,
boob would figure it out,
but other people would be like,
lottery winners.
They just go crazy.
Yeah.
Like lottery winners almost universally
lose all their money.
I know.
And they end up on the happier they,
yeah.
If you just,
if you win $5 million in the lottery,
everybody goes,
Josh,
come on.
It's free for you.
I can't hillsborough.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yup,
that's right.
And then people start,
look,
you and I are going to do a business.
We're going to paint cars.
You're like,
fuck,
I don't want pink cars.
And next thing you know your loan and
money out and family wants money from
you and you're just dealing with a lot
of bullshit.
And also you have expectations
immediately after winning that things
are going to get a lot better.
As you know from anyone who has paid
attention to there the process of their
own consciousness,
whether that's through psychedelics or
flotation tanks or you know what Sam
Harris and Dan Harris,
we're talking about recently about
meditation.
Your,
your conscious perception of life is not
determined by what's going on outside.
It is trivially occasionally and like
into like for in the short term,
but in the long term,
your actual happiness,
it comes from within.
But people always take the path of least
resistance.
And oftentimes the path of least
resistance is these patterns that we've
carved into our behavior,
these behavior patterns that we've
carved into our psyche.
And a lot of times those aren't even the
path of least resistance.
They become the path of more resistance,
but we're so accustomed to those paths
that we think of them and treat them as
if they're the right path.
Hmm.
Mind blown.
Fucking man.
There's no answers.
There's no answers to a portion.
There's no answers in North Korea.
We didn't figure out shit.
It's not the point.
Joe Pine to figure it out.
Let's end this and do yours.
Yeah.
Wonderful.
I'll talk to you.
I'm going to do like a quick,
quick round of questions and also
chickasha terrestrials on my podcast
with Joe.
Josh motherfucking steps.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you,
sir.
I love you.
I love you too,
brother.
All right.
We'll be right back with Josh as apps.