Hey everybody, this episode of the
podcast is brought to you by Squarespace.
Squarespace is the all in one platform
that makes it fast and easy to create
your own professional website.
Used to be a long time ago that it was
a real pain in the ass to get a website.
If you want to get a website, you have
to find someone who knew how to make one.
They had a code in html,
it was a nightmare and then they started
making these programs like Dreamweaver
and all these very difficult to learn
and try to figure out how to put it
together and then if it worked it
wouldn't work on certain platforms.
Now Squarespace has that
all covered and a buddy,
I mean you meet any person can,
if you could attach a photo to an email,
you can make a beautiful
professional looking website.
It's very simple drag and drop interface.
They have 24 seven support
there. They work on windows, Mac,
PC, I, iPhones, android.
Very easy to do about
as easy as you can get.
They also have it available so that you
can create your own online store quick
and easy credit in minutes. They have
a logo creator. We can create a clean,
simple logo design for
yourself in minutes.
Every design automatically includes a
unique mobile experience that matches your
overall style of your website.
So your content will look great
on every device at every time.
And for a free trial and
10% off your first purchase,
go to squarespace.com and
enter the code word Joe.
That's squarespace.com and
We're also brought to you by on it on it
is a human optimization website. Well,
we sell is strength and conditioning
equipment, health and fitness supplements.
We just tried to sell what we find
to be the best things available,
whether it's Kettlebells,
we sell kettlebells,
both the regular kettle
bells that we sell.
And we also have primal bells and
Zombie Bells, these artistic, um,
kettle bells that are, uh, the, the
pronto bells are the great ape collection,
gorilla, orangutan chimp, and how
we're monkey. Very cool to look at.
Cool to have around the gym.
They look good and they're functional.
Three d mapped kettle bells,
so it's not like they're out of balance
just for the sake of looking cool there,
there 3d balanced. Um, the best kettle
bells you can buy and when you use them,
you can be content that
when the apocalypse comes,
these fucking things will be still here.
They're solid metal that will
last forever. And the excellent,
we sell the best supplements
that we can find.
The best hemp force protein powder.
We have a new item called a warrior bar.
It's made, uh, the ancient, the code
away. It's a, a buffalo supplement bar.
Um, so like if you're, you know,
you're on the run and you need to get
some food in your body and you just want
to have a snack that's not
negative and not nasty for you.
This warrior bar has 140 calories,
four grams of fat per serving,
and 14 grams of protein. All
healthy, no MSG, no soy, no lactose,
no nitrates, no antibiotics,
no added hormones. Super,
super healthy for you and
like all things on it.
We just find whatever we can that is
the best version of whatever that is for
sale.
And then we sell it.
We try to sell it to you at the
most reasonable rate possible.
If you use the Codeword Rogan,
you will save 10% off
eight and all supplements. All right.
Why play around Hixon Gracie is here,
ladies and gentlemen and my brother
Eddie Bravo, Cuban music. Jamie,
let's get going.
Rogan, experience by day.
Joe Rogan, podcast by night.
All Day.
All right. We are live. First of all,
thank you very much for doing this.
I appreciate it at all the people online
when whenever things get brought up for
mixed martial arts guests or Jujitsu gas,
it's always get Hixon Gracie
on the podcast. So the,
the clouds have parted,
the stars have aligned and you're
here and we appreciate it very much.
I'm very thankful to Joe and Eddie to
be with you guys here and have this
conversation. Uh, it's,
it's funny because last time we
talk and my house, why our goal?
Um, of course you, you make me some
questions. You cure you is you,
you all about knowing what is what has
in my mind and at this point I was the
talker and um,
you know,
in the past and the time goes by.
And should they,
I can see after all this process of
evolutionary process in the MMA and the
martial arts world,
I mean,
since then I've been
watching you doing your job,
do command in fights, analyzing other
fighters and should, they can see man,
you a red belt and the whole in
the whole extension of the word,
you know everything you mean.
If I have a question,
I have a coach to call you and ask
you what's up because I'm very, very,
I mean impressed with your career,
with your charisma, with the way you,
you position your opinions in zones.
Very precise.
So I'm very happy to be here and
discuss some talks and talk with you.
Thank you brother. That's
an honor to me. And uh,
it was an honor for me to hang out with
you that night. It was really cool for a,
we had dinner with your family and
then we watch some fights. Yeah.
And it was really interesting watching
fights with you and watching you
breakdown positions and breakdown
the mistakes that people were making.
And I've told a lot of people about that,
man.
I'm throwing a lot of people about
that night. That documentary a choke.
Uh, that is one document
that I've told people,
if you really interested in Jujitsu, you
really want to find out, you know what,
what the spirit of Jujitsu is all about.
Watch the documentary choke that
documentary. So inspirational.
They followed you, was it in 94? 95?
Yeah. 95. [inaudible] 96
[inaudible] 95 going [inaudible]
96 and you were fighting in Japan,
in the Japan valley to doe and it
documented a lot of your training and
documented your philosophy and man,
whenever I, if I ever need some,
I'll slap
that DVD on.
He just get fired up.
You wanted to go see and do some yoga
on the beach or something? Yeah, no,
it's fine. How did that come about?
What? That documentary, Oh, was it
project we fight student of mine who
was working with the polygraph and also,
uh, cop. So he decided,
we decided to follow up to
the event. And so we, we,
they have a crew following
couple of fighters and a and uh,
follow myself to see what's going
to happen at the event. So it was a,
a nice,
uh,
introduction to a preparation
to the mindset of a fighter,
either myself or the Todd Haynes.
What's another,
and also the Japanese guy who was
also involved from the filming.
So it was a cool Brian will
experience tool to an MMA fight.
Like I've only to the fight.
Well,
it's very eye opening for a lot of
fighters who looked at mixed martial arts.
A lot of them come from a
wrestling background and
they looked at mixed martial
arts, more of like as a sport just
beat tough, you know, you gotta get up,
you've got to train hard,
you got to run hard,
you gotta live hard and your philosophy
was much more like a Samurai.
Your philosophy was much deeper,
much more meditation base.
And we got to see you
doing yoga. You, you,
I think you opened up a lot of people's
eyes to a different mindset involved in
preparation,
but also to yoga.
That was the first time I'd ever seen a
martial artist that was really into yoga.
Yes. I think, uh, for
the athlete in general,
the breathing and the understanding of
the breathing is a big plus because he
stretch or your,
I mean by hyperventilate you stretch
or physical potential by know how to
breathe properly.
You relax,
you can bring your heart beats.
Lower is a lot of elements in
the breathing who are involved.
We've controlling emotions,
getting more energy and so on.
So as I get exposed to
Brett to breathing properly,
I get addicted and I felt like was
a huge, uh, element of, you know,
too. In addition to the techniques,
in addition to the heart,
into the heart training,
learning the breathing is,
is a huge beneficial
thing for the athlete.
Now you see athletes,
like tennis players, they,
Oh hey, they play in breathing and the
breathing, the breath is much more,
do they support you?
They,
so it's a process of knowing
now I see grown, my son, he's,
I'm in before. He's just like, see all
that. I see you training and Brita.
But now he's coming to me and said that
this make all the difference in the ward
when I really, you know, start,
you're getting tired to make
hyperventilation and keep my,
in my mind like sharp because
sometimes you should get tired. Uh,
the is not enough oxygen
in the blood to fuel your,
your sharpness in your mind. So
you become a little, uh, stupid,
a little slower, you
know? So by having a good,
knowing how to hyperventilate,
you able to, to maximize this,
this oxygen you. So even though the
acid electric take over your body,
your mind is too sharp and you're
still responding accordingly.
So it's a great thing to do. And you were
born into the greatest Jujitsu family,
the greatest martial arts family of all
time. I mean, there's no doubt about it.
There's no,
there's not even a second place.
There's the Gracie family and then
there's, you know, there's the,
I guess you could have a debate
about who comes in second,
but it's kind of ridiculous that that
is the number one martial arts family of
all time. And you obviously learn
Jujitsu from a very early age,
but how did you get involved into
the yoga? Always, you know, uh,
was,
I'm very happy to,
to be related with this
master call learned to Connie,
which was the precursor
of the [inaudible].
I was learning at the same time over
the homeowner who is the guy who is now
making the tapes we learning together,
you know. And um, at that point,
um, it was just practic scene
with him. Like he loaned my,
my father, he's a older guy who's a very
tough athlete and also a yoga teacher.
So he combined,
he developed some kind of style of yoga,
which is not exactly a postural black
postures and breathing to relax or to
achieve meditation was more like a,
an active breeding for athletes. And,
and are there for you to jump higher.
You have to know how to,
to have arm when you, between
your, your jump in your breathing.
You want to keep Marty
strength for more long time.
You have to know how to breed a
quarterly chew to promote that.
So he has always,
he always in the active active
breathing and then we kind of,
we started doing privates and I
was in his place for, you know,
for a couple of months,
his guiding me through the,
the moves in front of a
mirror in a nice room one day.
Um,
we about to start the class
and sooner he's about to start.
Uh, he, he was calling the
phone and he said to me,
Hixon you keep going
and I'll be right back.
So for the first time I was able to breed,
make my routine without follow him up
without having my mind focus in what he
was doing. So I start to breathe
and move and breathe and move,
and then has some woods on the walls,
kind of.
We cannot imitate monkeys to
climb the wooed and stuff.
So in one point I come back to reality
and then I was on top of the highest
frame in the wall sweating like a pig.
And then I look around and start to come
back to reality and I saw him on the
corner crying and then I, what's up man?
What's going on? He said, man, you don't
have to learn anything else from me.
You achieve the highest level of Gut,
get empty mine. And
then I kinda said, why?
I say that said Yeah because you here for
an hour, 50 minutes in, completely off.
I mean you didn't notice anything because
he was applying did development of the
animal instinct,
which takes your brain off,
you're in your mind,
your your concentration and keep
you more like a instinctive anymore.
And that's was the vision in through this.
Because before that I was doing
transcendental meditation.
I did traditional yoga and and those
never did great for me in the meditation.
I was sleeping and it's not,
by doing that kind of routine,
I W I was able to not just breathing
properly but also achieve empty mine.
And I was like in a state of meditation,
Meditation State,
uh, for a long time,
like not concentrating in
anything like rational, oh,
he's there or he's, so I was able to
get a achieve like, uh, I empty mine.
And after I noticed that I start
to practice my routines to,
to get that same feeling of emptiness.
And that kind of meditation
works for me as no, no other one.
And I felt like being an
empty mine increases my,
my, I don't know, my, my intuition
increases my, my sense of,
of energy and so was incredible for
me because I could get in touch more
comfortably with my, I
mean, my third vision,
I don't know exactly explained,
but I could achieve a completely
peace of mine in that kind of routine.
So I was stick for life.
So you just got into this state and you
could just exist. No conscious thought,
no thinking about anything around
you and no past, no future.
Just exist is in our moment
as act with no context. Yes.
That's a kind of a weird positive feeling
because you capable to be present in a
sense which, uh, if
you have your mind set,
if you have something
expectations or you never there.
So I was able to,
to,
to be very confident very easily to get
into that situation where even prior to
the fight I'm able to sleep on the,
on the locker room,
making my workout, getting
a high, very high heartbeat.
And then like five minutes
before I make my praise,
I make my meditation and I kind of cool
off my heartbeat to 60 60 heartbeats a
minute. So I was able to engage
very hot and with the hard,
very hard, low heartbeat.
And as the fight progress,
the pace is very hard.
If I'm 60 he is 80 when I'm,
he's a Honda Day.
When I'm a Honda,
he's 120 when I'm 120 he's a 45th so
when he started to re have to regroup,
I was still having to go forward.
So at that point my opponents
always lose a little B. He is bay.
So I ended up time for me to make
the, the, the kill, you know,
so it was always working properly for me.
They re the breathing was
always working very well.
So this empty mind state
enhanced your Jujitsu,
this ability to achieve this state on
top of all the techniques on top of all
the training and the instincts.
This took it to the next level? Yes,
because you know in one point if
you allowed yourself to be present,
you're not commit to the office
or the defense, you commit,
you give nothing and take everything.
So you give me opportunity that will
be there. If you try to be surprise me,
I will be there a
quarterly defending myself.
So he's all on the table is like no
surprises because he's no expectations.
So keeping a coal mine,
even when it's boiling is something I
felt like was always like a something
which gives me an edge because I was there
just to either catch what is there or
resolved the problem.
Never disappointed or never a late,
no expectation. Yeah. And
he's always late. I mean,
sometimes we get late because you plan
something in the fight and it doesn't
happen. So we've well is you
start to be disappointed.
So for me it was always like whatever
happened, I'm there, I'm happy,
comfortable finding comfortable finding
the sharpness to, to achieve success,
you know? So letting great, you
grew up in this Jujitsu family,
but you were always,
at least from most
people's interpretation,
you were always the best guy out
of the family. How did that happen?
How did you rise above all the rest? I
mean you grew up with a bunch of killers.
Yes, everybody's trainee hired. Everybody
was pushing through the maximum.
And um,
for one point I feel like I'm as
dedicated and for perfectionist,
I'm competitive in my heart,
but some elements I get
was more like a god.
A God gift is not exactly
something I choose.
So we training the same,
why my brother,
I can play with my blood brothers and
they cannot have a chance with me.
So that's kind of hard to explain.
It's not me trying to do this.
This just happened is my, is my
self being, trying to be my best,
plus the emotional control,
the peace of mind. It was all,
you know, for example, my love, my,
my beloved brother Heuler,
he's a great fighter with sometimes
we get too emotional, you know,
and that's kind of times
makes him choose the home,
the wrong path. So
hoists he's a, you know,
great fighter,
but sometimes
he,
he get a little confused.
He's not having the sharp offensive
attitude or so sometimes something sleep,
um, you know, and so on.
So I not exactly know why I'm,
I'm the one,
I just have to represent and be,
you know, happy to be the one.
And I tell him, man, all
the opportunities, I have
to represent ideas already.
So I feel like completely
comfortable in myself saying, okay,
I have nothing to prove to myself.
I did all. And uh, you know,
I'm very happy with the results.
So, Jujitsu for life, for life.
Your brother that's not on Jamie,
sorry. You're, uh,
you had a cousin holes,
Gracie.
This legendary holds
Gracie who was actually,
halls is in the DNA. He's Mike. My cousin,
but he was leaving in my house,
CSI born because my uncle as he,
he's,
he divorced from his wife.
He hauls mother,
he give,
my father was just get
married so he give Hollis to,
to be care to my father and mother.
So he was like your brother.
So he's my older brother because hard and
come in just after and then Helson and
then when I born like eight
30 or nine years later,
I was the little one living with
halls, harden and house and for, for,
you know, so he's, my brother is
no way to see him differently.
He was known as a guy who
went all over the world,
studied sambo,
studied at some catch wrestling and the
wrestlers and he would bring that back,
right? Yes. What would
you credit holes in,
in bringing leg locks into
Brazilian Jujitsu? Is he the one?
Yes, I'm in the leg locks.
He specifically, uh,
it was not something I,
I kind of get the,
the major information from
hose was funny one day.
Eric Paulson was a good
student and a very good friend.
He brought a tape for me
from Japan. We've, uh, we've,
uh,
short too short the wrestling and I
saw that the new locks in the short,
the wrestle, you know, some guys fighting.
And I, I saw and I kind of interesting.
And then next day I start
to apply it. And then, uh,
it was funny because he
come to me afterwards,
said Hixon you mean I give
her that tape one day,
next day we're so meeting everybody on
the knee locks. So, Oh really? Yeah,
it was a,
you,
you would say you learn more leg locks
from Eric Paulson's tape then holes yet,
I mean halls, it was not specifically
I lead luck guy. You know,
there's a picture of him with a
Samba shirt on. Look, he studied,
he was a master of sound boat cause we,
we go in assemble as we go and any other
we go in represent these use you'd sue
against symbol, you know, and
um, independent American games.
We went in San Diego, um, was like, uh,
a very interesting because it,
the fighters,
they don't expect so much submissions
and we start immediately because duff
rassler's stuff, judo players.
So we started to meet at the,
bringing the fight to the gown ground
in goal, four foot locks in knee locks.
And immediately,
I mean in the first qualification phase
they statute tapping a lot and then the
referees statue becomes kind of a little
scap goes about that the statute become
one. So one's halls grab them and
then the foot lock, especially in the,
in the final match in his way division,
he get the gun to foot lock and the we
did the referee stopped the fight and say,
no,
you cannot get the food luck on the joint.
You have to get on like on the shin. And
then it's kind of confusing, you know,
and, and cutting the, that's why
halls lost the finals in this event.
And um,
this is what in the 70s was a,
I think eighties 81 or 80.
So they just,
they were trying to cut him out by the
referees stature getting upset because
like,
what's funny,
we suppose to come in with a team from
Brazil of 12 guys and we spell expecting
like I support from the government and
then the governor at that very less,
very less moment didn't, didn't give
to us. So my father page was to come.
So just me, Carlos, Gracie Jr and halls.
So we come in to compete in this event.
And how old were you at this time?
He must've been like 18 or something.
Yes. 19 something like that. And then,
uh, we coming and I was in
the, like my way division,
which is one above halls and halls was
below me and Carlos was on top of me.
So we kind of having one in each
division and as the competition progress,
the referees,
the statue,
see those three guys from Brazil just
submitting everybody because in sambal
chokes are not allowed. No headlocks no,
no collar chokes. He's only knee locks,
foot locks or straight on bars.
CanNot even do the Americans
because it goes into,
so we just go in trying to do foot
locks because those are the easiest way.
So we start to finish the guys
and they started to say, God,
this guy's coming and do food.
And everybody me complain,
I don't know if it's som both
though isn't sambal. Yeah,
that's what they do is footlocker. It's
now now back then there wasn't fun. It's,
it's, it's so interesting how enema
that's changed now. It was legal.
What was not used especially in December
when in the American concepts Russia
maybe. Yeah. You know what American
Samba focused on what Muslim,
they had a more likened to control.
The rules are,
if you pin the guy for 30 seconds
is, was like wrestling, not as as,
but you still win like judo.
Ah.
And as you attempt the P and every time
the guy passed the back on the ground,
you still making points.
So in my final match,
I guess the guy from the air force,
very strong guy with maybe wrestling and
judo background and he was whipping my
ass man. He was just like, and
the first like three rounds,
three minutes in the first round,
he stay on top all the time.
And because being in the
guide you're losing points.
The squad is about 12 or 14 points in
the first round in the second round is
about 18 or 20 I tell you in the very
final round I was about 26 or something
points against the zero,
you know,
and I was just trying to do my think and
in one like maybe a minute before the
very final Matt around,
I swept him and mounted and he
isn't the same time I mount it,
he's tried to push me away and I get like
a moving arm luck and he not even tap,
he's just yell.
So and then I win the fight
like in the very final seconds.
And you were down 20 something
points. I don't know, even chance.
I'm not there to, we need by points. I was
there just to see if I can submit. It's,
it's fascinating.
And then the guy that,
but like 15 seconds before the fight is
in and then like the whole crowd was and
then everything kind of who and then just
great.
No,
it's totally fine.
So when Eric Paulson showed you
these tapes of shootout in the 90s,
probably you already, you were already
doing leg locks a little bit, right?
I read that very like foot locks.
I always lost straight foot lock.
And then what Erik Paulsen showed you
was like fancy new bars and stuff. Yes,
because from the guard you just spin
around and go with the straight knee law.
So I get, I get amazed by this
kind of, and I to develop,
you'll know very quickly.
It was just adapt to my game and was an,
uh,
an addition to the arsenal.
You know, it was great.
It's funny when you look back at
old Eric Paulson fights in Japan,
you look at the stuff he was doing it
and people today still aren't even doing
that because she's way
ahead of the game to it.
Eric Paulson was an encyclopedia
submissions, him and Matt,
those guys back then it looked like
like advanced Jujitsu and of course,
you know anytime you got the mountain
there was always an arm bar, you know.
But uh, you know, that time Eric
was being trained very consistent.
[inaudible] he's a good, a good
brother in a training partner. We use,
always been a great warrior and
I have a lot of respect for him.
Great Guy. Very, very knowledgeable guy.
Isn't it fascinating that we've seen
just in the time that I started training
from 96 on this adoption of
leg locks in Jujitsu? Yes.
In the early,
in the 90s it used to be that leg locks
per frowned upon when when someone went
for leg locks, people get really
upset. Hixon you at the first
Pan American games in 1996 and our
1997 here in Elsa Gundo and La,
you must have been there,
right? Do you remember that?
It was the first Pan Americans,
there was like 500 Brazilians.
They shipped them all it were.
And there was,
the crazy thing is I was a blue belt in
Jujitsu and I saw Ken shamrock tape of a
toehold. So I was a blue belt doing
told John Jacques Machado is academy.
And uh, I competed in the
tournament and so did Eric Paulson.
And when I went through a
toehold in this tournament,
all the Brazilians started
throwing that was almost a riot.
They called the cough. There was the
one shoes at me and Johnny Machado.
I'll never forget him running
in slow motion sliding.
And I had the toehold that Johnny goes,
you got to let it go. You got all this.
So I had to told, and I'm
looking around, so I let it go.
People are throwing shoes at
me and water bottles and stuff.
It was like a big deal. And I ended up
losing, I let it go. And afterwards,
Eric Paulson's in the parking lot,
it was just me and him.
He was a blue belt as well. And he was
like his kid, we were like the same age,
but he was like, I was like a
little kid and he's like, you know,
let me talk to the kid and goes yeah,
let me show you a couple of leg locks.
So he showed me a couple things like
this weirdest leg lock that doesn't work
and he admits it now that it was garbage.
But he showed me this leg lock,
he showed me this leg lock where you go
like this is weird thing in the parking
lot and I'll never forget
that. I was like, man,
this guy is the only guy who understands
that, that uh, I liked toeholds and,
and um, he was on my podcast
not too long ago and he said,
and I asked him about that movie. Do
you remember that movie goes, Oh yeah,
it's garbage. It's trash as well.
Forget it raises that. Yeah.
Cause we got them outside. Isn't it
fascinating how these, these ideas,
they get innovated and within our lifetime
they started to get implemented and
they get weeded out.
The ones that work wind up staying,
the ones that don't work
fall by the wayside.
What do you think about the
IBJ JF banning heel hooks?
You think that's a good
thing? I like, I like
to first,
um,
of course it's a pleasure to
talk about all this and uh,
I can answer that because I feel like the
heel hook has to be implemented in the
top level fighters because
essence is a solid technique.
But because the is designed to
stretch the ligaments, not the joint.
You said difference between you going
in your finger this way. He's going to,
you're going to feel pain
before it brokes yeah,
but if you go this way,
you're going to resist and to pop's.
So he's just, ligaments is not a joint.
This is a joint. This is a ligament.
So when you twist the knee,
the guy can still resist and when
he feels it's going to feel the pop,
he's not going to feel the pain to tap.
So this is in a way,
if you don't have the experience,
you want to bust your knee.
So we don't want to see guys we've busted
me is just because they tough or just
because they know.
So we four beat in a hole,
the the, the heel hooks,
but in the end and then had events
at level like met Amaury is,
or like premium pros,
I think they should back bring back in
because this is part of the game and you
have to be responsible to let it broke
or tap. And especially a guy like Tokyo,
when you see Paul Horez,
he's such a master at it.
It's exciting to watch that guy fight
to see how guys are going to deal with
them. I would probably still
allows heel hooks, right?
That allows and Metamorris
I in my experience,
I've been teaching now 10
years and we've uh, uh,
I allow heel hooks from day one
only because I as an instructor,
I don't want some leg lot guy coming
into my school and tap and everybody out
with leg locks.
So I wanted all my guys to be
very well versed in leg locks.
And in my experience we reap,
we, he'll hook white belts.
I can't even tell you the last time
someone got hurt from it, he'll cook.
I kind of, I don't even know,
maybe, maybe once in 10 years,
think that that kind of education that's
going to positive because give the guy
the sense he has to, if he feels
the problem has to tap in advance,
you cannot allow you to pop happen
because you're going to bust her knee.
And in Naga and grapplers quest,
they allow heel hooks and you rarely
ever hear about anybody getting hurt.
And I think,
I think once you learn how to defend it,
it's actually people don't want to,
people will tap generally.
And some people that don't tap, uh, Gary,
Tony was talking about the first time
someone got him in a heel hook and,
and his knee popped a few
times. He thought, well, if
I tap now, it already popped.
Why should I tap? I should just keep
going now. And uh, um, if someone,
I think if someone is going to
let their knee pop or get hurt,
I think it's their responsibility to tap.
And if it pops is,
is it really a big deal? I mean, it's
part of the game. People get hurt.
People get their knees blown out in
basketball way more than Jujitsu. Again,
soccer. Yeah, I'm going in 10 years.
I, I can't even tell you that.
Maybe led compressions a couple of times.
Guys have had their knees pop from
led compressions and even locked down.
I've had a couple of guys get their
knee pop, but heal hooks and reaping,
that's not something that I ever
had to say. We got to slow down.
Be careful with the knee. Ribs,
just no one really gets hurt.
But seems to be a technique that
when people were ignorant of it,
that's when people were really
getting hurt more. Yeah,
it was some times when they really want
to go for the hood, they don't want to,
they don't visualize the,
the possibilities to hurt.
So they go in and go full power
from the beginning to the end.
So he's not even a chance to the
guy that he's already tapping late.
So that's more like the,
the, the, the mindset of the,
the, the guy who's attacking.
If you, once you break your knee
is a great chance to do that then.
And when we were adding wrestling to our
Jujitsu classes, trying to combine it,
now we separate, we have separate restroom
classes and separate Jiu Jitsu class.
But at a time when I was trying to
combine together, we would have a day
where we just do wrestling and we do live
ricin drills and we're all standing up.
That's where everyone got hurt and it got
to a point where he collided with each
other and just trying to take
someone down and tackling them.
And then they plant on their leg wrong.
Einstein broke his leg wrestling.
It just was his leg broke cause he planted
on it wrong. He got picked up. So they,
there came a point where I decided,
you know what,
too many guys are getting
hurt on wrestling day.
So I cut wrestling out and you know,
if you want to Russell,
you go to the rest of the class
and my class is just Jujitsu.
But we do allow reaping.
We do allow heel hooks and there's
no one getting hurt from that.
More from the wrestling.
Does a famous match where
you had with Mark Schultz,
what was, what happened in that?
Because that's a very famous, uh,
encounter and there's a movie coming
out called Fox catcher that's based on,
do you know the story behind this movie?
Um,
what was the guy's name that was a
responsible Fox catcher? It was based on,
there was the two brothers, the um, uh,
uh, all the one Marshall, David Schultz,
Dave Schultz got killed. And uh,
it's,
um,
it's based on this Guy John Dupont who
was this crazy rich guy who was taking
these wrestlers and he was, I
dunno, it was some weird gay shit.
There was something weird about
it. Pay For privates. He would,
well not just that he set up a training
center and pay them a lot of money and
we just get real weird with them,
wrestle with these guys.
But he was like this old
dude and you know, it wasn't
like, he was like, you know,
a guy who was really fit and really
in a training and learning techniques.
It was just real weird.
And you wind up shooting.
They creeped through every now and
then. Well, he was a billionaire.
I mean it was super, super
rich guy. Um, uh, so this, uh,
this movie's actually about to come out
now, but his brother, Mark Schultz was,
uh, fought in the UFC Olympic
gold medalists. Fantastic
wrestler. Like all time.
Great Wrestler.
And you and he had an encounter.
Yeah, well I was, uh, in a,
in the Utah visiting my,
my struck to be editable Pedro
Sauer. Yes. And then, uh,
we are invited to go to the Byu where
he was coaching the wrestling wrestling
team there. And as I get there, you know,
looking to for training stuff
and eventually he said, okay,
let's train a little bit. And then, uh,
immediately we engage immediately he went
to my guard and almost immediately he
stepping out and then
he was not happy at all.
And then she put them in a triangle,
a triangle first from the guard. Yes.
And then he becomes a little more
smart and he kind of, it come it.
So it was a long second round.
And eventually I went to his back
and submit him again. And, um,
after a few, few sessions, I
make him tap some. And, uh,
and he was very impressed. Like,
wow, nobody did this with me. I mean,
what's on I, I mean, he was
stronger than me. I mean,
of course a warrior. And
he was not happy. I mean,
uh, somebody said, once,
you show me a good loser
and I'll show you a loser.
So he was not happy at all. And, uh,
of course I, and I understood that.
And um, but eventually he, he,
he's saddle and he understood was it
technique involve and you start to become
the training with Pedro and uh,
become passionate about Jujitsu.
He training a lot and he become like a
supporter of the Jujitsu Cause in Utah.
And, uh, and you know,
it was a great experience because I can
felt like the whole level of trainee and
in body control he has,
but it's still like at that point,
the rest of us has no clue
what is, you know, submissions.
So what's kind of your not
surprising thing for them, which is,
doesn't happen those days.
Do you remember specifically what moves
holes brought from a wrestling and,
and, uh, from Samba to how good
way distribuition a good ways to,
like if the guy grabbed you, you were
able to, to, to make the movement,
you go to the, his back, like
a good turnovers. Um, a good,
excellent sense of, uh, Nogi base control,
a good grips to charm drags and stuff
that thinks like a very, you know,
he was training a lot with, uh, Bob.
Bob Anderson. Yes. Yeah.
So he was a good friend of Bob Anderson
and the barbarians to went to Brazil.
So it was like,
uh,
he was the one who brought the wrestling
ideas and concepts because he pushed us
once to compete in Olympic wrestling.
So it was,
Hobbes was always for me a
reference. You know, as I growing up,
he was the champion and he
was just a unbelievable guy.
We for good heart and a
passion for Zuihitsu loved,
represent and he was my idol.
You know,
as I grow in up and I tried to
follow his footsteps and uh,
as they grow a nap, we all train
hired among each other, we fathers.
So my goal was beat halls. You know,
my goal was to be better than him.
And let's suppose the,
our last 30 training,
uh, maybe he, he,
he beat me like in the first two or three.
And then we spend maybe 20
trainings or maybe 25 trainings,
even AARP,
like back and forth.
I start to get modern morning to
his game and what this new strategy,
Choo Choo catch me.
And I started to become more comfort
that when the surviving and then in one
point I start getting dead vantage in
the training because no luck either w you
better or not.
So in consistently I start to become
more comfort that when then eventually I
start to getting dead
vantage some positions.
And then in one day and the, and the
Rancho of my father, like in a weekend,
we all get together,
has a huge match.
So I was training with him
and I submit him first time,
you know, what'd you get them
with? A man was like, uh,
uh, um, you know, I hear an Ogee gree,
so you're not even remember.
I think it was some kind of
choke or something. But, uh,
what I remember it was,
uh,
the feeling I felt by achieving my goal.
I was making him feel like
he was losing his position.
And I felt the same way.
I felt happy.
I felt sad because was not,
he is anymore. He's my self,
my responsibility now and we know that.
And nobody in the news, I
mean, nobody knew. I mean,
of course people saw the training,
but at that point I felt like I
was dare is still to support him,
but I was better than him and we
still competing and events coming.
And, uh, we always close the bracket
because he goes into his weight division.
I go in mind and we go
together and the open division.
So we always close the open, you
know, and uh, I never will fight it.
I mean,
up should that day.
He always been the first and I'm the
Saquon the Maddow is here is even though I
knew I could maybe change this,
you know,
I never ever will,
if he's still alive he will be the
number one and I'm number two based on
respect base in, in Iraqi. So, uh,
once he passed away I have to take over,
you know,
in represent fully and uh,
but was,
I mean he is my inspiration and uh,
he's a great guy and then
he misses him dearly.
He died in a tragic hang gliding accident.
How old were you at that time?
Oh, I was, uh, maybe 20,
22, something like that.
So he was there when you
fought Zulu? Yes, he was.
He was my coach who was in
my corner with my dad from,
for people out there that don't
know what I'm talking about.
The Zulu maps that you
had was one of them.
That's like watching an old Ali match.
Can you,
can you put that up Jamie
actually versus Zulu? Yes.
I really, you know, this
conversation goes very well and I,
I mean, I really appreciate
your talking about the past,
but I like should make a
little pause on this and,
and really bring up the most,
because we have to leave today.
We have to be motivated and I'm very
happy today to come here to explain and
talk about this new
venture I'm involved with,
which is the new Jj GF
Jujitsu global federation.
Because talking about Jujitsu,
talking about rules,
talking about the future of shoe she had.
So I think,
uh, we having a huge problem
to be resolved, you know,
and that's is crucial for the future.
I see like this new organization will
bring to the table the elements to resolve
our problem.
You know,
I think our biggest problem today
and they shoot so community is losing
effectiveness.
We be losing effectiveness drastically
from the last 15 years because um,
the way in order for us
to restore effectiveness,
I felt very appealing to me
to engage in this venture,
which through this federation we are
going to try to resolve three important,
I mean we have three pillars of, of, of,
of action to try to resolve that problem.
Jujitsu has effectiveness in what an
MNF effective and like a fight. No,
no effectiveness.
I want to explain to you because it's
different efficiency and effectiveness
today I see the top camp champions very
efficient on getting medals but they
losing effectiveness in real life.
And if you see Jujitsu as I grew up,
the core of Jujitsu was self defense
isn't preparing the students to handle
situations.
Should they be evolutionary process
of associates who brought the sport of
Jujitsu and those rules diminishing
that effectiveness in the search for the
medal. So, and I like
nothing can be boring for me,
more boring then watch some
fights in Jujitsu tournaments.
Those days I believe in I'm in,
they can choose between stepping
on the brake or stepping on the,
on the guests.
They can choose because the rules
favor if you strategically correct,
you may go to go in the fight to fight
as situation where you can control the
pace of the fight.
You can managing the whole tank
and eventually by one or two moves,
you get advantage. And when the
model so great you have the metal,
but sometimes that's chose
a lack of desire to compete,
a lack of desire to engage
in a fair fight. La,
a lot of times they see our white belt
or a blue belt or a purple belt fight,
which is much more appealing, has
much more open situations, of course,
of changing positions.
Then a black belt who sometimes sit
on the floor and it stuck like an
acquisition who holds
stalling the whole action.
So by doing that,
he's efficient on get the medal,
but he's losing effective
is to handle real life.
That's why is hard to see as you
[inaudible] representative on the cage.
Who translates that?
I mean I seizures.
It's translates your day something I feel
like I never, we would fight like that.
The guys who shoots a practitioner
for life, his greatest talent,
he's tough.
He's sometimes a champion,
but he don't fight the way I believe
it's supposed to be fighting there.
You know, he has no idea of
clinching. He has no idea of sidekick,
has no idea of a volley to the guard.
They have a sportive guide all the time
trying to do a more plotters in the,
you know, instead, and the guy on top
just hammering them down. So it's,
it's kind of weird because
without that kind of efficiency,
I mean, I'm sorry, effectiveness.
A Jujitsu is losing,
you know, he's losing, uh, the
integrity, the whole culture,
the whole concepts I trust
and I believe all my life.
So if I can clarify your,
your issue is with points and
with advantage points. Yes.
For example, the new, this
new situation will be, uh,
this federation is not there to, to,
to compete with other organizations.
I'm not there to,
I,
I'm doing the job was not done yet.
You know,
based on this platform,
this state of DRM platform,
we try to have three different
elements to work with
de formation.
I think division is to perform
something or good service.
Mine tension with this is to serve
the community in the sport community,
the worldwide Jujitsu community.
In the sport of Jujitsu,
thinking that I have
three different elements.
The first one is the communication aspect.
Information through the site you're going
to have a listing of all the academies
on the planet.
We have a listing of all
at the athletes profiles,
downloads of fights.
So they will have the
option to request sponsors,
show themselves.
It's like a,
a Google slash Facebook for the community.
And uh, also we're going
to have a master's council,
which brings all the guys who have
traditionally spend their lives in, in,
in the Jujitsu community to have a voice,
active voice for the community.
So in the forums, sometimes, uh,
somebody makes a question
about a position,
so the master's will be involving
answers if they want and they will be
highlighted because that's his
opinion, that's opinion. And so people,
the community want to start to evaluate
what's beneficial and what's negative,
what's the master has to say.
So creates a network which is must
need it to unified. The community.
I see the communities, should they
completely split, you know, they did.
Some federations had their own circuits,
some either. So it's 30 sec, 30 events,
one side, I'm under 30 and the
other side. And then has, you know,
Nag a seven Grep request,
have dream,
have IBJ JF.
So all this is completely
disorganized and completely split.
So my intention is brink to the community.
A sense of,
of unity unification based on this
information who is go for every,
like another important point is have
contributors from all over to breaking
their reports of what's happening
in this event. Who's the champion,
who is dead and news and everything.
So because some magazines should they,
they completely partial,
they just will talk and explain about
bear athletes or in their society does not
cover the whole community. So
to this information, this solid,
uh, efficient, uh, general information,
the general, the whole community
will be informed, we'll be connected,
will be asking and being listened.
So I think that's a very
important for the community.
Another big pillar of our,
our federation is the competition aspect,
which by changing rules
we restore effectiveness.
How we do that,
cutting the advantages.
Because the advantage for me,
it's like a,
a ball in the ring is just touch.
The ring doesn't make a point.
How are you going to make
a half point or it's, it's,
it's the very hard to interpretate
what is really real and what is not.
What's our most,
I mean it doesn't matter how many
goals you try and hit the post.
The score is what matters,
you know?
So I have points just creates a
controversy in the interpretation for the
referee for so becomes
a very confused way.
So back to the reality,
you just go four clear points.
And also another important thing is
give mine was points for installing
positions.
What is it?
Stalling position is a position where
you hold with the intention to preserve
their position,
to preserve the control of
the dynamic of the fight.
You stalling because you want to be
in control by using what I call a anti
Jujitsu move,
which prevents you from
keep action. Because the idea is go
both engage and see who's the best,
who is submit,
who's
passing, who is mounting, who is getting.
And sometimes people
to minimize that risk.
They kind of keeping the
situation on the UCONTROL,
the position they can control.
This leaves putting the lag in tango it
so he's comfortable to proceed and to
the point he needs to
make a little advanced.
So this diminish the effect of in is
because this kind of strategy doesn't work
in real life. So they were
punished for that. Any grabbing,
grabbing the referee come and say,
Hey man,
watch your grip after 20 seconds
he already got a minus point after.
Then they're going to get mine was again.
And then eventually you're going to be DQ.
Is it subject to interpretation whether
a guy is stalling or they're guys just,
if they're canceling each other out?
I'm sorry if it's subject
to interpretation,
whether it's stalling or whether or
not they're canceling each other out.
Like one guy is trying to advance the
other guy stopping them at for advanced.
They just both looking for the opening.
Yeah.
But you can see easily who is wants to
progress and who's once you just control
the position for this guy who
don't want to progress, he will be,
I mean you can notice it.
I mean in theory may is,
but if you see it you can see who's just
trying to minimize the action and try
to wait for their opportunity and the
other one who's tried to make it happen,
you know, what about submission
only tournament's do you let those,
the federation also have this kind
of rule. We have two sets of rules,
the point rules system for tournaments
and we have the challenge rules for can
be even timing but for match
for matchmaking like the
Metamorris skyline or or
any promoter who tried to do
something like the baddest,
the baddest purple belt. So there's
no way division is no time limit.
He can approach that the time as you wish.
Like okay let,
we'll be 20 minutes Max. We will be 50
minutes match will be half hour match.
We can think about Gracie worlds
and Gracie nationals. They,
it's all submission only. And after 15
minutes, if there's no sub submission,
they're both disqualified.
I disagree with that.
That that disqualification
I spoke with hose and uh,
she may be, I mean we want to get
into the better for the Jujitsu,
but for me it's the same
roles in case of a bracket.
So I don't feel like both
who kind of didn't submit,
suppose sue should be disqualified because
sometimes in the same bracket should
tough guys, they fight each other and
they could not submit to each other.
And then some too,
I mean halfway busters.
Yes they want submit the order.
So this guy advances and
those two are disqualified.
So I don't think this is fair.
Somebody has to come in from this.
So the way I did is the first round goes
full force and if the 20 minutes sand
or 30 minutes,
then it depends on the arrangement.
After the 20 minutes you ask
the guy you want to fight,
the guy said yes and then ass Nigga you
want to fight. Yes. So He's another round.
So in the second round,
we still don't have positive points,
but every time the guy put himself in
a position and he started defending
himself without attempting to
escape or giving the combat,
just protecting or resting or whatever,
the referee going to say,
hey man,
keep going acting or you're
going to be penalized.
So we have negative points for diminishing
of combat tivity so at the end of the
second round, if we see like, uh,
somebody with mine was points, this
one will be the loser, you know,
because he displayed last desire or less
gas or less techniques to be on top of
the, the con, the con, the competition.
So his mind was because
he's defending all the time,
he was tired or whatever.
So he gets minus points and then the
other guy advances for the brackets.
So that's the only change
for this submission.
Are you familiar with my avid
submission only tournament as well?
I don't know if you're aware of that.
And it's very similar to Gracie
world's Gracie nationals,
but both at 15 minute matches,
but both competitors aren't disqualified.
We actually have an overtime round
and and that and the overtime,
it's kind of like soccer.
I didn't want overtimes to be uh,
determined by wrestling
and a lot of tournament,
it's like you go into overtime and,
and whoever's the best wrestler wins
because you get to take that and then they
hold and they went. So a lot of
wrestlers can go into tournaments and go,
I'm just going to stall for regulation,
taking into overtime and when with my
wrestling. So in order to eliminate that,
I wanted to know who the best submission
artist is, not who the best wrestler is.
So my overtime, each person,
like if we went into overtime,
you get to start on my back with the leg
cooks and an over under. And then we go,
if you submit me, then I get to go on
your back. And if you escape you win.
But if I submit you, then we'd
go another round. It's just,
it's like a extra innings and then the
next round you take my back, I escape,
I take your back and I submit you, I
win. That's an a dreamland of course.
But we that way we get to find
out who the best is at submitting.
We couldn't finish and regulation.
Now we go into overtime and we start
on each other's backs. Like free kicks.
Yeah but I think,
I think this is a valid but you take
the element of conquer that position.
I think the fight has to
be leaving in standing up.
If the rest of the statue avoiding any
avoiding of combat activity supposed to
be penalized but allow,
you could fake that though like a wrestler
could fake it like take shots and one
thing is for sure in this new federation
and the same way we have the master
council,
we're going to have the development
council and you are going to be invited
right now to be part
because I see people like
you guys are not just know the
deal no that the sport but
also has opinion Shumake
and my idea is not riding my
rules and stone.
My idea is to follow the best pattern
to create more effectiveness and more
dynamic aspect for the sports.
So the federation has this open heart
and open eye and open years to kind of
make the best conclusions for the sport.
So all the rules can be changed.
Everything can be adapted to a better,
more define display off effectiveness.
That's a beautiful thing.
When will this go into effect and when
will your first and injury? No, no,
I'm not playing only in events.
My idea is to serve service.
So I got to service through the
information I going to serve as to giving
reference in giving
guidance for the events.
But even though they don't do my rules,
I will legitimize everybody.
And I,
you start to relate the records of every
event who went here, who went there.
And I start to putting everybody to become
part of the same profile, the same, uh,
mindset.
And I will hammer the idea of why we don't
do the best rules for Jujitsu because
I bet they champions, should they, many of
them, they're gonna say, oh, I don't like,
I prefer to this or that, but I'm
not here to educate those champions.
I'm here to educate 85% of the competitive
community today who is still white
and blue belt.
Those guys,
they've been misled to understand the
strategy of the game to get the meadows
but they losing
effectiveness in real life.
So the change of rules aside of the
education aspect of the federation is very
important.
How I see the service of the federation
and the educational level because a lot
of times guys coming from the competitive
background and they from white to
purple to Moran and black so
they become tough competitors.
Sometimes champions they become famous.
Then they opened the school and as they
opened the school they teach what they
know.
That techniques who make
them few champions so great
but this is just like a a
percentage off what he supposed to know
to teach because not everybody wants to
debt go that you compete.
Not everybody has the skills and the
toughness to engage in a in that kind of
level of training.
I feel like Jujitsu is there to
favor the the community as a whole.
I feel like the instructor,
he has to be knowledgeable
about self defense,
about self defense for women,
about programs for kids,
kids class in law enforcement.
So as the structor become certified,
I mean I'm not,
I going to validate all
the audit, the, the, the,
the destructors,
all the black belts today,
I'm not going to say you don't deserve it,
but I will suggest to them
to get certified through
the federation because they
will get elements for dairy
schools become more efficient,
retained more students,
had a better teaching programs,
which are the core of effectiveness.
And the other day I heard some black
belts being asked for a student about self
defense, hey teacher, you teach? He said,
no, no. If you want to self defense,
you go to grab my guy. You
know. And I felt that's,
this is just something who is
goes in straight on my heart.
Because for me, the core
of Jujitsu, self defense,
if you don't know selfdefence
basically you don't know Jujitsu.
You have to be ready to shoot,
choose to defend yourself from a slapping,
from a hug, from a
headlock, from whatever.
And if you don't have those concepts
lineup, you become sometimes very path.
We've tough years with very
good grip and dudents forever,
but you still counting on your own
physicality. You still counting.
You cannot teach that for
the children or for a women.
So by having differation presenting those
courses in any spreading this all over
the,
the word,
the teacher will have much more elements
to have Molly students to feed the,
the have more knowledge
to feed, you know, the,
here's the students in
different levels and,
and make a different job with Jujitsu,
you know, so this is beautiful.
So your motivation is just
to improve digits. Yes.
You see a bad direction that it's going.
Usually it's as losing effectiveness and
we have to restore that buy in for me
very well by understand the competition
as a progressive thing to make you
better fight or not to make a
better competitor. You know,
if you're a competitor
sometimes at taekwondo guy,
he's a great competitor but has
nothing to do with real life. I mean,
you want to be a fighter.
Jujitsu is something you learn to protect,
your honor, to protect your dignity,
chew, to represent, to fight,
to make money in the cage wherever you,
your goals are.
Jujitsu is there to support you
in a very profound and deep cause,
which is effectness effectiveness.
The transition between Jujitsu and Jujitsu
competition and mixed martial arts is
it's a very tricky transition for
a lot of Jujitsu fighters. Yes.
Especially when they don't have that
kind of constant strong background.
You know, I think if everybody
who fights like crown,
we don't have to set up rules because
he wants to accelerate. He wants,
he wants to be progressive, you know,
he's not, once you won by points,
he wants to go to the kill. So, uh,
guys like him or Bouschet show
or some other great athletes,
they go and they choose to fight openly.
You know,
to see some other fights.
They choose the strategy,
strategic elements to just give
them more chances. Just points,
just points,
just advantages.
Sometimes 10 minutes fight
Hannafin happened is just
to advantage that stared at
women. I don't expect you see
this in a fight and nobody speaks.
So by changing rules,
we increase effectiveness.
We create a more dynamic fights is
more interesting to see, you know,
nobody wants to see something boring.
And we create under this
concept the possibility to
unified the whole community.
Not only this particular
association or this federation,
but everybody in the same polite.
And then without taking
anything from nobody,
my vision is to create a
worldwide circuit of Jujitsu,
which represents the same thing.
They are ASP for surf
or the att for tennis,
which brings major players
like big sponsors and and,
and until a vision for the sport.
So first is unified,
try to unify the rules,
try to create effective is try to give
a better condition for the teacher,
for the school Warner,
for the independent promoter.
Because I cannot think and about,
okay,
I'm going to start to make my
own circus and I don't validate,
nobody's just me like other people do.
So that's a a wrong way to unified and,
and in educate the community
in our culture for the future.
Raul said publicly that he
feels a part of the problem,
the stalling problem is the holding
of the sleeves. Do you think, uh,
is there a path? I, that's what I
think too. I totally agree with them.
I think the fact that you
have to have your sleeve,
you can't have your sleeve type because
then your opponent can't grab it.
I think that is so backwards.
I think that it should be illegal
to grab the sleeve illegal.
I think it should be illegal. I think I
think is possible to be illegal. What is,
what is unacceptable is that grip
promotes is only a cool off situation.
I can grab anywhere I want. If my
intention is to progress. Yeah.
If I start to say, okay, come into me,
come into papa and I stay here waiting
to waste your energy and then when you
make a mistake I sweep you. That's
kind of weak. Weak in your mindset.
We can your progressiveness weekend,
your effectiveness.
So what if he stuck there?
Like he has sleep and he stuck cause
he's trying to pass and if p let's go of
the sleeve then you're going to pass and
it kind of just stuck there and you're
like I can't let go of the
sleeve because let him home man,
let it go and go for the risk.
Don't you think that would cause
problems with the RAF and the refs
interpretation of what stolen.
Whatever is holding you feel
not moving is a stalling.
So you should have the MOU,
hip movement and the angles and the
quick fast on the news, whatever you do.
Because if the guy don't
make a complete pass
you still like arm was no advantage.
Yeah. So it's just keep going man.
Do you think it's less
of an issue with Nogi
is less because you know gay,
you can stall in the 50 fifties and
different things will be easier,
but you have much less elements to submit.
I feel like they know gay is just take
maybe 70% of the submission options.
Still some classic ones but not that many.
So I feel like it's just last options,
but it's still the same.
Exactly the same fight.
When you did the Butoh challenge, we went
to see that it was a great, great event.
What has changed since your,
your ideas when you put that on?
My ideas are the same would the challenge
is a great rule for I stream event for
a prime television event is not a sport
competition event because ames the
submission and only pros competing and
it's like a premium sensational thank
which has no time for stalling
is all pushing forward.
So the whole pressure
I think is almost that,
but in the tournaments has to
be a little more supportive.
We have to have points,
we have to have a time limit,
which is a quarterly to the the the
the bout and so, but it's the idea,
the concept of progressive concept
of going to the submission has to be
embraced. I mean it has to be in their
whole mindset for every fighter, you know,
it's not,
it doesn't change the way you fight has
to be folk was on the submit the guy to
be the best, the best one out there.
When is your first big tournament?
Are you planning on having a big worlds?
I want to have like a in October
the first event, but I already have,
for example, next week, uh, in the
second and third, the Vulcan Open.
They, we will apply the new
rules and it's all testing.
We're going to test the rules to
see because the idea is a positive,
beneficial idea for the sport.
And if we need to adjust a little
more than change, like I said,
it's not funny on the stone yet and
we're going to allow the think too,
if you know,
hearing people and see and the conclusions
because the mission is very positive
and the means we will be adaptable.
That's a beautiful thing. Yes,
it is a beautiful thing.
I'm very happy you've
seen Jujitsu progress from the time
you were a boy to what it is today.
I mean it's gotta be an amazing thing.
An amazing thing also to have taken part
in those first initial invasion moments
when you guys came and you like this.
So many of the Gracie in
action videos where uh,
you know [inaudible] is battling
with the karate guys and you know,
you're battling with judo guys and the
people that had no idea what Jujitsu was.
Yes,
I remember very clearly when I saw the
first ultimate fighting championship that
I saw was number two.
They had a video tape that was out and
I watched it and I watched hoist win and
a, I remember thinking to myself, man,
I didn't even know that there was anything
like this out there. I had no idea.
I had been martial arts my whole life.
I had no idea that someone
could do something.
I was doing karate and man,
when I watched UFC two first cause UFC
one they didn't have any highlights to
show cause they didn't release it.
Their idea was they were going to release
two first and then they were going to
release one for summer.
No. But you have to see one was they
did have paper view for UFC one. Yeah,
but it wasn't available on VHS. Yes.
And then so once I heard that you have,
see one was real, my friend said, Hey dad,
cause I saw pre before it and I thought,
oh that's fake. That's like WWF,
that's not real. So I ignored it.
And then my friend came home one
day, my roommate and said, hey,
I'm a challenge thing. It's real. Some
Guy Guitar Center told me it was really,
he said some, some Iranian guy
who was just choking people out,
he would just grab them by the throat.
He said Iranian sumo wrestlers
put the split, the split, the two,
my friend, the guy who told me he
didn't see it, he heard it secondhand.
So he said,
yeah,
some Iranian apparently was grabbing
people by the throat and choking everybody
out. I said some Iranian I
go did, he didn't fight it.
I was doing karate for six months ago.
It wasn't a karate guy wasn't he goes,
yeah, he'd be karate be boxes. He beat
it. I go by choking them out like this.
He goes, yeah, that's what they told me.
And I go, so that second one came out,
my friend called up goes, the ultimate
challenge thing is coming out again.
I go tape it,
tape it.
So I got home and I watched
it and man I hated hoists,
Gracie and that opening around cause
I want him to karate guy to win.
When he bought my Nokia Jr I'm like,
that was my hero.
I didn't even know who he was, but he did
karate and I thought, okay, he's my hero.
And then, but on the other side was
Pat Smith and I didn't like him.
And then I didn't like holy there.
But then by the time the finals came,
I fell in love with voice.
By the time the finals hit,
I was in love with them.
And I go,
I got to find this because I wrestled
in high school a couple of years and I
thought either this is primitive wrestling
or it's super advanced wrestling.
I didn't know what it was. So I
went in, I found John John Machado.
I went in there and I got choked out
37 times by a purple belt by uh, uh,
Dave Meyer,
Dave Marsh.
And I remember thinking one day I'm going
to be able to do this with someone who
just walked in.
I was,
so from that point on I was
obsessed with this is okay,
like a changing life experience.
What was it like for you to be there too?
Did Not Compete and knowing that
you are better than your brother.
There's all this talk about
why you didn't compete
in the UFC.
When I come here to support harden and,
and the cause of uh,
being like spreading the art.
And then one point I was hoarding
soldiers two to four, whatever.
And um,
and in another point I decided to
follow my own pet and of course keeping
keeping the alliance but
going into my own direction
and then hot and call me and ask me
to train hoists. I didn't know why.
And he said, then he said, oh, I blaming
should do some events. I said, okay,
let's do it. So I was his coach
for the first and second event.
And then somebody asked me through
Eric Paulson and a assistant of,
uh, of, uh, Daniel Santo, ut Nakamura was
shorter. Yes. So He's send me
invitation to participate, have a chart.
I showed top competition,
so,
and then they send me a tape to
see what the rules are about.
And I didn't like the rules,
but I like the locks.
So I started training the locks and I
said, no man, this is, I mean there's no,
I don't like it.
So,
and then we start to immediately
say I don't want to do.
And then my ex wife,
much more calm statue negotiate
with the guys in stature say by it.
If we changed the rule.
So was kind of talk and talk
and eventually they decide
to change the rules for
a new open rules like in DNA advice,
the way supposed to be the rule.
So we create the new night,
Eh Valley to the 94.
And then when I signed the,
I mean when I about to sign the contract
harder and call me and said, Hixon,
why are you doing? And said, yeah man, I'd
be invited to fight in Japan. Said, no,
you should not go because this goes
against the family. UFC is our game.
We should be in support the family and
stay here as high school coach. I said,
man,
that's not exactly what I
vision for myself because I
mean I'm here being coach.
I get an one penny you,
you put a lot of dollars in your pocket,
you give me nothing.
I'm in.
You give me some money too for me to
sit on the bench. We are in business.
But if you give me a knife in the
guys off of me, a lot of money to go.
You don't even have it. You gave me,
what did they offer you just gave them,
she'd given me some, he said, no, no,
he should do for the love of the Fetzer.
Yeah Man,
I love you guys but you love me and you'll
give me enough in how I going to love
you. I mean, so I,
I went to Japan and dealing my think
and stretch winning there and uh,
and then I get my, my, my
direction towards Japan, which
is, was very good for me.
The community there. The location,
the culture there. It was, was very,
I mean I feel like home and uh,
that's pretty much where I direct myself,
my career,
my end of my career to Japan and um,
but now crones back to see
what's going to happen.
So were you worried at all with
voice doing the UFC? Did you,
did you think, cause he was the
youngest one of the brothers riding him,
he didn't compete as much in like are
you worried at all that maybe it was yes,
but the idea,
the primary idea of high single in
is because he was not the best one,
but he was, something is going to be a
good task for him is a good, you know,
to break the ice and stuff but,
but not exactly if something happened
is always a backup you the backup. Yes.
So I was there to just jump in in case
if someone beat Hoy's you would have
jumped into the EOC,
the chemo incident, but
that after that, after that,
that was already engaged in
Japan. I was already, yes.
I you had a contract with them over there.
Yeah. Not for many fights. I never did,
did many fights, contract, uh,
many, many fights in one contract.
But I felt like hardened create
a very awkward situation,
you know, and uh, and uh,
was a kind of little d division,
you know,
so I was not appealing to go there and
show my support your voice and be there
just so al loud to him
to have his own destiny.
There was also the talk that voice
was a slender guy who was younger.
He wasn't as intimidating
as you and that it,
it sort of accentuated the idea of Jujitsu
due to his technique based where it's,
you're, you're a scary
guy, you're scary guy now,
but you were really scary guy then you're
the only, you were the school yoke,
Gracie one 85. Right? Something like that.
Yeah. It depends. I, yeah,
I start Zulu was like I have 74 kilos,
74 killers of maybe one 80, one 80.
Okay. Maybe, maybe a little less.
And then, uh, my,
my last fight in Japan I did with Nike.
Yes.
I was one a 95. Nice. Cause
he was a guest for two 20.
Right? Yeah. Nike for Nike should 30.
Should they do something and then, uh,
you know, I was making a
preparation to go heavier than this,
sometimes even 208 and then
Korea cut down for the,
to get my best shape.
When we spoke,
it was a 2000 and when we had dinner,
was it 2005 or something like
that? Somewhere around there. Sure.
Yet you were still thinking about fighting
the higher level guys?
Yes. Yes. But none of
that ever materialized?
Never. Yes. Because, um, I never have the,
after my,
my son departure on 2000,
I was about to make the best contract
of my life was I just finished with,
for Nike and I see what proposal meet
on their proposal to fight Sakura,
but he was still on the top.
And then, uh, my son departure,
I have to have like a moment for
the family and regroup as a whole.
By departure. Your son passed
away. He passed away. Yes.
So was a moment I could,
I could escape by doing a fight. Say,
okay, I want to focus on the fight,
but I felt like my family will be
completely unprotected and unsupported.
So I said, no, I don't care
about the fight I will be.
So I spent about two years to to make
the whole family feels good again and we
all regain strength. And,
and and happened is again.
So after that they start to,
to get another,
get a free agent for a couple of years.
We tried to make something close to
what I have, but the, the, the, the,
the whole business in itself in Japan,
the fact Sec Rabba last for four
Vandelay and things like that,
diminish that kind of huge
purse. And then I felt like, no,
I just want to fight if he's,
if he's that much.
So I to be very resistance about
my next fight, some opportunities.
But I kind of push away.
And to the point on 2008 I was already
moved back to Brazil for a while.
A guy from Texas,
even for items that you compete in a
new event and pull me to fight feather.
And a,
I was looking for that,
but I was have a little injury on my hip
and on two way I'd be able to feel good
to train me.
I could not sign.
And because he has a deadline in
terms of promotion and search,
I could not sign without having a hundred
percent confidence because if I sign,
I will fight. I'm not going to and I don't
have the time I want to get. So I said,
you know what? I don't want it. And in
my heart I went to the beach and said,
thank you God for everything I have.
I'm out.
So I stopped competing,
not exactly the way I want,
but I felt like I have to respect God's
decision and I just don't want to just
dip a deicing my life for the
money, you know, for. Okay.
The guy pulled me mine,
I go there and so I feel like I have to,
butcher represents Jujitsu.
Either I go 100% or you know,
I hope somebody else got me and then
I'll get to see what ground does
all the great fighters that you saw
during that time from the time well hoists
entered the UFC till the
time that you retired,
the guys like Mark Coleman and boss
route and fade or were there any that you
really wish that you could have had an
opportunity to match up against? Um,
I always visualizing myself
against the number one, you know,
I could not even think about.
So one point,
it was Coleman, you, the point was,
you know, uh, I mean you name it,
the champions and then
feather get the rise in.
That makes it like a big expression.
So I could not think and about other guy.
True to represent your shit. So, you
know, I have all this revision that,
but the set of rules are different.
You know,
at the time we could express technique
with more because we have time.
You know, I never, somebody asks me, Oh
yeah, you have only few fights in MMA.
I said, no, I never fought them in me.
I always fought volley too though
because MMA is a different animal.
You go there for three rounds,
five minutes is better to
have offensive techniques.
Then defensive techniques that the defense
not going to do good for you is going
to do good if you have at least one
round, 10 minutes. And then another.
So if you have like my fights arise,
endless rounds of 50 minutes is
endless rounds of five minutes. So,
and that way you can prepare yourself
for a different strategy. You know,
you have to follow the movements and you
cannot just go all the way empty or gas
and then fuel up in empty
again because you know,
if you amped your gas and the wrong time,
you in trouble.
So all the technique in stretching or
guess and be calm and finding comfortable
positions,
those are the street right now.
Now it's becomes a very
stream of very physical.
You see athletes in the same way division,
but a guy who fights in
the one 55 walks around,
we find 81 85 you know,
so the technology on the
sport today is a huge thing.
The physicality. That's why taking
any techniques is only a piece of it.
You know what chrome does today is
not only training Jujitsu and become
comfortable in the skills he trained
like a dog and all the elements he can do
to become a cleric and
explosive and physical and
then going to lost weight like
everybody else plus the technique which
I feel and one point we will be the edge
he needs to,
to make the difference.
So do you think there's something missing
in today's mixed martial arts that, um,
that the original Jujitsu
sort of expressed this,
this idea of having an open round,
having a no limit fight? Is the,
is there a room for that tonight,
do you think? Or do you think we're,
we're hampered by this idea of a three
hour paper view window or two hour
television window? It's
funny because, you know,
the other day I got caught watching,
I fought our match in tennis,
you know, it was a great match was
along and the still going one more says,
oh man. And you'll see, I have no
idea they were that long that long.
Your Palm Beach and the Dow and the s I
think French Open last year I was five
hours, five hours, five hours nonstop man.
And they break and start again.
And the advantage was unbelievable,
you know?
So if you're passionate about tennis,
sometimes the game can be like 45
minutes sometimes can be couple of hours
because you there in the action,
you know?
So for me when we
talking about engagement,
we talking about,
I mean the best one out there and when
I see a fight after 50 minutes because
somebody punched once or fallen
top or just give him the tro.
Both guys stand up, they both
design and then the time is over.
Who wins the fight in my opinion,
supposed to be a draw because
how the guy can, can we just,
because one more point, the guys are
warriors, the guys are willing to go.
So it's always like halfway to
what's supposed to be, you know,
because Eh, okay. You have to decide
by points after a few. Okay. So,
I mean, it's hard because, you know,
sometimes I even have the best of it,
but that's doesn't guarantee if the
fight goes longer, if he's still that,
because toughness,
resilience and in heart and technique,
they all want to pay in one point, going
to be a big, a big situation, you know?
So it's for me, not the, did the, you,
the rules today in the UFC
and such doesn't translate.
The best guy out there translates
the most agile, the most tough.
The one who get connect first,
you know,
because sometimes the fight can be
either way. The whoever connects first,
whoever makes the fruit can win.
So it's kind of hard to a virus.
But if you put two guys
in the cage and okay man,
whoever's get out first is the winner.
So,
and that's a different animal
because you have to be technical,
you have to be patient, you have
to be. So, you know, I can see,
uh,
first is the expectation is
all in the how chrome gonna do.
But if confirms what I believe
can be done eventually,
I feel like grown will be comfortable
to challenge anyone for a no time limit
fight. Because I mean I
don't care if he's Velasquez,
I don't care if he's John John's.
If crown do what he has to do with the
time he has to do, I believe on him.
Like I believe in myself.
If I have the help,
should they and the physicality I so I,
I like to have,
I mean I don't see a guy just
because he's winning on the cage,
he can win me cause they don't see
the opportunities happen on the cage.
I'm not going to give those opportunities.
So it's hard to say,
but you know,
the way division doesn't make too much
difference for me if I have the time to,
to, to cook and slow burn.
But if the thing's kind of,
if even my way division 80 kilos for
example, if I want to fight that guy,
we've had 95 kilos and make a technology.
So I going to fight a different monster
in five minutes rounds is almost
impossible. How are we, I mean,
so and then that's kind of unbalanced
now based on the stream aspect of the
sport, the physicality of the sport and
the technique who has to be applied.
So the difference between
a fight and a match,
the difference between a fight
in a sport and in a fight,
they're just two guys going
out each other. And I agree
that there's many, many,
many fights where a guy when a ten nine
round and another guy when the other 10
Reiner and then one guy
when the final round,
maybe tonight a little troll or something,
it's a draw to be.
It's not done. It's like sex without
an orgasm. Yeah, complete days.
He's men and normally happens.
I mean sometimes beautiful knockouts,
but sometimes you know, it's just,
you know, a too much strength,
too much physicality and every time goes
to the flooding I immediately stand up.
He, because if he knows
if he stay on the ground,
he's losing time and he's not going to
be able to capitalize because the time is
not as long as enough and too,
so that's kind of, you know,
a great area is not a,
it doesn't have the appeal for
me to see a good, a good match.
What about when hoist fought Sakuraba
and they had that crazy 90 minute match?
Yes.
What about that was uh,
an idea of like having these long,
long matches [inaudible] Jujitsu.
We need time because we don't have,
I mean we give that vantage off weight,
we give advantage of, you know, whatever.
So let's at least have the time
for us to be becoming strategical.
But would you have preferred that kind
of a fight to be no rounds though cause
that fight they broke up into
a series of rounds. Yeah,
I'm in at that point I felt
like it was a lack of action of,
I mean hoist supposed to fight better.
I was not on his side.
And a, I see a pads on on him too
sometimes make little mistakes,
which when I was there,
I was focused on making him
few sharp and we find not dad.
I felt like a little fuzzy.
I had to do it mentally.
His focus was not. So it's a lot of
different elements for Chu Chu, Chu,
Chu, Chu, Chu justified, you know,
because I believe hoist has elements
should beat Sakuraba, you know, and,
but he didn't, so it was just, he did
the second time. Yeah, the rematch.
Yeah. He found the second time
in a la right. Wasn't that,
were you there when he fought
him the second time? Did he
match? No. No. Did you, he,
you know, he beat him, right? Yeah.
And that's the rematch. We Oh, you
were aware of that, right? No, I'm not.
Oh, okay. Yeah. They had a rematch
and he beat him here in la one. Right.
It was k one. It was at the
coliseum. That was the first time.
Brock Lesnar fraud too. Yeah.
Now there's a, a lot of problems.
Jujitsu guys have world class Mundey Al
blackbelt champions have an MMA is they
get in the cage and it happens.
I would say it's a big reason why they
ended up getting cut from the UFC as they
ended up fighting wrestlers.
Like everyone at the top 10 is
really hard to take down the UFC.
So did you just a guy will come in and
he's fighting a guy who wrestled his
whole life.
There's zero chance that he's going
to be able to take down that rest are.
So He's forced to kickbox right.
So the wrestlers forcing the kickbox
kickboxing fight because the Jujitsu guy
can't take down the wrestler.
Do in those situations. Um,
uh, like, uh, I dunno if you remember
Nogueira when he fought Tim Sylvia,
the big giant guy,
he could not take Tim Silvia down.
So he eventually shot Tim Silvia sprawled
a little bit and then Nogueira pulled
guard. He was on his back. He swept him,
he got on top and then he choked
him out with the Guillotine.
So in that situation,
the guard pool saved Nogueira like,
cause what do you think about it?
I 100% I 100% confident in the guard
because what I see today in the display of
great Jujitsu fighters in the
cage is they have the guard,
but they have a sportive guard. They
don't have a valley to the garden. Yes.
They not dangerous the bottom.
Yes.
So they become technicals from the bottom
against the dangerous ground in pound.
Yeah. So they get all dead. They're
getting all that these advantage.
So in my perspective, for example, crown,
he's been training to deal with
tough wrestler, stuffed boxers,
but he don't try to apply wrestling
against wrestling because he going to need
another life to become like a shoots or
like a Matt Hughes or like some other
tough,
what is the strategy for chrome when he
fights a rustler that he can't take down,
he brings to the guard.
So he's so golf bowling has something
that he's thinking about guard his no
other option on the ground.
Jujitsu has to be happy on top
in happier on the bottom. Yes.
People frown upon.
I'm a big advocate of pulling garden and
they made their fighters that have done
it. There's a guy named Paul Sass from
England. He pulls guard all the time.
He's a master of pulling guard. He knows
exactly how to do it. He shoots deep.
The guy sprawls and as he sprawling,
he pulls guard and he's,
he puts people in triangles, triangle
victories in a row. Yeah, he,
but the triangle is risky because once
you know how to defend, like unluck,
you'll becoming available
for granted grounded pounds.
So if the guy is completely safe on
the not getting caught in the triangle,
your attempts of techniques,
I kind of diminishing your capacity
to survive and to defend yourself.
So you attacking techniques from the
bottom, but he's still on the rich. Yes.
So the idea of a perfect valley to
the guard is save your distance.
You don't get pounded by those surprising
elbows like John Kalench over her.
No, no. You cannot clinch.
You have chosen in the legs and
you have to heat with the legs.
So it's always a striking from the bottom.
You know, it doesn't have to be quick.
So you don't believe that you should
be clenched. And only if the guy,
if the guy promotes that,
if he wants to space to hit you,
you need to be comfortable
and hit him back.
So he's a fight where imagine a 12
year old kid laying down on the ground,
we feed to you.
If you start,
you're using the foot is going to be
hard for even you is a big man to reach.
Yeah. So there's no use of the legs.
People has no clue how to striking,
how to use.
I know in UFC has some illegal
heal from the barn and you can,
but you still can use different strikes.
You know,
you can even have the distance to survive
and to be completely protected against
elbows. And, and the issue though
that if someone can disengage,
if you're on your back and you're trying
to not clench and not hold onto them,
your Jujitsu practitioner, the guy
can just disengage you, haven't they?
They just stand up. Once it does
engage, he's escaping from the fight.
I can stand up again and keep
the same process of bleaching.
So,
so now crowns in a situation where he's
fighting a wrestler and he can't take
them down. Then he pulls guard. Yeah.
And then he opens up his legs to kick.
The guy stands up. Now he's
got to stand up again. Yes. So
they could just keep doing that over
and over again. Like how does he went?
Chocolate Dell,
who's an expert.
Stryker as well as the rest of
the very tough to take down,
but also an expert striker.
When you get that guy to the ground,
don't you want to optimize
that opportunity as much
as possible and hang onto
them while you're on the bottom?
That's depends.
Depends where the way division where,
what is the weight distribution is.
I have to obey the sense if he's on me,
I lose sweep him. I will be on his
back in no time. If he's away from me.
If he wants you looking for distance, I
have to understand that and respect that.
Then protect myself to don't get founded,
you know? And and that process of,
okay, I don't want to engage. He's
moving back and then you stand up.
And all of this process.
A lot of things happen.
What is important for as Jujitsu fighter
is know everything about the anti game
off the Stryker. I don't make grown, I
don't try to make crone a good striker.
I want to make him
comfortable to in and out.
I want to make very comfortable to
fight inside with knees and elbows,
you know, be, be dangerous inside,
be comfortable on top and
be very comfortable in the
bottle and the action man.
It because it's a lot of,
even though in those five
minutes fight is a lot of action.
I mean there's a lot of
stalling is a lot of studies,
a lot of disengage. I mean
they engage in it, it'll be,
and then they separate and okay now
let's think, let's see who's fight.
It's hard to see a guy who's just
goes like, and I feel like the,
the great uh,
element to give it to strategy of growth
is going to keep a prat consistent
pressure.
That means he's not going to be studying
or in a distance where the striker
fuels, like waiting is going
to be the two out or chew in.
And then once it's in, let's fight the
fight, let's fight like a, you know,
elbows, whatever. And then immediately
the fight goes to the ground,
no matter if it's one
on top or on the bottom.
And then the consistence of this,
I feel like opportunities will rise.
Do you watch MMA a lot to this? Did
you watch Bj Penn's last fight? Yes,
doubt that. If I was very sad
to me, very sad to watch. Um,
and I was very frustrated
watching it as a Bj Penn Fan,
as a Frankie Edgar Fan,
I thought it was a great performance.
But one of the things that frustrates me
about Bj is that he very rarely attacks
from his back.
When he's on the bottom,
he puts feed on the hips and
he just kind of holds on.
Yes, maybe he was not exactly, I dunno.
I mean he did the poor, a poor, poor
game from the bottom and my perspective,
he supposed to have a little
more um, elements, Choo, Choo,
Choo, Choo. Not preserve his integrity
but also to attack, you know,
and I don't fell that
then I feel like I'm in,
he's just not doing what he's supposed to.
Eddie, we talked that, yeah. That sort of
frustrated you a little bit too, right?
Yes. I don't know if you're aware of
the six and, but I'm, I'm obsessed with,
I've been obsessed with developing the
best guard for when they're striking,
I analyze it and to death and
I'm the guard that I comprised.
I put elements from, you know, my students
helped me. Nina Schembri helped me.
So I put all these elements together,
but it all started off when I was on
this quest to put together the ultimate
guard for MMA because I was seeing too
many guys just get beat up in the garden.
I thought we got to like, I felt like
you had like the effectiveness is gone.
What is the problem? Why are people
getting pounded in the guard?
We have to change this. So the first
thing I studied was you and Henzel.
This was back in the nineties
I go, okay, well I'm going to,
I'm going to attempt to
improve the guard in MMA.
So I looked at you and I looked
at him Zanga what are they doing?
They're in full guard and
their whole holding the over
hook to prevent the punch.
Like anybody tried to punch in
the guard with the right arm,
you would over hook it. And
when headbutts were legal, your,
your left hand was like this. You were
like this protecting the head bud.
But then when they met
head ahead of what's legal,
you don't have to do this no more.
So you could hold the head now and now
in this position with the overlook,
you have full guard, you're holding
the head. There's a clinch there.
So to me as trying to be a Jujitsu
scientist trying to, I'm like,
if that, that is the
stance in MMA, that's it.
You enhance or that's what you guys are
doing it. You look at all the old fights,
full guard stopped the
paunch hold the head.
And so to me that was the
starting point. Yes, I agree.
And uh, but Jujitsu is a, is an animal
whose never stopped to grow. Yes.
And one day I was comfortably
in California watching a
fight in Brazil and then
I saw like I eight men tournament where
fabulous Janelle was fighting mark care
in my care was the first
time he'd show up in the end.
The first time I saw him fighting.
That was his first tournament. Yes.
So, and he went to the finals with
fibro and I knew Fabul I train with him.
He's a brother, you know, we,
and I saw what he did with fiber.
You like stay on thought ground and
pound and smashing the elbow on his fee
after five years to forgetting to his
arm and was like next day he was all your
flame arm and you go into the,
the airplane like this,
you made almost lose the arm because
then they give antibiotic. We're never,
but anyway,
after I saw that fight and
the in the lack of options,
fiber was there. Next Day
in the morning, I wake up,
I call my son Hawks and he's down
to 11 years old, about hundred,
10 pounds. He said, hug.
So I'm coming here and then I went to
the garage on my mats, said lay down,
put him, lay down. And I
tried to represent the same
position because the, the,
the different,
the size weights does almost the same
from fiber would yell to kid, then me
for four Alexson.
So I kind of immediately put him in the
fibers position and I put myself in and,
and uh,
mark your position and then I start,
you will analyze his was insect
crow Huxson do this, do that,
move a little more this way. So
it was not, we're not a fighting,
but I tried to find him a position for
him to be comfortable and I spent about
45 and 50 minutes searching is studying
with him because I liked that kind of
unproportional size.
When I finish that,
that section
and totally like I reinvent myself in
terms of what are you going to do if I
have to fight my catch your model
because I was satisfied with the angles.
I could put Harkin in our that
you resist my leverage, my angles,
what exactly I saw in the day before.
So that means from one day to a neither.
I kind of focus myself in fix it.
The problem I saw with fabulous and
at that point I felt like, okay,
I'm fixed now I'm ready to fight for new
wears out your model and what does this,
what is the stance? What
did you change? I could not,
I could not have him go hawks and
could not have him in control.
He has to create distance.
He has true how shen across the belly
not he has to use defeat more properly on
the hips. Yes, he has to
use the knee on the chest.
Sometimes he has to use the element of,
of as I approach to
getting better position,
the bottom guy has to heat
because if you don't we strike.
You don't make the guy kind of go back.
So he's a combination between fighting
in Brazil we have two different names
when you bra and when you fight.
Fight is more like a sportive
and when you Brah you like, uh,
just do it whenever.
So technically speaking,
when somebody wants to
add back me as a brawler,
I don't want to fight a broad back.
I want to be technical and survive and
be comfortable and soon his statutes say
full, I cannot have anything here. Let me
be taking code to see if I can advance.
And that's the time I will blow
against him and make him get confused.
So I have to change your strategies as
he come. If he come in to be a fighter,
I will be aggressive.
I'd be mean if he come in to be a brawler,
I will be technical and
I will be comfortable.
So that kind of sense of change gives
up perspective for the the bottom guy,
it should be on on edge, which
will be on top of the, the office.
Now Mark Kerr in that fight
that you're talking about,
fibers or show headbutts were legal.
So that was a huge part of how he
was getting busted up with headbutts.
But since then headbutts
it becoming legal, uh,
we're the headbutts a big reason you
decided to change your guard stamp also,
but the elbows in the reach and the
way the guy position himself, you know,
and the way, uh, fiber was
always with the leg cross.
He was falling exactly what he
learned and what he saw. And he,
he could not have the time to improvise.
Nobody expect Mark Caribbean
tough as he was then.
The monsters just happened in front of
Fabio and he has to deal with whatever he
didn't know. He was crying and throwing
up in the locker room before that. Fine.
Yeah, he is. He was emotional.
Yes. Very nervous. And I mean,
shows in the little documentary he did.
He always have,
but then in one point he's a potential.
He was, the men should be beating.
He was like, he was enormous.
Yes. And, uh, you know, as a fan,
as a fan of Jujitsu and a fan of mixed
martial arts and valley to dope, man,
I would just wish you had had those
opportunities to face those guys.
I would have loved to have seen any true,
ah, now I'm what I, like I said,
when I was trying to figure out the
best MMA guard, I was looking at you,
I was looking at Hixson
grabbing the overlook and,
but the one thing I knew is if
that's the defensive posture,
this is what I was thinking.
I didn't know you changed it up.
But at that point I thought that was it.
That's the defensive posture.
Someone was in your guard, you have to
defend first. So I thought, well okay,
that has to be the stance. So we have
to create or offense from that stance.
So the defense is first and do we have
off fence from the overheard and my
instructor John Jacques Machado,
and he is one of the only guys I know
of out of all the top Jujitsu guys that
his whole game is based on the over Hook
and not grabbing the sleeves because
his left hand, he was born without
fingers. So no matter what,
whether it was Geeky or no geek,
he needed that over hook cause
he couldn't control the sleeves.
So his overall game was translated
to a students, me included.
So I was always looking for the ovary
because John Jack was my master and,
and then when,
when he got invited to Abu Dhabi,
before he went to Abu Dhabi,
there was a lot of legends there that a
lot of Jujitsu legends that were going
to Abu Dhabi and without the gay,
there was no offense,
there was a lot of boring matches.
But John Jack shows up and he
just rises above everybody.
If you watch what John Jack did in Abu
Dhabi, he didn't change his left arm,
didn't change without a
gears. I know, gee, I'm still
going to grab that over Hook.
Anyways.
Everybody else was lost because they were
used to their fighting stance or guard
fighting. Sam's was
sleeve color, color sleep.
So without the Geeta had to change
everything and they weren't used to it.
They didn't have any offense from there.
So to me, I took what you and Hanzo,
oh we're doing what the
overlook and the controlling,
but that's how John Jog fights with
the over hook. So all his sweeps,
John Jackson just look,
look at all the sweeps in Abu Dhabi.
He's throwing people around. He, his
first year he submitted everybody.
He was like the first Marcello Garcia.
Everybody was freaked out like how
is this guy doing it? They they,
they didn't even understand it,
but to me it was like it was
because his game didn't change.
When he's training in the gay,
he's trained for Abu Dhabi. The,
the people that we're training in.
The key,
before they weren't trained for Abu Dhabi,
he was, cause it was all over every,
he was sweeping wrestlers, all Carro
Uno. He was all over these guys.
So for me that over Hook
not as not for John Shock,
that over hook is important for grappling,
not even for valid Tudos.
So if he did valid due to or if someone
with that style guard did violet tutor,
the overhead game automatically takes
away the punch and he has authentic from
that style too.
So for me that became the,
the basis and the focus for the ultimate
MMA guard was to master the over Hook
like,
like John Jock and not only just defend
but put those butterflies in and try to
sweep or set up triangles like you,
you have an overlook you sweet pea basis,
you grab that risk boom triangles.
So I thought that was the uh,
based on what you and Hanzo did and John
Jack style because because of it was
like a blessing in disguise. Him
Boring born without fingers. It is,
it was a blessing disguise.
He's in Abu Dhabi legend.
Everybody looks at John.
Jack is Yoda.
Like how did you come into Abu
Dhabi and finish everybody?
To me it was just that overhaul game.
He didn't really have to change much of
his game. So that's how Marcella Garcia,
that's his philosophy to his philosophy
is, and he said this in interviews it,
if you can't do it,
if you training,
there's a guid technique that
you can't do Nogi throw it out,
only focus on the techniques that
are going to translate to Nogi.
So that way when you're
practicing the Geek,
you're actually practicing Nogi as well.
So John Jea or Marcello is very against
being reliant too much on the color and
too much on the sleeve. He stays away
from that because even take downs,
he doesn't want to do
judo takedowns because no,
that are not going to work as much.
He wants to do take downs at the
in the guid that translate Nogi.
So, um, that was, that's just this,
the conclusions that I came to,
that's how I trained my fighters
that are finding an Mba.
And it all started with
watching you and Henson. Yes.
I, I completely, you know, fuel,
like that's a good standard position too
because you have to have a control in
stuff. But the evolutionary process
brought all that kinds of the guards,
you know, and uh, I kind
of also, uh, find my,
my comfortable those days and,
and ensure a more spacey guard.
The more like towards my father's guard
was because he's was very weak guy,
always handle big guys and he don't have
like this kind of strength or control
Europe over here,
his opponents.
So he was more like hip movements and
using the ankles, losing the food,
you know, it's more like a, a
very Lito from the bottom, uh,
allowing the guy to get lost.
So it's a combination between the two I
think is today's is the perfect option.
Why do you think Ronda Rousey is
the only fighter in MMA today?
That when she, she's pulling off her arm
bar. Looks Amazing. Have you seen her?
I like, of course it's why his,
as soon as she's in the guard,
as soon as she's not going to wait,
she's going to go and attack that
arm and she goes right to it.
She doesn't wipe and I've trained with
their many times and her arm bar is legit.
It's, it's not a joke. It's, yeah. To me,
I think she has the best arm
bar in MMA today because she's,
no one has pulled it off
as much as she hadn't. Yes.
She hasn't really gone against
top level Jujitsu girls. But, uh,
based on me training with her, I
think that she can, she can tap out.
It's going to be harder of course.
But why do you think she's the only one?
And there's all these black belts
and Jujitsu and MMA and they're not,
they don't look anything like
Rhonda Rousey. Why is that?
Um, she's a special girl.
She's very competitive. She's,
she's a very talented person.
But a side of this,
she have a heavy trainee in judo,
which defines her character,
you know, defines her hair,
her desire to train,
hard to compete too.
So being a,
an Olympic level judo player is
being a wrestler in that level.
That's bringing Q two on different
level, you know, it's not being just, um,
an athlete.
She is a super athlete.
She is very defined and
very, very much, uh,
specialize in one thing.
Their game.
She hair game is always like going towards
the same pattern and in the opponents
she's facing a,
he is not exactly prepare for that.
I feel like nobody has the
skills on the ground to,
to,
to fight her and nobody has the,
the heavy hands in the situation to,
to beat here in standing up.
So everything's kind of even up. But
Gwen goes to the ground when the, the,
the opponent gets the first troll and
falls like without seeing it get lost.
And then she, she, her movements
are very, very effective and, and,
and we will capitalize on
that. But you know, um,
maybe five fights,
then fights more beautiful winds.
But eventually she got to have a person
who has the same elements and then she's
going to start, you have
competition, you know,
because so far it feels like
even too easy, you know,
it's like not even a competition for it.
She's like a Mike Tyson.
She's like,
when Mike Tyson was his job,
eventually a Cyborg.
Rhonda is going to happen.
Dana's going to make sure that happens
eventually. How do you see that going?
Oh, that's interesting
because you know, um,
she will have the, the
preparation, the mindset,
the heavy hands and also the, the, the,
the skill to become like a,
a competitive for four Honda I think.
And he's unpredictable. Like,
you know, any fight, you know,
you gotta put your money down,
who would you,
there's no reason for me to put my mind.
And then Honda,
I mean, he's in a good, I mean
I, it's getting better too.
Did you see her last fight?
Yeah, she's improved.
She's throwing combinations with
the judo throws and her throws.
They're just out of control.
Yeah.
She starts throwing people and,
and new HSA.
When she found me shut Meesha,
the legit wrestler,
Meesha can Russell and she was
making some big mistakes though.
She was very high up on her. Above
her weight was above the hips. I mean,
I think there was a lot of pressure
involved in that fight. She would,
you would think that when you in Nma
generally when someone starts doing
something that's effective,
that wasn't a done before.
Like the front snap kick that
Travis Browne is doing now.
Serone he's doing it all the time.
Nobody was stolen that we need to see it
first work in the UFC. Nickel, Oh man,
the front snap kick or the rear leg snap
kick to the chest and that's working.
So that's huge. Now, five
years ago, no one throw it.
They thought it was a waste of time.
It doesn't work.
That only works in the movies. But
there's all these kicks, head kicks and,
and now that we've seen Rhonda show the
effectiveness of focusing and drilling
that armbar over and over,
and she talks about you. I do.
You think people aren't paying attention
to it and aren't going? Look what works.
Look what happens with the arm bar when
you do it 100,000 times. Let's do that.
Let's do you think they're not
doing it because she's a girl?
No one's paying attention. Really,
you would think is easy. I mean,
hair performance is, it
reflects, it reflects a life.
Even her parents aren't
involved in judo. Yeah. So, uh,
it's a lifetime of achievements is a
subconscious reflex is not something which
you educate people.
It's like you don't think you could
learn it if you practiced hard enough,
you have to be like a,
at least a classification.
The classification phase to go to the top,
top 10 in judo is not just
learn is dedicate yourself,
your sweat and tears and blood is
intensity to get there. You know,
it's like being a Jujitsu
champion is one thing.
Doing what crown does two days.
Another thing.
He is not only fighting hard but he goes
and train hard and your run hide and
lift weights. Whatever he does, he
does with the compromise to excel.
And that's a mindset. There's
not exactly, you teach,
it's something I believe Honda
is a special girl because
she put herself in that
kind of level of stress and she handled
and she, I mean the training is hard.
The comps, the focus
is hard. She's serious.
And does the whole formula is there to
support him, have victories, you know,
he's not a flake or it's not as
good luck. You know, he's not,
oh [inaudible] come here, let me show
how to defend the analog and now you go,
you ready to fight? It's not like
that, you know, so anyone in the,
in the mixed martial arts,
it's coming from a background because
they see mixed martial arts egg as a good
exposure,
as a good situation to make money to me.
So they come in with I average
background to try, you know,
their best.
They sometimes having from the the,
the Hasni family and then learning some
box, some Jujitsu, some defense and go,
they're coming from the judo and goal.
They're going to be from the Jujitsu and
go into learning a little bit here and
there.
But very few are like,
uh, like uh, Randy couture,
which is already
established champion like a,
like a Coleman,
you know,
guys who have defined their lives in,
in one thing and then they
breed to another, but they
have already the sense of,
you know,
they believe in themselves.
They can capitalize on the
mistakes they forward forever.
So those things that, you
know, you don't buy it on the,
on the work ethic on the
supermarket, you know, those things,
his lifetime experience is high chew.
Yeah.
The intensity that Ronda Rousey brings,
the training just to life itself.
It's very difficult to
replicate and that it has,
it resonates throughout
everything she does. She's crazy.
Now when in the best way,
crone when against Shinier Okie.
I'm assuming that you studied
a lot of Shinya Aoki tapes.
Do you I personally think he's,
uh,
one of the best at Jujitsu and MMA as
far as he's gotten so many submissions.
You get you with leg locks.
He has a great rear naked choke
has guards really good. Yes. Um,
were you impressed by
watching tape of a Shinya?
Shinya is not only I'm impressed by tapes.
The first Buddha challenge I did
he win with honors. You know, he,
he winded the Buddha challenge in
some meeting. Everybody, you know,
he won your yeah, the [inaudible]
has different way divisions.
And here's way division. He makes you
fight since we meet bolt. And who,
who were the guys? Do
you remember? Uh, uh,
Carl. He fought two guys too.
I didn't even really know who he was
in 2005 to tell you the truth then you
already know. Yeah. So anyway,
I felt how Tavi, how tight,
how tight to help rescission.
His submission,
he got a flying arm in lock in the first
guy and the food log in the second guy.
So I felt like he's very
versatile, versatile, you know,
he has a highlight reel of judo where
he would define armbars in judo,
just one after another.
And that's was something I absorbed in.
Then we, in our training
we've grown, I said,
and we are kind of decide to,
because he was very comfortable
when you engage on the grip.
So from your grip he can go for a flying
triangle flying. I'm lots and such.
So crown was pressuring him.
We doubting engage using the food and
trying to make him feel like he has drew
engaged, not grown grabbing. So
that's kind of give the first,
the first way for him to feel like lost.
He was expecting chrome to attempt but
grown was pressuring without grabbing.
If you see the fight again,
you see so,
and the one point they engage
crumpled to the guard and uh,
he was kind of trying to stay and couldn't
go to the head ones he can escape and
then chrome finish with the
headlock as when the rule.
But the guy is very tough.
We are not worried about these Jujitsu
back and forth like that tempts him to
submit ground. Those are hard to catch
because grown is very skewed to defend.
But is he good at defending leg locks?
Chrome? Yes, yes. But uh, still,
uh,
the opportunity was raised based on,
he is his desire to act.
So we forced him to act.
He gave what we want and crunk catch
precisely and sharp and was over every,
every morning.
Every time I work out and go to the gym,
I warm up on a stairmaster
and I just go ADCC, Marcella,
Darcy or whoever.
And I just,
I just want to warm up and watch
people do Jujitsu at a high level.
And that just gets my blood boiling and
I just want to go lift weights. Right?
So I'm watching a Marcello
and crone and Matt recently,
and I'm watching the last one. Yeah. And
I haven't watched it in awhile, but man,
I'm so used to Marcello just
going through everybody.
Marcella just brushes.
He is unbelievable what he does.
People go to his gym, he's like, hey,
you can come to my gym,
I'll roll with you,
but we're going to videotape it and
we're gonna put it on the Internet deal.
And they're like everyone that
goes, there's like, Oh Matt here.
Like they're walking into the slaughter
slaughterhouse, right? He puts on a,
everyone's going to see the role. So
that's, and he just crushes everybody.
Big dudes. And then for him,
when he went against crone,
he passed crones guard for a couple
seconds. But then after that initial, he,
it was a double leg dragon.
He jumped in.
And then crones ability to recover.
Full Guard is unlike
anybody I've ever seen.
You rarely see full guard in Abu Dhabi.
People stay away from full guard,
but chrome will force uni,
forest,
Marcella Garcia and
crone into full garden.
Marcella was having a hard
time and then he broke it,
finally broke open his full guard,
then he tried to pass again and then he's
back and full guard again. And then, uh,
um, crump, put them in a
guillotine and the word is,
and Marcel I think admits this, he went
out, like he went out to him and he said,
Whoa,
that
almost best south. And then, but grown he,
because it going in the end off
the mat, the first, like the round,
he was trying to save himself
for it for the next round. So he,
he put pressure and then he kind of said,
dad,
I kind of just try to hold instead,
keeping putting all my power.
So, and then, I mean,
nothing happened and the guy kind
of survive and he kind of won.
But you won on a take down
so that it could have,
he could have put them to sleep there if
that's possible. I mean it's, you know,
but that's always the
thing with the guillotine,
knowing whether or not to exert all your
energy and gas, you're honest, but crony,
specializing the guillotine.
I mean,
he coming in the next for the next,
for the lest Abu Dhabi prepared to, to,
to face Marcel again. And here's this
guy, Laney, his progress is being very,
very, you know,
progressive. And um, and uh,
he was ready,
but fortunately Marcel didn't,
she didn't come and he made great
fights and he displayed like,
especially the good routine against Tanu.
[inaudible] what's great in the final,
the guy just when he jumps,
and I feel like you guys talking
about this fight and about the chicken
[inaudible] it.
At first I didn't believe it.
I'm like someone explain it to people
who didn't hear our other podcasts. Well,
what chrome,
when in 2013,
Abu Dhabi crone showed up and did with,
with what only I think maybe,
uh, John Jog did it. Marcella did it
and I think maybe Hodgett Gracie did it.
I'm not sure that he went in and submitted
all four of his opponents and in the,
uh, he, he submitted Gary Tonin
in an amazing match with guests.
Last fight I saw. Incredible.
Yeah, it was incredible.
I was losing my mind watching that
one. And, and he submitted JT Torres,
who's a beast, j d tours. So good. And
he got them from the guard. He got it.
He just had the overlook
and he just flipped his leg
over his face and just held
onto the over. Cause it was kind of like
one of those over hook arm bars and,
and then he beat a, who did
he beat first? I don't know.
But the first
one was like a,
I'm not sure his name,
but he put a guy to sleep and then get
this Gary Guy and the first day. Yeah.
And then join the second danger
and then I'll tell me on the finals,
well the match we're talking about and
me and Joe talked about this and they
made a, Stewart Cooper made a
film on it, but Oh Tevya Sousa.
His strategy was to not be honest back,
stay on top and just kind of maybe
get a takedown late, you know,
cause that's a,
in that rule format or that points format
in Abu Dhabi that that happens a lot.
People will just Russell and Russell
and Russell and uh, he wasn't engaging.
And crone is like, like just like Hixon
saying, he's like Marcello. He's like,
he goes after it, he's going to go
100%. All he wants is the submission.
That's cronies, especial
grappler, special fighter.
All he wants is the submission. And
Oh, Tevya wasn't really engaging.
And as a father, no,
no, no, not as a fire.
As a coach.
I saw his coach as the fight progress.
The guy saying [inaudible] Portuguese.
Okay man, that's it. That's all you want.
Okay, keep going. It's
perfect. Perfect. Perfect.
And I see a guy just running from
the fight in making strategy,
which kind of upset me completely.
I mean there's nothing perfect
on dead in my sense. And,
but in the strategic aspect of He's,
he's,
he's doing so I have to counter in
somehow and then I start to make sure,
try to suggest the referee.
He was escaping.
He was try to avoid the fight because
it's not positive points in the first 10
minutes, but it's negative points. So I
was hoping for a negative 0.2 with dot.
Well followed. This is stalling. So,
and then I start to say [inaudible]
the guy stature moving like you know,
he don't want to engage you.
It's just moving back like
a chicken la, la La la La.
And as the thing starts,
you're boiling. I start to say,
hey mountain sky like a chicken
and the whole stage was this
quiet watching the fight
is just this noise kind of
overwhelming.
It's like throwing a chicken inside in a
for a Jujitsu competitor. First of all.
I mean I know you're, you're right
here but I just have to be honest.
Everybody says you're the greatest ever.
You're the greatest Jujitsu
competitor of all time.
So you are here the greatest
Jujitsu representative of all time.
Your son is competing.
This guy has to respect
you and admire you and your
going Bock, bock, bock, bock, bock, bock
and the whole crowd is listening to this.
I mean that's a lot of
pressure on that guy.
How to get into his head
because in his book,
because I was suggesting the referee,
he needs should be punished and
eventually like with 90 minutes or so,
he get minus points and that's what's
exactly what generates him to say,
okay, now I'm hunting, be
raw honey running behind.
So I have to make it happen.
And as we talk and afterwards we've
grown, grown said dad, when I do start,
you're talking like a chicken.
I felt like he wanted explore them.
I don't want to make a mistake wasting
the opportunity, but I know he will come.
He so I was just ready for it.
So we kind of working together,
you know like it wasn't a father
and son Warren was perfect.
He shot right in and then he's already
waiting for boom is over. Go home.
Oh it's ice cream. That's one
thing. That's the one thing
John Jack would tell me,
cause train for John.
Jock obviously trained me from metamorris
and we would talk about crone and and
John Jack said, I asked John Junk, what
is crones best technique? He goes, man,
that guillotine,
he wraps his arms around your head.
He's got an incredible squeeze.
The guillotine used to
be a strong man move.
Like I used to think of like even the
arm and guillotine like that's a strong
man. I never got into
guillotines but over the last 10,
15 years they've gotten
so told him, I said, um,
I'm always been trying to specialize
myself in all the submissions
and I have my good routine,
which you know, giving me
some victories, but you know,
and then one day at one time I was
talking if grown on, it's not even on the,
on the mat was in the locker room.
And then I said, yeah, but you know,
team and you have the guy can escapes at
an old dead, those Inchcape. I said, no,
it's Kevin. I said, hello? He said, no,
if I get it. I said, I'll come on, man.
Grabbed me, man, I tap you.
And then I have to rethink
my whole strategy said,
yeah, this guy has, you know,
he's already have something to tell me.
His levels of squeeze right is the
level of grip is a level of grab.
The way you hold is all technical and
these did regular escape doesn't work
anymore.
So of course we have escape for crones,
Cha Guillotine, but it's a
different than I was visualizing.
So I have to learn how to escape
from Everage guillotines and Crohn's
guillotine. So it has to be
special. The defense, those levels,
the technical levels are lost on a lot
of people that are just watching it.
The differences, subtle variations.
That is the essence of Jujitsu.
I believe the beast, the biggest
aspect of Jujitsu is invisible.
My, I pray I'm in I my, my, my,
I preach the invisible Jujitsu because
easy visible because you see it but you
don't see it. You see the same guide
position. You see the same amount,
but you have to feel it. You know, I,
I base my Jujitsu and how you feel,
not what you see and that's
just totally different.
When I go in the seminars and stuff, the
guy feel different. They say, wow man,
I've been doing this all my life and I
never felt this way. So, so good though.
Okay. There's so much leverage. So, so
based on the way distribution base on the,
on the, on the sense of, of leverage in,
Oh this can change at the same position
you've seen a picture cannot be worth it
or it can be very much effective depending
how the grip, the angle, the elbow,
the,
the weight.
So it's amazing how the visible
Jujitsu is what really supports the,
you know,
it's not what you learn superficially.
What do you think about Marcella
Garcia is variation of the guillotine.
He that [inaudible] some people call it
a high elbow team and lot of people call
it the Marcella tin where he
doesn't believe like, like
this. Yeah. What have you,
is that part of something that you've
taught her? Is that new to you know,
he's not new is an option which
developed by him like he is,
he's the master on this, not, so you see
different submissions from the brag. Yeah.
Ambition. So it's
adaptations, you know, Eh,
if you focus and you know what's
coming and you have defenses,
I don't believe a good routine is
effective regardless. No. Yeah.
All they give the teams you can defend,
but you have to be precise.
If you make one mistake,
if you're thinking about defense one
and the guy come in with a little twist,
the difference one's not going to work.
And if you think about change for
the second you already tapping,
are you already sleeping?
Yes. So you have to be precise
on, on the adaptation of each.
So now we've grown, gets
me, I know exactly what I
have to go. If I delay five,
two seconds, then going to over yeah. Is
over. So, and that's, this goes for any,
any technique. There's so many
different ways to squeeze the neck.
I would off the top of my head,
you know,
including all the arm in a chokes,
like the Darce and the Japanese Necktie,
the arm and Kia teen,
the different grips,
all these different net cranks.
There's gotta be just those on the
nosy, various ones. Like how, how, uh,
how you call the, the neck brace from
like the one, the twister. Yes. Yes.
That was not really a chunk then
that's just straighten that. Yeah.
But there's so many ways, just know
[inaudible] there's so many ways to,
to put someone to sleep.
I would say there's 15 to 20 different
ways Nogi to squeeze the neck.
Everyone's got their own different stops.
Did you get into,
cause one of the most popular chokes
over the last 10, 15 years in the,
in the Nogi grappling seen is
the Darce are you familiar with,
what is the dose like? Bravo choke. It's
the, it's a bravo joke. It's a squeeze,
but it's the arms back. No,
no. From top sites. Like yes,
I'm going to half guard
like and half guard.
And you come in and it's like you have
an over Hook and you'd come and raise
that one.
That's become just the one of
the most basic standard chokes.
And it came sort of from a
wrestling a three quarter Nelson,
a technique that was used to fly
people over. And then, uh, uh,
I think it was Dave Terrell showed it to,
uh,
Joe Darcy and then every mark layman's
started calling it Joe Darce because he
learned from Joe Darce but he,
he actually,
I don't know John Danaher there's a whole
story but the name stuck to Doris. Um,
was that something that you guys were
doing back in the seventies and eighties?
That's more of a newer church and the
people understanding the origins of the
triangle, like just the leg triangle. Uh,
there's so many different
theories on where,
how that got injected into
a Heleo style and like do,
do you know the origins of a tribe or
is it just an old journal technique? No,
I mean you feel going to
hold the book techniques,
you're going to see all the
submissions, you know, like, uh,
the application of triangles in my life.
It started Chicago me by,
by my understanding the concept and seeing
that Longo guys like a Maca home guys
and we've long legs like Maca,
how, who was the car? My husband
is like old school guy, old school. I
saw guys doing this and I start to apply,
you know, I start to you,
my legs are not too long,
so I have to pick the perfect position
to do, but I start to get, you know,
familiar with and I,
man, it's just, you know,
it's hard to say where it come from,
but it's, I have, I have my open mind,
like
the Eric Postel situation with the
new, I always have, I opened mine,
chew a Psap, chew twin brace,
stinks. Our functional, you know,
and discard everything, which I don't
like it, you know, it's not about theory.
It's not about, it's about effective and
is about results is about, phew, phew.
Comfortable there.
So anything I see,
no matter if it's from Bruce Lee or
from any rest or a catch catch gun,
or if I see an I like and I want to be
going experiment immediately because I
just edge my arsenal. You
know, that's the concept, uh,
which leads shoe to development, to, to,
to progression and to success.
It's one of the beautiful things about
Jujitsu is that it's constantly growing.
There's always new techniques.
The idea that the Darce
choke wasn't around when you
were competing and now it's
a staple mainstay.
It's fascinating.
I'd have to bring this up because
if I didn't bring this up,
everybody online would go crazy.
There's a video tape of when Yogi
Anjo showed up at your Dojo and you,
you, you know, you saw it. No
oil. No, I've never seen it. No,
he didn't say let's make the next
barbecue and my house definitely wanna sit
planet the world wants to see
the world wants you. Will you,
will you release it to the world? Probably
eventually. Oh No, you gotta release it.
That's one of the number one things that
people are, and when I hit a couple of,
of people on my site, I may do that. We'll
do a free on the side. Make that happen.
I won't make that happen. Tell us that
story. How did that story come about?
Oh, just when I finished
the valley to the 95, uh,
was a legit eight men
tournament and I won. Um,
he started the,
uh,
like the WWF in like as a Ufo in Japan,
was very strong with pro pro wrestling,
like big magazines,
like a huge Japanese love pro wrestling.
So,
and then based on that kind
of exposure of this new event,
the champion off the rest of the SOC,
one of the champions off the UFO called
Takada. I start to talk, you know,
I like to fight The Hague.
They ask him and they statue talking
like all the pro wrestler stock,
I going to kick his ass, this and
that. It's not, you're talking,
are you going to gossip?
And at this point I'm back to La,
maybe after two or three months off,
this kind of talking around
my name forever. Some guy,
some, some, one of the friends I have in
Japan, they come, he said, Mister Greece,
they talking a lot about you. He, you
should have an official answer for that.
You know,
you cannot just let,
because people will start
thinking you afraid people.
So you have to have official answer. So I
said, okay. So I make a lattice stating,
um, I was never, we'll fight on
their ringing because they not legit.
They fixed fights. So
that's against my, if they,
if you want to come and fight in my event,
like the nine mine,
but the event I fight and then Japan open,
he will welcome to Carmen.
We want face each other for sure.
If other gays we can
find even on the street.
But I'm not there to fight on his
event because that's who the paradise,
my real fights status.
He real fighters stairs.
So with this being said, Cup,
I might, maybe few weeks later,
that guy that went out of
the, the, the, the, the,
the gossip and then owns
your show up in the magazine.
Static he stature saying he
will come into La to beat me up.
He will do this because, because he
said, oh, he's going to fight for free.
So I wanted there to fight to kick.
So in Dev guy commit and Mr [inaudible],
he said this said,
man,
I cannot just lost my sleep based
on his own on justice speculations.
You're not. He did. He said when
I come now, he didn't said, okay,
so I want to keep my life and if
you show up, okay, he show up.
So best may be couple of weeks or so,
even more.
One day I was in home in the morning,
my assistant at the school
called me said Hixon some guys,
yes and Japanese guys are here waiting
for you. I want to talk to you.
And immediately I figured it out.
Could support, could be that situation.
So I put my camera in my hand.
Hawkston wants to come in with me.
He was about 11 years old.
Um,
I was going back,
driving my car,
taping my hands because I know when a B,
so I was putting tape in my
hands as I driving the freeway.
When I arrive I saw like a van
full up with photographers outside,
you know,
like the,
I pass him through my parking lot and I
saw him four of Jap on news with gamma,
four of reporters inside. So I went
through, when they get in school,
I saw a huge,
like a tall Japanese guy,
very well dress it and the lady and I
need that. The Hey, how are you? Oh,
Mr Gracie,
I'm the president of the Ufo Association.
I come here to officially invite you to
participate on a fight in Japan. I said,
man, you crazy. I told you I
don't want to fight in Japan.
And then their your association and then
the onsite when I kind of deflect the
direction. He said, yeah,
but you also said you'll fight
for free for your owner in.
I said yes and he had to fight.
They specked fighting you but you
come into to negotiate. No, no, no.
By the fight there is outside.
Can you come? He coming? He
said, yes, he can come me.
So I tell my student, just say,
Hey, you have a standard door.
Let the lady with the fighter commune.
But don't let the reporters come in,
block everybody outside.
I didn't know what's going to happen.
I don't want to press.
So as angel come in with black at
ugly face and attitude and stuff,
I immediately asked my structure,
said Lumon grabbed the waiver and
tell him to sign. It's like a,
if I get hurt,
whatever those waivers.
And so he looked the waiver we
fugly face and then he spoke with,
uh, with his guy in Japanese.
And then the Japanese guy said,
Mr Gracie,
you mean if he don't sign,
you don't fight?
Immediately I felt like if
I say, yeah, he has to sign,
they may leave and they're going to
come in. We followed the excuse, oh,
he chicken out wherever, la,
la, la. I immediately said, no,
forget the paper. If you come
into a fight, let's fight.
If I get the bureaucracy,
let's, let's make something
here more simple. So,
and then he's, he come into the mat,
should they ring? I, you know, we,
and we start, you're fighting immediately.
I felt his intention
to hit me immediately.
I clinch put him on the ground and
the statue pine she'd done back,
but different than a normal event where
just put him to sleep or whatever.
And that particular case I have to
display, showcase his punishment.
So I was not happy just
to put him to sleep.
So I start to hear to him and with
their elbow, respect him to time.
Eventually he don't and I punched him
in the face and two broke his nose and
make it all bleed,
all cut a cut up.
And at that point when he felt like I
felt like he was just smash a knife,
he turned again backwards and I put him
to sleep and then I let him sleeping on
his own blurred. And then I said to
the, the press and okay now let them in.
So when the press come in,
saw him passing out,
waking up with the guy trying to hide
his face from the pictures and the guys
all Dz waking up, all
blurred, you know, big,
big mass of blood in the floor and stuff.
And the crowd,
my students can lift me up,
I cannot make my tee shirt is all
bloody and I kind of hang on the,
on the wall like a trophy and
a staff and we all yelling.
So the guy stood up and left and
then like three or four days later,
and you'll come back to me and uh,
at the my school I was teaching,
he called me with a package
and said, oh, I like to talk.
He was still like all brews and stuff.
So yeah, I like to apologize and,
and actually give you this as a gift.
And he gives me a Samurai helmet and a,
and then he laughed to Japan.
And when he got there,
he say to the crowd, he
was jumped, you know,
I was John the guys jumped me out a
lot because of the press didn't saw.
And then I get my,
my assistant,
my Japanese guy who's working
with me and the valley to the 95.
And I said, listen, you woody, you
take this tape, you go to Japan,
make a press conference display,
don't make one copy nothing.
Make sure no, no plea. So gold there,
make shoulder depress and come
back and bring this back. Okay.
So he went make the conference and then
my reputation when they saw was like a
free for a fair fight. And what
happened, my reputation went to this,
to the roof. And uh, you know,
he's just a big step for me and the like
in the publicity because I capitalizing
all the wrestling, publicity,
which is national in Japan. So,
and then, then my next fight
eventually was we Staccato,
he accept the fight and make official
fight and then we create the pride.
I help in the formulation of the rules.
A lot of folks don't know that you were
a big part of the original pride. Yeah,
they asked me if I want to fight the Cada
and for that they want to create a new
event. I said yes, I fight him and
then we discuss numbers and in,
in order to make a good rule,
I help in the rules because you know,
Ken cannot be, so I introduced the Globes
and the MMA and the mixed martial arts.
And the first one it said that we have
to put gloves because without glue can
beat your bloody, we have to cut head
butts and stuff. So I make like a,
a draw of the, the, the
backbone of flood could be.
And then from that they start the pride
I fought the pride one, the pride for,
and then the pride becomes like huge
in Japan and then because they have a
little involvement with the
Coosa uh, the diff, the sponsors,
they have Fuji TV like pull it off and
they getting problems to, to the payroll,
which is huge to have maybe
50 top athletes making a
lot of money so they could
not handle it down.
UFC come and they go over and get all the
footage and the fighters and now links
to a next level.
They took a huge bath cause UFC
page $65 million for pride and all,
all the contracts were fake.
Yeah. They're all void there.
There are invalid rather
than none of them were legal.
So I didn't know that she had the worst
of it. They are weighed the worst of it.
They tried to sue Japan
or they tried to sue the
organization.
While it's kind of funny,
this is how crafty they were
while the UFC purchased a pride,
the people that were running pride,
we're starting another organization
while they were working for the UFC.
So they were working for the UFC, running
the pride offices for the UFC in Japan,
but then they were running their own
interests is without know, with Disney,
God of everything. Now there's, there's
a Japanese style, there's a classic,
there's a classic match or not a
match fight that got, that's on video.
I might be on youtube with Healon Hugo
Duarte leaving the guy on the beach where
you guys are fighting. What is that on
Youtube. Oh yeah, yeah. Parts of it.
It's hard to see the whole thing.
The Gracies action.
They must fight on the beaches. You know,
who was holding the camera that day?
Who was highing cousin with 12 years old
and hawks and was seven John John was
there. There's John Jog
running. So what, what, what,
what was the reasoning behind that
fight? How did that go down? Okay,
let's make this the last day.
All right guys, because if not,
they're going to talk forever. He had
about things from the past you to talk
about present.
But anyway,
was a great time because at this point
[inaudible] was just finishing fight.
Fernando, uh, Fernando Pin Daca.
And I in a event after my
second fight off Zulu in Maria,
uh,
this Jujitsu community has a little
friction with the loot delivery community.
So they set up a fight between,
uh,
was Marcel bearing against
a fabulous Molina, uh,
Hennen against oceanic that deal and
then a pin Duca against Michael Hula.
And they draw and after
that draw Mako who are,
creates a good status off being a
great fighter as it is. He's a good,
you're not tough guy and the
gossip starts, you'll become like,
uh oh. And then people maybe ask him,
what about Hexion? I said, hey, so,
and they're kind of small
word is a position where mark,
who was as willing to fight me.
And I also,
of course we need to fight him,
but I don't want to wait or give him the
reputation where I challenge him is not
the case. He was just the first,
I was already famous, established.
He was already a coming up.
Like just make a good fight.
So to make things more simple,
my f my father,
myself, Marcello, in
Sandra, my best friend,
we went to his school and
a day and a nighttime,
he had maybe 50 guys training without Ge.
They all tough.
They all have a lot of pumping out to
Ireland. So they all big guys, you know.
So I went to his place, he said,
who is I like to talk to you?
So he come into me and said,
hey man,
I heard you use sport you to
showing desire to fight me.
So I like to fight too. Anytime
you want, regardless, let's do it.
If you want to do now you can do tomorrow,
whatever. And he look at me and said,
yeah, but it's not like
that. If you challenge me,
I may accept but I have, I need
four months to train. I said, man,
you crazy. You think like
I, I use all the names.
But it's like you think the Lakers,
we challenge a college
basketball team from,
from from Cucamonga, right? Fuck man.
What you're talking about, you've
come here to Charlie. I'd met,
I come here too because I heard you
planning to fight and if you find here you
want to fight or not. So when this
conversation statue become a little,
my dad called me has a a
mediator and said, hey guys
don't, don't want to discuss,
let's make a list if
somebody wants to fight.
So let's make a list and then eventually
you guys can can fight and then we'll
go from the back. Yeah, you can
put my name on that list and I,
first time I saw her in my life and I look
at him, I said, yeah man, you tell me I,
this is not a, because has a game, a
gambling in Brazil, like a popular game,
not official but unofficial game called
Juggle to be shoe means game off the
animals. You put a name, a
number, like a 24 is the,
is the deer.
So a guy put a $1 and if he wins again
maybe $50 something very popular at every
in every corner has this kind of
underground game. And I said to him,
this is not a game of animals, man.
This is just a seat as business.
You don't have to put your name in
the least. If you want to fight,
let's fight right now. And the guy
kind of get me noodle, confused,
sows and nothing happened.
And then we decide to leave.
So we left after that,
the whole Gospel,
every corner I heard Uga was
straining to fight you. Woo.
Start to force talking about woo.
And I felt like this has to have an end.
You know another guy who
could not challenge officially
because he's a nobody,
but he's the guy who if I just disregard
is something we're going to be against
me too, because I know he has
the potential. He's a fighter,
he just don't have the name.
But he's a legitimate tough guy.
So based on that,
I could not just ignore and I
could not challenge him officially.
So I have to do something in between
which fight him on the street.
So we decided to find a final, okay,
let's make a profile where he goes,
what beats you go where he walks
about. So we decided, well,
he goes into this beach was a very
popular beach and in real every Sunday,
every Saturday, Sunday
is there with the, okay,
so next Sunday we want
to be there Saturday.
So I was at this point,
separate from my, my
relationship, I was living like a,
a single in real and that's very
hard to do because a lot of options.
So, so I was not concerned
about the fight at all.
I was no sleep on the Monday,
Tuesday,
like just going Pyree a lot,
wake up on Wednesday,
kind of afternoon walk on his street,
close to my neighborhood.
And then I saw a friend of mine who
is always in the gossip said, hey,
as a living home,
I said,
I think I'm going to postpone who
was fight for the following week.
I don't think it's going to be a good
idea because man, I'm just too much party
when I get on the street. Men, first
time my first guy I saw it was this,
my friend Bodu who's just
come in and said, man,
you should see the everybody's spread.
Bet everybody if talking about the fight,
that would be great. They
are waiting, they all will be
there. And I say, Oh my God,
no postponement anymore. I
have to go regardless. So,
so as I approached the weekend, I
try to just recover, sleep, eat well,
but still like not enough.
Anyway.
Uh,
Saturday morning we all gathering
in the end the Gracie Baha Academy,
which is close to the neighborhood. And,
and uh, we guarantee like the students,
because we have to have a team
shoe to be there, you know,
what you hold and whatever.
So it's about 50 to 60 guys there and
we all kind of strategizing, okay,
you guys make this and that.
And um,
and then my son was seven years old,
old pumping up and down,
and one point everybody quiet. He's
just jumping the middle. I said, yeah,
and if he son will be dead,
I gonna kick his ass. I said,
so he's already with the DNA
of the battle. So it was funny.
And then eventually about 10 o'clock or
so, he arrive on the beach. The guide,
the message icon is age.
They are. They're so,
so you went to the beach and as we
approached the beach, I have the camera.
Nobody wants to hold the
cam. No, no, no, not me.
So I give the camera too high and which
is 12 years old at the time and he could
not get through is just yelling.
Everybody who could not get
through to film the fight.
The funeral is not even important.
So we engage was a at the moment
the first engage after a slap him,
Eh, we engage very quickly and
then we start to house on the sand.
He fall on top of me.
I was kind of having a hard time from,
from the beginning and
then able to sweep mounted
and he escaped from the Mt. One more
time because the scent giving me no bs.
So I kind of mass my knee on the sand.
So he come up,
I have to sweep him again.
Mounted again that time.
Much more concern of keeping the position.
So I grabbed his hand like,
like from the back and I started
punching him like a full Inaki.
Yeah, exactly. Like flank at sash touch
with punching him, punching, elbow, punch,
batch, punch, punch. And then at
one point I was dead, dead tired.
I asked him, you want to give up? He said,
you have to kill me. I said, okay, mother.
Boom, punching, punching,
punch. And then immediately
afterwards he says, okay, stop,
stop, stop. So I immediately stopped.
We went to the water dive on the water
has come back as we come back. He said,
yeah, I'm not happy. I said, okay, let's
do it again. Said, no, no, not today.
And I said, okay man. That's
okay. And then how's with state?
You're fighting you my cell.
Mandy's at the beach, they start,
you're getting it down.
It doesn't have the end is just
kind of mess it up a little bit.
Hanzo confront with the guy, but
it was not a hand fight. Anyway.
I put stitches on my hand and a back,
like all swallow my hands,
all swallows. So I went back home,
training, resting, giving my life.
One week later, you know, I
wasn't apart. A friend of mine,
his apartment,
you know,
resting tired from some little fun.
I was lay down,
you know in my underwears my hair,
I have long hair at the time,
but all Massey a guy who my student of
mine just stop in the bend, the on the,
on the street on the bike and said,
hey Exxon Hexion day inviting the
school is invading is a big invasion.
I said I kind of wake up in the run down
and when he saw me running underwears
you go like that and said hey man,
I jumped in the bike, let's go.
So I went to the,
to my school in your underwear,
in my underwear with the hair. All crazy
things to be animated by the way. Right.
And I, and as a approach the, the school,
because they come in from a
different neighborhood walking and,
and one of the guys like [inaudible]
was a black guy who lives in a ghetto
as they approached the Comey walk if
maybe five, three or four miles, you know,
something like that to a
different neighborhood.
They coming like from the street.
That's breakout hustle as they coming
like cause not only fighters as bad guys
guys, we like all the ice. I
mean only the co uncover eyes.
We've with guns,
with knives we've bottled break.
So it's a lot of covert actions,
a lot of average bed energy.
Not coming from a real fight situation
but it's more like a street dangerous.
So as I approach and I
come in through the crowd,
which is already controlling
maybe two thirds of the street,
which paint passing cars just
could not pass in cars anymore.
It's just like just the car
passing and a very fine line.
It's a big crowd in front of the school.
So I went through with the bike.
When I coming up to the school,
he's already coming down with my father,
the new song, which his a struct or
other guys. They coming down and we,
we kind of crush each other. And
in the middle of this, the stairs,
I said okay man, let's
go down, let's talk.
So we can went down to the parking lot
and like crowded maybe 20 guys from my
school.
One guy has a weapon,
but the other guys may be five or
six, 10 guns and knife. I mean,
he's a bad, bad weather, you know.
So before I start the fight, I said,
Ooh, I like to talk to you.
Come over, let's talk. Let's
walk to the backyard here.
So my father and myself,
the new Song Heuler and
the Oceania to deal,
we kind of move away from the crowd that
you were like a backyard. And I said,
man, I want to talk to you.
Something very important. Listen,
I fought to you last week
as a man and I come here,
I respect you as a fighter to challenge
me to rematch. So all of this, the school,
regardless who, when, who lost.
But if somebody touched the
fight before the fight is over,
because you bring here a lot of
people without no martial arts code.
So if somebody touches the fight before
it was over, I guarantee you, man,
you wake up on the ditch.
And he said, no, no,
he's a man meant you man. There's a spice
as the owner thinks, okay, let's go back.
Let's talk finish books.
So we went back to the crowd,
they make a a Rina like
people make a real uh,
circle and was on the concrete
and I felt when we start it,
I felt like his mentor or whatever
she was supposed to say to him,
hey man, the first fight last
week, you engage too quickly,
you give the grappling to,
you should punch him in the face.
So I felt a completely different animal
because he was already trying to buy his
approach, his position,
he's the way he moves.
I felt like he wants to punch me different
than was before and I kind of make
myself like available.
I kind of played dummy,
you know like play kind
of stretch and he come in,
punch me right that I deflected very
quick, grab him around the waist,
like high,
make a little hip movement and put him
on his own and throw him on the concrete.
So He fell flat on the concrete.
I tried to mount hitch escape,
I move like to the other side and mount
again and I ended up by mountain on him.
Like we're 15 maybe 20 seconds
I use is mounted on him.
I punch the cover up and
I could not punch anymore.
So I get his everything and Bang his
head against the concrete few times.
You're not going to bang their head on
the floor and then he's soft it up a
little bee. I give them a couple of pints.
He kind of quit immediately. Stop, stop,
stopped.
For me it was not exactly the well
done job because it was just too quick.
And he, he, he quit. He quit very quickly.
So I want to do something else.
But the crowd was already trying to,
it's too much. I said, if
I insist here after his Rx,
ask for mercy can jeopardize the whole
thing. So even though I was not happy,
I stood up and he stood up and
he said, yeah man, I'm happy.
I'm satisfied now he would really
demand shake your hands, said yeah man,
you have a very valuable guide shoe
with very strong keep training,
you can be good. So we kind of
ended up our it, our our different,
yes. So once we out of
that highly statue, uh,
highly start to fight the urogenital
deal in the same because they are already
having a little, so they start, you're
fighting at that point the police come in,
a guy with a gun machine just because
nobody would listen to possess is nothing.
So he cannot make a shooting.
The the roof,
the bullets come up and breaking some,
some Rico shit down and somebody
get hit and then he come,
he was very small guy with a
cigarette and said, hey, why not?
See who is the tough guy now,
now.
And so it's like very small guy for gum
machine. So he knew everybody like quiet.
So, and then I talked with
the new said, hey man,
the fight is just start here with hydro
has to go next week we're going to set
up something that's not Andy
and said, yeah, that's all we,
we set up for a different
day when then is over for me,
we and what we kind end up with
are respectful, honorable way and
uh, that's pretty much it. That's it.
Great Story. No more
old stories. That's it.
Because there are those all night. We
can go forever here man. Some guys,
you know, this is the biggest response
ever on Twitter for a gas. Like,
I don't know about your Twitter,
but my Twitter people are going
nuts that you're doing the podcast.
People are losing their minds and they've
been going nuts ever since the Yohji
Angelo tape. There's screaming, please
release the tape, please release the tape.
Will you release it?
Yeah, let's do that. Oh,
the couple of million people in the site.
We'll do our best to get
as many people on the site.
Where are you sending people? What's the
site? What's the address? Jay Jay g f.com.
Global Federation that call.
So just the initial J J G f.com.
It's all set up right now.
Beautiful.
So I wanted to ask you something
about what's going on today
in MMA.
There's like,
like Nick Diaz and there's been a
bunch of guys that have been, uh,
suspended and fine for having
a cannabis in their system.
And there's big controversy because in a
lot of states now it's 23 states in the
United States where it's legal now.
So how do you feel about a banning
cannabis as a performance enhancer?
Do you think? I mean, what do you, what do
you think about it man? I think, you know,
we are,
I mean the,
the beginning of the Times drugs are
always involved with was not dressed drugs
for body drugs or, or let's I
totally talking about painkillers.
We talking about coffee, we talking
about alcohol, we talking about, I mean,
Geez and Arabs and so we all luck.
Wish to meet you use medicines and drugs.
Tween. Hey. Should diminish
to account too. So this is,
is, is, is there, you know, I think, uh,
that kind of judgment goes from
person to person from, you know,
some people can have a little bit of some
drug and get a reaction which can make
him crazy or can make him
addicted or can hate him.
So the chemical in the brain
can respond differently. Yes.
For some people can I bust as a medicine,
as they play fight all this can be
a stimulant or it can be uh, uh,
below. I mean low yourself. Steam becomes
bipolar. If you smoke, you can be,
I mean,
I mean you don't know.
It makes you more of what you are kind
of right there. It's hard to say what is.
So and that point I feel like we
have to obey the law, you know?
And if, if some kind of
drugs are forbidden by law,
for you to become a proact athlete,
you have to obey that.
If we not with Korea and what
you're doing in your life, you know,
it has to be respected. It
has to be, you know, whatever.
But what's the rules for MMA?
I mean,
I try to input in the Jujitsu,
the anti-doping, you know,
because you'll see guys
in the same way division,
but one guy has 10 times more,
10 times more power,
10 times or so. And the guys that you
know has the addictive, like he has a,
an extra I extra iin Haysman so we have
to balance this in art in order to make
a fair sport. How much they
can I be is affect the athlete.
I'm not sure you know and but I know
audits like steroids or hormones,
those are proving so whatever is being
proved against use the cannabis for
fighting for e sports activities.
If it's proved this kind of support of,
I mean the drug use can be in hasting
center. Maybe we could, I don't know.
It's up to the prognosis.
It's, it's their,
they're testing people for something
that stays in your body for a long time
after its psychoactive. So if you took
cannabis like a week before your fight,
you're not going to be high when you're
fighting but it's still going to be in
your system.
So you're still going to be penalized
for something that has like what's the
reason? What's the reason
why they took it? Yeah.
Because you can have caffeine in
your blood, you can have like a,
another kind of why
the cannabis has to be,
because I don't think he's in haste.
Mint of performance I think
is only control your emotion.
Emotional give you kind of some kind of
feeling of happiness sometimes even give
you like a little laziness,
you know?
I don't think that's what will help
you as an athlete. I think if you get,
if you get high before event, you're gonna
lose your sharpness. You're going to,
so I don't think that's will support.
So I don't see why they have to bother
in legalizing or four beats. I Dunno.
Maybe it's just because of the law,
just because it's illegal.
And the reason why it's
illegal has nothing to do
with whether or not it's safe
or dangerous. Does nothing. It's
all political at this point. So,
but they did lower it right now.
It used to be in a few of you,
if you were in Colorado, let's
say, where it's totally legal,
it's not illegal there.
Anybody can smoke in Colorado.
You could buy it and you could buy it.
And vending machines,
you have to stop a month
before your fight because it's,
it's still going to show up in the
test and you could lose the fight,
the fight to no contest. You've
get fine. So now they're,
they're kind of changing it
and adapting now I guess, uh,
according to the numbers
I think you can go,
you have to stop two weeks before a fight
or something like that. So, um, yeah,
maybe eventually,
depending on the card they have to
change the fight for Colorado. Yeah.
So the training camp be in, in
Colorado, so everything that is legal,
but there were, there
are there definitely. Uh,
well, how do you say relaxing? The rules
are, or he wouldn't say that though.
What do they,
what's the word he made it from a,
used to be 50 nanograms
per milliliter to 150.
So it changed quite a bit.
300% increase.
So you have to have 300% more
marijuana in your system.
That's a step in the right direction.
Now, as far as performance enhancing,
surfing is a serious sport that
requires serious technique,
lots of hours. And generally you, you,
you hear that surfers will be under
the influence of cannabis while they're
surfing. Um, Eh, it wouldn't, it if it,
if it doesn't, makes your reflex is
some people believe that it makes,
it's a dulls your reflexes.
How can surfers, uh,
be under the influence of cannabis
and ride a 25 foot wave? No,
the, the, the way the ocean is, um,
he's an animal, you know, he's alive
is in movement. These can be dangerous.
Has this kind of,
you have to have the perfect lecture.
[inaudible] you have to
have it to Beth mapping
the way out, the way in. So
He's a lot of strategies,
a lot of technique and is also,
is a lot of Armani between
you as a surfer in the ocean.
So you have to find yourself comfortable.
You have to find herself disputed
to be connect to the force.
And sometimes some of guys who,
my friends who kind of
normally, uh, smoke some,
they feel peaceful and they
get in the Armani. He's not,
he's not about Stan News, uh, physical.
The only if you get caught in the bad
situation, I guess the bad report,
you have to swim like a dog. You're a good
surfer. You've served your whole lives,
right. So for my whole life, what's the
biggest way of you've ever served 38?
No ma'am. No ma'am. I'm
a, I'm about 12 feet.
Dangerous. Longboard shortboard
shortboard okay. I'm a short board. Yes.
And crone serves to grow surfs,
but he is just,
he is more passionate about Jujitsu then,
then surf.
Surf still. Oh, depends on swell. I
have to check her for lunch today.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Oh yeah man. What is it
about surfing is about? Uh,
for me is mod.
The water, the ocean.
Because I believe in energy.
I believe in, uh, in the
ocean being the most,
the most,
the hugest and electromagnetic Paul
in art or the electricity coming from.
So as I go in the ocean, if
I'm stressed, I get energy.
If I'm, you know, lazy, I
get energy. If I'm to tests,
I get relaxed.
So He's,
I equalize it for me because I feel like
the contact with the ocean keep me in
balance.
Keep me.
So for me it's not about the perfect
waves about going to the ocean and make my
routine, make my exercise breathing.
You know, I'm a tropical rat.
I'm born and raised in so I cannot
stay away from the water is just,
you know, somehow the energy flow
in the Holy Spirit spiritually.
That's kind of have empower me in a
sense that you would say that physically
surfing does translate to Jujitsu
as far as the balance, right,
because you need incredible balance. Not
really. I think a, it is of course you,
you stimulates your yard,
your neural muscular activity in
surfing and skate and, and Juju.
But uh,
I think the most important thing in
surfing is as you become under pressure,
you have to strategize. You have
to be in control of your emotions.
You have to be a focus
in and everything due,
right? And if things go wrong, you have
to be fine. Your comfortable zone in hell.
And that's the mindset.
The similar because the
ocean is not the only enemy,
but he's there to do his
tank and is very powerful.
So you have to find her,
your mentor, your mindset,
you'll find confortable in
all of this turmoil, you know,
is all you know is if you get quite in
a wrong position and if you get panic is
gone. So you have to be
calm. Same thing than fight.
You have to have like the focus, the
strategy and uh, even when things,
when the problem arises
you have to be in control.
What do you do with your time these days?
Like what's a typical
day for Hixon Gracie? Um,
right now I backed, should teach and
cross place because I want to, to,
to have him dees, distress
with the, how the academy goes.
So I pick two times a week to teach.
They're giving selfdefence
glasses at this point.
Before that I was doing seminars
once a month at the most,
once or twice every couple
of months to make my living.
And also because I feel like
the best things in life,
money cannot buy. And I feel
like the quality of my, my,
my meals, the way I eat, the
way my relationship, my sleep,
those are very, very
valuable assets, you know.
Plus the time I have to
do things I love to do.
That's kind of when this is fuel.
Like when I feel like I'm every,
so I feel like I'm happy enough to be my
best at service because I always tried
to be at service, helping somebody with
Jujitsu, with knowledge, with nutrition,
with breathing. You know, it's not about
the price is about the service, you know?
And then I put my head in the and
said, yeah, I have a nice day.
I make a good speech. We've, Joe Hogan,
I'd have a girl I spoke
with at Bravo was great day.
So somehow in a purpose
for the federation.
So I always try to be positive,
but I have no schedule fix.
Like I have to wake up vote.
You wouldn't know because at this point
I create a lifestyle which make me a few
good to engage in different elements like
this federation now and having glasses
on crowns and be here to be
full of energy. You know,
because sometimes you don't notice,
but based on your, your,
uh, your commitments,
your obligation, you'll becoming
more like a Robert and you, you,
you lose the perspective of what
you need to be at your best.
And if you lose that perspective,
even though you still doing your routine,
sometimes you just minus you just 80,
70,
60% of what you should be. So you're
not going to be the best husband,
you're not going to be the best father,
the best employer, the best employee,
you just, you know, it's just,
so at this point I feel like I have
to be at my best physically do my,
if I feel like I have to stretch, they're
going to stretch, breed, joke, have fun,
listen buddy, whatever, you know.
And then when I feel like, man,
I'm so happy I could not eat so, and then
I can go and do my service, you know?
And you know,
because the window of life is
smaller now for me is becomes,
I don't have too much time.
So I don't waste time to do what people
expect from me. I tried to do things.
I read the relevant to my soul,
like this federation now I,
I when I dream I don't dream small.
I dream like I make like
a very space for a huge,
the biggest dream I can dream. And
I see that, you know, that level of,
of need for the community
and the level of,
of position I have to be the reference
for that shift in the direction of our
culture,
in our knowledge.
I feel like I could not be more motivated,
more happy to engage on this.
So, and that's always life is about
is just do your best and, and,
and be excited to be motivated
to, to, to the next day.
There's such a refreshing
attitude. Your attitude, your,
your philosophy on life because I
think it's very easy and I've been,
I've trapped myself in it sometimes
where you concentrate too much.
I'm making money,
concentrate too much on being ambitious
and you forget the quality of life.
And you are focuses almost
entirely on your quality of life.
Yes. You know, because like I said,
and then how much cost your motivation,
how much cost your friends, how much
cost your health, how much costs,
your intelligence, those
things is priceless. I, man,
if you take those off your life,
you take on more vision of your life,
can be Bill Gates can be the biggest.
So if you,
if you ask me if I want to have bill gates
life, I don't know. I don't know him.
So it's not a base on his bank
account is based on how happy he is,
how horny he is, how, you know, how, how,
how motivated he is to wake up and do
his thing. He don't look too horny.
So, so that's, that's
a very essential thing,
which sometimes sleep
to people's fingers and,
and the priorities in the daily,
you know, in the payments.
And so I put you in a role
where, uh, I feel like,
um,
if you tell me in the
past what's the core age,
what's the opposite of courage?
I want to see cowardness because either
you tough enough to challenge and to
fight or to Orin,
Daniel cow and then you chicken out.
So that's in the past was like the,
the, the, the, the opposite of, of,
of courage.
It's very hard to measure this in those
days and I believe the opposite of
cordage should they use conformity,
you know, is people get conformed,
oh I don't like my wife
the way I used to like,
but I'm never going to divorce because
I'm afraid to lose my house or the
situation is so established so I want
to keep, so I don't like this job,
but I want to keep here because better
than his. So in, in, in other hands,
the future, if you get quite
on that kind of compromise to,
to maintain because you
were afraid to risk,
that's keep you like one step
behind from you, follow your heart,
follow an ambition. You should 18 years
old, you don't think twice. Like I said,
hey, let's go to Australia.
You think, okay, let's go boom.
But when you fifth to sales training
and what are they going to do there?
Maybe I'm going to, so
it's different, you know,
and that's kind of hate
or what's going on. Yeah.
So that's kind of pretty much where keep
you from be at your best because if you
willing to sacrifice,
if you will into two
broke new new challenges.
If you really chew you in stage
of liveliness and excitement and
unpredictability,
who make you feel like you in heaven?
You know, every time I was engaging in
a compromise on a fight was something I,
I think like I have my
routines prior to fight.
One of them is at the day off my fight,
I wake up and I thank you.
Glad to be alive and I acknowledge
how perfect we'll be that day.
If I die today, say fuck my wasn't, it'd
be a perfect day if I die because I have,
you know, I accomplished my think. I'm
in my mission, I representing my family.
So I don't go that your tap, I go, that
should die. Like I have to kill me.
It's not, I'm, I never won at that. So,
but that's not a spotlight orientation.
This is a philosophical, uh,
owner representation, you
know, is not something I
teach. My snow should not that,
no, it's not like that is about
how I feel, how I feed my kids,
how I follow my tradition.
So in engagement,
I am not going to be the one who
going to quit. Then I have to kill me.
My brother, he can throw the
Tao. But for me is unacceptable.
You know,
I do give up from my life.
So based on that kind of spiritual
guidance, my life is very intense.
My life is very, I mean, directed shoe
accomplish give up is not an option.
You know, I can do, I can
direct my, my, my focus,
I can give up from something
to go somewhere else,
but I never will give up from something
because I feel like I cannot reach there.
I may say, okay, that's not for me. I
go somewhere else. But if I still focus,
I will take those falls.
I will take those obstacles
as a motivation to just set
up a new strategy to try
again. You know, I'm very
competitive in a sense.
I like the perfection of things.
So this is like a,
a situation where put you in
a situation where you have no,
either you go forward or you don't,
but don't stay in the middle.
Don't say just waiting for
people are waiting for more.
Those are kinds of things going
to stack you back in life and,
and just make you feel like passing
through life as you know, you have,
you know, you irrelevant,
you know, is, is very weak.
It has a beautiful way to end this.
Thank you very much brother.
I really appreciate it.
Let's make this sometime
again and absolutely.
Thanks [inaudible] we can do this forever
I'm sure and anything we could do to
help your association.
I'm 100%
committed to making the state
of Jujitsu better. You know,
improving on what is going
on. That's what I'm on. Yeah.
Jay Jay g F. Dot. Com.
Chew on that then definitely you're
going to be invited for the Development
Council. Thank you. Very [inaudible].
So, uh, go there. J J G F. Dot
Com. Enjoy it. Uh, Hixon Gracie.
Thank you very much. Thank you,
Bro. Thank you to our sponsors.
Thanks to squarespace.com go
to the court@squarespace.com
use the code word Joe
and save 10% off your first
purchase. Thanks also to
[inaudible] Dot com go to o.
N. N. I. T.
Use the Codeword Rogan and save 10%
off any and all supplements. Uh,
we will be back in a little while with
Bert Kreischer. Much love my friends.
Yeah, that was fun, man. You.