Hello Freaks,
here we go again.
This episode of the Joe Rogan experience
is brought to you buy naturebox.
Naturebox is a company that sends
healthier snacks to your door.
Now I really appreciate my message board
because every time anyone claims
anything now people fucking crawl up
their ass with a microscope and find out
what's cracking.
And one of the big things about
naturebox is people go,
this stuff's not healthy.
We're not talking about Kale or grapes
or,
or blueberries.
It is healthy and quite delicious.
Um,
I'm,
I'll tell you,
what are these things?
I'm smitten with these things.
I may get addicted.
They're sweet blueberry almonds.
Oh,
they're so delicious.
I'm not sure what's in there because I
don't have my glasses on.
I need glasses to read.
Fine print.
I thought,
why?
Why the fuck did they put fine print on
box unpackages where they know that
anyone over 12 can't read that shit.
All right,
that's ridiculous.
It puts them print on.
I know it's illegal thing they're
putting print on so that you know,
like you can get away with it,
but you should,
you should have it on there.
Where people can fucking read.
So I asked naturebox what is,
uh,
what's the deal,
is it,
is it healthy?
And their response was very reasonable
and they said their products are all
natural and containing much higher
quality ingredients than the typical
vending machine food ingredients which
makes them healthier.
They have over 100 snacks to choose from
and if you're looking for something for
certain dietary needs,
like wheat free,
which I,
I,
I'm a gluten free person because I'm
very trendy,
a low sugar content,
a gluten free,
which is basically the same thing.
I don't know why they had to be
redundant.
Uh,
they have it to,
whenever possible they also try to use
non gmo food as well.
Although that's a thing about gmo.
It's not necessarily unhealthy to eat
GMO.
It's very tricky anyway.
Their products are made from wholesome
ingredients.
And our nutritionist approved.
They abide by strict quality standards,
no high fructose corn syrup,
no partially hydrogenated oils,
no trans fats,
no artificial sweeteners,
no artificial flavors,
no artificial colors.
All sounds good to me.
And like I said,
I've been enjoying these snacks.
They're very delicious.
It's good to have laying around things
that you don't feel terrible about
eating.
And as I said,
they do have things like pretzels,
okay,
which are impossible to make healthy.
They're fucking pretzels.
Uh,
and that was one of the things that was
brought up on our message board.
But again,
I appreciate you guys.
You guys are fact checking
motherfuckers,
but check out naturebox.
They have some really delicious stuff.
A barbecued kettle corn,
which is really good stuff.
I'm a South Pacific plan team chips,
that's one another,
one of my favorites.
Zero Trans Fats,
zero high fructose corn syrup,
nothing artificial.
And with free shipping anywhere in the
U.
S naturebox is busting up the vending
machines.
Monopoly on your midday hunger.
They got rid of that dumb thing where
they said that they,
they're big deliver,
just like nature does.
They deliver for free.
That was something they were doing for a
while.
They gave that up.
So try nature box right now and get 50
percent off your first box by going to
naturebox.com
forward slash rogen.
That's naturebox.com/Rogan.
So,
uh,
go get some.
Enjoy it and get 50 bucks off your first
box.
Naturebox.com
forward slash rogen.
We are also brought to you by
squarespace,
one of my favorite podcast sponsors
because I have many friends that have
used this,
a sponsor to make their own websites and
I recently met the people that are
responsible for this company in New
York.
Excellent folks,
and the product is really fantastic.
For the longest time,
if you wanted to have a professional
website,
you really had to either learn html or
you had to hire someone to do it and it
was a huge pain in the ass.
Squarespace offers you a very simple
drag and drop solution that is quite
excellent.
It also works on everything.
It works on ipads,
works on android phones,
it works on windows,
it works on pc.
They offer 24 slash seven support and
they've even launched a logo creator.
If you're thinking about opening up a
company and you want a logo,
they have a very simple logo creator.
We can create a clean and simple logo
design yourself in minutes.
You can start an online store quite
easily.
Not Difficult at all.
Brian Red Band who's not here today but
has made dozens of websites while we've
been doing shows during commercials.
He's actually constructed.
Oh,
that's good.
Jamie,
you learning from Brian said Brian's
name.
You did just like him.
Um,
the,
uh,
drag and drop interface is super easy to
use.
You could literally make websites during
the time that it takes to do a
commercial now,
no bullshit.
They also have a new health website that
will deliver a better customer
experience.
And for a free child free child,
is that a child or as trial?
It's a hybrid of a trial and a child for
a free trial and 10 percent off of your
first purchase.
Go to squarespace.com
and enter in the code Joe.
So for 10 percent off your first
purchase and a free trial,
go to squarespace.com
and enter the code word Joe.
Another thing I like about squarespace,
they allow you to try it out before you
enter in your credit card information.
So if you're thinking about making a
website and like,
let me see what the squarespace shit is
all about.
You can actually enter in,
um,
you know,
all the stuff,
build a website and then say I liked it.
Then you put in your credit card.
It's a beautiful thing.
Squarespace.com.
Use the code word Joe.
Save yourself some money.
We're also brought to you by on it.com.
O n n I,
t on it is a human optimization website.
We basically sell things to allow human
beings to reach your potential,
whether it's physically strength and
conditioning equipment,
whether it's cognitively,
which I don't think is a word through
things like Alpha brain or new mood with
new moon is a five htp supplement if
you've never heard of five htp five HDP
is actually a supplement that allows
your brain to build more Serotonin,
actually can enhance your mood.
So much so that people who are on Ssri
eyes,
which is a serotonin uptake inhibitor,
people are on antidepressants
essentially.
Um,
they tell you not to take things like
new mood because new mood and the
antidepressant together might actually
give you too much.
There are Tonin,
which is not good,
but if you're interested,
go all the science behind all the
supplements are available at [inaudible]
dot com,
whether it's Alpha brain,
whether it's new mood,
any of the supplements are explained
with science.
And also with the research has posted
with references.
Uh,
we recently completed a clinical test.
The first of a,
another.
We were in the process of doing another
one right now.
A much larger one.
The first one was a pilot test.
It was 20 people a couple dropped out,
so I think we were left with 17 or 16,
but we had excellent results and the
results are published at [inaudible] dot
com.
It's o,
n n I t these are all very expensive to
do.
And the,
um,
the process of selling supplements is a
very controversial thing because there's
a lot of bullshit out there.
I personally believe in supplements.
I've been taking supplements my whole
life,
not my whole life.
When I was a baby,
I took nothing.
How about that took mom's milk,
I guess as a supplement.
But since I knew about vitamins and
supplementation,
I've always been interested in
optimizing my health,
optimizing my fitness,
optimizing the way my brain functions.
And uh,
I've been a big fan of nootropics.
I got turned onto them by,
um,
by neuro one,
which is bill Roman [inaudible] company
built Roman house if you don't know who
he is,
he's a former pro football player who
was experiencing a lot of what we're
hearing about today in the news about
pro football players.
A lot of these guys get busted up from
football,
develop a lot of cognitive problems,
and he wanted to combat that with
nutrition.
So he developed a product called
[inaudible].
That was my introduction to the world of
nootropics from um,
uh,
Alice from Sarah and no name in San
Francisco.
I got into that and then started
researching all the various supplements
before we ever created Alpha brain.
I'm Alpha brain is what I believe is the
best combination of all of the known
ingredients that can increase cognitive
function.
And again,
if you go to [inaudible] dot com,
all of the science behind all the
various ingredients individually is
referenced.
And then on top of that,
all of the,
uh,
the,
all the research that we've done and the
study that was just recently completed
is also referenced.
We also have a 100 percent 30 pill,
90 day money back guarantee it on it.
We're not trying to sell any bullshit.
And we,
the last thing I personally want is
anybody feeling ripped off.
That is also the last thing Aubrey
wants.
Who is my partner in this?
We sell you the best shit we can find
and we try to sell it to you at a
reasonable rate.
That includes strength and conditioning
equipment like kettle bells and battle
ropes.
And that includes health and nutrition
things.
Supplements like a hemp protein powder
or hemp force bars.
All of it is available on a.com.
It's o,
n n I t go there.
Enjoy it.
Get your freak on.
All Right,
ladies and gentlemen,
Louis Theroux is here and I'm very
excited to talk to him.
So let's just get cracking
experience.
Joe Rogan podcasts all day.
Can you not hear that?
The headphones?
Is that what's going on there?
Just too loud.
Too loud.
Jamie.
Wants you hook them up.
This is probably something that we
should do before the podcast starts.
Doo Doo do.
Is that better?
Is that beautiful?
Louis?
First of all,
thank you very much for doing this.
I'm a huge fan.
I've enjoyed your work over the years.
You have had probably one of the most
unique views of Americans as an
outsider.
I think possibly ever,
you know,
your shows are all about.
I mean,
if I wanted to think if I was like a
conspiracy nut and I wanted to thank
like me,
man,
this guy is probably like an,
an anti American propaganda is what he's
done is found the wackiest Americans
ever known and,
and put them on television and shown
just how fucked up we really can be.
But uh,
your shows are really excellent.
Thank you very much.
I don't remember which one I got turned
onto was many,
many years ago,
but,
uh,
I've watched.
I went on a marathon last night.
Last night I watched the wrestling one,
I watched the African hunting one.
I watched the Indian Gurus,
one are watched the born again Christian
one.
I went on like a five hour Louis
Marathon last night.
I lived to tell the tale.
That's a lot.
What,
what got you started in exploring all
these bizarre human beings?
Oh Man.
I've always,
I've always had a kind of fascination
with the dark side of human nature and
with lifestyle outsiders and you know,
it goes so deep with me that I don't
remember ever formulating a conscious
decision to explore weirdness.
For me,
it just came naturally from,
you know,
from when I was very,
very young.
I was,
I remember my dad having a things about
the Ku Klux Klan laying around the house
and,
and reading them and thinking like,
wow,
it's so weird.
And it just sort of.
And then I used to subscribe to a
magazine called the unexplained that was
all about a conspiracy theories and use
bows and esp.
And I remember I subscribe to that.
And so it's always been part of my
natural environment.
And then,
uh,
my dad's American.
So it felt very natural for me to come
to America at a certain point after the
fact,
after I left university.
And then once I was here I just felt
like I was tuning into something
different and strange.
Well,
you're a perfect guy for what you've
done because you're so friendly and so
amiable,
like when you're around these bizarre
fucking freaks,
you,
you put them at ease to a certain
extent.
Right?
Right.
And I,
and,
and again,
it wasn't something I sought out to do
consciously.
I just,
my natural mode is to try and be
ingratiating.
I mean,
I'm not a confrontational person,
have quite a cowardly person.
I,
you know,
and I,
I try and avoid conflict and so I have a
natural strategy in life,
you know,
it's not something I just do on my
programs in life.
I try to,
um,
get along with people and put people at
their ease if possible.
At the same time,
I also have a kind of inquisitive side.
And so sometimes I get my questions
answered by asking a difficult question
politely.
You know,
I don't think you're a coward at all.
I mean,
I think you're being very self
deprecating right now because you might
avoid conflict if you could,
and,
and I do as well,
but you're also very brave and the
situations that you've put yourself in,
you know,
you,
you've thrust yourself into some very
bizarre circumstances.
Well,
you know,
um,
maybe I'm more,
I am county,
but I'm more afraid of the consequences
of I'm somehow not delivering on a
creative idea than I am of the danger
that fulfilling it involves,
if that makes sense.
So sometimes you're in a spot where the
story,
you know,
people say you must be afraid when
you're out on location,
you know,
what I'm afraid of is going home without
a story.
Like that's what keeps me awake at
night.
Like are we actually going to get any
usable material?
So I was in Johannesburg doing a story
on crime in Joburg where the police are
hugely under resourced.
And so a private security agencies go
around policing the streets.
They're heavily armed,
they're accountable to no one.
And yet after.
So we went out to do this story and
after about two weeks of being there,
we hadn't really seen any violent crime
and I was getting to the point of we got
to go and cause some crimes ourself if
we have to,
like we got to get the story.
And so there was a,
I,
I tended to thrust myself into dangerous
situations just out of a sense of panic,
you know,
that we weren't kind of doing what we
were supposed to do.
That's hilarious.
So essentially what's going on in South
Africa is like a lot of what happened
where was criticized the American
military started using mercenaries that
we're accountable to no one black water
and the like.
And that was a huge,
huge issue because these folks were,
we're doing a lot of things that if
soldiers had done them,
they would be responsible for war
crimes,
but they fell into this very strange and
gray area because they were mercenaries
because it was.
Yeah,
that's
a great story.
And in fact we spent a long time looking
at trying to do that story and getting
into blackwater.
They rebranded themselves as something
else now,
but um,
and the fact that these private citizens
essentially,
because they weren't servants of the
state,
they were,
um,
the citizens of private companies,
but they were still in Iraq,
but accountable to no government because
they could commit crimes more or less in
Iraq,
but be a go and arrested and
unprosecuted because they were in this
legal gray area.
They changed their name twice.
Actually.
Black water was x e dot a dot and then
they changed the name to academy with an
I at the end of it.
So they just very strange.
Yeah.
Well I think they don't understand the
internet,
so they probably did
figures that may work for people.
Sure.
For a little bit,
for a bit.
For anybody who doesn't use google.
Yeah.
Sort of work.
That's what,
that's why con artists changed their
name.
Yes.
I mean,
it's interesting that,
but this is how beautiful the Internet
is.
I didn't remember what the name was.
I found out while you were in the middle
of a sentence and then by the time you
were done,
I had the answer,
which is pretty incredible.
We live in strange times.
I have a friend who went to blackwater.
He was a,
uh,
he was in the marines.
He was a sniper and then he got a job
with blackwater and he didn't like to
talk about any of this stuff that he
did,
but he did it for money and he went over
and made a tremendous amount of money
over.
They did more than one tour with
blackwater,
but it's very disturbing that that is,
uh,
this,
this gray area and these words that we
use like in surgeon and contractor.
Those are also disturbing.
Like contractor,
you know,
like,
Oh,
you're a contractor.
You're,
you're a mercenary.
No,
no,
no.
Contractor contractor to me is the guy
who fixes your house,
you know,
a contract to me as a guy that you hire
and he,
you know,
he builds a,
an addition onto your home.
It's not a fucking sniper,
but it's across the board as well
because,
you know,
I've done several stories on,
on prisons and there is a,
um,
there are private prisons as well.
And,
and if I could make a general
observation,
it's that what I found in the course of
making documentaries is that nine times
out of 10 you get more access and more
accountability from a public agency
from,
I mean I've been inside and spent weeks
inside San Quentin prison and Miami jail
and a maximum security mental hospital
for pdf files here in California.
And all of those open their doors to us
and I just wonder around and document
what was going on in a way that I
thought was very laudable.
I didn't agree with all the practices
that were going on.
And yet if they're private prisons,
they,
they don't feel like opening up their
doors they've got,
they don't feel the same sense of public
trust.
And that's,
that's just a personal observation.
Well,
they also,
they're a business and that's a real
issue.
And anything that you say that's
negative could negatively impact their
bottom line.
They can make less money because of you
and so there's no benefit in having you
there.
Whereas the public outrage in a,
in a public institution is to have a
real impact.
You know,
the public can actually vote to get
people out of positions that are causing
certain rules to be in effect.
You can't really do that with private
prisons.
Private prisons are,
in my opinion,
one of the most disturbing aspects of
the current situation that we're in
right now because so few people are
actually aware of what's going on.
Most folks who have nine to five jobs
plus whatever commute time and family,
they don't have the time to research any
of this stuff and they're really unaware
of what's going on that we have this
good percentage of our prisons in this
country,
in this country are actually businesses.
They're making money and even more
disturbing.
They're lobbying to make sure that
certain laws are in place so that they
can ensure that they have more people in
their prisons and make more money.
It's very creepy.
Scary stuff.
It really is.
You.
You've been to the public prisons.
Yes,
and didn't know private prisons.
They wouldn't be here.
No,
no,
no.
Yeah,
we've never.
I mean it's,
it's.
If you can just talk into the alternate
towards you,
like it's a story.
I'd be.
Oh,
that's better.
Yeah,
much better.
It's a story I'd be interested in
telling,
but uh,
we,
you know,
very Hong King.
I'm a,
I'm a victim of,
of,
of access,
you know,
I can only really tell the stories that,
um,
that I get inside,
you know,
I,
I sort of like,
well maybe I should.
I'm like a vampire.
I have to be invited in.
That's only so many a horror movies
though.
That's my,
my issue with the recent trend of
vampires that they just fuck around with
the rules.
Like blade was the first word the
vampires could wear sunscreen that go
outside.
I remember I wanted a piece of paper up
and threw it at my tv.
When I saw that,
I was like,
yeah,
I'll fight.
You can't fucking wear sunscreen.
You changed the rules.
Well,
Wesley snipes was a vampire,
right?
He was half vampire,
but he was a day walker.
He was allowed.
You have to wear sunscreen as well.
He did not.
He was allowed because he was half
vampire.
It'd be a good guest for your show.
Yes,
he would.
I would enjoy having.
Is he at?
Is he at liberty now?
He was,
he was doing time for tax evasion.
Um,
I wonder what he can say or what he
would say if I was him,
I'd probably keep my mouth shut.
They locked him in a cage for several
years and not only that,
they didn't allow him to just pay the
money back.
They imprisoned him,
which is really disturbing to me because
if someone owes you money,
you should just have to pay that money
back.
And the government is different when you
owe money to the government,
they decide that we're going to put you
in a cage.
And he had gotten a,
I don't know his full story.
I've never met Wesley,
but he had gotten some really shitty
advice from someone.
And if you're,
I think he was part of a religious
group.
Do you know that side of the story
called the New Orleans?
And it was,
there was some kind of Egypt to logical
dimension to it and there's a,
I think there is a pyramid somewhere
outside Atlanta and Georgia where they
wish it.
Does this ring any bells with you?
Well,
I know that his is a secessionist idea
that we don't really belong to the US
state,
that we are our own sovereign in a weird
way.
It kind of aligns with certain aspects
of the sovereign citizen movement where
you see yourself as not beholden to the
federal government and an independent
entity.
Why?
No,
he's his,
his production company was like almond
raw productions.
I believe it would make sense.
Yeah.
He's got a big thing with,
uh,
with Egypt and,
but I believe his thing was
constitutional.
His argument against taxes,
you know,
there's,
there's a bunch of people in this
country that state that federal income
tax is actually unconstitutional.
Exactly.
Yeah.
So it was for him,
it was a philosophical position.
I don't know if it was or was not.
I think it was,
but it was a ridiculous position.
He just can't fucking not pay taxes in
this country,
this couch.
Neat.
Without a doubt,
this country is run by by money,
without a doubt.
They need money and anyone who comes
along and fucks up that system and says,
Hey,
you know,
we don't have to give money.
What,
what,
how,
what percentage of the United States
runs on taxes?
A pretty large percentage.
If someone comes along and fucks with
that,
they're just going to throw you in a
cage when it doesn't work on kind of
ethical grounds because,
well,
if you're driving on the roads,
you're using tax dollars and on
pragmatic grounds it doesn't work
because they will send you to jail.
A pragmatic grounds of the most
important,
the,
the ethical grounds about the roads.
There's a,
there's a large argument for that for
sure.
But then there's also weirdness like in
New York where it used to be that they
set up the toll systems on the bridges
and the tunnels and what was going to
happen is once the bridges were paid
off,
then the tolls would stop.
But the state and the city obviously got
addicted to all that money that keeps
coming in from those tolls.
So even though the bridges are long
since paid for,
they still,
it still costs like nine bucks every
time you go across whatever the fuck.
It's really ridiculous.
Now when I was living there it was much
less,
but it's,
you know,
it's a substantial amount of revenue
that they're just not willing to give
up.
So it doesn't matter if it's paid for,
the money has to keep coming in.
And then of course the money funds is
bloated bureaucracy that keeps expanding
in order to keep itself alive.
Like any other organism that continues
to expand and just gets more and more
ridiculous and needs tax money to stay
open.
So a guy like Wesley snipes,
it comes along and says,
I'm not paying taxes.
You know,
it's hard for everybody to be
sympathetic to that because here's a guy
that makes millions of dollars,
doesn't want to pay taxes.
And the regular folks that have to pay
taxes and make a fraction of that,
like they don't have any sympathy for a
guy like that.
Plus he's half vampire indeed.
Yeah,
indeed.
So I don't,
I don't know what,
uh,
with his current situations,
I may have a chance to meet him in
Dallas.
Apparently there's a martial arts thing
that is going on in Dallas.
There's a UFC event,
ultimate fighting championship event and
there's
also like a,
something that he may attend a,
I'm,
I get a chance to meet him.
If I get to talk to him,
I would definitely bring them on here.
I was supposed to fight him at one point
in time,
get off how we're supposed to have a
mixed martial arts fight.
Several years ago before he went into
jail,
he,
um,
he owed a lot of money in taxes and a
promoter,
one of the original promoters for the
ultimate fighting championship.
Uh,
apparently he contacted them and wanted
to have a mixed martial arts fight in
order to make some money.
And they contacted me and offered me
some ridiculous amount of money and I
said,
yeah,
I'll fight that guy.
Fuck that guy for that much money.
But,
uh,
he changed his mind after a time went on
and I'm sure he was embroiled in legal
battles and there might've been some
chemicals involved in his decision
making.
So have you bought a,
I mean,
is that something you used to be a
taekwondo champion before I was ever a
standup comedian.
And uh,
I've done martial arts pretty much my
whole life.
I've got a black belt in Brazilian
Jujitsu,
black belt in taekwondo of kickbox.
I fought probably a hundred taekwondo
matches somewhere around there from age
15 to 21.
That's pretty much all I did.
Since you've been a,
you know,
an older man,
have,
you know.
No,
it's not,
it's not advisable to do unless it's
absolutely necessary.
And I wouldn't do it now if I was given
the same offer,
but back then it was like five or six
years ago.
It was a tremendous amount of money.
And he,
he's not a,
he doesn't know Jujitsu,
you know,
he doesn't have a background in that
he's experienced and striking.
And if you've never experienced,
if you don't have an experience in,
in grappling,
a person who does have experience in
grappling can pretty much have their way
with you.
It's very disturbing.
I found that out firsthand when I first
started taking Jujitsu in 1996.
I thought I knew martial arts,
I was going to take Jujitsu and I'll get
fucking awesome at this too.
And I just got strangled and manhandled
over and over again for years.
It was a long,
brutal,
painful,
humiliating process of learning.
And that's one of the things that was
sort of exposed in the very first
ultimate fighting championships.
If you don't understand grappling,
if you don't understand Jujitsu and
submissions,
you're almost helpless.
And uh,
that's Kinda what I was banking on.
I was banking on just kind of grabbing
him,
choking him and I,
my background was standup martial arts
was striking to.
I mean I competed and I knew he had
never competed.
He was a trained martial artist who is
apparently really good,
like in the gym.
But I thought it was probably a good
idea to do.
Sounds like he got off lightly.
Who knows,
I mean anything can happen when people
are throwing punches and kicks out each
other.
It's a crazy business.
You know,
as I've been doing commentary for the
UFC since I started,
I did a post fight interviews in
[inaudible] 97 and I've done commentary
since 2002.
So how
many,
many years.
And I've learned along the way that
crazy shit can happen.
People are throwing bombs at each other.
It's a.
have you ever done a show on mixed
martial arts?
It's,
it's an interesting question because we,
it's one of the few times when knowing
that we approach a story because it
feels like it should be right for us and
then it doesn't pan out for whatever
reason.
So I'm well aware of your work with the
UFC and about three years ago we spent a
couple of months really trying to crack
it as a story and then what happened was
we didn't get what we were trying to do,
mma and we and we didn't get access to
the UFC or not good enough access.
So we will look at the second tier,
but it's quite a big drop off from the
UFC down to the smaller leagues.
There was a guy we were dealing with,
cold terry,
triple cork.
I know him,
you know him.
He's King of the cage.
I always liked that name.
So that was why I remembered it.
Yeah.
Trouble cocs coc,
you know,
I wonder if we should get together with
Jean tripplehorn ha.
But,
but I,
uh,
he,
he ran it.
I don't remember what his league was
called.
Do you know what you're thinking of the
cage?
King of the cage.
So we spent a bit of time with them.
They were doing a series of fights up in
northern Michigan.
Uh,
and it was kind of interesting,
but there was another one we would,
and part of the same shoot we looked to
a,
an outfit that I want to say it was cops
versus cons or does that ring a bell?
Wow.
No,
I'm sure.
I'm sure it's out there though.
And they did.
They did felony fights as well.
You're aware of them,
but they'd sort of cleaned up since
felony fights was very brutal,
very hardcore ex felons,
a really wailing on each other in in a
way that was hard to watch teeth
literally popping out.
And have you seen any of those videos?
I saw one where a guy bid a guy's face,
held the man down and bit his face.
It's hard.
Some of this horrible,
horrible,
really horrible.
The full range,
you know,
that's if you have a spectrum of fights,
that's probably the darkest,
but the guy in charge of it had got
religion and he had.
He'd started a new outfit and he sort
of.
He was.
He was in the awkward maneuver of trying
to edge away from the brutal super
brutal,
horrible stuff into a,
into a lighter mode,
more acceptable,
fair but without,
but still kind of trying to keep his
brand viable.
And,
and his new thing was called something
like cops versus cons.
And the concept was it was law
enforcement personnel fighting
representatives of the criminal
fraternity.
Does that not ring a bell is going to
help him with Jesus.
That was his.
Because it was like he wants to show how
a,
there was some rationale,
like he wants to show how we can all be
on the same team and kind of fight and
then shake hands at the end of the day
and there's not a big difference between
cops and the street street brawlers oh,
that sounds like a spin them.
It was a kind of a spin,
but when it got down to it,
it was.
It was nowhere near as brutal as what
he'd doing with felony fights.
And the reason we didn't pursue the
story was it became clear that it was
actually a sport like it.
And if anything to my mind,
and correct me if you think I'm wrong,
but less brutal than boxing,
that you take more punishment because
the.
Because boxing bouts for so long and
possibly because of the gloves as well,
you're getting more brain injuries
through boxing and that compared with
boxing and even maybe you know,
nfl football and stuff.
That was like,
it wasn't that questionable what the UFC
or the or the mma guys were doing.
They were just going out there fighting
and then shaking hands,
hands
while there are certainly less animosity
between fighters and much more
comradery.
In fact,
two men who were probably two of the
best in the world,
Leo Machida and Chris Weidman who are
going to fight for the UFC.
Middleweight title Weidman is the
current champion they met recently at a
seminar or some some convention and
there's a photo of them together,
smiling,
holding like arm and arm.
I mean these guys are in a couple
months,
they're going to try to kill each other,
but yet they're smiling and very
friendly.
It's very common for people to be
friendly both before and after the
fights and there's.
With martial arts,
the true martial art mentality is not
one of thuggish nature.
It's not one of it's.
There's a photo of those two guys.
Those are the Weidman.
The guy on the left with the monster
milk shirt on is the current champion
and the other Guy Leo Machida.
The one on the right is the number one
contender who's two amazing fighters are
gonna fight and you see them hugging and
smiling before they're about to fight.
The Weidman,
who is a wrestler,
which I consider one of the very best
martial arts and Machida is a karate
master,
a true martial artists.
Machida,
he really embodies what you expect from
a martial artist in the bowing he
practices Cada.
He's very disciplined,
meditates,
and really is,
um,
what you would expect in a sort of a
movie version of a martial arts
competitor,
a martial arts master,
except he really truly is a real deal.
But I think that that attitude,
the martial arts attitude is,
is one of the more appealing aspects of
fighting where it's not like a Mike
Tyson,
you know,
the sort of a thuggish,
insulting.
There's some of that in mma as well,
but it's very rare and boxing that you
get someone who has the martial arts
ideals or an ethics that sort of
competes.
But when it comes down to whether or not
it's more or less dangerous,
it really depends upon the bouts.
And it depends upon the style that a
person fights in.
Um,
if you look at like a floyd mayweather
fight,
floyd mayweather is probably like the
least hit boxer of all time.
If you wanted to argue that boxing is a
super safe sport,
watch a floyd mayweather fight.
Watch how he fights,
rarely gets hit and he gets hit and hurt
much less than mixed martial arts
fighters.
I would think that his style of fighting
is probably arguably one of the safest
styles ever.
But would martial arts in mixed martial
arts provide is more options when a
boxer gets hurt,
they're not even allowed to hold on and
clinch.
Whereas with MMA,
that's the number one strategy.
If you get hit and you get stunned,
you grab a hold of your opponent and try
to take them to the ground and fight on
the ground and having all these
different options,
it definitely gives you less a head
impacts,
but not really much less,
you know?
I mean there's still a lot of standup
fighting involved.
Yeah.
Is there any evidence of degenerative
brain injury stemming from mma?
Most certainly.
Yeah.
Most certainly from long careers and
from a lot of training,
hard training,
there's also,
um,
there's a bit of evolution going on
right now.
I'm in mixed martial arts as far as like
how they train,
how fighters train and there was a lack
of knowledge and understanding about the
proper way to go about training.
In the old old days when it was first
starting out were people would just try
to be as rough and tough as possible so
they would spar in the gym at 100
percent.
They would basically have fights in the
gym.
They weren't just sparring matches,
they were like full on fights.
Your uh,
your mic is on.
So when you do that click is making
noise,
um,
the full on fights where they don't do
that anymore.
Now it's very wise to rarely spar at 100
percent,
most of the time spar at a lighter,
lighter impact rate and a much more,
much more on technique and much more on
strategy and positioning and preserve
yourself inside,
uh,
inside the gym.
And uh,
so as I say,
we abandoned it almost because of it's
sense of feeling like there's the,
it seemed healthy and normal in a non,
you know,
like kind of in a masculine.
So you would only go after it if it was
a freak show,
you know,
with that story we needed some extra
dimension.
I know and I think that possibly if we'd
got to the top tier like with the UFC
then that would,
that would have been sufficient sort of
show business gloss to it to fee or,
or just a sense of stakes.
But the guys we will,
we were meeting,
we're all part timers.
They were guys who worked during the
week,
it's mechanic's teacher's personal
trainers and every couple of weekends
they would fight a few bouts.
So it felt like a,
I mean I don't,
I'm not disrespecting them,
but they were,
they were not full time fighters and
there was this,
there was missing some kind of sense of
scale or something.
That's interesting.
So you decided to not pursue the story
left that one.
We spent a few days on it and we
thought,
well,
you know,
it might be that there's a way of coming
back to it at some point,
like I said,
the UFC side of it seemed more
interesting,
the sense of the personalities,
the ways in which intersected
with this multimillion dollar business
that they were running,
that felt maybe more.
Um,
and we will look at,
we're trying to find back yard backyard
bounce as well,
which if you remember a guy called,
there was a guy called data something.
Yes.
Data five thousand five thousand,
so $3,000.
Mother fucker's name was.
There was a scene in Florida have
backyard mountain.
So we were going to fit into it,
but it was.
And then they call him smokers.
Yes.
Do they still have smokers?
They still do like a true smoker,
which is going to be a what?
No,
no gloves.
What kind of,
what is a classic smoker?
Kickboxing and boxing is where smokers
really came from.
And what it is,
is essentially fights that would take
place in the gym.
And what they would do is wear head
gear,
boxing gloves,
like sparring gloves,
Shin Pads,
which you don't see in a regular
kickboxing.
And they would go at it essentially full
clip in front of family and friends and
it would be unsanctioned amateur bouts.
The problem with a lot of these smokers
is there was oftentimes no medical care
whatsoever and they were just,
you know,
hoping that no one got badly injured and
regulatory commissions frowned upon them
because they were really competitions,
but they were being labeled as non
competitive sparring,
you know,
they were there were calling them
sparring bouts.
So I've also had smokers where they had
full mma rules with little gloves and,
and no pads at all.
You know,
they've done those and I'm sure they've
had smokers where they had bare knuckle
fights as well,
especially during the,
the formative days,
like from 93 on.
There was a lot of evolution in mixed
martial arts.
There's a lot of things going on and
there was a lot of ways to skirt around
the rules.
Like for the longest time it was illegal
in California.
And that's one of the ways king of the
cage shine,
just because king of the cage would put
on bouts in Indian reservations when
they would go to these native American
reservations.
The native American tribes could form
their own rules.
And so,
uh,
I went to see a lot of the king of the
cage bouts in the nineties and when we
would go see them,
they were all on native American
reservations.
Then they also started doing a thing
called pancrase fights and what pancreas
fights where there was this strange
rule,
a loophole where you allowed to fight,
but you could,
you could slap,
you couldn't close your fists and punch
to the face,
but you could pull your hands back and
hit with the palms to the face and then
kick full blast to the face,
kick full blast to the body.
So there was a lot of those fights going
on in the United States as well when
there was no regulatory body for that.
It just sort of fit into some strange
loophole.
But King of the cage is still one of
those places right now where young
fighters,
when they're looking to get experience
that they'll start to come up through
that and that's still going.
And is it?
Yes.
Yeah.
I mean I just,
I don't know how many bouts that guys
had.
Terry triple cock used to my,
my friend Bud Brotzmann is a good buddy
of mine,
was also one of the original owners of
that.
And he got out and um,
he became part of shark fights for
awhile.
It was another organization,
but I don't think he does anything with
them.
I may now,
but triple cox still going strong.
Um,
another one that we never quite figured
out was um,
bare knuckle gypsy fighting it and we,
I don't know if you have a sort of
documentary cold,
not cold.
Yes.
It's one of my favorite documentaries
about Irish traveler families and the
foods that go on between these families
spending generations is the Joyce family
and another family.
Can't remember the name,
but um,
and the strange dynamic,
it's just really weird.
Like the family,
they're very traditional that they got
no money.
They were very close to the soil kind of
families and um,
that they issue these like fight videos,
like calling each other out into the
fight saying like,
you come and see me and tell you,
you never instruct me access.
You have no courage.
Yeah.
And they.
And they're very secretive and we spent
about three or four months trying to get
into that world.
I always found it fascinating and the
code of honor and that and the defending
your name and the strangeness of the
rules whereby there was all these,
this whole code of have rules about if
you were called out,
you had to fight.
If they insulted your dad,
you have to fight.
And then the kids getting groomed into
it very young and,
and we could never build trust with the
families.
But the guy who made knuckle,
do you remember how he gets in with the
families?
No,
no.
He shoot.
He gets invited to film one of their
weddings as a videographer and so he
films the wedding.
He's like,
this is really interesting.
These families,
they are wild.
They can of drinking and fighting and
getting married and having done one
wedding,
he,
maybe there's another wedding and then
he builds trust through,
through the access,
through the wedding videos.
He parlays that into shooting the fight
videos.
And so,
I mean,
I was glad someone did it,
you know,
uh,
it's really worth if listeners who
haven't seen that,
we should,
should check out.
Yeah,
it's a fascinating,
fascinating documentary and there's so
many of those call out videos that are
available now.
They put them up on Youtube now to
really embarrass the person that they're
calling out instead of just a video
where you hand that cassette off to
somebody else,
like in the olden days,
now they put these videos up on youtube
and they're their damn hilarious.
They're beautiful,
amazing stuff.
I don't want them to stop.
Does that exist in,
in the states,
in this,
in the same way
as far as you know?
Well,
I'm sure there's probably a few people
that have called people out to fights
over the Internet,
like travel,
uh,
fights gypsy fight.
No,
it's very different.
It's very different.
That's a uniquely European thing.
I love it,
just the language they use,
it's just so unique and unusual.
Ansys I also feel like that culture,
the Gypsy
culture,
it's,
it's probably a culture that's not going
to be around too many more generations.
It's very odd.
Like people sometimes ask me what the
strangest or the most difficult story
have ever done and one of them was
definitely a this gypsy one and it
wasn't for lack of a story being at the
story was there,
but we just couldn't figure out how to
get to it.
And,
and,
and there was just no sense of you'd be
having these conversations with the guy,
you know,
there was a guy who was um,
very high up in the Gypsy community and
he had a number of sons and he was big
in the fighting world and he was,
he was just connected in various ways,
both legal and probably not legal and,
and,
but you will have conversations with
them and just,
you couldn't figure out what,
what was real and what wasn't real.
And there was a slight sense of,
you know,
they call non Gypsies Gorgeous.
That's a phrase they use scorcher
gorgeous.
I think it's Geo.
Our Gis or maybe I'm in the spellings
could vary,
but we were gorgeous and I always felt
that because we were gorgeous,
you know,
non Gypsies that he,
that he is a gypsy,
just felt like no,
no real,
uh,
sense of needing to tell the truth to us
a lot of the time,
you know,
I don't,
I'm not trying to generalize.
That will be,
you're say that's true for all Gypsies
are travelers,
but,
but for him it was like,
because we were gorgeous if felt like,
you know,
we,
we just didn't count.
Wow.
Well it makes sense.
I mean,
what a tight knit culture.
I mean these people are living in these
caravans.
Is these a,
what do they call those?
The,
they don't call them trailers that they
call them something else.
Oh,
well,
caravans would be,
it would be really cool.
They call them caravans and they uh,
what was that movie?
Snatch?
Sort of highlighted it with Brad Pitt.
But these people,
they travel,
you know,
and they,
they set up shop in places and I have
some friends from England and they have
friends that live in this wealthy
community,
the suburban community outside of
London.
And these people apparently just moved
into the area,
set up their caravans,
set up shop,
and just started destroying the area.
They started putting garbage everywhere.
They started robbing people.
They,
I mean,
and they can't do anything about it.
Apparently.
There's like massive protection of these
people in,
in England and they're trying to be
polite about it and the way they,
uh,
they go about dealing with the situation
and these folks that lived in these,
you know,
multimillion dollar estates are really
kind of fucked.
Well,
it's one of these situations where,
um,
it's,
it's very hard to find the right line
because on the one hand we're talking
about a community that is heavily
discriminated against,
is deeply poor,
has massive dislocation in various
respects,
very high rates of illiteracy,
of Cha children not going to school,
the children's health not being good.
Um,
and you know,
having a massively out of work.
And then at the,
so,
you know,
by all normal,
so barometers you'd think that's a
community that needs help,
but also there's various social,
um,
vices that go along with that.
And um,
so then it's,
I think it's fair to say many of the,
uh,
the traveling folk are not well liked
in,
in rural areas and they are.
And as a cultural thing too where they
say like,
it's not in our culture to I'm a stay in
one place,
we have to rove around and we have to be
allowed to build a house in a field
where you're not supposed to build
houses.
So it's one of the,
it's like one of these,
you know,
they can sort of make a cultural
argument,
say like,
you,
we're culturally,
you can't.
Our tradition is,
it's like,
you know,
it's like a native American saying like
we have to be allowed to kill whales,
you know,
like,
there's these debates and there's a
spectrum of.
And there's a point where you say like,
well,
it's your culture to mutilate female
genitalia,
but it's still illegal and you can't do
it right.
Or we say it's your culture to hunt
whales.
Well,
we really want you to do that,
but maybe you can hunt deer instead.
It's our culture to,
you know,
so you've got to try and find.
It's a trick.
Yeah,
it's very tricky.
The,
the,
the area about the hunting whales is a
very unique one because I believe
there's certain inuit tribes that are
still allowed to hunt.
Certain animals,
like sealed are allowed to hunt seals
and whales.
I think on nails.
I don't know,
maybe some type of Wales.
Um,
I think in Alaska they allow certain
inuits to hunt certain type of Wales.
I think it's a very weird area though,
where it,
for anyone else,
it's very illegal.
Frowned upon endangered species.
The fact that they're intelligent
mammals,
dolphins,
you can't,
but these people that have this long
history of doing that somehow or
another,
it's preserved as a cultural artifact
and it gets very tricky in the female
genitalia.
Mutilation is a very good example of
that.
But my friends who are from England,
it's a horror story of these people that
live in this community that is besieged
by these gypsies.
It's allowed to say Gypsies,
Gypsies,
like a sort of a negative term.
I think it's again,
like I not,
I'm not sure there's a show big show in
Britain called my big fat gypsy wedding.
So that made me think maybe it was,
maybe it's not.
I don't know.
Some of them have a problem.
Well,
the Eskimos one that apparently inuits
don't like the term Eskimo,
but yet they call themselves eskimos
sometimes.
It's very tricky.
Um,
but the,
the,
the people that I know that have friends
that live in England,
I mean to them it's like this,
this horror story they lived in this
beautiful,
peaceful countryside is these elegant
manners,
beautiful states and multimillion dollar
properties and these people just sort of
destroyed it and now people are moving
out and selling their homes and it's a
pretty devastating according to my
friend.
Yeah.
So that's,
I mean,
you've got to have a law,
you know,
laws.
We do need a few tools.
We certainly do.
But the,
you know,
what is,
culture.
That's where things get strange.
Now what do we accept a clearly,
you know,
we moved,
we meaning North Americans,
whoever team here from Europe and
wherever when they migrated here,
encroached on native American land and
sort of changed the whole rules.
So what are the rules the remaining and
that's where this whole Indian
reservation thing comes into play here.
We allowed them to set up shop and these
areas usually that sucked places that
the,
you know,
the new people didn't want it all.
They allow,
these native Americans have these areas
and then they allowed them to sort of
establish their own rules in these
areas.
So then that was fine for the longest
time and they just sort of lived in
poverty until they started making
casinos.
Then it got really strange because then
non native Americans were allowed to
invest in these casinos and then they
established these crazy businesses where
they make millions and millions and
millions of dollars and they allow
gambling,
which is frowned upon everywhere else.
Again,
it's very strange.
Very strange.
That's another one that I'd like to do a
story on.
It didn't,
didn't figure out a way of doing,
but you know,
in talking about this,
I think what was the realization I had
was in the end of the stories I do on
about wackiness in my view or even stuff
that's kind of ethically dubious,
although I sometimes go into those
areas,
it's more what I'm interested in is,
is it's an angst and the and the deepest
kinds of,
of human angst where you are facing
issues the emotionally take you to the
core of your,
of your,
of your being and your soul.
And in some cases it's,
you know,
it could be stuff that seems kind of
dubious like the world.
I've done a story on brothels or I did a
story about porn performers and it's the
strangest of taking the intimacy of the
sex act and putting it on TV.
And then in,
in other cases,
it's stories where the angst is
something where you're presented with a
choice that is,
um,
is,
is really through no fault of yours.
Like you've got a parent who's got
dementia,
so a serious Alzheimer's and you or a
loved one,
let's say your husband who you been
married to for 50 years,
doesn't recognize you anymore and is
having sex at his old people's home with
some of the other women there are.
You still married to him?
And we did the story about dementia.
And again,
so that's not really about a choice.
Old people homes,
they get down.
What happens is we're in the post
Viagara era.
Ah,
so they can get Viagra and the old
people and some of the homes,
as I understand it there,
I mean we didn't actually film,
you know,
elderly people having sex.
But it was clear when one of the women
are spending time with,
uh,
with visiting her husband of 30 years,
whenever she visited him,
he would take one of his new
girlfriend's out.
They'd go out for a meal and they went
out as a threesome because he didn't
remember that he was married to his
wife.
He thought he had a new girlfriend.
And so,
I mean,
but I'm just taking that as an.
So when I come to this question of why
didn't the story about the,
um,
about,
about the mixed martial arts workout,
I think it was to do with like,
there wasn't a great deal of angst
there.
It was kind of healthy and people just
venting a little bit of male aggression.
Hm.
Does that make sense?
Yes.
So I'm trying to give you the DNA of.
We started out by talking about
wackiness American culture,
but the DNA for what I do is,
is much more about the fundamental
existential kind of the eras
irresolvable Oh,
my word.
I don't know.
Let's let it be a word like those sort
of like those deep complex that we have
as human beings from which are just
bundled into the whole package of being
human.
Do you find it limiting in that you have
to have conflict in order to have a
story?
Can you have a story where you're
pursuing conflict and there no either.
Like,
to me the conflict,
that's what I live for.
I kinda thrive on,
on experiencing conflict.
I'm vicariously through the medium of
reporting on the stories.
Like I couldn't see a story like,
did you see this film her?
No,
I did not,
but I heard about it.
So a lot of people love that film.
I got a lot of respect for Spike Jones,
but I didn't get that film at all
because there was no conflict in it.
Uh,
it,
it was just like a love story,
like a man falls in love with his,
his operating system and then she,
she kind of evolves to a higher
consciousness and a breakup,
but they're just having a lot of cozy.
I sort of ruined it for fucking spoiled
it man,
but they kind of have a little cozy
chats and I'm watching things like,
okay,
well I'm not getting,
I don't.
When's this going to start?
And I think like,
it maybe I'm programmed in a different
way for some people because I could not
watch that film and get white people
what people were getting out of it.
So you require conflict in order to be
engaged?
Yes.
You must have it now.
Well,
I found one of the things that I've
found really fascinating about your show
was the episode on Indian Gurus.
Yes.
That was my favorite.
Really.
It's just so fucking bizarre.
The American physicist was the most
bizarre to me.
There was a mike that was a long time,
I guess Mike from California.
Um,
there,
there was a Guy Swami,
Swami Satchidananda,
Swamiji love those names.
Yeah.
The Indians have fantastic language.
Their names are amazing,
but there was this character who is this
a yoga master,
spiritual
leader,
whatever he is without judging.
And there's this guy named Mike who was
a Divo Tay who lived in this guy's
Ostrom,
I guess,
and he believed that this man could
materialize jewelry and objects and the
story of him stomping his foot down and
a 50 pound note appeared in his hand.
Like,
this guy's a fucking physicist.
That's right.
It's just so strange.
That was a good one.
It was my favorite,
but my,
one of my favorite moments was you
sitting on the edge of the bed talking
to him and you asked him whether or not
you said try not to take this the wrong
way,
but did you have sadness in your life
before you,
before you met the sky?
And He,
um,
and he,
he took it a myths and he didn't like
that question.
And um,
he said something like,
uh,
what I,
are you asking me?
I'm like,
am I a burnout and burnout?
And this quote was fascinating because
it was about fundamentalism.
Yeah.
He says like,
I always say that,
uh,
having a breakdown is the,
is like the precursor to fundamentalism
when I thought he was going to say that
he had a break.
Yeah.
So I sort of went with the question,
like what he said,
I thought like he was setting me up for
that,
but he didn't see himself as a
fundamentalist and I'm.
It was a really,
it was a misunderstanding.
I normally try and get into the
difficult questions a little more
gracefully and because I've
misunderstood what he was saying.
I don't think you did.
I slid into it a bit.
I really don't think you did.
I think he changed gears,
you think?
Yeah,
I think he was sort of happened.
Like the deep story there is that I
spent.
That was weird weekends,
days,
which was about 10 years ago and I used
to try and spend.
It was like a little rule of thumb.
I'd find a contributor who I could
relate to the most.
Like you take something that seemed
really out of whack.
Something that on the face of it you
think that how could people really think
it's cool to move to Idaho and not pay
taxes and think the UN is going to
invade.
How could people really think that an
Indian guru is going to manifest rolex
watches?
They call them cities by meditating and
cure cancer by jamming on a keyboard.
Right,
and an old bon tempe keyboard and so.
But the.
The.
The technique we used was to try and
find the most likable,
reasonable seeming person who
exemplified that belief system.
So you was,
you take a weird subject but cost it
normal,
like cast it a person who's likable and
relatable and Mike was the guy we
thought and when you found that guy and
say,
and I'll move it,
I'll spend the night with them.
It was like,
it was like supposed to signal my
commitment to the story as well.
So in that story I spent the night at
Mike's Ashram and um,
but I,
I,
they had very thin mattresses,
although I later found out there were
different thicknesses depending on how
committed you were,
you would choose a thinner mattress so
you can choose a thick when buying real.
I just found a thin one so I put it on
and I had one of the worst nights of
sleep in my life and I woke up the next
morning kind of groggy.
And as you are offering night's sleep,
not just going to have bad tempered,
but also just my ci wasn't flowing right
now.
Wasn't in tune with what was going on
around me.
And so when he asked,
he said something about if you're,
you know,
uh,
if you fundamentalists because you've
had a breakdown.
And I think,
oh,
he's saying he had a breakdown.
I think so did you have some sadness in
your life?
And then he,
he,
let's play that and you can find that.
You can find that Jamie,
it's that video that you just showed if
you back up about three or four minutes
before that find it is,
is you'll see louis getting out of bed
and he looks very groggy and then he
communicates with this guy and they have
this
sort of a weird breakdown.
It's also the one where I try and call
because then the guru says he's a big
fan of siegfried and Roy or David
Copperfield.
He says he went to Vegas and I took that
as a kind of slightly very subtle coded
possible admission that he takes an
interest in magic and therefore what he
does is it kind of conjuring.
So I sort of,
I was trying to edge towards getting him
to admit that,
you know,
like we,
we know that you can't make a Rolex
watch appear out of thin air.
Right.
And so why not just,
let's just get that out there and admit
that you know,
that's what you do.
But he's a guru so he couldn't really
admit it.
Yeah.
This is a
no,
he doesn't.
He's working on a cosmic level.
Don't take this.
Don't take this the wrong way.
Mine who was there any sadness in your
life before you came to see the Swami
and committed to him?
I've always have a little saying
fundamentalism is the aftermath of a
nervous breakdown when,
you know,
it's a little bit of course,
but no.
Did you ever break come up with that
please?
Yeah,
no,
I don't know.
I like um,
you know,
the,
she pauses all this,
you know,
then he goes down.
But I think these are all tells.
I think he changed gears on you.
I really think his statement,
his initial statement,
fundamentalism and,
and you know about nervous breakdowns,
I think that's what he's really saying.
Yeah,
I really do.
And then when you confront him on it,
he realizes he's on camera.
That's why the all the,
you know,
he's thinking too much.
He's trying to come up with a way to
spin that story in a,
in a better light.
He's not just free flowing,
what's going on in his mind.
He's dancing around the subject trying
to wrestle it into a more acceptable,
palatable.
I think
I created it,
but I think what I see my take it is he,
he's emotionally,
you know,
close to the surface and probably has
been through a lot of difficult things.
I,
I mean,
I mean I getting dangerously close to
kind of diagnosing him,
uh,
in absentia.
But uh,
I,
and I think,
but I also think he's trying to step
outside it.
He's trying to say like,
I agree with you like,
but I'm not one of them.
Like I don't think he thinks that he did
have a breakdown.
Well,
it could be bought.
He's trying to play it off.
Yeah,
I mean,
I think maybe he was a lovely guy
though.
Uh,
it was from the bay area.
I hope he's doing okay.
Okay.
It seemed like a very nice guy,
which is one of the interesting aspects
of it.
He also seemed fairly intelligent,
but he also claimed to be a total
complete scan
dick.
But look,
you know,
Isaac,
I mean I don't want to go on a little
lecture,
but Isaac Newton believed in Alchemy.
Right?
Did he?
Yeah.
And spent the last 20 years of his life
having made probably the most important
scientific breakthroughs of all time,
the last 20 years of his life,
kind of calculating the dimensions of
Noah's Ark based on biblical
information.
I mean,
just Wacko stuff and,
and believed in the philosopher's stone
and the idea of.
I mean,
so the,
I,
I'm constantly surprised and the ways in
which your rationality or what we can
choose to think of is rationality can
coexist with rationality.
Sir Isaac Newton.
Didn't he also have an issue with
sexuality?
I believe?
I believe he was asexual.
The light that he was pretty weird.
He was a pretty weird dude and then at
the same time it may have taken someone
with a certain credulity or,
or like a willingness to believe in,
you know,
occult forces to come up with the notion
of,
of gravitational pull through a vacuum
at a distance.
You know,
when,
until then,
you know,
they'd been grappling with science as
mechanistic,
you know,
in other words,
don't say gravity.
Nothing explains why gravity exists.
Right.
You know,
why do objects attract one another at a
distance through,
through a vacuum.
They just do like,
there's no prior cause before that.
So in a strange way,
I'm,
his mind may have been predisposed.
Am I going to it?
No,
no,
you're not.
And I don't think there's anything.
I mean,
obviously he's not,
I don't believe he's correct about
Alchemy,
but I think you're dealing with a time
when information was so limited that he
might have thought that he was onto
something the same way he was on the
gravity.
He might have thought that there was
some sort of a scientific basis to
alchemy that he just couldn't hunt down.
Well,
exactly.
And I think that's what I'm trying to
say,
and at that time,
the paradigm of science in the 17th
century was that I'm all that nonsense
that they used to believe in the Middle
Ages was nonsense,
that you didn't have an even
Aristotelian ideas of things going up
and everything could be explained
mechanistically.
It was a mechanistic that objects banged
into each other and that's why things
moved.
So
it took a leap of faith to say,
you know what,
maybe objects move each other are
through forces that are invisible and
can't really be explained well.
It's also important to note that most
scientists were religious back then,
guess most scientists were Christians.
It was a,
there was a or Islamic,
um,
it was very common to be a Christian.
Very,
very uncommon to be an atheist.
Yeah.
In fact,
anyone espousing atheistic ideas was
thought to be a fucking nut.
Which is really interesting today where
you look at the vast majority of
scientists,
you know,
huge percentage of them either are
agnostic or claim to be atheists.
You know,
I think it would be comparable to saying
nowadays saying I'm a pedophile,
you know,
I think actually being an atheist in the
17th century was so outside the norm of
what people considered acceptable or it
was.
I mean,
I think that's the only way we could get
our brains around thinking you would be
shunned.
People would look at you and think like,
what is wrong with you?
You know,
because it was just taken for granted,
uh,
in,
in all levels of acceptable society.
Well,
I,
it's really interesting just going back
into our past just recent past,
so we have with recordings and
television and watching how different
our culture is from today,
say from the 19 twenties and 19
thirties.
Even films from the,
you know,
the 19 forties and fifties,
they're,
they very.
So there's so much of a difference.
I'm a standup comedian and when I go
back and I listened to the standup
Comedians of the 19 fifties in the 19
sixties,
I mean,
it's incredible how much different
culture is between now and then.
The greatest,
probably the most important comedian
ever is lenny.
Bruce,
in my opinion,
but if you try to listen to Lenny Bruce
today,
it's really not funny.
No,
it's not.
It's not funny and it's almost blast for
me to say,
but it's,
it's true because our culture has
changed so much since then that it's
just not relevant anymore.
The things that he's saying and the way
he sang them,
the,
the humor,
the shockingness of it.
Then it's so normal today.
Do you find any old,
like do you find the Marx brothers funny
or chaplain or there's some physical
comedy that's still pretty funny.
Okay.
But if it was new it would suck.
You know what I mean?
If it was released today,
if someone tried to release a three
stooges movie today,
be like,
what a piece of shit and that's a
person,
you know,
I have great respect for the three
stooges.
Sounds crazy
decide,
but I,
I think that it's,
it's,
it's an evidence of the references.
Our culture is just extremely different
now and I think that's one of the more
challenging aspects of trying to look
back on the 16 hundreds and trying to
imagine what life was like trying to go
back to the days when they used to have
to put skirts on table legs because were
thinking that people are going to be
sexually attracted to a table,
legs and piano and it's hard for people
to imagine that that was a real thing.
What about thinking of 100 years in the
future and what will look back on now as
a culturally weird that we take for
granted?
Oh,
there'll be so much.
There'll be so much.
What would it be?
Oh,
massive amounts of contradictions that
we have in our society.
I mean,
I think first of all,
the way people dress,
be bizarre.
Women's high heels will be laughed at
women's high heels.
Like when you see women walk around with
spikes,
you know,
and when women love wearing stilettos
and pumps and all these really bizarre
feet distorting shoewear or footwear,
I mean,
I think that's one of the things it's
going to be looked back upon ties.
People look back on ties the way they
looked at powdered wigs from the,
uh,
you know,
George Washington era.
So strange.
I mean,
uh,
and racism was normal in the 19th
century.
And even someone like Lincoln who we
think of as being a hero of the civil
rights struggle,
you know,
freeing the slaves,
the emancipation proclamation made a
number of deeply racist statements,
you know?
Yeah.
The world was different.
The way they looked at the world was
very,
very different.
And have you followed the whole story in
Britain about show business celebrities
being a accused of sex crimes based on
behavior in the 19 seventies?
Did I followed that whole thing about
that one guy who was that famous talk
show host Jimmy Savile?
Yes.
Wow.
That is fucking crazy.
That guy was a pedophile and apparently
for decades and it was covered up much
like the Jerry Sandusky case in America
for a lot of folks are aware of that.
The Pennsylvania State,
uh,
the guy who is a coach football coach
who was just a massive pedophile and
they covered it up,
they covered it up so much,
so I don't know if you're familiar with
that case,
but the DA,
the guy who was the prosecutor was
trying to try to find out information.
He turned up missing.
He turned up missing and they found his
laptop and a river with no hard drive.
They killed that fucking guy.
They killed the guy that is
investigating Jerry Sandusky.
Someone did.
And he would go,
well,
why would someone do that when you're
talking about a pedophile?
But then you find out how much money the
school makes and the school makes from
their football program the school makes
from people who went to that school who
donate to the school.
And it's an insane amount of money.
It's hundreds and hundreds of millions
of dollars.
But did you know that I was the only
person who,
uh,
who lived with Jimmy savile on it's on
and off for two weeks and made a
documentary about him?
No,
in 2000 you could find that on,
on Youtube.
What was that like?
Well,
let's see.
It's been a,
it's been a matter of a lot of soul
searching for me because of the,
um,
because of the strangeness of them
discovering that he had track record of,
of apparently sexually abusing where you
that keen and excited.
I'm like,
goodness,
just,
he's talking and it just appears.
Wow.
So go ahead place on the difference
between us.
We should be able to do something.
When Louis met Jimmy,
so you,
you spent two weeks with that guy?
More or less?
Yeah,
off and on over the,
over about three,
three or four months of miserable
Americans who were not aware of the
story at all.
It's not a very popular story.
Explain who he is.
So he,
there's no exact cultural figure in
America to compare him with.
But he was mainly known as,
as a DJ and from the late sixties,
right through to the nineties,
he was a,
he was just on the radio a lot and then
he got a TV show on the back of his Dj
career where it was called Jibo fix it
and people would call in with requests
for special fixits,
which were dreams that he would make
come true for them.
So kids would say I've always wanted to
a box with a big bulk,
you know,
meet Mohammed Ali or,
or drive a Ferrari or um,
whatever it was,
a dance with shorty know,
like just,
and they would come on and he would fix
it for them to do the things that was a
very popular mainstream TV show for 20
years.
And I'm all to.
Everyone in Britain knew who he was and
he was very,
very in his appearance was very odd.
You know,
you could see him there,
but even more so in his younger years,
he had this helmet of hair.
And so you,
you always looked at him and thought
cottage,
he looks really hard,
like something not right about him.
But at the same time he became a knight,
he was very well as a,
the establishment.
He,
uh,
became a night.
Yeah,
he was knighted for any raised millions
and millions of dollars for a pounds for
charity.
So he like this unique cultural figure.
And then after he died,
it turned out that he had sexually
assaulted a number of,
of women and um,
many of them were under age.
So it was a women thing.
I thought it was boys as well.
Well,
there's that that's been alleged and I
don't know,
you know,
with all this stuff,
the truth is,
it's not kind of been completely
established because he hasn't been know
he's dead.
He can't be tried in court.
But some men have stepped forward and
said that they were abused by him when
they were children.
So it was all children,
boys and girls.
When you say it was some of them,
some of the people who who said they
were assaulted,
they said it happened when they were in
their thirties,
twenties.
And then if he had a victim profile,
it seems to have been younger teens.
Oh Wow.
Anyway,
so that's a whole other can of worms,
but I just,
since you mentioned it,
I,
I felt I should,
I should say you,
I mentioned that had a connection.
So what was your experience when you
were with them for two weeks?
Well,
there was a scene in the scene.
We should play this bit of today.
I,
uh,
you,
you don't bother with anybody else,
et cetera.
No,
never,
never know.
Even for like a week.
Nope,
not even probation.
So he's saying he never had a girlfriend
go me meaning he wants to fuck other
people and he says don't bother with
anybody else
basically.
That's what he's saying.
He's saying that I've never had a
girlfriend.
I've only,
I've only kind of flitted from girl to
go.
He says friends that are girls,
thousands of them,
but girlfriend.
No.
And he's like 70 there.
Yeah.
But.
So I didn't really even at that time I
didn't.
I mean,
you,
you decoded that straight away.
At the time I wasn't really sure exactly
what he was saying.
Really?
Yeah.
Because I think because like he'd been
so confusing and he said so many
different things about the nature,
I mean he'd been so evasive on the
subject and if,
uh,
but yeah,
absolutely.
He's saying now that he had lots of
different girls who he would sleep with,
so this,
but this line of conversation leads me
to believe that you were suspicious
about him that
knew that it was well known that,
um,
let's say it was well known that it,
that his interests were unclear.
Like in other words,
it was well known.
There was a mystery.
I would say that no one ever.
If people always say like,
what are his interest?
I don't understand.
He's never had a girlfriend or a wife or
you know,
maybe he's gay or maybe he is.
Maybe he celebrate.
Maybe he's a sexual.
And I'm.
So I knew that there was a blank spot,
like a gray area space where,
you know,
his,
he kept his sexuality kind of.
Um,
and if you questioned him on it,
it was,
it was clear there was a secret.
And I didn't quite know what.
I didn't know what the secret was and
there were rumors of him being attracted
to underage,
underage girls.
Was one of the rumors.
Wow.
So this is not something that just
dropped after he died.
This was something that was,
was it because of the fact that he did
so much charitable work?
Was it difficult to question him because
the fact that he was knighted that
for me,
like I never felt inhibited from,
from asking tough questions.
Well,
you wouldn't know that's your nature was
culture where they.
I'll
truly,
I think,
um,
what's emerging now is that there was an
atmosphere of,
of protection.
I don't think there was,
there wasn't like a memo that went out
saying don't touch him.
He does a lot of work for charity.
But there was a,
there was an atmosphere of a feeling
that he was um,
uh,
doing good works for charity and he was
a vip.
And you know,
I think abuse victims,
even when it's not a celebrity,
there's a lot of pressure on them not to
come forward due to embarrassment and a
misplaced sense of guilt.
And when it's a
prominent member of,
of,
of the celebrity world who's viewed as a
kind of,
um,
uh,
you know,
a benevolent,
a philanthropist,
you know,
even more so,
yeah,
that was the issue with Sandusky as
well,
that he worked in charities,
charitable organizations that helped a
lot of young kids that were orphans and
he took a lot of these young kids on
trips and this was apparently when he
had sexually molested them,
allegedly.
What have you.
I don't know if he's ever admitted to
any of this,
but of course he's obviously he's guilty
of something.
Um,
but that was his thing that he had
helped all these kids and he was
involved in all these charitable
organizations,
but there was suspicions about him and
there was stories about him for a long
time and someone had protected him.
And the idea is the reason why they had
protected him was because it would take
down penn state this enormous,
a money making machine.
This huge cultural.
Uh,
it was,
it was a huge business.
And it was also like a big part of the
community.
I mean,
Penn State is this institution,
this,
this established institution that would
be brought down by this and victims had
come forward.
Yes.
And gone to the police or,
or,
or gone to the university authorities
authority.
It's a good question.
Um,
my friend Dom I rera is actually friends
with the prosecutor,
the,
the one who chased him down at the end,
not the guy that turned up missing,
but one of the ones who was involved at
the very end when he did wind up getting
prosecuted.
That guy,
he's amazing.
He's in jail now,
right?
Who Sent Dusky?
Yeah,
he's in jail.
Yeah.
The whole thing is very disgusting,
but it's,
it's so disturbing to think that they
protected him.
Like that was the whole thing about this
joe paternal character who was the,
the much was the legendary coach,
legendary coach who knew what was going
on.
Allegedly.
Yes.
Yeah.
Allegedly knew,
know,
and he took early retirement.
He died very quickly afterwards too.
Yeah.
I mean,
I think the news was just absolutely
devastating.
And when he was,
I don't think he took early retirement.
I believe he was removed.
I believe he was removed as a coach and
that's when everybody went crazy.
I mean,
there was like riots when they removed
him as the coach and then the news came
out and then when the news came out
everybody was like,
oh fuck.
And then he died shortly afterwards and
I,
I would probably safely say that a good
reason why he died was not just old age.
That devastating effect of this all
becoming public was probably just
unbelievably hard to deal with.
Of course,
you know,
not minimizing what happened to those
kids is much more difficult for them to
deal with it.
It's the whole thing is just totally
disgusting,
but fascinating in some sort of a
strange,
bizarre way that human beings are
capable of doing something like that,
that they're capable of shielding this
monster.
It is.
Yeah.
It really is.
And so,
uh,
but I'm curious about the fact that you
enjoyed the,
the guru story.
Uh,
I,
because I look back at that and it's not
one that I would feel is kind of one of
my finest moments.
I loved it.
I love the part where you met the woman
who is this guy or this female guru,
and she hugged me
right?
And I had a sort of transcendental
experience.
What happened there?
What was that?
Um,
it's hard to explain,
but I,
you know,
sometimes I think,
in a male way,
I'm not that connected to like the
deepest sources of my,
of my emotion,
so I don't really know what it was,
but I do think that being hogged is a
very simple and it's a physical act,
but it's,
uh,
it,
it creates all kinds of emotions inside
of you.
And it just sort of welled up from
nowhere.
It was just really odd.
I don't really know exactly what
happened.
Um,
I thought about that quite a bit after I
watched it.
And one of the things that I took from
it was the emotions and just the whole
group of people waiting in line to hug
someone.
The anticipation of it and the love
that's in the air.
There's sort of this group minded thing
that's going on
and there's a lot of music,
loud music.
There's a lot of people around,
there's a,
there's a very heightened atmosphere and
then she gave me a sort of turbo hug
too,
like she gave me the executive platinum
card hug and I think they whispered to
her like,
give this guy the works.
And um,
so she hugged me for longer and she was
actually muttering things into my ear.
What was she saying?
Not Words that I recognize,
but it was like,
it was sort of like,
um,
so it was,
is it comforting noises?
That's the word.
Poon job is the word for their language,
right?
Well,
there's several languages spoken Hindi
or I'm this or there's a few others,
too many to mention.
I would think that just the experience
itself of being around all those people
that were in this sort of dancing joyous
state in this long line to get to this
woman and she probably had some sincere
loving gesture towards everyone as well.
I mean,
you imagine what it would be like to be
adored by so many people in such a large
group of people that are established
there to come see you and get in line to
hug you or then you did it and.
But you are really like movies.
I was,
yeah.
I mean I think as well I was under a lot
of pressure when I'm doing those
stories.
I feel very pent up and I'm aware that I
have one chance to kind of get the thing
that I'm trying to get and we.
It was one of those classic things where
I was supposed to hug her the day before
and then we took a crew break and went
for an Indian meal and then when arrived
at the hugging tent that packed up and
left and I was like,
Oh my God,
we missed the hug and then it turned out
she was doing two nights.
She was doing like two dates in that
city because she was on tour,
like hugging her way around India.
So I was like,
oh,
we're fucked out.
We can get the hug now just because like
our crew wanted a nice meal and,
and,
um,
uh,
and so I got to here another night,
so it was,
it was this long lead up to getting the
hug.
It's always a tightly wound coil of,
of anxiety.
So when I finally got there and had the
hug,
it was a several levels on which I felt
just sort of relieved.
Wow,
that's fascinating.
That's fascinating.
But you know,
religions,
you know,
it's one of life's life's mysteries and
um,
I'm trying to do a thing on scientology
at the moment and that's proven quite,
quite a difficult road.
Well,
religion is certainly,
it certainly is one of life's great
mysteries,
but I think there,
there's also group states have like
mindedness that I find quite fascinating
and you could get them when the people.
I was at a military base once it was a
UFC fight for the troops and uh,
they sang the national anthem.
It's in the middle of the Iraq war.
And um,
the,
when they sang the national anthem,
the intensity and the feeling in the
air,
the patriotism,
the,
just the emotions involved in you're
dealing with thousands of people in the
audience who have lost loved ones,
lost friends,
maybe been wounded themselves,
may be taken lives themselves.
Many of them have shore taken lives
themselves.
And the,
the,
the palpable,
the patriotism and the emotion and the
environment.
I am a person who was absolutely against
all of these wars,
whether it's the Iraq invasion,
the Afghanistan war.
I thought the whole thing was about
money.
And the whole thing was ill advised.
I thought that the idea of going in for
these supposed weapons of mass
destruction was incredibly transparent.
And then I thought that the government
and the military industrial complex was
capitalizing on a horrible event in
September 11th.
And using that as an impetus to go and
invade these countries and,
and take over,
you know,
resources.
But that moment when that thing was
happening and that person was singing
the national anthem was a soldier that
was singing the national anthem and
everyone was standing there proud.
And the energy in the air and they cheer
when it was over ready to go to war.
I mean,
you are ready to support the troops.
You're ready to not just support the
troops but support the war.
You're ready to,
to back them.
I mean,
there's this weird thing that happens.
These group minded sort of states that.
So did you get into a kind of altered
consciousness in that moment?
I felt something for sure.
Did you feel I could have easily if I,
if I
coached myself into it or if I entertain
those thoughts,
let it go.
If you'd gone with the feeling.
I mean,
I was working at the time I was,
it was,
you know,
I was there for the ultimate fighting
championship and um,
but the state of mind,
the,
the group state was fucking intense and
it was,
it was palpable.
It was tangible.
It was in the air.
And you know,
this is coming from a person who I
believe that it's very important to have
military.
I believe that there are bad people in
the world.
I believe that there's sometimes no
other solutions mean I don't believe in
pacifism when you're dealing with thugs
and evil people in the world.
I believe that,
but I also believe that there's good
people that are sent into bad situations
for all the wrong reasons,
by people that are trying to make money
in that state,
with being there with all those
soldiers,
being there with those people.
Man,
you got swept away by it.
He just carried away by this,
this intense feeling of patriotism.
It's an indescribable because you could
feel the emotions of those people that
are in that room and I wonder if that's
similar to what you were experiencing
when you were there.
I'm sure.
I'm sure we're very close and,
and,
and it's not the only time when.
I mean if the only time I think I felt
that exact sort of emotion of sort of
whatever that was as a religious
transcendence,
but I've,
you know,
there's plenty of times when you are
around people.
I mean,
in a way,
a lot of the stories I do are about the
altered consciousness of being exposed
to people who believe things
passionately and the slight sense of
Stockholm Syndrome that sets in when you
were there for prolonged periods,
you know,
and,
and the weird,
um,
change the,
the change in consciousness that takes
place.
You know,
I,
I did a story where I was with the
Phelps clan,
the Westboro Baptist Church,
and uh,
I was spent three weeks with them if I
did two different things,
but for the first one,
I was there for three,
which was called the most hated family
in America.
And it was really odd because when
you're inside there,
the little compound in their,
in their castle imbibing they're at and
their doctrine round the clock,
stuff that seems really weird and
hateful on the outside starts to seem
mundane.
You know,
you're still able to step outside of
their life.
I'm here to do a job and this is wrong,
but you,
you get a nice sized,
your mind,
your mind starts to get influenced.
It's really strange.
I would imagine it is.
Um,
I've found the Phelps won very
fascinating because of the one guy that
came there to film a documentary on them
and then became one of them.
He joined up.
Steve.
Yeah,
he's very high up there now.
Steve.
He's and his daughter left,
um,
a couple of years ago we went back and
did a followup because a couple,
the people we featured in the first one
then left.
But Steve almost you could argue by dint
of having been born outside the church
was compensating by being even more
hardcore because he was the fiercest and
the most,
um,
in conversation.
He was the hardest and the most,
um,
the most abusive,
I guess most verbally
full of bile.
And he also,
when you questioned anything that he was
saying,
what starting salting you.
Yeah.
And aggressively insulting you.
And I found that fascinating as well.
Wasn't just that you could have
questions.
It was,
what are you fucking idiot?
It was immediately this aggressive sort
of
told me I was the most.
I can't remember the phrase that it
sounds like the most iniquitous or the
most evil man in the history of the
earth or one of the three most evil men.
He said,
you're right up there with punches pilot
like I was one of the three most evil
men of all time,
like way beyond Hitler.
And the reason was the reason was
because I'd been exposed to the
teaching,
so like I'd been given a special
opportunity like I was blessed beyond
measure because I had been exposed for
three weeks to the pure teachings of the
only people preaching salvation on earth
and having seen that and still rejected
it,
then that put me way beyond the Pale.
I found it incredibly fascinating.
How effective of a guy who sucks at
speaking is at running a call,
like he's a terrible orator.
He's not like this really charismatic
gramps.
The main guy.
He's very old now.
He's in his time.
He could.
He could do it.
I thought he was.
I think you're being a little unfair
real.
You remember the bit where he says,
I'm going to eat.
You're going to eat your babies.
Like he,
he still,
he's very old and decrepit,
but he still cranks it up and he goes,
you're gonna,
eat your babies.
See,
I don't agree.
I felt it was so one note,
it was like death metal.
You can eat your baby.
I mean,
it was just so obvious.
It's just there.
There's.
Who Do you like,
you like Billy Graham?
Like what preaching style do you prefer?
A Sam Kennison.
It's my favorite.
Um,
I just think that there are people who
are better at it than Phelps.
Phelps is so negative and so abrasive.
I think there's almost his.
He's so evil.
Bill,
he starts dearly beloved.
He has a slow bill and then he ramps it
up and then he get,
he hits his,
his kind of power chorus.
If you can eat your babies,
I think there's something when someone's
unbelievably evil and aggressive where
you don't want them to be angry at you,
so you're willing to sort of like bend
your mind to what they're saying and
accept it and allow it in.
And that's what I felt watching that
guy.
And I've seen that in him before and in
his speeches,
I've tried to sort of rationalize or
understand what's going on when,
when he talks,
why would anybody gets sucked into all
this evil,
hateful talk and not question it,
but I think it's,
he's so over the top and so aggressive
that he's frightening to people,
like when you sat down with them.
And
here's the thing,
they,
I mean by and large,
they don't really make converts.
They make a few,
but he's not trying to recruit new
personnel.
If anything,
it's the opposite.
They re,
they view it as a,
um,
as a confirmation of the holy status of
their salvation that they rejected
because there's some verse somewhere in
the Bible saying,
you will be hated of men and people will
throw things at you.
It's somewhere in the Bible.
And so every time someone says,
you're full of it,
you're scum.
We hate you.
That what they hear is,
yes,
we are.
We're saved.
So,
and so when he,
um,
and so,
like 90 percent of the people in there
were born into it and a family members.
And in fact,
they lose,
they hemorrhage membership constantly.
They kicked people out.
So when he's preaching,
he's not thinking,
how do I get new new followers?
While I'm not saying that he's thinking
that,
I'm wondering the effectiveness of
retaining anyone.
I don't think it's even there.
I guess there is a,
the,
the main effectiveness is that,
um,
I don't know what it.
Well,
you would know obviously much more than
I,
you were there for three weeks deeply
embedded into that organization.
He hated me.
GRANDPA did.
And he was one of the few times where
you try and do an interview with someone
who clearly can't stand you.
And I did an.
I said something like,
how can you really believe that there's
no.
Like,
even if you accept that what you say is
true,
you know that position is,
there's no other church in the world
that is preaching the doctrine.
I said,
how would you even know?
Like there could be some tiny church in
Nigeria that's preaching the exact same
message.
How would you,
you wouldn't even know.
He goes and he says,
I didn't know about them.
And I asked another question you guys
asked and answered and I also have
another because asked an answer and he
just kept saying Austin answered,
which is a legal term and you know,
what do you do what you do then?
Well there's nothing you could chuck.
He's the epitome of a close minded
person.
He is
closed minded.
Not just that,
but this arrogant assumption that he's
the man with the word of God and that it
comes out of this angry old fuckheads
face.
You know,
it's,
it's a,
it's an amazing thing that this guy is
able to put together this group.
I mean I just.
This is the moment where you sat down
and talked to this guy.
You know what I mean?
How long have you been with him by then?
I think this was,
I'm trying to think.
It was the end of it.
We made three trips each of a week.
This was the second trip last day.
Just a little knowledge of what you just
said is stupidity
in Spanish.
I don't know how to deal with questions
like that.
Just you just took dom.
Sorry,
W you're,
you've got the duty to know the Bible as
well as I can.
Why?
Because you are a human being because
God Almighty major and got all my is
going to send you to hell.
Is it accurate to say that you regard
the Westboro Baptist church is the only
biblical preaching?
Just three minutes of answering your
question is yes.
No,
it was five minutes.
Well,
but I already talked to them.
So there's three left.
He even had a laugh.
Their fucking shitty math preaching that
is according to the word of God.
It's been asked and answered my next
question as far as your concerned.
We got it.
Yeah.
I mean this is angry old shitty man
who's able to get a bunch of people to
listen to him.
I finally gets his kids,
his kids and his grandkids know how many
people were there.
It seems like there was 20 or 30 or 90.
That's good.
Yeah,
he had 11 year.
I think I want to get this right.
I think it was like 12 kids,
but for them had left the church and um,
and each of them had,
had quite a few kids,
but I think,
um,
I think if you're an EGOMANIAC number
one,
number two,
if whatever reason you cleave to a
certain kind of dogmatic religious
outlook,
it's probably not that difficult to,
to,
to run,
to have a cult.
It's unfortunate,
but I think you're right,
you know,
shocking.
But I think you're right,
I've,
I've often said that all you have to do
is speak confidently and clearly and
most people will be like,
I can't.
Yeah.
And,
and have no compunction about saying
that you speak the word of God or
whatever it is.
It's really all you have to
do,
right?
You have to be the guy with the answers.
You have to be the guy that absolutely
not just the is like as a human,
but the answer is from above.
Have you read the new medicine book than
you Charles Manson Book by Jeff Gwinnett
came out last year?
No,
I try not to read anything that comes
out about Manson A.
Oh,
well I'll ask you why in a second,
but when you read it,
it's like,
Oh my word.
You just have to be kind of come out
with a few kind of riddles that you've
learned from St Pimps and people fall
into your lap or so it would seem.
You made me hate your garbage,
man.
You people made me.
I'm your product.
All that fucking shit.
I think that that guy's the Bob hope of
serial killers,
you know,
because Bob hope was a comedian that
never really made anybody that in my
generation laugh.
Like we always knew him as a comedian,
but it's just really wasn't funny.
Manson's never scary to me.
Like there's some real serial killers
that we're fucking terrifying.
But when you think of serial killers,
it's always Manson Manson Manson is the
guy,
the crazy guy,
the wild guy because he carved fucking
swastika on his head.
But if you mean Henry Lee Lucas,
the guy from that,
they made that movie about him.
Henry Portrait of a serial killer
allegedly killed somewhere around 60
people.
You know,
and I,
I,
with Manson,
the.
I think the reason people are fascinated
with medicine is because he didn't kill,
right?
He got other people too because he got
the children that he,
uh,
he sent them out.
Tex Watson was as big killer,
right?
Become a born again Christian and I
think he writes children's books or
something fucking creepy
that.
And you know,
a number of them still believe,
you know,
that trial is that Charlie's still.
Yeah,
of course.
Otherwise they're idiots.
Then they're fucked up and you know,
well,
what he did,
what they did do to Sharon tate,
tate labianca murders,
fucking unbelievably horrific and caught
a baby out of her body and a lot all
over the walls.
And it was all really,
really terrifying shit.
I mean,
don't get me wrong,
but there's been a series of really,
really evil people that almost no one
knows about and it's bizarre what
becomes popular,
what becomes famous in the world of evil
people you know.
And sometimes it's just a name,
you know,
Manson,
and everybody remembers that name.
They,
they're too lazy to kind of investigate
and find out about other names.
But there's been a,
you know,
so many God damn serial killers in this
country or have been.
It's bizarre that that one guy gets so
much ink.
Yeah.
Well Geraldo can take his share of
responsibility because for all those
fault.
Well he did a number of landmark
interviews in the,
I guess in the seventies or the early
eighties.
You can see them on youtube where he
sort of turned him into a celebrity.
I mean,
I guess the,
the,
the cases were big at the time,
but then he,
Geraldo did some shows.
I think Diane Sawyer might've done an
interview and then they passed laws to
say that you couldn't basically,
you couldn't interview Charles Manson
anymore.
It's fascinating to see what Geraldo has
become.
Did you know that Geraldo was like a
counterculture figure at one time
Geraldo was the guy who introduced the
world to the Zapruder film.
He had Dick Gregory on his television
show and he showed the world as uproot
or film essentially establishing the
idea that it was more than one person or
someone else other than Lee Harvey
Oswald that killed Kennedy.
Now he's on Fox News.
And what happened to Dick Gregory?
Dick Gregory is still around.
He's,
you know,
he's not really a comedian anymore.
I think he does some shows,
but he's more of an activist and he's a
very,
very old now.
But I saw something recently with Dick
Gregory sitting down with Paul Mooney
who is a,
um,
a great old comedian from Los Angeles
who was a writer for Richard Pryor and
just a great comedian.
And the two of them were sitting around
talking about racism and culture.
Some of his jokes back in the day were
pretty good.
Very good.
Dick Gregory was very good,
but he was
also not just a comedian,
you know,
he was an activist.
He was the guy who somehow or another
got ahold of the Zapruder film.
The zapruder film was made obviously in
1963 when Kennedy was assassinated,
but it was put on.
It was bought by time life magazine,
I believe,
by whoever owns life magazine or time at
the time.
And they just put it on shelf for,
for years.
And 19 seventies is when Geraldo had it
on a show.
So before that it had never been ed
never.
They just made a TV show about it.
I think about the router family.
Yeah.
I think.
Look at this,
look at the way they're dressed.
Right.
Straight out that if you 75.
So think about that.
Eight years later,
a crazy little queasy then don't watch
this film.
Just put on the uh,
the late night movie,
uh,
because this is a very heavy.
It's the film shot by the Dallas dress
manufacturer.
70 five Zapruder and it's the execution
of President Kennedy Way.
Geraldo has a mustache.
What we're seeing as we show this film
bruter film.
Okay.
So the cars are coming along now into
dealey plaza.
Yes.
These are the lead motorcycles in the
motorcade.
All right.
Now with the president and Mrs Kennedy
is also governor connally right now.
Before he goes behind the sign,
the president is waving to the crowd
when it comes out from behind the sign,
he is shot.
Then governor connally,
his shot.
He's already been hit.
And now at the bottom of the screen,
the head shot,
that's the shot that blew off his head.
It's the most horrifying thing I've ever
seen in the movies.
Now the Warren Commission said that all
of the shots were fired from behind by
Lee Harvey Oswald alone,
assassin firing at the president.
And then she could see clearly the head
is thrown violently backwards,
can completely consistent with the shot
from the front.
Right now,
this is an extreme blob of just the
president from the film coming out
behind the sign.
He shot his head from the sit here in
the front from the front.
Now Jackie doesn't realize what's
happened yet.
She goes to his aid
and now
he's said again,
the violent backward motion.
I've never seen that before with really
never seen this uprooted from a,
just like the bits they showed in jfk,
you know,
the Oliver Stone Film.
Uh,
I'd never,
I'd never seen.
I don't think they showed that bit.
I don't know.
I mean,
it's,
it's pretty common.
It's,
it's available.
I mean,
they've broken it down.
It's been enhanced.
There's a variety that you believe in.
The,
uh,
there were two gunman.
I think there was probably more than
two.
Garmin.
Yeah,
I think,
but I don't think.
I don't think it's an either or was one
of the Woody Harrelson's dad.
It very well could have been.
Yeah.
Isn't that fascinating?
Well,
I don't think it was an either or
because everybody wants to say that he
was either
Lee Harvey Oswald or it was other
people.
It could have been Lee Harvey Oswald and
other people,
and that's.
I don't understand why people have to
have everything black and white and
everyone's Lee Harvey Oswald acted
alone.
Like,
why do you think that?
Why do you think that?
Like why would anybody think that he
acted alone?
If you look at all the injuries that
Kennedy was Bonnie,
first of all,
the shot in the neck.
It's an entry wound in Bethesda,
Maryland.
They called it a tracheotomy,
but in Dallas,
fort worth when he was first
administered by taking care of my
doctors,
they said it was an entry wound.
They changed what the wound in his neck
was in order to fit with the established
narrative of Lee Harvey Oswald being the
lone shooter.
That's one reason to think that there
was more than one person.
The other reason to think there was more
than one person was the single bullet
theory,
and I've heard a lot of people say that
the single bullet theory could have
happened.
That bullets can act very weird when
they go through and they absolutely
can't.
People have shot people and bullets shot
someone from the front and the bullet
has ricocheted inside their head and
come out there.
I and landed in front.
I mean that has happened,
but let's take very strange past when
they ricochet off bones.
That's not what's weird about the bullet
passing through to people.
What's weird about the bullet passing
through to people is first of all,
why did they think that one bullet did
that and the reason for that is because
a bullet hit,
the underpass ricocheted off a curb
stone and hurt some person that was
standing in the underpass.
So they had to attribute one of the
shots.
One of the three shots to that bullet,
they knew that Kennedy and connally had
both been hit and then they knew that
there was a headshot,
so those are three bullets,
one boat that hit the curb stone,
the other boat that passed through two
bodies,
and then the headshot.
That's the reason why they had to make
the entry wound of the neck a
tracheotomy and that's the reason why
they had to say that one bullet had
caused these wounds on two different
people.
They found the bullet on the Gurney in
Connolly's hospital,
Gurney when he was administered in the
hospital.
Oh look,
we found a bullet in pristine condition
if you've ever shot a bullet,
and that bullets hit bone.
When bullets hit bone,
they distort the idea that that bullet
came out like that.
After going through two people's bodies
and hitting bone.
It's ridiculous.
It doesn't make any sense.
That's the reason why I think that more
than one person was involved and that's
the reason why there's a book called
best evidence by a guy named David
Lifton who goes into great detail.
He was a.
He was a bookkeeper and an accountant
and uh,
he,
he had some assignment revolving
involving the Warren Commission and he
was such a meticulous guy that he
actually read the entire Warren
Commission,
which is some insane number of pages,
but he read it and he wrote a book
called best evidence all about all the
contradictions in the Warren Commission
report and why he thought that the
entire thing was established to make a,
a,
a predetermined conclusion and to
establish that with the American public.
And he thought it was all horse shit.
So I don't think so.
I think more than one person was
involved,
but it could have been Lee Harvey Oswald
to.
That's what people don't understand.
Why people have to have either Lee
Harvey Oswald killed them or there was
other people like it has to be there
alone.
Assassin or other people.
I think the Harvey Oswald clearly was a
fucked up guy who had some sort of a
connection to the government.
He went to Russia,
lived in Russia,
and then came back to the United States,
got a passport until he was living in
Russia and then was readmitted back into
the United States and had some dubious
connections to the,
uh,
to,
to the,
to the world of,
of,
of government.
It was a very strange,
strange story that in this day and age,
you know,
all these years later,
we're most likely never going to get the
full.
How many impacts do you see in that
video?
It's hard to say.
You know,
when Kennedy is holding his body like
this,
most likely he's.
He had been hit,
but they're saying that it was from the
front.
How do you know it was from the front?
It was from the,
behind the sign.
He could've been hit from the back.
It's hard to tell what happened.
Me,
he's going like this.
You're assuming that that's because he
was hit,
but it might not have been.
I mean,
he might've dropped his fucking pen.
he might've been like,
where's my shit?
And then got hit in the head.
I don't know.
It's very difficult to tell from that
video how many times he's been hit,
but the idea that Lee Harvey Oswald
acted alone seems the least likely of
those of the scenarios,
and then the photos of the Howard hunt
who was arrested allegedly along with a
bunch of people that were quote Unquote
Hobos,
that they ended up arrested behind the
behind the grassy knoll,
but then they were all released.
Their hobos were,
they were dressed normal,
their address,
like,
you know,
regular people.
And then you know,
Woody Harrelson,
his dad who was a known murderer who
supposedly has some sort of a connection
to it.
I don't know.
You know,
I don't know,
but you know,
there's a guy who wanted to get rid of
the Federal Reserve.
There was a guy who wanted to get rid of
the CIA.
He wanted to pull out of Vietnam.
I mean,
there's a lot of shit that Kennedy
wanted.
He wanted to put us.
He put us out of Vietnam.
He wanted to disrupt the military
industrial complex.
He wanted to do a lot of things that
were very unpopular.
I mean,
in a way you could pose the question is
not why would he have been assassinated,
but why aren't more president's
assassinated?
We'll look at a guy like Obama who,
it's amazing to me that given the level
of vitriol that's directed at him from
quarters,
you know,
in the far right that someone.
But I think every day there are threats
and probably some of them are credible
threats against him.
Sure.
I'm sure that CIA or the rather the
secret service does a great job of
stopping a lot of assassination
attempts.
I mean,
if we lived in a time like,
you know,
during the Lincoln administration,
whether there's.
Everything was very just,
you know,
they just didn't have the type of
security that they have today.
They didn't have this sort of
technology.
The ability to track people,
the ability to keep an eye on
questionable
folks
did.
Uh,
did you follow one of the guys they
questioned in connection with threats to
the president was Ted Nugent,
did you know that question with?
He was actually for statements that he'd
made about Obama.
He got a,
he got a visit from the secret service.
Yeah.
He said that he would wind up in jail
if,
if Obama was elected again,
you know,
that he would wind up in jail.
Well,
and that was construed as a threat to
them because I made a program about.
Here's another guy.
I did it when I started out working in
TV with Michael Moore.
Uh,
he gave me my break on tv and I worked
on a show called TV nation and one of
the early segments was with Ted nugent.
I've always had a sort of fascination
with the far right.
Yeah.
He's a very fascinating guy.
And the FARC row on the far right
because there's been so much bizarre
shit in his past.
He had adopted some 17 year old girl or
became a legal custody.
Took legal custody of her so we could
have sex with her.
Is that rights as parents allowed it or
her parents maybe or 11?
Yeah.
It said in a recent New York Times story
that he had admitted to having,
um,
I guess unlawful,
a relationship.
Sexual relations with underage girls.
Underage girl.
Okay.
Goals.
Does that ring a bell?
There was something that Courtney love
said that she gave him a blowjob and she
was 12.
Really am.
Yeah.
Apparently allegedly A.
He's a fascinating character.
You know,
he's a radical far right,
sort of a guy,
but what he said about Obama was clearly
a joke,
but you can't have jokes about Obama.
Like we had a guy on
that was a joke as much as just A.
I'm a racist,
insult,
racist.
When he said,
well,
this was a different occasion.
This was when he called him a subhuman
Mongrel.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
Well that's not what we're talking
about.
I don't think that was the reason why he
got up with the visit.
Yeah.
I'm sorry,
I switched the subject.
It was more recently in the news because
of this comment.
Yeah.
The visit was before the reelection
instead of Obama got in office again.
He would wind up being arrested.
That was,
I'm sure that was a CIA visited him and
I think he was just talking shit,
you know,
I think he just talks a lot.
He does an incredible amount of media.
I'm pretty fascinated by that guy.
He said,
when I was with him,
she said that I said something about the
Oklahoma City bombing.
I said,
why is your flag at half mast?
He said,
because of the Oklahoma City bombing.
It was at the time when I,
I,
uh,
it had just come out that Terry Nichols
had,
had some relationship with,
um,
uh,
the Timothy Mcveigh.
And,
um,
I said,
well,
it seems as though the suspects that
they have in custody,
it was pretrial have the same sort of
profile as you,
ted,
they're,
they're pro gun rights members of the
Michigan militia who you say you
support.
Which was kind of a cheeky question.
Like,
I,
if I was asking you
now,
I'd asked it in a different way,
but he,
he kind of went nuts and,
and,
and started shouting abuse at me.
He said,
um,
he,
he became logarithmic.
Like he became incapable as he was so
angry.
He didn't hit me or he just read it.
You see that this is what,
this is what the media does and why did
I mention you could kiss my ass.
Like he said something like Ted nugent
impression by the way you even touch
the,
took the tone row,
he said,
and then he said,
um,
I said,
what do you think about Janet Reno?
He said,
she's worse than Hitler,
and I was like,
worse than Hitler,
like even if you hate Janet Reno,
she's not rounding people up and sending
them to their death in,
you know,
in,
in the millions.
And then,
and then he had a mony said,
well no one's worse than Hitler I
suppose.
And he kinda climbed down from it.
I think there's a thing that he does
where he just talks a lot and I think
when you talk a lot you just need to
keep talking.
He's also very,
he talks a lot and he's very angry.
He's just very keyed up sometimes,
but he's watching them,
a lighting guy,
like he's actually quite and he can be
quite.
I went on a little hunting excursion
with them as part of the show as well.
And he's capable of being kind of a
mellow,
interesting dude as well.
Yes.
And that's what I was going to say.
Like you watch them,
I was hunting show.
He seems very happy,
like I hunt and I've watched his hunting
show many times and it's,
his hunting in quotes is very odd too.
And this leads us to another subject
that I wanted to cover with you.
Um,
he,
he hunts in his yard,
right?
He's got a compound of 300 acres and in
Texas and he's got one in Michigan as
well.
And you know,
he leaves out food and weight and a tree
and shoots these animals.
It's,
it's a.
So it would be caught,
it would be considered canned hunting
there 100 percent.
Yes.
But he's using a bow and Arrow,
which to me,
mate,
I've got more time for bow and Arrow
hunters in the sense that it's so much
more difficult unless you're leaving
food out and the animals are eating food
10 feet away from you and you're hiding
in a tree.
And that helps.
It helps a lot.
It's a very controversial method of
hunting and there's two types of people
in.
When it comes to the hunting community,
there's people that are fair chase
hunters and people that believe in high
fence operations and sometimes they're,
they're interchangeable.
Sometimes people support both.
Um,
and I,
I would.
This is the way I feel about it.
I think that it's a great way of
acquiring meet.
That's probably way more ethical than
being a farmer.
You know,
if you're going to look at it that way,
you're going to say,
well,
this is how I acquire my meat.
I leave food out for them and then I
shoot them.
Okay,
I see that and I agree with that.
It think it's better than farming in
that sense,
but it's to call it hunting the same way
you would call hunting,
like climbing up to the Alps and looking
for a mountain goat that lives in the
wild or
going through the rockies and chasing
down a moose,
you know,
that lives in the wild.
It's a two completely different sort of
endeavors.
When you've got these animals fenced in,
you have an account of how many are
there?
There's 300 a year.
I need to kill one of them.
You know,
and that's not really hunting and one of
your shows,
which I found very fascinating that I
watched last night was about canned
hunts and Africa.
Right.
And that was really fascinating what a
contradictory and complex subject
because for folks who don't know,
Africa was on the verge of a lot of the
animals that are now being hunted.
We're on the verge of extinction now.
They have extremely high numbers all in
these high fence operations and these
people go over there and hunt them.
And that guy that you had that own,
that operation that got crazy with you
and put his hand on the camera and hold
it down was very emotional.
Where was the.
I was making the exact same point you
just made and I think the phrase I said,
you know,
if you've got a fence up and the animal
knows it's going to be fed and you just
hide in your little a bunker until you
know the wart hog or the lion shows up
knowing that the foods out and then you
take a puppet.
I said it's like it's like tennis
without a net.
Yes.
And that was what he took exception to.
You said it's very artificial.
Something very.
Any.
He agreed to it.
Yeah.
But then what was fascinating to me,
he was like,
had,
don't understand Africa.
Africa's fucked.
Yeah.
Africa is fucked.
I hate fucking elephants.
They don't eat the shitty push.
They always eat the tall trees.
And he goes on a rant about Africa is
fucked because we eat everything and we
kill everything.
And he sort of A.
I mean,
it's a great moment because he,
he in,
in the act of asking,
I don't think the question was that
cheeky was,
it was a fair question if he'd said
similar things to me about,
you know,
it's not,
is it real hunting?
Not Hunting,
but some people don't want a big flash
cards.
They wanted little shitty car,
you know,
that was his analogy.
And I said,
so when I say tends without net,
he would agree.
But he was,
he was kind of a little tweet.
Um,
I think his point though,
and his point was well taken and it's
set him up to go to deliver a very
impassioned monologue on many of the
problems that are very real.
You know,
in Africa.
Yeah,
most certainly.
I also found it incredibly fascinating
when you guys were feeding the lions
because I saw both sides.
They're on one side I saw like this is
so strange.
There's this in enclosed fenced in small
area where these lines are being bred
and they're hurling these calves,
these dead calves over the top of the
fence and these lions are eating these
calves.
And you were talking about how clean
they.
And he's like,
yeah,
they don't fight,
they have food.
Here it is right here.
I mean,
but the other thing he,
where he was saying it was like,
you think these things are your friend.
Like if I,
if I put you over there,
if you went through they would tear you
apart.
Like instantly,
like play with your clouds.
Yeah.
And play with your clothes.
I was fucking dark reminders.
The top part of your skull and the
roots.
They will eat everything and they will
play with your clothes.
Oh,
oh,
that's so fucked up
because it's so true.
When you're close to them,
it's like,
just to get close to that fence like I
probably 2015,
20 feet away.
But just to get it was something in you
that almost prevents you.
You're,
you know,
you're safe.
Like there's a fence.
He's not going to not defensive,
but you just physically,
there's something really embedded in the
psyche that tells you don't get any
closer like lines when you're up close
with them.
Then put that video back again a little
bit earlier.
When you see the,
uh,
when you throw in the,
um,
the cabs over the fence and you get to
see the looks in their eyes when they're
staring at you,
they're fucking so terrifying.
You don't need to put the volume on it
just to show the,
uh,
the images of it.
It's so terrifying.
That such an unbelievable.
And it's very different than the zoo.
The zoo is a different experience and I
don't know if it's because the animals
get that food slid to them underneath.
I mean,
it's a plate of food.
It's not an actual animal that they're
tearing apart.
I,
you know,
I don't know.
I think,
I don't know,
maybe they,
I think he kept his lines a bit hungrier
than the ones you find at the zoo.
I think maybe the zoo's get handled.
So they used to.
Human contact is part of that as well
and get handled.
Ever.
Zoos?
Yeah.
Well they can't,
you can't handle lions.
I'm mean you can,
if you train them.
I,
I did a story about,
um,
I mean,
uh,
you know,
siegfried and Roy,
I mean,
illustrates both sides of the equation.
I did another story.
There was a tigers,
right?
Targets,
but same thing face.
I think tigers are a little easier to
train them.
Lions,
I don't know about that,
but I know that I did a story called
America's most dangerous pets and it was
about people.
I don't know if this is true now,
but at the time it was true that there
are more tigers in captivity in Texas
than there are in the wild in India.
I mean,
there's thousands and thousands of
targets in America and um,
kept as pets in people's back yards and,
and,
and what I heard again and again was
like I will get into the cage and stroke
my tiger,
all my lion and cuddle it and that's
fine,
but I am not getting coast to my
monkeys.
The big fear was if you have a,
uh,
especially chimpanzees,
like they are,
don't go near the chimpanzees will fuck
you up.
They will rip your nose off,
rip your balls off and eat your face.
Yeah.
There's really
creepy about chimpanzee attacks too.
Is there to aware there they're too
intelligent.
Like they go after they can plan and
they know that you at some level they
know you are the one keeping them in
there.
But also I think they're intelligent
enough to become seriously neurotic and,
and dysfunctional from confinement.
Yes.
Whereas a tiger I think can,
I don't say it's a good life for a
tiger,
but a tiger doesn't necessarily become
dysfunctional from being pent up,
but a,
um,
a chimpanzee and is like a person in
need stimulation.
And not only that,
they also know to go cut the video,
they'll they also know to,
to go after your fingers that go off to
your balls.
Like they know what you want when you
want to keep your fingers.
So they bite your fingers off.
Like there's,
there's a certain intelligence to their
attack that's very disturbing as opposed
to like a tiger that just wants to kill
you.
Tiger will bite your.
I read a thing about a chimpanzee attack
at a zoo.
Like before I went out to do the story,
I was reading up on chimpanzee attacks
because I knew for the story to work,
I'd probably at some point have to
cuddle a chimpanzee or something like
that.
No,
it was making me nervous.
Like it was making me more nervous than
the idea of going into a prison cell or
a jail cell where you know,
you know,
there's enough rationality on the part
of the prisoner that he's not going to
attack me and bite my balls.
I mean he's not gonna shift me.
He,
he doesn't.
There's nothing in it for him.
You know?
Why would a inmate attack a journalist?
It doesn't make any sense,
but the chimpanzee is not going to think
like that.
And I read an account of a,
of a,
of an attack at a pr at a zoo,
a chimpanzee,
and the news local news turned up and
the chimpanzee ran over and bit the
cameraman's balls off.
Fuck.
And so then with that filming on my,
I just don't want to get in the cage
with a chimpanzee.
Was Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
No desire,
no desire and almost or fucking
terrifying if they're a violent man,
you know,
really crazy.
I it,
that was a small one.
I was like,
okay,
I'll cuddle this one.
We had a small one on news radio wants.
I'm a sitcom that I was on.
Oh yeah.
I remember news radio and he was a,
he was only two years old,
uh,
or,
excuse me,
less than two years old,
I believe he was a baby.
He was small.
He's got a little Zapper on him that
they give him electric shocks if he,
if he gets out of line.
The one I had a hold of was a little
smaller than that one and he climbed on
my back and fucking slap me on the back.
Just so strong.
He's so strong.
It was so small.
It was a small chimp,
a baby chimp,
but it was.
It's hard as a reference because we look
at a human that size and we look at a
chimp that size and we're going,
how fucking strong could it be like a
person,
like a full grown man on your back?
It was a baby,
but it had the strength of a man like
the way it moved me around.
That would make sense because the cliche
and it may be true.
That gets passed around.
Is that a full grown chimp?
It has the strength of seven men.
A 500 pound man is what I've heard.
Really?
Yeah.
See that I would pay to see like a UFC
guy.
It gets to full grown chimp will.
You would have to take the chimps main
weapon away,
which is its mouth,
you know,
put a mouth guard on it or something
that you would have to,
you know,
maybe men would,
would,
are they guys that would do that.
I'm sure there's an idiot out there that
would do almost anything that you came
with.
Those guys that you interviewed that
were progressors,
that are beaten each other with a
fucking barbwire.
I'm sure if you put a mask on one of
those dummies,
they would,
uh,
they would get in there and scrap with a
chimpanzee.
What.
But my point that I wanted to get back
to was the,
the,
the complex contradictory aspect of
those canned hunts and Africa.
You had a draw on a warthog you were
thinking about shooting it and you're
like,
I can't do this.
Yeah.
It didn't make.
It was,
didn't make any sense.
It wouldn't make any sense.
I mean,
I,
it was just the whole situation,
the idea that I'm going to take the life
of this animal just to indulge my own
sense of either what I think I need for
this program to work or my sense of
like,
oh,
I'm going to experience a experience
this to see what it feels like to take.
It didn't feel.
I just didn't feel an urge to do it.
Like I could have forced myself if you'd
put a gun to my head and said,
do it.
I would have done it of course course.
Or if you were starving to death if I
was starving,
but just to do it.
Oh,
I want to see what this feels like.
It didn't feel right.
You had,
you captured some of the more disturbing
aspects of hunting on that show because
those people were not doing it to
acquire meat at all and you see they're
trophy hunters.
They're trophy hunters and they weren't
doing it to acquire,
meet these people were doing it to to
have this to kill things and the video
of them being all joyful and happy when
they all got together and compared notes
after their individual hunts,
like several individual hunting parties
had went out,
came out like after the second day,
the first full day of hunting and then
we do an inventory of that.
Got like three zippers to Kudu,
a gazelle and it was an inventory of
kind and and you can sort of pick them
out like they're on a shopping list and
they know it's like 5,000
for a Kudu and it's 3000 for a Zipper
and it's $20,000
for a giraffe and $50,000
for a rhino and stuff I thought was
endangered is you can actually I guess
not endangered and you can pay enough.
I said,
I thought rhinos were endangered.
The guy who reinforced loop,
who,
who ran the place.
He said if you want one,
I can get you 20.
Yeah.
How fucking crazy is that?
Well,
there were $100,000
American,
which,
well,
that was what was going on in America.
There was a big issue recently all over
the news where there was a safari club
that had auction.
It was in Dallas and they'd auction off
a hunt for an endangered rhino and the
idea was that all this that they had
auctioned off would go.
There was a controversy about it that's
really nice and it was also
controversial because they were going to
have to do something with that rhino
because it was an old rhino and the old
rhinos will kill the young males.
They don't breed anymore,
but they're still.
They're very aggressive and territorial
and they'll destroy the breeding male
population.
They'll actually kill some of them and
so they had to remove them.
They had to remove this rhino in order
to keep the herd healthy.
Well,
this is the thing like if you want to
see the most grisly way more grizzly end
up studying than any kind of UFC a show
is,
what's your nature program with the
elephants getting lost in the mist and
getting attacked by like the level of
Gore.
It's like the like snuff films in a
sense.
Sure.
And so,
and I think one thing that Ted nugent
used to say when I was filming with him
was he objected to the disneyfication of
our experience of the natural world.
I think he's got an excellent point
there.
I mean,
he,
he's got an excellent point.
I mean,
think about the animals that we,
we take this,
this weird approach with like polar
bears or a,
the grizzly bears like Yogi.
We turned them into our friends.
You know,
polar bears are the weirdest ones.
polar bears are like Klondike bars.
What would you do for a Klondike Bar?
Or they're,
you know,
they're fucking drinking coke.
It's like,
it's this weird thing that we do with
the anthropomorph Promar,
phising,
these,
these really violent,
dangerous animals and some of the more
violent and more dangerous animals are
the ones that we,
we may come cuddly and cute and
bizarrely twist their nature up and
that's sometimes the only exposure that
people have to these animals for a long
time.
Like my children,
my children.
Uh,
I have a five year old and a three year
old that are just starting to understand
that the animals that they see in
cartoons are not real animals and that
real animals don't talk.
Real animals are very different.
I mean they,
they obviously see the five-year-old
especially sees that.
But I'm starting to explain to her that
if you ever see a bear like bears are
not to be approached and they're not
cuddly.
They're not your friends.
And there's a real big difference
between a bear that's trained like a
bear in a movie and a bear that you see
in the wild.
And so then like while their dogs in the
wild will not necessarily.
Sometimes there are.
And if you see a wild dog,
they are dangerous as well because the
only thing that's not dangerous about
dogs is that they are pets and that we
train them,
we get them used to people.
So there's this weird relationship with
animals that I have to sort of relate to
my children.
Then in doing so,
I start to review this bizarre thing
that we have this weird relationship
that we have to certain animals.
Absolutely.
I mean,
I don't think we really know how we feel
about a lot of animals and if we gave
half as much thought to the conditions
in industrial,
in factory farms in the way our chickens
and pigs are raised as we do to,
um,
you know,
endangered species.
I mean,
I'm more concerned about that in a way,
like the conditions of how our food is
created,
you know,
that um,
that pigs get fed their own minced up
piglets,
you know,
and,
uh,
all kinds of hideous practices.
Yeah.
It's,
uh,
it's very hideous.
There's a great deal of disgusting,
um,
practices that,
that are involved in agriculture and
farming and taking care of livestock.
And mad cow disease,
which,
you know,
England had a huge issue with which,
because they were being fed their own
their own offspring.
Yeah.
And brain tissue.
When an animal eats brain tissue,
that's the same disease that cannibals
developed.
Jacob fell disease,
which I think so,
yeah.
That's,
that is the way to say it.
Um,
I mean that is exactly what it is.
It's you,
you have these animals that are eating
brain tissue.
The same thing as humans that
cannibalize your,
like it's fucked.
It's fucking crazy.
It's really crazy.
It's a weird,
weird thing,
you know,
that we,
we,
we de-humanize and we also allow
ourselves to put money above humanity
about above ethics and morality.
And when it comes to animals,
it's more profitable to stuff them into
containers and where they can barely
move and just feed them their own
bodies,
you know,
and fatten them up and then sell them to
otherwise that body,
you know,
the,
the dead babies or whatever the fuck
they feed them goes to waste the parts
that we don't use for hamburger.
And what have you goes to waste.
And did you know,
I mean probably everyone knows this,
but you know,
in the,
in the world of egg raising chickens for
eggs,
uh,
all a male hatchlings get mashed up
within a couple of days of being born.
Yeah.
Did you know that?
And then,
so this is about,
I don't know what the figure was like 10
million baby chicks every year I went
straight into meat grinders.
Yeah,
it's fucking crazy.
It's crazy.
It's really weird and hard to deal with.
It's hard to wrap your head around the
fact that people can detach so much from
what they're doing to do something like
that.
It's uh,
it's just,
uh,
to,
to take a person who knows what's.
I mean we have,
if you,
if you did that in front of someone who
you cared about,
you valued their opinion and you know,
you started feeding these,
these chickens a torn up chickens.
He started giving a cow,
a cow brains and cow meat,
you know,
and,
and mashing them up and feeding them to
each other.
Like someone will go,
what the fuck are you doing,
man?
Why are you doing that?
Cows don't eat cows like,
what are you doing,
man?
Ah,
make us more money.
Oh Man.
He really.
That's how you.
That's how you're going to be.
You're going to maximize your bottom
line.
They're going to feed them cow brains
and they see the cows all shaky and
fucked up because their neurological
system is rejecting this.
This notion there,
they're rejecting the this practice and
they're,
you know,
the nature actually has a whole system
set in place to,
to sort of discouraged cannibalism and
that's really what it is mean.
You cannibalize in nature fucks your
immune,
your nervous system.
It's crazy.
Did you read about.
Anyway,
what I wanted to ask you about news
radio though,
because you may not know this,
but when I started out in a trying to
break into TV,
my f,
my first objective before I had my own
show was to write for news radio and
actually wrote a spec script and sent it
to Paul Simms.
Ha Ha,
that's no kidding.
That's amazing.
You've got a meeting on the back of the
script and it was sunset gower lot.
Ah,
yeah.
You remember where we were taping that
and um,
in the end I went off to do my own
thing.
Um,
but,
uh,
I just thought it was funny,
like all that was my dream was to back
in the Phil Hartman days.
Wow.
That's incredible,
man.
That's incredible.
Do you keep up with those guys at all?
Occasionally,
or just,
uh,
just to see.
He was communicating with someone who
worked on the crew last night.
We were emailing each other back and
forth.
Do you know what Sims is up to?
I don't know.
I think he's working on boardwalk
empire.
That's why I had her as a writer,
is writing on boardwalk empire.
He's such a fascinating guy.
He's brilliant,
brilliant guy.
But just curiosity.
He was a real eccentric.
He'd come off.
So He'd worked at spy where I'd worked
the magazine and,
and people kept saying that I looked
like him and I and I,
I fixated on it and I thought,
wow.
He and everyone said,
oh,
he was so funny and he didn't stay very
long,
but he was so talented and he went on to
do letterman and then from letterman he
went to Larry Sanders and uh,
Larry Sanders at that time was viewed as
sort of the pinnacle of kind of smart,
funny TV.
And I thought,
wow,
if I could get on Larry Sanders,
that would be amazing as a writer.
And then he went and started his own
show,
which was news radio.
And I thought so,
well maybe that'll be a smart,
funny show as well.
That's what I should do.
So I wrote a script to winter,
but I remember going along there and,
and all the windows were blacked out
with,
with a tin foil,
with aluminum exit.
Come along for a meeting.
I said,
what time?
He said,
well normally I get in around six in the
evening.
I thought,
Whoa,
CCS time,
people go home,
isn't it?
So I went along and he was hanging out
with a,
a,
like a,
there was a,
I'm a runner or pa or something called
spider,
spider.
And he's like,
what kind of music do you like?
And I'm like,
if this is this,
the interview,
like he's asking me what kind of music
and then I just,
I thought it was just weird,
like there was.
So there was no sense of night or day.
No natural light windows all blocked
out.
He's hanging with spider.
I just thought this is kind of the
spider.
I was getting kind of slight,
very faint cult vibes.
I was like,
there's a little lag going on.
But in a good
they um,
they would work all night.
And those were his hours.
I.
Yeah.
Well he knew everyone had to fit in
around that.
Yes.
If you had a family or something like
that,
you were fucked because they would do a
writing.
But that didn't affect you,
right?
No,
it didn't affect us at all.
The actors.
Well there's sort of union rules for
actors.
They couldn't make us start work at 2:00
in the morning feed to be like,
you were a writer.
Then you turn on.
He's like,
yeah,
the,
that we work from six in the evening
till four in the morning.
And we,
uh,
we like to hang out with spider and we
basically,
we all play Yahtzee for a couple of
hours and then we worked for half.
I mean,
it wasn't literally that,
but it was Kinda like,
oh my God,
it's like that episode of the twilight
zone where the kid is in charge of the
family
and they're all like,
oh,
well he had a method,
his madness and the message of Bhutan
this,
you're very talented.
But the method to his madness was that
you get silly when you are a sleep
deficit mode when you're really,
you're really late and tired.
And oftentimes that's when the most
preposterous ideas are allowed to come.
That was his theory.
Well that was the practice.
I mean it really did work.
He didn't,
but it was that way.
In other words,
did he articulate that or was that he
oftenly articulated it.
Yeah.
So it was.
But it's Kinda like Vanna earhart saying
like,
after you stayed awake for 48 hours in,
peed your pants,
then you have an enlightenment
experience.
Well,
sort of.
But maybe there's another way of doing
it.
They were definitely,
in a lot of ways,
there were definitely lazy.
Can I tell you,
my theory is that like if you haven't
made a creative breakthrough by 6:00
in the evening,
then hey,
why don't you go home and have a good
night's sleep and try again the next
morning?
Well,
I think they liked the idea of working
under the
wire as well.
I think they would oftentimes deliver
the script for the run through,
like we had to run through in the
morning or a table read.
Um,
so if the table.
It was Monday morning,
Sunday night,
they would still be working.
If we had to be at the table read at
9:00
AM,
they will be writing at 8:00
AM.
Like sometimes we would get,
we would,
we'd go to rehearse,
we'd have no table read and we would
wind up rehearsing the first,
uh,
the first,
like five pages.
That's all they had.
I mean,
we wouldn't have a full script.
We'd have five pages.
And then while we were rehearsing,
you know,
Josh Lee would come stumbling down
barefoot.
His hair would be all fucked up,
be smoking a cigarette.
Uh,
here's,
um,
here's the next 20 pages and you know,
the next x amount of pages and we would
go over that and then the next day they
would.
But it always came together as a really
solid
theory.
Like Michael Moore was a little like
that too.
It was the feeling that unless your guts
are on the floor,
you know,
then there's a chance you might have
been able to improve it with more work.
Do you know what I mean?
Like stay late and worry and worry and
worry and stay late and work on the
weekends until you just despair and you
just think I can't give anything more to
the process.
Well,
everybody has their own method,
you know,
as far as the creative process.
And I'm
not saying that their method was the
best,
but it was fun for them and part of what
the young family,
they're all single.
There's a few guys that were family guys
that had real issues and wound up
leaving,
but they were,
they were having fun and that having fun
led them to be funnier.
And I think whether or not it was a
consequence of their laziness,
that it was so good,
or whether it was a,
there was a method to their madness.
I mean you would really have to take
that up with Paul and he would have to
really soul search to find the actual
correct answer.
But it worked.
It really worked.
And it was an amazing cost as well.
Like it was you,
Stephen Root,
who I always thought was super back to
very,
very awesome actor,
Dave Foley,
to one of the secret producers of that
show.
I mean,
I've had dave on the podcast before and
I'd love that guy to death.
He's so fucking talented.
And if you ever want to hear one of the
worst divorce stories of all time,
listen to the podcast with him on and
just what kind of a nightmare divorce
can be ruined his life.
Wow.
I'm doing.
I'm researching a story at the moment
about divorce.
Oh God.
Listen to the podcast with Dave Foley
because Canada has some wacky laws.
Oh,
well,
I want to do it in La.
That does it.
Well.
He lives in La now,
but when he got divorced in Canada or
here?
Yes,
Canada.
Really?
Yeah.
I was married in Canada and Canada has
some crazy laws where the wife has
access to the bank account for a full
year,
a while you're getting divorced,
you're not allowed to get divorced until
you're separated for a year or at the
time this was the and they also have
like insane laws as far as like the
amount of child support you're supposed
to pay.
His child support was based on the
highest income he had ever made in his
life and unbelievably unrealistic.
Some.
It was the height of his career when he
was on news radio,
so he's making an extraordinary amount
of money and that that was what his
child support was based on,
so he had to pay that for the 18 years.
His children were alive and it was all
going to his wife and his wife was
redecorating the fucking house and begin
to hate her.
Oh yeah.
Oh God.
Yeah.
So don't you like that?
I just love that whole dynamic is very
strange.
Love someone.
You love them so much.
You're willing to sign a legal contract
with them and then they become your
sworn enemy,
and of course obviously I've dealt with
that with Phil Hartman in his wife or
his wife,
shot him in his sleep and then there was
still together though they had when they
were getting broken up,
but they were living together but
separated.
They were living together,
but he was leaving.
He was breakup.
He,
they had gone through some.
They had broken up and you know,
he had,
he had a boat and slept in his boat for
a while and then came back to her and
wanted to keep the family together and
was trying hard to kids.
Yes,
yes.
Very.
So,
you know,
when people just are committed in that
sort of a situation where they have to
stay or if they do stay,
it's devastating to their lifestyle,
devastating to their emotional state.
You know,
it's,
it's very troubling and very scary when
they started attacking each other as
well.
When they know they go after each
other to try to hurt that person.
Did you get on with Andy Dick?
I got on occasionally with Andy.
We had a love hate sort of a situation.
He to this day maintains.
It was all my fault.
He was so angry.
You're always angry.
White Guy was pulling his dick out in
front of me and jerking off my trailer.
When my girlfriend was in there,
he would show up,
so fucked up.
He couldn't read the script and he would
forget his kid and leave them on set,
but on the other hand,
incredibly talented.
Very funny,
funny.
I had more laughs like rehearsing scenes
with that guy and doing scenes in fact
guy than anybody in my life.
He's an unbelievably talented guy.
Deep down inside.
He's a sweet guy,
but he's very troubled.
He doesn't even remember his childhood,
like he's missing like up until like,
like before,
like age seven or something like that.
He literally doesn't remember it.
He was adopted.
Locked it out.
Yes.
He's had some.
He had some hard times,
you know,
I mean,
you don't create a guy like Andy Dick
because everything turns out perfect.
You know,
he's the product of a lot of angst and a
lot of issues and a lot of what have
you.
But the,
you know,
looking at the glass half full,
he's a brilliant guy,
brilliant,
brilliant comedic actor and it disturbs
me when I see him go off and,
you know,
he was sober when he did my podcast,
we talked about it and you know,
but then six months later he was
arrested for doing this and that and
getting crazy and doing drugs and you
know,
he's just a real,
constantly troubled guy for a variety of
reasons,
but at his best,
one of the most brilliant comic actors
ever.
I think it was fucking hilarious.
So funny in that that show news radio
just really figured out how to utilize
him.
Very much so.
And we were very different people back
there.
I was very different.
I was much younger,
stupider,
angry or version of who I am now.
And I wasn't very tolerant of people
like Andy.
It's easier for me to snap at.
Um,
and you know,
I,
I'm sure I would handle him much
different now if we ever did,
if we will,
you know,
if I was thrusted in that same situation
with my current personality.
But that said,
you know,
brilliant.
Brilliant.
Is that show still on in syndication?
Does that still.
Oh,
you just don't get money from it.
I'm not sure.
It's not much.
I'm sure it was one of those things,
the initial payment,
you get a chunk and then it gets less
over time.
It's one of those things.
Um,
I reached out a little bit too,
Andy Dick last year because we were,
we were trying to make a bunch of shows
that we'll all set in la since I was
living here.
The idea was,
you know,
let's do sort of La stories and one of
them was going to be standup comedians
and,
and we were trying to find intriguing
guys,
your guys who sort of represented
something about.
I couldn't quite figure out what it was,
but I thought it was something to do
with the pressure on someone who's who's
their own producer,
their own writer,
their own performer and whose,
whose performance is the performance of
themselves or a version of themselves
that and that that entailed a certain
kind of vulnerability and a kind of high
stakes professional maneuver that you go
on stage and it's just you and a crowd
of people and whether you might face
heckling and whatnot.
So that was how I formulated it in my
head and also that you might be
cannibalizing your own life to some
extent to a material and whether that
imposed a certain set of strains and
whether being funny itself came from
some angst or something in your
background.
Anyway,
so that was how I forgot,
but it was very hard for us to kind of
find the right people.
So it's sort of.
We reached out to Andy and a few other
people and he always said like,
I really want to film with you.
Oh yeah,
that's perfect.
I'd love to do something.
Light that out.
You can meet me after the show and then
he'd never show up or we were just not
the best example.
You would want to get a guy that's
actually a writer.
It actually does write a lot and perform
a lot,
but he doesn't build burger would be
good.
But Andy does his own material,
right?
Yeah,
I'm sure.
But you know,
you want to call it comedy,
right?
That was the thing like it wasn't.
Is it,
is it,
is it actually comedy?
That's the mean.
It's funny sometimes,
but it's also out there and kind of what
just sort of blurts well sometimes and
sometimes he prepares things and you
know,
I mean,
but I think he's a very,
what I'm trying to say without.
I'm not trying to dis him,
I'm just saying that his style,
if you were on it to find a standup
comedian,
you wouldn't necessarily categorize him
as a standup comedian.
You would categorize him as a performer
who occasionally works in standup comedy
clubs.
So that's a good way of,
of looking at it.
And that may have been one of the.
But you know,
in the,
in our sort of a keenness to eagerness
to get intriguing people,
w we perhaps stretched the categories a
bit in a way that wasn't helpful and
that may have been a clue that it wasn't
quite the right story.
Or do you think there is a good
documentary to be made?
It felt like when I was doing it,
it felt like the world was not.
Dis,
was too close to my own world in an odd
way.
Um,
well there's certainly something to
describing standup comedy mean it's sort
of kind of has been done in a way,
in some ways I guess has it.
I am comic.
I did,
I watched them all now they didn't get
it.
I mean,
they're all,
they've all got their moments,
but it's almost like,
um,
what about Jerry Seinfeld's documented
that best one?
Yeah,
that was a really good one.
He was really open about the creative
process showed well,
I think one was kind of used there to
make Jerry look a lot more likable.
I mean,
there's a reason why they chose Origami
in the middle of like his struggle and
angst.
You know,
one,
I know very little,
very little,
you know him from that and I've had a
few,
hi,
how are you doing in real life?
But I almost felt like he was kind of
thrust into that situation.
He seems like quite troubled in that
documentary and it's almost like they're
putting them in there to make Jerry
look,
you know,
like in comparison to,
to Jerry,
you know,
he's fucking crazy and it makes Gerry,
Luke,
luke,
this really likable,
affable,
sort of together do right.
Well not,
not that I don't think Jerry is,
but I think I just found it weird that
they would choose that guy.
Like why would they choose that guy out
of all the comedians in New York City
who was like,
he liked a certain level of self
knowledge.
Yes.
Which I think made him a spectacle.
A spectacles and excellent way of
putting it.
Yeah.
He,
uh,
yeah,
he's fucked in that documentary least.
I don't know,
you know,
but it's just,
comedy is a tricky thing,
man.
You know,
it's um,
a very bizarre art form where you,
there's so many different types of
comedy.
There's so many different styles of
comedy,
there's so many different ways you can
go about it and you're the only one who
really knows your best way and you have
to find it.
And the only way you find it,
it's in front of an audience,
one of the few art forms that you
require other people's input.
You require them to be there while
you're creating it.
You write on your own.
I write all my stuff on either I write,
either I have an idea and I write down
notes or actually physically sit in
front of the keyboard and I write long
form and then cherry pick ideas out of
those long forms and introduce it.
But they don't.
It doesn't really come alive unless you
do it in front of an audience.
If I approached you,
I don't think we did because I'd
remember,
but if I had approached you to be in the
documentary,
what,
what would've been your thought process?
That it would probably be intrusive?
That didn't really.
I probably wouldn't be interested.
I would be the plus side of it wouldn't,
it would seem like I would have to pay
attention to all this and there's
something about observing something and
filming something and recording
something which changes the nature of
the thing itself.
And I think that,
uh,
in standup comedy,
what's really important to me when I'm
creating it especially is just getting
it right is like working on it and
getting it right.
I wouldn't want cameras there and
observing the whole process of it.
Then I would have to think about that as
me.
And where do you write when you write?
I write at home.
So if it's on the road,
which I know it sounds like we're not
going to,
but if I was saying like,
Joe,
where do you write this is your room?
Can we see a notebook,
a re read?
Can you read out some of the.
I wouldn't do that.
No,
I'm just sort of tell you about what my
processes.
But I wouldn't want and I don't even
like people like filming things at my
shows and I'm working on shit because I
don't want to getting on Youtube or
whatever.
It's not done.
It's like,
you know,
it's a sketch and then if,
if that gets on youtube and then someone
sees it like three months later and it's
better,
they still know where it's going.
Like part of comedy is you want new
stuff.
When you go to see a band,
you go to see the rolling stones.
Do you want to hear new rollingstone
songs?
Fuck No.
You want to hear the classics?
You want to hear sympathy for the devil.
You want to hear satisfaction.
You want to hear the songs you already
know that you can relate to.
Comedy is the exact opposite.
You want to always hear new stuff.
Like I have a standup comedy special
that premiered on comedy central Friday
night and one of the points that I've
made in advertising,
all these current shows that I'm doing
is it's all new material.
Like if you saw the thing from Saturday
to Saturday night or Friday night that
aired.
If you go see me live next week,
you're not gonna see any of that
material.
The materials done,
it's gone,
throw it away.
It's filmed,
it's out there and the Internet and the
ether and comedy central and it's there
forever.
But what I do on stage now,
Amanda,
new stuff.
So I don't,
I don't want my process to be a part of
what's like record because it's not done
like get it,
you know,
and that's why we didn't do it in the
end because I,
that's a very understandable reaction.
I don't know,
don't see,
we would have got that across the board,
but I think you could describe the
process of.
I would describe it,
but it's boring.
That's not,
that's not a TV.
It's not something I could,
I could document and know.
And then.
So we figured it's too much work.
Like why?
Um,
it takes away from the finished product.
Yeah.
I think when you know the whole process
behind it,
it's,
I mean,
for someone who's like a comedy nerd or
a Dork or.
But I say that in all loving terms,
like there's comedy nerds that like come
to like dozens and dozens and dozens of
shows every month and they'll,
they'll have seen me three or four times
in a period of three or four months.
I've had people come up to me and say,
I love watching the material grow.
I think it's amazing watching you add
new bits to it or come up with new
things.
And I'm always uncomfortable about that
because then the last thing you want to
do is see someone in the front row two
nights in a row like that happens.
Like you'll see someone like you'll be
in Portland for the weekend and you see
a person in the front row Friday and
then their Saturday to you like,
shit,
this guy knows all my fucking jokes that
you know they know all the set.
So you feel artificial when you're
setting up the bits.
You would like people to see your bits
when there is close to done as possible.
When there close to the finished form as
possible.
That way you're going to get.
They're going to get the best show.
You have the best economy of words,
you have the best manipulation of
language,
the best setup segues,
all that stuff has been fleshed out.
It's been worked out on stage,
countless hours,
examining notes,
listening to recordings,
and then performing.
That's what you want.
You want people to get the show at its
best,
you know,
and which is why when someone releases a
special like right after the release of
special,
it's oftentimes not the best time to go
see them because the material is like
fucking scattered and they're trying to
put it all together and then you see the
same person six months later and it's
just fucking just boom,
boom,
boom.
It all comes together,
you know,
so it's a long sort of a brutal process
but exciting,
you know,
it's challenging and you know,
and it's got a lot of downs to it,
but the ops are awesome when it's done
in a nutshell,
I feel like we've made the documentary.
That was great.
I want to talk to you about scientology.
Okay.
What is the,
the issue that you're having in trying
to pursue this and what,
what exactly is the reaction to people
in the scientology community now?
Because it seems like the Internet has
sort of exposed that religion in a way
that it before it was always like,
what scientology me,
what is this?
But now the internet is sort of all the
tom cruise recruitment videos have been
released and all the craziness is out
and the people like that have wrote
going clear that book.
I'm reading that right now.
I'm Lawrence Wright's book.
Uh,
the,
the whole religion would call it a
religion.
Where the fuck it is.
The whole movement seems to be in a very
state of flux right now.
Uh,
I think that's probably true at the same
time,
I think for the,
for,
for students of a,
I guess religious,
a oddity or,
or,
you know,
new religions or whatever,
whatever you want to call it,
you know,
it's known and it's out there in your
reading Lawrence,
right?
I read that Lawrence.
Right.
But there's a vast,
you know,
there's a vast,
massive kind of main street people for
whom they still all they know is,
it's that thing that Tom Cruise is
involved in it,
it's kind of weird,
you know,
and they.
And so they don't know.
So I think there's a huge.
So I think step one for a lot of people
are like,
what is it,
you know,
it's something to do with Ufo shows and
Tom Cruise and John Travolta and maybe
his sexuality,
but beyond that,
they don't know.
So,
so part of it is,
is trying to convey what it actually is.
I mean,
I've been studying in the area for,
you know,
like reading all the books for about 15,
20 years before Lawrence Wright's.
There was one by Janet reitman called
inside scientology.
There's a whole laundry list of books
about scientology.
I still don't quite get what it is to
you.
Well,
I do in a sense,
what is it,
what's it called?
Unquestionably.
But they don't,
that's fine.
But it was created by a science fiction
writer.
Okay.
But say,
say that's true still,
like there's lots of cults out there.
Uh,
what,
beyond that,
what is it,
what do they,
how do they practice,
how they practice?
Meaning what,
like what do they like?
We know with Catholics,
they go to church,
they kept confession,
they eat crackers and,
and it's the,
the body of,
of,
of Jesus Christ rise and um,
and,
and they believe in the pope and,
and you know,
we know roughly what their sacrament is
and they read the Bible and they believe
in Jesus and,
and so and so.
So,
so what is it with scientology?
Um,
that's a good question.
I don't know,
like if they have ceremonies,
if they,
I think when you look at that Tom cruise
recruitment video,
which is fucking fantastic,
you know,
when he's standing there,
if you've
seen the one where they give them a
metal.
Yes,
which is fucking,
just so rich.
It's a giant metal,
many times larger than an Olympic gold
medal.
Uh,
uh,
he's wearing this metal and he's
standing there in front of a fucking.
It's called the freedom middle of valor.
Hm.
And um,
he's standing in front of all those
people and he's such a charismatic
person.
There it is right there.
Oh,
Jesus Louisa's.
We'll look at that fucking thing.
Come on.
Just the,
the lack of like understanding how you
come across that would allow you to wear
that,
the lack of objectivity that it will
allow you to put that on and,
and,
and be able to do this fingertips down
thing on the,
uh,
on the desk.
Like you're making a very important
point while you're wearing a fucking
Frisbee,
a gold frisbee around your neck.
It's almost like he's trying to convince
himself by tricking all these people.
I think there's something to that.
There's something to,
if you can get a thousand people to
cheer at these words that you're saying
and you know,
no matter how fucking crazy they are,
if you can get all these people to
believe you and listen to you,
it sort of validates that maybe you're
not fucked up because you're in with all
these other people that have agreed in
fetuses and fucking,
you know,
all the other wacky shit that they
believe.
There's something to that where he's
putting on this massive performance,
not just for them but for himself as
well.
I mean,
to me it,
it,
it's a bit like the Oscars,
like that's when I was watching the
Oscars last night.
I was like,
wow,
it's like a scientology event,
you know,
it's that level of,
um,
I think that's,
that's the,
that's the kind of the,
the performance or the or the light.
That's the semiotics of it,
you know,
the signifier they're trying to send a
message of grand,
big golden.
Yeah.
Important.
You know,
like both Oscars and the freedom,
you know,
he's wearing around his neck,
but like is it any more silly than
having a little gold man?
No.
My friend Greg Fitzsimmons put posted
something on twitter and I retweeted it.
He said,
I hope the Oscars get beamed to the
troops so they could see all the people
get rewarded for brave and courageous
work.
This year was such a great tweet and
especially if you know,
Greg is a brilliant comedian himself,
but it's such a great tweet because it's
so fucking right on.
It's so pompous and self rewarding and
self aggrandizing and so ridiculous or
wearing suits with fucking special ties
and you know,
a formal attire and it's
it and,
and you know,
not
to say they shouldn't be.
I mean but,
but,
but my,
my point is though is that so like with
Tom Cruise,
okay.
He's got his fingers down but in the
end,
so why pick on,
on TC and scientology but,
but,
but we're letting the Oscars know.
We'll say that we'll give that a pass
but we can't have guys wearing golden
little golden ones around their neck
that they have to be little men.
You know what I mean?
Oh sure.
Well,
and also why is it okay?
Why is it okay to pick on Tom Cruise?
But it's not okay to pick on Jewish
people with curls and there bobbing up
and down.
And that's their religion.
That's their,
their traditions.
This is just a tradition where it's not
a real religion in our eyes.
We know the guy who wrote it.
Right.
Good point.
That's the thing that people have
part of I think,
and I think what I would try and do in
making a documentary about is to try and
see past a lot of the things that people
find weird or ludicrous about it,
you know,
which is,
the fact that they have big glitzy
scientology events and get to the core
of what it is.
Well it is craziness is what it is,
is nothing.
You can't get to the core of it.
The core of it is established sort of
pattern of thoughts that allow people
who are not normal to feel normal,
allow people that are troubled,
allow people that are searching for some
sort of a structure.
TC is normal.
I do not think he's doing based on what.
Well,
based on the fact that he's so fucking
famous.
It's impossible to be.
But he was in it before he was famous.
Yes.
And,
and it helps the company know about
that.
I believe he got in at when he was still
running
pretty early on and I think,
I think jt got in it,
Shane in the Carter years maybe,
I don't know,
but very early.
There's also the ambiguous sexuality
aspect of it.
There's the,
the rumors of homosexuality that are
attached to a famous male scientologists
that they shield them,
you know,
and especially the,
the,
the John Travolta thing.
Do you got to get out of here pretty
soon where it's almost 3:00.
We're almost wrapped up anyway.
I think there's,
there's a lot of weirdness going on and
there's also the people that have you
talked to people that have done
expositions on scientology and what they
say is that during the auditing process,
when they audit you,
meaning when you go over past life
experiences that are quite troubling.
You repeat them over and over again
until they lose their meaning.
Like the same thing as like if you say
fuck around someone who never says fuck
that,
like Oh say fuck around a priest or you
know,
act like it's some horrible thing that
you've done.
We say fuck around your friends.
You don't even,
it doesn't even register.
It's like,
oh,
this fucking thing.
It's another word.
It just,
it has no power because it's so used so
much,
and I think maybe that's a bad analogy,
but in a sense it works because what
they're doing is repeating the stories
over and over and over and over and over
again until they lose their meaning.
But in the process,
they're recording all this shit.
So they have all this dirt on you.
They have all these crazy stories.
If you're going through the process
earnestly,
you're telling them all the secrets of
your life,
all the crazy gay orgies,
you'd been a part of all the,
the,
the nutty fucking cocaine binges,
whatever the fuck you've done that
you're ashamed of
and you think that,
that.
Does that get released?
The point you decide to leave?
You think
it's a good question.
I don't know.
Um,
I know
they,
uh,
they are adamant that,
that is held under a priest,
penitent bond of confidentiality.
Of course they are,
but I mean the,
no,
what's the mother of all rumors?
The greatest rumor of all time.
Yes,
thank you.
Richard Gere.
Do you know when that rumor was
released?
Oh,
when Richard Gere left scientology.
I didn't know he was in scientology.
He dabbled.
Are you?
Are you,
are you serious?
Yes.
He dabbled in scientology and that,
that rumor was released when the Tom
Cruise or the John Travolta massage
therapy stories were released.
Allegedly that's when John Travolta was
having issues with scientology.
So way to keep you under wraps.
This is the rumors,
obviously completely unsubstantiated.
I'm talking out of my ass 100 percent,
but that makes sense,
doesn't it?
I mean if you,
if you have a powerful organization that
gets a certain percentage of the amount
of money that you make every year and
they have a lot of crazy shit on you,
you'd like to go and get massages and
talk these guys into Latin.
You fuck them.
I mean that would think that would be
something that,
you know,
maybe if you were going to leave and
take all that money away,
they might,
uh,
they might bring,
you know,
assuming they have an organization
it any damaging.
Um,
confidence is about Leah Remini as far
as I know.
Well,
Leah Remini had that situation where she
was saying that the leader of
scientology,
his wife was missing Shelly miscavige.
Yeah.
What's the story there?
Well,
a lear.
Is it pronounced remedy?
Remedy.
She alleged that David Miscavige,
his wife,
who hasn't been publicly photographed
allegedly for a number of years,
maybe even five or 10 years,
uh,
was being held captive or had been
disappeared in some way.
And,
and that she'd had,
she'd been at Tom Cruise's wedding to,
um,
who would it have been at that point?
Katie Holmes in Italy,
I think and said,
Here's David miscavige with shelly.
Why aren't you here with your wife?
And it became a scandal within
scientology.
People felt it was disrespectful to the
head Honcho David miscavige to be asking
where his wife was so that she got into
trouble.
And then she left.
And then after she left,
initiated a police inquiries.
She made it.
She filed a missing persons report.
But then the police after a couple of
days said,
no,
she's not missing.
So I guess she's not missing.
The fact is she must be in a retreat
somewhere somewhere.
I think there's people who know know
where she is,
like scientology watchers,
say there's a certain church
headquarters up in the hills.
I can't read it somewhere in southern
California and that's where she's
living.
She,
maybe she just doesn't want to be
published or maybe she just wants to
live on her own.
Like without going public,
you know,
I think that's more likely than the idea
that she's being held against her will.
Yeah.
Um,
could be.
I don't know,
but I think this kind of goes back to
the,
a Swami g's I what his name was that the
guy who was the supposed physicist who's
living with Swami Gee.
Yeah.
I think people love being a part of a
group.
Whether the group makes sense or doesn't
make sense.
I think people,
they find comfort in that and they also
get addicted to being a part of a group.
And then when you're a part of something
as powerful scientology,
especially when you look at all the
examples of people who are
scientologists who are greatly
successful.
My old neighbor was a scientologist and
we had this really weird revelation when
it came out where he and I were talking,
he was talking about buying a piece of
land in our neighborhood and said he
couldn't buy it right now because his
wife was going clear and I said,
uh,
what are you talking about?
Like,
what does that mean,
you know?
And he said,
well,
we're scientologist and uh,
my wife is going to go clear and it cost
$50,000.
And I was like,
this is a guy who was a contractor.
He builds buildings,
you know,
he's not a wealthy man,
he does.
He does fairly well,
but I mean $50,000
is a giant chunk of his income.
And he was talking about how his wife is
going to be no longer affected by
outside influence and they buy going
clear.
It eliminates all the negative impact of
people talking shit about you or you
know,
fucking traffic,
anything,
nothing was going to get in anymore.
She was clear of all that stuff that she
was going to be removed from.
And I was like,
are you clear?
It's like the reactive mind is removed
so you can make decisions without any
interference from your reactive mind.
Yeah.
What the fuck,
I guess.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean,
but this poor guy was going to spend
$50,000
on this and he had this sort of glassy
eyed thing about,
um,
this sort of last thing.
I think being a part of a group,
we have these ancestral instincts that I
think are passed down from the time
where it was very important to be a part
of a tribe to stay alive if you're by
yourself and the hunter and gatherer
times is very difficult to get enough
food to stay alive.
It was very hard and I think we have
this bond with being a part of a group,
whether it's fucking Mac users,
man.
I mean people that love Mac,
they hate pc users.
People that hate that loved pc.
They hate Mac.
They get in these groups,
the Protestants versus the Catholics,
you know,
there's Chevy versus Ford.
People are weird that we have these
weird desires to be a part of groups.
And I think someone like the Westboro
Baptist Church,
or someone likes Swami g's disciples or
someone like scientology,
part of the appeal of that is being in a
group and then when you have
scientology,
I'm not too familiar with what
scientology does do.
That's beneficial,
but you look at a guy like Tom Cruise,
sexual stuff aside,
he's talking about a tremendously
successful person who looks great.
He's fucking 50 and he looks amazing.
I mean,
he's in great health.
He seems like really optimistic all the
time and very,
very charismatic,
very appealing to be a part of a group
that that guy is in.
If he is benefiting from scientology and
from the principles of scientology,
surely it can't all be wrong.
Surely it can't all be bad.
Let's say Louis,
you're awesome,
man.
You got to get out of here and this is.
I think we're done anyway.
This is.
We're running a three hours in.
We turn into a Pumpkin is three hours
the normal length?
Yes.
Oh my goodness.
Crazy,
right?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Get edited.
Nope.
Not only that,
it's live and people listened to the
whole thing.
Sometimes.
Sometimes they listened to five minutes
and then go fucking bullshit liberal
nonsense park these people.
There's that too.
Thank you for having me on.
It was really fun.
I would love to do it again.
If you ever have anything that you're
promoting,
please don't hesitate.
We have you in an,
you know,
one of the reasons I came with.
Well,
there were two reasons,
but,
uh,
hundreds of reasons,
but one was,
I was saying before I came on,
there was a couple of guys outside
trader Joe's and they were,
they were like,
you've got your own cult.
They were brainwashed,
Mooney's,
uh,
advocating on your behalf saying,
I gotta go,
I love your stuff.
I said,
how have you seen it on Youtube?
how did you find out about Joe Rogan was
talking about it.
I said,
oh,
really?
You listen to the show Joe Rogan
podcast.
I hear how it's so awesome you said
there's so much information.
So I,
I,
um,
I was like,
well he's obviously got a lot of pull
out there and um,
and,
and just more generally like it's just,
I love getting feedback from people
who've seen me on youtube button,
so I'm trying to kind of put the word
out that,
you know,
I think it's illegal actually.
I don't think people are supposed to
have it up there,
but I've,
I'm okay with it.
Why is it illegal?
Because I think it's ABC.
Technically,
BBC also they get it though.
They'll be like,
that's the whole thing.
I don't think they could get it
otherwise it on Netflix or only in the
UK.
It's on Netflix and on different around
the world on different channels,
but the BBC is trying to monetize it so
they want to,
they want to retain rights and keep
selling it.
But as far as I'm concerned,
it gets a lot of hits on Youtube,
but it's nice to go for you for people
to see it.
Yeah.
I mean it puts no money in my pocket,
but I'm fine with it.
Well you've done some brilliant work,
really fascinating stuff.
I've enjoyed it.
I've gotten countless hours of
entertainment out of your programming I
think so.
I really appreciate having you on.
It was really enjoyable.
Thank you very much.
See you next.
What do you got coming up that people
could say?
Is there anything that
three shows going out in Britain,
new ones going up the end of March and
so they'll probably be put up quite soon
and it's the thing I was telling about
La Stories.
There's the first one is about strain,
abandoned dogs and our attempts to
rehabilitate them using a controversial
dog therapy,
you know,
it's like turning criminal dogs and
bringing them,
rescuing them,
bringing him into middle class homes and
then sometimes they attack the new
owners and then thousands of them are
killed every year in the shelters in La
as a huge stray and neglected dog
problem in La.
Second one is about the,
the hospitals where people are sort of
under pressure to keep trying new,
like they're close to possibly dying,
but there's a new experimental therapy
and they have the insurance to pay for
it and it's this weird 21st century
conundrum of when do I stop and say
like,
I just want to have a peaceful death.
When am I allowed to say like,
I don't want to try any more chemo or
these on BBC America?
Uh,
no,
they're on the UK,
BBC,
normal BBC and the third one is about
sex offenders living down in south la,
especially around torrance who live in
these hostels with a electronic
bracelets,
heavily monitored lives and the whole,
the strangeness of having done something
so terrible,
you know,
they've abused their own children or
some of them are rapists and so on.
And then they've done,
you know,
whatever.
We're 10 years in prison and they've
come out and they're on parole.
And to what extent,
if any,
you know,
do we give people a second chance?
I give her.
They're out.
We're going to live.
We are living alongside them,
you know,
more or less with certain restrictions.
What do we,
how do we relate to those guys?
Well,
those are three fascinating subjects,
so I'm just saying that I can't wait to
watch those shows.
Really big fan man.
Really appreciate you coming on.
Thank you very much.
All right folks.
You could follow Louis on twitter.
It's Louis Elo U I s through t h e r o u
x.
follow him on twitter and a thank you to
everybody.
Thanks to everybody tuning in.
Thanks to all the Nice people out there
that send me kind tweets and facebook
messages and all that good stuff and
come to shows and I just can't say
enough about so many positive people I
run into because of the show.
Thank you all.
Thanks to a squarespace.
Go to squarespace.com
and use the code word Joe and get 10
percent off your first purchase.
Thanks also to nature box.
Go to naturebox.com/Rogan.
That's naturebox.com/Rogan.
Get 50 percent off your first box.
Thanks.
Also to [inaudible] dot com.
It's o n,
n I t used the Codeword Rogan,
save 10 percent off any and all
supplements tomorrow.
Robert Green is going to be on along
with Aubrey Marcus and we're going to
learn about mastery.
Should be fascinating.
And then Wednesday,
Greg proops that fabulous and hilarious
and awesome dude,
a hilarious comedian,
Greg proops.
He's also a brilliant guy with his own
podcast,
the smartest man in the world,
and a lots of good shit coming on and
we'll see soon.
Much love.
Thank you.