Hello Freak bitches,
but I feel a lot better at doing this.
I'm going to do to Kilimanjaro by the
way,
on a bad foot.
Oh yeah man.
And a challenge.
I have a friend of mine who went to
Bolivia.
He filmed a.
He has a television show called
mediator.
His name's Steven Rinella.
He's a professional hunter and he went
to Bolivia and he lived with the Toumani
for a couple of weeks and he brought
them shoes like,
hey,
you know,
try these shoes on that.
They didn't want to have nothing to do
with those shoes,
like stupid things out of here because
those people walk barefoot everywhere
and their feet.
He said their feet don't look at
anybody's feet.
He's like,
they're all splayed out like their toes
are splayed out and there's like a
thick,
thick padding underneath where they're
basically have their own shoes,
like the calluses and the bottom of
their feet act as shoes.
That doesn't sound too attractive for me
to,
to have to attract abby,
to have feet like a heart and know what
I do is using my mind.
So you don't want to have like callouses
on the bottom of your feet.
I got very soft baby feet.
So you really.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
My wife always does a self defeating
man,
man.
So you are going to do this barefoot.
Are you going to wear shoes at least?
No,
no,
no.
Nothing like that exists to go once
again,
mind over matter.
Well,
what about frostbite at?
I did the half marathon,
barefoot.
You did beyond the polar circle at
temperatures even far more below than
the,
of my joy.
Is it?
Do you think that's possible?
There's any benefit from the fact that
you're walking so much or running and
then your body is heating up and maybe
that has a positive effect on your skin?
Um,
the thing is I'm very able to,
uh,
to go way to tap into the hormonal
system creating a adrenaline.
You know,
this fact where people are sometimes
refer to,
they lift up and mother because the
child is underneath that actually is the
mind staring directly into the reptilian
mode.
That reptilian brain,
which is the primitive brain and that
you have direct access to pure
adrenaline,
makes you able to do almost
inconceivable feet and accomplish it
only any to write trigger.
Now because I have been so much into the
cold,
cold is cold.
Is there a real force impact upon you?
So you need to learn how to connect
within with your mind and you breathing
into the brainstem,
into this adrenaline to withstand this
force.
The cold impact.
I've learned it.
So you're tapping in your brain,
you're causing your body to produce more
adrenaline and you're focusing on the
areas of your body that are contacting
the snow,
like you're focusing on the bottom of
your feet.
Yes,
yes.
And it works.
You know,
I'm still able to look around how nice
their sunset or the sunrise and and be.
So there is a margin even there,
right?
We just need to go back to belief and
belief there in means the
neurotransmitters and the neurons.
Those have sick notes and say churches.
So if you charge your,
your buddy,
then if you're able to influence up to
DNA level,
and we have proven this already,
but the aisle six,
enter,
locating those,
uh,
connected to safe inflammation,
we could not find it off.
We could not suppress the side against
the flammatory markers.
And we showed very effectively not me,
only a whole group of persons which are
trained just in four days to be able to
go into the DNA and create the right
chemistry consciously by breathing and
using the mind to fend off flammatory
markers a cost by say a bacteria inside.
So we are actually able to tap into the
deepest of ours,
create,
have control over adrenaline's trestle
and go up to not only in the deepest
part of the brain,
but also in the DNA.