Hello freaks.
This episode of podcast is
brought to you by on it.
That's o n n I t on it is a
human optimization website.
What we sell is all things that we have
found that benefit you physically and
mentally like strength and
conditioning equipment,
healthy supplements and foods.
I was camping in Alaska for a week,
hunting deer on Prince of Wales Island
and I ate about a thousand of these
fucking warrior bars.
They,
I lived off these things.
Buffalo meat with cranberries and pepper,
no antibiotics,
no added hormones,
gluten free,
no nitrates added all this shit's healthy,
no MSG.
Then it gives you 14 grams of protein
and only four grams of fat in a two ounce
serving with 140 calories.
Super healthy and natural and it's one
of the things that we sell@onat.com as
well as things along the lines of
strength and conditioning equipment like
kettle bells and battle ropes and steel
clubs and maces and the guy that was
just here,
Keith Webber,
the extreme kettlebell
cardio workout series,
excellent workout resources.
We also have the Onnit academy
that's filled with inspiration,
all sorts of informative articles and
videos about strength and conditioning and
fitness and how it applies to things like
martial arts and athletics and various
pursuits.
If you go to [inaudible] dot com o
n n I t and use the code word Rogan,
you will save 10% off
any and all supplements.
Rejoice,
ladies and gentlemen,
because Anthony Kumi has flown in the
great metal tube from New York and he's
here.
Please cue the music.
Yeah,
experience.
That's nice man.
Dude started doing your show in your
basement while you were doing the opn
Anthony show and you set up like a pro
studio with a fucking green screen and
the real professional like
camera broadcast quality cameras.
I was like,
Woo.
To fucking do something like that.
And that's when Brian and I started out
with the youth stream shows directly
influenced by not just you
doing your show in Long Island,
but also the style of show that
you guys did an ob and Anthony.
Yeah.
Which was just pretty much a hangout,
you know,
talking like real people talk,
not professional broadcasters.
Hello,
you're on town,
you tell them.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
What are you talking about lately?
That's what I wanted to do with the light
from the compound especially is make
it look as professional as possible
and then have people watch and go,
why is this guy like,
did he hijack a new set?
Cause he's drinking,
he's talking about he's cursing,
he's talking about shit
that shouldn't be discussed.
And uh,
that's kind of why I wanted
it to look so good.
I wanted it to look a very professional
but be done very unprofessionally.
So,
well it is,
it's unprofessional,
but it is professional.
Yes,
exactly.
But not in a sense of what we see
everyday on the news and that,
that,
that phoniness that you just see every
day with those people that don't act like
real people.
Uh,
if something happens,
a mistake or a blooper or someone yells,
fuck in the background of
somebody doing a live shot,
uh,
the anchor loses his mind.
Like he just saw a murder.
They didn't freak out.
So,
uh,
I,
I just wanted to bring that look,
that professional slick look to me.
Who is just sitting there,
like I said,
drinking,
probably hung over.
Uh,
yeah,
I,
I made the show at 4:00 PM eastern
time just so I could sleep late.
I didn't even think like,
let me let me research and see what
the best time to do a live show.
It's like I could be up by four.
So that was pretty much
the criteria for that.
So it,
it really is being able
to do my own thing,
which uh,
I hadn't been able to do
for many years as well.
When you were doing it also while
you were doing oh and a much do have
management chagrin telling
you not to do it right?
Yeah.
They,
they wanted exclusivity.
And I was like,
this is completely different from
what I'm doing on the ONA show.
Um,
it's video based.
It's me alone in my house.
I'm not bouncing off of opn gym.
Um,
I rarely have guests.
Well,
the new show is a lot different
than life from the contract.
Cause like I do have guests,
but uh,
but back then they were getting on
me about exclusivity and it's like,
it's a completely different
thing and it's in my house.
I bought this shit.
Let me just have fun.
You weren't,
you had no agenda,
you're just having fun.
That was it.
I had no schedule,
no anything.
I would just pop on whenever I wanted to.
If I people over the house
singing karaoke with machine guns,
with machine guns.
That was crazy.
Gun Guy Karaoke and uh,
just anything.
But that is the freedom of being able
to do whatever you want like that.
It's,
it's amazing,
uh,
when,
when you're able to do stuff like that,
you realize how tied up you were
when you worked for the man.
Yeah.
Do you ever see yourself going back to
serious and doing something like that
again?
Are you two free now?
It's,
you know,
once you let the dog out of the house,
man,
it's very hard to keep him,
keep him in and uh,
I'm loving this.
It's so much freedom.
It's a lot of fun.
Uh,
I'll be honest,
the,
the Gig at Sirius was great.
It was four hours a day.
I made a boatload of money and sat there
and the joked around with the likes of
Jim Norton and Opie and comics would
just come through and it was fantastic.
It was a lot of fun.
Um,
but then there were those little instances
where management would come in and
fuck the whole fun up.
Just fuck it up.
And now to have the ability
to just do anything,
talk about anything,
not have to go through all the logistical
red tape bullshit with management.
Keith,
the cop is my executive producer here.
He's never executive produced anything
but probably bruises on perps heads when
he was a cop.
But with three emails,
we set up a poker tournament,
uh,
over,
in,
in Kent,
Connecticut.
They're fucking,
where's the Foxwoods or Mohegan?
Mohegan.
Always get them confused.
W in no time.
And we had been trying to do
this with Sirius Xm for years.
Just let us get a poker
tournament together.
Nothing.
Oh this,
that we got to sell this,
this one got to talk to that one,
that and now it's just like,
Keith,
let's do a poker tournament.
Okay,
I'll call the guy and boom,
we're done.
We're set up.
I always feel like satellite radio was
the bridge from terrestrial radio to the
Internet.
Very good that it's this bridge
that allows people to see,
oh this is what it's like.
If you allow guys to come on and just
swear and say whatever the fuck they want
and talk.
The way they like what you guys did an
ONA is you would talk the way you would
talk if you were just hanging out.
Right.
And there was no other radio
show that was doing that.
Every radio show you would go on the
guy who was the host at a very clear
agenda.
He was pushing the conversation.
You were being interviewed.
They would ask you probing questions,
try to keep you on your heels,
you know,
try to manipulate the
conversation where it,
when on ona you got,
I mean,
you would ask questions if
you were curious and then
we would all just hang out
and talk.
Yeah.
It was just more like friends
hanging out and that's what,
you know,
especially with just a room full of guys,
that's what we do.
We hang out,
we goof on each other,
we hope to get a great line in that
makes the other guy look like an asshole.
And,
and the person you goofing on his laughing
more than the people that are goofing
on him.
That's what friends do.
That's how guys hang out.
And to have a show like
that is a very rare thing.
And,
uh,
I think you're absolutely right
about that bridge to the Internet.
When I was on terrestrial
radio early in my career,
uh,
you looked at satellite radio like watts,
who's listening to that?
Nobody.
It's,
it's,
you know,
it's the graveyard for radio.
Uh,
and then we ended up there
when we died in radio,
the sex for Sam thing.
Um,
and then went over to
satellite and it built,
you could feel it like
it was getting momentum.
People wanted this.
They wanted to hear people speak openly,
honestly,
and in real language.
Uh,
but then that again got fucked
by management and people
that they're beholden to
that they,
we couldn't speak about anything anymore.
Like,
I liked the idea of
speaking about anything,
anything and everything.
I think it's detrimental to not be able
to talk and to have people that want to
shut other people up based
on their ideology or,
um,
anything that they're saying.
If you want to take someone off the air
of shut them up or fire them from their
job,
I think that's copping out and saying,
look,
I,
I can't logically argue or,
or intelligently argue.
So I just want them quiet.
I want them silence.
Don't they know that by hamstringing you,
they fuck up their product and they open
up the door to the internet like the
Internet.
It's right there.
It's the wolf at the door.
It was just a matter of the
technology catching up to the,
the talent base out there.
Uh,
when,
when you're on regular radio,
you're heard by anybody in their car
that could just flip on the radio
satellite.
You needed a subscription,
you need it,
the cars to have the radio in it.
And in time that did build up and,
and there are many satellite listeners,
the Internet had that problem
with technology and that,
you know,
it,
you have the product,
you just couldn't get it out to everybody
in every location that they were in.
But now cars are Wifi enabled and uh,
people have their phones and they could
download podcasts and web shows and,
and play them in their cars.
They're going to work just
like they would radio.
So yeah,
it's right there.
They don't,
they don't see the danger to their
business and yet they keep making the same
mistakes to push people away
either hamstringing themselves.
It's amazing.
And they're doing it because they want
to save sponsors where they don't want
people to protest or
they want to save they,
they're a publicly traded companies
and get about all that stupid shit.
It's this phony ethical
vision that they want to have.
They think that people are looking at
them in a certain way and they won't
respect them if,
uh,
if they don't react to 'em.
But people like me,
you know,
and there was no,
there was really no outcry to
have me a booted from Sirius Xm.
No one said anything.
They just went,
wow,
well we have got to
come down to of strike.
Yes.
Preemptive racial things.
It's also a weird thing
like being on a network,
like a Sirius Xm type thing where you
have all these channels that are like
music and Christian radio and it's like
we're selling so much shit and on top of
that you've got something like Ona,
which should really be its own individual
entity because it's so uniquely
different from the rest of
the things you're having.
Things like if you're
a fucking going like,
let's see what's on Sirius
Xm and you click in,
right when Jimmy Norton's doing uncle
Paul tried to defend the seventh heaven
guy,
did you fucking hear him yesterday?
Hilarious.
Oh my,
he was defense uncle Paul is Jimmy Norton,
a Chogm Lester character that he
occasionally breaks out and he's like,
well first of all,
the guy with within doing nothing wrong.
It's an acting thing.
And he was practicing for acting.
He's in and he was,
oh,
he was telling me it was doing something
about having the kid licked the water
off the tip of his Dick,
like a sharable,
sharable has ethics and
then we mix the sound.
It was so awful and Opie was
cringing and Norton was fucking,
he his uncle Paul was
in full bloom yesterday.
It's,
it's despicable and hilarious.
And if you were flipping
through the channels,
you had no idea and you just let,
let's see what's on Channel One.
Oh,
what
is that?
Oh fuck.
Can you just get to that other,
what are they thinking in the first place?
You know,
you guys should be a
specifically different,
you mean should I should have been on
the Internet through two or three years.
Exactly.
The,
that's a prime example for context.
By the way,
everyone is held to this standard now of
the same like we are language on Sirius
XM satellite radio.
What we used to say on on the ONA show
was held in the same light as what an
anchorman would say on the evening news.
Like years ago you didn't
see Walter Cronkite being
held to the same standard as
George Carlin and vice versa.
Like you knew the context
of who was saying what.
Now,
no matter what you say in what context,
it's just held to this generic
standard of that's awful,
right?
So you get somebody like
Jimmy doing uncle Paul.
It's looked at like as if Tom Brokaw
got on and started just saying that,
yeah,
that's how outrageous we've lost the
ability to distinguish the differences in
context nowadays and that's what's
really fucking everything up.
I think it's absolutely is lost.
Also,
when you take it out,
your extract it and you put it in quotes
and put it on a blog or it's going to
look different than it was awful.
It looks terrible,
but a show like Ona,
what it is is a haven for like fun.
It's like one of the few remaining havens
where you can tune in and you can hear
awful,
ridiculous shit and you could hear
Jimmy defending a pedophile and that,
look,
I have daughters,
man.
I mean,
and I have little kids and I
thought it was fucking hilarious.
It's the,
because I know what it is.
He's being naughty.
He's being fun,
I think.
I think people don't want to know anything
about context anymore because they
don't want to believe that people
can hang out in a room like that.
Talk about stuff like that in
a funny way and laugh about it.
They don't want to think that people like
that exist and they don't want you to
be able to do that.
Right.
You'd want to change your way of talking
and thinking and they want you to their
own social standards,
thinking that everyone can be changed.
Like we're all sick or something.
We're all ill if we laugh like that,
but there's hope for you.
If we just stop people from talking
like that and stop an airing them,
then it'll all be nice and
people won't speak like that.
Like the idea that if you stopped Jimmy
from making fun using the uncle Paul
character,
you're somehow or another
going to stop child molester.
Yeah.
You're going to stop
[inaudible] I haven't gotten,
no,
he was,
he was full boar balls
out for fucking kids.
Jesus and wrote books about it.
Oh,
he wrote books.
He wrote two books that supposedly what
started the whole thing because one of
his victims row read both of
his books and one of his books,
it's about sleeping with
like a babysitter or a,
it had something to do with like a
younger kid sitting baby actually.
Yeah,
the babysitter is hot.
19 year old baby who didn't
have fantasies about that.
John Rowe
isn't it?
It certainly is,
but he's a fucking real pig.
This guy,
real piece of shit.
Unbelievable.
He never,
he's one of those guys too that you never
really would have thought that seventh
heaven show and oh boy.
It's fascinating too that he admitted
to it all in therapy with his wife who
does that.
Like,
I really wants a divorce bad.
You know,
you just do this,
we'll get you out of the marriage.
But you got to kind of do this confession
thing with the wife is demanding it
and then it's like,
ah,
was this,
was this recorded?
Well she apparently without his knowledge.
Right?
Is that what happened?
I think what happened is is that the
one of the victims contacted the wife.
The wife then tried to figure out
what was going on in the navy.
They sign like all these papers about
like the whole thing deposition,
is that what it's called?
And then they recorded it
with him knowing I think they,
it was like,
I don't think he knew that
it was being recorded.
I think his wife recorded it because that
was part of the premise was that it's
legal for her to record it because he
was involved in committing what they
consider a violent crime,
but that's what also I films weird,
weird.
The use of the term violence,
like it's obviously a heinous crime.
He took a little kid's hand
and put it on his dick.
That's a crime.
But how has that violent,
like what,
what?
What made it isn't violent
is they're involved in it.
Definition of violence that it can be
mental or does it have to be a physical
assault?
I don't know.
Here's what's interesting
because the word assault,
that's another one that's getting thrown
around a lot and really weird ways like
sexual assault.
Like one of the things
that's coming up now,
a California just passed this
new law called yes means yes.
Well you have to get actual verbal consent
from someone before you have sex with
them.
Can we just get back to fucking,
no,
because the thing that
they're trying to push,
and this is a,
a feminine agenda in 2014,
is that if you have sex with
someone who's been drinking,
it's sexual assault.
They want to say that.
Well,
a guy got kicked out of Occidental
College because him and a girl had sex.
We had Thaddeus Russell on is a
professor there and he was going,
well,
he drives him fucking crazy.
But Guy was,
uh,
a guy and a girl,
young 18 year old freshmen.
They both were drunk.
They both were texting each
other back for the guy was like,
get over here.
The girl was like,
do you have a condom?
She said,
do you ever caught him?
He said,
yes.
She said,
I'm on my way.
She texts her friend,
I'm going to go have sex now.
Went to the guy's house drunk,
had sex with them.
They were both drunk and he got accused
of sexual assault and he got kicked out
of the college despite Christ.
All the evidence,
despite the text messages,
she didn't get kicked out.
She didn't get expelled.
He did because he's the one with the
penis because it's sexual assault.
It does seem like drunk.
If she was,
you know,
with it enough to say,
hey,
you got a condom?
Yeah.
Text her friend and you know
that she knew what was going on.
Well,
it's also absolving someone responsibility
because they're drunk and only a
sexual context.
You don't do it.
It's driving.
You don't do it to like she
went out with a baseball bat,
just start fucking braining
people and it was like,
look,
I'm not responsible.
I was drunk.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
Why is it in that case it's a,
she's not responsible for it.
Well,
it's because feminists are pushing this,
the,
they're trying to demasculate men and
trying to take away masculine behavior and
masculine behavior is seeking sex.
That's right.
So they're trying to say that seeking
sex while the woman's intoxicated,
even if the mountains
is intoxicated as well,
that the man is being
sexually assault their,
the sexually aggressive and is
committing sexually assault.
That is spectacular ending sexual
assault because you're drunk.
How's it assault?
Uh,
how has it assault by the way?
It's sex.
It,
I don't know.
Yeah.
If it was,
I don't even know.
It's so confusing now what
happened at drunk fucking dry?
Everyone drunk.
Fox,
Saks.
It's got to have a little
bit at least to loosen up.
First of all,
it's fun at those,
uh,
inhibitions to kind of slither away.
Now you're having fun.
But this idea is that,
that those inhibitions are therefore
reason Anthony and sex is bad.
Well,
so are the male fucking,
I want to fuck instincts.
Those had been there for fucking
since we've been on the earth.
How are those denied now?
I love when people try to deny the fact
that we still have so many animalistic
tendencies that you know,
they get covered up by a suit or the
ability to use an iPhone and shit like
that.
But the fact is guys love to fuck and,
and they will do things that sometimes
aren't the most honest things to get
late.
And,
and this is just the way it is
and there's no changing that.
It's just the way it is.
That's another thing that they're trying
to push is the ability to withdraw
consent after the fact.
If you feel you were tricked
so you could say yes,
have sense of summoning a Connie's like,
guess what?
I didn't love Ya.
Hey.
And he leaves and that's
rate and that's now,
now it becomes rate becomes
rape after the fact where yes,
this is the new new rape is
what I like to call a new rape,
new definitions.
It's astounding what's
going on in this society.
Do you,
have we always been in like just on
the precipice of society failing or,
or is it worse now?
I cause you hear shit from
years ago and it's like,
that sounds pretty familiar.
You know,
I think we were always fucked.
Yeah.
But we're here and now,
so we see it as the most
important fuck that we're getting.
You know,
grandpa's fucking was
probably just as bad.
Yeah.
The,
everybody's always been
fucked and everybody's always
been thinking the society
is failing.
I was listening to this hunters
Thompson documentary recently.
He was talking about the state
of America in 1970 whatever,
and it was all falling
apart and I was like,
Huh,
here we are 40 years later.
It's okay.
Yeah.
We're always on the brink of,
of
just complete disaster.
And I think people like
to think that we are,
I honestly feel that just
based on your own mortality,
I think people like to think that
they're going to be the last of it.
You know?
Like if I'm dead,
I wouldn't,
I don't want this carry on without me.
So if there's a cataclysmic event,
then everyone goes and
I could be happy by,
you know,
I'm checking out too.
That's like part of the
Zombie apocalypse fantasy too,
right?
Yes,
exactly.
We all want to be part of that.
Yeah.
Mad Max style.
The total over the
second you dropped dead,
someone's alarm goes off and they go to
work the next day and the fucking earth
spins round and round,
but everyone wants to think
like we're on the brink.
Oh,
society.
America's gone.
Just look at it now compared
to years ago and it's like,
no,
no.
I think 200 years from now
someone's going to be going to La.
Fucking crazy.
Then we should still
have flying cars by now.
Right?
You don't want to
be the guy that's on his death
bed watching CNN and they're like,
utopia has been achieved.
Long life is forever on everyone's.
Dick will now grow six inches.
We're all billionaires.
Congratulations.
Three d printers have come up.
You can make your own house.
Whatever shape you want,
material is free,
right?
Everything's free.
The Internet has made everything free.
You just download the specs to whatever
device you want and now objects.
Materialism means nothing now because
you could have whatever you want whenever
you want it.
There you are fucking check
in an hour and you're rotten.
You're the fucking liver spots on
your hands are blowing up and shut.
I'd missed the boat when it happened.
I may stop boat,
but there's also like 40 years in the
context of hunter s Thompson in 1974 to
compare it to where we
are today is nothing.
If you go back to like Rome,
like if you went back to ancient
Rome and any 40 year period,
they were like,
Eh,
we'll always be here.
No,
I know.
And that's what people bring up also.
They always bring up that Roman empire,
you know?
It's like,
well that fell and that was a pretty
strong and long lasting and everything and
everyone got up.
I see it happen in though now,
but that's just the thing.
When they bring it up,
they think that now is the fall
part of the American empire.
Well,
they see Rome when Rome fell.
Well remember when we were kids we'd,
we'd hear about it was
always like the excess,
the vomitorium.
Geez.
You know,
vomitorium is just like a
way to get out of the arena.
Like a vomitorium is not a
place where they go and vomit.
Really?
Yeah.
It was a pathway that the entire crowd
would go out of the arena had nothing to
do with Bob
because it's like,
yeah,
spelling the people.
It's kind of,
oh,
that makes sense.
But it sounded funny as a kid
to just say like vomitorium.
Yeah,
well that's what we used to think that
it was like some place where they would
all get together and fucking throw
up and then have orgies and shit.
It was just that whole concept of of get
bingeing and just eating everything and
that's the vomitorium.
Oh,
there you go.
That looks fine.
Just a passage doesn't look bad.
Yeah.
It's a passage situated below or behind
a tier of seats in an amphitheater or
stadium too.
Which crowds can exit
rapidly at the end of a performance.
So when the lion kills the dude and then
everybody wants to get the fuck out of
there before it leaps in the stand,
they start to fucking up the Romans.
They would go through the vomitorium,
but I'd have to hear all
your not entertained.
Well,
they would,
you know,
we would always hear
about the vomit Torrens,
whether it gets what was bullshit,
but then we'd also hear
about the Christians versus
the lions or crazy shit they
would do and have people fight to the
death in front of everyone and the fucking
thumbs down.
You want that was society falling apart
and you compare it to today with our
fucking drones and war and the UFC
and all this chaos and fear factor.
I'm apart of a lot of things that you
really are the downfall of America.
Well of society in general.
That's what we would think of like,
oh,
this is a sure sign.
It's just,
it's fucking over it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's how people think because they want,
they want it to be over in a weird
way because of your own mortality.
If people lived forever,
you would never want it to be over.
Right.
So this is great.
You'll change it into something else.
Cool baby over time.
But I don't want it to be over.
But since you are a mortal
being and you have a lifespan,
you just want to be like,
yeah,
no,
I go,
everyone goes,
it's like the ultimate like flip the
board game over if you can't win.
Yeah.
Like someone with terminal cancer,
that fucking takes a machine
gun and heads until mall.
Right,
right.
It's opening up.
And that's another thing.
People have these ideas of what they
would do in certain situations and you
know,
well,
if I found out I had cancer and stuff,
I'd fucking get a gun.
I'd head over to Siri and start
shooting nicest people and says like,
now you'd be in the hospital with no hair,
chemo,
fucking getting pity from your family.
And everyone has this idea,
this,
uh,
this notion about themselves
that are very rarely accurate.
Yeah.
It's all based on books and movies.
It's all based on romantic depictions
of what you would do in those scenarios.
It makes for a fun read.
Right?
Yeah.
And honestly,
we're very rarely that why there's a
beautiful thing about being influenced by
movies and books and songs and that
they provide us with entertainment and
inspiration.
But they also really distort the
shit out of realistic scenario life.
But I think you're supposed to be
able to distinguish between that.
Oh,
you know,
art is one thing in
reality is another art.
It's,
I think it's based on reality
and then we got a couple wins.
Winces reality so much.
Yeah.
Especially with women.
How many women have these,
but especially young women that have
these distorted perceptions of Channing
Tatum movies.
Channing Tatum is,
that's how men behave and this is reality.
It's going to happen to me.
I just got to find my prints.
Yeah.
It's just not a bunch of
way want to come in you.
And so it really is out there.
They're just lying and both sides.
The,
the,
the aggressive male
side and the men who are pretending
they're not like all the other men cause
they want to come.
And you too.
And that's the only way they can go
about getting in there as being unique.
Yeah.
Or,
or just being like on your side,
men are shit.
Right,
right.
I'm all,
I'm horrified to be a man.
Made your shit
that on Twitter and
it's most archaic form,
which is the White Knight.
Yes.
I fucking love the light night.
I don't think I really verbally go,
oh yeah,
reading anything else but
white knights on Twitter.
When you bash somebody who's a girl,
uh,
and,
you know,
you call her out on something.
Uh,
and then some guys swoops in,
don't take that.
You are beautiful.
You're a beautiful person and this,
and he just like,
dude,
first of all,
you just want to fuck her.
You want to do the same thing,
the guy that's fucking bashed
in or if it wants to do,
he's just taking a different angle,
you know,
and you swoop in.
And what is their mindset?
Oh,
DM me.
You're a good man.
They just want to love love.
It's what love.
It's not going to get their way.
They just want love.
It just doesn't have it.
I've given up on the concept of love.
I honestly don't think it really exists.
And this is something a lot
of people have called me on.
I think love is a cross between,
um,
lust and an obsession.
Kind of a,
not really obsession.
I think maybe um,
a,
a fascination kind of just
this quick thing that happens.
It doesn't last long.
It could last maybe a couple of
few years to quite a few years,
but it's still the same thing.
It's lust and this fascination with the
person and that conjures up this mixture
that seems like something
that's love in the
fixing narrow.
You don't think that
people can be in love?
No.
I honestly don't see two people.
I think honesty would be like,
you just never argue.
You agree with everything.
There's never a snooty snippy moment,
so it just doesn't exist.
And in time it transmit,
it transfers into something more,
a habit,
a habitual thing.
The,
the lust turns into habit and the
fascination turns into comfort zone.
And then you're just together and you
continue to be together and you don't even
know about love anymore.
You're not coming home every day.
You're not at the office going,
fuck,
I want to be with her.
God.
When you first get together,
you're like,
I can't even work.
I love this girl.
I want to be with her.
I want to fucking smeller
hair and kiss her and hug her,
and then you've got to leave and you
go into the store for 10 minutes,
Sweetie.
Oh,
I love you all the one law.
I wish I didn't have to go.
Come with me.
Come to the store.
It's just fucking crazy.
20 years of marriage
and you're still doing that bullshit
and you still love the person.
No,
you're now a habitual in
a habitual relationship.
I honestly believe that he is
fucking pissed all over everybody.
There's a bunch of people at
work right now listen to this.
Hmm,
well,
you definitely don't get the newness,
but you could still have
a great relationship,
but what is that?
It's not love,
but the falling in love park,
the falling in love.
The newness.
Well,
we know what the newness is.
The newness is a hormonal rush to make
babies and you're supposed to fuck time.
Yeah.
That's why relationships,
most relationships.
Peter out around three months in,
that's when the woman
hits her first trimester.
She's already supposed to be pregnant
and you're supposed to be out of there.
Right.
Bang in a new one.
Why?
Because people were getting eaten
by Jaguars in a daily basis.
He had a fuck as many people
as you possibly could in
order to ensure that this
species survived.
The problem is our high
mortality rate when the,
when human beings were in their infancy
are high mortality rate led to very
specific types of behaviors that
are ingrained in our genetics.
And those specific types of behaviors
are frowned upon by feminists now.
They,
the,
the very thing that got us to
2014 they trying to curve back.
Yeah.
This like deceptive behavior
in order to try to get laid,
you know,
any type of sex other than the sex
that they feel comfortable with.
I'm happy that this happened.
If,
if,
if the man's happy,
I fuck and I left pig,
you know,
it's anything that's not
along the lines of their,
their,
their ideal is,
is a rape.
Yeah.
And,
and like you said,
it's just biological for the
preservation of humanity early on.
That's how we needed to add.
Here's where it gets more fascinating.
The women who are trying to tighten
this down as much as possible,
no one wants a fuck.
Yeah.
At the very top of the fucking machine,
the very top of the machine
is run by troll agents.
Sure.
All ladies,
ladies,
they're not like really sexy,
attractive objects of desire.
Yeah.
You know,
I think when,
when they speak about like how like how
can a man dictate what happens to our
bodies kind of a thing.
It's the same thing as how can you
dictate what happens to a pretty girl?
Like you are not a pretty girl,
so you don't understand what it's
like to be that and to be able to,
you know,
manipulate men in such a fashion.
So you,
she should probably,
the troll ladies should probably steer
clear of what they think attractive men
and women should find amazing.
Should hide the social justice,
Social Justice Warrior,
uh,
people.
One of the things that they love is when
transgender people go way overboard and
become very overtly like
high heels and a lot of makeup.
You go girl.
But if a woman does that,
if a woman does that,
she's playing into the gender stereotypes.
That is brilliant.
Yes.
Wow.
There's so many hypocrisy.
That's a big one.
But that is a giant one.
Yeah.
That's great.
Woo.
Look at you.
He's go girl.
He,
excuse me.
He fucking asshole.
Trying to be gender neutral.
Better not be,
uh,
you know,
I don't want people to be gender binary.
Yeah.
I like queer because we're is whatever.
It's everything.
Everything.
It's all queer.
Well,
I like when I see an application
for something and it says,
um,
gender and it says male,
female.
Both.
Neither.
Hmm.
Those are nice.
Neither either.
Really.
I mean she just say chromosome.
Can we get it down?
Do you and your why in there?
Okay.
You're a dude.
Next fucking woman.
I betcha we can tell God anymore.
They're pretty good at it.
They fucking to do.
I don't know if they're good at it.
I'm not sure.
I don't know.
I definitely don't know.
But uh,
I mean,
have you seen a photo
of a really good one?
Have a really good
spot though,
right?
It's in the wrong spot.
Well,
when you look a,
the vaginal canal is a little more upward.
Right?
And when you have to turn a penis
inside out to make a vagina,
you see where the penis comes?
It's a little more,
actually the Trans Sexual
Vagina is exactly where you
thought it was before you
saw a girl naked.
And that's true,
right?
Yeah.
Cause it,
cause I don't remember the first few
times you're trying to get down to girl's
pants and you're like,
I am so far below the belly button.
Now where is it?
This is like God over here.
Oh,
what a great adventure that was.
I remember my friend Paulie Hudson,
he was the first one to
tell me that you had sex.
You Go,
you went up inside a girl.
Right?
That's like you just went straight,
straight in.
It's what I thought.
I was like,
you go up and he goes,
you never even had sex.
So yeah.
Well Dude,
I don't know what happens.
You think back at some of
the misconceptions you have
in your youth about sex
and it really is hilarious.
I was under the impression that you
needed what was called at the time a scum
bag,
which was a condom.
A rubber.
These are called,
it was economy.
That's where a scumbag comes from.
It was called a,
yeah.
A condom was a scumbag
back in the old days.
Wow.
And this was when I was a kid.
So I had never used that term.
But I heard like my parents
say that my dad's friends,
you know.
Yeah.
I didn't have a scumbag last night,
so I fucking shit like that.
I know.
It's hilarious.
So I thought you needed
one to get a girl pregnant.
I thought the shit that was
on it got the girl pregnant.
Yeah.
And uh,
and I thought you had a fucker in the ass.
Like I didn't know that
there was a vagina.
I just thought,
you know,
there is an ass you have,
so you fucker in the ass.
Why with a condom and she has a kid.
Wow.
Are,
but the fucked up thing is now I fucked
girls don't want to have a kid so I
don't wear a condom and I
fucked him in the policy.
So it did have some kind of an influence
on my future when I was in high school,
and I don't remember where I learned
this or if it was taught in class,
but I specifically remember
something where it was,
it was like a real source where they
were saying that in order for a woman to
get pregnant that she
has to have an orgasm.
Because when a woman has an orgasm,
it opens up the canal
and the eggs get through.
I remember like there's been some just
ridiculously ignorant shit that I was
taught.
Yeah,
that is I,
I would,
I would think maybe
because of the moisture,
you know,
it gives a little more fluid
for the sperm cells to swim up.
But it was like a door
was open at that anyway,
like a door was opening.
There's like 1980s healthcare shit.
I Dunno if they didn't know
back then or they just,
it was an older even textbook
where they were just ridiculous.
That sounds like something
you'd tell a girl like,
so you could come,
look,
I won't give you an
Oregon and you'll be fine.
As long as they don't make you calm when
I'm making any bays and then after I
come,
I'll make you come.
Yeah.
There's nothing better than that.
Well,
as long as you do that in,
in,
you know you're a rapist
because then the woman can say,
I'm withdrawing consent
because he tricked me.
I said I was going to get to come after
the fact and now I want to put them in
jail.
You can't withdraw consent.
That's something that can't be done.
It's you.
You consented and it happened.
Nope,
not anymore.
The rules have changed.
The rules are changed.
Male feminists have stepped in
and support and this as well.
It's fucking dangerous.
Dangerous.
It's dangerous because
people were actually like,
it's,
it's affecting people's lives.
They're going to jail.
Like this kid that got expelled
from Occidental College.
Meanwhile the girl didn't.
That's sexist.
That is absolutely sexist.
Yeah.
It's confusing.
I saw the best White Knight
tweet once a guy said,
ah,
I'm going to stop calling
myself a feminist because
it's up to women to decide
whether or not I do feminism correctly.
Oh,
tweeted it.
He tweeted it.
Wow.
I'm putting it all out there,
girls.
Yeah.
He should just come over his head and
beat him to death with a brick just
kicking his front door and just smash him.
Fuck.
You're fucking up everything
with your nonsense.
You're stretching the curve out
way past the boundaries of reality.
You are out.
You fringe.
Fuck you fucking Weirdo.
Do you think with that
first blow to his head,
he'd know exactly why you were?
Yes.
He'd be like,
you didn't have to say a word.
You didn't sres that blocking and going,
no,
I'm trying to get laid.
No,
cause he can't possibly said anything.
Let's with these puppies and read
it over and over and over again.
Just like this.
Ah,
it would be a great ironic website.
Like,
if you were a guy that was pretending to
be a male feminist and you were saying
like these really
preposterous things like that,
just see my website,
it's fucking hilarious.
Check it out.
Just subtly sell like a faggot,
kill Steen's genius.
Then it's just subtle enough
to jail your way into it.
Yeah.
It really is a amazing how,
how easily people are bamboozled
online and we didn't know this.
We really,
we didn't have a good bead on
the masses before the Internet.
We knew our friends,
but they were pretty much like us because
that's how they become your friends.
We didn't really know
just anonymous people.
We knew movie stars and TV stars,
um,
and our friends and
that was pretty much it.
Strange as you can see in the store.
You'd might look and go,
what an asshole and think.
You'd never realize how many assholes
are out there until you got to see like
everyone now has a voice
and their pictures,
their families,
how they live their lives,
what they believe in,
what they like,
what they hate.
And it really does open up
a open everybody up to see
like this world of Weirdos
and strange people,
but then where we are to them.
You know,
I understand that part.
We're not these perfect beings
looking on where this asshole Joe,
check the city,
get out.
Oh,
we're,
we're up.
Everyone's weird.
Yeah.
But,
but to be able to see now,
uh,
what a lot of other people are thinking
and how they believe things and how they
get tricked so easily how they
believe false news and uh,
and uh,
blogs that just like,
they'll read a blog and,
and believe it or the onion,
an article from the onion,
which is hysterical.
It's a parody site and I have
gotten links and Anthony,
check this out.
I know you'll be talking about this.
I can tell you it's a joke.
It's just worse than the onion because
there's new ones that aren't even funny
that just make shit up.
But make sure you go to the website,
they'll say it's a parody site
and there's a bunch of them.
They're not even remotely
funny and just bullshit.
They're just bullshit.
My fucking sister calls me up and says,
did you kill him out in line with a belt?
I heard that one.
That was great,
actually said you did.
That's pretty madly write
a fucking mountain line.
I couldn't even kill a cat with a belt.
Try to get a fucking house cat.
Your cat Beavis you have a reserve.
All right.
Uh,
it's a bangle.
Yeah.
It's,
it's,
they're a little smaller than a
serval circles of fucking nuts.
You can't even really have one in a house.
They rip it apart.
Really.
The people that own servals,
they have those houses that
you go into and you're like,
oh yeah,
okay.
You really don't care about anything.
I understand you'll live in the mountains
somewhere and stuff and that's cool.
But uh,
no,
that's a bangle.
It's like,
it's,
I think three generations
removed from an Asian
leopard and a tabby mix.
And then they breed
them with tabbies tabby,
tabby.
And then you get this like
leopard spotted cool fucking cat.
What does he do like around your house is,
he's a maniac.
He's fucking like really intense and,
and just like,
I'll come down the stairs
and I'll be pretty tired.
Pajama pants on and shit.
And it'll fly out of the dining
room and with all of his weight,
throw the side of his body against your,
you're a calf and then grab your leg.
Like he's trying to throw you off balance
and then grabs you and sinks his teeth
into you're a fucking leg.
So He's trying to take you down.
Yes.
He's constantly trying to
take people down in the house.
I've had a video of him,
I guess.
Yeah,
there's a little beef.
I guess he's outside there.
I let them ask with always
in the Christmas tree,
this is the one that amount a kitten when
you let him out when he was a kitten,
then uh,
he goes crazy.
He starts fucking,
he gets this low slink walk and he's
constantly looking around and shit.
It looks like a little wild animal.
It's cool as fuck.
Does he have balls?
Uh Nah.
I had to cut those fuckers were right off.
Yeah,
they get,
I've read that.
It's just insane.
They will piss off fucking pissing it
and like just fuck everything and come on
shit and
there great.
He likes uh,
he likes when girls have no shoes and
socks on bare feet walking around the
house and he'll just attack and girls
are hilarious cause they just scream and
run and he,
you know,
you run away from a cat.
They fucking love that and they're
chasing them and I'll just laugh.
And girls running around
the house getting a,
how much does he weigh?
Like full grown now.
Oh God,
I don't even know what
the fuck would you say?
He weighs about 16 pounds.
Big fucking cat.
Yeah.
He's pretty fucking big.
He's,
he's pretty cool though.
Like as far as a people cat goes,
you'd come up to anybody that
comes to the door and you know,
let's see you pet him and shit like that.
He fetches honestly fetches not even like,
you know,
oh he'll sniff it or bring it somewhere.
He brings the thing right back to you,
sits there and waits again for you to
fucking throw it and brings it back to
regular cat that did that.
It's pretty cold when a cat acts like,
oh,
that's when he was a little ah,
little little guy.
He was trying to get my glasses off.
Oh he's so cute now.
And I saw his video.
I'm like,
I will put this online and
it will get a fuck load is,
and it did so adorable.
You can't beat a kitten
taking your glasses off if
you thought about getting him
a friend.
Uh,
well I,
I have a friend who has a,
uh,
another bangle named Freddy and uh,
she brings Freddy over the house and they,
they brawl and shit.
They have fun or they,
they,
they love fighting.
It's like I have said,
if you ever come to New York
and come up with a house,
I would love for you to
call one of their fights.
And then I just,
I just come down like I had this thing
where I come downstairs because I hear
you calling a fight and I come down and
the cats are fighting on the floor and
you're calling it and I just go,
Joe,
that's my couch.
My cats,
what are you doing?
That would be cause they
brought in so fucking cold.
Yeah,
there you go.
That's his little fetching
little fetch maneuver.
It comes right back.
Oh Wow.
Oh,
he didn't want to be smart as shit.
Yeah,
he's pretty.
He's pretty cool.
And then he catches too,
like,
well not that time.
Great.
Good.
Thanks.
Beep.
You'll fucker.
But that leopard a spot
pattern is really kind of,
that sold me on it.
What made you get them
the leopard pattern?
I looked yet,
I kinda,
I guess I guess being alone
in a big house for that long,
I needed something since
I don't believe in love.
So it cat of,
you know,
you'd dumped some food in the,
in the little,
uh Oh,
that was when you said he's smart.
Here he is with his head stuck in the
trashcan lid and he thinks if he puts it
back,
fucking get back out of it.
So it was kind of smart.
Smart.
That's a Freddy,
his little pal.
And then he,
uh,
he's frustrated.
He does not like that at all.
He figured out how to get it off.
I took it off of him,
the poor little guy.
I feel bad for him when he gets
himself into dumb situations or bill,
he'll jump up on the table that's been
like polished and shit and just fly right
across it.
And without any of that
cat grace that you've seen,
hit the chair,
fall down.
He's bouncing off of things
like a pinball machine.
It's really funny though to watch.
And I'm a lonely cat guy in my house,
Joe.
Right.
That's what it's come to.
A lonely cat.
You know,
I occasionally have some
bitches over though.
You know,
you gotta I tell I,
I mean,
like I said with this whole,
uh,
I don't believe in love thing.
I've had to convey to two girls
that do come over the house,
um,
that I am not a boyfriend.
I'm not your boyfriend or anything.
And it's so hard.
It's a hard thing.
You tell them so you're
not your boyfriend.
I went through so many years,
Joe,
of being with girls much too long,
much longer than I should have.
Um,
a couple of weeks.
Yeah.
Yeah,
no,
I was one of those fucking years guys.
Like I've stayed in the marriage
that I hated for nine fucking years,
nine years.
I think radio was part of it because I
had gotten into radio halfway through the
marriage.
So the second half I didn't
even pay attention to it.
It was all about fucking radio.
I mean radio is straight.
I'm,
I'm going to build this
in a concentrate on that.
So whatever burden she was was outweighed
by the pleasure of doing radio.
Uh,
but after nine years,
that was,
that was it.
So,
but I jumped right from that into another
relationship that just lasted years.
And then after that,
when I started thinking
like maybe I shouldn't be,
and to tell these girls like that,
I feel for them so much,
you know,
and now I just say,
look,
understand what this is.
We are not boyfriend and girlfriend.
I am not in a relationship with you then.
And it,
it,
it almost works.
I have to,
I have to fine tune it.
I'm almost there though.
[inaudible] they don't get
the message and it's um,
I start getting thing.
But then when I stuck getting texts,
I'd be like,
these are girlfriend texts.
We're not in a relationship.
Yes,
I go,
this is a girl friend.
Texts look like.
What's an example of a girlfriend?
A girlfriend tax.
Uh,
you said I could do this.
And then at the last minute you
told me that I can't do it with you.
I can't go here or do this or something.
I'm like,
I change my mind or I have something
else where I made other plans.
It happens.
It fell through.
Oh,
well you're treating me like shit.
This is,
hey,
no,
that's a girlfriend that isn't a friend.
If I call my friend Joe Curry,
let's say,
and I say,
Joe,
this weekend I'm having
a party at the house.
Come on over.
It'd be like,
okay.
And then on Friday afternoon
I call them and say,
Joe,
no party.
It's just not happening.
I'm doing something else.
All right,
cool.
That's like that.
Only if I could fuck Joe Curry.
See the girls and you're trying
to make that you're trying to,
I'm trying to make it
so they understand that,
that they are one of my friends that are
girls that if we want to have sex and
stuff,
that's great.
It's cool and everything,
but we can't have this relationship where
you live here and where where we are
obligated to go out for certain
occasions because your mic top bitch or
something or whatever it is.
What about them fucking other guys?
Yeah.
That doesn't happen.
No,
no,
no.
What were,
you were an asshole.
Who's this guy?
No,
they,
they could,
I don't want to hear about it.
Just like,
I don't want to have
to tell them about it.
Oh,
I,
I've heard this one like,
oh,
who are you going out with tonight?
This is none of your business.
It's none of your fucking business.
Oh,
is it?
This girl is at that one.
Look up.
I'm not telling you.
Why would I tell you?
Why wouldn't you?
Oh God,
I don't want to hear this.
I just don't want to hear it.
But that's,
you know,
there's certain patterns
in relationships to,
people automatically fall into
and they think they're allowed to.
Yes.
These are,
these are allowed because it's become
commonplace and that's what they've been
used to their whole life.
And that's what this,
this a groove that the guys have fallen
into over the years where they know
like,
oh my God,
you just realize at one point you go,
oh,
I'm in a relationship.
I didn't even want to be in one
when we were dating or something.
Or just hanging out.
Like,
why does it always have to
turn into a relationship?
And I've said to to girls before,
I've said,
relationships are the,
the,
the death knell for a good companionship.
All of a sudden now there's obligations,
responsibilities,
accountabilities,
all these things that come
along with a relationship,
take away from the good
parts of hanging out,
which is we're watching TV,
we're drinking,
we're fucking,
we're going out to dinner.
We're not arguing about
anything because that my phone,
oh,
I hope not.
Oh Man.
How did you manage to avoid your,
so you avoided a,
you avoided children.
You got no children.
Yes,
that's a big one.
That is the biggest,
because I almost had a kid with my wife,
which would have just been,
I'd have had to kill myself.
I think I would still have to
do something to get out of it.
Um,
Eh,
yeah.
Yeah.
She,
she got first,
she got one of those ectopic pregnancies,
which happens in the Fallopian tube
and blows up and she started bleeding
internally and a boy,
if I had a future me came back at the
moment I was driving into the hospital,
I may have made a stop at
Mcdonald's first or you know,
I might've had to pick a few things
up while she was in the passenger seat
bleeding to death.
Oh my goodness.
Oh,
well you say this because she,
she basically,
I mean,
how much money did she
take over the years?
There was a bad divorce.
It's seven figures she took
and her long period of time to,
right.
Yeah.
She got Dominic Barbara for her lawyer,
you know,
famed bloated Howard Stern attorney.
But Dominic,
Barbara was her lawyer and he was
just so much fucking anger that I had.
You think I'm angry now?
People wow.
Oh,
was I angry?
Um,
and yeah,
I hated them.
I hated that whole camp.
The lawyers,
they'd come in and I,
I had to pay her legal bills,
which is another one of those great
fucking amazing feminist things.
I had to pay our legal bills and mine.
So she hires Dominic Barbara and he's
just this fucking way expensive attorney.
And I think,
well,
I got to save some money,
so let me hire a cheaper attorney.
Oh,
that doesn't work,
Joe.
That's ridiculous.
I had a guy that would come in with
like a Manila folder into court and they
were,
they had hand trucks of,
of those big boxes of legal
briefs and stuff on their site.
And I'm just,
I was just like,
oh,
this is the worst thing ever.
And uh,
we,
yeah,
over the course of quite a few years I
had to keep paying her and paying her and
then it was over.
And I'm very happy with that.
Do you ever communicate with her now?
No.
Thank God and I don't have to and
if I had kids I would have to,
I don't understand how that happens.
I like a lot of people say,
well no,
you know,
over the years we've built
up a nice relationship.
I'm,
I'm friends
with my ex wife was like,
no you're not.
You had to develop something or you
would have killed her or yourself or
everyone involved.
You have a kid so you have to kind of
build some type of relationship with her.
I have a buddy who's friends with his ex
girlfriend and his ex girlfriend is now
married to another one of his friends
and they have kids together and they get
all their kids together and play.
That's weird.
That's just odd.
I don't think it ever goes away.
I don't think that you fucked her.
Ever goes away.
No,
probably not.
Probably not.
The uh,
the ex boyfriend and the new husband,
they do have a little weird thing with
each other and the new husband will
occasionally criticize the ex boyfriend
and a little bit of an over excessive
way.
Wow.
Cause he knows that it's kind of coasting,
gone on their lip and
the Dick to the misses
pretends to be cool with it.
But we know he's a lot
of weirdness to it all.
No weirdness.
Oh,
but you got a note hand tall.
That's true.
Yeah.
Dominic,
Barbara,
the lawyer for why he came to my house,
um,
a couple of months ago for what?
Knocked on the door.
It came to the house because he heard
that I got fired from Sirius Xm and he was
like,
I just got out of rehab,
drugs and alcohol ruined my life.
I no longer have a law practice.
I'm,
you know,
he got arrested for stealing from one
of the stores of the Miracle Mile there
and a lot on long island.
And um,
and he's just,
he's destitute now.
He was living on his friend's couch.
He went from that attorney that was always
on Howard's show and made millions of
dollars,
obviously made some off of me.
Uh,
and then he's just destitute now.
So I,
I read the stories in the paper before
I got fired and everything and ended,
I'll always laughed.
I thought,
good,
good for him,
Karma motherfucker.
Um,
but,
and if you,
if you crow about Karma,
isn't that bad?
Karmically,
thanks.
I think it is too.
So,
Eh,
whatever.
Um,
but uh,
he,
he knocked on my door and I'm looking at
the window like I think that's fucking
Dominic Barbara.
And he comes in and he was trying
to preach to me like he's saying,
uh,
I read what happened and
I'm thinking maybe you know,
you need help or something or
he wants to be your sponsor.
Fuck what talking about probably a sees
you as an opportunity to get back into
the limelight.
And B feels bad that he
stole your fucking money,
maybe it,
and he might've been doing one of those,
uh,
12 step things where he's got to make
some kind of reconcile affiliation with
me.
Uh,
so he came over,
he did that,
but then at the end he sees like,
so you've got the new show,
you're going to be starting up.
I'm like,
yeah.
He goes,
you know,
I know this advertising thing where this,
and then he's pitching some type
of advertising for the show.
So yeah.
So he,
uh,
he left his number let,
and if people,
you stole money from
me fucking out of here.
Yes.
And people were saying that.
They're like,
why did you even let them
in your house?
Why?
You know,
and they're saying you should've shot
him when he got in the house and say that
he just trying to attack you.
He's crazy.
Who was on drugs,
money.
He's destined to look
at his fucking record,
man.
And,
and check this knife out.
Yes,
it matches my cutlery set,
but very well,
very popular item.
Yeah.
So people were asking me
that and I don't know,
I can't really do that.
I don't know.
I'm not the get the fuck out guy.
I'd rather just k come in and I had
a fan come to my fucking house once,
just knocked on the door and he's like,
hey.
And I'm like,
He goes,
yeah,
I found out where you lived.
I just thought maybe,
you know,
I can hang out and have a beer and,
and I'm looking going,
all right,
I can do this two ways.
I could fucking tell him,
get the fuck Outta here and,
and he leaves pissed off and I have no
idea who he is or I can have him come
into the backyard,
grab a beer and interrogate
him pretty much.
And that's what was done.
That's came in,
had a beer.
We found out everything about him.
I gave all the info to Keith,
he ran them and you know,
figured he didn't have any problems.
He's a married guy with
kids and he lives out,
uh,
out on long island is stony
brook I think somewhere weird.
Yeah.
And so there are two ways
you could deal with that.
And I had been wondering,
you know,
who was that guy?
And now he's pissed.
Now he's a disgruntled fan,
you know,
now I can pretty much tell them,
hey,
you had a beer at my house.
Shut the fuck up.
Leave me alone.
You know,
and maybe,
but then there's that stalkerish
angle where I'm friends with them now.
I could just come over any time.
Did he ever do it?
Did you ever come by again?
No,
he didn't.
But me and Keith saw him
at the Mexican place.
Uh,
we were eating at about a month
ago and he came up and was like,
hey,
how you doing?
I was like,
Hey,
look at what is the fucking crazy guy?
But he's married,
he's got kids and New Orleans has,
he has a Facebook account
and I see his Facebook posts,
his kid like rides horses
and why a nice place.
He's holds a job,
you know,
it's a fan.
So he,
Jay turned out,
he was just a fan.
And you know what,
I really don't have any
problem with certain fans.
A lot of the people that come over to my
parties were formerly just fans of the
show or people that were on the show,
a crazy fucking big a.
And a,
and my buddy Dennis and,
and all of my poker playing friends,
they were pretty much fans of the show
that through one way or another hanging
out.
I figured they were pretty cool and a
responsible and I kind of shoot up or rob
my house.
So,
uh,
they come over and,
when your house to be one of
the worst places to rob anyway,
because you're armed to the teeth and
your fucking houses strategically set up,
case breaks through,
you're pressing fucking
buttons and safety,
the magnetically locked
doors that are alarmed.
I'm not kidding.
And all kinds of,
yeah,
magnetically locked doors,
magnetically locked.
They got separate alarm systems on,
on them.
Just a separate from the house.
Uh,
and you know,
that's like the gun storage,
shit like that.
Cause you don't want,
you don't want anybody guns.
I'm not even sure.
It's probably,
I'm probably almost a hundred.
Maybe we're around there.
That's a lot of rifles and stuff and uh,
yeah,
it's uh,
but in New York it's
getting very tough to,
uh,
to own rifles that anything
but a lever action.
You're going to a gun store in New
York now it looks like 18 hundreds.
It's all lender stanchion.
Fucking the riflemen during actions,
bolt actions,
a lot of those.
But ar fifteens you just
can't find them anymore.
Semiautomatics things like that.
Um,
and that's a whole nother discussion,
uh,
about the effectiveness of banning certain
weapons as a opposed to banning box
ones.
Didn't they make it so that the magazine's
size was literally non-existent.
Like the legal magazine size for guns,
they made it seven rounds and
magazines only come in five,
10,
15,
things like that.
Um,
so by saying seven rounds and then
outlawing the 10 round magazine,
this is,
it was a very calculated,
they said,
we only want you to load
seven rounds in your,
in your clip and your magazine.
So you go,
okay,
and we're banning 10 round magazines.
So it's like,
so what you're saying is I can only
have five rounds because that's the only
magazine available to
me that isn't over the,
the seven round limit.
And uh,
so they,
they put the Kibosh on that.
They figured that was excessive.
So now you're allowed to have the 10
round magazine and 10 rounds in it.
You are allowed.
Yes.
She fought against it.
They changed it.
Yeah.
Who,
who changed it?
It was appealed the court,
the Supreme Court in New
York over through that.
And they're constantly,
all of the New York,
uh,
chapters of the NRA and New York,
a rifle associations
are constantly battling,
uh,
legislation.
Um,
uh,
supposedly gun control legislation,
gun safety.
They always call it good stuff.
Safe that this safety act,
it's never taking away.
Laws never are,
uh,
you know,
anti gun law or take away
gun laws or it's not,
it's a safety law.
It's for your pleasure.
It's everything.
Everything that is given
to us by the government.
Thank you.
Government,
which is supposed to be the people.
Everything that's given to
us is presented in a look,
oh,
we're giving you the,
the marriage protection act.
You know,
you want to,
we was protect marriage.
It's not the fuck the gaze law
and gays can't get married law.
We're protecting something here and that's
how it's presented because they know
that people are going to call
them out on being anti gay.
So they're getting no,
we're not anti gay.
We're just pro marriage.
It's the same thing with
everything government tries
to present to you.
It's convenient,
it's nice,
it's safety.
And then you realize,
how about the Patriot
Patriot Act is another one.
I,
if I don't agree with this,
I'm not a patriot.
The Patriot Act,
your Antonio and something good.
And it's so,
I mean the hacky thing obviously is to
bring up 1984 and the way language was
used in that book and,
and it's so real,
it's crazier and it's all semantics.
It's crazier than 1984 then the bus.
And I'm wonder what it's going
to be like 50 years from now.
I really do.
I Dunno.
I think the end of the world's
come in like next week.
Any day you could just see at
the downfalls society please,
please.
I hope so.
Like the Ebola thing.
Everyone loves talking about Ebola.
I'm scared of the ball.
I'm,
I'm scared of the fact that
something like that exists.
I'm not scared that there's going to
be a big outbreak here in this country.
Why?
Um,
I,
I think,
I think it's,
it's not,
I think it's more sanitary
conditions than it is,
uh,
people getting it from each other.
I think in West Africa you
have hard sanitary conditions.
People are literally living in,
in Shit,
the shit flowing down.
You walk out of your little shack and
there's shit going down the street.
And uh,
I think those conditions and
eating bushmeat and shit like that,
not what we consider Bushmeat,
which I love here in devastates.
You see what he just put up plain
detained over Las Vegas for fears pasture,
heady bowl symptoms.
Now the,
could that be the guy
that coughed on a plane?
Some paranoia.
I Dunno.
Some guy I just saw on the news before
he was coughing and then he goes,
oh,
I got Ebola.
He said that to somebody.
They pulled him off the
plane in space suits,
they fall off the blight and spaces.
That's like saying you have a gun,
right?
It's the new,
I have a gun where,
you know,
through the airport security where you
put your bag on going to La and I hope
they don't find the bomb in there.
Right.
Hey,
we're going to have fun in Vegas.
Yeah,
no you're not.
You're going back here for the old
full body cabinet is no jokes in Vegas.
You not allowed to have no jokes at
the security of the airport rather.
Oh,
that's amazing.
People still do that.
And this guy said he
bullet and they came in,
grabbed him and fucking
took them off the plane.
Space suits.
Amazing.
People are petrified.
Well,
it's so contagious and it does have a
100% mortality rate here in this country.
Right?
The one case.
So there's two people that have it write,
a second person was brought
in to La from Liberia.
They found out that he
doesn't have it though.
Oh,
and this guy in Vegas,
supposedly,
he just got back from Africa
and he puked on the plane.
So that's why the Christ,
the fucked up thing is like
planes make people puke.
So you're picking on the plane.
He,
that's why they have a bag in front of
the seats in front of every person for
Puke.
I've never puked on a plane though
of,
you know,
neither pussies.
He's puking on you got a boat?
Uh,
no I haven't.
I've puked on boats.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's socks.
Cause I love boats,
but it gets you.
Yeah,
but like Keith's got
one and I go out on a,
you know,
the great South Bay and Shit like that,
um,
on long island and it's cool.
That's fine.
I've got no problem with that.
Uh,
but so like going deep sea
fishing and which I love doing.
It's fine.
You're having a good time and then it's
so weird how it hits you seasickness
cause you'll just be,
yeah,
fucking haggard.
The whole,
what the hell was that?
And all of a sudden you just get sick.
Yeah.
And you can't do anything.
He'd start puking.
It's terrible.
Yeah.
It doesn't get me for whatever reason,
but I know people that does get some
weirdest visual inner ear thing.
It's your whole vision combined with your,
your balance and how the two,
if they're separated too much,
if they're not in
compliance with each other,
it's like,
all right,
make them vomit.
I don't know why.
I guess they assume you've been poisoned.
Your body assumes it's been poisoned
and needs to get the poison out.
Just get it.
If I'm sitting in the backseat of
a car and I'm reading something,
that style make you queasy.
All the bumps and like
staring at something also.
Yeah.
We have that swallowing thing
with the saliva starts coming up.
Awful,
right?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I'm not a friend of a,
of puking.
Here's what's funny,
that the drug that they use to
keep you from getting seasick,
the those little patches,
those little things,
it's scope.
Paula mean that's that same drug
as the Columbian Devil's breath,
that they blow on you and they
turn you into a fucking Zombie.
Get the fuck.
Yeah.
Really?
That's that same drug.
Vice did a documentary on
Columbian Devil's breath.
It's the exact same drug that they
use to keep you from getting seasick,
yet it's just a seasick
version is a very low,
low dose,
right?
Yeah.
The Colombians,
they'll take this stuff and then they
blow it in your face and it goes up your
nose and you're gone.
You wow blowing in your face and you
literally become a Zombie and you'll move
shit for them.
Commit murder or fucking dig holes.
Does it ever wear off?
Yeah.
Oh,
okay.
That would be frightening.
You don't have any recollection,
you have no recollection.
Yeah.
This stuff,
Columbian Devil's breath of people been
arrested and use that as a defense.
No,
but it's a good idea.
They think that it's also might be one
of the reasons why Haiti is so a Ebola
was told 4,007 months,
233 of them are healthcare work.
That's a lot of fucking people.
Dead.
4,000 people.
That's a thousand more than nine,
11 and seven months.
Look at that guy.
He's just crawling on the ground.
What that is some real
repugnant poverty over there.
Well,
when I was in,
um,
when I was doing the sci fi show,
we did an episode on hemorrhagic viruses.
We did an episode on what they call
weaponize with weaponry and uh,
we talked to them at the CDC center
that they have down in Galveston,
Texas,
where they have these fucking,
we went into the building,
they have these four foot thick walls
with solid glass and concrete and these
ventilation systems.
It's suck everything out.
And everyone's wearing space suits.
They want to meet or wear a
space suit and get in there.
And I was like,
get the fuck out of here.
Going in there,
you know,
like it's solely safe.
I'm like,
there's no,
no,
it's not totally safe.
It's reasonably safe if fucking earthquake
happens and you're just system breaks
while I'm in there and I have to fucking
take my mask off to work the gear.
No,
I'm dead.
Fuck you.
You bleed.
You be,
you bleed from everywhere.
Your eyes bleed,
your asshole bleeds,
your mouth,
your nose,
your,
your body starts to liquefy.
You just start oozing.
Ah,
just so one of the worst ways to die ever.
Innards.
Yeah.
It's fucking terrible.
And then I guess the,
that guy,
uh,
Dunkin,
what was his name?
That guy that just recently died.
They came over from Liberia.
His family is now criticizing the hospital
saying that they might not have given
him the care that,
what could he,
they closed an entire floor.
He comes from Liberia through Brussels.
Comes here gets,
oh I do you think they weren't giving
him the most attention in that hospital
out of any patient and
then the family was like,
you know,
well we want an investigation.
It's like you should be thanking
every doctor in that hospital.
They should tell the family we're going
to have to kill you because you might be
contagious.
Might be contagious.
We'll just put the house on fire.
Y'All in the house.
Good.
Okay.
Nobody allowed from Africa for a year.
This has put a moratorium.
You keep your country.
We got ours come back one year.
Yeah.
I have friends that go to Africa
for hunting and they're still,
and they're still going over there.
Cameron Cameron Hanes.
You just went over there
and shot a bunch of shit.
Their pictures,
he Facebook,
they don't,
they're the type of person
that doesn't give a shit about,
yeah,
that doesn't give a fuck does every so
often those pictures come out and people
are like,
oh,
how dare you know what's interesting
and my friend Steve Rinella had a really
good point about this.
The real outrage came when a
white girl was doing it through.
It wasn't like some old fat man took a
picture of him with a line that he killed
and everybody went crazy and
it got a million Facebook hits.
No.
There's old fat men that have Facebook
pages that are filled with fucking dead
unicorns and no one gives a shit.
No.
It gives a shit because it's an old fat
man that nobody wants to have sex with,
but they,
you take one of those hot young chicks,
a cheerleader from Texas,
and she's got a pink bow which is
standing over a zebra and everybody loses
their shit.
Why?
And sexism.
Well,
that's how stupid is.
That was actually thought that Steven
Spielberg kill fucking triceratops
lose,
so fucking dumb people thought
that he killed a triceratops.
People
are so fucking stupid.
I don't want you to use
on a triceratops around.
Yeah,
there's what,
there's a lot of people that have those
websites where they go to Africa and
they kill animals and they
put them on the website.
Nobody gives a shit.
Why is it that the hot young girl
with a pink bow and everything,
she's the one that gets the,
Oh you bitch,
you con well my friend Steve,
he got a bunch of good points about it.
One of the things you said,
he said to believe a lot
of it is real sexism.
That's real sexism.
Like if it's okay for a guy to do it,
but if a girl does it,
everybody goes nuts and they don't want
pretty girls getting involved in that.
Like for some reason.
Wow.
Like first of all there's a lot of people
that resent pretty girls cause they
feel like girls have a fucking free ride.
And especially if you're a chick that
maybe is unattractive and you're also
someone who loves animals and you see
some pretty girl with a fucking dead
zebra.
Oh you fucking cunt.
Like she was a con already
just because she's privileged.
She's got great bone structure and a big
juicy ass and everybody wants a common
side of her.
Fuck her.
Right.
And so there's that.
There's that.
But you have,
now you have a license cause she's
standing over a fucking leopard.
She shot with a bow and Arrow
and like this fucking bitch.
I hope that animal eats you alive.
I hope they make you suffer.
Yes.
That is it.
Because the,
she couldn't just call
her out for being pretty.
She'd look petty and exactly.
And the marital and men who know that
that girl would never fuck them in a
million years.
Dane get angry too.
Right.
And then there's also the men that want
to go way overboard to show everybody
that they really support animal rights.
And you know,
people eat animals are assholes and
people shoot zebras or pull shit.
Yeah,
it's a fad.
It's a fascinating thing because you look
at all the restaurants everywhere you
go,
you can get out of this office right now.
We could drive down the street and every
fucking place on the left and the right
and the left and the right is failed with
the carcasses of animals that died in
ways far more horrible than any fucking
zebra suffers when you double lung them
when the narrow,
right,
right.
Oh these animals live their lives in
pens and cages bred specifically for
consumption.
Killed in horrible ways.
Fed other dead animals when they're
not even supposed to be eating animals,
but just so they can get more protein in
tune to make them fatter and stupider.
I mean were were horrible.
It really is great when you
take the byproducts that
cannot be used for anything
else.
Grind it up and feed it back to that.
That's what they did with mad cow.
They fucking were feeding him
brain matter and that they got,
they got diseases that
cannibals in New Guinea got.
That's Scifi Shit.
Right?
It is.
That's fucking dark.
That's soylent green stuff.
Right.
So fucking eat it.
I mean back to them they use it.
They've already used it.
They've always used different dog food
and animal food and things like that.
Which I don't necessarily think it's
that awful cause dogs thrown is the lead.
Anything in each shit.
They look into this balls
and then he's not picky.
I mean does it have protein in it?
Yeah,
it was probably good.
Yeah.
I don't understand.
But the hunting thing in Africa is
even more exacerbated by the reality of
conservation,
that these animals were on the verge
of extinction and now they're valuable.
So because they're valuable,
there's far more of these animals
than they've ever been before.
Like ever in recorded history in Africa,
like they have,
they have areas of high fence hunting
operations that have these once endangered
animals and they're just
fucking roaming free,
wild everywhere.
And these hunters fly in and they
go to these spots and they kill him.
So it's so fucked up.
It's like on one side,
like you know Louis Theroux,
the documentary in from England.
You ever seen these documentaries?
Fascinating guy.
Really,
really cool guy.
And I had him on the podcast before
and we talk specifically about these
operations cause he went over there and
he was staying with them for three weeks
and he was saying that these people
have these hunting branches and without
these hunting ranches,
these animals would probably be extinct.
But because they're valuable
and people fly in and hunt them,
they're worth money.
So he's talking to the guy and he's trying
to figure it out and the guy goes in
this fucking crazy rant.
That guy goes,
so you keep asking me the same question.
I'm going to tell you what's
up Africa East fucked.
You're not going to stand it.
Efficacy is worth money or it's nothing.
These animals that west
something so then that alive,
if they went out alive,
if they went with anything,
they wouldn't be alive.
Africa,
east fucked and he just was,
he was in that South African accent.
Wow,
that guy is fucked.
And he's this old guy that's been living
in Africa his whole life and he's just
talking about,
I would just grinds everything.
Like if it's not valuable,
it's not going to stay alive.
Yeah.
Only reason why these animals even exist
still is because people can come over
and hunt them like,
and how ironic,
right isn't that?
And they pay a lot of money and we go
over there and hunt these animals and then
the money,
from what I've heard,
I don't know how accurate it is,
is it?
It's supposed to go to some conservation.
A lot of it does.
Well I would be suspect to anything that
goes over to Africa and that's supposed
to go somewhere when you look at starving
nations and just plane loads of food
or going over there and
there's still justice starving.
Yeah.
Someone's getting rich off of that and uh,
yeah,
it's not the,
the,
the people,
well there's the numbers of people
that are in poverty are so high.
It's almost like you're insane.
What am I going to do with this?
Like we showed an image the other day
on the podcast of what Africa looks like
size wise,
that you can fit pretty much every other
country in the world inside of Africa.
Like it's a fucking enormous place.
Just the Congo itself
is as wide as American.
Yeah.
Like dis imagine tree.
Imagine the Congo,
a fucking giant rain
forest filled with wild,
crazy monkeys and some of them
that they were mythological
until recently.
Do you remember where we were on the show?
We were on opie and Anthony,
a lady called up.
We were talking about the Bondo aid,
which has since been proven by DNA
and photograph and video evidence.
But I was talking about it based on a
national geographic article and some woman
who was a biologist,
we called up and said it was bullshit.
And you guys don't know
what you're talking about.
You know,
getting angry at her.
I'm like,
I'm not making this up,
bitch.
This is the Congo.
The Congo is a crazy place.
Imagine that though.
Yeah.
Well I like I,
I just flew over the entire country and
you'll look down and you see America and
your,
imagine all of that being
a jungle full of wildlife.
You don't know everything that's in there.
And there are pockets of places where
there are little communities of one
animal,
certain things they're,
they're,
uh,
diet dictates where they are,
their surroundings,
whether they migrate or not.
You're not gonna be able to keep tabs
on every fucking living thing in one
country on the continent.
That is that big and that covered.
It's just astounding that people are
surprised when new things get found.
That that was a big one though.
A new primate in a big six foot tall,
super aggressive chimpanzee
that occasionally walks upright,
can wait as much as 400 pounds.
And they call them lion killers.
Oh Man.
They say there's two types of chimps,
tree beaters and lion killers and the
tree beaters are the smaller ones that go
up into the top of the trees and run it.
But the lion killers bed on
the ground like gorillas.
What was she like?
Planet of the apes type girl.
We just jumped on the plane
with a fucking giant gun.
The last one was not doing
the last one was pretty good.
I can let my anger in their
anger in those monkeys.
Oh yeah.
Um,
but this,
uh,
this area of the Congo was also were like
fucking all the cold trend comes from
when they're,
they're making cell phones out of stuff.
There's so much minerals and shit
that they extract from these areas.
Yeah.
It's,
it's a very wealthy nation
as far as resources go.
And it's the poorest not nation continent.
Um,
and it's the poorest continent,
sub Saharan Africa on
the face of the earth.
It's astounding to me.
And,
and I know it always gets
blamed on imperialism and,
uh,
you know,
every other country has come in and raped
and ravaged Africa and then left with
the wealth and riches and blah,
blah,
blah.
But I mean,
it hasn't,
that happened with every country and
continent on the face of this earth pretty
much during some point in history.
Well,
unless someone comes along and revamps
their infrastructure and creates some
sort of a central government that's
democratically elected and gets rid of the
majority of their
corruption and their debt,
the civilization there is so old and
the corruption and the violence is so
embedded in their system to
break the momentum of the Congo,
that fucking,
that fucking Kony 2012 guys remember?
That's it.
Where'd that go?
That well,
when the fucking guy that was heading,
it started beating off
naked on the street corner.
That hashtag went into the old dust bin.
That was so quick.
That was a fast one.
People cared.
They didn't care like that.
That is the Hashtag though.
Like people care then they don't care.
Yeah.
That was the biggest one.
It was huge peep.
Celebrities get involved.
And there was a kit,
like there was a kit that you could
send for that on one day in April,
I think of that year.
Uh,
people were supposed to wake up and just
see Koni signs everywhere and you could
send for these big kits where
the had Coney stickers and stuff.
And one day people were supposed to get
out of bed and go to work and be like,
what's happening?
Coney everywhere.
And then the guy just started jerking
off naked on a corner in San Diego where
they don't play no play in San Diego.
You can't do that.
It's fucking conservative.
They're close to military bases,
changes be jacking off with
a bunch of old rich people.
Donald Rumsfeld's neighborhood.
Yeah,
yeah.
The,
all the slacktivist at
that point we're just like,
we need a new hashtag no hashtag.
The point is like these warlords that
essentially control large parts of the
Congo,
it's like to get them out and to revamp
the system and deal with the fact that
there's a jungle and there's no roads,
no roads,
uh,
very fuzzy borders.
Like all of these borders are constantly
moving based on which warlord is
warring with the other one and how
much land they take and killing,
taking resources.
Yet there needs to be some kind of
legitimate infrastructure put in place.
But yeah,
how's that ever going
to happen doing that.
But that's another thing
we think about it like,
oh boy,
it's never happened in
the time we've been alive.
So it won't happen.
This shit takes thousands of years.
Does.
Yeah.
Well you look at,
uh,
some of the,
Middle East with all their oil.
I mean,
they were walking around
on that shit for years,
not knowing it.
It was pretty much more civilized,
technically advanced cultures that said,
hey,
let's build these things and start
pumping fucking oil out of the ground made
them rich.
But that's the infrastructure
that was put in place by the West.
Uh,
and kind of made them who they are now.
And why can't it happen in
Africa with all those resources?
Because the second someone swoops in
from the West and decides that they're
going to start building things,
it's instantly seen as taking advantage.
And raping the land.
But meanwhile,
jobs are created when you rape the land.
Sorry to say,
but it does happen and I think that's
better than just having a population that
doesn't even know how to take
the shit out of the ground.
And his is what literally walking on
gold and starving and dying of disease.
Literally walking on goal.
But there's no roads
and there's also this,
there's this problem,
this fucking trees everywhere.
Like you cut them down
or else you're even when
it will go terribly.
Oh you bad person,
you non green.
But if you're in Dubai,
you get to everything.
Slap down a road and you're good to go.
Start chilling.
All right,
we got cash.
What do you want to do?
Let's build the biggest
fucking building ever.
Let's do it.
Go ahead.
You got 12 Leeann's twice.
Aliens and swellings and Dallas.
Maybe mine.
Maybe we should then just look at it for
what it is and not try to incorporate
that into the world.
We,
we know and we're familiar with,
uh,
and and just accept that for what it is
they are going to be people that live in
these places that cannot be industrialized
and they are going to have to suffer
the consequences of living there.
I don't know what else there is unless
you want us to deforest build some roads,
get some big cat fucking
bulldoze in there.
What's the answer there?
This is not a lot of answers.
Everywhere you go that
has a big jungles fucked.
Yes.
Once you get into the jungle,
like what is this fucking people
with the leaves over their dicks.
When are we going to do here?
When you're fucking around
as a kid in the woods,
you have been in certain
situations we were like,
oh,
I'm in the stickers.
I went off of the path.
Oh I'm this.
That's nothing.
Like imagine that the size of the United
States and a thousand times worse now
do something in there
now live and no shit man.
That's crazy.
That is,
that is fucking terrifying to be living
in the jungle to then you got to think
about the bugs,
all the fucking light when you put a
little off on you and the backyard because
the mosquito I got bit.
Did you see this?
I got bit.
That's just
fucking like those be
beards of mosquitoes.
Well have you ever been
in Alaska in the summer?
No I haven't.
Alaska is incredible.
You go outside like I'm not,
I'm not exaggerating at all.
You get out of your car,
you step out of your car and then a
swarm of mosquitoes will engulf you.
Ari and I went fishing last year and
what we had to do is we pulled up to the
spot and there was,
the boat was over there so we go,
all right,
you ready?
I got the keys,
you've got everything,
got everything in your hands.
Ready,
go.
And we would open doors,
slam it,
lock it and just start running.
And you had to just run to where we were
running to the bow of the boat because
if when she parked the car,
if you stand put,
if you just stay there and
just get swarmed and then
they follow you everywhere
and they just staying in the,
so once you get on the
boat and like pull out,
they don't fuck with,
you can't find you once you ran
[inaudible] going down river.
Yeah.
If you stay put for a
while they'll find you.
But the idea is that they breathe,
they detect your carbon dioxide so right.
They're coming to your mouth.
It's the first thing that come to and
then they find that you're in the air and
they just start stinging
in the shit out of you.
I'm talking like thousands of mosquitoes
instantaneously arrive because there's
no like they have no time.
They're,
they're only alive for
like a couple of months.
They're in high gear.
Yeah.
Everything they do,
June rolls around man,
they fucking roll out.
They hatch and they
just start going there.
Only live til like the end of August.
August is over.
It starts getting cold as shit.
And it's over again.
Wow.
Yeah.
I uh,
you see animals sometimes just sitting
there covered in bugs and they don't seem
to mind.
I don't give a fuck.
Just amazing to me.
Well,
I know I am knowing that
tale may be it's awesome.
Swap away.
They could swat away flies within a
fucking two foot radius of their asshole.
That's pretty much it.
If it's on your fucking eyeball,
your fuck.
Thanks.
Have evolution.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Fucking tail.
Just fail a lot.
Back and forth.
Barely does a half assed job.
No Pun intended.
At least they put it where they know
most of the flies are going to be going.
Cause that kind of makes sense.
Put it by his ass of make have tail.
That's why a lot of animals have tails
that swat the flies away from their
shitty stinky ass
can purposes tail serve an
account unless it's the Swat.
The fucking flies away.
Yeah.
I mean it's not balancing it.
They don't care either fucking cows.
You ever see that?
They got like some Bush shit all over
their whole ants can green cow shit
handled for fucking level.
Good luck.
There's another way to look at it.
Fucking a cow.
Has it been a guy ever?
That's fuck to cow for sure.
Right?
I am sure.
Every animal on the face of this
earth has been fucked by somebody.
You imagine that people would get
animals pregnant if people were almost
pregnant,
the world would look so strange.
There'd be half human,
half horse,
half monkey,
half,
half cats.
We go,
we go,
we go nuts.
Sometimes when we see,
you know,
mixing of the races,
people go crazy.
Oh,
imagine a fucking half horse person.
It's kind of walking around.
Yeah.
Nature figured that shit out.
It doesn't work out mathematically.
This,
uh,
does not compute.
And if it does,
even if they're close enough to
breed the whatever they breed,
whatever they fuck,
and they have a kid becomes sterile.
Yeah.
Like a what?
Donkeys and mules.
Yeah.
A mule or donkey and a
horse or the laggers.
Laggers are sterile.
Kathline half tiger.
It's,
it does seem like there was
some type of plan put in place.
They're a little bit do that.
You could do that,
but we're not going to
let it go any further.
That's why we won't even
let get to that point.
Cause somebody fucked a
chimp and it made a bit.
What if you could make like babies but
the baby's couldn't breed some half
person.
Half chairperson.
I mean how much different is
that than a cow or Alaina tiger.
Fucking Elian.
Yeah.
I mean that's the idea behind
people breeding with neanderthals.
Right?
Right.
Yeah.
They fucked and they made a some sort
of a half hybrid human neanderthal thing
that just kind of petered down
the line somewhere.
Yeah,
they were too thick.
Yeah.
You got another note over there.
I don't know what that is.
Vice Colombian donkey.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
My show on the Colombian,
a donkey fucker.
Those poor bastards.
He seemed to be enjoying it.
I saw the clip and he just,
he was a little embarrassed is
literally a little embarrassed,
but barely,
yes,
the donkeys and convenient size.
I want to know if someone
fucked the Giraffe,
that gotta be a dude who got figured out
a way to get a draft to come near the
tree.
And you just,
I think if you're around
where there are giraffes,
there's so many other fuckable animals.
Yeah.
But there's gotta be a
guy who like had goals.
There's dudes who climbed Everest.
This people ran a sub four minute mile.
You gotta be a guy fucked everything else.
Like God dammit,
I'm going to fuck a giraffe.
I want to fuck a live giraffe
because it's not fair.
If you shoot a giraffe and then fuck it,
fuck it.
While it's still warm,
unethical,
it's rude.
And most of,
uh,
if,
if the animal is a little taller,
I heard about animals being stumped,
broke where you,
you,
you train them and break them to backup
to a stump so you can stand on the stump
and fuck them.
So the animal stumped broken
nose like meant to the stump.
What?
Yeah.
What kind of animal gets stumped?
Broke horse.
Of course.
If you're going to fuck a horse.
I remember,
uh,
I,
cause I used to live out here,
I actually used to live,
here's the horse fucking here
is the horse fucking capital.
It is.
I lived out in San Juan Capistrano and
I had horses and everything like that.
It was always the joke about who,
you know,
stumped broke their horse cause it
didn't apply that you were fucking,
your horse was stumped.
Broke.
Yeah.
And then there's that
other thing where you'd um,
I guess a boot broke was the,
the,
you have your boots and you shoved the,
the goat or the sheep's back legs in the,
in your boots and they
couldn't go anywhere.
And then another one you was supposed
to go to the edge of an embankment or a
cliff and push at the sheep and it would
back up cause it would be afraid of
falling off the cliff and it
would back right into your Dick.
Yeah.
And you get a little action.
I haven't heard of that before.
How insane.
People get a lot of desperate.
They get desperate.
I've been without pussy grown up,
especially when it was really hard back
in the old days to get fucking laid.
Uh,
and,
and you're desperate,
but you never look around at
an alternative live source,
but you fuck you fuck everything at York.
You grew up in Long Island,
right?
Well Long Island and yeah,
out here but but long island as a kid.
Yeah.
These are places where people are,
there's a lot of people.
You're on a farm somewhere in the middle
of Bolivia and there's no one around.
You just get on a top of the
farm house and you look around,
you don't see shit for as
far as the eye can see.
And you look at one of these sheep and
you look at the sheet vagina and you go
out,
let me just stick my finger in there,
fill it.
You really do put things in perspective.
I'm thinking from my own privilege terms
at the way in about an urban scenario,
right?
Where you know,
these are desperate fucks
living in hard times.
He knows he's not going
to even see a girl.
Poor bastard.
You can get a shit,
roll the dice and live in the Congo.
You could just wake up one
day and your feet are dirty.
That and your house is made out of twigs.
That was always the um,
the intense fear of the
thought that reincarnation
might be true and even though
no one really remembers who they were
in a previous life or who they are going
to be in the next or something,
you always like,
I don't want to man,
I got a good one this time around.
I got so fucking lucky.
New York males wide scale job.
This fucking is,
I aced this and then you get reincarnated.
You're like fucking,
you got Ebola,
you're coughing your blood
up in front of a fucking guy.
Fucking a goat or you're a monkey or,
and you know,
you used to be a person but
you can't talk and you're like,
ah,
and that's all you're getting
bummed out.
That would be a bummer.
Beaten off.
Bummed down.
No one.
You only have to be 10.
I was fucking,
I was in New York,
I was,
it was a white guy.
It was a white guy who had this whole
thing where I was telling chicks,
no girlfriends,
girlfriends.
It was crazy and they still came over.
It's crazy.
How many of you would think come over
because they think I'm going to fix him.
This guy with his no girl shit.
I think so.
I think there've been
a few that think like,
oh well he just hasn't
found the right girl.
And they had,
they'll say they go with
it in the beginning,
but then they start
getting angry with you.
Yeah.
As it,
as they realize,
oh this motherfucker serious sin.
Oh wait a minute.
He meant that bullshit.
You guys say the same but
they can't pull it off.
No one really means that when they say it.
Fuck.
Do you think you are that
you could pull this off.
They get that.
Oh yeah.
Fuck.
Do you think you are?
Who?
The WHO.
It's a fuck you.
You fucking idiot.
Exactly.
He,
while they already fucked you rape.
Wait a minute.
I take away,
take away consent.
Consent.
Draw a troll.
Women have spoken
the fucking cliff with a horn.
We've found another one.
You haven't fun.
What do you live in your
life by your own rules?
What's said it's fuck you if they don't.
People don't like that,
I guess.
Do you think in retrospect that
this whole firing was a good thing?
Yes.
In retrospect,
at first I was freaked out.
It was just before a 4th of July,
4th of July weekend I had this big fucking
party and now I got to like entertain
people as I'm just bummed,
just completely bummed.
And,
uh,
and,
and another thing when we talk
about how dumb people are and
you realize how stupid a lot of the masses
are by reading their comments on the
Internet,
I took a picture the next day after I got
fired because it was the big party of,
uh,
my buddy Carlton,
who's a black guy and a,
we were in the pool and stuff and I,
I was,
I had my arm around him,
I'm doing a thumbs up and I'm like,
Hey,
look,
people thought I was seriously,
they said,
you know,
the fact that he posted a
picture with a black guy,
he tried to let us know like,
look,
I have a black friend.
I was like,
but that was the Gulf that I was,
I was parodying that uh,
you,
uh,
it doesn't matter.
Even if they know you were doing that,
they still want to call you
on it because it gives them,
it gives them a license to be upset.
Yes.
People are always looking online,
especially for a moment where
they're allowed to be mad.
Isn't that great?
Yeah.
They want to be mad because
life sucks for most people.
Look,
it doesn't suck for Anthony.
You got to fucking beautiful house.
You make money.
You got your own show now.
But for most people,
they're trapped in a
job that's unfulfilling.
They have to listen to a boss or a
fucking company that's probably way more
restrictive than what
Sirius was given you.
Oh hell yeah.
And there's no fucking hope in sight.
So anytime they get a
chance to vent this anger,
this frustration,
this existential angst at the very life,
they're fucking trapped in with
a majority of your time all day,
all week is doing shit you hate.
That's the majority of your life.
So it,
fuck this guy thinks he's going
to trick us with his black friend.
You did describe a great bad life.
It's a lot of,
it was mine until I was,
that popped up at 35 years old.
It was terrible.
And then like last night we were flying
here in a beautiful new fucking Airbus.
Uh,
it,
the TV is as big as most people's
house TVs were a few years back.
And I'm watching the new planet of the
apes and I'm sitting in a fully reclined
seat hurdling through the cosmos
coming here to Los Angeles in,
in time that could only
be dreamt about years ago.
And uh,
my,
my screen was fucking up a little bit.
It kept pausing the movie and then
setting it back a little ways and stuff.
And I had to keep sitting up pressing
it and scrolling back to where I was in
the movie.
And I started for a second to
get pissed ice for a second.
And then it all started
jelling where I was,
what I was doing.
And if I'm getting pissed because my
fucking first run movie at 35,000 feet on
my way to Joe Rogan's show in Los
Angeles isn't working properly,
not even,
not working,
it's not working good enough for me.
I should have thrown
myself out of the plane.
So I didn't allow myself,
I actually chuckled at myself
for starting to get mad.
You checked your white privilege.
I check my white privilege,
which I implore all of you to do.
Please check your privilege,
check your privilege.
That's a big thing that they
say on college campuses today.
Of course they do.
Kids are being indoctrinated
by the hard left.
It's running these
colleges and the hard left.
Once you
check your privilege,
check your privilege.
I still don't know what it is and I've
said what I believe white privilege is
and I've gotten a lot of shit for it.
What do you believe?
White privileges?
I think white privilege is
something that isn't a privilege.
It's been earned over
the course of many years.
I know it's,
it's,
it's something where if
you act a certain way,
do certain things,
you get certain prizes for that.
Certain gifts you don't
get followed in a store.
Life's not a fucking carnival.
I know,
but you know to be followed in a store.
Let me tell you something.
When I was a kid,
when five of me and my friends and
everything would go in at eight,
nine years old to a candy store,
we got followed in the candy
store because the fucking Guy,
I knew that people that were stealing
candy where the eight year old fucking
kids that would come into his store.
So he followed us to make
sure we didn't steal.
Uh,
when,
when people go into stores
now and they are followed,
they look at the people
that have been profiled yes.
Profiled over the course of
their loss prevention and say,
all right,
make sure you keep an eye on these.
We can individually interview everyone
that comes in and find out what their
character is.
So let's just take the slice of people
that have been doing the most damage to
our inventory and follow them
around a little or you know,
falling with the camera but
in the back room a yeah.
Yeah.
Because that's pretty much where we
have kind of fallen there and the,
and the theft of a,
of goods at stores.
When do what people want people to do
that do live in places where they do get
robbed all the time by black people.
I wonder what they expect the
store owners to actually do.
I don't know.
Just ignore it.
Let it happen.
Get robbed.
Do you remember those Korean store owners
that were fighting back against the
Reginald Denny Shit,
the ride during the riots and the
Rodney King David got some guns too.
They had to,
I mean there was some crazy shit going
on where they had nothing to do with any
verdict and nothing,
but it was a free ride is a free ride and
we got to see a very unique and almost
almost like accepted form
of racial violence during
that time where like people
where we're literally targeting white
people and attacking them and no one was
being out.
No,
there was an excuse for it.
There was that.
Well,
you got understand the dre man,
they're very angry,
very frustrated as they lob that planter
over that man's head who's laying on
the ground that,
oh,
here comes the toilet bowl lid and
there's a lot of blood on the street.
But the anger is really the
story we have to look at here.
It was accepted completely and I think,
um,
we saw yes,
sanctioned and we see a lot of stuff in
'em happen that happened in Ferguson.
What does this say?
La Riots and the looting.
That was crazy.
Crazy.
Looting is a weird thing.
Like,
oh,
something went wrong.
It's time to steal TVs.
Yes.
Yeah.
And it's a very festive thing.
Like,
like the,
the,
the reason that the looting goes on is
very grim and it's usually a very awful
thing that happened.
But then the looting itself,
everyone's smiling.
Like they come out wall,
they're like Colden stuff up.
No one's mad anymore.
Maybe it helps alleviate tension.
Tension breaker dancing.
Just dancing around.
Looting though.
He sees,
yeah,
they're stealing this huge drill
dance
dance on dragging it on
the ground with a fuck.
It's always been my dream
to make little wooden Wales
try sell them that.
Yeah.
Where are you going to get
advance that Yo man can
no,
you gotta come get it homie.
15 blocks.
The throwing up gang signs
where they're standing signs.
That's a pretty good la riots,
but I will never forget that photo or
the video rather of Jenny Denny getting
pulled out of his truck and
then that guy took that brick,
smashed him in the head with it and then
did a little victory dance and Reginald
Denny was just a truck driver.
He didn't do anything.
No,
he wasn't a cop.
He didn't beat anybody.
He's just what he did wrong.
Stepped on the breaks.
Yeah.
That mother fucker shit fucking bog.
Right.
Don't you have a lock?
What are you doing?
Yeah.
Getting out.
This is the video.
Oh,
there it is.
Yeah.
Awful awful shit.
I remember watching this lie bastard.
Yeah,
take it away earlier.
They just,
when when things go bad
and people start writing,
they just completely lose their humanity.
Something that happens to human beings
when you get too much of us together and
they're mad about something
and chaos is going on,
like people are smashing
shit and stealing shit.
It's just all the rules go out the window.
It's accepts it.
They call it a mob mentality,
but I think it's more
than just a mental thing.
I actually think there's a
physical like pheromones or,
or there's something that's thrown off
by people in a group like that that just
makes everyone rabid.
Yeah.
Look at everybody like chasing after
the cars when the cars are slowing down.
Like some cars,
they're leaving alarm,
but other cars have white people in them.
They're chasing after the white people,
I assume I would assume too.
And regimental Denny's truck just
breakdown or something like it doesn't it
stop,
right.
Maybe people were in the crosswalk.
He don't know.
You know,
you don't go out.
I don't think you think this
is going to happen to you.
So maybe he stopped,
uh,
to let people go through the crosswalk.
Yeah.
Right.
You know,
a boy,
they beat the fuck out of that.
They really did.
She was driving.
He was driving real slow.
I thought totally on that
move to move to the side.
I could take him to the hospital.
What did you pick him up off
the street all by yourself and,
and uh,
get them in your truck?
No,
he was already the other
part that they have to do.
It's like,
well,
let's show who took him to the
hospital are black gentleman.
Let's show that everybody
that they're not all bad.
Did this last more than one day?
I can't remember what your day.
Yeah.
This one on,
there were many deaths too.
Well,
Anthony Bourdain's show was fascinating
about this because they talked to the
Korean folks.
They talk about some
of the people that had,
uh,
shops that had been raided.
I feel sorry for your mother town.
Korea town got fucked.
But there was like a line of
cops protecting Beverly hills.
Like there's cop cars like
literally down the streets skeet.
Whoa.
That's funny,
man.
Yeah.
Well,
wouldn't you fucking,
everything's on fire in Korea.
Yeah.
Well,
they were also getting mad at Koreans
that were on top of the roofs with rifles.
People at shotguns and shit and they
were protecting their businesses.
It's like,
yeah,
they were protecting Beverly
hills and the wealthy areas,
but it's like,
what do you put in your
safe in your own house?
You don't put,
you know,
fucking candy bars in there.
You put your valuables in there.
It's the same thing.
They want the valuable stuff protected.
Yeah,
and the people that are
spending all the money,
right.
Paying all the taxes.
Exactly.
It's just a larger scale of your own
personal little life that's you want to
protect your investment.
What do you think would happen
if the fucking raids and the the,
the people that were going crazy,
if they went into Beverly hills,
start pulling people out
of their houses and Shit,
that would've,
you would have absolutely seen the,
the national guards start just
shooting people like it was Vietnam,
I probably right.
Yeah.
That just would have been,
it's not fucked,
unheard of.
Korean people can get
fucked over like that,
but the moment they move into the Jewish
neighborhoods and start yanking people
out of their houses and
the white neighborhoods.
Yeah.
That would be crazy.
Again though it's,
you know,
it's,
it's cost effective to protect
the wealthy neighborhoods.
That's still fuck though.
You know,
you're using your police resources
to protect your other resources.
There's a price on everything.
Do you feel like now when situations
come up a racial situation,
you have more freedom?
You have like you don't have this
like filter that you throw up.
Like you would have to like pause
before you would talk about like there's
certain things like this,
what we're just talking about.
Like there's certain people that would,
might think it'd be racist if we're
showing that they're attacking this guy
simply because he's white by exposing
an obvious incident of pure racism,
pulling a guy out because he's white,
hit him in the head with a brick.
You're being racist.
You're commenting on that and not
taking it all into perspective.
What about the context Anthony?
Their life and the disenfranchised
Los Angeles neighborhood.
Exactly.
But then,
then we have like a nice debate,
a nice little talk about it.
Uh,
that can be done.
Why should,
why should one side be silenced?
I mean,
and I do feel more freedom to talk
openly and not have to walk on so many
eggshells when I'm trying
to present the point.
Um,
but that was what the most fucked up
thing about you getting fired was you
didn't even have an opportunity to
go on the radio and talk about it.
No.
And one of the things that I've talked
about on the show before a hundred times,
like your style of talking,
which is entertaining,
is to rant and say crazy shit,
swear a lot.
And that's exactly what you were doing.
I was stilling,
I guess,
you know,
like you said,
if you put quotes around
it and print it does,
it looks different.
It looks a lot different.
But if you were on the show and you were
doing that and then Jimmy Norton starts
doing uncle Paul and then,
you know what I'm saying?
And it was nothing different than I'd
done on their very airwaves for many
years.
And for them to throw me
out over over that was,
it was ridiculous.
Make no sense whatsoever.
And to demand an apology,
a women and apology.
Well,
there've been some people
who have demanded apologies,
some people that think
I should have apologize,
let's say not so much demand at them,
but think I should have apologized and
I have always stuck to the point that if
I do something wrong I have
and will apologize for it.
I was assaulted in New York City.
I was,
I was hit about the head.
If people don't know the story,
there are certain people I'm sure that
are living listening to this that don't
know the story.
Sure.
So let's,
let's give them the whole
brief for the story.
I was,
I was out,
uh,
I was taking some pictures early morning
pictures of Manhattan and I posted all
the pictures that I took.
It wasn't just,
I was just creeping girls.
Like some people said,
let's take an Manhattans and amazing
place at four in the morning.
It's a giant lit up city
with barely anyone in it.
And the people that are
in it are a little off,
uh,
including myself.
Cause I was there with a camera
a and I was taking pictures.
It's amazing.
Uh,
and it's not the groundbreaking.
I mean other people have taken
amazing pictures of New York City,
uh,
very early in the morning.
So I was doing that and I took pictures
of a few of the ladies of the evening
that walk around strippers that we're
leaving some of the strip clubs,
hookers,
whatever.
They're,
they're hot.
It looks great as they're walking on a
wet street with the lights behind them
and the nice shallow of field.
I
mean,
it just looks like a
fucking amazing picture.
Uh,
so I took a picture of this one woman
that was walking down the street.
And again,
it was very early in the morning,
very quiet,
and it's a big fucking cannon camera.
I wasn't with my iPhone and she hears
the shutter clicking and turns around to
look and she goes,
ah,
you white motherfucker,
don't you take my fucking picture?
And she's coming at me,
you know.
So I rattle off a couple of more
pictures because she's coming at me,
uh,
and just punches me right in the face,
just punches me right in the face.
No ifs,
ands,
or buts.
And A,
I'm like,
what the fuck are you doing?
I don't take my picture.
I was like,
well,
you could have said that.
So we get into a little
argument about that.
I call her content.
Um,
and she just keeps hitting me
and now out of the woodwork,
like fucking walking dead,
five black guys just start kind of kind
of walking around looking at the scene
and one says,
you better not touch that girl.
And I had my hand up.
Uh,
I was just using it like my forearm to,
to kind of let her bang into,
I wasn't pushing her away or anything.
I just was trying to keep our at a
distance so I could see her fucking hands.
Uh,
and she just was punching
me in the side of the head.
It didn't hurt,
but it was just,
it was annoying me that
she was doing this.
Um,
and then that's when I said one of the
most embarrassing things I think I ever
said.
I said to one of the black guys,
it said that I said back
off the saint to your show.
I'm Sergeant Barnes back off
this ancient the your show.
Yeah.
I'm Sergeant Barnes from
platoon to dropping the n bombs.
Uh,
no,
no.
That's one thing.
And I,
I didn't drop any in any
of my tweets or anything.
I just didn't say he was.
Who said that you did?
Someone said that you did drop it in
by plenty of people that said I did and
yeah,
people,
most shit gets made up
in those situations.
So,
uh,
she,
I said I'm going to get a
fucking cop and she goes,
get a cop.
I'll just say you were
sexually harassing me.
So now I'm like,
I'm looking around.
There wasn't any cops.
Uh,
I wasn't exactly in time square.
I was a little north of
Times Square at that point.
Um,
but I,
I was,
and I'm waiting to see a cop car just to
flag them down and tell them that this
fucking bitch is pounding
me on the side of the head.
Uh,
but no cops showed up.
So we kind of break up a little bit.
Uh,
and I just start walking back
to my apartment and I'm pissed.
And now within minutes of what happened,
I'm actually communicating
to the outside world,
which years ago you would have time to
cool off and then make you maybe get on
your phone at home,
call your friend and say these
fucking bitch was smacking me in that.
But now minutes after I still
got the adrenaline going.
I'm angry,
I'm pissed that this happened and I'm
voicing it on Twitter and this is what got
me in trouble.
And I say,
I think my biggest crime here was the
fact that I was talking about the incident
and how pissed I was.
And then I also added a little social
commentary to the same conversation.
So people put both of those
together and got the impression
I was talking about all black people.
Anthony said,
all black people are violent.
He said No.
I said,
there's a problem with violence in
some segments of the black community,
which has been addressed by black leaders,
reverends pastors,
community leaders.
It's been,
it's,
it's just been out there,
but you didn't check your white privilege.
I didn't check my white privilege and I
brought it up that there was a problem.
I said,
why did this woman jumped instantly
from zero to physical violence?
There wasn't a talk.
I mean,
I could think of a lot of situations
where I would take a picture and someone
might go,
hey,
I don't want my picture taken and I'd be,
oh,
okay.
Whatever.
Without them instantly coming and,
and resolution number one is
punched the person in the face.
That's one on the list.
It's astounding.
But she was probably a hooker,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm thinking she was a hooker.
Yeah.
But I also took a picture of a white
hooker and it turned out to be a beautiful
picture.
It was great.
It was amazing.
And she didn't catch me in the face and
she knew I was taking the picture and
she didn't mind.
I got a picture of a black hooker once
was she pulled her tit out while she's
eating.
A meatball sub is one of the best
pictures ever taken in my life.
See if you can find it somewhere.
It's in my wall.
I took it with an old phone to
look and Motorola flip phone.
At the time it wasn't,
yeah,
it wasn't a very town camera.
Probably wasn't even a
one megapixel camera,
but the pictures,
it looks like it was the sage.
It was the subject that really brought it.
You don't need good equipment
when you have a great subject.
She's fat.
She had a big giant tits.
She was eating a meatball
sub and she wore a wig,
so all this was going on
and we're in downtown La.
It's like one of the best pictures
I've ever taken in my life.
It sounds it.
And she was so happy though.
She was so happy.
She didn't try to hit me at all.
Well,
I just go,
can I take a picture?
She goes,
go ahead baby.
And she pulls her tit out and I took
the picture and she had the sub in her
hand.
She pulled it it out.
It was her idea.
I wasn't say good for her.
Yeah.
Nobody got hit.
No one gets hurt.
Was it?
I wasn't arm though.
That's the other thing.
Yeah,
that was the other thing that came up.
Well,
they,
the Sirius XM fired me because they
said it wasn't the race racial thing.
They said it was the violent tone of
some of my tweets and it was because I
said,
I fucking hope some ha she mouths off
to some homeboy like that and he shoots
her in the face.
That's what I said,
because at that point,
that's what I wanted,
because if this bitch is going to be
just Malvin often smacking people,
I'm sure she's gonna get her
ass handed to her at some point.
If she'd mouths off to the wrong person.
I on the other hand,
didn't hit her back.
I,
like I said,
I put my forearm up to just keep
her from getting closer to me.
But that was the only contact and it
was her banging against my arm saying,
don't touch me and
punching me in the face.
So the violent tone of my
tweet is what they didn't like.
Meanwhile,
yes,
I am a privileged to be able to exercise
my actual right a second amendment
right to bear arms and carry a concealed
weapon in the city of New York.
Yeah,
you one of the very rare people,
I mean,
if she wanted a punch,
some dude in the head,
that's not a cop.
And think what are the odds this guy
has a fucking write a license to carry a
pistol,
a legal license to carry a pistol.
How long did it take you to get that?
It was a good year,
I guess a year and thousands of dollars
and I had to fess up with every bit of,
of record of my entire life.
Pretty much like,
here,
here's my tax forms,
here's anything I ever did,
including a ticket and how it was
resolved in 1988 I got a speeding ticket.
Or like a parking,
like a parking ticket speed.
No,
not parking tickets.
Speeding ticket.
Yeah.
And uh,
you know anything,
you just put it in front
of them because they,
if they find something you didn't include,
they will say,
whoop,
nope.
So you've got,
you're playing this weird puzzle game,
uh,
with them to try to get this.
And then you need a lawyer.
You can't go in there yourself.
Crazy.
So you've got to retain a
lawyer for probably five g's.
You need to get a lawyer to try to
get a concealed carry gun lawyer,
a gun lawyer.
Yeah.
There she is.
Oh that's my girl.
Fantastic.
Put a picture of her boobs.
So that's really cool
that I can make it out.
We'll look at that.
Come on.
That is with the greatest picture of
ever taking them on as a good one.
That girl,
she was a real woman and she was happy.
She was laughing.
That is something.
Wow,
that's great.
I hate this dog cause
I see Morgan and miss.
I Miss Patrice so much,
which I do too.
She's a meatball sandwich and her hand,
I mean it's just an amazing picture.
Hey,
she got to eat.
Yeah.
And you're going to do it was
just as good as a picture gets.
Um,
so yeah,
so it takes a long time.
A lot of effort.
And I think they bank on the fact that
a lot of people aren't going to go to
that length and a,
and they've turned down a lot of people,
a lot of uh,
uh,
someone did an article a few years back
on who they turned it down and it was a
lot of people like on the mets and uh,
some,
some radio personalities and
some pretty big celebrities.
So what did you say?
Like,
did you have to have a
reason that you wanted,
it's pretty good if you have a reason and,
uh,
as far as to protect your ego,
Amos.
Yeah,
I've got,
I get a lot of uh,
death threats.
He saved them up and things.
Yeah.
Good.
Have that.
You bring those in and stuff.
Yeah.
Like a threat assessment,
threat assessment done
by security guy and um,
and yeah,
you get these letters.
I get letters to mail directly to my
house that have just all kinds of Nazi
propaganda and you know,
uh,
just weird shit and tear your house to
my house so they know where you live.
Fucking 2014 PV.
You could find out where anyone lives now.
It's no secret to you when,
okay,
when you have all this stuff you,
you bring it to them and you say,
look,
these are the threats that I get.
So let your lawyer though it.
Yeah,
they'll let the lawyer doe it.
You give it to him.
Everything he asked for the lawyer knows
what to kind of ask for is actually
shows that you were a good risk
to give that sort of a license to.
That's what they're doing because
you got hit by this woman.
Right,
and you never want escalated.
I never do not hit her thought about
it like because it's a huge fucking
responsibility having a gun.
It's an in something that
you never not think about.
You need to know that you have this on
you and that kind of leads you into how
you handle certain situations.
What would you have done if those
guys or five guys that were circling
back off,
it's not your show.
Those guys came in.
I'd probably just tried to run.
I've run into times square
where there were cops like they,
if if your light,
if you're going,
I have no way out of this.
I am fucked and I am going to die.
Then the gun comes out.
So you would run,
I would run my icing you and
they grabbed a hold of you once.
Once they grab a hold of you again.
Yeah.
It's life threatening
situations are very fluid.
They change by the second,
so based on what's happening
at that very second,
if you use deadly physical force,
you might be fucked.
We might be justified.
That's how,
that's how crazy it is to
try to get a hypothetical.
The legality of it.
Yeah,
so if you're in that situation and she's
hitting you and they close it and he
just pull the gun out.
Yeah,
that's brandishing.
It could work my trouble.
Someone else could pull on out and go,
yeah,
I've got one of those two mother fuckers.
You know,
it's you're,
you're putting a weird situation
where it absolutely is.
The last ditch effort to
save your life is that gun.
It's not your first fucking
way to try to save yourself.
I'm not saying that your controls
amazing cause you didn't shoot her,
but you control is pretty
amazing that you didn't hit her,
you didn't do anything.
Yeah,
I'm harmer.
I,
I wasn't,
I didn't feel like I was
really being injured.
She was hitting me with
those kind of girl fish.
You had to make our fists weird because
she had the long nails so she really
couldn't make a fist and that she was
kind of doing this side of the head thing,
like my ears a little and my cheek.
She wasn't really boxing me,
you know,
so I never felt like I was on the
verge of being knocked out right.
Or injured or even injured.
So I was able to keep going and keep
reassessing as it went on and realize I'm
being kind of dumb
staying in this situation.
Let me break this off and go home.
A lot of people that once
they get hit that's flipped.
Yeah.
The switch flips and then they hit back.
If it was a guy,
I would have reacted in
a second and hit him.
And that sounds like,
yeah,
let me tell if it was a dude,
I'd have been all over the flatter the
face thrown a or summit or a woman.
But you can't punch a girl.
I don't know.
I would have loved to,
I have love to punch her right in the
fucking face would have made me so happy.
But would you have punched her in
the face if she was punching you?
She was like,
if she has,
she has a really punching me.
If she had like her knuckles up it had
to do some trying to knock you out.
Yeah,
I would have,
I have to have done some defending you.
So I do a lot of what ifs.
That's a hard situation
because when you're in it,
you know for just from fighting,
when you're in it,
it's different than when you're
thinking what you would do in a fight.
It's weird.
You know what everyone
thinks it's going to be like,
you know,
some fucking action movie fight or leg
kicks come out cause it's like you're not
even hitting her in the head.
Just one solid one right above the knee.
That meaty part,
the shins,
just one one fucking really hard.
Nobody expects that chicken high heels
to go running to turn the hip over.
But then I want to eat into it.
Then I might have to deal with
the five little helpers there.
That would have been a problem.
True that.
So you did the right thing.
You know I was,
I was really waiting for a fucking cop.
I would love to him had
a cop drive by and go,
hey,
you know,
but I had to just,
whatever and kind of backed off and
started walking home and tweeting and
tweeting my anger that that gets me fired.
And then the thought that I should
apologize that anyone that just heard the
story second hand or anything thinks that
I should then apologize for anything I
tweeted in that angry moment.
Twitter isn't a fucking
representation of anything,
but how I'm feeling at that
moment that I'm tweeting.
It's an open forum of that.
It's just not a good form for you
because you're so animated in should,
it should be.
It should.
I should be allowed to post
just outrageous things as
should any body and end.
If it captures the mood I'm in,
then deal with it.
This is what just happened to me.
Holy Fuck this.
Read this.
And you could really feel
how Anthony feels right now,
or this guy or that guy
based on what that feels.
Why is that bad?
Why is it so bad?
I don't think I hurt anyone's
feelings to be honest.
I've gotten into many debates with people
and didn't use a horrible language or
insult anybody and,
and I pissed them off
just by debating them.
So by really expressing how
angry I was at that moment.
How is that a bad thing?
How is that a firing offense?
Well,
they just protect their brand.
That's all it is.
Any criticism that might
be able to come their way,
my dropdown,
their stock,
they're all about brand of uncensored.
Uh,
on an unrestrained entertained,
look out with crazy Joel Olsteen doing
his religious show on a fucking channel.
Now who's that it Joel
Olsteen always O'Steen,
I dunno,
but they'd been playing commercials
forum nonstop on series.
He's one of these,
uh,
Christian Church guys that get everybody
to put their hands up and big arenas
and close their eyes.
It's fucking insane.
It's insane.
And he's now has a show
on Sirius on serious.
And I'm like,
who?
Why he's a huckster.
Yes.
A fucking huckster.
One of those guys stealing money
from people by using this huckster.
Cause I'm sure the huckster,
yes.
For donations of course,
donations,
arenas full of misguided people with
their hands stretched up to God,
their eyes closed,
cry in their eyes out poor kids that
you see standing next to these mutants
thinking they're fucked.
They don't even have a
chance to receive Jesus camp.
Oh yeah.
What a great documentary that tastic one
and the woman justifying the fact that
they're training these kids because in
Islamic countries they're training these
kids to be jihadists.
Yeah.
So we need to do that with Christians.
Really,
really fun.
I do.
We,
is that the solution we need
Christian suicide bombers.
I played a clip of a,
of some church gathering and there was
this guy dressed like one of the dancers
from the old Lawrence Welk
show and he had two girls,
uh,
women next to him similarly dressed
and they were doing this song and dance
number two,
like some weird hip hop beat.
And they were white as
fucking white could be.
And it was about Jesus and everything.
And then I play like some
isis videos and I'm like,
see,
this is what they're doing
and this is what we're doing.
And I swear to you,
I don't know what's more
dangerous or horrific to watch.
It was,
it's like that's our version of,
of extremists.
Religious extremists is just this,
everything has god.
You ever hang out with somebody
that that is a born again,
like completely into God and
Jesus and it's 24 hours a day.
Like I'm into a lot of shit and I'm
really heavy into a lot of shit,
but,
but I take a break sometimes.
I love my radio control helicopters.
You love Beavis by love.
Beavis and we talked about
little beav and stuff like guns.
I love guns,
but you know what,
it's not 24 hours a day,
but you hang out with it.
That's why you can't hang
out with people like that.
You'd like to think like,
hey,
he's got his beliefs.
I,
I'm cool with that.
We'll hang out,
play some cards and stuff.
Jesus would have fucking
folded a jack and eight.
Have you ever seen June two diesel?
Jim Covey's Ligo played
the passion of the Christ.
He played Jesus.
Oh Wow.
He's fucking all in.
All is,
hey Jesus,
what's he [inaudible] the movie do it.
I don't know.
That was part of the
other one or the other.
I may might've been
before and is more so now.
But he does these interviews with these
religious shows and start talking about
how it hurt him in Hollywood,
has religious beliefs and his belief
in Jesus and his belief in God.
Like,
no,
this hurt you.
This right here,
what you do,
you're on a show,
a wacky Jesus show and you're talking
about the impending apocalypse who talking
about like Armageddon.
And,
and the,
the fucking,
the reckoning,
the my favorite though this uh,
in this day and age now
and it's relatively new for
the religious community is
the people and dinosaurs.
That is my favorite thing.
Do you know Sarah Palin
said when she was running,
she was in Alaska.
She told the school teacher up there
that dinosaurs and people lived together.
Yeah.
And that she saw a photo on the Internet
have a footprint of human footprint
inside of dinosaur footprint.
Ah,
that's nice.
And then the human and
the human said dinosaur.
Why did you abandon me during the my
most needful times and the dinosaur?
I said,
no,
that's when I was carrying you footprint.
Dinosaur footprints in the sand.
Hashtag dinosaur footprints
side friends has,
has there been any pests though
that have seen this hook?
A street meat or lady that uh,
or any officers that go,
you know what,
it looks like a girl we arrested
a couple of weeks ago or nothing.
No,
nothing.
She valence footage or nothing.
People have said to me,
I'm so surprising she hasn't come forward
and tried to get something from this
or anything.
And,
and I just,
I know she knows nothing.
She has no clue what she has wrought.
Uh,
she,
she's just some fucking dumb hooker
who knows nothing about the news,
knows nothing about what's
going on in the world.
She knows money and Dick,
that's it.
You know her corner now and her time that
she works at and I would move around.
You might be dead.
She might be dead,
you know,
whatever.
Don't last long.
Maybe some home.
He shot her in the face.
You're getting fired again.
Now I know.
Fire yourself of that fire myself.
I was saying when a,
I'm never,
since it's my own show now,
the Anthony Kamia show,
I'm never taking vacation.
I'm going to say something so outrageous
and then suspend myself for a week.
That way I can go away,
come back and go fucking boss
asshole.
Do you have any desire to try
to go back with opie and Jimmy?
Do you try to talk to them until like
your sweet side of the woods that you're
in now?
Well when,
uh,
when they were still working
out a contract because
they're contract went until
October,
which they just resigned.
So they did,
they did resign,
but I got fired in July.
So from July to October,
there was a lot of speculation.
What's going to happen in
October when the contract's up?
Are they going resign?
Those two?
Are they going to bring Anthony Back?
Are they just going to tell
everyone to go fuck themselves?
Um,
and Jimmy and,
and Oop,
we're under contract.
So they couldn't just leave.
That's a fucking breach.
Right.
Uh,
they couldn't just leave
because I was fired.
Um,
but they did resign.
I think they,
they squeeze more money out of him.
I think it was very easy to take my money.
You could take half of my money.
Right.
Do you ever eat that up into,
give it to Jimmy and Oop,
now they pocket the rest.
They,
Jimmy and I'll be like,
hey,
we got a raise and the
show's fucking money air.
Right.
So,
you know,
I don't fault them for it at all,
but I wasn't sure what was
going to happen in October.
And that's why I,
I was so adamant about getting this
up and running so fast as was Keith.
I was mourning on the couch for like two,
three days after I was fired.
I'm like,
fuck,
oh fuck,
fuck.
Keith comes over and he's like,
that's all you got to fucking
studio in your basement.
It's so true.
Chop Chop.
You already had it set up.
I was the crazy guy that was building
the bomb shelter that all the neighbors
pointed and laughed at that are banging
on the door when the bombs are dropping.
Hey,
let us have you thought about doing
something in Manhattan though?
Because it's probably tough to get
people to come out to long island.
It is tougher to get
people out on long island.
We've had two,
uh,
is sent cars for people,
but I've had,
I've had a few pretty fun guests.
Andrew dice clay came out.
Oh,
what?
His whole family,
big fat fucking,
he,
uh,
and he demanded a super stretch limo.
He demand like it was the 80s.
They cost does that anymore?
You're going to say.
So I guess for a black one,
I want the sunroof so I could
poke out like the kid in big
fucking that is a genius daisy.
Nice.
He came over with his whole
family and we did the,
the good thing about this is it's my
fucking house and I could put the cameras
anywhere.
So I set the cameras up,
uh,
at the back table by the pool and
we did the whole interview outside.
I got some really hot girl to tend bar.
We had a little rollout bar by the
pool and she just kept coming over and
serving drinks and stuff like that.
And it was just a fun,
real relaxed hang the little waterfall
of the pool and everything made a really
cool atmosphere.
And then Colin Quinn,
I had him over and uh,
I set the cameras up by the
bar that I got in the house.
So we were just sitting there
at the bar and it wasn't like,
it doesn't have to be in
the studio is what it is.
Um,
I want to,
I have Kevin Pollak come in at some point,
um,
and do that from the movie theater and
play like an old Colombo episode and
we'll just talk.
And then every so often refer
to the show and you know,
cause he does an amazing Colombo.
It's hilarious.
And just fuck around like that.
My whole house has become location.
You do it anywhere.
The camera's are they remote?
Like how does big fucking expensive
cameras and I have a lines that I just run
down to the tri caster in the studio.
I runned.
They're not portable.
Why did you go?
We were actually talking about wireless,
high def high def photos
or high def video.
Yeah,
but you,
you prefer the tri caster.
You think that's the way to go?
The one I have,
uh,
I'm pretty satisfied with it.
I'm always looking into something,
see what it is.
But I like the control.
I like the fact that I could roll
video and audio and it's very easy,
um,
integrates well with the,
my computers and stuff.
So yeah,
I kinda like it.
So you run it down to the tri caster in
someone else's working it down in the
basement where the studio is and then
you have the cameras are just operated on
long cords.
Yeah,
yeah.
I've,
I've run them right out,
you know,
through my,
uh,
my oil burner closet out
the vent in the back yard.
But we're having a,
the whole thing set up
where I have sockets where I
could plug them in and then
we'd go outside,
there'll be a little bay
where I could pop all my,
uh,
uh Jackson and get everything done.
Mike.
Nice.
Yeah.
So I could put it anywhere,
but I am going to get a wireless also,
so it will,
uh,
put the video signal wirelessly so I
could do something from the Jacuzzi and
shit like that.
Cause we're having a,
having a Laneys bring in one of our,
uh,
porn stars.
Oh,
so yeah.
So we're gonna I want to do it naked
from the fucking Jacuzzi naked.
I want to just fucking turn
on some bubbles so we could
keep it family friendly
sorta except for her tits.
Just sticking out there.
And then,
uh,
you know,
do it like that.
How do you,
what do you stream it with,
with service to use?
Uh,
it goes through live stream but then it
also then goes to a service that we have
set up with the,
some guys down in like Tennessee.
It's very,
very crazy.
It,
the logistics of this was the hardest
part cause I already had the studio built
pretty much.
It was weird cause it was a trial and
error over the course of years that I'd
been building this.
So I,
I usually set something up,
it worked or I wanted something better.
I'm like fuck,
rip that out.
Put something else in.
And I was constantly building it and it
just looked like linguine all over the
floor,
wires everywhere.
And then,
uh,
when we got this rolling,
we got some tech guys in there to kind
of rip it apart and put it back together
again the way it's supposed to be.
A,
but for the most part,
everything was already
there except for that,
you know,
we could do the show now we've got to
get it out to the masses and it's there.
We're going to be a lot of people
that needed to get this immediately.
Uh,
so we didn't want crash
issues and things like that.
Are you having a hard time growing
it because it's a pay service?
It,
cause I'm sure you've got an initial rush.
Right,
right,
right.
You get that initial rush and then
it's constantly growing though.
It's,
it's initially it,
it really took off,
um,
got a lot of subscribers and I needed
to do a subscriber based show because I
knew,
I knew I had an audience.
I was keeping a cheap enough,
I wasn't going to charge
people a lot of money.
Um,
for,
for the show.
What did you like six bucks a month
or something like seven bucks a month?
Uh,
and then if you do six months,
it goes down to like $6,
and then a year it's
like five bucks a month.
So,
uh,
it's,
it's relatively cheap.
I think 60 bucks a year,
it's like 48 cents an episode.
Um,
and those pork little African kids,
that takes like 50,
so it's cheaper than feeding
starving African children.
So get right it,
that's my slogan by the way.
That's my slogan how it is rude.
Uh,
but
I kept the cost low and um,
Eh,
and happy with the growth.
It's growing well.
Yes.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm very happy with the way things,
it's like I would love,
you know,
hey,
here's another fucking
hundred thousand people.
Let's get them all on board right now.
Uh,
but it takes time after
you get that initial boost.
What made you decide to go subscription
base instead of decide to have
advertisers?
Uh,
well,
I'm kind of doing both
because I'm a greedy fuck.
So I do,
I do reads during the show,
I have a few live reads,
um,
just a couple actually.
And then we have other ways that
we're advertising on the website.
And things like that that aren't quite,
um,
live reads.
But we also have the ability with the
video to pop up those intrusive little
things like you see on TBS coming up.
Seinfeld like those can be sold.
Um,
the video screen behind me with a logo
and the great thing that the advertisers
like is they could send videos of their
stuff over and play it as I'm doing the
read.
And most of them don't care what I do.
So,
uh,
we had this guy,
we got this Guy Dale Bond Danza,
he does this a Dale
Bond Danza dot comedies,
this former fat guy that got skinny
and he calls himself a former fat fuck.
And,
but I,
I just decided to,
you know,
he's Dale Bong Danza it's an extremity
things based on the old Tony Danza bit
from years ago.
And he loves it.
Like they just,
the advertisers know and
I'm not tied to them.
They know if the I do
something they don't like that,
I could just say,
well later I forgot about
that Tony Danza bit.
Oh God fucking killed me.
Once you had this v there was a,
an audio rather have this old lady
who was in love with Tony Danza.
Yes.
And you were talking about
getting her into the green room.
She was online for the Tony Dan's a
talk show that was on for a week or two.
And uh,
and she was online waiting outside
at one of the studios in Manhattan.
And Iraq went down with a phone call,
drop us and said it was,
she went down the line,
said,
you want to talk to Tony?
And they were like,
yeah,
yeah.
So he hands her the phone and I was like,
well this is Tony,
how are you doing?
And,
and she thought it was Tony Danza and the
conversation got worse and worse as it
went along.
So you enjoy the show.
Did you like me on taxi
and things like that.
And then it started being like,
well,
I could use some relaxation in the,
uh,
in my dressing room.
How about you come back
when you come in and,
you know,
maybe you'd give Tony a massage
and she's laughing like,
all,
I would do that.
And then it got to the
point where it's like,
you know,
I could use a hand job
was something and she,
they never broke.
They were always like,
oh,
like it was they,
they sewed,
didn't want to be disillusioned,
but there their celebrity crush.
It doesn't want to just went with
her think that he was a perv.
Did they ever find out that it was jus uh,
no.
Not those people.
The people at the Tony Danza
show did and what did they do?
They started having security walk the
line and Iraq picking rocks picture was
put up,
did do not let this man near
the people coming in about that.
That was one of the funniest fucking
things I ever heard on the radio.
That was a good one park.
I parked somewhere and I was crying,
laughing and I had to go inside for a
meeting and I sat in my car for like an
extra 10 minutes just listening to that.
Yeah.
There was one point where
I said something and,
and everyone knew what the
next line with and I was like,
oh,
hold on.
IATSE kids.
Here it comes
all the listeners like,
yes,
we know it's,
that was some funny shit we used
to be and that's what XM was.
We were at Xm radio with
that when the merger
merger happened.
That's like when you remember
when Germany merged with Poland?
Yeah,
the merger happened with a serious,
they completely took over and did,
uh,
did away with all the people at Xm that
were show friendly and things like that
and,
and just put us in their building instead
of the building we were in where we
were able to go out in the
street and just do fun shit.
We did box a Cox that day
where we put up a box,
we lined it with a gay porn
and just dildos in it and
fake rubber dicks and then
we close the box and put a free kittens,
please take,
give them a home and left it
in the middle of the sidewalk.
And then we were just,
and we didn't even have a video.
We were,
we just had audio of like,
I think Danny was down on the street.
We were upstairs.
We were watching out the window watching
people walk by going all she's looking
at,
she's looking at the box and then they'd
open the boss see of kittens are in
there and the reaction was hilarious
and we were doing this on radio.
It wasn't even a video to it and we were
just describing it in the fact that we
were laughing so hard.
People really could kind of get what
was happening and they just stopped all
that with serious.
So it kind of conversations did they have
with you guys as far as like what you
could and couldn't get
away with that was just it.
Nothing.
They never had conversations
with us when we would ask.
It was always this weird.
They point to the ceiling and talk
about the people upstairs and be like,
yeah,
well you know,
they think and I'm like,
who the fuck are you pointing at?
Like I want to name,
I want someone to talk to and say,
how can we do this?
Not that we can't do something,
please work with us and say,
how can we do it?
Maybe?
Well,
we got to,
you know,
run it through up the old flag pole
and run it through this and we'll,
we'll greenlight that as we skylight
this and get just middle management
bullshit that would shine us on every day.
And we'd realize months and
months would go by and we go,
you know,
we haven't done anything.
We haven't gone out to do an appearance.
We haven't done a poker tournament.
We haven't,
we want it to do a cruise.
We want to do a big O and a
cruiser promoted a year in advance,
a cruise ship with all the comics
and fans and fucking Q and A's and,
and shit on stage at,
on a cruise ship.
5,000 fucking people and,
and do that.
And serious came up to us and said,
yeah,
that's great.
We want $1 million up front
to allow you to do this.
What?
Yeah,
because it was going to be done with the
same promotion company that did our a
virus tour and everything.
So they came to us serious,
wasn't involved at all.
It was going to be sold and that and,
and you know,
everyone was going to make money and if
serious had a notion to sell that would
be able to sell that and make money
off of it instead of shaking down the
talent,
uh,
to give them $1 million upfront
to allow us to do a Gig.
That would be huge.
They wanted you guys to
give them $1 million,
$1 million.
How much,
what was the profit potential for this?
It was a lot less with
$1 million up front,
just to serious,
it was going to be a pretty lucrative,
pretty lucrative.
But to that extent and the,
just the nerve of your,
your company coming to you and saying,
we want to shake you down for 1
million bucks to allow you to do this.
It's fucking mafia tactics and,
and there's a,
there's a,
an ability for them to make
money on an appearance like that.
Sell the shit out of it.
You,
you,
you sell with the cruise line,
you do this whatever.
I don't know the ins and outs,
but I know in terrestrial radio
when we used to do appearances,
it wasn't coming out of our pocket.
That's unbelievable.
Yeah.
$1 million,
1 million bucks.
Like fucking Dr Evil.
They just dying on the vine.
Uh,
I,
it's easy for me to say based on the fact
that I was thrown out of there to say
yes,
they are like we were talking about
the end of the world and stuff.
Yeah,
it's happening tomorrow.
Uh,
but uh,
I can't see them sustaining a
themselves based on what they're doing.
It's just a lost cause.
They're,
they're showing themselves to be as much
regular radio as they were trying to
be.
The alternative of they're
showing themselves to be the,
the corporate guy and not
the cool show that you know,
gets away with stuff and
the concepts so archaic.
When you have the internet
and you have like a provider,
like your situation,
you're,
you're just,
you and Keith and that's it.
You don't need it.
Don't need it anymore.
People,
you don't need it your own ads.
Yet.
You guys could both solicit
companies to advertise.
Like,
look,
I've got x amount of thousands
of people every fucking day.
They listening and watching.
You can sell your products to that,
boom.
And then you cut out all the nonsense.
All you need is an agent to
handle that stuff for you.
So like this idea of having this,
I mean,
I've been to the ONA studios,
you guys are in a fucking
shiny building in Manhattan.
That must cost fuckloads of money.
Unbelievable.
It's gotta be,
it's gotta be sound crazy.
It's way the fuck at the
top of this building.
You gotta show your Id and they
give you a fucking sticker.
My name is Ba.
You go through the thing
and go up to the floor.
I mean it's crazy how
much money is involved.
You go there,
this receptionist and people walking
back and forth and all they're doing is,
I mean they have music.
Yeah.
But with you guys,
I mean that's one of the reason why
you guys should be a separate entity,
right?
Cause you don't need any of that
live talk aspect of it
is something different.
And,
and the worst part for them is the fact
that the most important logistical part
of their whole setup is
outer space.
Like if something fucks up at the house,
we can pretty much go to radio shack
and patch something together and fix it.
There shits in space.
If something breaks on
one of their satellites,
what are you going to do?
Well,
how has fucking Scott Greenstein
up there to fucking fix it?
Good luck.
Yeah.
They can be wiped out by a
solar flare and solar flare.
Fucking meteors,
whatever,
whatever.
Some errant Russian fucking,
I don't know.
Uh Oh yeah.
Well power outage.
Yesterday we did,
we had a power outage
at the house yesterday.
The generator,
they have a generator.
I have a giant fucking generator.
It's the size of a truck
and it's in my backyard.
And when the power goes off,
this thing will automatically
automatically kick in and,
and I could run everything in my house
and probably two more houses with this.
For how long?
Until the fucking to 1000
gallon propane tanks run out.
That RN took it up yet?
Yeah.
So,
oh,
so you power just went out.
I went out yesterday and stayed off.
I did the rest of the show
from an iPhone in my kitchen
then to a battery backup perfect.
And my laptop to show videos and uh,
and uh,
Keith having a writing down the sponsors
and shit that I have to talk about.
It was great.
It was like we went from the
most technical technologically
advanced studio to
pretty much a bin Ladin in the cave is,
yeah.
Yeah.
It was weirder when you run and crouch
behind them than if you just walk,
you're just lost.
Get done saying how this is,
this is the opposite of serious.
You don't have to do that.
Yeah,
I can't hear you when you say that though.
The yellow that sat on either when
we're at our house doing it and he's on
camera,
I have to crouch on
the ice.
That's true.
He does crouch.
But there are times too where people
are at the house and they're talking and
the doors open and I don't care.
Like I liked kind of this ambient
noise that people are hanging out.
There's some people get,
I got used to doing like live reads
with people talking all the time.
When come when commercials
would happen on the ONA show,
I would do the live reads and
people don't stop talking.
And that was yesterday.
That was yesterday phone.
Geez.
What's the power out?
It's amazing that you
could stream like this.
Yeah.
So you're doing it all to you in four G.
Yup.
That's amazing.
This has taken forever because of red
tape with these stupid fucking a town.
Uh,
and there's zoning and
permits and everything.
It's a good commercial for
the show here on your shelf.
So while the is what went on
and it would have been great,
Keith,
I do believe if you go to the
alarm system and punch the code in,
all the alarms were
going off in the house,
Cook for a battery backup and everything,
but it worked out.
You know,
I'll get the generator on at some point.
The neighbors are gonna hate it.
It's got like a turbo
diesel truck engine in it.
Nice.
Yeah.
When I was in Colorado,
we had one of those would
kick in all the time.
Cause the power up there sucked.
Yeah.
Long Island's sucks
because the wind blows.
And for some reason where the only place
on the face of the earth now that's
still has wires strung on poles.
Like it's fucking like 1850 and,
and they're all between
the property lines.
Yeah.
Why did they underground?
I don't know.
That's so stupid.
And they put them between
the property lines of,
of uh,
everyone's house,
but then also in between the property
lines are trees cause you want like trees
and trees and wires.
They don't fucking men.
So the second it gets too windy,
the wires rip out of
the fucking works and,
and you lose power.
So,
so you get this set up here,
back that up a little bit better.
Look at it.
That's beautiful.
That's the background.
Is that all screens or
is that your actual,
that's a green screen.
And that's my,
that's my pool in the backyard.
Uh,
done,
uh,
on the green screen.
But I can put anything back there.
So there's a green screen,
but it's all broken up.
Like you have some of it's green screen,
an entire greenscreen everything.
The fake screen behind me,
the desk,
it's all fake.
It's all fake.
So I sit there at a desk and a console,
but you don't see it.
You see that?
And the reflections are in the desk.
It's all computer magic.
That's amazing.
The reflections and the desk
are also manipulated fake.
And uh,
I could put any video on those screens.
So that's what I use
when I'm showing video.
Who built the a desk for you?
Uh,
that isn't a real desk.
The fake desk.
The desk is faith hold as being
a fake right here I'm sitting,
I'm sitting in a chair in a
very relatively small room
with a green behind me.
That's why when something happens,
um,
and,
and like they were showing some of
the rioting and Ferguson and stuff and
they'll just play that on the
green screen behind me and I'll be,
I'll be in the crowd going like,
ah,
don't hurt me.
So the desk being faked.
So do you have green screen
in front of you as well?
No,
it knows how to layer.
That's the thing about the tri has that
I like it knows how to just layer things
like you would in Photoshop.
Uh,
where,
where the background is the back layer.
Uh,
my live video is middle and then the
front layer is that desk and whatever else
is in front of me.
So with the odd thing is I could never,
I could never reach over
the front of the desk.
It's always in front of me.
So no matter how far I lean,
I can never reach over it.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
But it looks like I'm fussing with stuff
behind it all the time and I put my
beer down there or I have my Obama bobble
head doll and I'm talking politics or
you know,
it just,
everything could kind of be behind the
desk and it looks like I have what people
actually,
they come down to the studio and go,
this is it.
That's it.
It looks like a giant complex,
a studio.
And it's really pretty simple.
Wow,
that's amazing.
Yeah,
it's fun.
Man,
I,
I've always been into a video and,
and uh,
I used Adobe after effects.
We,
it's like Photoshop for video and a just
been fascinated with keying and green
screening and stuff like that.
And you know,
the,
the equipment that's available to people
now as opposed to even just a few years
ago.
Is unfucking believable even
just when you first started,
right?
Yeah,
when I first started I was just grabbing
a few cameras there at B and h a and
popping it up and doing a show and then
slowly trial and error figuring out how
to do things.
Uh,
it's left a lot of electronic waste
and a lot of closets around my house.
So I got these lights don't work.
What made you decide to do like a video
based show as opposed to like the way
ONA was,
which is primarily audio base,
but you used to have pal talk and,
yeah.
Yeah.
I,
well I've always been into
more of a visual aspect to,
to a show.
I,
and especially nowadays,
everything is so visual,
uh,
live leak and youtube and stuff.
People like watching videos of
something and then talking about it.
So I'll just pull videos all
day and all night and um,
put them in folders and uh,
put him on the Tri Caster,
play them and be able to
just discuss it with people.
So,
uh,
it,
it adds a whole nother dimension.
It is weird in the fact that I
can't just roll out of bed and,
and go downstairs without
showering something,
you know,
a shaving.
I mean,
I don't want to be a complete disaster.
I didn't have any hair gel today,
so I'm a little frizzy.
Uh,
so it is weird to be on
camera the whole time.
I'd find that kind of strange.
Uh,
and then one of the things I learned
is you can't play a song parodies or
anything on a visual thing because you're
just kind of sitting there listening
to music.
We were playing an old,
I'm an old reverend Al Song
that I did years ago and,
uh,
I realized I'm just sitting there going,
well,
this is it.
Are you listening?
It was kind of weird.
You,
you,
that video that you just showed Brian,
the,
you guys are sitting
right next to each other?
Yeah.
Is that weird having a conversation where
you sitting right next to each other
like that?
No,
you get used to it.
It's where you kind of address each other
and then the camera and it's a little
odd,
a little odd,
but you get used to it pretty quickly.
And then we're,
we're adding more cameras
to the studio itself.
But a lot of times,
like I said,
I'll do it from out by the bar or out by
the pool or upstairs by the fireplace.
What,
wherever.
Do you think you'll eventually
have a place in New York?
And they said they would like to,
I would like to rent a place
and have somewhere to go to do,
uh,
interviews or,
um,
yeah.
And I think it'd be a lot more convenient
for me not having cameras strewn all
over my house and lights.
My house is strewn with
cameras and lights everywhere.
Oh look,
I look at it.
You got it outside.
Yeah,
that's outside with me and Jimmy Norton,
uh,
hanging out.
Just,
it's just,
uh,
go anywhere.
It's,
it doesn't have to be just in the studio.
No.
Have you had any conversations
with serious since the firing?
Uh,
they send me an email when they fired me,
it was an email and I called Greenstein
who is the kind of boss over there and
said really fucking email after
10 years with you and you know,
years before with the XM and stuff,
but an email and he's,
wow,
look,
you know,
I,
I can,
I was like no explanation,
nothing.
No.
Come in and talk and you know,
give your side or anything.
Well we,
and he just didn't have anything.
I said,
okay,
so I'm,
I'm fired and that's it.
He goes,
yeah,
there's really nothing.
I go,
okay,
thank you.
You'll hear from my lawyer cause I have
to sew him for the rest of my money.
Are you suing?
Yeah.
Why wouldn't I would like my contract?
I don't think they had
legitimate reason to fire me.
It had to be something that,
um,
di,
what does that word,
when you do something to
accompany that makes the company,
puts the company in a bad light?
The company itself,
like disparage,
uh,
if I have something in there that said,
if I disparage the company now that's
me going on and saying serious socks.
Don't fucking subscribe to them.
Uh,
Howard Sachs,
this sucks.
Everyone sucks with the
bosses are assholes.
They don't know what they're doing.
Like that's disparaging the company.
Me expressing my thoughts that I had
expressed on their airwaves for years is
not disparaging their company.
So,
uh,
I say you owe me from July to October.
So see up motherfucker.
When he does that,
go to court,
uh,
they're working on it already.
My agent and uh,
one of the lawyers is this
all on top of that shit.
It won't go to court.
All these things just settle.
It's like,
yeah,
I'll take some fucking,
I'll take some cash.
All their money.
I mean,
did they have a lot of subscribers?
How's it work?
Uh,
their subscriber.
I don't know how many subscribers they
actually have at what they say they
subscribe at because they count things
like when you buy a new car and you get a
free subscription,
they count that as a subscriber.
A lot of people were canceling
their subs for when they fired me.
They were very cold.
A lot of people.
That's fucking,
yeah,
not me.
No,
no.
Sorry.
I,
you know,
I hung in there.
Thank you.
I'm not,
I wouldn't hold it against any potential.
Um,
but they uh,
they canceled and everyone was saying,
wow.
They called me back and said
they're going to give me,
you know,
a year subscription for like a
third of the price and stuff.
And that just adds up as subs.
So when they go in front
of their shareholders,
when they give their quarterly reports,
they say,
well,
ladies and gentlemen,
the subs are up.
We're doing great.
We went from this many subs to this many.
Now meanwhile,
if you went from that
many or that many paying,
and now they're paying
a third of the price,
you're kind of losing money.
They never tell how much money.
It's always the money.
Actually,
they always tell is that a loss?
But there's subs always going up.
It's amazing how that works.
The subs,
so many subs we have,
it's just a very strange business.
It has,
it's not ratings,
you know,
SharePoint's things like that
that I remember from a radio.
It's a way we need subs.
And I remember the boss of the company,
the actual boss,
I don't even remember his fucking name.
That's how little I dealt with him.
Uh,
I dealt with Scott all the time,
but this boss Guy,
he,
uh,
he pat us up,
we met with him once and he goes,
he goes,
I don't care what you guys do,
what you say.
He goes,
to tell you the truth,
I barely ever even listened to your show.
He like,
he didn't even know what we did.
He thought this was good
to tell us by the way.
And then he goes,
all I care about our subscriptions.
That's what I want subscription.
And it just reminded me of twilight
zone where an old boss was like,
you've got to push,
push,
push.
And the guy's like fucking
sitting there in black and white.
All crazy.
All I care about is subscriptions.
That was it.
And that just told me right there like,
oh boy,
this isn't good.
It's just,
it's too archaic.
It's history.
It's just too archaic.
The idea that like I'd
get a podcast on the,
on my phone and I can stream it live.
Like immediately I press a button on my
phone and it starts playing in my car.
I was that not true.
This thing and I can pause it.
Yeah.
And I could start the all things
that I can't do with serious.
Yeah.
This is all things,
this idea of a show is on when it's on,
that's when you have to be tuned again.
That's ridiculous.
That's our cake.
Well,
I think their hope is that hey,
people still turn on their
fucking radio in their car.
They do.
And you know I do.
Yeah,
like the uncle Paul thing.
I heard about it because I was just
flipping through the dials and because I
turned it on when it was happening,
you know it when I was in my car
was right when Jimmy was doing that.
If I had watched listen
from the beginning,
I might not have made
it to that part I made.
It might've gotten to my destination
and not hurt the whole show.
Yeah,
there's something to that.
People still listen to just FM radio
that just put that fucker on ab and it's
still,
well,
you know the ratings is still there,
but they're the weirdest
ratings of all time.
Those books at the handout
that diary Nielsen Diary,
we need carpet tron diaries.
I wrote it in and I represent
10,000 people and we,
well not enough diaries got
returned from the urban areas,
so we're going to flood them with diaries
the next month and then at the end of
three months we average it to
get who came up with this shit.
It's 2014 they're using
fucking the same system.
The,
the,
the mercantile used in little house
on the prairie Wilson's mercantile.
It is the Nielsen is a goofy,
but the arbitragers are even more goofy.
Yeah.
That book,
that rating the John,
that was the one,
yeah.
Yeah.
That's the goofiest.
That's the go feet book.
They send you a book and they sing
it like a dollar or something.
How do they know he's listening?
They can't,
no,
no they can't.
They really can't.
To serious.
Now who's listening?
Did they have any idea?
I think they do in some way,
shape or form.
They have to write,
don't they?
I would imagine with that technology
they have to know who's turned into a
channel.
I would imagine it would be
like an IP address on a website.
Like,
oh,
there's 40,000 people listening to,
I've always said it's like one way,
but they've always said
it's like a one way signal.
They send it to your radio,
but your radio doesn't
send anything back to them.
When you,
when you subscribe you'll have to do it
from either the phone or a computer with
your radio number.
So you can't just go to your radio and go,
Hey,
I'm subscribing.
Click Kevin Smith was telling me that
they know who's listening to what.
Yeah.
I don't know how he knows.
I don't know either.
I've never heard a number.
They've never given us a number.
I think cause they know
it would be a barber,
a bargaining chip for a negotiation.
I would think that just the information
that shows like on your display it,
I says like you know guests today,
blah blah blah.
Right.
That there's something sending out that
separate from the signal or something,
but it's not because that's sent this,
they're doing that with a regular
radio too now with HD radio.
That's true.
If you listen to regular
radio that it's part,
it's embedded in the signal
that they're broadcasting.
What else has embedded in that
folk can go over them.
It's the harp system.
I love Jesse.
Oh,
what a nut.
What about nine 11 nine
11 what about patriot?
If you don't think they
brought the building down
that that was embarrassing incident
with him and Jimmy Norton who was
embarrassing.
Thank
you for your service.
He was embarrassing.
He really was.
He just,
it was such a blowhard.
Yeah.
Well that's the like him before that.
I think something happened to him age,
like age.
Yeah.
There might've been some kind of,
well,
some kind of brain thing,
a little snaps thing or,
I think it's also people that get
really conspiratorially minded.
They start getting really nutty with that.
That starts,
it starts becoming something
they just automatically go to.
Yeah.
What?
Automatically there's no room for
reasonable discussion on a topic anymore.
It automatically goes to,
well,
what about nine 11 nine 11
explained to be the Patriot Act.
They had it ready to go look.
All fucked Tonkin.
Yeah,
right.
Another one.
Gotcha.
Operation Northlight
fucking hilarious.
I think also they get real high on
finding conspiracies and things like just
several people that I follow online that
will find anything that's online and
think that there's some fucking
grand scheme behind it all.
Like some guy was going on the other day.
About what Isis really was
with some Israeli plot.
Some fucking,
that's how stress,
well,
it's just always something,
man.
It really is.
They just,
they also don't acknowledge real facts.
Sometimes they just throw them away if
they can't put a conspiracy to a fact.
It just never existed like,
uh,
well why didn't they find any
plane parts of the Pentagon?
Well,
they did.
They did.
No,
no,
they did.
Ah,
okay.
It was a missile that hit,
it wasn't a plane,
so they found this,
they found an engine.
They found it,
you know,
apart from American Airlines here
on the fucking lawn and stuff.
Nah,
they didn't find anything.
Oh,
okay.
Now I saw a website,
bro.
The,
I saw a website and the
website said to the contrary,
right.
Or you don't think the fucking,
the right there at the Pentagon,
you don't think they could have
laid plane parts out on the lawn.
That's a much smaller truck pulls up.
The guy gets out.
Just fucking throw in plain fucking pies
out of video of a guide you in that.
Just like,
you know,
you ever see those trucks that farmers
have with a spray seeds at the back of
the truck that they,
with that just chuck and
play and playing parts.
Yeah.
That's a piece of a tail light gas.
We need a fucking turbine of a,
yeah.
There's never a logical explanation for
anything and the easiest explanation is
never the one that it could be.
It's always got to be a very complicated
something that would've taken planning
on the lines of a movie.
Uh,
but you know,
and once they get it in their
head that there is a conspiracy,
they'd look only for everything
that supports that conspiracy.
Yes.
We had this episode on Chem trails
at all that Scifi shows we did.
That was the one that more people
got so fucking angry chem trails.
One because we had a guy on who was
explaining in very clear scientific terms
that jet engines,
when you fly through
condensation in the atmosphere,
create clouds.
There you go.
They create artificial clouds
and these artificial clouds,
you could do it over and over
and over again all day long.
All you have to do is fly
through and they were like,
yeah,
what about one time there's a video
that shows the plane and it's flying and
it's creating a cloud and then no cloud,
and they turned the jet off.
Did he turned it on again?
Or you know how you look up at
the sky and there's a cloud here.
There's not a cloud here.
Yeah,
because the level of condensation
atmosphere very varies and it's different.
And if there's a lot of
Barium,
what about 911 if you squeeze
the air that has moisture in it,
that's not visible as a cloud right now,
but you've run it through a jet engine,
it's going to come out
the other end as a cloud.
Yeah,
but let me tell you what it is.
It's a weird thing that people want to
believe that the government is spraying
the skies and they're down here too,
but they're just spraying those skies
and have they been doing that since
there's been jet engines?
Because there's been con trails,
which is,
that's the thing people
don't want to admit.
They want to pretend that there weren't
these contracts back when we were young.
They used to dissolve very quickly.
We fly and then the
controls dissipate quickly.
Those are normal controls the controls
are seeing today or chem trail ride.
Oh,
okay.
It's aluminum and barium aluminum.
Barium.
Meanwhile,
if you fucking sprayed aluminum,
it wouldn't look like a goddamn cloud.
You need something that's moisture,
right?
A cloud that needs to be vapor.
Like aluminum is never
going to be a fucking vapor.
It's hell no,
it's,
it's all so dumb.
Uh,
another thing I love is the fact that,
uh,
how,
how UFO phenomenon has just disappeared
with the advent of everybody having a
phone and a camera and stuff.
Like,
I think that killed the UFO thing.
It,
cause now anything that
happens is on camera.
Anything.
You can't do anything
without it being on camera.
The second something happens to 20 people,
at least they're holding
their fucking phone up.
Now you would think if you have photos
were gone around with everybody having a
camera now there would be so many
great UFO videos and there's none.
There's a few fake ones.
There's like fake wines
that have been done,
um,
on after effects and you know,
great production companies that put out
great shaky fucking things and it looks,
it looks pretty cool,
but there are no fucking like
go to youtube and go authentic.
Like it's just not happening.
No.
You would think it'd be great.
Like finally everyone's got a camera.
We're going to see these
motherfuckers gone.
It's true.
It's so true.
I mean,
we're seeing videos of mountain lions
and fucking parking lots and crazy.
There was a mountain line in
San Jose on someone's car.
They caught it.
A security camera is standing
on the hood of his car.
That's scary.
Cat Man.
A big Beavis,
a big giant beavers.
You'll see the Hawk that
took out the little drone.
No,
that's one of the videos up today.
I think it just today or yesterday down
in some fucking guy has gone what is
drawn and you see a hawk kind of going
around this thing comes at the drone
clause fucking out.
Wham hits the fucking thing.
It's great.
Let's end on that.
Yeah.
If you could find it,
you'd love it.
It's nature saying fuck
you technology off.
I'll show you his boss up here.
It's arrival.
Yes.
It's a rival for another hawks affections.
That's fantastic though.
Man.
Walks by my house while
he's fuck with the crows.
Yeah.
Hawks and crows to fuck with
each other because hawks,
we eat crows.
Yeah,
I saw a hawk stole one of my chickens.
Oh really?
Man.
One of my chickens vanished and I think
it was probably a hawk because I let
them roam and do most of
the area where they are.
These are the protected under the canopy
of oaks so the hawks can't really swoop
in,
but if the chickens get
stupid and they'd go out here,
the yeah,
you sit throughout that,
that drop cam that it gave you.
It has night vision and then it will show.
You could just watch it anytime
you went to a show you like,
it will notify you if something crazy
is happening and styles are great HD.
Yeah,
that's probably a good idea.
I saw a big hawk fly
cross Canoga last night.
Yeah,
it was pretty cool.
Oh,
hawks are around here.
They just fuck it.
Dove down and then back up into the trees.
I thought instantly,
I thought it was a bad cause it was night
and that would have been a big fucking
bat.
They have big fucking owls out here.
Owls.
Oh my God.
That would require,
maybe it was,
I'm not a bird owls out here
that I'm not bullshitting.
Were like two and a half,
three feet tall,
standing on a post for days
on end just sitting down.
We have rubber ones,
subtle flavors,
houses to keep away stupid birds.
We can't figure out that really knocked,
knockdown them.
Fucking guy won't leave
most uncalled Al ever.
Have you ever thought about setting up
out here now that you don't have to be in
New York?
Uh,
you know I don't have to be in New York.
No one that is very cold.
No winter.
I know,
I know.
I do.
Collaboration's shows
anytime fucking fucking,
but I'll take you to the range.
You got guns together.
Do you do spin a nice yarn there?
I,
uh,
if I did move,
I would consider a few other
places just because of like,
I,
I can't go to another state that just
has ridiculous gun laws like New York.
Well,
this place has better
gun laws in New York,
believe it or not.
And you him easily.
No Way.
Yeah.
You think you think it would be harder,
but you can't even walk into a gun store
in New York if you don't have a pistol
license for New York state in the city.
Forget about it.
In New York state,
let's say you go into a
gun store and you're like,
oh,
I want to see what that
Walther Ppk is like,
can I hold it?
No.
You can't even hold a gun
in a gun store and like,
Oh wow,
that's kinda cold without a gun license.
You've got show them first.
Yeah.
New York is way more,
way more California,
but California has more a cake
hunting laws in California.
They don't,
they don't all allow them to hunt a
lot of animals that are really problem
animals like bears and cougars,
these,
these dogs to hunt bears.
If you don't use dogs to hunt bears,
there's,
there's really,
there's three ways to
hunt bears spot and stalk,
which is really tough.
You got to find them and stock them.
And Woods,
it doesn't work.
Use It on like hillsides and in areas
where they're gonna be out eating berries
or like grizzlies in large Tundra
areas or you gotta use bait.
We have to leave bait out for them to
bear is completely vague and then you tell
them it's the only way to do it.
Like it's cheating when
you use bait for fish,
that's cheating too.
He's got fucking answer.
I love it.
I mean it is kind of cheating,
but how else are you gonna
get him a really good beer?
You don't use bait for most animals.
Most animals it's illegal.
Well,
there's some like Texas that kind of
allow you to do with it or fuck you want,
you could use bait for
deer like they have,
like you'll leave out corn and fucking
shoot him in the head and they go to,
I think it's fair if you put
the bait for the bear on a hook,
the land,
I'm like a fish
caught on his lip that big fuck it's
gone under the leaves smartbear.
We're gonna need a bigger tree stand.
Yeah.
Um,
but outlines,
they stopped hunting them altogether
and there is so prevalent now that the a
six year old kid get attacked and
fucking Cupertino with a fucking apple
campuses in Cupertino.
Wow.
Same town as the apple campus.
A six year old got attacked
by a mountain lion.
They're everywhere.
Yeah.
There's this one ranch that I hunt at.
They have a trail cam up at this ranch
and they caught 16 different mountain
lions on camp,
on the calves.
16 different mountain.
It's right.
And,
and people that get eaten
by the mountain lions,
they're doing exactly what
the mountain lion loves,
like running or biking.
It's always like,
yeah,
I took a jog in the hills,
but mount line just sees like,
oh,
this is great.
They can be throw something for your toy.
Yeah.
Throw a toy to a cat and
I'm watch what he does.
They're so God damn strong to Q magic,
the cat that's as strong as a house
cat but weighs a hundred pounds.
Yeah,
just it fucks things up all day.
That's what it does.
It sound like this is the first time
it's ever killed anything when it's face.
It's been getting it's food delivered
like Beavis has and a nice little aluminum
tray.
No,
it's,
it's fucking food.
As he catches his food with
its face catches fucking food.
You see that the guy that got
in the cage with the tiger?
Yes.
And,
and he was,
he was cowering in the corner with
the tiger like two feet away from him,
just staring at him for 15
minutes before the tiger,
bit him that 15 minute looking at that.
There are times I look at
Beavis his face and go,
oh shit,
I don't even want to fuck with them.
And it's a cat because
he's got those fucking,
his eyes turned completely black and
he's got that look on his face like,
yeah,
I could just lunge it.
Your eyeballs right now,
imagine up tiger head,
which is if you've seen
a full grown tiger,
they heads are fucking bizarre.
Big,
just from side to side and
and that thing just like,
all right,
is it still there?
You'll look at it.
Yeah,
it's still,
he was also praying a lot
and we his hands up and down.
He was like being with,
I'd find God at that point somehow.
I don't know.
What are we?
God,
there's nothing you can do.
The amount of power,
that's just unbelievable power,
that muscle.
We are very weak and the animal world.
If we didn't have a a few fucking
sparkles of miracle up in our head,
we would be done.
Well.
The idea is those sparks of miracle with
sent us down this road of decay for our
bodies develop this fucking soft,
fleshy outer layer that
tears on rocks and twigs.
Just looking like look at a chimpanzee.
Just fucking going through trees,
hitting sharp branches,
nothing there.
Made a leather Temaze leather with muscle,
crowded fucking thick tendons and we
don't even understand like they have
tendons that are so
much stronger than ours.
Oh yeah.
You think they ever wake up just out.
Ah,
when often,
oh,
what happened now they grab a branch and
launch themselves into the air with it.
They throw themselves through the sky
will catch things and wash skin like
fucking easy rider.
So different than us.
We're just bags of Jello.
Just fleshy.
I had a two year old chimp on
news radio once it was an episode.
I don't think we will even
wound up using the scene,
but they are adorable,
adorable.
But it was a tiny little champ and it
fucking slap me in the back and I was
like,
Holy Shit.
It was hanging on to me.
It was being cute.
But then it just whacked me in the back
and I couldn't believe how hard it hit
me.
I was like,
this is fucking crazy.
Even the small,
cause we had one on the ONA show,
Jimmy.
Jimmy had worked with a chimp on some
MTV thing and he found out that the chimp
was in town,
so they invited the chimp
on the show and it was,
uh,
probably a couple of years old,
maybe three.
And you could just feel
like you feel his shoulder.
It's different.
And it's this rock muscles
tight fucking muscle.
It's totally different.
Yeah,
we're weak.
We're,
but we have guns and we went,
we have guns and we'd holdings
tactics and backup generators,
propane tanks,
iPhone os,
sonar,
electric toothbrushes.
I got quince stuck in
my head now listen man.
I'm glad we got to,
we're out of time,
but I'm glad you're doing your show.
I'm so glad you're doing it
the way you're doing it too.
And not just getting hired by some other
radio station that's going to fucking
hamstring.
Yeah,
it'd be in the same boat.
I'd be in the same boat in,
in no time.
I think.
So it's kind of Nice that
this worked out and it's,
it is odd that the inspiration that you
got for this from me doing the compound
show and then you doing this was an
inspiration to go back to actually do the
full show on a scheduled basis because
I think it was you that told me at some
point you got to,
you got to put these
things on at the same time.
Like if you're going to do it,
like when I'm going to do it,
it's gotta be from four
to 6:00 PM Eastern,
the be the keys.
It's just consistency,
distance,
make sure that people get into it
and it becomes a part of their day.
And it's very rewarding for you too,
I'm sure.
Right?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Back to it's fucking coal.
It's just fun to do.
I don't think I ever did so much
preparation for any other show.
I did.
I,
and I'm honest,
it's,
it's like I would go in and not that
I would phone it in or anything,
but it was kind of easy to sit there
with the likes of a Jim Norton and bounce
shit back and forth and just
start laughing our asses off.
Goofin um,
when,
when it's your show though,
I want stuff.
I want to know that
I'm talking about this,
this,
that I want to be very
interactive with the audience.
We're doing a pal talk,
um,
thing where,
where pal talk is joining us.
Uh,
so subscribers,
we'll be able to go to a room in pal talk.
Now I'll be able to just
pull up their cameras,
put him on my virtual screen and have a
discussion with these people instead of
just primarily going to the phones,
we get interactivity.
Or if I could just want to surprise them.
If someone was just
sitting there jacking off,
Bam,
we can pop that off and go,
hey Nance,
all want to get done.
And then Jimmy stopped.com go watch it.
Subscribe.
Be a part of it.
It's only seven.