Did your own experience podcast is
brought to you by the flashlight.
A lot of people like
what the fuck is that?
You leave your use Treemont and
then it just comes onto that.
The fuck did I do man,
the Joe Rogan experience is brought to
you by the fleshlight and if you go to
Joe rogan.net and click on the link for
the flashlight and during the code name
Rogan save yourself a lot of money.
We found out 15% to be exact.
We found out that um,
the,
the Joe Rogan experience listeners who
call into the fleshlight are much more
likely to buy them, the people that, uh,
the click on the website and
much more likely to buy them.
Then the average list with many, many,
many times, which is kind of crazy,
but maybe sad. Maybe we're all a bunch
of fucking twisted perverts. Yeah. Your,
your listeners are listeners
are all per for sure. Um,
if you go to, uh, Joe rogan.net,
there's also a link for Alpha
brain. What's Alpha brain?
Joe, do you have any? Yeah,
I do. I just need more. I,
I've now become your gel.
Like the last, uh, since he
gave me that last bottle,
I think glass battery morning,
the, all the issues that, uh,
people started having about sensitivity.
We've eradicated them.
I was one of this batch. Yeah, but it
still has the same kick to it. It's, I'm,
you'd go to,
I have to go to onnit.com for all the
information because I'm not a fucking
scientist and I'm a little stoned.
But on it is o,
n n I t and what Alpha brain is,
is a nootropic.
It is a cognitive enhancing supplement.
You know,
it's a very slippery slope when you
start advertising shit. You know,
when you start selling things and people
know that the words that are coming out
of your mouth are designed to make money
and so they just assume that you will
be full of shit.
Like I can't tell you how many fucking
assholes I've had to deal with online
that say those are fucking placebo.
You're ripping people off for placebo.
It is absolutely not a placebo.
There's no way nootropics would get
to this point through the scientific
community, scientific community
to the scientific community,
so the supplement community,
there's, there's no way
it's, these are not placebos.
They use them on Alzheimer's patients.
There's considerable amount of both
anecdotal evidence research and more
research is being done and
particularly by us. We've got,
we're running it right now. We're
running some double blind placebo study.
It takes months to do these things and
I don't want to talk too much about it
until after it's over, but if the results
are bad, I'll tell you, do not worry.
The results are good. I will tell you,
don't worry. I believe in supplements.
I've always used them.
I take every day I take fish oil,
I take key laded minerals.
I take multivitamins when I don't.
I don't feel as good. I don't have
as much energy when my diet sucks,
I don't feel as good either. When I'm
not eating healthy, I don't feel as good.
I believe it's very important
to take care of this body,
to take care of this vehicle.
It doesn't mean you know that you have
to fucking be a Vegan and you can't ever
have cheat days and eat ice cream.
That's bullshit.
I just think the majority of the food that
goes into your body should be healthy.
The majority. If you want to have a
burger, want to have a fucking burger man,
what are you going to live forever?
But the majority of your food should
be healthy. And on top of that,
I am a big fan of supplementation is
the thing that I was talking about.
Sledging is this some new
compound that's supposed to also,
it's not some new one. I just took it
today for the very first time. So, uh,
I'll tell you, I'll tell you what it
does. If it makes me feel any different.
I just took it like an hour ago.
So I'm not even sure when it kicks in.
There should be those,
somebody that regulates all of these two
to make sure that you should be able to
take what you're taking. And Alpha
brain, you know, like that kind of shit.
Vitamins.
You don't have to worry about that shit.
But what you can worry about is when you
get into like compounded drugs and an
Ssri or eyes like, you know, the,
the issue that a lot of people
have had with taking a new mood,
which is another supplement we have, which
is a five HTP supplement and five HTP.
There are issues that people have
that are taking antidepressants.
So if you're taking an antidepressant,
essentially it's giving you a bunch of
dopamine, a bunch of serotonin rather.
And uh, it's a, it's giving it to you,
like the, the antidepressants are,
you're getting it from the antidepressants
and you're also getting it from the
five HTP, which is really basically
a natural antidepressant mean.
The word antidepressant mean
what is really going on? Well,
what's really going on is, and when
you're depressed, your serotonin is down.
It doesn't necessarily mean
that your life is any different,
but now all of a sudden you're enjoying
it. And there's a big debate on that.
You know,
there's a big debate on whether that's
smart and whether or not a lot of people
are taking antidepressants and fucking
with their brain chemistry when what is
really going on?
Is there an a shit stage of their life?
And if they can learn by
these bad feelings and learn
by the lessons they could
possibly move to a better
place in life where you know,
you eliminate all these things
that are making you feel bad,
improve upon all these areas that you
have real problems with and then you won't
have these bad feelings all the time.
You won't be quote unquote depressed.
But I know people that have
had fucked up lives, man,
that have used antidepressants and gotten
themselves back on track and then wean
themselves off of it and
are really happy today.
I have a friend that for you know,
he was,
he was on the verge of committing suicide.
He said he was super, super depressed,
terrible life, terrible childhood, you
know, very abusive childhood. But when,
when he got an antidepressants,
he got his shit together.
And then once he got his shit together,
he met his wife. He fell in love,
he started a business,
became very successful at this business,
then slowly weaned himself
off the antidepressants
and now he's very happy and
he's convinced that his state
of mind was directly related.
His depression was directly
related to how shit his life was,
but antidepressants saved his life. You
know, if everybody's story was like that,
I wouldn't even be remotely skeptical,
you know, I would say, hey, you know,
obviously this is a great thing,
but human beings were some slothy
fucking fuck Slovenly cunts.
And if we find just any excuse to take a
pill, oh, I need a Xanax, I can't deal.
I can't deal. There's a lot of
that going on and wasn't trim,
smile and help me out. I'm typing.
So fairly new trim spa. Um, anyway,
I have a pot of term spot. I should kill
you. No, that's not phen. Phen right now.
It's not like rip fuel,
rip fuel will kill.
I used to do Rick fuel in high school.
You won't kill everybody.
It only kills pussies, but
it will kill you. I'm crazy.
I don't know why he used to do that.
Then I think it was like kick it. Yeah,
speed is speed. It's like,
just like caffeine is speed.
I remember thinking is speed.
What is speed?
Speed's a nickname for things that
are accelerants things a fucking fire,
your heart rate through the roof.
That shit's terrible to do Jujitsu on.
I did Jujitsu on it once. I almost had
a heart attack because it was like,
it was like being on crank like you have,
your heart is already pounding too
hard and Jujitsu is all about like
maintaining your heart rate.
Like it's all about like keeping a
pace going and uh, you know, and,
and not wearing out.
Like if you just try to sprint real quick,
then you're going to get tired and
then the guy's gonna choke you.
Like it's all about like, and then
the rip fuels the worst for that shit.
It's terrible for your cardio.
You're like, I remember
the bottle, I see the logo.
It's not illegal. Right. They
got rid of it. Right. It,
they might've changed the formula because
I feel like I've seen it recently.
My point about all this Alpha brain,
all this supplement stuff is anything
that I'm telling you about is something
that I use and I believe in.
That's it. I don't need to do this.
I don't need to sell these things.
I'm selling these things cause they're
legit because I support them because I
use them, I get the benefits
from them, I believe in them,
and then after all that
we make money from them.
We make it as fair as possible.
I'm trying to rip off no one.
I want everyone to feel like
they had a good interaction.
So the way it works is when you
buy your first order of 30 pills,
if you don't like it,
you get 100% of your money back.
You don't have to send the pills back.
You don't have to send the bottle back.
You don't have to do shit. You just
say, this sucks. Give me my money back.
That's how much we believe that you will
like it and you'll want to keep using
it.
There's nothing better in this life.
Then doing your best to improve your
quality of thinking and the quality of
thinking that you have.
When you've done your best and you're,
you're taking care of your body and
you improve your quality of thinking,
you make better choices.
When you make better choices and
you think about things better,
your life becomes better.
I think there's no more important thing
in this life than maintaining a quality
of thinking. And that's what
I use Alpha brain for. And uh,
that's why I endorse it. That's, I take
three of these bitches before every fox.
I mean, yeah, I can forward
it gave me a jerk. Yeah.
Well, the last one, I
used to take three cars,
but then I started getting that a slight
headache for was like I had a shaky
hand when I was playing pool.
Yeah. I just think, uh, you know,
if you were playing football or something
crazy, I think four would be great. Um,
but what,
you know,
the thing that I've been getting
into lately is the shroom tech. This,
the quarter steps mushrooms,
uh,
supplement dude is 100% legit.
I had way more energy than I deserved.
Last night I was the last guy on the mat.
I'm never the last guy in the map,
but I took five of those fucking things.
It says take four, but I took five. She's
five right before class. It was awesome.
We're going to over desk.
It's just mushrooms.
It's just mushrooms and B12 and be 12 you
don't overdose on, you piss it all out,
but man, it's amazing how you can
affect your energy levels by nutrients.
Really amazing. You know? I, like I said,
I've eaten like shit for a few
days and especially as I got older,
I really feel it much more now than when
I was 20 when I was 20 I felt like I
need to eat a cheeseburger and then go
work out and it wouldn't even hardly
bother me that much,
but now it's just every little thing
has to be in order for my body to feel
smell.
Anyway,
go to [inaudible] dot com
check out all that shit,
check out all the different
supplements that are available.
I stand by and we got credibles
kettle bells around their coming out.
That'll be coming out very
soon. I definitely, yeah,
I think they're already
on the up on the website.
We're just trying to figure out
the pricing and the shipping.
It's very fucking expensive
to ship cannon balls. Yeah,
it was really canon balls with
handles its way it should or whatever.
It makes it heavy.
Should be something that you could
just buy at a grocery store. Yeah,
but no one's going to do that. I wouldn't.
What if it was something like, oh yeah,
it's just a bunch of pepper.
The lightest kettle bell
pepper.
That's the most ridiculous
shit I've ever heard.
They have some that you fill
up with water, but again,
you can't make it heavy
enough. You know, if I,
when a 50 pound Kettlebell to train with,
I have a bowling ball bag that I bring
on the road with me or if I want to bring
them on the road because all
I have to do is bring one.
I don't need a gym anywhere.
If I bring one 50 pound kettle bell,
I got one workout that I do
with a 35 pound kettle bell.
It's fucking awesome man.
It's a brutal workout and it's
a 35 pound kettle bell. Yeah,
I need to get him my waist seam at
target and I always went to buy one.
I just been using my Pekinese instead.
Did you know you needed to do for real,
you need to just take up
something like spinning.
I don't have time to do any.
You got make my time.
There's people that work full time
jobs and train for the Olympics. Man.
You've got the time too busy son.
Get realistic.
If you really wanted to do something, you
would join a gym, join a gym membership,
join,
join a gym and go to like some classes.
Go to like a hardcore class where you,
you enjoy it.
Somebody else is making me
do it and then it's over.
You're doing it with everybody else
in the class. It's a really easy
way to get a good workout in.
Yeah.
I know a friend that's going to yoga
class some wing until she graduates.
So I can be your first person cause lunch.
Just go to yoga because I don't want
to do it in front of other people.
I want my own private yoga instructor
in my bedroom or something. You should,
you should go to yoga class
and meets. That's embarrassing.
Yoga bitches, Sun Yoga.
People are embarrassing so far.
If all the time is I too many
uncomfortable moments and yoga. Well,
it's really uncomfortable was when he
talked to them and they bring up like
crystals and energy and that's, that's
where Yoga crosses the line, right?
It crosses,
crosses the line into fuckery.
When you start worshiping rocks and the
energy that come off these rocks and you
start, you know, sacred this and sacred
that, unless you're fucking around,
you say sacred.
You know,
you have to be fucking around or talking
about like war or something like that.
That's it. That's the end
of the commercial. Um, go
to Joe Rogan. Dot. Neck.
Use the code name, Rogan. Click on the
link for Alpha brain. Use the code name.
Rogan. Save yourself 10% off.
All right. You dirty bitches,
great Joe Rogan Experience
Joe Rogan podcast all day.
Hopefully internets. I
got to wear this, uh,
this tee shirt that I got
from these kids in Canada.
Blue Gorilla Glue radio. It's
out in the hallway. Cool.
I'll go get it. But I just did
this show in Edmonton, man,
these fucking shows.
It's all,
there's many times where we're doing
these shows and hanging out after these
shows where I'm like,
well,
this feels like it's some sort
of a weird dream or something.
This doesn't seem realistic. It doesn't
seem like that, you know, there's,
it's when you're just sitting
around and it's just you and me,
and this is how this all started.
So you and me and a laptop just sitting
around and then you think of the fucking
numbers of people now that,
that tune into this thing.
It's very surreal because to us,
we're still in the same spot.
We're still doing the same thing.
We're still sitting in my fucking hoarders
office boxes is turning into hoarders
office.
Don is ridiculous.
I've got to throw an
almost everything out.
It's like a lot of it is like gifts
though from people that uh, yeah.
You have a lot of cool Schwag here man.
Yeah and a lot of apple
products that are unopened.
Just the thing over there,
you got to,
it was a bag over there with an apple,
something that's stuff in there.
It's funny here on my hard drive crashed
so I had to get a new hard drive. Yeah,
sorry. I had to get a new
Imac. My Shit's been acting.
All my max have been acting really fucked
up lately and there's two things that
that that that are really what?
It's a government man.
Well one is iPhone has a problem
that no one has been talking about.
I haven't seen where the text messages
are disappearing right in front of your
eyes.
Like go sit there,
open it up and suddenly at the
text messages just disappears.
I told you,
you sent me a photo and the photo vanish.
I looked down and I saw the preview of
the photo and then I went back to my
thing I did was in the middle of playing
pool, so I didn't look at it right then.
When I went back to look at
it later, it was gone. Yeah,
that Shit's been happening to me more
and more and I don't hear anybody else
talking about government. The government
stealing our texts or text messages.
Yeah, they're going to find out
how fucking boring we really are.
Talk a lot of shit. Talk a little shit
on the podcast. Occasionally smoked pot.
Ooh,
dangerous.
And the second thing is the flash on
safari and chrome and everything has been
really horrible lately to the point
where it's been freezing up my computer
until I moved the cursor
down to the toolbar.
And then for some reason I
don't have to click on anything.
I just moved the cursor down to
the bottom and unfreeze everything.
And it's really weird.
I don't you think that's a memory issue
is that no, it's the government, Joe,
the government governments in flash
governments in flash from Flash,
they could learn a lot from flash.
Right.
Because I guess a lot of those probably
pornos that are online or flash or
aren't they? Yeah. A lot
of them are still flash,
but a lot of them have been
switching over to html five,
which seems to be a decent,
that's so you can watch them on iPads
once they realized that people were going
to iPods. Right. It's amazing. They should
figure that out by now. Right? Yeah.
It's amazing how,
how porn just evaporated before our
eyes as far as like as an industry.
My next door neighbor's a up porn guy
was my next door neighbor years ago down
the street and uh,
I think they just repossessed his
house or something like that. It's um,
these guys like, we're like high
on the hog. I mean these guys,
I know dudes who were in the porn business
who are making millions and millions
of dollars. I mean they had incredible
cars. They had these beautiful houses.
These guys are making fuckloads
of money selling DVDs.
Well the Internet just took the wheels
out from under them like completely and
that's an industry that's like,
nobody talks about that because the,
there's some hidden sort of a moral
like judgment that you pass on porn till
it's like fuck them.
They didn't deserve it.
They didn't deserve the money they were
making. You know, they deserved it.
They got it on the back of
exploited women and they, you know,
blah blah blah blah blah.
For whatever reason we make a distinction.
It's legal and it's a business,
but it doesn't need to be
bailed out as much as cars do.
Car companies like we can't lose Chevy.
But if we lost vivid pictures,
who gives a fuck?
But then the hypocritical aspect of it
is fucking this is $1 billion industry is
everybody's using it. Like to pretend
that everybody's not using it is insanity.
Like the amount of people that are
online that are looking at porn,
it's something crazy. It's something
like porn is 40% of everything online.
Something nutty like that. I
forgot, pulled that right of my ass.
I think I might have read that, but I
can't keep track of all these numbers.
You stop and think about that number.
That's a lot of God damn people
and everyone's pretend in this.
This industry doesn't need to
be saved. You know, they, they,
they couldn't get any respect if they
wanted to try to get a bail out for the
government because the economy
went south from, they'd be like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
What are you gonna do man?
What are you gonna do with newborn?
What are you going to get by?
I think it's like everything that
like look at like, you know, you have,
porn is now not making money because now
the access to being able to do porn is
so much easier.
Radio station DJ's aren't making as much
money and they're failing because now
podcasting has been able to tick to read
and easily you can do it at your own
house now and have your own radio
show and that's just like TV.
That's like every single thing ever now
because everything's now more diluted.
You're more, it's more accurate
to what you want to see.
Like I want to see a band that's a two
people are dead in the drummer still
alive. You know it's probably out there
on the Internet if that's your fetish,
if that's your thing,
that's your music choice.
Where before it was kind of like
whatever you were pumped or whatever was
available at the CD shop or and whatever
you were sold on the local radio
station.
So money is just more scattered out and
like porn is easier now because like me,
I can now watch some girl that's a
waitress and fucking Indiana, you know,
put a Dildo in her ass for free.
You know, I'm going to watch that.
I'm going to have to spend my fucking,
I've never spent money on porn in my
life now I'm fucking spending $20 a month
sending it to her.
And that's what a lot of these porn
websites used to charge $20 a month.
So you are your go to Web Cam Sites on
the web cam sites. These are real people.
These are real fucking blue collar.
Even in your jerky jerking off,
like you're like Middle America. If you
don't have to be like I'm not hot. Right.
You're like, I'm like, uh, I
like normal fucking girl. Yeah.
Hot Normal girl. Yeah, six.
But she's got a nice smile once in
a while I'll click on the Africa,
the checkbox on the very bottom
cause that you could, uh, you know,
a lot of these websites you can choose
what's countries you want to see.
And so I just see a bunch of African
women sitting around and going, hey,
by the Lesbian Africans that
women I've noticed. Wow.
They just probably get tired of dudes
raping them. They just go those bow wow.
African, what do they jerking
off with gourds or anything
crazy like, no, they're,
they're pretty basic and it's funny like
the vibrators into different countries,
how they look like the ones that they
were using really did seem like antiques,
you know, like wooden or, or you know,
something like that where like then you
go to like click on Asia and all those
girls that they're either Vietnam,
Vietnam,
where they're using bamboo
sticks and stuff like that.
Or they're actually like Japanese where
they have these high tech vibrators like,
like once you've never seen before and
it looked like fucking dolphins with hats
on.
Wow.
How many different web cam
shows have you watched know?
Oh, I do it every night. It's my
new Twitter man. I go to it time.
I want to masturbate now.
I go to my free cams and
I have no connection with
these guys. It's my favorite,
my free cams.
I fucking love it.
I saw about five different people on how
does it go? If you go to my free cams,
it's, well one, it's the worst
designed website ever and, and I,
I don't know who owns it and
if they ever listened to this,
really spend the money on your website.
That shit so fucking crazy.
But you just get this
checkerboard of cameras and it's,
you just scroll down, you choose
what options you want, you choose,
click on one of them and
then it's usually free.
And what you do is just hang out in
this chat. I'm looking at it now.
It's just a bunch of photos of girls.
Those are sticking out.
These can't all be real
girls. Yup. Yup. Oh No.
Go to a home or what's online right now?
What's online right now?
Okay.
Yeah. These are girls that are
online models online. Yeah.
These are girls are online. And
then when you go to them, yeah,
you go to them and when you log in then
they showed a little previews of them.
And so every time you log in you
just see a bunch of previous,
oh this girl's just playing
with her titties. Titties. Wow.
This is bizarre.
Bizarre.
And the thing is is you'd never have
to spend money there, you know, ever.
But this is so strange.
What am I awesome?
One of my favorite things to do is, what
you do is you put 20 bucks in at a time,
you get kind of like points,
you know?
And so my favorite thing to do is you
can also spy on like private shows like
these girls are doing with other
people. You know, it costs more,
but you kind of jump in real
quick and you're just like,
what's going on in this creepy room?
Like, what's this guy making this girl?
Do you know what I mean?
How can you spy on private rooms?
It will say that the show is private
and then underneath it it says spy on
private show. So you could just
sit there and it's ridiculous.
That's not private then. Yeah.
But if you knew that going in,
you know you're like all right,
whatever it, cause it's a lot of money.
Like I'll do it like 10 seconds time like
right when I know I'm about to come or
I'll find a private show real quick. I'm
like okay. And it's a little bit hotter,
you know? But I don't understand
how they can sell it as private.
You could be a hundred percent private,
like mid private.
And so the mid privates are what most
people do because if it's 100% private
costs more for the person to do.
The private chef,
people want to get really freaky.
There'll be a hundred percent hundred
percent private or he'd just go on,
got to do,
take advantage of your area.
He should probably doesn't get
off to a couple of those girls.
Just cause you don't see it every day.
It's like,
well we're looking at a girl's ankle
and the 17 hundreds you don't see it.
There's like old ladies or there's like
black really old black fat ladies that
kind of turns me on once in a while.
It's because you don't see that.
You don't masturbate to that everyday.
Some of these bitches just,
they just sit there and do it enough.
It was big giant guitars.
But that's what's cool is when you find,
when you create account,
you could see it refreshes
all these avatars
and you can see who's doing what.
Like oh I'm clicking on the growth of
Delta owner. She muted everybody. Yeah.
How dare she? Uh, yeah cause you have,
that's where you have to create count
cause he can't chat until you actually put
it.
I'm not doing any chat.
When you chat,
what do you talk to these girls about it?
I usually just say off guard,
I want to take you to off garden
and things like that. Yeah.
And it makes them laugh
every time. They're like, you
want to take me? No, I love,
I have guard anything.
I would love the other or one of these
days you're going to be doing this to a
girl who knows the show. Oh, it's
already happened, dude. Dude,
you tell her who you are because I've
talked about this website before.
I'll say like all of garden and people
would like desk God for life bitches and
stuff like that. Shit. That's a lot of
our listeners are already on this shit.
These girls that are really hot. Yeah.
I can't believe this. This is so crazy.
It's like peering into this world of hot
girls that are taking off their clothes
and then just sitting around here.
The window's really small though.
Does it expand it? There's this five
dots on the right side of the Webcam.
Oh Dude. You just dragged that shit. Do
whatever you want to do some screen caps.
No, nevermind. Wow.
Screencast. Oh, that's right.
Because then they know. Then they will
fix it all. Sweetie, why are you smoking?
That bums me out. A lot of marijuana use
marijuana use doesn't bum me out man.
But when I see a chick with a cigarette,
I want to suite,
there's this black or I wish I could
remember her name on it and she never
really shows her face too much.
But she has a hot body and she
always has this huge fucking Dildo,
just suction cup onto the coffee table
and the camera's always just her.
But just teasing it like, like she's
just going to take the whole thing. Oh.
But she talks,
oh my God,
I'm such a bad little girl.
Do you know how they have those uh,
previews?
Like if you click on some porn sites,
they have like a preview.
You will have to watch their camp,
a commercial for their camp site before
they show you the actual porn. Yeah,
they had, you know, you don't,
you get different ones every time.
I Dunno who is editing these fucking
things, but one of 'em was this chick.
She was, she was at least like, I
would say 35 40 pounds overweight.
She was black as coal and the bottom
or feet or in front of the camera.
So I was like a bomber feet,
which are really pink.
It was like an odd pink and her feet
are like bucking in front of the camera
while she is fucking the
shit out of her black,
black pussy.
With this deal though,
it could not have been a least sexual
thing. It was like, it was, it was like,
like grunting and shit. It was, I mean,
I guess it was sexual if that's what
you're into, but for me it was like,
what the fuck? Like I, I
would put my boner away.
You may be washed out for a minute. It's
like, what are you trying to do? Who's,
who's looking at dangling? Yeah, she'll
fuck me. There's certain girls we go,
she'll fuck you. You know, you look,
you look at the guys they fuck on film
and the things that people do to them and
you know, girls that like drink a
of calm or guys pull their eyes,
lids open and shoot loads in their
eyes. That girl, fuck yeah, let go.
That poor kid, that poor kid doesn't
know what the fuck she's doing.
She's a little fuck Zombie on my free
cams. It's tried to search for this name,
apple bottom teen. That's the
black chick. And if she's online,
just turn up your speakers and
fucking sit back and enjoy life.
I can't watch this and do
a show at the same time.
We want to blanket for
your bone or did here.
That's just be sitting here watching
street of your jacket makes me my boner
beggar. Hey, I've been sitting on and
it's warm in my field, but it would
so is the uh,
what is the profit?
How do they make profit from this site?
The girls get a fraction of whatever
money is donated to them and I,
I don't think it's very good.
I'm sure there's other
websites that are a lot better.
Like my free camps that does not pay the
girls as good as the lot of the other
websites. Oh really? Wow. His name
is fuck me hard. Really? Yeah.
If you find apple bottom team,
dude, you're going to love it.
Some bitches just leave their camera on
and leave the room. That shit is rude.
This approach. There's a lot of that to
fuck me hard. How dare you? Fuck me. Hard.
69 she just seen her fucking
computer desk. How dare you?
They just get lazy.
It's probably,
they probably lived their whole
day in front of the Webcam,
just trying to collect money. Yup. Wow.
What a weird way for
chicks to get attention.
And some of them really fucking love it.
I bet they loved that.
Every time they log on, there's thousands
of guys waiting to beat off to them.
You know?
That's like a gotta be kind of a trip.
And I bet if a lot of chicks have shit
jobs and they start doing this and raking
in the cash saying,
you know how I mean,
just like doing podcasting from
your house, how easy is it to,
you can just now have a job that you
can do from your house and that's what
these girls are doing.
They're like,
why do I want to be a waitress at Chili's
when I could fuck make twice as much a
home? Just fucking shut in my bottle.
Yeah. He's a what? A crazy roll. The dice.
It is for a girl to be born hot. Such a
powerful fucking roll that dice. Yeah,
because it's really all you need
for a lot of these girls. I mean,
all they need is the,
just to have the right bone structure
and the right dimensions and the right
look and boom. Everybody didn't mean
it's just like hitting the lottery.
I guess.
It's sort of his for a dude to,
but dude's still got to go out
and fucking make something happen.
You can't be a loser and look like that.
There's no losers that look like,
what's her name? Christy
Canyon. Remember that porn star?
There's no losers still look like
that even though she was a porn star.
You know what I'm saying? Right.
Well, she was so hot. She was,
the best example I can put up was what's,
um,
the fuck is her name?
That, oh, Cindy Crawford.
It's impossible to be a loser.
If you look like Cindy Crawford,
you really can't be a loser. She's
just too hot. You know what I mean? And
be like,
you could be a guy and you could be like
the male equivalent to Cindy Crawford,
like bone structure Wise Hanson was,
and still wind up fucking broken
alone easily. You know, you,
you're not going to be a loser if you
look that good. She's just too hot.
This is it. Like values. It's
so much somehow or another,
some wealthy man will find his way
into her life and marry her away.
But for a dude she does. You
know, it's not worth as much.
It's not,
it's not as much of a roll of the dice
for a guy to be born good looking for,
for a girl, if that's all you're
trying to get done in this life.
Not saying that that's all. Every
woman was trying to get done, ladies.
It's all get crazy. Don't, don't get
angry at me. That's not what I'm saying.
Like that's all you're capable of.
That's not what I'm saying,
but I'm saying it's a fucking big
deal. It's a big deal. It'd be hot.
Yeah. But you know, a lot of these girls
and these rooms are not even hot at all,
but that's even makes it hotter because
this girl looks like somebody that would
never do this and she's doing it.
That's high. I love this shit, man.
I ain't never been more addicted
to porn that ever in my life.
When I was 18. How long did this
start off? When did this start out?
But I don't know man.
I think I've always like Anthony from opn.
Anthony.
Uh, there used to be this website that I
used to be addicted to that he's always
talking about, I forget the name of it
was a Webcam website. Cal Talk. How talk.
I used to pay for a membership for pow
talk and one of the best things is while
the show's going on, used to go on
these girls that were fans of opiate,
Anthony would just be sitting there for
shoving vibrators on in there and all of
us would be watching,
even while they're doing a radio show,
everyone would be watching that shit off.
Didn't you show me that once
at the Tattoo place? Yeah.
You were showing me we were at
the tattoo place. Yeah. Yeah.
And you were a broadcaster when you're
getting your tattoo. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And Pal. Talk, talk, and then you're
showing me, look at this girl,
what the fuck is she doing?
Just regular girls finger banging
themselves, fingered the girl,
had two fingers in her butt hole and like,
Whoa,
Jesus. That was one of our
first broadcast, you know,
doing that and doing green rooms,
but that,
I remember sitting there just with
my laptop just pointing at you.
How many texts a day do you get to say
desk squad, bitches, twitters, Twitter.
So yeah.
Yeah. Twitter is Facebook messages. Yeah.
It's funny how that all came out of some
fucking silly meeting at the opiate.
Anthony show a dumb thing to
name yourselves death squad,
but because somebody else named us, we're
allowed, we're allowed to keep it. Have
you heard the band death squad? I think
those are bad bands called Jessica.
Really? Yeah, there's, there's,
there's a song called red band,
which is actually pretty good
at listening to ban the ban.
I think it's that.
It's either the artist is named red band
or the song is called red bands from a
diner or
uh, like a year ago, two
years ago, something like,
hmm, wonder if he is a fan.
I don't know. Podcast fan
maybe likes, yeah. I don't
know. It's weird. Do you ever,
do you ever, uh, do you ever want to
sing again because you had that hit song
and I think somebody should dubstep
that song. I really did have a song.
It was only a hit in one town though.
Tempe, Phoenix and Tempe and Phoenix,
Arizona. For whatever reason,
there was these guys, uh,
Tim and Mark Shit. Why is it always
like so hard to remember? Oh,
that's what else? Pretty short term.
Supposed to take four a day. There.
They were great guys. Um, and they, uh,
had a radio station down there and they
played it and there were like one of the
few people that ever played it.
And for whatever reason
it took off in one town.
Like I sold way more records in
Phoenix than I did anywhere else.
It became one of the reasons why I
filmed my 2005 special in Phoenix. She's,
I just had a bigger draw there than almost
anywhere. It was real weird, you know,
and p and when I started doing
standup, people were like, do the song,
like I can't fucking sing. Like I only,
I only did that song because it was like,
you know,
it was broken up into like choruses.
We could splice it all together.
It was all done like
in a computer with um,
what is it called, what's
pro tools, you know,
how they do it and move everything
around. So it was like, you know,
if I just did it by myself,
then I'd have to practice and actually
like start singing it and like I just
want to do it for fun. And the idea
was Warner brothers executive idea,
his idea was if I came
up with like a song,
then they could play something
on the radio to help sell the CD.
So song was about Voodoo Pussy.
The song was called Voodoo poo nanny.
And you could probably find it on,
it's probably not even an iTunes because
I don't think that CD is on iTunes.
I'm going to get it put on iTunes.
My first CD from 1999 Warner brothers
was bought out by Disney in the middle of
my, um, my time there. What about her
records? I wonder whether the records,
I think it was Disney, but they went
like super family values and my,
my CD was dirty as fuck.
My CD started out with two guys fucking
each other in the basement of one of the
most amazing,
I'm sure everyone's heard it,
but it was one of the
most amazing skits ever.
It's one of my favorite things I've
ever done because I knew that, uh,
I could never do it anywhere else.
I was like,
I want to write something that's
so fucked up and it can't be,
it can't be on stage. I can't do
it on stage cause I'd act it out.
It wouldn't be as funny. You want to do
it visually? No, I don't want to see,
I don't want to actually see it.
I just,
it's better to actually just hear this
and what it is is two guys who were gay,
but they try to pretend
that they're not gay.
They just really like lifted weights
and it always winds up them fucking each
other and always like,
you got a fucking great ass.
It's wound and muscular.
Really? Eh, dude, I bet.
I don't even think I could get my cock in
your ass. Oh, cool man. And it became, uh,
you know, just this thing and you
know, me and Brian Cowen did it.
Brian counts the other voice in
it and I'm the fuck is her name.
Goddammit. Kelly. Kirsten. Yes.
Kelly. Kirsten for real. I know. Yeah,
but you had to say that name all the
time. Chuck, Here's together Carson.
But you'd say it as Joey and I was like
an olive garden between me and Jodie is.
Yeah, Kelly. Uh, Kelly played my
mom or mom, my, and Brian's mom.
She's so funny. And, uh,
Ginger Lynn introduced to
[inaudible] on the, uh,
on the CD and I got to do a
thing with her the other day.
I did Dave's old porn with her.
Dave's old porn is,
first of all it's David tell
was so fucking funny man.
He's just one of those guys. It's like,
and he works hard man in between takes,
they got notes,
notebooks and shit and they're going
over scenes and what's a good scene and
what about this and then and, and you
know, and then you sit there and you,
you watch these porns and then you
do like mystery science theater.
I remember that show. You've seen Dave's
old porn for those who haven't seen it,
you're sitting on a couch with Dave and
you're just kind of clowning on porn and
you realize the difference between
porn then and now. So much more hair,
so much more here. So much more hand.
And it was like, they were like,
they were like all sexy.
The real boob look back then,
it was one of my favorite things because
they all had really nice big natural
boob, kind of natural boom. They all
kind of like hung a little, oh yeah,
they did that. It was nice. Like
Ginger Lynn had small boobs,
but they were really nice. They
weren't small. They were like,
I would say ginger's mom, like
medium and small, but yeah,
and it seems like bigger areolas were
more popular back then or lately.
Maybe girls area let's have been shrinking
for some reason. Maybe it's nature.
Cell phones could be
radiation that kills the bees.
It's true. It's just strange watching
like we were talking about, uh,
whether or not society has changed or
whether or not people have just more
access to it now.
We see it more because of Twitter,
but people always been fucked up.
And I say that porn is probably the best
evidence that society has gotten more
fucked up because there was like
very little dark porn back then.
There wasn't even, there wasn't
even any slapping, you know,
there's no dick slapping and there was no,
no pulling in the hair and shooting
loads up their nose and stuff like that.
Like they're doing,
they do Mike mean anger shit now you know,
and there's,
there's something hot about slobber all
over your face and streaked Mascara and
asa, Asa, Akira man, I heard
latest DVD is one of my favorites.
I forget the guy. I think his name
is Rocco or something like that.
Fucking just fucking man,
like dragging her by the hair.
She's just gagging and he's just
fucking, oh, and Nacho. Nacho. Nacho.
That dude's awesome.
I don't think I have any,
I don't give a shit about porn guys
much like I don't ever look out for one,
but that every time I see him
in a movie, he's cool. He's,
he's a, he's a cool ass. Be Very
violent with the girls. Great.
I'm dragging around with their hair.
It doesn't seem to be a nice thing to do.
Somebody that you want to fuck. Do you
think some girls like that? I didn't.
I never thought so, but yeah. Wow.
They definitely did it. Oh No.
Girls like being choked.
Yeah. Veronica slap me.
I slapper. Yeah. She always like slap me
in the face. I'm like, no, don't say that.
Because then you put it on line. You're
fucking, she does punish videos. Yeah,
that's dark dude.
I would be like,
I don't want to connect me beating
the fuck out of you with something.
The sexual. That just seems like a bad
idea. I had a girl that wanted to rape me.
She wanted me to rape her.
Whether
she would tell me she
would want to wait me too,
but she would actually tell me
that she wants me to rainbow. Yeah,
she wants to fight me off.
I'm like,
that's not something you want
to connect with sexuality with.
My sister always wanted me to do that.
Why Jesus Brian,
don't you think that would that be awful
mean taboo subject because rape itself
obviously is a deplorable act,
but the fact remains that there are girls
that get turned on by that deplorable
act.
There's girls that have these fantasies
of getting like finding themselves in
the wrong place and the wrong
time and a fucking pack.
A wild thugs come out with 14 inch Cox
and just forced her to suck their dicks
while one guy bangs or from behind.
There's girls who have fantasies
like they're really scared,
but that would really be excited and they
probably fingered themselves thinking
about that.
And you know,
they don't ever risked their actual
physical wellbeing in life by putting
themselves in a situation
where that could happen.
But the fact is they
could do that at any time.
Girls can just drive around to a group
of guys at any time and get out and go,
hey boys, what's going on? Is that
talking about this and the guys,
come on over here. You want to
suck my cock? Yeah, I'd love to.
It's not hard for a girl to find a
cocktail she shouldn't talk about.
Cause once they figured that shit out,
what do mean anyone's? I figure it out.
They're just going to wander around you.
You don't think they know it already.
Please do. Girls know it already. You
don't think they know the routine?
They know it. Of course. Massive
knowledge of their power. Women,
women have power like a superhero,
a hot girl,
hot girl in a bikini or a hot girl and
a mini skirt walking through a mall.
Every guy stops. And you
just immediately go, oh,
there is one there because why?
Because you know that if you are alone
naked with her and she was blowing you,
it would be out standing.
It'd be such a great feeling
to have that face suck
in your costs. 75% chance, right?
75% chance that that or that,
that girl does not have to give a good
blow job. No, that's not true at all.
I think more girls suck.
I blow jobs that are good at
it by a large one mark mark,
you do in the wrong girl son. It's
very rare that you find a bad blow job.
It's hard to find a bad blow
job if a girl was enthusiastic.
If a girl's enthusiastic, just like
if you're enthusiastic about her,
if you're both turned on,
she's going to give you good head,
like you're going to eat her pussy. Good.
Like when you eat a girl's pussy. Dot.
Are you trying to like, you want her to
feel as good as you can make her feet,
right?
What is the a hundred percent goal?
That's a woman's goal too and she's
blowing you. You just know. But I think I,
maybe I'm more sensitive
to teeth or something.
Maybe just getting some lazy bitches
that are chewing on your dick
suck. Have you ever had a
girl data byte it? Yeah. No,
not like mad at me or anything. No.
No. I always feel like, you know,
like especially back in the day
when you did a lot drugs and stuff,
I was thought this girl's or we're just
going to snap out of it and what they're
doing and just start by Mescalin
flashback and chomp down on your ball bag.
Ah, some guy a recently got
bid on the balls by, uh,
I think it was a cop got bid on
the balls by a, by a convict.
God wouldn't let go of his balls
either as biting him through the pants.
Like they had the guy like nice
job. Yeah. Think of that shit.
That shit's happening,
man. Ouchy bath salts.
We're all going to be
bitten the ball soon. Yeah.
Does other people that have done
bath salts and say it's no big deal.
I have a feeling that bath salts
or a bunch of different fucking,
or it's just how your body reacts to pass.
So it's just like any other drug,
you know?
It's just like fucking,
you have somebody that's borderline
skitzo and they fucking smoke weed.
That person becomes fucking psychotic.
Hmm. That's a real good point.
It's so true. People don't know.
You know when people say, hey man, should
I do mushrooms? It's, I don't know you.
What the fuck are you crazy?
I would never tell anybody to do anything.
Although I tell everybody they
should do mushrooms drink.
But what I say everybody,
I don't mean everybody.
I just mean everybody's not fucked up.
Right.
If you're barely holding onto reality,
I don't recommend psychedelic drugs.
I don't recommend alcohol for sure.
I don't recommend anything.
But get your shit together. You know,
go to a doctor, find out what's wrong,
you know, whatever. Whatever you
got to do, get your shit together.
That's more important than psychedelics
did. That fucking cat helicopter shit
that everyone's been fucking flooding the
tweets with. And if you haven't heard
about explain it to all the folks at home.
Somebody's cat died.
And to remember him,
he liked to make helicopters
or something like that.
And so he turned his cat into
a whole copter. He stuffed
it and it made like his,
Paul's like spread out kind of like,
you know that's like doing a snowman in
the snow and each one of them had like a
helicopter fan on it. And then so he
sits there and flies is dead cat around.
And at first I watched it and I was
horrified and then I was like this is the
coolest thing in the whole entire road.
I hope this catches on.
Cause I could just imagine a bunch of
cats, helicopters flying in the sky.
And that would be cool if it became
popular cause then I'll kite is going to
attack. But if there was cats
everywhere in the sky at all times,
it could be going down sunset and
there's everyone had their old dead cats.
Like that'd be cool. That'd be tons of
cats everywhere. This really is crazy.
But then I was thinking,
what if it crashes?
And then it's like fucking knows falls
off because it hits concrete or something.
That would be disturbing now I now I think
it's creepy. Well you just got a knee,
put a helmet on him.
You see his little fucking cat face.
That's the funniest face ever.
A large plexiglass dome over his head.
Like he's a space cat or even better.
No, I'm in a space suit is his
head. It's actually pretty cool.
Or actually get the clear film
companies that did the IPAD,
like clear films to
make like a clear armor,
like have an arm or for your cat where
it's just like some kind of crystallized
shit.
That's awesome.
That is awesome.
Did you hear that there's another drone
attack that killed some top al Qaeda
Guy?
Yeah. Wasn't that Persian? Is it
purple or was it a Siamese cat?
Can you imagine if the army starts really
using cat cat weapon? That's awesome.
Can you imagine if like there was a
country where like they used flying pigs
because like Muslims would be terrified
of house Higgs flying through the air
and cows. If you go to
war with India, India,
yeah, they, they killed some dude
in Pakistan. That's what it is.
That's kind of fucked up man.
That we're not really in Pakistan,
but Pakistan is the place where we
try out all of our newest shit. Right?
Cause we can get away with it.
We must have some sort of a weird deal
with the government or the government
won't say anything. We're, we're sending
spaceships into their air. I mean,
we're sending like some science fiction
things that were controlling from
halfway around the world with
a remote control and they're,
they're launching missiles.
I mean,
it's really crazy that they're
allowed to do that. I, you know, look,
I'm 100% in support and get rid of bad
guys and taking all the terrorists out
and all that happy horse shit.
The legit terrorists.
But this is a crazy little
precedent to set the year,
allowing space ships to fly
around in launch missiles.
Hell fire, bunker buster fucking
missiles at these people.
That's what they're called.
Hell fire. They'll dig.
They're allowed to spray rockets from
the sky and blow you out of the room out
of the road. You just wandering along.
You don't even know they're there.
They're like a mile away in a rocket
comes in fucking you would disappear.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
It's amazing that that's how we're
doing more right now in Pakistan.
That's the peak of the technological war
right now is going on right there and
very few people are even aware of it.
You know, you just hear drone attack.
That's what you hear, you know on on
the, on the radio or drone attack on CNN,
but you don't really stop and think
about what the fuck that means.
There's a remote controlled flying object
that launches missiles at people and
they're watching a camera through it
halfway around the world pressing buttons
and launching these things. It's
incredible. The technology is just,
it's amazing what they can do now. It
doesn't. That one that crashed and I ran,
it wasn't, there was another moment
where life feels like a fake movie.
Where would they,
they'd fucking captured our shit.
And Obama goes to the news and talks
about it. Well we've asked for it back.
That's what he said. We've
asked for it back. Hey,
you know the thing that we were flying
around and we might have just shot
rockets at you from the sky? Yeah.
Can you give that to us? Cause so a,
we could do that again. It's weird
like what they asked for it back.
Could you imagine if I ran,
had some shit flying around over
here and taking pictures of us.
Something that's got the capability
of shooting missiles. That's crazy.
But it didn't have any missiles on it
though, right? No, that one didn't.
I could say that.
One of my random,
just how far they can
go when I have a bet.
Some of them are solar powered,
right?
Probably they must have at least something
solar. Have you seen that Fisker?
The new solar powered automobile?
It's a, it's, it's not solar powered.
Only partially solar powered. The, I'm
like stereo and things along those lines.
The roof is a series of solar
panels. Yes. I have seen that.
It's fucking beautiful.
Car Mat. Take a look up.
It's like they finally got it right
because these a shitty ass fucking Prius's
and these disgusting things.
Oh, by the way, number nine,
ninth person I've ever seen.
Throw a fucking cigarette out
the the window of their Prius.
You twats I'm watching all you hypocrite.
Cons.
It's just such a,
I know some people do it for economy.
I understand that it's not just,
but I like to think that they're green
and they're just hypocrites. Yeah. I mean,
I would buy wine.
It would just be because I don't feel
like spending $90 every time I filled my
tank up. Yeah. Well this is, um,
this is a beautiful fucking car, man.
This Fisker look at this thing, man.
Take a peek at that. Look at that shit.
It's amazing. Let's say recalls.
Yup. They recalled, recalled,
they already recalled them.
There was a fire prone hose clamp.
This was, uh, this was a while
ago. Oh no, it wasn't. It's today.
That's crazy. Recall realized
partly cloudy day stranded,
but of the January 5th is June 5th earth.
Yeah.
It's a fucking beautiful car though.
It's theirs so slow though.
I'm just so used to the the,
the pap of a car that's quick,
you know. No, no, no. I don't drive like
an Asshole, but I do love the engineering,
the responsiveness of like a
well engineered car. Pirate dice.
Was that a comedy store last night
and he can't, he's going pirate now.
He's got guys clay, where's a pirate
patch to get discounts at stores.
He is what the people say.
He says because he says he's handicapped.
He's I vet or,
and if they don't have a vet that then
he goes a senior discount is what he's
been telling people something.
I think that's what he's saying.
Or no handicap discount
and that seems hilarious.
Was his idea only take 10 shirts
and then lift the building begin.
But he had his car there. He had a, uh,
what's the charge or not to charge her,
but what's challenger Challenger?
I think it was a Buick or a dodge.
Dodge Buick hit me. His
car was amazing, man.
It made me want to get well yeah,
those are sick. How much are those?
I think fully loaded. They're like 40
grand. Oh Wow. And they're beautiful.
That shape is just so iconic. The
challenge or shape, it's just like,
you know what it's like.
It's like my old Barracuda,
but it's not going to leave you stranded
every couple days. Those old cars,
man,
they look so bad ass,
but there does the design
involved in them. Like there's,
it's so crude like drum brakes.
There's so crude.
Like he hit the brakes,
like barely stopped.
The car takes forever.
Now they have cars like the new Porsche,
the nine nine one which is the,
the new nine 11 the new Porsche nine
11 that just came out can stop from,
I think it's 60 miles an hour to a hundred
to zero in less than a hundred feet.
That's like crazy.
They do it 96 feet.
The new corvette can do that too now.
Less than a hundred feet from sixties
the old days that she would take you a
mile, it was 60 miles out,
not a mile, but you locked up.
It takes a long ass time to stop the car.
Now it's antilock brakes and
traction control and all the,
the new shit that you can do now,
the old cars or retarded,
they're just useless to have unless you're
just a hobbyist who love the idea of
like this old mechanical thing that
you were switching the gears and all.
There's a lot of people
that really do enjoy that.
But what the challenge has done is they've
gotten like most of that old look and
put it into a new car. You
know, they figured out,
they figured out how to keep that shape.
It's not a good shape for handling.
It's terrible. Like the design is
not, it's not smart. And that's what,
it's like a big heavy car too.
So like they're not that good
around corners and shit like that.
Not like a corvette or not current.
It's designed to do that. But you know,
what do you do for regular
driving? They're great. Gabri
Aubrey has one of those.
Yeah,
so it was Tom Green.
I was either thinking about selling my
car because my car gets horrible gas
mileage and getting something like
that cause I'm about to pay off my car.
Finally and I'm like, Oh, I finally
on this piece of shit, it's not pizza.
It's a great car,
but uh,
and get something like that or
just get a really shitty small car,
like something like one of those little
baby fiats or whether it's, you know,
like the teeny little cheap cars.
Dude, you wanted to get a Mustang. Um,
if you want to trade your forward in
because maybe Ford would give you a good
deal. I never thought about
[inaudible] 49 Ford. Yeah, the Mustang.
The boss 302 is not expensive.
It's not expensive at all.
Yeah. The new, the new
Mustang boss three Oh two,
I think is like 35,000
bucks and they fucking fly.
And the new Mustang Gt,
just the GT,
the GT is a fucking really good car man.
The GT is,
um,
400 plus horsepower just for the
Mustang Gt. And it's, you know,
it's a little bit crude and it's a
design. It has a live axle, which is,
it means the backend sort of
bumps around a little bit,
but it's a really fun car to drive.
Well, why would they do that?
Why would they do what? Live action.
It helps. It helps drag racing.
It helps keep the power down. They,
they, I mean, it's not that bad.
You know what it is, is it's an older
way of designing suspensions, but they,
uh, they made the best out of it.
It handles well, you know, I mean,
it doesn't handle as good as a card
with independent rear suspension,
but mean the Mustang, uh, three
Oh two, the boss three two,
it lapse a race tracks faster than
that already are eight. You know,
that Audi, a space looking car that a
Everlast house. You know, that thing,
this, uh, this bus, um,
the Laguna Seca boss
Mustang can lap, um, uh,
race tracks quicker than that, which is
pretty amazing. Yeah. And it's, uh, it's,
they only have, uh, I think it's
only 400 and something horsepower.
Yeah. But it's a, uh, it's a dope car.
It's like one of the best
bargain cars. I think it's, um,
you know, if you like, if you wanted to
get a bargain for like performance, it's,
you can only go American.
There's no real bargains in as far as
like foreign cars for performance. Yeah.
Like American cars. Like these are not bad
in a hundred days on days. What the, um,
the little sports car thing, the APP, but
you don't get that kind of performance.
You don't get 400 plus horsepower like
you getting the Mustang, you know, that's,
uh, that's just not going
to get that. This is not,
you're not gonna get that kind
of, that kind of oomph. You know?
It's like if you want a fast
car that's a foreign car,
there's a few Japanese cars are pretty
quick, you know, like the three,
seven disease pretty quick, but they
can't fuck with like this most dying.
But then you've got to get to like
big money, like, like the Nissan Gtr,
which is like $100,000,
then then shit gets crazy because
then the Japanese have one of the best
production cars, one of the fastest,
best handling cars in the world.
But you have to,
you have to get right to there before
you get that kind of performance to
universal studios for my first time the
other day. And did you really? Yeah.
And uh, it's funny because I
went on the first one I went on,
it was the terminator two ride,
which uh, you know, it's been
a while since that movie
came out. Right. And I never,
I almost freaked out because
they make you get in this,
have you been on that right before?
No.
They make you get in this huge room
and like I have no idea what if this is
going.
Yeah,
I did go in that and then you're sitting
there with all these people like,
and then the door's shut and
you're just like, all right,
this is where the gas comes out and we
all get murdered or something, you know,
like we couldn't leave.
And it's something that was just as bad
actor acting job where like this lady
comes out and Ugh, hi,
welcome to whatever, you know,
we are here in the future anyways,
all her ship or computers behind her,
since the ride is so old,
like we used to look like it
was supposed to be the future,
but now it looks really sad and
depressing like a garage sale,
like monitoring and you know what I mean?
And it's totally outdated and you don't,
and then she was like,
before we go into the next room, I want
you to look at this. And they like,
it's a video that I'm guessing when
the movie came out, which was what,
93 or something something.
Yeah,
that and that all these things
seemed really futuristic,
but now half the shit that they showed
you could do on your iPhone and it was so
weird.
Like imagine in the future
your grandmother is far
away and you want to talk to
her. How about talking to her on your
wall? You know, and you're like, yeah,
I could do that in my phone now.
You know, everything. It was like,
imagine like being able to like control
like a doctor couldn't sit somewhere
else and control an operation far away.
You can do that now.
You know doctors are doing
that now and it's weird.
Like all this shit was so perfect.
Do Doctors do remote control operations?
Yeah, I think uh, I think it's
at the very beginning stages.
But there has been a successful operations
where they've done that from remote
relic locations and stuff like that
using advanced computers and robots.
And that scares the shit out of me.
That's scary.
So I want to open you up and
remote control operating on.
So then I was really scared though because
I was like really figuring out how,
you know, shitty this ride was,
I'm like damn this, you know,
why does it universal have this?
But then you go into the next room and
you watch this really old three d movie
in a three d was really
good, you know, for his age.
And then there's this one point where
there's lots of live actors mixed in like,
like in the theater.
So like,
like this guy will come out like
a motorcycle and then like, uh,
he had like a shotgun and he'll shoot
somebody like a real, like, like,
like back like holy shit that you could
hear it, it sounded like a gunshot and,
and then you will like disappear off
the stage and it looks like it goes back
into the three d movie, Shit like
that. So it was kind of interesting.
And then they have two more,
three d screens that go around you.
And this is an old right? So
everyone's probably like, yeah dude,
welcome to 93 but the three d
was coming out at all sides.
It was really awesome.
And I guess there's a new transformers
ride there that just takes that to the
whole next level. And so I, I'm there
a Spiderman one that did that too.
I don't know. It was down in Orlando,
I think that's in Orlando. I don't.
And then there
was the Simpsons ride where you,
it was a virtual roller
coaster where you know,
it's one of the things where the whole
thing moves but you go into this like
fucking dome where the whole dome
is a movie and it's really trippy.
If I want to do shrimps and did that
cause I think I'll die and go to heaven
because it,
you go into this huge room,
you're like holy shit that and then
you feel like you're going through this
roller coaster.
There's parts where that Maggie,
a huge Maggie would like try to grab your
roller coaster and the spray like baby
powder smell.
So you start smelling baby powder
and you're like it's fucking bad ass.
What I always scary like for
a like a little kid cause I'd
fuck,
you know I was scared but I was thinking
of other things cause I was like holy
Shit. Is this one of those elevator drop
rides where you drop? Because I thought,
I thought I was going to freak out.
This is weird how they
can pull that effect off.
We're just showing you a screen and
then moving things around works.
And I wasn't even stoned. If I was
stoned, I would fucking be you.
We should go sometime, man. I've got a
season pass now. It's, it's only $20 more.
What was the big one that they had?
They had the one famous one.
There was a Jurassic Park. They
have Jurassic Park I think. Wait,
did they have drastic no,
I parked at Jurassic Park.
Yes. They must have had you.
Yeah. I feel like there's a
drastic park ride. Um, no,
but they have it a water waterworld one's
still there, which was fucking creepy.
Who wants to see a at universal the,
that is the Jurassic Park one.
There's a water scene in it.
You're in like a log? No,
the movie water road movie.
Waterworld yeah,
the fuck I was still there.
You know they have a King Kong one.
That's the one in the jaws one is the
one that you can cause pretty new. Uh Oh.
Is it within the last couple
of years they redid it. Yeah.
It's the new King Kong from like
four years ago or five years ago.
I didn't go to it and I only
went to those two because it was,
I went on a Sunday.
How many king kongs or they've
been there was the original one,
which is fucking awesome to watch today.
You ever watched it today?
The original one? Yeah, the one
in 1984 was my favorite one.
I think it was 1984. That was my favorite
one. That's the Dino de la Renta Swan.
Jessica Lange. Yeah. I like
that one. Back in the day.
I haven't seen him since that was trip
and Jessica Lange played, uh, uh, abroad.
That was just ditzy enough to fall in
love with a fucking giant gorilla. Right.
You know,
she was just ditzy enough where,
where you could buy it
and believe it this a,
the latest one was fucking incredible man.
The latest one,
when you go back and you see like the,
the newest King Kong,
compare it to the oldest King
Kong, the oldest one is like, wow,
what a window into a different
world like you ever see. Um,
is it called metropolis? That
old, really old Scifi movie.
Wow. It's incredible what they
thought the future was style. Yeah.
Maybe it was so amazing.
Well, even like the old alien,
like I'm fucking slick prometheus's
coming out this weekend.
But if you watch the original alien,
you know when they were
on that spaceship one,
a bunch of wack ass fucking
fake equipment they had,
everything was all lights and shit and,
and the monitors,
these shitty little green tint monitors
because essentially this is before the
user interface,
the graphic user interface that
would we think of as computers today.
Everybody thinks of them a Mac
or a PC and clicking on things.
There was no clicking on anything back
then when people don't understand is the
first computers. When when the movie
alien came out, they were like,
it was all just like
green print on a screen.
You weren't downloading anything bitch,
you know, it was like 1979 or something.
Right.
There was no downloading.
There were just these weird things
that sat around and laboratories.
So they never predicted,
you know,
like not even remotely what
the future was going to hold.
They didn't see that even they
didn't see anything common.
They didn't even see a little,
it's kind of fucking crazy when you stop
and think about what a big difference
the graphic unit user interfaces played,
the ability to click on things and
just when you look at a smartphone,
like I was looking at
that big giant ass note.
I've got a note anyway. New iPhone. Yeah.
I don't think seem to need a new iPhone.
No,
it's like it's pretty much the same,
but the whole thing's almost all screen
real. Yeah. But it is not bigger.
Um, no, but the screen is like,
if you look at your iPhone now,
it doesn't take a path even,
you know like what,
75% of the fund now it's most of the
phones all like from wall to wall up and
down. That's going to mean I don't, no,
I mean the note is cool because
it's a small tablet and I think,
I'm pretty sure my money's is all on that.
Apple is releasing a smaller version of
the IPAD that will kind of compete with
the note cause they're going to use it
also as a remote control for their new TV.
That will come out soon.
But so that that will take over that.
But I don't think the note as it phone is,
I think it's the dumbest thing ever.
Like I saw this person use it and have
you ever seen them like hold it up to
their head. It looks like they're
going to break their hand,
can watch the tumors grow in their
brain as they're holding it up to them.
The fucking thing is enormous but a, it
looks beautiful though, man. It's fucking,
I got this new iPad but a little bit the
latest one with the Verizon service on
it. That makes a huge difference cause
it's my first iPad with the service on it.
But the hot spot feature is faster than
my high speed business class Internet at
that squad.
That's incredible.
But you only get to use a little bit
of it before they fuck you in the end.
You know what, you would think that.
But I used it pretty hardcore and you,
you don't really know unless
you're downloading movies.
One movie and I got an email for one,
that's the one thing.
Everything else that's ridiculous.
If you have an iPad and you download
one movie and they're like, oh,
you're fucked. Like what do you mean
I'm fucked? That's the whole thing.
Because if everyone downloaded
one movie all this time,
then there would be there. There's not
that much internet. They need us fix that.
It's ridiculous. That's you use
when you use mobile internet,
it's offensive how much it costs.
You just need to expand Wifi so it hits
everybody. So we have wifi everywhere,
not cell phone. Then everywhere,
every B's going to be dead.
We can put fucking hot spots on all the
helicopter cats. You know, an Aspen,
uh,
it's a free Wifi for the whole city and
we'll just sit out there in the middle
of nowhere and just fucking,
I bet this website's probably blocked
Joe rogan.net blog that I think they did
block.
They've tried that in a lot of cities.
There's a lot of cities that do that.
I was happy when I couldn't get to
my website from Dubai. I was like,
look at that bitch to teen choice
and dangerous for your Wifi.
Yeah, there's um, there's
a good argument for that,
but we don't know what the fuck is
happening with all these different wire
signals in the air. People didn't
say nothing. We're adapting to them,
but there's something going on man.
You're shrinking when you can send yeah,
no era hills.
When you can send images and ones and
Zeros and you send them through the air
and there's something else that picks
him up, receives them. That is a, that's,
that's a crazy thing.
You're sending a signal and where
the signal is just in the air,
it makes no sense. Is that
hitting me? Is it all over me?
When someone's like Wifi
like crazy near you,
are you getting pelted but like random
information as it makes its way from,
you know, from the Internet somehow
or another into their computer.
Where's it going from? What's
the, is it passing through your,
your dimension at all?
I mean that is like some inter
dimensional fucking transportation of,
I mean the physical object of a,
a piece of paper that you print and you
turn into a photograph that you just got
from the Internet.
I mean that is a way where something
physical just gets created and it wasn't
there before it sent to you
and print it up like that is,
that's a crazy thing,
man.
It's really crazy that we can just do
that and we just don't even think about
the fact there's television signals and
radio signals and internet signals and
cell phone signals and all these
different signals going around.
I don't know if they're affecting
us. I have no idea. It might.
It might be that we would all feel a
little bit better if we didn't have them.
It would be interesting.
Too Bad.
There's not really any place in their
world that you can probably not have.
You have to go to complete zero signals.
You'd have to go to somewhere that
really sucks like Alaska and Arctic or
Antarctic. I mean, Alaska has cell
phones now I'm in an a and r get ups,
but they would still probably
have some kind of signal.
I would bet up there like at least
satellite or something. Maybe. Maybe.
But satellite doesn't work everywhere.
It depends on where the satellites, uh,
where you can receive it. Like I don't
think you can get XM radio in Hawaii.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure I um,
I rented a car there once and I was
trying to listen to opie and Anthony,
you know,
I went to the Cadillac and I was like
looking for the satellite button.
I pressed the satellite but it was nothing
going on. And I was like, you know,
I don't think this shit works here.
I forgot to look it up though,
but I don't think it does, but I'm not
sure. But you could always get it online,
right. Which is what everybody's
going to do eventually anyway.
You're going to have your peoples,
Gee,
they're going to be selling phone or
rather radios that come with your car that
connect to the internet, allow you to
download podcasts. If you have a Ford,
you already have stitcher,
there's the new Fords,
have the stitcher APP Builtin
fucking mad man. I want that so bad.
It's not.
That's the thing I hate.
I hope if if anyone that designs for these
Fords and these awesome new cars with
these new stairs, they have these apps
like stitcher, it's called sync for Ford.
I have that, but there's no way to
upgrade it so I can get that shit.
And when that's not fair, that's
what you mean. You go and you get it.
If you buy a new car, you
have to, they have the,
it's been releasing her hardware and
series. So like you have like, you know,
sink version one, two,
three and you can't like,
it's not like an iPhone where like
you just old grade, you can upgrade.
He can't do that. It really
makes me mad cause I, I can't,
what am I going to tear out the
computer and you're in your car.
It should be interchangeable
and upgradable and pull
out and put a new one and
they're just being cheap and they're not.
They're telling nurse software developers
to move on to the next stuff and just
abandoning. That's almost a leak should
be illegal because this car is that,
my car is like a 2008
right now and it should,
I haven't been able to update it
in three years, you know? So yeah,
that is kind of fucked.
It's like a planned obsolescence mean.
It really is the fact that it's,
the computer itself is an upgradable,
how long do you expect people to
compete, you know, to keep that car?
Because when you really think about
like all the, the different law,
was it Moore's law for computers?
We stop and think about how quickly
computers become obsolete. Yeah.
Like metal having a classic corvette and
it had a black and white television in
it. Yeah. Come on. What
the fuck? Well those,
those knuckleheads though that like
those really classic cars that people,
they want like classic hubcaps.
They want everything.
They want to time travel so they can
go back in high school and fucked her.
Their 15 year old girlfriend. Oh, I see
him all the time and live in Burbank.
That's like that big boy there every week.
Fucking Leno or driving around in a
fucking fire truck waving at, you're like,
nope, it's fucking Burbank's
the creepiest place effort.
How weird is it j waves at everybody.
He's the nicest guy. Nicest guy ever.
I seen him all the time. I'm like
walking the streets and waves of people.
There was shitting all over him on the
radio today on Stern. Him and Joan Rivers.
Oh yeah. I haven't heard the rest
of event generally was pretty funny.
She's ruthless and she's
still fucking sling and he,
Joan Rivers is still going to war
with chicks. It's Hilarious, man.
She's still struggling,
still fighting.
She's like 79 something years old and
she still does stand up. You know,
she's still obsessed with work.
And have you ever met,
have you ever met Jenny Mccarthy?
No. Yeah, I met her once. I met her.
She was really nice and I stopped
doing a joke. What was it?
I had a joke about,
uh,
that I heard that Jenny McCarthy was going
to get her breast implants taken out.
I said it's like tiger was chopping his
fucking arms off 10. That's not bad.
I would say,
I think you'll,
why don't you put them back in
and make them big and no talking.
She was on Howard Stern yesterday
and I had forgot about her, you know,
cause he married Jim Carrey and you just
kind of like, right, she's dead to me.
She married Jim Carey dated.
Oh maybe I thought would make they married
but now they're separated and she was
on Howard stern just talking about
how much, I mean she's a dirty girl.
And she was talking about
how much he masturbates,
how much she needs caulk that shit.
And then you go online, you're like,
what's she look like now? And you go to
our Twitter and you're like, Holy Shit,
she's still fucking hot as hell.
And she's a Nympho and she lives in the
valley somewhere. So what are you saying,
dude? I need to find out what
she does. She wants a podcast.
You could get with that. She
didn't McCarthy. You think
you could pull that off?
I don't think so, but, but you never know.
I don't think you could pull out half the
girls you've pulled off already. Right?
True. Yeah. So why not her? Why not
just make a complete fantasy land?
I want to just go full on Coen brothers
movie. Well, my mission was Lindsay Lohan.
I thought that would be a bigger niche.
That's harder. I think it's please.
I know guys are fucked her. I don't know
anybody's Fuck Jenny McCarthy. True.
Jim Carey. I don't know
that guy. Do you know? No,
I thought maybe you knew him from the
comedy store to know. I've never met him.
He kind of stopped doing
standup along time ago.
Some of those guys that's interesting.
Stand up,
gets him to the dance and then
once they get to the dance,
then they just become an actor. A
lot of dudes do that. What was, uh,
did you,
you ever do comedy store shit with Mark
Marin where you there at that same time
period as him or while he was there a long
time ago. He was really young
and he was there with Kinison.
Here's the door at Tennyson was alive.
Yeah.
By the time I got into standup Kinison
only out a couple of years of life left.
He died when I lived in New York.
So I think it was probably 90,
I want to say 92 that Kennison
died somewhere along those lines.
So I still hadn't made
my way out to Elliot.
And Marin got in deep with,
uh,
with Kennesaw and when he was a kid,
you know,
he was hanging around with them and
you know, he got, uh, got to see the,
the crazy dark coke years.
He got to see the chaos and all that shit.
That story about, um, uh,
about Kinison fathering Carla Bows,
wife's child.
It's just so fucked up. So fucked up, man.
He thought that it was his
daughter for the longest time.
And then a DNA test reveals
it was Sam kinisons kid.
He just think of his wife just laying
there and letting fat Sam climb on top of
her and shoot his loads
inside of her and go,
what kind of a fucking
friendship that they have?
What kind of a world where they eliminated
what kind of decadence and depravity,
what kind of Hollywood chaos was going on?
Kennison was just banging his friend's
best friend opening act wife on the side
and shooting loads into her.
Well,
it amazes me that dude was
got a lot of fucking pussy,
like he was on the Howard stern calling
and hit like four girls in his bed.
And you're amazed with that, but yeah.
You're not amazed when you get posted. No,
I mean, well one at a time. I don't know.
Sam Kinison was a big guy and I don't
know, I would not very attractive really.
Like I never thought Kinison was, I guess
he was bigger than I thought he was.
You know, back in the day I'll
never thought, oh, you mean big,
like physically or you mean no notoriety,
notoriety. It was huge. Yeah. See,
I didn't see that because I
was an end of the comedy scene.
I only knew what I saw on TV and I always
thought the big guys were like Robin
Williams and they were all big.
Kinison was huge. Dude. Kinison. Uh,
I found out about Kennison and 86,
and all my friends knew about kids and
everybody knew Kennison when I went to
see a Kennison live, I brought a bunch
of my friends. Everybody was fucking,
it's to see Kennison live.
We suck. Tennyson live saw.
I saw Carlin live before ever did
stand up. I got to see Carlin live.
I live. I said, I got to see Carlin
bomb. Really? Oh Hey. He ain't shit.
It did not work out. It was
not, it wasn't good. He was,
he got to this weird stage in his
life in like the late eighties.
This was before I had done comedy and I
was with maybe I'd done like an open mic
night, maybe one or something like
that. But it was, uh, me and uh,
my roommates and we were out in
New Hampshire and we saw him at,
there's a casino up there and they have a,
they do shows there.
And that was the place where everybody
would go up from Boston during the summer.
We'd all go up to, uh, to this
casino was at Hampton beach.
I think that's it. I don't
remember. Anyway. Um, we were, uh,
we were all there and George Carlin had
this weird thing that he was doing where
he would,
he just have like a notepad
and it was just reading off,
fuck this and fuck that.
It was like his whole and fuck Israel and
fuck this and fuck like the whole, uh,
the whole bit was like, it wasn't
really working, you know, it was weird.
It was like there was all this energy
and there was all this, you know,
push into it. And it was fascinating
for me to watch because it was like,
this is George Carlin.
I mean George Carlin is a
like an all time great comic,
but this at this point, his life,
it wasn't working out that night.
I don't know what it was,
but my friend looked over me.
It was just kind of fucking
sucks. And I was like, wow,
I couldn't even say anything
cause I had dragged them there.
They weren't Comedians,
you know,
I dragged them to go see George Carlin
and he was eating it. It was weird.
And I,
you know,
I stopped listening to him for like a year
or two and then I bought, he had like,
um, x warning, a explicit lyrics
I think was one of the cds,
which was great. And I was like, he got
it back. It was almost like, you know,
he just had a bad, see, he did so
much stand up. Everyone has a bad set.
It wasn't just a bad set, it
was a bad, it was a bad set,
like not that night, but set out the
way it was written. It was just, he,
he went through a period of like,
I don't know how many decades or
he made a new hour every year.
So because of that he
was so fucking prolific.
He would essentially like
write a whole new monologue,
a long monologue every year.
And to do that and still have
something to say after all those years,
you're going to hit some stumbling
blocks along the way. I mean,
you're going to hit some, you're going
to have some awkward moments. You know,
like if you,
uh,
if you go to see like Louis C k this is
very possible that Louise work on new
shit right now. You know what I
mean? Like he's always got new shit.
If you do that, it's so hard to
maintain the quality. It's so hard,
you know, to every year a new
hour. What the fuck man? God Damn,
you wonder how many you would have to
start doing things like specifically to
write material
kind a universal studios. Yeah,
exactly. Yeah, go to, you know,
you're going to go try to do it once a
week now just do stupid shit like that
just to get material. It's kind of
cool cause it makes you do more things.
It's a two edge sword because
you still enjoy it. You know?
It's like you're going to
do some cool shit. Like,
well what have you done that day?
You didn't like it
done. Ah, fuck. What was
that recently? Uh, there was
something recently that I did.
I did. Oh well no, that was still
fine. What did that Black Strip club.
But no,
I can't think of,
there was something I did
recently that was really boring.
I can't even think of what it was.
But I remember thinking like,
well that was kind, oh, doing uh,
mushrooms and a shitty hotel
in Venice. Oh yeah. Yeah.
That was horrible. That's not a good move.
I still got kind of material from it.
You kind of, I guess, what kind
of material did you go? Oh,
it's just like on stuff. I haven't really
tried out too much, but, uh, you know,
like, you know, you can have bad
tell. Like, you can tell you kneel,
you're in a bad area where everywhere
you look there's evidence, you know,
stuff like that, you
know, they're just like,
all these tags I've kind of built
up and trying to make him do sets.
But I don't know, things like
that. I, I've been doing more now,
I've never done that. But usually once
a week I tried to do something crazy.
Like I wanna go to magic castle. I wanted,
like, I've never been, I've never been,
but I want to go there and just get drunk.
My friend Zack go to Jujitsu
was a magician. Oh really? Yeah.
He's always inviting me to go there.
But you know what?
You have to wear like a
jacket and a tie and I know,
and there's always least rapey
actors there that you, that you're,
I heard every time he'd go, there's
somebody weird there. You're like,
why is that person here? Like some guy
from the eighties? No, not even that.
Like shit, what's his name? I think, uh,
I, I don't want to say it, but I don't,
I don't know who, what is the name is, but
it's somebody you're like, wow. Really?
Like pat that guys here,
I saw the Stephen Baldwin is suing
Kevin Costner for Kevin Costner has a,
um,
apparently he owns a piece of some
company that makes them machine that takes
oil out of water, which is
pretty surreal. It doesn't,
doesn't make sound spill or that last big
spill he donated or something to that.
Pretty crazy.
When you stop and think that somehow or
another Kevin Costner is a part of this.
I don't know how he got to be a part.
I don't know what the story behind that.
A real bro I might've been.
I bet they paid him a fuck
load of money for water world.
I mean waterworld it wasn't like,
it was one of the biggest budget movies
of all time at that time and it made the
last the most, I guess. I
don't know if it lost the most,
but it lost a shitload. She looked that
shit up, find out if it done. But um,
I remember when it came out there was
like, God, what a fucking crazy idea.
This movie sucks. I never watched
the whole thing. What the fuck?
Don't they can film a whole movie on the
water that's so hard to do just to get
your shit out there, get your goddamn
equipment out there on the water.
Everything's getting wet and fucked up.
Dropping your camera in the water
all the time. It's so stupid.
And the premise sucks
anyway. What's the, oh,
everything's water now because we
go just in the future, you know,
like we're like earthquakes,
everything fell into the
ocean or something like that.
That would be way more sharks. If that
was the case, there'd be way more sharks.
There would be,
everybody would be Jackin like sharks
and all sorts of things be grabbing
people,
pulling them under starfish
and shit octopus's to pursue,
grabbing them,
dragging them underwater.
There'll be a lot of that
because people would,
we'd be like a little bobbers everywhere.
Kevin Costner was on
the set of that movie.
Hundred and 57 days working
six days a week for a movie.
That's a long ass for a movie that's
sucked a big fat bag of Dicks or we got
widely considered to be one of the
biggest box office bonds of all times.
Although it grows 255 million
from $175 million budget.
This does not factor in marketing and
distribution charges or percentage of the
gross that theater's keep,
which is up to 45% the film came to be
nicknamed Kevin's gate after Heaven's
gate and fish tar after
Ishtar to make bombs. Yeah.
Ishtar was a huge, never saw that
either. Did you ever watch that? Yeah,
I think I watched part of it when
I was a kid, but I don't remember.
It was Warren Beatty and Dustin Hoffman
and I don't even know what the fuck it
was about. And what was the other
one that they showed was a big bomb.
The other one I didn't even,
I never even heard of,
but it was called heavens gate.
Yeah,
I think that was a Warren Beatty
movie too. What's that? No, no,
that's Chris Christopherson.
Christopher Walken and John hurt
and actually got a 6.5 on imdv.
Huh. But just Bob, that's a
pretty cool cover. A poster.
Never saw it.
Never saw the Ishtar.
I remember [inaudible] was a
bomb and it was not just a bomb,
but everybody talked about what a calm it
was. So it became a massive bomb. Like,
oh my God, have you seen Ishtar what a
piece of shit like didn't even see it.
And they were just saying it was a piece
of shit. Yeah. I mean, even as a kid,
I used this term as a reference. It's
something cheap or Shitty, like, you know,
like I would say things where
that's like Ishtar. Oh really? Yeah.
Like that was meanwhile I was like super
expensive probably because they had to
pay Dustin Hoffman and Warren
Bay, right? Yeah. Yeah. What,
how much Kevin Costume made for 157
days on a piece of shit movie. Right.
We had some guys from a fear factor stunt
guys that worked on that and they were
saying it was, well, it sounds like,
yeah, it sounds pretty ridiculous.
Just the idea behind it,
man.
You gonna make a fucking movie where
everything's floating. Stop it.
You silly bitch. Like, well, the
best one though wasn't even that.
The best one was the post man.
Did you ever see that? No.
I never watched horses. Right.
It was, I came on horses.
It was in the future after
the shit hits the fan.
Kevin Costner is a fucking hero
because he delivers letters to people.
He's the postmaster. Oh
my God. Dude, it's so bad.
You can't believe it's real
and the acting is so bad.
The acting is like ABC after
school special acting like
there's no way it seems
real. It's like shut up
mom, get out of my room.
Like it just does not seem,
there's nothing realistic
about it at all. And the,
the premise is dawn shit.
Yeah. And did you, did you see
her about fucking Thq and ea?
Yeah. Yeah. Crazy. Yeah.
The UFC is going to make um,
their new video game with
ea and apparently teach cube
bought it or ea bought it
from Thq. You know, I feel bad at Thq
shut down a shut down the developer that,
you know that did it shut
down their office yesterday,
he three just closed down and they didn't
have a booth at this year's e three
because I was originally,
cause I'm going to eat three Tamara and
I wanted to talk to them about UFC and
all that crap like that.
And they were like,
and we don't have a booth where
meeting at a hotel and I'm like, Whoa,
what's going down? But then, uh, yeah,
I think THQ did a really good job with
that game and Thq I thought, you know,
with saints row, I mean they've been
saint's row just released a map pack.
Then Brian Keeley who does
podcasts with me, uh, she,
she's in the new map packs
so they actually combining
video games with penthouse
now, which I thought was
cool. That's smart. Yeah.
But um, I think they're, they're
losing a lot of money, man.
The UFC game was the only game
apparently that was making good money.
Now are you going to be,
do you know yet?
Are you going to be doing the
EA Games of this yet? Right?
Are you sure? I'll probably do it. Yeah.
Yeah. It's, it's a pain in the deck,
but a,
it's worth it
in the long run. It's the, you know,
the, the, the finished product.
They're very thorough. Yeah. Like
we do, we did so much commentary.
You don't get too much repeat like words,
like there's all sorts of
different versions of, you
know, things that you do and,
and like transitions
like Armbar to knee bar,
transitioning from the
triangle to the arm bar,
like all that different kinds of stuff.
Like we've voiced them all individually,
you know, so it's, there's,
there's so many moves you can do.
It's like really kind of crazy
that you look at that, that thing,
that remote control and you're supposed
to be able to figure that out like down
here and up there and laughed and
push this and push that. It's, it's a,
it's a fucking,
it's not that you got to like take a
lot of time to figure out all the moves
that you're your, your guys capable
of doing because there's so much shit.
There's so many different submissions
and punches and kicks and,
and to know what button is doing what
at the exact same moment as fucking hard
man.
There's a lot involved.
Or now that it's with ea,
you need to hold out for
more money because they are
the big pimps of the video
game industry.
Do you know what I'm saying?
They hear exactly what my
fucking plans are. No. Yeah.
But no they,
that's cool though.
Cause ea does make the best sports games
and a lot of people get yeah it gets a
lot of shit for being like the monopoly,
like buying out and killing all the small
companies and shit like that. But EA,
they do make some fucking kick ass games
like the tiger woods golf fucking mad
and football. Right. You
know, I mean they, they uh,
they own some of the biggest franchises.
So I think it's better way better for for
UFC video game in the future. I think.
Well Dana is very excited about
and when he told me about it,
he was saying that these guys are the
best and they're going to make the best
game.
It's funny cause ea had recently said
that we're going to have a new MMA game.
Right. And you know, no one knew that
it was going to be the UFC. Yeah.
But everybody was like, oh it's
probably going to be EA MMA to right.
The second version of it cause they had
an EA MMA game with like fade or Anna and
right.
I wonder if they're going to use that
engine or if they're going to buy out that
THQ engine or started creating a new
engine. Cause that'll be interesting. Yes,
that's a good point. It might just
be a restrict MMA game. I wonder.
MMA looked looked decent,
but man,
a lot of the fucking fighters did
not look like the real fighter.
Yeah. I think they rushed that game.
They were like, oh shit, we can't,
we gotta we gotta release
the game now. You know, like
I think they saw what, when,
when UFC all the heat from UFC,
those guys fucking work.
That's the one thing that it really puts
in perspective when you hang out with
the garlic cliffy be you
go to the epic game studio.
You know like when we went down there or
if you go to Thq and you see like the,
the hours that we put in the video game,
pretty minuscule.
I mean I could complain it like six
hours of sitting there going, yeah.
But the reality is that's not the,
that's not a hard job,
but these fucking guys are
working long hours every day.
And then when things don't go well,
they just get laid off.
Are we back? Jesus Christ,
Ladies and gentlemen,
the technology here is
just ridiculous. We, um,
had a, an issue here at
the Rogan compound with a,
at one point in time the uh,
um,
router tip fucking up and I would
have to reboot it twice a day.
So today we replaced everything and yet
the same thing happened really twice a
day. Yeah, sometimes.
Sometimes I would do it would
have to reboot it twice a
day and that sucks. Well,
the router was shitting out, so I
replaced the router today and it shut up.
You mean the Cape, the router
they give you, you had replaced,
my house has a system and there's a
ethernet jacks all throughout the house so
you can get online anywhere. And then, you
know, that was when I bought this house,
wireless wasn't that big.
And then now we set about wired,
but so there's in the garage,
it's like a big box that has all this,
these wires going into it and this giant
big ass router that runs everything.
It's unnecessarily complicated,
but that's the way you want to have it.
If you, uh, have a house
that has, you know,
if you want Ethernet ports in your house,
you kind of have to have it. They all,
all the wires have to go to a sum. And
why don't you just do wireless? You can,
but it wasn't,
won't work for the whole house.
You can get those little repeaters
everywhere throughout your house. Yeah.
I've never tried that.
We have different stations.
We have stations throughout the house.
I want to make sure that
it's a strong signal to,
there's nothing more annoying than a
flitting wired, fleeting wireless signal.
You have to fucking,
you've got to sit on the corner of
the couch if you want to get it. Like,
why the fuck out of here? You
should just have like, you know,
like Time Warner on
one side of your house.
You verse on the other side of your
house and have like all of them. So like,
whenever one's down in back,
all right,
let's just go into this side of
the house and use something else.
Or You could test them all out at the
same time. See which one's the best. Yeah,
that sounds like a huge band.
That sounds like something you would do
if you had to buy way too much free time.
I would do that.
That I finally get Verizon out here.
I'd give Verizon Internet out here to
fight us or whatever it's called. No,
I mean, on your phone.
Oh, right. Works. They,
Verizon updated it for
the longest time out here.
I couldn't answer a phone call
and Verizon, but now I can't,
especially if I'm outside from outside,
I'll get confident.
I'll answer the fucking phone. I'm like,
I don't give a fuck. It can do stuff.
Has two bars right now. That's
just, yeah, it's good for texting,
but it's for phones. It's a pretty
ridiculous, have you heard this thing?
I mean it's on infowars.com I think so.
It might not be real, but, um, not
that info wars is all horse shit,
but they get a little crazy sometimes.
It's a,
it says 5 million farmers are suing
Monsanto for seven point $7 billion.
Hmm.
That's a pretty incredible five bill.
5 million farmers.
Seven point $7 billion,
which is like what they make in
a month probably. Right. But uh,
that's a lot of fucking people.
It's chicken scratch. Yeah.
They say that a farmer commit
suicide because of, uh,
because of, uh, Monsanto
on some fucking ridiculous,
ridiculous rate.
I'm trying to find it here in the
articles because there was something crazy
like every 30 seconds a
farmer commit suicide.
17,683 Indian farmers just
in 2009 committed suicide.
Whoa. That's just ridiculous.
So they're all suing.
Okay.
For as much as 6.2 billion euro,
seven point $7 billion.
I don't even think this is an
America. I was just going on. Wow.
Oh, suicide. Every 30 minutes.
Wow. That is what it is. Oh,
it's probably really hard to find red
chickens, not chickens. It's the seeds,
man. It's not the, it's they're
trying to patent animals,
but right now it's mostly mostly seeds,
but they're selling they their
terminator seeds, you know, they're,
they're only good for a certain amount
and then they don't make seeds that work.
It's really kind of crazy that anybody's
ever let them make these fucking
horrible distorted versions
of life in the first place.
Who fucking creeps. Did you hear this
thing about a Pentagon suspects? Uh, uh,
they, they, some people, uh,
in the Pentagon apparently, uh,
downloaded porn run two,
three go some people in the Pentagon
that were working there download kitty
porn. It's for research bro. Yeah. And uh,
the, there's some, you know,
investigation but they won't turn over
the records because they say it's a,
it would compromise national security.
So they can't, the Pentagon is allowed,
the only people in the world apparently
that are allowed to watch kitty porn
cause they can download it and look,
we know what we're doing. Trust us.
This is all about the United States
government and keeping the beach and the
security of our fire nation.
You imagine watching kids get fucked by
adults as a part of the security of your
fine nation and you, you
can't, you can't tell.
Why can't you say it's a
part of a research project
where this guy downloaded it
or that you know what they're doing.
I bet.
Okay.
I bet they have some sick fuck, that's
a child molester. And they were like,
you know,
they,
they'll give them a little child porn
if he gives more information. Yeah.
You know,
I wonder if child porn is
going down lately because
of the other trends in child
porn. Well, yeah. I mean, you
know, like the, nowadays that
disk, I mean, the old thing.
What was school girls? Japanese
schoolgirl. Okay. Wait a minute.
This is way crazier than I thought.
The Pentagon checked on. Wow.
The Pentagon employee is suspected
of viewing child pornography.
Fuck what? Okay. This is crazy.
In 2006 the immigration and
Customs Enforcement Agency,
which conducts Internet
pornography investigations,
produced a list of 5,200 Pentagon
employees suspected of viewing child
pornography.
5,200 employees.
Wow.
I Dunno. That's incredible. I wouldn't
even thought they were that match. Wait,
what? What? What website is this? What?
This website that I'm reading right here.
boston.com
this is not a conspiracy website at all.
This is a real real website,
right?
The suspected of viewing child pornography
and asked the Pentagon to review it,
but the Pentagon checked only two thirds
of the names unearthing roughly 300
defense and intelligence employees who
allegedly had viewed child pornography on
their work or home computers. Iris. Right.
The defense investigators failed to check
an additional 1700 names on the list.
Defense officials have
revealed in correspondence
with Senator Charles Grassley,
a Republican of Iowa,
probably they found out that their systems
were hacked and all these employees
didn't look at child porn.
And then halfway through
searching all of it, but like,
no, we just got hacked. They
could be, they could, you know,
not want to bring that up.
Right. You don't want to
admit exhibit hacked. Exactly.
Very possible.
And it was probably some like
famous goats eat 22 year old pick.
You know, it was probably something
stupid like that. That is kind of crazy.
Number. Yeah, that seems like, boy, I
doubt. I mean, how many employees is or,
but I mean 5,000 seems pretty big.
It's fun.
Now how many employees
are at the Pentagon?
That's a really good point.
That probably these knuckleheads
I didn't even think of.
Yeah.
Well
we have a show tomorrow.
Oh yeah, we know. Showed him off the Ice
House and Friday at the Hearst house.
Both in the little room. So don't
sleep. It'll sell out quick.
It's something like 85 seats.
Um,
depending on how many people
come on bitch. To what,
how many employees? 24,000.
24,000 so that's a, what is it?
10% how many of you did,
what did we say?
So that's saying one fifth of the
employees are addicted to child points.
So that's, yeah, that's, that's stupid.
That's have a 2,400 you're right,
it was 5,000 bosses.
They don't want to talk to Burbank.
That's pretty ridiculous. I wonder
if that is the truth. I'm one,
I wonder if you nailed it. Absolutely.
What is, and that's why they did Pentagon.
Didn't say anything about it.
They just realized that they got hacked.
Or imagine if the government is just
infiltrated by kid fuckers and it's just
like,
just like the Vatican kid fuckers Galore.
If you had to imagine how many people in
the Vatican got busted for kid fucking,
how much, how many of them value?
Let's, okay, look on Vatican child porn.
I mean, it's gotta be
something. There's some scandal.
You can write Vatican child porn and
you know, you're going to get us up.
There you go. Vatican, uh,
fucking the Canadian bishop
convicted for child pornography.
Boom. How easy. So simple.
Isn't that amazing that you know that
you could look that up. That's so weird.
You can just look up Vatican
child porn and there's something,
some Canadian bishop, he, they uh, they,
they got rid of him. They booted him out.
So it wasn't that, you know,
the Vatican had child porn.
It was that they got rid of
a guy who had child porn.
But then there was the whole issue
of the guy who was the actual, uh,
pope himself, Ratzinger, Ratzinger, Pope
Benedict, whatever the fuck are you.
I was when,
when he was a bishop or whatever silly
name they like to give themselves
whatever the hell he was.
He was in charge of following up on cases
of child molestation and it's clear,
clear evidence that he,
he's tried to,
he tried to divert the investigation and
like really slacked off on it and then
got rid of the guy like a aided
and getting rid of the guy who uh,
they were going after. They had all
sorts of little things they would do.
Like they would,
a guy would get busted bang and kids
and they would just move them to another
place.
Like that's,
that's been the standard protocol of the
Catholic Church for the longest time.
Whenever someone,
a car no gets caught and gets in trouble,
they just move them to some other place.
It's really bizarre man.
It makes you really wonder
what it's all about.
It makes you really wonder if at the the
top branch of the Catholic Church when
they're all alone,
like are they just all kid fuckers?
They all bring like a bag in
there all around in big circle.
Ne Empty the bag of their child.
It's like it comes out like,
would it be something really fucked up?
Like they kidnap one shout a month.
What did you hear about the
child that was missing from the,
I'll pull up child a whole and then
now you are in the Pentagon list wasn't
there was a, there was a, okay, here's a
child sex investigation. Yeah. This is it.
There was a story where I'm,
a former bishop said that a girl
who turned up missing missing was,
um,
was taken by the Vatican and they used
her as a sex slave and killed her.
Oh my God. Yeah. It's
so fucking crazy. Yeah.
Friday of fucking
strange man. Crazy. Yeah.
Wow.
This is so,
whenever they look at these things and
these probes and they find out how many
different reverends were fucked up.
The church previously insisted the
crimes of the late Reverend Massey,
l m a C I e l were his alone.
He was a long held up as a model
by Pope John Paul the second,
despite credible accusations,
later proven that he raped and molested
his seminarians lesion of Christ had
over 900 priest while Jesus Christ,
this guy,
I don't even want to hear this,
he died in 2008 a year later,
the Orthodox order confessed that he
had fathered three children with two
different women and that he had abused
as seminarians. Just so there's,
there's an arrogance and a lot of these
dudes have when they become priests that
they feel like they're,
everybody kisses their ass.
Have you ever been to a church? You ever
been to like Catholic Church, Catholic?
Well, I mean I've been to him but I
didn't go to one. You know what I mean?
Catholic churches is very creepy
and it's very, um, it's very strict,
like very strict.
Like if you giggle and a Catholic church,
they'll smack you and your fuck.
Yeah, they don't want that noise.
They don't want kids to be
kids in Catholic church. Gary,
like you go to Baptist church,
baptist churches and everybody's
laughing and giggling.
A little babies are crying. They'll smack
a baby in a Catholic church. Nobody.
Nobody wants little kids crying out in
a Catholic church there, there, there,
it's like a harsh environment. And the
priests are con yes, father, father,
everyone's talking to them father,
and everyone's like real nervous
to be around them. So they,
especially the old ones,
they have this arrogance about them,
which is really strange.
Like you,
you're just some creepy old
queer and a fucking weird outfit.
He can't come out of the closet and you're
spouting off nonsense and everybody's
kissing your ass.
So you've gotten confused and you really
do believe that you're above everyone
else. Like they have a weird
fucking sense of entitlement.
And it's very strange talking to a lot
of priests. Obviously. Not all of them,
a lot of priests,
but the one who gave the eulogy for
my grandmother's funeral is a perfect
example that he was, first of all, you
had gin blossoms all over his face.
This poor fuck. You know when they
get those broken blood vessels,
when they get hammered all the
time. I mean, it's a shit life, man.
This fucking dude, his whole,
he was an obvious drunk.
And then so it was the one who married
my sister. Same thing, gin blossoms,
all risk crushers. What is
bird have those bridges.
And to have those outlets for like
old dudes are like on death's door.
Um, but anyway, um,
my grandmother's name was Josephine
and as they're doing the eulogy,
he keeps calling her Geraldine.
He calls her Geraldine like three
times and someone steps up and goes,
it's Josephine, her name was
Josephine. And so he just,
without missing a beat,
Josephine,
and he doesn't say my apologies.
I mean this is a bunch of people who are,
are sad because you know,
their mom has died and these fucks,
you know, this guy's given that he's
just completely phone in this end.
So when he's saying Geraldine, Geraldine,
they correct them instead of saying,
I'm sorry, you know, I made a
mistake. Uh, her name was Josephine,
not Geraldine's. My apologies. Instead
of that, he just changed it. Geraldine,
we hear on a,
Geraldine died,
not Geraldine at Josephine
Josephine who died.
It's just like phoning him down saying
the way he just said like the words and
the order.
No emotion behind it and know enough
and goodnight everybody take it easy.
I'm going to go drink no pussy,
no fun,
no riverboat gambling.
Just little children's mouth suppression.
I wonder how many of them are gay and
how many of them were just miserable.
How many of you want to fuck kids?
How many of them want to just
shoot themselves in the head?
What are the actual numbers and
I'm sure a few of them are happy.
Don't get crazy Twitter.
That's the thing that people get fucking
most angry at me about is a shitting on
religion,
which I think it's so hilarious cause
I'm only shitting on specific acts that
you could, you could attribute
them to religion, but this is,
these are human beings
that are fucking kids.
Call it religion and crawling up. That
religion also makes me like, I see,
I don't see religion as bad
because I grew up Lutheran,
which is like I guess you know we had a
Starbucks and stuff and our church or in
a Starbucks. Starbucks. And your church
with a coffee place like a Starbucks.
Really? Yeah. I mean it was you know a
lot different than like a social thing.
Happy. Yeah, it was good. It was
positive. It was like it was,
it was more relaxing and shit like that
so none of that shit in the Catholic
church and I wasn't too too intense.
Catholic church is all about guilt.
If you look at like if you think about
the the churches that are involved with
the most fucked up accusations, the
Catholic churches at the top of that list,
the top and they're also
the most suppressive, the
most suppressive, the most.
They just fill your head with guilt
and anxiety and suffering and the feel
you're the, the, the,
the feeling rather that you are a failure
and that you are inadequate and that
you will never measure up and you're a
sinner in the eyes of God and then have
any of that. It was God, it
was horrible. First grade.
I did a full year of Catholic school and
we went to church when I was like six
or seven and when we went to church like
on a regular basis all the time and it
was all leashes. It was
disgusting. It was just,
it was all like terror.
All I could think of is every day
before school I'd be like, fuck,
I can't believe I have
to go to this place.
Just as torturous place to drop off
your children where they just gland onto
your fucking neck and suck
off all your happiness.
Just suck it out of you like a van
prior man. Really Weird. I remember,
I really clearly remember being in
the middle of class while the teacher
was doing something crazy and they were
talking about something crazy.
I was like, you guys are knots.
Like how are you even saying this?
Like listen to what's coming out of
your mouth. This is complete nonsense.
Like what the fuck are we doing here?
That's kind of weird.
You almost got some kind of weird,
I don't know,
like some kind of like not
being molested as a child.
You were exposed to something that's
probably a positive and offer your,
your as an adult mental
molestation and a huge percentage of
Catholics go through that shit. I mean,
I've talked to kids who went to Catholic
school. It didn't have a bad time,
but most of them,
a good percentage of them had a gruesome
experience with the sole sapping.
It just sucked the life out of you.
And that's why the Catholics are so crazy.
They bounce back and he
can't suppress people.
And then we've talked about this before,
the Catholic school girls,
girls that like Jenny McCarthy,
perfect example,
you're talking about a horny she was,
she went to an all girls
Catholic school man.
All Girls Catholic schools
produce the best slots. Really?
Oh yeah. They're all fucking locked
away. They have to sprint for Dick.
As soon as the light turns green,
they don't get to see Dick all day at
school and flirt around with them and make
friends with them and pass
notes in class. No, all day.
It's just boiling pot of Pussy.
This,
this big boiling mass of
estrogen and female hormones.
And then the light turns green and they
run out the door and just dive on a cock
like a patriotic soldier on a grenade.
They can't wait to get some dick in them.
This poor fucking girl
that I did in high school,
her and her sister were both the biggest
pigs and they both went to Catholic
school and then there was another one
who was like a prude who went to public
school. It was really weird. It was
like for some reason, one of them,
they started her off in public school and
they just kept her in, but our sister,
they, they had a little money. Her
sister was a couple of years younger,
so they said, well, we're going to
put, we're doing a little better now.
We're going to try to put her through
Catholic school and that girl was the girl
I dated and all my God,
she was a freak.
She was a fucking freak.
She would fuck anybody.
Anybody who tried to fuck her, she would
fuck them. She was, this pitch was crazy,
man. I told you that.
She was a girl where my,
my friend was fingering her in front of
my house when I got up in the morning to
deliver newspapers. They
were still up from, you know,
the night before partying and
they're parked in front of my,
my fucking house and I
slammed my hand on the hood.
I don't remember what I said something
half witty, but I was like, Jesus Christ,
my,
uh,
all my expectations for relationships
were shattered by my first two girlfriends
right away because one of them was a
complete slut that could not just leave a
dick alone.
A Dick was like a kitten with a ball yard.
You can't roll a ball yard in front
of a kid and they just fucking pause,
go up and they dive on that shit.
That's how she was with Cox.
And then the other one was
like really manipulative. The
other one, like, you know,
you drive an hour and a half to see her
and she's like, I'm not in the mood.
You know,
she was like really creepy.
Like she wanted to be the one who
always decided what was on TV and always
decided what music we're listening
to too. Yeah, it was, it was,
it was a weird selfish thing.
She grew up an only child and her mom was
kind of a con and so it was a, wasn't,
it wasn't happy.
Her mom was like a big woman and
she had a bad opinion of it was.
So it was a lot of weirdness in
that house. So I got to see both.
I got to see Conti but pretty and nice.
You know,
most of the time just country behavior
occasionally and then super whore. Yeah.
And so I was like, Jesus
Christ, relationships are
disastrous. Like right away,
like the first couple of years of
relationships. To me it was like,
what's the point in this? Not that I
was in a fucking prize back then either.
I mean I was completely crazy,
but just,
it's funny how you can have a couple of
crazy relationships while you're young
and it completely shapes you. You know,
you just, that's where you get your x.
That's where you form your opinions
of what relationships are like.
Like I've had some relationships as an
older man, you know, when, uh, you know,
it was, uh, like when I got to be like,
you know, my late twenties and 30,
well like, they're really
nice people. Like, you know,
you enjoyed being around him.
I didn't even think that was possible when
I lived in Boston. I thought, you know,
based on my own personal
experience and it was like,
this is just some shit you got
to do to get some pussy and then,
then run away from them as quick as you
can, go find your friends. You know?
That was, that was my, uh,
my, uh, my, my take on it.
Plus if you're trying to do
anything else while you're a kid,
you don't really have the time
for a real relationship. You know,
if you're going to high school and
you're trying to pursue something,
like if you're pursuing a sport
or trying to be in a band or any,
anything you're trying to do,
where you're throwing all of your
possible energy at that your,
your amount of time that you have for
relationships is, it's pretty cool.
I feel that way right now. Most, you
know, like I was watching that old movie,
Howard Stern Private Parts and he and
that movie was taught how to part with his
old wife Beth, where Beth was like,
that sounds old wife. His new wife,
his path or what's his old,
the girl that he dated before?
I don't remember Alison. Alison.
Alison was like, you know,
there was a creepy that I
know that, yeah, we can go is,
but Alison was like saying like,
you had never had a time,
you only have time for your radio show and
Blah, blah blah, and everything's know.
And I'm thinking like, Shit,
you know, that's the St well,
how I feel right now because I'm putting
everything in one basket with doing
podcasting and all that crap.
Why do you do that? Listen man,
you're doing really well now.
And you,
you went on the road with Joey Diaz and
did stand up and had a great fucking
like a little baby. It's like a little
baby. It's like a little, you know,
little little project that I'm watching
grow and blossom. And especially,
it's interesting when I have people
like take over and then like it,
like I come in in the room
and I'm like, you know, I'm
like, Oh shit, look, you know,
the camera's not even on that
person that he ended up per se.
It's shit like that where it's like people
you haven't taken over are stolen. No,
no, no, no. These are the friends that are
just helping me out. But, but, but that,
but that's what, that's a good example
of like where I'm like, you know,
I feel like I have to have some kind
of quality control and you know,
cause that's like a little baby
that I created. You know, it's like,
I totally understand.
No, I totally understand where
you're coming from. I just think, um,
you could get there easier for you
with less of them. You know, I have,
I've been cutting a lot. Good, good.
But on the other hand,
we've been doing three Joe Rogan
podcasts and to ice house shows now.
So it's like I'm even working harder now.
We're, we're killing it though. It's too,
it's too,
I feel too much of an obligation to
all those people that we're meeting.
Cause it sounds goofy and it's really
hard to talk about without sounding like
you're crazy or you're an EGOMANIAC.
But I feel like this is
something bigger than all of us.
I feel like we're the ones
who are responsible for
broadcasting it and we're the
ones who are the, you know,
were the voices on the podcast.
But this podcast is resonating
with so many fucking people.
It's so many people come to the
shows and it's not just, hey,
we really liked the show.
It's you changed my life.
It's this show changed my life.
This guy came up to me the other day in
Edmonton and he was telling me how he's
much nicer to people now.
And he just,
he takes the time to tip more and be
nicer and it's changed his whole way of
life. He says, my life,
I'm more successful now.
He goes, I feel better now.
I'm happier now.
He goes,
I would never thought that being nicer
people like on purpose and then tipping,
like being nice and generous
would make me feel so much better.
It's been a lot of that and sue people
that you really did save my life.
Like I kind of point in my life
where I wanted to kill myself.
And you guys really have like shook
me out of that. Yeah. Look, I,
I've had moments in my life when I haven't
been happy when I felt like shit and
then I have now or I could not be happier.
And when I look at my life, what, what
has changed physically in my body?
Well actually I've gotten
older. So thinking about my
past and my, you know, my,
my history of martial arts and all that,
my bubbe, my body should be a mess.
So it should be in pain all the time. I
should be, you know, you know what I mean?
Like I shouldn't feel better and more
happy and vibrant today than before.
So why do, why? Well,
one of the reasons why is because I
don't have any negative shit in my life
anymore. I don't have any bad people
in my life. I don't have a bad job.
I don't have any negative thing I'm
going to anything's, I'm trying to avoid.
And when you don't have anything you're
trying to avoid, you have happiness.
And it takes a while for
people to recognize that your,
there's a direct correlation between
your state of mind and your state of
existence. And if you get both of them
in line, you get both of them in line.
You can have a good fucking life. You
don't have to be rich. Rich is bullshit.
That's not what's important.
You know what you have to do.
You have to have enough money
so you don't have to worry.
Have enough money so that you can feed
yourself so that you can take care of
your, your family. That's what you need.
When you get crazy and you want, you know,
stacks of money and big,
that's just another form of obsession.
You might as well just be jerking off
until you put blisters on your deck.
The keyed, all this shit is balance.
You know, the key to the whole thing.
It's balanced and it's a
constant struggle. If I've,
if I slip for a couple of
weeks, if I don't go in the
tank for a couple of weeks,
if I don't write for a couple of weeks,
if I can go a week without working out,
anytime I do anything where I throw off
the balance and I don't do the work that
I'm supposed to put
in, I feel the difference.
I feel, I feel less, less,
uh, less capable when I sit down
and write again. I feel less,
less vibrant. Uh, when I train, I
don't feel as good when I go on stage,
but that's not my fucking, very
rarely, like, I don't know,
hardly ever take a week off of standup
anymore. It's like I can't even,
even one week I have to go up and,
and, and, and, and, and kill it.
I have to go up and throw
my new shit out there.
I have to go up and record it and go back
and listen to it. If I don't do that,
I feel like I'm wasting something.
I feel like,
I feel like I have been gifted with an
incredible opportunity and incredible
moment in time and incredible,
just very,
just an incredibly fortunate
and fortuitous roll the
dice and I feel like it's
an insult to the gods if you enjoy,
you know, you, you enjoy that,
but then you neglect it and you let it
rot away when you got it right there.
You know what I'm saying? It's like
when I get on stage now when I'm,
when I'm at my best and you know,
and I'm killing and people came to see
the show and they'd come out to the show
and they say, oh my God, my stomach hurt.
And it was the funniest shit
I was so thank you so much.
We had the greatest time. You know
what? One of the things I'm thinking,
thank God they had a great time.
That's good. Boy, I'm so happy to,
the next thing I'm thinking
is I got to keep doing this.
Like I have an obligation like,
cause I this it's not,
it takes a long time to reach a
state of proficiency at something.
It takes an even longer
time to develop an audience.
It takes an even longer time to actually
get a message out there that might
change the way people think.
And when you combine all of them together,
that's what I, when I say that I think
it's bigger than all of us. I do,
I feel like I, I, it's uh, it's something
that started and I got to keep going.
There's no way. You know, like
people's don't ever stop the podcast.
Like I don't think I can,
I don't think it's legal.
I don't think the laws of the
universe wouldn't allow it. You know,
it sounds pretentious, but
for real. But that's just,
that's the hundred percent honest way
how I feel about the whole situation.
I feel like we just,
we,
we lit a spark and we started something
and now we're like the keepers of the
flame and everybody adds
to this fucking thing.
It's like people are constantly tweeting
things and sending things and offering
suggestions and,
and you know,
coming to shows and being enthusiastic
and in pumping like you remember when you
came to Atlanta? When I, when I filmed
my a special Atlanta. How, what,
what the fuck was that like wandering
around with all these people?
Thousands and thousands of people.
Everybody's friendly, everybody's happy.
There's a very specific vibe to all
these shows and something that me and Ari
were talking about when we were
up in Canada. He goes, wow,
the crowd up there was great.
And almost like they were awesome man.
But when was the last time we had a
shit crowd does not happening anymore.
It's like you're getting the same
type of people everywhere you go.
Do you ever worry about uh,
getting a Dui?
Uh, sure. Because that's why I
don't drink. No, I know. But, uh,
just for the point that like you can't,
is that true that you cannot go
to Canada after you have a Dui?
Can you imagine that though? Like for
you? Yeah, that would be like, hey,
no more fucking, you know, that just,
you just got a huge job cut or salary cut.
That would suck.
You would have to hire a lawyer to try
to get you in and then you'd have to
probably make some restitution,
but they just don't want any douche
bags up there. That's insane. Yeah,
it's insane. But I understand
that Canada is so fucking Nice.
People are so nice up there.
They're,
they're insanely inflammatory
with their niceness.
It's like, it's like Jesus, you've
read what do you real slow down,
turn this down and what's
going on. You don't, you don't
even realize it. You know,
when, when you're, when you're around, uh,
like especially big city Americans,
you know,
it's so rare that you
find like really outgoing,
friendly people and then you
go to somewhere like Calgary
or something like that.
Everyone's friendly. You go to Vancouver
and everyone's friendly, you know? I mean,
a friend of mine was talking
about that in a bar that he were,
they were doing standup in Vancouver
and they were at a bar and a girls will
like, hey, where are you from? And
they're like, why you talking to us?
What's going on? What are you doing?
He goes, we thought it was a trick.
Like there were hookers or something.
Like girls are just saying hi coming up
and saying hi girls in America don't do
that. That's rare as fuck.
They're nicer up there, man.
They don't have that conquer mentality.
They don't have this, uh, America.
You know that, that when
you're from the best, you know,
and you can talk all the shit
you want about other empires,
but they can all suck America's Dick.
There's never been anything like America
as far as the, you know, we're lucky,
you know, as far as, I mean, I guess
you want to look at it that way,
that we were born here in this,
this crazy machine.
But if you look at like empires, like
the Roman Empire, the Persian empire,
any empires that like
tried to conquer the world,
nobody did nothing like what we're doing
and we're denying that we're an empire.
We're like right in the middle of it
military presence in over a hundred
different countries and we're like, you
know, we're just just trying to be nice.
You know when you have that kind of a
country and it's just so much military
power and the whole world kind of like
think about how many assholes just act
like Douche bags because their team wins.
You know like when the Lakers win the
championships and dudes are driving,
I was treated well number one pitch
pitch and you don't even know the Lakers
were playing.
You're like,
what the fuck is going on with these
periods are number one for what?
What happened while there they choose
the Lakers there. They live in La.
So there are a number one now.
That's what a lot of people are about.
America being a military power.
There's a lot of fuck heads in
this country that are like, they,
they act like extra cocky because
we're this giant military powers.
If they have anything to do with it,
you know, wouldn't know but won't bitch.
We got the bombs
bitch some backdraft last night.
Remember that? No, he didn't.
The Kurt Russell.
Yeah.
And you remember like how paranoid you
were to open your front door for like two
weeks. The whole movie was
about fucking backdraft.
I remember just sitting there like,
like touching my door real quick and like
spitting on it and made a movie about
fire.
Gone through doorways really fast.
Who gives a shit about backdraft
now is what I'm saying.
It's like I'd never think about backdraft
but yeah. When does that come up?
When was your last backdraft
fire? Scariest. Fucked all man.
It's weird that we got this thing that
we control and we don't even think about
it. It's just, you know, light
it with you. You know, you
can buy it anywhere you go.
Think about how irresponsible people are
and then thinking about the fact that
we got fire in our pocket. We have
fire in your pockets. It's amazing.
There's not way more fires then there are.
Look at this fire.
We're just sitting around here talking.
I got a fire. That's crazy. Yeah.
We're so stupid that could burn a whole
city down. I think I'm fucking stupid.
We are. And the fact that you
could go to a corner drug store,
give me 10 of those and just kid
10 of them go to the liquor store.
Give me some lighter fluid. Yeah. And you
can just light shit on fire everywhere.
It's amazing when you really think about
the potential for damage with all the
shit that we have, how little things
actually get damaged. And now,
especially with fire. Yeah. Have
you ever been in a big fire?
Um, were you around when the
uh, the big, uh, brush fires?
Yeah. Did you see any of that? Yeah,
I've been here and like when I lived in
Calabasas, when I first moved out here,
there was no,
that's writers and members get evacuated.
I remember we were on the road,
I think that real men of comedy tour or
something like that. Yeah. Fire was there.
And my ex fiance at the time had to
pack up our whole entire apartment and
because she got it back. Yeah, that's
right. And that's right. So bad.
It's like she's just like, where do I
go? I'm like, I have no idea at all.
It's scary as fuck man. When when we, we,
I've been evacuated twice and
where I used to live in Colorado,
that burnt down to, and not the
house, but that area burnt down too.
They lost like something like
hundreds and hundreds of houses.
It was some insane amount of
acreage to got burnt down.
The reality is once those motherfuckers
get started, especially out here,
it's so dry fires start like
right now it starts right now,
June 1st is the time where we
have to have brush clearance.
So you're supposed to clear out all the
dead shit and the brush and you know,
people get fined for that.
It's a big deal because some asshole
doesn't take care of his lawn, you know,
and you,
you let the brush pile up and all of
a sudden you've got a really dangerous
situation.
If anything flies and lands on it.
That's what fucks them up is these fires.
They start in the embers,
float through the air and then the embers
will land on some dry grass and poof,
there's a new fire and
that's the epicenter of a
new fire and it just fucking,
the wind takes that bitch and carries
those flames and that lights a tree on
fire and the embers from that fly up
and they catches some other area. Yeah.
That's a fucking pain in the ass man.
It's hard.
They got a circle of drop
water on him and shit.
Have you ever seen them scoop down
and get the water? Yeah, because uh,
when there was fires in Burbank is,
I also experienced when in Burbank,
there was a fire at the Hollywood
mountain two years ago or a year ago and I
guess there's a big water scoop for
helicopters on the top of the mountain.
They just sat there and watched
him scoop out of like a big pool,
like a swimming pool. Most.
When I first came here,
there was a big fire in the Hollywood
hills, so it fucking really nice area.
The Hollywood hills. And we were
watching it from the Virgin Mega store.
There was that little area out
front with like Wolfgang Puck's.
I don't know if it still is there,
but it used to be there.
We were sitting there watching these
helicopters drop fire on this building and
I just kept thinking like what
a strange world we live in,
where we take something like fire for
granted and here it is just eating its way
through the earth,
this energy source and everybody's
freaking out and drop and things on it and
try to stop it and really inadequate,
really ineffective.
Like it takes a long time to put
out a fucking fire. They're trying,
but they have these giant fucking planes.
They have to go down,
scoop up the water,
fly over and poop.
It's like they shoot a little tiny water
load on the fire and then right back to
it.
It takes a long fucking time to actually
put the fire out and most likely some
houses are going to get jacked and
there's nothing they could do about it.
And all those houses inside
of them have electricity.
This other crazy power thing that we
totally take for granted is fucking
pulsating energy through the wires of
the House that powers your Internet and
that was your fucking lights and,
and our life would suck tremendous cock
if we didn't have it or it might be
completely amazing. I would be amazing
cause it'd be really cool. It'd be fresh.
More people would have sex.
I'm hard to get healthy meat.
You have to kill things that day.
It's annoying as fuck.
Imagine you have to kill
fish and animals that day.
That's the only way your whole life
would be about hunting and gathering.
Once you cut out the electricity,
it's really difficult to
store things. You know?
It's hard.
You can,
you got to go with cattle and then
you've got to make sure if you kill it,
you eat all of it. So you have to
calculate how many people are here,
who's working and going to make
sure everybody's doing their part.
To get a piece of this animal,
I'm going to kill another one tomorrow.
And how long have you lived
in a place like California?
And it was the summertime. How long
does an animal last once you kill it?
I'd probably give it 24 hours.
Really think 24 hours. Yeah,
I think it would be rotten. It's
fucking 24 hours, man. Maybe not.
But in this heat when it's
like 90 degrees outside,
I gotta think that animal's
going to be a mass.
Well if you wrap it up and come
or a leaf or something like that,
that's come the new preservative
that you're using. Well I tried it.
I tried Kumon didn't work so I as well.
Let's just try comment. Sounds like it.
It's cool. And even a
preservative. No, it's a spice
that choked. Didn't make sense.
I
don't fuck are you saying
so tomorrow night we are um,
live at the ice house
and a eight 30 and uh,
who's on the line? I'm so far. Uh,
we got Brody Stevens, franchisers,
Tony Hinchcliffe,
Randy leaky fucking funny man.
That kid has got some great jokes. He's
really good. He's a really good IA writer.
He made me laugh. Jeffrey Ross hired
him for a reason. How dare you.
Dare you. Try to pretend he wrote those
jokes. Yeah, guys, when they're writing,
when they're doing like, um, roast and
shit like that. And that's when, you know,
there's a lot of comics that make a good
living just doing writing and punch up
or stuff like that. You know what's weird
is that I, I don't even realize this,
but like two of my good friends,
Pete and Tony who both help us out on
almost every ice house chronicles there
are both from Ohio and they're like,
that's weird that I'm almost,
I feel like I'm getting, you're
pushing the boredom. Yeah.
Because of the cause of Ohio,
but kind of grew up the same.
You all have stunted emotional
development. It's amazing. You'll,
you'll get all be children
forever together. Yeah.
It is a weird thing how you, you,
you sort of like where you grew up,
that's like sorta like hanging out
with Boston people you hang out with,
you know,
all these Boston comics.
Speaking of which Bill Burns
doing the podcast next Thursday.
So make sure you get up on
your RSS feed knowledge and
love Melbourne. I love bill bird too.
I wonder if he's still mad at stitcher.
I doubt it if they all given up on that.
I think they've all come back to stitch
sugar cause are a lot of them have been
coming back to stitcher because
they're realizing it's Corolla. Yeah.
He's always been on stitcher. He's
been a stitcher Darlin for of our time.
But he does his commercials like he does
him live and he does them in the moment.
Like he,
he'll like break for commercial in the
middle of his podcast and it's several
points. Yeah. Radio. He does a
radio format that notice total hop.
So he doesn't have to like, they don't
need to like splice in ads on him.
You know his ass get out
there no matter what.
If stitch or takes the feed and sends it,
his ads get out there.
So it's not like I'm serious.
For example, we're our, our,
our show when it goes to serious,
they cut out the flashlight. Weird.
Every time I hear that it's
so weird. Strange. I'll get,
cause I always have it on either, you
know, stern it opening Anthea channel.
I'll turn on my car and just hear myself
talking about it confuses the fuck out
and me like, whoa. Yeah.
It's weird when you don't expect
to hear yourself and hear yourself.
That's really weird. I'm like, that
sounds like me. Wait, that is my,
do you sound like an idiot?
Do you listen to yourself and get mad?
Fuck saying probably old ones.
I did
because that's changed about you.
How have you gotten better at podcasting?
Because I, I'm not trying to just be
as goofy and stupid as possible anyway,
you do that as a almost like a girl,
you know that's at a party and no one's
paying attention to her so you'll do
something nutty because I like,
I act like I was acting like how
I act like you know, drunk. We,
I'm hanging out with my friends
instead of just saying like, oh,
people are listening to me actually
talked. You know what I mean? Right.
Well then you had to hear though.
Here's something weird that happened to
me last night. I wanted to talk about it.
It's kind of the same way.
I had this weird thing happened to me the
last two days where I have been giggly
and silly and fucking really high
energy and like really happy,
like giggly,
happy.
Like I was running around poking
people with straws last night,
like a little kid and then,
and then it just went away and then
come back to normal. And I was like,
what was that all about?
They get almost felt like there was some
kind of government up in me for now.
You want to remote control. It was
fear way to tune into your frequency.
It was weird though cause it was like,
have I been going through like a uh,
a long time, that pressure and that was
just like a bump out of it, you know,
or something like that. Or have I been
like, you know, lacking something in my,
in my head or diet or something like that.
And I just had whatever had like a
normalcy for awhile because I felt like,
I was like, wow, if I felt like this every
day I would fucking love life. You know,
like crazy. He should on
every day. Yeah, I guess so,
but like how do you even explain that?
Like you can't like rewind, like, Hey,
can you look at my database files? You
know, and tell me what was going on there.
Yeah. It could have been a lot
of different things all at once,
but it was unnecessary and came out of
nowhere. I mean, it's probably good.
Oh yeah, it was great. But I
don't feel I got right now.
But you,
she can't always feel like that was like,
you want the good feelings to
just come to you instead of you.
Her felt that in how long it, like it
was one of those things. It's like,
holy shit man,
this is crazy.
I feel like fucking like I'm on
ecstasy right now for no reason.
You haven't felt like that in a while.
I mean, it was weird. It was just like,
it happened last night and I was just
like silly and giggly for no reason.
Like I was sober and I was just
running around being crazy.
Huh? It was great. So while I'm
setting up this new studio by the,
by, we're working on everything right
now. So I'm started pricing out, you know,
equipment and getting
everything ready in place.
I was going to have a raw cement floor,
but I realize that sound wise going
to be good. So I'm going to go with,
go with rubber rubber,
rubber floor. You know,
like when you have like an a gym
locker room or I shouldn't be fun.
It'd be comfortable, be great
for sound. Maybe like the chores,
that shit in my garage, my gym
that I drop weights on. Right.
That might not be a bad idea.
That way if we drop some phones and Shit,
they won't get broken. Right. I was
actually thinking of going with um, uh,
office carpeting, but that rubber floor
might be better recycle tire floor.
Although it's a, it's a con to
clean. Yeah. It's not fun to clean,
so don't be jizzing on
my fucking rubber floor.
What about like a floor that
they use in like, uh, like a gym,
like racquetball. Racquetball
is hard. Hardwood floors
and that's a real echoey room. Aramco
ballroom when you want a soft things.
So with the carpet absorbs and do you
want to put stuff on the walls like a
Corolla joint. He's got
um, like these big cloth,
uh,
ace broadcasting banners that are
framed and they absorb, you know,
they're,
they're framed and it's,
it's like screen printed are silk screened
onto the cloth and then it's framed.
So it's his banner, several different
places and that absorbs the sound.
But it might actually be cool just
to have, um, just, uh, I liked those,
those soundproof little cone things,
you know what I'm saying? Like that uh,
goes panels with like individual little
cones and I'm like hundreds of cones.
Yeah. Egg Cartons. Exactly. Put
that shit on the wall. But um,
I'm trying to find,
and this is where people out in
the Twitter verse can help me.
I'm trying to find what's the best
office chairs. These are kind of cool.
I like these.
These are all right,
but when I sit back on him
some to get this net ones now,
if you want to get the best ones,
sell those the best fucking thousand
dollar net ones. While men mailer.
How dare they the fuck. How did
they hack the, the mainframe?
I had to turn it back on because our,
our phone went off and went off. No,
I got rid of that feature.
Hold on. It's a good future.
Um,
this is super old school podcast.
If had Internet connection problems.
We've had old phone calls. Yeah.
This is as old schools. We can guys
need to talk about trailer vixen. Oh,
Gary, you can't, you let
it go son. And you should,
the way you should look at
that relationship is that
there's no way you should
be able to fuck girls like that in
real life. I have no problems with her.
She's fine. Okay, good. Beautiful.
So whatever craziness you gotta say,
you gotta say to yourself, why? Of course
there was craziness. She was fucking me.
How could she not be crazy?
You've got to look at it that way.
Make girls go crazy. Yeah. You
sent her crazy and she wasn't,
she has to be crazy to be
fucking you in the first,
but she should be fucking some
giant supermodel dude. Right? Crazy.
I don't do websites that good.
Is that what it is? How dare you?
You're going inside inside knowledge
for folks at home. This is again,
just like the old pot attending.
The one's listening as a fucking million.
Oh Brian,
we got to get those O'Brian tee shirts
made. We keep promising those. Yes. Um,
but so anybody who has any um,
insight is to like, what's the best,
most comfortable chairs within reason?
I guess probably those gravity
chairs from relaxed to back.
Those would be kind of dope.
All massage chairs from Spencer gifts,
but they make too much noise.
You'd be in the middle of the podcast,
the Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah,
Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah. Yeah.
They probably make them say no,
they're not quiet. I mean
they're, they're fairly quiet.
I think it does water massagers where
you like lay in and your head sticks out.
Fuck. Those things are ridiculous.
You have to have like an engine
that pushes all that water around,
doesn't it like a pump?
I don't know if it ever got one of
those. It must be, must be loud as fuck.
How could it not be?
It's a mechanical thing,
something spinning around and
a lot of movement, you know,
you're forcing all that water
through, but I think, um, they, uh,
they have some other chairs that are
like these gravity chairs and lean back,
I think to like more than a
thousand bucks each. There's, um,
there's gotta be something that's like
a decent chair that's like comfortable.
I don't know if office
chairs are the way to go.
I love these shows are really good.
It seems like office chairs. Oh,
for the most support. Right.
I think obviously there's
other way to go. I never,
I mean, couches and other
kinds of chairs are always,
seemed like I've tried almost everything.
You know, we started off with couch.
Yeah. I think we started off with
the couch that was super whack. Uh,
then we had some other couch.
Seems like it would work,
but then it's annoying to sit on the
couch. What would be the best that,
I mean the ultimate, what's the
house? We all had lazy boys.
That is the ultimate. Right. Do you,
have you been to a lazy boy? I store it.
They've done a lot of
good shit with lazy boy.
Would that really be the best
we can all have lazy boy.
I have a laptop right on our lab.
Fucking on the side.
We have our fucking little
places for our drinks.
You know you could easily
do that. If we're going to
do it might as well be most.
How much does the lazy boy cost?
It's much.
Let's find out the lazy boys start
off probably around 300 bucks even.
But I mean getting us some
pimp. Lazy boy, Dude, lazy boy.
It makes them good couches and
everything now. Lazy Boy Rico. Wow.
$2,584 boy store to look at that shit.
No, no, not that. That's old school.
Lazy boy. Good to, I think it's lazy.
Lazy boy.
I'm there@lazyboy.com.
It's la-z-boy.com.
If you just got a regular laser boy,
it takes you to that one and um,
check out these chairs.
Recliners is what you want to check sites.
There's sites getting crushed.
Wonder if it's us two people at once.
Was too much to people,
to people and everybody else
online. It was like, yeah,
let me open up a separate window
here and see what they got.
So these lay reclined all
these reclined, right? Yeah.
Lazy boy recliner. Okay. How much
is this bitch right here? Let's see.
This is in cloth. Should it be
cloth or leather? Leather boots.
Leather boo fuck cows,
right? Fuck. By the way,
all you silly bitches on my website
forum that really think that, um,
when I say fuck all the animals that
are really want all the animals to die,
I'm talking Shit folks. Did you ever
talk shit? They have this website.
This website sucks up back x.
So they met four modems that
this website is fucking terrible.
It's terrible. They show their stupid
things and it's like add to my favorites.
It doesn't tell you about them. That's
it's show me your chairs. Your fuck ass.
That's a sucky website. Lazy
boy. Your website blows, Dude.
Get off your ass and get a new website.
Fix It on.
The other guys are lazy.
They're
just too comfortable to do anything.
You want to be the official chair of
desk squad West, you'll fuck heads.
You have to come up with
something better than that.
Well they have some good
products. They look good. Yeah,
but the websites suck so hard.
It's hard to look at them.
If Lazy Boys Listening to people
listening to the podcast or doing that.
I'm dude, he ha, I mean 3000 people or so.
Just go right to lazy boy.com
at the same time. It probably is
a a I'm retyping pimp lazy boy.
Oh you know there's one I want ostrich
skin cause ostriches a conc fuck conti
birds. Whoa. These are dope
dude. My pimped out low. Okay.
I just found it looking at the
sun. Look at this. Look at this.
If we all got those,
you could have like a little fucking
hoes so you could smoke weed. You know,
decided that laser we Aalto
lazy boy double recliner review.
Ooh,
that might not be a bad idea.
And maybe have the table where it comes
like we can just like pull the table out
or something like,
so kind of like a 1200 bucks for the
regular ones and then 1900 bucks for the
ones that are in leather and that
thing looks pretty fucking sporty dude.
Lazy Boys. And maybe how would that
really be? Would that be annoying? No.
After like a couple of hours would it,
would it get annoying laying down?
I be awesome. You think so? Yeah. Dude.
Lazy boys are just like
this when you lay back,
but just imagine more comfortable.
You have your feet up like a gentlemen.
You think that that would be a good
thing for podcast seats though?
It would suck if I got five lazy
boys and then we decided to blows.
Well we can and you
can't do just have one.
If it was just like me with a lazy boy
and everybody else would regular chair
fucking Dick,
invite me over your place and sit me
in a fucking staples $50 office chair.
Like you got some lazy boys suck.
We just moved the death squad east or
whatever. It's called, well, this one,
this one. Yeah, it does squad
east. It's east. This one is, um,
450 bucks.
That's not bad.
That's a cloth one was like sides to it.
It looks pretty good.
I think the only thing that we might
run into is like people falling asleep.
If it gets boring, those bitches that
could write, especially with stoners,
that could be the issue. Yeah, I do. But
I mean just if you, if you had to ask,
would I rather sit down for three hours,
uh,
with your feet up and comfortable
or bouncing on his office chair?
You know, you want a true,
I mean if we wanted to beds,
we could get single beds each have a
single bed. We'd just all lay there.
That's the move. Bitch. We should stay.
I'll have her own little blankets
would bring her own Kayla.
It'd be like nap time,
wherever. Little blankets
and each person can have their
own quotes that, you know,
fans make and we could have like the red
band quilt have conversations like at
camp you're lying in bed
and the lights go out. Hey,
you guys really think ghosts are real.
Well we get the one where we
each have our own fucking number.
What's it tempurpedic
where we have around the,
although they know the blow one of
air one. Whenever the fuck are they,
what's their fucking the one where the
the one we were back goes up. Yeah. Those,
those, the Tempur-Pedic's are the
ones that foam the memory foam.
That's the good stuff though.
The ones that the blow the air in it.
Like you can get it harder or softer.
And what your number is those,
I had one of those socks.
Just get one of the like the hospital bed
ones where we can put it up and we can
all like we're in a hospital room.
Teeth out would be the commitment if we
all had like hospital beds and we had
like oxygen just going pumped into us.
Why we're all laying there talking. Yeah.
The um, this website is going to
keep me from buying a lazy boy.
No, you need to go to
a lazy boy, uh, store.
I think there's one here in thousand
oaks or something like that that it maybe
we get some sort of a deal with lazy boy.
If you're listing goes boy, contact us.
We'll talk about, we'll,
we'll get you back into that.
Fucking will blow you back up.
We'll get you in.
We'll get a real website designer
to call you. Call at you.
This sack of shit you got going on
here where you don't even you guys,
you silly bitches.
You don't even have prices.
Like there's no prices on your website.
Right? What kind of nonsense is that?
Store locator,
store locator,
but there's a website and you
can't buy shit from your website.
That's ridiculous. Oh, it's
probably because of shipping.
That's 2000 that's so 2003 yeah.
Well you can't even ship kettlebells
without being a headache.
Imagine having shipping,
big old lazy boys. Well,
we can ship kettlebells without being a
headache. It's just a pain in the ass.
But there's other, there's
countries because a lot of money,
but there's a, this is rather
than that ship, big stuff
like that. Crates, comedies.
I like restoration hardware. You know they
sent couches in the mail all the time.
Not in the drop ship river.
I wonder if Amazon has lazy boards.
They have everything now. Him
Aren't. Yup, they do. What?
From a different seller. Let's see
how much shipping is for lazy boy.
Whoa. Okay. I found it,
dude. You go to Amazon.
Look at this sweat. This right here. This
professional high back leather, lazy boy.
Look at this. This, this. This is
what we need, dude. There's no,
there's no foot leg support. That's
that. That's the thing. We get those.
We get separate legs. Supports
Fan. That's not the same.
I know you get a nice ass fat.
Lazy boy feels like you're just
one has a leg sport. Look at that.
That's fine. That's not the
same thing I'm talking about.
The one where you're like,
you know,
think comes out of the bottom of the
chair and you're like pretty much laying
down. Yeah. It's just a bomb.
Yeah. Basically recliner is
what it's called. Yeah, that's,
he really do have to get a recliner,
Huh? Yeah. Yeah. You can't fuck around.
This is pretty sick though.
This lazy boy chair,
the presidential hi back swivel chair.
That looks pretty fucking sporty.
Like that looks cool too.
That will the be like a cool chair to
have in their styles of bucks, man.
You look at the look, this one's
not a lazy boy, but if you look,
go look at this one. It's called the
Wickenburg bonded leather rocker,
recliner and Brown where it's just
a big old puffy lazy boy chair.
That looks fucking comfortable.
It's fun.
It looks like something that you sit
in before you suck cock bill. Man.
I don't even know what that means. I like
which one is that? That's that. Oh look,
this one coaster few coaster furniture.
Try Tom Burgundy top grain leather
recliner. That, that right there man. Oh,
it's only got three stars though.
This recliner comes with
the aids climate in China.
Um, if you, if you had
lazy boy recliners though,
do you think that it would change the
overall tone of a podcast and make people
like to like comfortable mythology
chick, man, we keep the receipt.
Joey Diaz a fall asleep man. Well,
let Joey Diaz put his feet up. Dog.
You blame on one fucking Penn and
teller thing it. Fuck Penn and teller.
Remember how angry he got when
we played Penn Jillette's ramp?
What are you wasting my time
man for like he was angry.
Why are you letting somebody talk
besides me? I'm the fat guy around here.
Um, I can't find a, there's
some pretty good ones.
It seems like that might be an option,
but we have to find a place where
we can sit in one of these things.
That's funny. It was one place
that that chair I looked at,
it was 900 bucks and this place, the
same chair, lazy boy, Presidential Chair,
1500 bucks, bedding,
pillows, bed and Belgians.
That's got a huge fucking
bad wall-to-wall wall.
We all laid down like hippies and we all
have our own little beanbag pillows and
stuff and we act can bring blankets.
I think that's the move like rave style.
I think this is the move.
I think there's a high back presidential
office chair is the move that looks so
suck. 12 person hot tub.
But this looks so sick.
This presidential chair looks
so dope that would like,
and it looks comfortable and a
whole like studio filled with them.
I think that's the perfect compromise.
Like that doesn't look comfortable with
it. I'm just kidding. Super uncomfortable.
It was like one of those
stiff chairs where you have
to climb back. Yeah. You can.
Yeah. It reclines it's leans
back. No, that just rocks back.
That whole thing is connected or,
yeah. Yeah. I'm sure. Yeah. Oh,
I see what you're saying. Yeah. It doesn't
fold at the, uh, at the joint. Yeah. Yeah.
You lean back. Lean back.
I don't know, Dude. I'm,
I'm partial to this. I need to
try this out somewhere. I think
we just need a silver,
one of the silver bullet trailers and
we pimp that motherfucker fucking studio
anywhere the fuck we want. Well,
we could have a mobile studio.
It's not a bad idea to also have, but
I want to just have one of that. Well,
because it's not enough space. No. Have
you seen the big ones? They're huge.
The silver. What are they just
one that the airstream trailer.
look@itasgoodanairstream.com this shit
could completely give up the idea of a
studio and just get a trailer.
Look at these fucking trailers.
These things are fucking amazing and you
can have this anywhere you want to go.
Like if you want to go to fucking
San Diego, if you want to fucking,
I do like the idea of having
something you could bring with you,
like something that you could tow with
you, but really if we're going to do that,
why would we get a studio?
We could get a studio bus if the right
way to do it is to have like one of those
mobile home things,
not a mobile home.
One of those calls RVs or people travel
across the country and those big trucks
like that motherfucker. That's pretty
dope, but it doesn't have a car park.
You know what I'm saying? That's why
we get x suite card at add to it. Yeah.
I guess we get a fucking, how big is
inside of that dude? It's humongous.
They have all different sizes. They have
sizes that you could people, I mean,
people live in these things, right? But
how much does one of those costs look,
they look at these floor plans.
Well these are pretty fucking huge dude.
The dope move would be dude,
to get one of these as a travel
thing and then we go on a tour.
We go like we start in Seattle
and we'd go down Seattle,
San Francisco or Seattle, Portland Klein.
You could fucking pimp this bitch out.
Like look at this shit. You can
pimp this to be our podcast studio.
The whole student. If we gutted this whole
thing out, we've got it all soundproof.
Got It. High Tech. I know. I know
companies that actually do that.
You imagine though, if you've got a
car accident while you're podcasting,
how bad that would suck and who's going
to drive? All our friends are assholes,
dude. We get your fucking driver dude.
And then music guided by it. All the CDS.
You get that guy. That guy might
not be a bad idea. I mean, and I,
and we can just go anywhere.
So fuck like,
oh well you have a show
at the Hollywood Improv,
you fucking park this thing right in
front. That would be pretty dope. Yeah.
You grab people. I mean that's like
having a studio anywhere you go,
but these things that they're towed,
what you really want is one with a
steering wheel. It drives, right?
You just got torn coach. The thing
about this though is when your tea,
if you get towed,
if you have one of those that gets towed,
then you don't even talk to the guy that
was driving. He's just taking you there.
You're completely closed
off in a whole nother area,
so you don't have to hear him on the
phone and have to hear him yelling in
Russian. The ads, what I'm
talking about, big ass one,
we're looking at one that
says the Mercedes Benz one.
Which one was that called?
That's called a avenue or interstate
touring coach. Buy airstream.
And they also have one
called the interstate,
which looks like air streams on
the same server. Your here. Huge.
Yeah, and I mean, this shit's
like a fucking house. I need it.
Maybe I should just buy
one or one of these things.
There's a smaller one you could live in.
Dude. Leave that. That's a van. Basically.
You'd be like, you'd be
the creepy van guy. Yeah.
That's not bad day
because I'm only at home.
I just need to put my animals somewhere.
Maybe get one of this. You know what?
I live in a van. Why not give up on life?
I'm never home just to sleep.
Well,
you should get a secure
department somewhere. Yeah,
I'm safe place where I just have too
many animals for that shit. Oh yeah.
You can't get apartments beyond hog.
If anyone in la once a fucking cat.
I got one free give away.
Your Dad was one cat that I need to
get away with the old one, right? Yeah.
The old ones. That's rude. It's just, it
just doesn't want to be around anybody.
We bought a dog and another cat involved.
It hates those mixed up the the cat.
The cat's life.
What did the other two are fucking like
buddy cop movie and they're cool. Yeah,
they're cooled again. They love
each other and this one's just like,
I hate you guys. Get those
old cats. They don't like new.
Just want to make it a helicopter
and be done with it. Why One cat?
I have one cat that's 15 and one cat.
That's too, I love both of them though.
You have good cats?
Yeah. Nice capitol. Cool.
But the the two year old's Fox with a
15 year old relentlessly. She's always,
you need to out for that cat.
The small dog.
We'll take care of buddy buddy
when he can. His cat. By the way,
I don't ever bring your fucking dog over
here because my whole family would go
crazy for it. All the girls, oh my God,
I'm going to bring it over next time.
I'm going to get a nice haircut. Get
some Bose, bring it over. He did.
It would be gone if you want to get
rid of it. Oh sure. There we go.
I could probably take
it if you really want.
The girls would go nuts cause your
dog is so friendly and she's so small.
My daughters will go crazy. How
old is your dog? A year and a half.
But it's got herpes from the
ex girlfriend, right? No, no.
I sucked all the herpes
or right out on that dog
fucking shows.
Cleaned the bullet out of
that deteriorated drastically
since we came back.
Cubic Karen, I'm sorry about
the, the shit going down earlier.
Ladies and gentlemen, we're really going
to have to fix our issues here. But um,
death squad west should
be up and cracking.
I'm trying to get it
done. Um, we're in June.
I want to get it done before July.
Uh,
we're trying to figure out whether or
not we're going to do a big Vegas show at
the Mandalay Bay in July. If we do
do it, it will be full desk squad,
Ari and Joe, we hopefully, um,
and Brian will come down to,
and maybe even Doug Benson because a. Dot.
I think Doug's playing poker down Dan.
So he,
cause he just asked for tickets the
other day and I'm supposed to come down.
I'm doing Doug's a podcast in Vegas. I
think that's the weekend. Yeah. Yeah,
he did that. And let's stay for an
extra day to do Doug's all right.
We might do that. I can't stay an extra
day, but uh, we'll get things cracking.
All right,
let's get the fuck out of here.
Let's wrap this bitch up tomorrow
night. Uh, the Ice House comedy club,
the second stage and
which is only 85 seats,
if you never been there for those
shows, it's the most intimate. And uh,
I got some new shit I'm trying to work
out on and I'm going to do some question
and answer to it just in a, in an effort
to try to come up with some new shit.
It's a, this is the period of time
for me where it's the most, uh,
nerve wracking and chaotic cause I'm just
fucking around and writing a lot. But,
uh, but it's really fun and one of
the funnest things about it is, uh,
doing these ice house shows
because the crowds are so cool.
It's like it's the perfect environment
to fuck around and practice and try to
stretch out and come up with new stuff
and everybody's really enjoying them.
We're going to do them on a regular basis,
folks,
most likely Wednesday of every week
and a lot of them are Friday. Um,
I'm not going to be at
all the Friday ones,
but I'm going to be at most of the
Wednesday ones and uh, that's all right.
We're rolling bitches.
We got more common. Uh,
tomorrow we are, we're off cause
you got something going on.
I'm going to eat three,
but then we have the icehouse chronicles
that tomorrow it starts at the podcast
was starting at eight. The show's at eight
30 ice house comedy.com. Thursday, um,
is not John Anthony West. John
Anthony West has been moved to Friday.
Thursday is now your Riaa Faber.
So Thursday you're,
Ryan has a really short schedule and he's
in town and he's going to do it live.
John Anthony West is going
to do it through Skype.
It's going to be our first Skype podcast.
So video, just audio, video and audio.
So he's going to show us
pictures and tell us things.
So it'll be a little weird for
the folks that are just listening,
but we'll explain it as best we can. And
if you don't know John Anthony West is,
he's one of my personal heroes.
He's an egyptologist, a fascinating,
brilliant guy who is the producer of
a video series called magical Egypt,
which is one of the most comprehensive
video series on ancient Egypt.
And especially like the hidden
symbolism involved in hieroglyphs and,
and the, the, the construction
of their, their, uh, their,
their pyramids and their,
their temples and all their different
thing. I mean, really amazing, amazing.
Stopped.
I,
I can't stress enough how pumped I
am to talk to this guy cause he's,
uh, just, uh, an incredible source of
information when it comes to Egypt.
The guy's been involved in studying it
his entire life and he's got just some
brilliant work out there. I can't
wait to talk to that dude. Uh,
so that's Uriah Faber on Thursday.
John Anthony West is going to be on
Friday and I think we got someone on
Saturday, dude. Saturday. Yeah. I think
some something's going on at Saturday.
May or may not be happening on Saturday.
Like someone who couldn't
do it any other day.
I'll let you know soon as
we'd get out of his pocket.
So I'm not sure what the
fuck I'm talking about here.
I don't even know what I'm saying. That's
scheduling stuff. I'm not sure about.
This might be ruined in me.
Selegiline and Alpha brain together
are battling for dominance. Right. Um,
thank you everybody for tuning into the
podcast. Thanks for everybody who, uh,
thanks to everybody who came
to Edmonton this past weekend.
Ari and I had a great fucking
time. Uh, like I said before,
I appreciate the fuck out of
it and there's not a moment
where I'm taking any of
this for granted and, uh, uh, we're
gonna keep this pitch rolling.
Thanks to the flashlight for sponsoring
our podcast. Go to Joe rogan.net.
Click on the link for the flashlight.
Enter in the code name Brogan and save
yourself 15% off the number one sex toy
for men. Thank you also to onnit.com
makers of Alpha brain, shroom,
tech, sport, shroom,
tech, immune and new mood.
We will have kettle bells and protein
powder made out of hemp and raw cocoa and
Maka coming soon and got a lot of good
stuff on the horizon and a that's all for
today.
You dirty bitches.
So we'll see you on Thursday with Uriah
Faber and then Friday will be John
Anthony West today.
If you're wondering if you're somewhere
in the future and you have just stumbled
upon this podcast,
it is June 5th,
2012 would have been better if
I said 2000 without slurring.
2012 all right, that's it,
right? Death Squad shirt.
Go buy a death squad shirt.
Go to desk squad.tv and we've got
a Mike Maxwell desk squad shirt,
a new one that's coming out.
It's fucking dope.
It's a chimp with a gas mask on
it. It says death, Death Squad,
department of Health and
welfare. Love it. Excellent.
We're also going to have those t
shirts that Maxwell made, or excuse me,
those posters at Maxwell
made for Chicago and Atlanta.
We're going to turn those into tee
shirts because so many people have been
requesting them and the,
they're really cool posters and
it's available on Mike Maxwell,
art.com Mike will also be there
tomorrow night. He's coming down to a,
to the ice house. So that's
it. You've freaks. We love you.
We're all in this together. All
of us. As unlikely as it seems,
although it makes no sense,
we are all part of something
much greater than ourselves.
One big giant fucking soup
of things spinning around.
Okay.